Oh yeah, that's all he is. And
we're live. That's it. Hi. Hello?
Richie. Yeah, this stuff. Purple
Venom. That's what he calls it.
That's what his friend calls it. And
uh, yeah, it's friends like, you know,
I'm pretty skeptical, skeptical
about other people's stuff.
But then you try to hope. Now
was that a coke nail? No Fun. No.
I know people think long and people
think that their coke nails do not know
they're real. You. You don't
do coke. I don't do coke ever.
Have you ever done me? I do. Coke
zero. I have done, I, I have done a,
it's like coke light. It's like, it
looks like coke. You can snort it.
It feels like coke weed doesn't give
you high. Um, no. Uh, I, I have,
I've tried it. I would say honestly
maybe four times and I've never,
it's always just felt like I just took
three shots of espresso and I'm not,
it's not really, it doesn't do
anything for me. Then I'm like,
I better get him a better invest in that.
I need to try it one day because it
just, I need to know what's going on.
I'm 51 years old. How do I know
no what coke is? I, you know,
I think it's worth, I mean, if
you don't, if you, you know,
if you don't have a predisposition for
being a hyper addictive personality,
I definitely do. But Oh gosh,
I'm also wise enough to know and I can
quit things and you've got experience.
You can control yourself. But like
I, I, I was never, I was never like,
I guess I've just never been
someone who's like, Oh shit.
Gotta have that forever. Like
I've never been that way.
The only thing that I'm reduced to now
is just weed. That's it. Well, me too.
But I also think that it's one of those
things if your, if your life is healthy,
if you have a good balance and you're
enjoying your time and you're being
creative and you have good
friends and you have fun,
you're not looking for
something to fuck your life up.
I think many of the times when you
dealing with people that have like severe,
debilitating addictions that are
really just taking over their life,
there's something else going on. Almost
always just like problems, you know,
relationship problems, work
problems, life problems. Yeah.
They're not happy yet.
There's an emptiness.
There's an emptiness that wants to be fed
or maybe you have a lot of success and
you're freaking out about the success.
I think that happens with some
celebrities. Yes, I think so. Yeah.
Overstimulation and you don't know how
to handle, let's do this show. Yeah,
let's do it. Yeah. Here it is.
So you can have the first I used to
an automated machine or the auto.
Have you heard of it? No. So cool.
It's like this like little reminder
and it's like grinder and it,
and it fits on a tube that you put an
empty rolling thing in there and say like
you put that in there or you got
it. Um, and then it's like a, yeah,
it's like a clear tube. You put it
in the pre-rolled, you know, empty,
whatever joint thing. And then a,
and then you put this machine that
just goes over, attaches magnetically,
and then you put it in your weed and
you just press a button and it's like
coffee makers
and it fills it up perfectly.
And then you just pack it by shaking
it and twisting it and you're done.
These goddamn stoners today,
they're getting too crazy.
I don't, I rarely spoke.
I always make exceptions for stuff
like this. You look at it? Yeah. Wow.
That's actually a pretty
sleek looking. Yeah,
that's by banana brothers
I think. You know, I,
I smoked pretty regularly but
um, I got high with be real.
I did a this smoke box
show and I'm like, okay,
I'm going to be real a rat Cypress Hill.
I was separate and it would catch
him how dialogize I bought it.
I just see now I know nothing
about hip hop. See that damn ready?
I not know anything about Cypress Hill.
I know, I know. People are always like,
you gotta know about hip hop. I'm
like, I know shit. I know. Run DMC,
you really don't know any hip hop.
Now I kind of stopped after
the Bohemian phase, you know,
like after a tribe called
quest and de la soul.
Like it just kind of lost me because it
then it turned into I liked gangster in
the beginning, you know, cause it
was something new and you're like,
what the fuck is this? Oh that's
so cool. You know? But uh,
then it kind of morphed into club hop
where it just was all about bitches and
cars and all that shit. And it was
really the lyrics, the beats I loved.
I thought it was cool, but
I just like, no, I mean I,
because I left in 95, I left pop in 95,
96 and then I know there's plenty
of hip hop heads. I'd be like, dude,
you gotta check out so you
gotta check out. You get your,
I know there's shit loads of shit and
I'm, maybe I'll go back into that phase.
But mostly I just liked the beats
and the production and the lyrics.
I'm not really, I'm not, I'm
not a lyrics guy anyways.
I am a lyrics guy and Nas is definitely
my favorite lyricist because his stuff
is so creative. Like what it was that one,
we did everything backwards
to the whole song backwards.
Like he started at the end then
what the fuck was that called?
James can rewind. Yeah. I mean
I mean made you look creative.
Yeah. It made you look like
I saw that and I was like,
that was actually a
moment where I was like,
Oh am I gonna am I going to start
getting back into this shit?
Cause cause it was intelligent.
Um, you know what I mean?
Like my thing is like if you're going
to be boastful and all this shit,
it should be like Muhammad Ali. Right,
right, right. You should have clever,
clever flare, but also you can
just be right in someone's face.
But I liked that.
But then when people are like kind of
going off about how much money they have
and all that shit, I'm like, I don't
really care about that. Well I,
I've analyzed this many times while
under the influence, the culture,
it comes from not having something.
And then once you have something
bragged about it, right,
like that's like Jay z,
like that's a 99 problems.
He talks about that 99 problems.
Yeah, I mean I get it, I get it.
But like at the same time if the,
if it just sounds like basically the
three things that everyone talks about,
which is like women cars of some sort
and money or the things that you can buy
with money after awhile it just
all bleeds together. It's all this,
it's the same song and I mean it's so
dope that you can come from nothing and
you can work your way up and you can
hustle and you can get stuff going in.
But like once you get to that place,
like why not take advantage of that?
Plus what about run the jewels? I've
heard good things about chance the rapper.
I've heard good things about it. God
Dang. I know. I don't know shit man.
I'm more of like a the jewels. So
cream and electronic guy. I like music.
Let me, let me turn you
on to some run the jewels.
I wish we could play it on the podcast,
but then we can't do that anymore.
Back in your day, yeah, they would
run your Julius and out of town,
but back in the day when you
had a, like the Internet was,
no one knew what a podcast was.
You could do all kinds of shit.
You could just play things.
I mean you still can,
I mean the best live stream you could
take him down and get d monetized.
You get a strike against your
channel. If you get three strikes,
they take your channel down
permanently. [inaudible] Youtube. Yes.
That's the real problem. I'd
choose the real problem. I'm a,
I'm bypassing all that very
soon. What are you doing?
I'm just doing my own live
streaming. That's all right.
Yeah cause that way I just don't have
to worry about all that bullshit. Yeah,
I mean that lead, that's where it's
probably going to have to go. Yes.
But at the same time everybody's
at Youtube. Yeah. So, so the,
the secret is, or the question is like
how can you, it could be both. Yeah,
exactly. That. That was the way to
zero. Zero Alcohol High Mountain.
Are you serious? Yeah,
I'll try to zero. Yeah.
Cause my problem with
alcohol is alcohol. So yeah.
Actually they taste like
a regular Hanukkah trick.
What I found out, if you see
these, what does that, it's a
microtech uh, California
legal switchblade. What? Yeah.
What are you stabbing people at a tiny
knife. What are you doing right now?
I've been going on since I saw you. I
like it. Well, I like having done that.
I'm from Montana. You always have
a knife. You just always have it.
It's like the greatest tool,
but uh, it makes sense.
How's the button go? Okay. So hold
it the opposite way. Turn it around.
Flip it around. Yep. And then
the button on the top side.
See there's like a lever. No thing here.
So this is on the back of
the glass breaker. Okay. Oh,
glass breaker for like if you're
in your car, you know, or whatever.
I needed to break the window. Jesus.
Um, but uh, here's the switch.
Does that really what that's for?
Yes. Let me say that mean. Crazy.
So this would break
your window? Yeah. Hmm.
But how many people do you think
could break a window with this?
I bet if you've got a lot of people
and some old car windows and like,
like line them up and just fucking,
yeah because it seems like that's like,
that's like kind of weird.
A weird like standardized tip for
glass breakers really. That crazy.
So would you see, but it seems like
it's slime in your hand. It doesn't,
it's too small. I think if
you, you know, if you wedge it,
if you held it tight and your fist,
you know with your thumb over.
I think if you hit at it's more about
velocity I think rather than strength
black it. Yeah.
Because the way it's designed is to just
be like super like precise strike wants
carrying a glass breaker with them,
man. Yeah we're playing the games.
You Ready? Do you have water? You have
like bottled water in your comment cards?
I have bottled water, I
have a jumper, jumper self.
You know you can jump yourself if you
have bottled water in your car in La
you're basically drinking.
What is that shit that comes the leaks
into your from your plastic PC. BPS.
I'm not using, I have glass. It's all
glass. You have glass. How dare now.
Fuck that. I don't, I'm not, I mean like
people are going to be like bitch him.
Cause I talk about plastic
bottles all the time, but oh,
because we have one here. Yeah, it's
you, it's a better solution for that. B,
get glass and get a water
judge. Hey, just you just get a,
you just get a municipal
filter and that's it.
And you get alkalized water
room temperature, whatever.
And you can just have clean water and
you just have tons and tons of vessels.
I'm sure. What someone would BKR would
sponsor you or something like that.
That'd be kr. They're
uh, they're uh, like uh,
I guess you'd a canteen company or
water carrying like Judd Company.
It's having people drink out of
mason jars. That would be terrible.
Like old folks. Yeah. Hell yeah. Are
you kidding? Yeah. It'd be like a,
you know, like grandma's
kitchen cupboard. Yeah.
Why do people like
drinking out of Mason Jars?
I think it started with
grandma's. What was that band?
What was that one brand?
No, it was that one. Um,
sort of a bluesy rocky
band that pretty recently.
Bam. Goddamn whizzer. Jamie's
damn wizard. How he do it?
He's how he do it. He knows what I'm
going to ask before I, he googles it.
He's a wizard. He got something. He's got
something, some special talent, but a,
yeah, those guys, they dressed like
they were from another era. Right.
They wore like weird clothes
from like the pioneer days.
They look like time travelers, like
from a steam conqueror. I mean kind of.
I mean, I know what you're saying.
Like in the beginning, you know,
Fortune Fester, the, Oh yeah, yeah,
yeah. It's really funny. She's funny.
She had her, she's, I
wish I remember her joke,
but she had a funny joke about
Mumford and sons and mason jars.
W really sweet. Yeah. Oh, that's good.
I think it was like something
to the tune of, you know, shoes,
Mason jars for real, not like,
not like this bullshit. Oh yeah.
So I actually grew up poor. I think
that was it. I apologize from wrong.
That wasn't, I mean, that's very
funny. I mean, she is. She's so rad.
I saw her in a, an Oh
and Australia. Sydney.
She's doing a podcast with Tom Papa.
Oh yeah. Who's Tom Papa? Sorry,
dare you again. Sorry guys. Tom Papa
is a brilliant standup comedian.
Really, really funny guy.
Super, Super Nice guy too.
And he's the master of bread.
He read bread. Oh Shit.
He makes his own sourdough bread and it
is sensational out that, that, that's,
that's, that's too much. Versus
to be able to take over here.
He brings a loaf of bread and
grass fed butter. Oh no, Bro.
You cannot resist us. This
bread, it's bread is so good.
Fuck your Kito Diet. If it
does include Tom Papa's bread.
Fuck your Quito Diet. Does he
sell it at a bake? No, no, no, no.
Just makes himself, there
he is. And he has a,
here's a television show he's doing on a
food network where he's visiting bakers
. He's a brilliant guy and super nice guy.
Like couldn't be a nicer guy and just
loves making bags. He's so silly.
That's meat and his bread.
It's so good. And it's like,
I really believe this, that if you get
the food from someone who's really cool,
like it feels different. It
tastes different. And Tom's just,
Tom is just such a nice guy and
he's so funny and he's so smart.
Like when you're eating his bread,
like you feel like I'm eating a
cool guy's bread. Yeah. You know,
it's like someone who you love cooks.
You sound like if your mom cooks
you something, it's like wow.
So it's not just good. It's good. And
it comes from love. Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah. Cause yeah, the person who made
it to standing right there. Right.
You're having it. Yeah. It's pretty
unique experience. Especially with bread.
Yeah. I think that's the big thing with
food too, with, with cooking. You know,
I, I never really thought of food as
an art form until I started watching no
reservations,
which was a Anthony Bourdain's original
show backwards on the travel channel.
Okay. And then I was like,
oh Duh. Like I in my head,
like they were just cooks. I'll
go. They just cook and food.
Cause I cooked food before I used to
work at Newport creamery. I made burgers.
Yeah. Make grilled cheese. Sure.
Yeah. Yeah. That's cool. Good.
So it's like I knew how to put
the fucking fries in. Yeah.
But watching these chefs create these
like really elaborate creative dishes,
you start going, oh,
oh this is an art form.
It's just a like a weird one.
Like it's temporary. It doesn't,
don't only exist for a
short window in time,
but now that we have film of it and
now that we have photographs of it,
like things in Instagram, now
you start to appreciate that. Oh,
it looks amazing too. I
guess part of the thing,
it's like if you could have
like the most incredible steak,
but it came to you and it looked like
the shittiest looking lentil soup,
like split pea soup. It's like
a split. Just put just a Gr,
just the peas though.
Just a bowl of green.
But it was the most incredible taste,
like, yeah. But it looks weird. Yes.
Right, right, right. But yeah, but
they're like, they're making things like,
yeah, they're addressing it as
many senses as possible now.
Like everything red looks
good. Yeah. Looks like seven.
You want to hit cross in the outside of
those little slices on the top of the
circle the bread. Like look at that.
See how it gets. Yeah, I know. Yeah.
And you're like, oh, this has to,
we have to take care of this. Yes.
It's our message. It's art too. It's
like, it's a temporary art form.
We just think of art as
something like, you know,
that Buddhist statue or something
that just lasts forever. Yeah.
But there's some art, like a sandcastle
temporary. Well, you know, in a,
in a weird way. Um, or in, in a weird way,
music is kind of like that if it's
not recorded, right? Yeah. Well, no,
I mean if it is recorded because
you only experienced it temporarily,
but it is this as an idea in
your head, you know, that like a,
like a ghost image of it. But then
when you listened, listened to it,
when you press play and you listen
to it, it's happening in real time.
As soon as you stop it, it's
no longer, no longer exists.
So you're still just like in the
kind of shadow memory of it. Right.
If you're not interacting with
it, it doesn't exist. Yeah. Wow.
Yeah. Imagine there was something
like that you could do with smells,
right. Oh, smells one sense. That
doesn't get any love like your eyes,
people who make all these
beautiful things. Right. Your ears.
People make beautiful
music. Yeah. You got like
perfume, Cologne and some fucking flowers.
It's all you got [inaudible] and weird
shit like Pachulia where like settle
down, settle down. So that way
you wouldn't set it down. What?
You wouldn't have beads settle down.
Settle Down with your instinct.
Incense sticks, amber,
amber sticks, amber smells.
By the way, Ms Pat, after she
was on, she sent me incentive.
Did you send it to you
to Black Pussy incense?
Does she make one? No, she was
just talking about crazy incense.
A flavor that she, she,
she's aware of. Oh,
she's saying she uses them or people use,
I mean the thing is you know that
there's a niche market where people were
making custom incense with names like
that. Right? Like they legitimately are.
I'm naming them that way
because it's a hip thing. Yeah.
That's a very specific kind of person.
Right? If you're in an intense person,
you have some kind of rug on the floor,
like some kind of Persian type rug.
Is Ms Pat that she said?
Yeah. So what is it?
Hey Joe Rogan could have said
you. These one says button naked.
What is the other ones? How many lack of
love. There you go. Black butter. Yeah,
pussy to. Do you know Ms Pat? No. Oh my
God, you got to meet her. She's a funny,
she's one of the funniest human
beings on earth for sure. Damn.
One of the funniest people I've ever
met, like right up there with Joey Diaz.
Shit. She's so funny. She's ridiculous.
Like you leave a podcast with
her and your fucking face hurts.
Someone said that if you get
John Witherspoon, Joey Diaz,
and miss pat on a podcast together,
we would like break the space time
continuum. Are you going to do it?
Fuck yeah, I would love to do
this, but I would just, I would,
I would shut my mouth. I
wouldn't say a word. I'm like,
I just want them to have fun.
Do you know John Witherspoon?
I don't know dude. He came on with his
son. His son. JD is a comic as well.
Yeah, I met JD at the comedy store and
we're talking about his dad. I'm like,
your dad is, he's like epic human
being like, he's so fucking funny.
And he's like, let me, let me get my dad
to come into the podcast. We're like,
yeah, let's do it. I would love to have
you guys on, let's see. Come on. So, uh,
it might acts with my idea. I don't
remember how it came out. But anyway,
he comes in here and it's like,
the sun is like completely normal.
Jay d intelligent. He's funny.
He's like very, very like you've,
you've, you know, you're not shocked
by him. He's a funny, Smart Guy,
but his dad is from another planet.
Everything he says is funny
the way he says it. It's funny,
he does not give a fuck. Oh,
I know that cat dude. Yeah,
he's on like his own
groove. He's on this a,
I don't give a fuck times a million groove
and it's been doing it a long time. Even
as it sounds like laughing like wow.
He's like, see this is what I grew
up with. I'm like, that is crazy.
He's so funny. Like that guy. You can
make him funny in a movie. You know,
you give him a good movie part,
he'll deal, do great in it.
But he will never be able to compare it
to him. Just being him in the moment.
Cause you lose that in
the moment. Well you know,
he doesn't have anything planned out.
He's not reading a fucking script.
The guy just for three hours is just
hilarious about anything about shoes.
He's hilarious about money.
He's hilarious about his drink.
He gets to put his money in his
pocket and rub it like he's, yeah,
he like can hit any, any angle,
anything is fair game. It's,
he's doing a kind of art.
The Art of being him,
this is what me and his son were talking
about and this is why it relates he's
doing an art form, but it seems like
he's just being himself and he is,
but he's figured out how to beat himself.
That is the most hilarious to the most
people and it's a matter of whether or
not you can plug that into a
movie successfully. Schmidt,
maybe the best thing about
him, just let them talk.
Just let them talk like
fuck your fuck your scripts.
Like this guy's got a thing. You
know he's got a thing. Yes. That is,
it's an art about art. It's
like, it's just like cooking.
It's just like any like just like music.
There's an art to being a person even.
Yeah, for sure. Yeah. Right.
Like why are some girls sexier?
Is it just biology or is there an art
to the way they communicate with you?
Like when people are being flirtatious
and and talking to each other.
There's an art to that. Just like a
little bit of a dance going on there. Yes,
absolutely. Some people are
better at it. Yeah, I mean, yeah.
I mean it's a, you know,
what gets your attention?
I mean there's so many factors and it's
like what it's like also like what you
tend to view, what's the first cue
that generally will set you off,
whatever that is experienced as you
were a kid or you know, someone,
your aunt or whatever it was was really
cool and your cousin was a really sexy,
and those two,
a combination of those two elements
are like something that you hit.
But I will say like, yeah, I
think it's just someone who's,
who's come when they're comfortable
with themselves. They just have,
it also depends on what
you're looking for too,
but because there's a co-residents,
there has to be just like art,
just like music. We're talking about
like, do you like it or not music to you,
it might be the greatest song of
all time to Jamie. He's like, yeah,
I can take it or leave it. Yeah.
Yeah. And then we can have a con,
you can have an argument about it, which
is really sweet. No one's ever right.
The bottom out. Yeah. It's all
subjective. Love Motley crew.
You love Molly crew. It's not, it's not,
this isn't anything wrong with
bloody crude example, but if you,
if you're fucking at
home by yourself going
[inaudible] you're loving
it. That, that's art.
Like why was that judge, I do that with
Whitesnake all the fucking debts up.
Told the story before. But a dude sent
me in a Whitesnake is set and a, I,
I used to, it's in the office because, uh,
I had a girlfriend that made me throw
it away after I got in a car accident.
I had a Whitesnake is set in my
call. Why? Why don't you make it?
Because she thought it was bad Juju.
She's really into telling me what to do.
She was older than me.
Okay. And, um, she, uh,
she's packing up all my stuff cause
I, my car was broken, you know, got,
I got t boned and uh, as I'm grabbing
all my stuff, um, she's like, leave that.
I go leave what? She's
like, leave the white snake,
see like you gotta get over that music.
And I was like, really? She's like,
yeah, it's terrible music.
She was in like the pixies,
that kind of Shit I don't even know
existed back then. I loved that.
I loved them too. But I
also loved Whitesnake.
There's a thing that people do though
where they only like things that make them
appear smart or interesting and
there's like, it's like a hustle.
Like you, you tell people you're
really an Indian food and you really,
you might really be, but there's also
a thing you're doing. Like you're,
you're that person that's
only into the cool stuff,
but like that fucking
Whitesnake song is bad ass.
[inaudible] yeah, that's, it's awesome.
They only had a few that
were like really good.
They had that song is fucking
bang and to this day is this love.
That's a sexy video. That was good videos.
It's like one of my favorite videos.
It's like the coolest,
even though it was eighties and it was
like hyper eighties it's one of the few
videos to me in my mind
that is, that had a style,
that was that kind of approach
is timeless. Really? Yeah.
In a way it's good this week,
this sincere, the sincerity of it.
I mean that video is sexy with tawny
contain and and and like her moving like
around the bed or whatever. It was
classy. It was, it was like sexiest,
very adult kind of like
watch it shit I have,
but she looks amazing and, and I love
him just leaning on the wall like that.
I mean it's like come on, just
take brick wall and he's like,
Mr Cool Guy. Certainly it's,
it's done in such a sincere way,
but it's just on the right side of me
still thinking that it's fucking great.
It's great art direction. It's
promoting ridiculous interactions.
It promote him up promoting a ridiculous,
a relationship. Just fucking talk.
What is all this trauma? I mean
that shit like those shots come on.
His hair is one man. He's very
serious about what he's singing.
He's like a better look and
Luke from general hospital.
I remember Luke and Laura. That's what
that guy is like a better look in Luke.
That's so hilarious. His
hair is preposterous.
I know everybody's hair is
just like off the chart.
Imagine if you had a friend that
just had hair like that. Like, Hey,
let's go down, let's go hit the gym.
He's like, hey man, you want to go go.
And he's Kinda like,
look at some a gallon of hairspray and
that shit I primped out. That's just,
I mean, back then, that's just
crazy to me. That's white hair, bro.
Yeah. You have the solution to that.
Yeah. Yeah. Your hair, you just,
it's fantastic. You don't have to do
anything. Yeah, exactly. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's a totally lazy, it's lazy. Yeah.
It's chaos. But at the same time like,
ah know, but there's no work involved
in that. No. It's a beautiful chaos. Oh,
I see what you're saying.
As opposed to like,
you know you got one of them pics and
you're spraying pics and spray. Oh yeah,
his hair that, oh I know there's
a lot of work involved there.
That's a shit ton of hairsprays the
lady offset. It's just to keep pumping.
Yeah, kind of constantly
checking, symmetry,
duty cheering and Jan,
I mean the, the guitar,
the band that like Whitesnake
the band once it was like,
it was the Super Group of hard rock like,
like it or metal. I guess you can
kind of, it kind of bleeds into that.
Like classic metal.
This has been a few of those supergroups
I just went freaked me out man.
I'm like, yeah, off the car. 20th doing
the Car Lady. It's like she doesn't,
she just doesn't care. She's rude.
She's doing cartwheels and wild look up
since serious. That's what I mean man.
He's really serious about what he's
singing about and he's got three synth
players in a row, but in the way.
Yeah, look at that. Yeah. How,
what does that mean?
That's kind of hardcore.
I wish we could play this cause it's
so wonderful. I do love the idea.
I mean let the hair color combination
in the car. I mean, you know what,
this is good. This is what happened when
the war on drugs had a brief victory.
Oh, what happened that you were talking
about the band for a second. I'm like,
ma'am, you are talking about
tense release times care here.
You're talking about the
time Jimi Hendrix in this.
Is that the absence of drugs like
Oh this music created all this coke,
this coke music. This is definitely,
maybe it's every now and then,
but it's not created by coke. Yeah,
but it's like high end party. You know,
like these guys are living like the high
end party shit. Sure. I guess that's,
I guess that's where they're coming from.
But I mean to me that's what I like.
You know, someone described
the Ns ten's the uh, the uh,
classic stage monitors or
sorry, studio monitors.
Like when you're switching between
different types of speakers,
show me what that looks like. Um,
right now you and Jamie were on the same
frequency. He's the audio guy. Oh yeah,
yeah. Well they're like a, they were
like this classic mixing and like that,
like our atone and like they're just
like speaker systems that have kind of
become standards to a
certain degree. And so,
and the weird thing about Inez tens,
it's like in the 80s when
they were using them,
I believe that's the
right name for it, but uh,
went in the 80s when they were
using them, it was really,
it had so much harsh high end.
It was so crispy sounding and they
said it was because of uh, yeah. Um,
it's because of a coke usage
and coke usage like creates a,
basically brains tend to favor different
sound frequencies under the influence
of different drugs. And with coke
they like the high end crispy sizzle.
That was like hitting all the
time and that was all amplified.
So then when you hear eighties
music, it tends to be, it's mixed,
not all of it,
but a great deal of it is mixed with a
lot of like upper mid trouble minus crisp
enos. That's kind of a, that totally
makes sense. That's what, you know,
sometimes albums need to be
remastered because of that. Wow. But,
but that speaker is responsible.
That's I, this is what I heard.
So this is second hand information, but
position that makes sense to you. Right.
It does totally make sense to me. I mean,
it's one of those subtleties that you
may never think about, but then when you,
you hear about it and you learn about it,
it blows open a whole new way
of thinking about things. Well,
I don't know this, but that's what
everybody has always said about the, the,
the dead and LSD. Exactly. Yeah.
That if you like the people that don't
get the dead [inaudible] and I'm guilty
of being one of those people. Yeah.
I'm not a huge fan, but I respect them.
It's because you haven't
listened on LSD, a parent, Lee,
according to people that
I say, you listened to the
dead on LSD and you're like,
oh my God, I get it. Oh, I
see. I see. Interesting. It's,
it's LSD music. Yeah. Yeah, totally.
My cousin used to follow them around.
Really? She followed it down for cod,
I want to say a couple of years where
she was on Twitter with selling bacon and
eggs out of the car. She was total hippie.
That's like a real super legit hippie
that's kind of sick. That's rare.
So I gotta talk to her about like the
culture. It's like everyone's on acid.
They're all doing. So many
of them were doing ass trams.
I would say every one of them,
but it's like it's probably half,
which is crazy for a concert.
Imagine going to a concert and half the
people were doing mushrooms like percent
a hundred percent of the time, half
the fee. I don't know if I'm that,
if you're some pros we can
all say that right now.
Going to just don't have number. I'm
sorry. I'm just guessing. I think it's a,
it's, it's a psychedelic inspired music
that once you're under that psychedelic,
apparently it makes sense. And this is
not me talking from personal experience.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I mean, it could be
one of those things where, you know,
there's like a photo that's slightly out
of focus and then if you like bring in
another, uh, or now
better yet, like a code.
It's like you get a picture of something
and you're like, I don't can't,
I can't tell him what it is. Abstract.
And then you put this other layer on it
and it completes it and you're like, oh,
that's what it is. In a way. Like
I can imagine that being true,
but I can also say once you've
experienced music that really ignites your
imagination. If you hear music
that sounds amazing on LSD,
it should also sound
amazing to you personally.
Not on it.
How you can tell that it would be
even more amazing if you were on LSD,
but it already sounds
great. It's like, to me,
qualities like it exists in all
states. So like it's just, uh, yeah.
Anyways, that's kind of how I look at
it. It's an interesting perspective.
But you would think definitely the people
see things differently when they're
under, when they're under the influence
of shootings. Absolutely. You,
you don't think there can
be like a tipping point? Oh,
I think you're right. No,
I, and to to your point, yes. I do think
that there is music where you're like,
I don't know man.
And then you listen to it on mushrooms
or whatever and you're like, oh fuck,
this is dope.
I remember the first day it does into
to whole lot of love when I was high.
Yeah. And you know that period
there's a, in the middle of the song
where it's all just
thimbles and fuck music,
it's like Ah, ah, ah, oh yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yes. God, Tim, I love that song.
But when you listen that song high,
you like these guys were wild. Oh yeah.
I mean this is the 1970s right?
And these guys made a song
where it started off great.
And then for a minute and a half it was
just bones and fuck sounds shake from
baby. I want to be your
backdoor man. Hey. Oh,
what? I was looking up to
this LSD grateful dead thing.
So their sound engineer who
went under the name bear,
which if you know anything about the
grateful dead, they used the bears.
He was one of the only scientists when
LSD was out lost. I could still make it.
Wow. That was the sound
guy. Oh Jesus Christ.
He made over 5 million doses,
but in between 65 and 67 it says they
had their own personal guy and he was the
one that making the sound.
So if that guy still alive,
man put him in jail for the rest of the,
so they were strictly
formatted for listening right
here. Says he died in a car.
Oh Australia.
That's probably on the wrong side
of the road because he was on acid.
Let's just pause. Don't
get mad. Oh, he's my hero.
I just cry in jail. But that's amazing.
So they have their own built in chemist.
God, that must've been good
to them. That's so cool.
I love that because that's responsible.
I think that that's the responsible
thing to do your own chemist.
That way you're not buying any nonsense.
You're getting it from a
guy who's a chemist. Yeah.
This is your person that personally
makes this stuff for you.
You know where it comes from? Just Matt.
How many people got
busted at those concerts?
The feds or the DEA ever crackdown?
Those concerts when I worked, I uh,
you worked, you said you worked
security at like a [inaudible]. Yeah,
I did two for a summer and one of the
concerts we did was for Phil as she's the
Bass player of the grateful dead.
And my job for that day was to walk
around the parking lot and they would just
yell at me and my buddy,
we were 19 years old,
six up six up that thought we were going
to arrest everyone and they would try
to give us the goofballs which have a
bunch of drugs and I'm already to sort of
dose this so that we'd leave
everybody alone. What's a goofball?
It's like a popcorn ball.
But from what I was told,
I've never had one bunch of psychedelics
and all sorts of shit in it. Yeah,
just like a thing you would eat.
Oh my Jesus. Never heard of that.
That's not what you were eating.
Yeah. You just took a chance,
just get too high. The first guy,
the first guy who stumbled on
mushrooms, I was like, what the fuck?
Like mushrooms had to have been like
relearned at some point in time they were
like had to be some people that lived
in an environment where there was no
mushrooms,
where people didn't get them and then
someone found them somewhere but they
didn't have any personal knowledge of
what it was and tried it and ate it and
tripped.
That had to have happened. Yeah, I
mean I think, you know, it could,
it could also be like, Hey, I'm
foraging for Blah Blah Blah.
And because arguably they would say
mushrooms are around like way, way, way.
Some people, you know, not so
scientific perhaps, I don't know,
or maybe scientific have surmised that
may be consciousness or self awareness
came from thes r species running into
some kind of a psychedelic event which
caused like this hyper self awareness
loop or whatever and then deserves a lot
of attention because people are so
resistant to it. Like really rational,
intelligent people are so
resistant to it. And a,
it's almost resistant to that
concept of, well, yes, maybe, uh,
our consciousness was somehow
influenced by psychedelic, but to a man,
almost to a man, all the, wow.
I shouldn't say that even.
I'm overstate over generalizing,
but many of those people have not had
psychedelic experiences that dismiss them
so readily. That's true.
The people that have had psychedelic
experiences that tend to be skeptical or
more rational, they wouldn't,
they're not going to have a definitive
position on it. They're going to go,
well, yeah. Right. Something to
consider. It's more measured. Yeah.
The hard liners, you know, there's
a hardliners on both sides.
The hardliners definitely believe that
happened in the hardliners who believed
that they don't have any positive
effects whatsoever. Yeah, yeah, totally.
I both almost equally foolish.
Exactly. Yeah. Yeah. I mean, that's a,
that's what we're experiencing right now,
but at least the people
that have experienced it,
they know what they're talking about.
The people that haven't experienced it
and don't think it's worth trying. Like,
all right. Right. Like
how do you know? Yeah,
I know all these people are
saying that it's amazing.
And then it might be this literally
the source of religion itself.
Some people when they've had it,
they have these complete life changes
where they just rethink things and want to
be kinder to people in Nigeria.
People want to just have more
of a sense of community. Yeah.
And then you're just, people dismiss that,
but yet they'll take yoga
seriously and meditation seriously,
and they'll go to a therapist all the
time and maybe they'll leave and get on
antidepressants, maybe get
on a little bit of Xanax.
I'm having a little anxiety
issues. Reggie Watts,
and then they're scared of mushrooms.
It's weird and interesting. Yeah,
I mean I get, I get it and I, I dunno.
Oh, I get it. But it's a flaw. Yeah,
it is a fly. I mean it just,
I guess if your job is to take in as
many angles as possible to a problem or a
situation or a concern or whatever
way all of the things about all of it,
and then come up with a
solution based off of that. But,
and this isn't even
encouraging anyone to do it,
but this is just saying to dismiss it
as being not important when you've never
done it. It's nonsense. Yeah. That's
all I'm saying. That's what I'm saying.
It's like I'm not saying you
should do it. I don't think.
I know a lot of people that birth to grave
have done no psychedelics and they're
great and they're wonderful people now
life and they had a wonderful experience.
It's not an prerequisite. It's not
a necessary thing. No, I agree with,
I haven't had it. You might
want to shut the fuck up. Yeah.
If you're speaking on the
issue. Yeah. Shut the fuck up.
I was like, well the
research shows like, oh,
you're going to let the research
show you what the experience,
let me tell you about the research.
Five dried grams in silent darkness as
turns mechanic would describe Oh and
prescribed. Yeah. Do that. Oh my gosh.
Do that. And then we'll talk. Yeah.
You know, just have one quick
DMT trip and then we'll talk,
cause there's no way that, I
think it would be difficult.
I'm sure there's someone who has done
psychedelics and has and still says no.
Sure. Yeah. Yeah.
But I would say that most people they
would understand it at least maybe they
didn't have a great time,
but they would at least understand
the power of that experience.
I think some people have
the burden of intelligence.
And what I mean by that is that they're
really smart and they see a lot of
people around them that are silly and
they experienced that so often that they
get weary and they get,
they get, you know,
they sort of get rigid in their belief
that their opinions are correct because
they dismiss most of the
people that are around them.
Cause you're on a bunch of dummies if
you're really smart guy or smart girl,
it's hard.
It's hard to maintain a good perception
of what things are and what things
aren't. When you're the
smartest person in the room,
you kinda never want to be the smartest
person in the room. Yeah. And also, yes.
And also believing that you are in a
way excludes you from including other
people who are also smarter than everybody
in the room. Well, it's only men,
maybe not even smarter, which, but I
know you're saying it by an ideology,
their perspective isn't dimmed, right?
Yeah. Yes. They see things clearly,
which is I think one of the most
underrated forms of intelligence.
Like there's all this intelligence in
solving mathematical problems and yeah,
right. Social Intelligence.
But there's, there's,
there's a bunch of different
kinds of intelligence. Absolutely.
Able to see through the bullshit is an
intelligence and some people just don't
have it yet. No, absolutely.
And I think that, you know,
at the same time wanting to help someone
see that angle is also an important
thing. So if you're like a, if
you're someone who's like, Oh shit,
like let's say it's this, maybe you're,
maybe you're trained in
tactical awareness and you, uh,
I just have a different way of
being in a room where you sit. Sure.
Think about all that stuff and the
situation arises where like potentially
something dangerous could
happen or whatever. Uh,
then being able to explain that idea and
that type of awareness so that someone
can see that is also
possible. Like sharing it.
They may not get it to the
extent that you do, but they,
at least you've included it in
their viewpoint. Yeah. Maybe, well,
people that are soldiers, they do have
a weird women. Men are in the room.
It's insane. My friend Andy Stump, he's,
uh, always sneaking up on me. He says,
you got no situational awareness.
Yeah, yeah. When a crowd like,
what am I supposed to do? Just constantly
on three 60 looking for danger.
I mean, yeah, that's what
he's saying, what he's saying.
So, but that's because
he was a seal. You know
how they look at, they look at
things a whole lot different.
So how you stay alive.
Yeah, exactly. Yeah.
I think one of the things that's super
important for people to recognize and it
helps them open their mind up to other
opinions is that even if they failed
themselves very highly, um, the,
that competitive thing of comparing
your intellect and your reason to other
people, it's a very limiting step.
Instead of worrying about yourself.
If you're smart, just be smart. Appreciate
other intelligences. If it just,
just get into talking to them.
This is, that's my thoughts on it.
Instead of being competitive with them,
get in to trying to find out how they
they work cause there's a lot of different
humans on this planet and we have this
egocentric position almost everybody does
that.
They're at least better at one thing
than other people are or they know some
more about one thing that other people
do and it's a weird competitive thing
that people get involved with. It's,
it's stupid like you should recognize
that it's awesome to have cool people
around you that are like really smart
and interested in weird shit and
intelligent and inspiring. You
almost envy their, their creativity.
Those are massively important
people to have in your life.
But when people get,
they feel weird about comparing themselves
to the other person because they come
up [inaudible] insecurity. Exactly.
That's where like you see that with a
lot of guys guys puff up chest and start
comparing like how much their
houses cost. Like so like,
like literally doing stuff that you're
like, oh we're still doing this.
Like to my mind I'm like, Oh
shit, you guys aren't aware of it.
Like a way that I bet anyways.
Yeah. That kind of thing.
You guys are doing some 1990
shit here. Yeah. Cause it's like,
I know cause like either
they're like doing an act,
which I'm always hoping and I'm always
hoping that that's why there's disbelief
when it really is what it is. And I'm
like, Oh shit. Oh that's best for real.
That's actually the thing. It's
weird, right? Yeah, it is a little,
it's a little weird.
I mean some people have a lack
of cool people around them too.
That's a real problem.
Yes. Stuck in a shoe.
It's like a good tomato plant is not going
to grow in the fucking Sonora desert.
All right. There's no nutrients there.
It's too bright. It's the sun's too hot.
It's not the right climate. Right? Yes.
If you're stuck in some fucking shit
hole city and it's just your whole
neighborhoods fill with dummies
and there's no prospects
and his fucking lead in
the water yet Flint, Michigan water,
you're drinking there still
haven't fixed that. No.
People drink bottled water in
Flint, Michigan in 2019. Yep.
Like how, how would do they not have,
how did they let that ever get to that
point? Like at all the things you need.
Well, what do we need to stay alive?
Number one water. Okay, let's ignore that.
Let's ignore that and work
on the cracks in the streets.
Let's ignore that and have new
uh, traffic lights that, uh,
have cameras on them to bust
you so we can get more revenue.
Let's make sure we hire Parkington. What
about the water? We can get to that.
We'll get to that low water.
Well, it's, it's my new
phrase for, uh, you know,
our situation cause capitalism cause
the current version of capitalism.
I said capitalism,
I don't even know enough
about economics. I mean, I,
it's not really, it's more
just like a philosophical,
but you have capitalism with regulation
so that you make sure that there's no
pollution. You make sure that you yes,
don't correlate with
environmental disasters course
and aren't we also going on
the fucking momentum of decisions
that were made a long time ago.
Like a lot of this stuff,
like a lot of these mines that pollute
everywhere up pollute environments
wherever they are.
They kind of made those when environment
where my environmental laws were
different. Right?
Yeah, for sure. I mean
environmentalism was,
it wasn't really a thing until
like the mid 19 hundreds I guess.
So like,
like Roosevelt like was like a huge
like environmental groovy dude.
But uh,
the idea of preserving swaths of land
and like considering the environment when
growing an economy simultaneously
like that just a, that just stopped.
Like there's like some national parks
stuff and maybe some things pass with like
ozone, some led stuff, some mercury
stuff, you know, kind of common sense,
really hardcore shit that should
definitely like no brainers.
Those have been done. But anything else,
making sure that that balance is there.
As the economy grows,
it just doesn't exist.
It's just the way capitalism is
right now. It's like, it doesn't,
that's not considered a value.
There's the more, in fact,
the more scarce it becomes, the
higher end value it is. So it's so,
it's in it's own best interest to continue
to grow and grow and grow until it
can't grow anymore. Jeez man. So,
so that's why decisions like
that are made in my, in my mind,
well, decisions that impact the
wilderness and impact in the environment.
Like did you ever see that movie gas
land? No. Great document around fracking.
Oh Wow. Really crazy. Um,
what does the director Sam,
Josh Fox Rolan no,
he shares a different guy bro. No, there's
no way. No, it's a different guy. No,
no way. But it's an amazing documentary.
And Josh Fox. I did, I got it.
Josh Fox. Um, it's really good. Really,
really good documentary into is Josh
Fox. He's a guy who made the film.
He and he was inspired by a
personal experience with a,
wasn't it? Do you remember
the actual story, Jamie?
It's like personal experience with some
pollutants or something like that in the
river, but got anyway, anyway,
made this amazing documentary and watching
people dismiss some of this stuff.
That documentary was
so, so surreal. Oh yeah.
They were lighting their tap water on
fire and I don't know if you saw that.
I did see that. Yeah, and that's crazy.
People literally were saying you could
do that before the fracking. That's not,
it's not because of the, wow.
People were saying that like, okay,
let's assume that's true.
Let's just get crazy in as soon
as true fucking water is on fire.
That's the last shit that should be on
fire is the shit they used to put out
fire. If your God water's on fire. Yeah.
Do you know how much shit has to be in
your water for it to be on fire? Okay,
what's going on here and why are you so
sure that this didn't come from fracking
and that you could always let your water
on fire and now you're telling us you
use it and make videos about this.
Before, before there was a fracking thing.
Yes. Showing me a video that
has that. See, are you sure?
Are you really sure that there's,
have you tested the water?
You a fucking scientist,
you sitting over there with a lab coat
and a fucking check sheet making sure
that the toxin levels are exactly the
same before and after fracking. No,
you're not, but why are you so interested?
There's a thing that people do with,
they're like really interested in the
interest of big business and they want to
like they guess and regular people who
don't even have a financial stake in that
business will make up excuses for the
business. I know. It's crazy. Yeah.
What is that? It's fear. It's
just fear of losing jobs.
Like people like losing jobs or
losing the thing that keeps their,
their bills paid. It's also like
that no nonsense, right wing mindset.
There's like a no nonsense right-wing
mindset. All these fucking tree huggers,
Goddamn tree huggers. Oh yeah.
Stop us from making a good living.
You want those people to be
poor. You want those people to,
you ever see the look on a poor coal
Meyer's face? Yeah. You know what I mean?
There's that thing that
they do no nonsense.
So they want to go with anything that's
like good for the economy but bad for
the environment, which is crazy.
It's because you never find it.
You have to factor in the
other the additional costs
and how much can it cost to
fix what you did and if you ever can fix
what you did and if you can't fix what
you did to the environment, how much
should that cost? Cause if you can,
if you decide like, Hey,
I'm gonna pull copper out of
this fucking hole in the ground,
but it might kill a million salmon.
Like you imagine how much a
million salmon would be worth.
You're going to kill a whole population
of Salmon. How much is that worth?
Like give you ruined fishing for all the
people that want to come to this one.
Salmon River. Yeah. You kill a million
fish. Like how much is that worth?
That's, that should be
worth $1 billion. Yeah,
you should get fined $1 billion if not
more. Yeah. You can't even fix that.
That's what I, that's what I'm
saying. That's, that's what that,
that value that it has no value. These,
it's also what's ours like poisoning is
our stuff. I know. That's what I mean.
It's like the earth. This is the
worst because it's like it does not,
it's just a nut. It's not a part of
the equation for growing the economy.
That's like, and I know there's going
to be people listening that are like,
just know about this shit hardcore.
I'm just approaching it from like
an over kind of philosophical,
energetic viewpoint. Right, right,
right. We're being hippies. Yeah.
We're being like kind
of, I don't know, Weirdo.
Don't even know what the fuck
we're saying. We're stone Zers. So,
have you ever seen some of the
image of the mining that they do,
the images of the mining that they do in
northern Canada? Like Northern Alberta?
No dude, it's like some hellscape shit.
It's crazy cause it like there's a giant
industry of oil mining up there and all
kinds of mining in northern Canada.
A lot of folks that go up there and
they do shifts but I mean you're talking
unbelievably, brutally, ruthlessly cold.
Occasionally people get
jacked by bears. Like really?
They live in,
they're living with monsters just outside
the gates and some fucking night's
watch type deal where they're trying
to suck oil out of the ground.
And I mean there's so much of it up
there and it's such a big part of the
economy that you have these giant
like aerial views of these, this,
these places that are just
fucks Ville. Uh Wow man.
There's one of them.
The one that I saw was much more
horrific cause it involves a lake.
So what does it say? Photos,
fame photographer, Alex Mclean's,
new photo of Canada's oil
sands are shocking. Yeah.
I mean it's creepy. It's, I mean,
but there was nothing there anyway.
The idea is like, hey,
if it's just flat like that or it's
ugly because we have holes in it,
an oil coming out of the whole who
gives a shit? No one's up here. Right.
I get it. I get that mindset. We've got
jobs. Everyone has jobs and it's true.
It's a great job to have.
They make a lot of money.
You meet those dudes that come to a
lot of shows when you do in Canada,
they have a name for them. Like look,
real rich oil worker. Yeah. It's royal.
It's real, real rich oil worker fellows.
That's the nickname drilling these giants.
That's one that I saw when
see the water all fucked up.
It's all filled with oil and
shit. Oh my lords. Yeah. That's a,
that's a water man. The waters. Fuck. Wow.
Yeah. Yeah. It's, it's, it's funny.
All of the, all of the issues that,
all of the imbalances are
completely solvable. There's like,
there is no deficits. We
don't have a deficit, um,
in what it would take to just make good
decisions that make life really nice for
most people on the planet.
I think a lot of managing has to be done
because there's a lot of stuff that has
unintended consequences
and moving pieces. In fact,
all the moving pieces
around them. Of course.
I think that's one of the things that
people are really bad at predicting.
This is why I was saying
like, yeah, you know,
how much is it worth to be able to get
copper out of a hole in the ground?
It's going to poison a river and kill a
bunch of fish. How much is that worth?
Yeah. Yeah.
It's like these people have this sense
that like you make one decision and it
only affects that thing,
but it doesn't affects a lot of
things or connected to that thing.
It also affects the way people
feel. If you do something Shitty,
like kill a million fish, people
get bummed out. Like that's real.
It affects the way they interact
with other people. Yeah. You know,
when you read something really fucked up
on the news, you're like, God damn it.
Until you leave your house like that,
you leave your house like God damn it
to people that have that God damn it.
And then they, they get upset at each
other for something that wouldn't before.
Yeah.
Cause they're just thinking there's a
bunch of pedophiles out there and a bunch
of monsters and a bunch of murderers and
a bunch of people pouring oil into the
ocean. Yeah. No, it's a bummer. Changes
when people do fucked up things. It
changes how we feel about people. 100%.
And I dunno, I get, uh, I dunno, it's,
I try to get that to get overwhelmed
by those things. But, you know,
it's like really the best thing,
at least in my life that I try to do is
make friends with as many technologists
and designers and people of that ilk, um,
to be able to at least be a part of
the conversation. Cause they're at the,
they're like that the head
of the wave, like there's,
there's nothing really in front of them.
They're just on that, like, you know,
whatever, bleeding edge or whatever.
But it's just like that the place where
chaos is being ordered and like the
decisions are being made, which
waves are, we're going to do that.
And if you can have good conversations
with people like that, you can kind of,
I believe you can kind of help steer
things at least technologically to uh,
allocate funds to different
portions of technology that are,
it should be more prioritized
than that than they are. Like,
like just a figuring out things
like accumulating water, um, out of,
out of the air, like more of that should
be used or reducing carbon emissions.
All the various things you can
do for that. Um, you know, uh,
try to close that gap between the ultra
ultra, ultra, ultra rich and the poor.
It's like everyone can still
be super happy if everyone,
if everyone had access to be able to
level up to a point that's ridiculous.
That can still happen, but not at the
levels that they are, but he's not in.
Interesting that that instinct that
people have to resist that idea that poor
people shouldn't be somehow or another,
we should engineer a way to have less
poor people that we should consider it as
a problem, but people get really resistant
to that. Right? You start thinking,
oh no, no. What do you want to do?
You want to take my fucking money and
give it to jumble? I know I was. No,
I dragged my money buckets. Socialist
Jug in my mind. Yeah. It's like, well,
he didn't work for it,
so he didn't find the right way
to work inside of the system,
so there's a failure. I'm sorry,
I don't think they're right.
I don't think they're wrong about the
whole concept of not giving people money
doesn't solve a problem. No,
he doesn't solve a problem.
But recognizing that it's a problem
and engineering it so that we have a a
better society where more people are
doing good. That's great for everybody.
Totally. It's great for the economy.
It's a weird caste system thing
where people who are really poor,
you almost want them to stay really
poor. Yeah. You don't want to,
I don't get it. It's a weird
devil get it. I'm like,
cause I feel uncomfortable if I'm in a
room of people and I feel like someone's
being kind of just
looked over consistently.
That's the person I'm going to engage
with the most. You're a great guy.
That's awesome. But it's the, you are the,
I mean that's a good way of looking at it.
I mean cause it's it and then also
it's just like, well thanks. But it's,
but it's also just a practical
thing, right? I mean, I mean,
if you're sensitive to that as that,
if that's part of your value
system is to feel like, you know,
not everybody should be doing
this or this or that or that,
but everybody is entitled to be
recognized and respected for that.
And so that's kind of a
cool place to operate from.
But I guess what I'm relating
to economically, yeah.
If more people are doing well, then you,
then you have a very productive society.
Right? So there are no drags on it.
Like there's a lot dragging
this, this economy. Sure.
It's just like crime and poverty
is getting gum drug addicts. Yeah.
And a lot of drug addicts
come from abuse. Yeah.
A lot of abuse comes from
poverty. There's a lot,
a lot of those factors that play in
there that make us a weaker country.
That's how I just you like
if you really patriotic,
he'd want to fix all of the
impoverished neighborhoods. But yes,
if we're a team, the team is stronger
when there's less losers, right.
When people are not losing in life. Well,
people are losing because they're stuck
in a spot where they can almost never
get out.
And by the time they're 18 they've already
been in jail twice and they're kind
of programmed by their environment to be
hostile because the world around you is
harsh and nasty and doesn't
give a fuck about you,
but you have to adapt to survive. I mean,
that's how people are able
to kill people in war.
People have a remarkable ability to adapt,
but the idea that they should be able
to figure that out when you didn't have,
that's crazy. It's crazy.
It's such a bad hand.
You have the worst hand of cards
ever. Yeah, and they're us.
We're all on a team. Like if you really
say you're American, I'm American man.
I'll fucking support this country. This
country is everybody, man. Everybody,
everybody. I forget it. Let's leave.
Let's see. Just for convenience sake,
let's leave out illegals and only say
the poor people that were born here that
are registered United States
citizens. We got work to do. Oh yeah,
we got work to do.
It's, it's, it's just insane to me. I
mean, I see it and I'm like, ah fuck man,
that shouldn't be a thing.
But, but I see why, you know,
it's like you're talking about there's
this weird biological human instinct to
create a tiered system of society because
that's the way you control society.
It's like creating a transmission.
Looks like a social transmission.
And like that is, we were sitting,
we were looking on it. Yeah.
Cause it's like that
way you can manipulate,
you can like switch
gears and you can play,
you can play them off of one
another. And, and you know,
and I think like some conspiracy
thinking shit just went deep.
I'm like, what is he writing
this writer? Is it convenient?
Is it just convenient that people
want to keep it's crabs in a bucket?
You know that expression. Yeah.
Crabs never get out of the bucket
because the other crabs grab them,
drag them down. Yeah. It's
true. It's, I mean it's, yeah,
it's predicting human behavior,
you know, to a certain extent.
And a lot of the leftover monkey
stuff. Yeah. Man. It's the,
it's not, it's just, it's still here.
It's still here and it's fucking shit up.
That's what we also needed it just
a hundred years ago. Totally. Yeah.
People were doing duals when they were,
the president was doing duels just
a couple hundred years ago. Yeah,
you're right. This is so recent.
Yeah. I mean Barrick shit man.
Shooting each other with little
mini muskets in the fucking street,
the front of everybody. And you
were the president. Is that true?
Was there a president that had
gotten a duel? That is true. Right?
I think you're right.
That up as Andrew Jackson got
in like over a hundred goals.
I think that like what
duals, where it like that
dual type to,
it was really just like a challenge to
see you if you would show up really.
And then like, oh, it was like
just a, it wasn't really a goal.
It's like someone died at
every shoot. Anybody he did.
But I think like one person. Oh Oh.
Cause usually they have a crazy story
about it. They don't aim at each other.
That's why. That's why I
heard that there's like you
kind of like aim near them.
Something like that. Yeah.
And that was a way to concede in one
day he got shot I think in the chest,
but he was such a bad ass. He, he stayed,
he like put his hand over it and held
it and s and s cause his gun jammed when
he was supposed to fire.
So the other guy got him and then he
fixed his gun and shot the guy in the head
and that guy ended up, I'm pretty
sure that's how that stuff too,
the way I went about like the
one guy who killed town, she,
you have a real motivation to kill a
guy when shoots in the chest that should
eliminate threat.
Now this becomes real and the guy just
has to stand there and can't even run
away. So goofy is that you have to
stand there and let a dude shoot you.
That's part of the deal, right?
I don't turn around and go,
you can't be like, I went, bitch, I'm
out of here. You have to kind of stand.
There is a guy named Charles
Dickinson, not the writer, but a horse,
a rival horse breeder,
and here's the account of their drop.
That was on May 30th,
1806 Jackson and Dickinson
met at Harrison's mills
on the Red River in Logan,
Kentucky at the first signal. From
there seconds, Dickinson fired.
Jackson received Dickinson's first
bullet in the chest next to his heart.
Jackson put his hand over the wound to
staunch the flow of blood and stayed
standing long enough to fire his gun.
Dickinson seconds claimed that Jackson's
first shot misfired which would have
meant that the wool was over,
but in a breach of etiquette,
Jackson re cocked the gun and shot
again this time killing his opponent.
Although Jackson recovered,
he suffered chronic pain from the wound
for the remainder of his life. Ah, Dang.
Jackson was not prosecuted for murder
and that dual had very little effect on a
successful campaign for the presidency
in 1829 many American men in the early 18
hundreds particularly in the south, viewed
dueling as a time honored tradition.
Wow. That was just a couple of years
ago. We were barbarians and like, well,
sometimes you just got to do it.
That is a time honored tradition.
200 years ago,
people were so goddamn crazy that you
could shoot someone in the fucking face in
a dual a street fight and then run for
president and win. Yeah. That's consent.
Consensual. I mean, there are versions
of that now. That's amazing. But yeah,
his divorce rate raise more of a
scandal than him killing that guy.
Wow. How is that possible? Wow. I mean
again, priorities, different societies.
Yeah. What was gossip like back then?
Like gossip magazines and have like a
like hand printed newspaper with gossip at
that they would hand
out. Yeah. What would it,
why would his divorce become a big deal
out there? The printing press back then,
right? Oh yeah, for sure. Yeah.
The United States. Got It.
There's an 1856 now. Um, like
everyone had to buy into it.
People are so that just a
couple hundred years ago
there were so goofy. I mean,
that's one of the best examples of like
a difference in a shift in culture.
I imagine hearing that today.
Imagine hearing that we had slid so far
down that Trump and Putin were engaging
in a duel and they were going to go
back to back and trauma cheated and shot
them. And we were, yeah, I wonder who
would cheat who? Well, if that happened,
if Trump Trump took a bullet,
but his gun misfired and then he
re cocked it and fire again. Oh,
that would be a Trump thing. That's
what, but that's what he did.
That's what Jackson did. Oh my goodness.
Jackson. Yeah. Yeah, though. Okay.
So he married Rachel Jackson, who,
this is part of the dual because a,
the guy who killed Dickinson had publicly
called her a big amiss because she
married Jackson, not knowing
her first husband had fought,
not finalized the divorce
or something like that.
So that was a bigger scandal that he was
married to some already married woman.
Oh. Like that got outed. So he's
like, fuck you, I'm gonna kill you.
Oh my goodness. Wow.
So he challenged to him to a duel because
Jackson challenged him to do that.
And I'll read N***a horse,
Betty said, oh my God. Oh,
you can cheat on horse bedding.
That's, those are two big things, man.
Don't say I'm a man's wife, is a big mist.
Then you don't say that's what they're
shooting people over fucking horse bets
and Shit. Yeah.
Those were barbarian people and this
our ancestors just 200 years ago.
This is like very civil, civil, barbarian,
civil Barbera whereby
bearings with their rules.
Well that's one of the more hilarious
stories of the Revolutionary War, right?
The way the British soldiers
dressed was so silly.
They literally put a target
on their fucking chest.
They made their vitals lighter. It
made like if you, you shoot guns,
you know what it's like. You can
see if you could see things clearly,
it makes a much more viable
target. Yes. Period. Yeah.
And you're talking about
people that didn't have any
sights on their guns aren't
right. In terms of optics,
obviously they had like little
machine sites, little metal sites,
but the way these guys walk towards them,
especially the ones with the xs on
the chest, that shit is so ridiculous.
They're walking bulls. Odds
is the dumbest thing. Wow.
And the only thing that makes sense to
me is that they had just had it easy for
too long. Not, not even easy, but they
were in control for too long. They got,
they got a little silly.
You forgot how barbaric people can
be really thinking about fashion.
Well that's the weirdest fashion, right?
Like that was what they used for wartime.
Like this is really what the
professionals, you know what I mean?
Like soldiers looked a little
bit more like, hey guys,
we're a professional soldiers and we're,
it doesn't look like good clothes for
fucking people up in. No, it looks cool.
Yeah. But what a weird outfit.
Right? That militarily weird.
How much hand to hand combat were
they doing? Cause they didn't,
there wasn't a lot of swords. It's
was just jerking each other off.
That's all they did.
They just got in the woods and if they
knew any Jujitsu, they call it, be great.
Someone could choke everyone out
with that, with those outfits. Yeah.
All that clothing doesn't move good
too. I mean, I'm just guessing,
but I think they're fucking cloth. It
was probably dog shit back then. Yeah,
probably real stiff, hard to move
around and it's just a weird outfit.
It's not like something that you would,
if you had to run through
the woods and fire a gun,
you want to wear it with like soldiers
wear today and you want to be able to
blend in, but it's just so strange that
that wasn't even a concern back then.
They had knee high
leggings or weird shoes.
Wars were more like chess, like every,
like the soldiers and all
the different rank and file.
They're all like pieces on a chess board,
so it's all about strategy, you know?
It's like, we'll line our men up this
way and we'll do this and blah, blah,
blah, blah. That's it. It's more like
that's how battles are being organized.
It's like chess games. You want to know
how God before he got gorilla, right,
right, right. Well, it was gorilla
at first and then it became true.
Mongolia, daisy, we're lighting
people on fire and ms catapults. Yeah,
by any means necessary war.
Those shoes did not have tread.
They'd had invented tread on shoes
yet. That's why a few people are, yes.
They had leather shoes.
So the soles were leather.
So they were scuffed up,
but there was no tread.
I bet you some soldiers like figured
out how they wrapped, you know,
like sunken leather and wrapped
layers. You know, I'm around the foot.
So to create traction. Yeah.
Cause if you think like you take
like a trail running shoe and a,
if you ever wear like a, like a Solomon
speed cross trailing, she loves us.
Yeah. They're great. They have
these big divots in the bottom.
You can really dig into the
dirt with those things. Yeah.
If you had to compare yourself running
up a hill in cowboy boots that have that
flat leather smooth,
slippery surface versus you would
fall on your fucking face. Yeah.
There's no way you'd have any
confidence. Yeah, I have that.
Nothing but those Solomons
you just dig in and go,
it gives you a totally false
perception of re like I have, um,
those Vibram five finger running
shoes. Oh yeah, yeah, yeah. And uh,
I run in the trail ones, which have
like a good amount of treading it.
But one day I tried to run in the
ones that aren't trail ones, they're,
they're basically just for
the gym and it's super thin.
There was no tread at all. I
was falling on my fucking face.
My legs would just go, whoops, just kick
out going up hills. Your legs just go.
Woopsies no tread at
all. It's just slippery.
I can imagine that you need, like
if you're running up a stiff hill,
you need defense. You know you
need something that's going to
even have that bad gun. They
just had leather defined tread.
I sort of found a shoe, I think it
says it was from the revolutionary war,
but it doesn't show the trend. It's
just a fucking old piece of leather.
Something don't tread on me there.
That was their shoes back then.
Bullshit ass shoes. But the bottom was
just fucking leather. I mean when did,
when they figured out like
Vibram leather soles, you know,
I mean rubber soles with figured out
how to get those like fic d Troggs slave
shoes some of our time. So yeah,
those are, those are clogs. Wow.
Basically they just borrowed
that touch technology. Yeah.
Wouldn't choose fuck that. Look
at those things. Wow. Dude,
this is a couple of hundred years ago.
People would just take animal skin off
and chop it up and put it on their body.
I love it. That's how people stayed alive,
like how they figured
out wood and leather.
I wonder who the first fucking monkey
was to figure out how to skin an animal
and where it's skin. You know?
It has to be like in the monkey days
right now it feels like it'd be a couple
generations away from the monkey. Maybe
it's don't you think maybe it was one,
I just can't imagine a monkey doing one
mean motherfucking chimp and they were
going north and there's one
dude who always annoyed him,
so he kills him with a rock and then uses
the rock to take his fucking skin off
and wears it to freak everybody else out.
But then he realizes it makes him warm.
You didn't go a little further north,
Huh? It's like a movie. Okay. I like
it. A movie. Can you see that scene?
I can see that, that, that, that's like,
that's what the entire movie leads up to.
And the first monkey figured out he
could kill an animal with like a tool,
like the, for like Australia pithy
kiss or one of those, Oh yeah.
Primitive humans.
When the first one was that
stabbed something like a
stab at or rat or a rabbit
with a stick and went, Holy Shit.
Right. I can just use this tool.
What other tools? How are you
going to start eating? Yeah,
I'm going to eat good. Cause
if you didn't have a weapon,
how hard is it for our person to
kill something with your hands?
What are you even gonna get?
What are you going to catch?
What the fuck can you catch with your
hands? Well, you can't catch a squirrel.
You'd be just your hands. No tools.
You'd be hunting and gathering. Mostly.
I mean, I mean gathering,
I would say, yeah,
you beat and Shit that you
found on the ground. Yeah.
That's primarily what you would eat.
And then once in a while you'd get
something, an animal, but, but yeah,
but then, yeah, you're right. Uh,
they obviously had to figure out
different ways of getting animals. Well,
it's one of the shifts that they think
took place to allow the human brain size
to double over a period
of 2 million years.
Don't really human brain
size apparently. Um,
I was listening to a Terence Mckenna
lecture on this once and he was talking
about all the human brain size doubled
over the period of 2 million years is one
of the biggest mysteries
in the fossil record.
And his idea was that they discovered
mushrooms and that the chimps over this
period of time where the monkey people,
whatever the fuck they
were ancient hominids had
discovered mushrooms after the
climate had shifted and he
backs it up. He did back it up,
believes he's dead now.
He backed it up with, um,
some climate data that
we know from, you know,
core samples and stuff like that.
He thinks that they experienced climate
change where the rain forest had receded
in the grasslands and that this gave
birth to the rise of undulates like cows
and you know, deer and
things like that. Yeah.
And they would shit these
mushrooms grow on their a shit.
And then they've observed a lot of
these monkeys in the wild picking up cow
patties and looking for grubs and
beetles underneath it. Oh, I see.
I think they might've experimented
with the mushrooms and that if they
experimented with siliciden mushrooms,
a lot of things could take place once
they realized that it was not just a
viable food source, but also provided
them with a bunch of different benefits.
One being their vision and
increased visual acuity note,
especially in low doses. Yeah.
So I'm going to make them see things
better to make some hornier make some more
communal and it makes them more creative
and all those things possibly could
have given birth to the, to, to
language and to a lot of other things.
They also think it's possible that that
creativity could have enabled them to
start hunting,
that they started using tools and you and
thinking and trying to figure out ways
around stuff and trying to, you know,
try to figure out how to make a,
an effective weapon to kill
something in the distance.
Like the more they're thinking
and becoming creative,
the more that that stuff's
enhancing them. And this,
this period of 2 million years is like
a pretty profound jump for the human
brain size.
They think some of that also came to
do with our desire to kill things with,
with weapons, but once we
started hunting and eating meat,
we got way more protein,
more bioavailable protein,
or it was healthier for the
animal, for the human animal.
And then we also started to try to figure
out other better ways to kill these
animals, which made us even more
creative and competitive. Yeah. Yeah.
They think that all these, these, all
these factors might've taken place.
That turned us into a person
that's pretty amazing. 2 million years.
Yeah. It's just like a deviation. Well,
you know, it's even crazier. 65
million years ago. We were like a mole.
Oh yeah. People were like a little
shrew or ancest. That's right.
I remember that. What's the
name of that thing? Oh no man.
I think it's North
Korea. Fifth [inaudible]
North Gustav versus, I think you're
right. A Pisco for Christmas district.
It was like a weird little mole screw
specific with this. That's what it is.
Yeah. It's the little tiny rodent. Yeah.
Cause I did a podcast or now I
toured with, um, what is it Jamie?
Oh, there it is. I don't know
the earliest of, what does
that word you thery in you?
Therian mammals was a small
rat like creature depicted
in this illustration that
lived 145 million years ago. Wow.
In the shadow of the dinosaurs.
So that rat like creature apparently
survived the earthquake or the asteroid
impact. I don't think
that's the thing though.
And it's, there's another,
there's a formal name for it. I,
I know because I was on a podcast and
they were the one of the segments of it.
They talked about this thing.
This is, but they don't, the only way,
reason why I'm skeptical is because
it says 145 million years ago,
but I guess maybe they
survived the impact screw.
Scroll back up to the top of the title
says these rodent like creatures are the
earliest known of humans, whales
and truce. Oh, okay. That's what's even
more crazy. Like we used to be a whale.
It's like, or our ancestor, we shared
a common ancestor, I should say. Yeah,
we like went into the sea and
then, yeah, on land. That thing,
that fucking rat became a whale.
What? Maybe that's it with area there.
There it is. Okay. [inaudible]
that turned into a person. Folks,
think about that.
When you sat in your rat traps and
a hundred million years from now,
rats might be some super superior human
form. I think that's very possible.
But I mean that, I get why Christians
are skeptical now. I'm like, what?
What do you show me your work?
God May this, God didn't,
I was not a rat. I was not a rat, sir.
Yeah, I just appeared. But in essence,
here's the, here's a way to it to
kind of maybe justify that argument.
It's like, let's say the mushroom
thing is true, right? So in essence,
humans became humans with
the, uh, intervention,
if you will, of a natural
psychedelic substance,
which then expanded the mind and
enabled the growth of that. My,
the acceleration of intelligence,
self-awareness, like,
like lightspeed and so in essence like
God created man or whatever you like that
idea. It's like, well in
essence it is the unit.
If you can think of God is
the universe or whatever.
That's one way thinking of it,
God, collective consciousness,
whatever you want to call it. Like
that, that intervention or the,
the ability to see or sense
that expansiveness of that
collective intelligence
could be attributed to God. So
therefore you could say, well,
I was never a blow. It's like,
well yeah, you are from that.
But what created you was
something more cosmic. So,
and if, if that's even true. Well,
I was reading a quote today from
someone was mocking from Piers Morgan.
We was talking about the unit,
like atheists and not knowing
what happened before the Big Bang,
not knowing how no one has any answer
for what happened before the Big Bang and
about how this made sense
to him. That um, this is,
I think the way he was saying it was, uh,
somehow or another it was
evidence or at least in his eyes,
something more superior. Oh, here it is.
No atheist can never say what
was there before. The Big Bang.
They just say nothing and they can't
explain what nothing actually is.
No human brain can.
Which is why I believe in something that
has superior powers to the human brain.
Well that makes sense that
there's definitely, oh,
Brian Cox went after his ass.
What? Brian Cox, if you
mean the hot big bang,
than there may be a period of
rapid expansion known as inflation.
This theory is able to account for
the observe features of the universe,
including cutting the CMB power spectrum
and the flatness and horizon problems.
I love it. Cox just came at him with the
science. I love it. I always to do it.
I know what he's trying to say.
What Morgan is trying to say
and the EAS.
He's right that no one has an answer
as to like why this thing became,
why the big bang happened.
It's a w this is an interesting quote
by this guy we were talking about,
forget who it was. I
wish I could remember,
but he was talking about how people have,
it might've been mckenna have so much
faith in science and so little faith in
mystical things,
but yet science revolves on one
initial theory where magic took place,
where everything came out of nothing,
that it was smaller than
the head of a pencil.
Everything you see in the observable
universe, including planes,
trains and automobiles,
all of it had to have had an origin in
the most spectacular sorcery the world
has ever known. Like it is all
dependent upon magic. So he wasn't,
he wasn't saying that, you know,
ridiculous ideological ideas of the
start and birth and death of the universe
are fact. But he was
saying that, look, look,
the fact according to scientists is that
all evidence points to this whole thing
coming out of nothing. This whole thing,
this whole thing existing out of nowhere.
And with Piers Morgan is I think is
saying is that that gives birth, that,
that that gives proof to something
superior to the human brain,
which for sure it does. Well, yes,
he, we are at this, this is Terrence.
We kind of,
we were asked by science to believe
that the entire universe sprang from
nothingness and at a single point,
and for no discernible reason.
This notion is the limit case
for credulity. In other words,
if you can believe this, you can believe
anything. Well, I think I said it,
I said it in a paraphrase like away.
That's basically the same thing. He's,
I'm just saying it's all nuts, man.
Yeah, I mean it, my, my thing is like,
I think I like to think of it
as in simulation terms, in, in,
in the sense that if thinking of like
reality and the way it's perceived and the
way that we weave through it as kind
of a designed game of, of sorts.
And so if I think of it in that
way, like nothing and something,
nothing in something that's just kind of,
that's the core of our reality, right?
We live in a binary reality.
Everything is a complex assortment of
binaries that add up into a really complex
system in a way. So what do you
think it's moving towards? Well,
think about that. Well
that's, that's the thing.
I think that part of the rules or
what makes it hard to rationalize like
nothingness or, uh, or something very,
very fantastic is just because
it, because it's binary.
We are binary in our thought process.
So it's hard for us to not
think of things in a binary way.
So we think other was the
beginning. No, there was an ending.
There was a beginning. There's an
ending. But really it's infinite.
It's like it's paradox, right? It's
everything and nothing simultaneously and,
and the absence of which, but,
but I guess what I'm saying is that
the idea that things are infinite,
that reality is infinite is kind of
a good way, but kind of can be scary,
but a good way to think of it because it
doesn't make any sense why it wouldn't
be,
it seems like we have a limited way of
viewing what reality is and I think we're
limited by our binary thought
processes, I guess. Well,
it's also interesting that we want
to put any sort of limitations on the
universe in that. Yeah. It's immense
size isn't crazy enough for us.
Yeah. You know what I mean?
I know we can look at what we know,
if we know that the universe has
hundreds of billions of galaxies,
like just there's a bunch of competing
theories as to what happens, you know,
with black holes and whether
or not there's multi verses.
There's a bunch of yes, right?
But the one of the most profound ones
that it was ever explained to me is that
there's a supermassive black hole
in the center of every galaxy,
and it's exactly that. I think one half
of 1% of the mass, the entire galaxy.
Oh really?
It works out that the bigger galaxies
have bigger supermassive black holes.
And the concept is that it's,
there is a real possibility that
going through that black hole,
you would encounter an entirely different
universe with hundreds of billions of
galaxies. Each galaxy have a
black hole in the center of it.
Go through that black hole, an entirely
different universe. So each one,
yes, universe, when you have
hundreds of billions of galaxies,
there is hundreds of billions of
universes through those black holes.
And each one of those galaxies or each
one of those universes has also hundreds
of billions of galaxies and each
one of those has a black hole.
You go through that hundreds
of billions of galaxies that,
the whole thing fractal. Exactly.
Just like just keeps happening.
There's a resistance. Nah, come on. Yeah.
There's a thing that can instant
reaction to resist that notion as if the
universe itself isn't already the most
incredible thing of magic. Right? I know.
What do you care if it's infinite? Why
is that? Why would you even resist that?
Because that's the part
of the binary thinking.
It's like you want something to
have an end. It's like it's, it's a,
it's a way for us to survive. But
like, you know, it's like, oh,
there's an end to that that
creates a, uh, a need to survive.
But when you think of things in
an abstract like, like, well,
if something is just
infinite, infinite, infinite,
and what does that mean about us?
It's like, that's the question.
That's the thing to explore because then
you have to re negotiate your, your,
your relationship to reality,
which is pretty sick.
We have at least we'd like to take comfort
in the idea that the universe has at
least there's a certain parameter to it.
I know now it's 14 billion light years
and that's it. No more, no more. Okay.
If you can even understand
what 14 billion light is,
there's no way it could be that number.
It seems more like 19 whatever that
number is. They know what I'm saying.
The Way Cox explained it to me, that you,
and I believe Sean Carroll explain
it this way as well. There's a real
does real lack of understanding about
what goes beyond that because it takes a
certain amount of time for light to
even get to us in that time that,
that the light doesn't move fast
enough to reach us from further events.
Yeah.
So like if you had something from like
200 billion light years ago when maybe
the light wouldn't even get to us
yet. Yeah. There's things that, yeah,
I mean we're living in a time
pain. Yeah. I mean that's when you,
that's the other mind fuck.
When you're looking in the sky and you're
seeing a galaxy or a any sort of star
like in the deep, deep, deep
distance of space. Yeah.
The fucking light coming from that
thing left a million years ago. Yeah,
I know way more. You're literally
just looking at the past. What is,
if you got to imagine what is the
closest star to our star in the the f the
seeable universe. When you look
up into the, to the night sky,
what are the things? Was the dog
star? I know our way. Is that a star?
Sometimes things are called stars,
but their planets from old school times
and I could be wrong if you had to guess
was the closest. How many like
office in right? I don't know.
That's how it's great. I have this
entire, is it? How much is it?
How far was that? Four.
4.3 light years from Earth.
Wow. That's bad. That's a hop. Skip
and that jump kills. Here you go.
The speed of light take you four years.
Like the Hawaii of outer space that like
they go there and they was a pit stop
there before they come to earth and
the aliens come. They want to chill.
I hope so.
All right. So hold on. There's a this is
it. Oh Shit. Breaking. No, not really.
No. So it's a binary pair.
So I imagine that means that they move
around each other a little bit orbit
around each other. There's technically
a third star Proxima Centauri,
which is because it says
those are an average of 4.3.
This one's 4.22 so it's nearly
closer. Nice. It's that average.
So two are closer than
the one on one day? No.
Do they know if there's planets
around those stars? So the um,
they didn't even know there were other
planets for sure. Other than, I know,
isn't that crazy? Until just a couple
of decades ago. It's so amazing to me.
It's like shining a flashlight
in the ocean. Yeah. You know,
like that's what spaces,
like you're removing a beam,
but like things are constantly changing
at different distances and you can see
better under certain circumstances
and you can see at different times.
So like it's kind of like a big
existential party. You're like,
I think I'm making sense of this.
And then there's all these theories
and then someone catches another angle.
They're like, no, no, no. I mean, yes,
a little bit of what you guys
were thinking but also this.
And they're like fuck. And
they just keep adding to it.
But I don't know if we're going
to find necessarily anything. Um,
well when you talk to physicists about
the subject and they try to explain to
you how they even reached
these conclusions and how
they know that there's black
holes out there in the first place
and the theories fucking like these,
these, these theories of multi verses
and yeah, that's my favorite. And brains.
The membranes that there's like, yeah,
in theory, like lines of Universes,
then we collide with each other
occasionally. Yeah. What the fuck?
That's what I think ghosts are by the
way. Which was like in the interest in,
it was an interstellar one with, yeah,
with Matthew Modine. Is that the star
[inaudible] [inaudible] list
guys, vision quest. Different era
or the Russian training with the
log. Yeah. The stairs. Yes. No,
he wasn't rushing. He was a no, no, no,
no. Here's the shoot. Oh yeah, he was,
he was like the cold trick,
right boy. Yeah. Some,
but there was like a guy training
that was gable brick and mortar was,
was the opponent training. Well,
Matthew Modine was trading crazy,
but he was trying to drop weight to
go down to fight this, the Russell,
this guy that everybody was terrified
of. Yeah, that's right. What it was,
but was shoot the one that
was walking with a log. Yeah.
He was carrying a log up us up stadium
stairs. Right. That was so sad.
And he was like super hardcore. He's like,
you think you're going to make the
weight? He goes, I hope so. He goes,
I hope so too. And just kept
walking with a long boom. Good.
See if you can find that scene. That's
so good. I mean, it's a great movie,
man. It's a great thing. Cause
like that interaction right there,
it's so genius because it's like tells
you everything you need to know about
both of those characters. Yeah,
exactly. So they go there. Here he is.
There's a dude as bad as a
beast wrestler. Of course.
He's by himself as his friends.
Got a fucking cool headband. Well,
his friend was a fake Indian.
Oh friend lied about being a native
American so he could get into college.
No cheaper started made him look cool.
Like, Oh, here we go. Do I know what you
thought on Sweet Thompson hug? Can you
play this over the air? No, no, don't.
We'll get, we'll get pulled.
Yeah. Taken. Make. Wait.
I hope so. I was like, oh, hope so too.
Just walking around with his
log. Boom. Everyone's scared.
Fuck that dude. It's pretty big. Yeah,
dude for 80s yeah. Good. Well
he looked like a wrestler. Yeah.
He looked real like guys like Mark Schultz
when he's competing in the Olympics.
He was fucking jacked man. Yeah. There
was some Jack wrestlers back then.
Still this obviously. Yeah.
It's one of the more physically intensive
things you can do at that protection.
That muscle protects you. It's also,
I mean just wrestling all the time.
You're gonna get strong. Oh
yeah, that true. That too.
You get a certain kind of strength to
that weird grip strength Yo man and
telling you that shit. It was
like, it's like immediate,
like violent amounts of strength
like for grips and stuff like that.
Cause I just remember my friend who
was a wrestler and I was like, yeah,
I don't know wrestling. It seems
pretty hard or whatever. See here,
let me show you a move.
And I was standing,
I was looking at him and I just blinked
and I was just out of breath on the
ground, on my back. Just like
the experts at throwing bodies
around. Just like, ugh. Okay.
I mean it's like strength grip and being
able to torque shit and shit happened.
I mean it's insane to think about
things you do to get fit right.
Like with sandbags and stuff. People
do lie like extreme things, right?
They flip tires, throw sand bangers. Yup.
They take a heavy bags too. They throw
them over their shoulder. Oh yeah.
When you're wrestling,
you doing all that plus and plus it's
resisting plus another things trying to
get you right. Yeah. It's super active.
It's like it's like active strength.
That's going to be a deeper form of
strength. Range of motion. Strength. Yeah.
That's why the worst kind of strength
is like Nautilus machine strength. Yeah.
Yeah. Weight assisted mission.
Not the worst kind of strange,
I shouldn't say that. Those
things all have their purpose.
They're really good for like specific
types of works at workouts and specific
types of exercises where you're just
trying to fatigue the muscles like a lot,
a lot of strength and
conditioning athletes like to
use those to bang out reps
because it's, they feel like there's
less factors going on in terms of, um,
whether or not you could
drop the weight when the,
when you're losing your coordination.
Safe lost. It's safer, but it's,
most people don't think it's ideal for
just for sports specific maybe for,
um, um, just overall
strength because you're,
you're not getting balanced with it.
Like if you, if you go to heavy weights,
like free weights,
most people think that free weights are
superior to a machine because you got to
balance that thing, push it up. Then
you develop, you develop stability,
you're actually holding the weight
instead of just pushing against a for like
using your force against something
that's lined up on tracks. Yeah,
you're controlling it. You have
to control it the whole way. Yeah.
So that's what wrestling
is, but it's fighting back.
It's even harder to get a hundred on
top of that 80 pound dude who's also
fighting back and fuck.
Like he was trying to pick them up and
move them around and he was also trying
to get you at the same time. And
it's true and it's all strategic.
So you're like honest,
strategic, instinctual level.
Then your hope for your,
your training and your
reflexes and your intuition.
It's really interesting to watch like
really skillful technical wrestlers cause
they'd go from one technique to another
and they just chain wrestle like
watching. Like a lot of
those, particularly Russians,
there's a lot of Russian,
a lot of Soviet block athletes from, you
know, years back even were like really,
really technical.
What they're wrestling really beautiful
to watch them chain these techniques
together and do these different
moves to try to achieve dominance.
Still crazy sport. Yeah. I,
whenever I watched it
it's like you feel like,
it's like when I watch dance I'm like
I'm kind of moving with it, you know?
I mean that happens with all sports I
suppose. But wrestling, it's just like,
like, like the energy when I'm
watching it, which has been very rare,
but in high school used
to see wrestling matches.
My friend was a wrestler and
just be like, oh whoa. Oh Man.
Oh fucking exciting. Yeah, it's
cool cause it's like it slows down,
it's fast, it's slow, it's fast,
they're exhausted. You can take a break,
they go in and then, then
like nothing for awhile.
Like really just like slow mayors and
then suddenly someone just does like this
really weird and it just flips and
it's like, I love that energy man.
It's a different thing
than any other sport. Yeah.
It's different than any other
sport that's in the Olympics too.
Like the Olympics, you have boxing and
wrestling and then you have sports, judo,
judo, even tuck window. They have
talked when don't even pitch to now.
But the thing is that those, those are
the, it's a different kind of sport man.
It's a sport where people get fucked
up. Yeah. Those are different. Yeah.
They're just different. It's a
different feeling when you watch in it,
it's a different consequence
when you fail. Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah. Yeah. I mean it's
as close as you can get.
It's the closest thing
to fighting. Oh yeah. Um,
I mean cause fighting is mostly
grappling. It's a lot of it. A lot.
It's not everything. Yeah. But like
at least what, two thirds maybe?
Well No. Okay. Real fights.
Really like a street fight or like make
street fights go down pretty quick.
Right. Sometimes they do, but sometimes
they just get, people get knocked out.
Sometimes people can just get flat
cause they don't know how to strike and
someone does and they punch them
in the face. That happens a lot.
There's a lot of videos. I think
I've seen some of those. Yeah,
I mean it definitely does happen that
a lot of fights go to the ground and I
think Jujitsu,
a great thing to learn and wrestling's
a great thing to learn because of that,
like the ability to manipulate
someone's body is really important,
but you also should under
understand what someone's doing.
If they're trying to punch you.
Some people just don't have any idea
what's happening. Then they just get bong,
their fucking bell crack because they
don't see a guy pulling his hand back.
They don't see the shift in weight. They
don't see someone about to punch them.
They don't see where the
punch is going to come from,
what direction that they have to avoid.
They don't see those things because
they've never experienced it cause they,
they don't have a training. They
don't have any training in striking.
That's justice. That's
fucking dangerous man.
This was because if you lose to a
wrestler or you lose to a Jujitsu Guy,
a lot of times you wrestling
my beat you up on the ground.
You might ground and
pound you, but Jujitsu,
you guys probably just going to choke you,
but the kickbox is going to slam
his fucking shit in your face.
You do not want them, man. You
do not want that. Holy Shit.
The worst way to lose, the worst
way to lose is to a striker. Oh,
past weekend. No, this is a fastest
ever knock out in UFC history.
This Guy Jorge Mazda doll knocked out
this two time Olympic wrestler, Ben Asker,
who's a beast of a wrestler and it knocked
him out in five seconds because asked
her and went to shoot to try to get
ahold of his legs and Matsudo ran at him
with a flying knee and hit him right in
the face was while he's trying to bend
forward. That's legal. Yo Up. Fuck yeah,
it's illegal. That's her right there.
Boom. Oh fuck. It's all over the
Internet. You want to see it? So yeah,
it takes five seconds.
It was one of those things where we
watched it and we went whole Lee shit like
as it happened. Okay. Is that
US talking about it? Yeah,
that one down there. But
that one dog. Oh man,
you just turned away from it wasn't
the one below it. That wasn't it.
It wasn't it. No, it wasn't it. Oh,
it's other people talking
about the reaction. I see.
It's definitely on Instagram,
but apparently it's getting
pulled left and right.
Of course. Again tried to do that.
She's like, that's for everybody.
I don't understand why they would let
everybody have that. It's like, no,
we need that. We need to own
that commodity. But that's, it's,
it's good for everybody. It's not
how the Internet works either.
You don't win the fans here. Here we go.
So this is the beginning of the fight.
Ready? This is route one. Yup.
Al Cold. Five second call
by the ref though. It wasn't
even really five seconds.
He was out cold at three seconds.
Someone did a time from here.
Boom. Out Cold. Three seconds as
a reference. Running over to him.
Yeah. And why is he yelling at
him who hated each other really?
Or they hate each other?
Jorge Mosfet all said that
guy was taunting him for
like 10 years talking shit
to him. So he couldn't wait to
do that to him. Yeah. Now what?
Well, Ben dust himself off. He took
it like a man. I mean he really did.
He went on a talk show and talked
about it afterwards. Good. Yeah.
That's, that's how you fucking do shit.
Yeah. Yeah. He's like, look, it sucks.
I don't like losing that guy.
He's a Douche. Yeah. Right.
But they're probably going to end up
being somewhat friend friendly later down
the line. No, you don't think so? No.
Mazda Dahl said that if you saw them
at a whole foods, it's not over.
He's still smacking him in the face.
Even whole foods couldn't hold him.
Bet whole foods can't hold him back.
Right in front of the Kombucha.
The real gts can Bucci the kind that you
need a credit you going to show your id
to get.
It's like no whole foods, man.
That's like, that's like, Hello Gran.
You can't start a fight there. It's like,
no, he's willing to break the rules.
I saw a fight at Disneyland
on Instagram the other day.
Dude are going out on Disneyland.
Someone got punched a chick to
seek fulfillment to.
People were filming it and these people
were throwing down in front of their
kids at Disneyland. Terrible
technique to everybody's terrible.
Terrible. I love that. The
equally disappointing aspects
of it. Oh, it's terrible.
It's the most disappointing.
It's like guys,
if you're gonna find it's just
learn some technique. Yeah.
I mean it's like someone's stealing
the stage and playing a bad guitar.
You'd be angry with, of course. See
what I'm saying? Yeah. I get it. No,
I'm in complete agreement.
I think that that is kind of
equally important because, hey man,
if people are filming, yeah, people
would like a consensual fight.
You look like you're trying to
pretend you know how to fight. Yeah.
And the worst is the
pulling off of the shirt.
I don't even know how that
even becomes like an instinct.
It's actually a good move. Well,
it's to keep you slippery, right?
So you can like, well you want, yeah.
You don't want anybody choking you
to death with your own jacket. Oh,
that's true. Yeah, that's
true. Well, okay. But I mean,
I guess in the videos that I've seen,
it's been mostly about like, hey check,
she's Jack that I am and like,
oh bro. Yeah. At the end here
I kind of look like this
dude got choked out,
but I couldn't quite tell what was
going on here because he went down quick
cause that's security and he
might even been off for a second.
So he's pulling that girl's hair.
See? Oh yeah, he's out cold. Yeah,
he's out cold. Oh Gee. Dropped him.
His head banged off the ground too.
That ball dude choke the shit out. And
he's like, well I just killed that guy.
But to get outta here I think.
But yeah, no one will ever choke.
No charges were pressed because no one
wanted to say what the fight was about.
Hilarious. Yeah.
But was that so it was a guy that was
holding a girl's hair at the use get you
guys said he got spit on and
then he went crazy. Oh Wow. Yeah.
I don't know if that was their
whole thing. Not Funny. That's all.
It takes a little bit of water. A
little bit of, yeah. It's funny. Yes.
I got all the things that make people
go crazy spit in someone's face.
It's like, wow, we're ready to go
to war here. Yeah. I mean it's,
it is pretty quick not approved
biological weapon back in the day.
If you had some like smallpox shit. Yeah.
Like how dare you potentially infect me.
Do you ever hear Damon
Wayne's joke about, uh,
when a magic Johnson came back
to the NBA, Magic Johnson,
after you had HIV and then came back
to the NBA, he said, Damon Wayans,
who's my opinion, one of the most
underrated comedians of all time,
still one of my fantastic all time
favorites, but in one of his HBO specials,
he goes, he goes, everybody was avoided.
Magic. Nobody wanted to play defense.
He goes a step. Dennis Rodman, he
goes down as rob was like, listen,
I spit in your mouth and
accelerate your symptoms.
I'll spit in your
mouth and accelerate your sim to this day.
That's one of my all time favorite
lines. I hear that line on my God. Damn,
that's a great, that is a crafted,
brilliant thing to think. It's like,
it's like 180 it hurts. That one hurts.
I'll spit in your mouth and accelerate
your symptoms I made today. No, he says,
I'm sorry, I fucked Madonna
and that's what he said.
I'll spit in your mouth and
accelerate. You said, oh, it's even,
it's even more potent.
Oh, that's
like some shit talking. Just like
that's the type of shit that man is,
that wins the whole thing. Yeah.
You got to walk away. Yeah.
Keep talking after that. Now that's
it. And I think you lost like, man,
take it last second man. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Maybe that's why it's bidding and it's
also, it's gross. It's just gross.
It's just gross and so rude.
It's so fucking rude. I mean,
when someone purposefully spits
at you. Yeah. You're like,
I want to destroy you. Okay. I would
kind of understand that reaction.
You said thing people were getting
like licking food at grocery stores.
Like some girls going to get arrested
or she's facing like 20 years or
something. I don't understand.
I don't want to know why
they thought that it was funny to look
food and then know that people are going
to buy it. Yeah. Yeah.
Well people think it's funny to
spit in people's food when they're,
they're serving it to, yeah, it's weird.
People would kind of grow sometimes,
you know? They'll get it any way
they can, man. Yeah, we'll get back.
We'll get back at the, where else do
you take this shit position in life?
It's like, no, I don't,
I don't agree. He's your
salad. Sorry. Yeah.
No, I mix it up. Eh? So
you gotta be nice to son.
You gotta mean that to everybody,
but we like swapping spit with people
and that weird. That is really weird.
Well, because that's consensual, right?
Yeah. Well not just, it's consensual.
It's like it's pleasurable. It's
like even if it's consensual,
you don't want to be
spitting in your mouth. No,
because that's super fucking gross. Yeah.
Kissing someone's okay amount and they're
like, took like that would be weird.
Like you just spit in
my food. This is gross.
But if someone's kissing you and
their tongues in your mouth and you're
swapping, literally swapping spit,
it's sexy. It's hot. We like it. Yeah.
Yeah. I'm glad. I'm glad
that I liked that part. Yeah,
because the other part I'm just like, Yo
Bro, you can't, what's wrong with you?
Why are you doing? Are you doing
spitting in each other's mouth?
You don't need to do that.
You can just choose not to.
It's like the delivery methods where we
have a real problem with, yeah, exactly.
Apart from the program is two
fucking football players do it.
This specific giant loop that's a moving,
so they really did do it for the
scene. Pretty short. They had to, oh,
fucking viscous. They spit
at each other's mouths. Why?
Guess when you're playing football,
you just want to be as savage as
possible and you don't give a fuck.
You'll make out with a dude,
you'll fuck a couple of guys and
then you'll go play football.
Cause then you feel like you don't care
the entire force of the universe behind
you out. People do things to let people
know they don't give a fuck. Yeah,
that's true. That is true. I do things
like that. Like have you seen euphoria
with HBO show? No. It's
fucking fantastic. Yeah, it's,
I think it's out now. You
know what it is, Jamie?
I've heard of it and heard it's
good and have not watched it yet.
It's ridiculous. It's a basically about a,
it centers around a drug
addicted, uh, high schooler, uh,
played by as in [inaudible] and uh,
it's just about the modern
kind of modern generation,
high school experience through her, uh,
drug addiction or trying to overcome drug
addiction or kind of realizing what is
going on with her at that stage
in her life. And there's just,
it's just the culture of all the
things that kids deal with these days,
but it's done in a really, really
hyper beautiful stylized way.
It's so crazy intelligent. It's amazing.
It really blew me away. I was not like,
I just went to the opening and
it was like, ah, I don't know.
I don't know what this is. And then, uh,
the guy got up and talked about
it because the writer, uh,
experienced addiction has been
clean for 15 years. Something that,
but that was his life back
then as a, as a teenager.
And so they had adapted it and it's great.
But the reason why I bring that up is,
what were we talking about a second ago?
What are talking about
spitting each other's mouths?
Yeah. We went from that to people want
to pretend they don't give a fuck.
I'd want to let you know they don't give
a fuck. Oh yeah, that's exactly right.
Yeah. So there's like a great scene.
The first in the pilot doesn't
really give away anything,
but one of the characters,
she's in a kitchen
and there's like a big bully dude,
popular guy that's like getting,
getting interface and
being really threatening.
And then she takes a knife and
she just slices her arm and shit.
That fixtures, she, she's like,
stay away from me mother fucker
or something like that. Uh,
there's something more
eloquent that happens and then
she introduces herself and
leaves. She goes, oh, by
the way, and she walks out.
But it's such an intense scene.
It goes from the darkest of the
darkest to like a practical, this,
this person is really smart. The girl
who cut her arm is incredibly smart.
That's a crazy thing to do
to someone. Yes. Yourself,
that kind of stuff in front of them.
It just shows you that it's like, I've,
I don't give a fuck. Like that's
like, yeah, exactly. Yeah.
And the guy was, everyone was just
frozen. They were like, I don't know what,
they're just a bunch of high school
kids in the kitchen. Pretty cool.
Pretty cool.
Like a character detail that just kinda
like shows you everything about that
character in a split second.
Yeah. Jesus. I'm amazing.
I love that shit. That's intense. Yeah.
I mean I love when you
don't know something's good,
you don't know anything about it.
And then it turns out to be awesome.
It's the best feeling Christmas or my,
one of my favorite parts of going to
the movies I love previous but yet they
ruined moving. Exactly. I know I'm
the same way. I'm the same way.
It's like peeking into
a Christmas present.
Like when you're a little kid
like can I just unwrap this pitch?
He rabbit out to fucking tie fighter.
Oh my God. It's Darth Vader's. Yeah,
it will little fucking sneak
and then [inaudible] act like,
oh my God. And your parents like
let me look at that rapping again.
Yeah.
Fuck I haven't been caught but
that's almost like what previews are.
You had to see a little bit
about what the movie is about.
Wouldn't it be better if he had
no fucking idea of you just,
I don't want to even know a
synopsis. I don't want to,
I don't know what King Kong is, which
if you didn't know what King Kong was,
I'm like the newer King Kong,
you thought it was like about
like a king in the land.
You have no idea and you sit down.
You have no idea how the
store is going to come.
Come out and the moment you see the
gorilla, you probably like, Holy Shit.
Yeah. When he's fighting dinosaurs and
stuff, you'd be like, Holy Shit. Yeah.
It would be so much better than you watch.
All those previous are just partial
fucks are amazing, you know?
But you go to see it and it's
like, yeah, I've already seen it.
I know he's going to breathe fire out
of his mouth. I know what it looks like.
You've shown me. Yeah, it's I,
my favorite trailers are the ones that
just kind of give you a feeling of the
world and that's it. Like the
new joker trailer is sick. Yes.
It's perfect example. It's great.
It's a piece of art unto itself,
but it's not giving away a lot. I mean,
there's a lot of time you see a lot
of shit and you kind of get an idea,
but not really. It's a, it's
a very artful trailer. Yeah.
But you gotta have something. Yeah.
As people aren't going to go to you.
I know that's the problem. But
remember Cloverfield. Yeah.
When that came out and make that weird
and the ads that they would show would
just be like, whoa. And that's all you
heard Cloverfield. And you're like,
what the fuck is this? Those are weird
movies, right? Like those movies,
like this movie sucks because it was
just filmed by people who were there well
yet. Right. Quality's terrible. The
camera's going to be shaky. Yeah.
You're going to scream and drop the
camera. It's going to bounce it.
You're going to see, like kind of knew
back then. If, I mean Blair, which,
you know, it was kind of the
starter of that Bro Blair,
which freaked me out the
first time I went to see it.
I want to see it with Chris McGuire,
a comedian, Chris McGuire, and um,
a couple folks that worked at the movie
theater across the street and they came
to see us. We were performing
at the Houston laugh stop. Okay.
And so they, they, we were talking to
them before the show and they're like,
hey, we work at the movie
theater. I was like, oh,
we're going to probably go there this
weekend and see that Blair witch movie.
And the dude was like, Hey,
I have the keys. If you want,
we can open it up tonight after the
show. I was like, what? I was like,
fuck yeah. So it was right across
the street. So me and McGuire,
and I think there's like three
of them that worked there.
We all hung out and watched the Blair
witch together in a fucking empty movie
theater. They made popcorn and everything.
What does dope, the key to the place,
I mean, if their boss found out
they would be flexible. Yeah.
So don't share this,
y'all not telling anybody,
but this is like 1718 years ago at the
very, I mean, when that movie come out,
as long as I'm movies, a long
ass time ago, 1989 99 so yeah,
20 fucking years ago and we were at the
Houston laugh stop. That was awesome.
So cool. What a great flow
of an event to go pass gag.
And then you're like, oh fuck,
check this out. Yeah, it was fun.
But that movie was [inaudible] effect
scare the shit out of you. Yeah.
It took me a while to get into it cause
I remember dogma. Do you remember that?
That crew has so that I remember
the celebration that had come out,
that was the first movie that I saw that
was made all on India because they had
those rules. Like they, we only use
natural light. We only use DV Cams, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
Um, and it was great.
It was interesting and Weird and
Oh my God, that's kind of crazy.
And then Blair witch came out and had
that kind of vibe but a little bit more
curated, like a narrative. But I was like,
I thought it was eerie, but I really
didn't get scared until the very,
very end when when it's going down
the stairs and then the flashlight is
searching around and then sees that girl
facing the corner. That fucked me up.
Yes. That, that, that one moment.
So the whole thing, I was like, oh,
it's pretty, you know, it's cool.
It's creepy. Okay, well then it just,
that thing, I was like, fuck
you. It was a strong closer.
There was this real strong closer. I
mean that's the way you go out. Yeah.
That's the way you go out.
But it's an interesting that we
like movies that are on film, right?
We'd like that look. Yeah we do.
We like the things that are
in the forefront and focus,
but everything in the back is just like,
yeah cause we're in fuzzy. That's true.
It's got this like quality thing to it.
Even though now we see videos that are
very literal from phones all the time.
We see that kind of imagery.
We still don't necessarily see,
you wouldn't see that in a movie
theater necessarily. You too.
Too distracted by all the outside images.
So like if you're talking to
people like you and I are talking,
I'm focusing on you.
I know there's some stuff over the
laugh and some stuff over the right,
but I'm not seeing it the same
way I'm seeing you. Yes. Right.
That's one of the reasons why
like when you interpret video,
like you visually interpret video,
it's a very weird distortion.
Even though it's the most accurate
representation because you can't look at
everything at the same time.
So if you look at a photograph and
everything is in focus, what kind of,
what are you using? What are
you using to see things with?
Because this is my eyes
don't work like that. Yeah.
My eyes are looking at you
and everything around you.
Like I know there's a clock
right here, but I'm, dude,
I can't even read what time it is.
It's right there. I can't remember it.
But now I can read it, right? Yes. Okay.
You know this stuff that's just a few
inches to your left or right and I
literally can't see
them. Yes. Just a tiny,
tiny point that you're
actually focusing on. Yeah,
just focus on right in front of these
things right in front of the face.
So that's, make that make sense. Like
for focus, it kind of replicates the way,
and it's also a storytelling mechanism,
right? Focus on this part. Yes,
it definitely is that. Yeah. But it
also, it's like the, it looks cooler.
It just looks, yeah, it looks
dope. It looks pro, you know? It's,
it's High Rez. Yeah.
Many like a video camera,
like a regular standard consumer grade
video camera almost takes clearer
pictures. Oh, for sure. Yeah.
It's like if you ever put your
phone in timelapse mode. Yes.
It looks like the way it tracks
when you're moving it over objects,
it's got a higher frame rate
or something like that. Um,
but it makes it look like that
pan and scan shit. You know,
when you're watching sports events
or whatever and it just looks wrong.
You know what I mean?
Like it's too literal.
There's something to the way everything
moves just feels slightly off.
Do you think that we're just accustomed
to the way film looks and then if we
were accustomed to the way video looks
than film would be look clunky to us.
You have everything started off as
video and then they said, you know what,
it's not really good to
have everything in focus.
It's only good to have some
things in focus in the bag away.
Some things are blurry and then they
come into focus and actually enhances the
filmmaking. Yes. Right? Yes.
Like in a horror movie when something's
blurry and then they zoom in on it and
you see it, it's like a fucking monster
Highlander under the bed. You're like,
oh no. Like that's not what,
I didn't want that to happen.
You've now just revealed yeah, exactly
what I didn't want to see. Yeah, yeah.
No, I agree. Yeah. I don't know. I
mean, I don't know, but I know that,
you know, people have like film, I think
it just looks, it's the texture of it,
but now people like DV. Well, it's
like people like vinyl, right?
There's people that are just die hard
vinyl fans. They like to sound. Yeah,
I mean, you know, I like, I like, I
like anything, you know, but I like to,
I'd like to make sure
that it's the best quality of it or
the most natural use case for it.
You know? You know, it's
like when people used to mix,
when people started listening
more to music in their car,
that they could like put a thing that
they bought in their car with an eight
track or whatever. Or they used to
have record players for cars too.
But you know, uh, the way that
music sounded, they were kind of,
they also had to consider
the mix of car speakers.
What does it sound like on car speakers?
So going back to the aura tones and the
ns tens and then the standardized car
speakers that people test audio in
and it's a different parameter, right?
Cause you're, you're stuck in this
little contained metal box. Yeah. Yeah.
So you gotta figure out
how to mix the music,
but generally it's the sound
system that has to be adjusted.
The sound systems have to,
but you mix Tuesday, they,
they kind of meet each other in the
middle, but great, high five systems.
My actually, it's a
quick anecdote, but uh,
when I was in Seattle I knew
that I liked high five systems,
but I didn't know why
they were so expensive.
And so I went into this place, this guy
named Leland. Oh, who was working there.
I was kind of friends with them cause I'd
come in and I just scoped gear all the
time. Just look at like, oh, I love audio
gear. It's just really sweet. And um,
and then one day it was towards the
end when they were closing and, uh,
he turns to me and says, hey man,
do you want to get your brain fried?
And I was like, what do you mean? And
he's like, stick around. I'm like, okay.
And he closed shop. A couple of his
friends came and closed the shop.
It's like maybe five of us went into
the back room, smoked some marijuana,
went into the showroom,
the main room where they have all the
speakers and all the different types of
units. And he says, then he
just kind of turns to us.
We all sit down on the couch and he
says, okay, you're going to listen to a,
this is a system in total it
costs about $150,000. Wow.
And, uh,
and then he just goes proceeds and goes
through and explains all of the stages
that, you know,
that the current is going through
and what the music is going through,
what's being played on all the cables
that are being used, all this stuff.
And then I heard all of that
crazy speakers like, okay, cool.
He lowers the lights and he puts
on a Bill Evans trio record.
I can't remember which one. Um,
and he just presses play and we sit down
and like within probably 30 seconds,
people were crying. Wow. And
cause it felt holographic.
It felt like you were in the room with
those musicians that were playing right
there for you. And then I had the
realization, it's not the money,
it's not about the money,
it's about what does it take to engineer
a machine that becomes invisible to the
experience. And that was,
that kind of blew my mind.
So whenever you're designing anything,
it's like you're designing the
experience. The engineering should,
should get the fuck out of the way.
What was the medium? Was it vinyl?
Vinyl? Yeah. Yeah. What you think,
like in your description,
what is different about vinyl?
Well, I mean,
supposedly if you have a really nice
quality piece of violence cut really well,
um,
you get as close to the original mastered
recording experience like coming out
of the studio if you're
talking about older tape.
So whatever that final mix is, when
someone plays it and they're like,
it's been mastered, here's the Stereo
to track, we're playing stereo to track.
It's been mastered. Excuse me,
I'm a little wheezy. Um, and uh,
and that's what you hear.
You hear it in the best possible context
on the speakers that it was mixed on.
It's everything's optimal. So
essentially when a record is pressed, um,
if it can mimic that, the
stereo to track the master, uh,
which it does, uh,
then you have something that for
at least the first, I don't know,
vinyl people will say how many times,
but a record starts to wear down.
But if you have a fresh press,
you can run it a bunch of times before
it starts to degrade. But in that state,
you're hearing it like analog, super
analog. It's like as analog as you can.
How many times do you think you play it
before it starts to grid? I don't know.
I guess it depends on the
ears of the audio file,
but there's probably an average, I don't
know what it would be. Maybe 60, 30,
40, 50 times.
Now is there a digital format
that at least comes close?
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah. Flack
files. It's a file format. Um,
black files are good. Um,
usually 128 96 killer hurts.
Like that's,
there's like kind of a mastering digital
mastering standard and that standard,
uh, is is basically what
that is, what a record is.
So that's why you have like sites
like HD tracks that I really dig.
You can get all your favorite out. Well
not all, it's not as big of a selection,
but you can get a full resolution from
like stereo two track master from the
studio level quality in a digital format
that you can buy and then put into a
high rez player. So I have a high
Rez player, a high five pro player,
and it runs the,
has really nice circuitry and all that
stuff and then use a really great pair of
headphones. And you've got the closest
thing to a record that's repeatable,
infinite times.
And is the headphones the way to go or
one of those crazy tower speaker jammies,
the way to go? Oh well it depends
on your, your use case. Like if you,
if you know,
if you ear and a house and you want like
a cool living room system or whatever,
I would always opt for speakers and not,
not Sonos and not that kind
of stuff. People, they dig it.
But um, true.
I mean records are meant to be
played off of two speakers with this.
It's a 2.1 system, unless
it's specifically engineered,
which is very rare for like
atmos or whatever the fuck.
But usually it's two
speakers in a subwoofer.
So why would I not want to hear the music
the way it's supposed to sound? Right.
However, I understand the
convenience of those speakers,
so I'm not totally
knocking it. But for me,
if you're going to get
a for your living room,
if I can get a 2.1 system, yeah,
you want it played out the way you
want, the sound to come at you,
the way it was recorded. Otherwise
it changes the experience completely.
The Sonos and those types of
things, they, they fake stereo.
Henry Rollins was on the podcast and he
has this most preposterous set up in his
house. He is a gigantic
audio file. Oh Shit.
A massive lover of music. Oh my God.
He collects all these albums and
he even runs a radio show. He does.
I love his radio show. It's dope.
It's on case here. So these are the,
like these are the crazy fucking speakers
he has in his house. What the fuck?
And there's some, what are those
$200,000 is what they are. Oh, I forget.
I have seen those. I've seen pictures
of that. That's um, who makes this
Alexandria XLF is what they're called.
Okay. Wilson. Alexandria. Dope.
They look, I mean, it's disgusting
looking at those things,
but you have to have their
weapons. You know, like you, you,
you have to have pull back so
we can see a gas for full size.
Those things like look at what a weird
looking piece of equipment looks like.
Future robot. It looks like an
ATM machine, right? Yeah, totally.
Or like a display screen robot. Yeah.
Today we have here swipe here for your
thank you for your business. Goodbye.
So is the one that we're looking at on
the right hand side? Is that the back?
Yeah. Wow.
Look at all that shows the inputs to
know what the fuck they have discreet
inputs for each of the um, the frequency
spectrums, the different speakers.
Oh Damn. Some people go deep.
It's like everything, right.
Look at it. That's what it
looks like. That's another one.
Look at that Guy Razor's thing.
I mean it's, it's beautiful.
I mean audio is hundred thousand dollars.
Fucking speakers. Look at that guy.
He's like, I have it off my spirit.
Look at the fringe on my captains.
I am Heinrich odor wardens.
That's crazy, man. Yeah. Well there
you go. And around system and the cars.
Amazing to man because right. You know,
like you get like I'm a mark 11 sin,
like I've a alone as a
mark Levinson system in it.
It's just like the whole
thing's engineered for the
shape of the inside of the
car. Yes. Such as rings out
and all these perfect places.
It's tight. One of my favorite places,
listen to music is a car and I was
stoked to get my Audi cause I got the BNO
system in there and I've
never heard better audio.
I mean I've heard some
dope ass. I think I have a,
I think the Tesla uses Levinson stuff.
I'm not totally sure people
haven't been able to figure it out,
but they should've by now.
But I remember like five years ago
trying to figure like what is the premium
audio system like what is
besides a premium audience.
And I couldn't get an answer if
someone figured out what the amp was,
but they couldn't figure out the speakers
or something. That's interesting.
But um, but the, how eight
man banging all of a sudden,
and I have some eighteens at home.
There is a 2.1 system and
it just finally started,
it kicked in and now it sounds amazing.
I was like really kind of disappointed
for a while. Yeah, it's weird.
There's almost, yeah, there's like a
burn in what? I think there's a burden.
I'm not sure. Maybe it's totally,
maybe you got a bad ball.
Maybe I did get better weight. I mean,
what'd you think of this? We'd buy them.
Fantastic. It's pretty real groovy.
Really good. Yeah. It's just,
it's not weighing you down. No, it's
just a nice, friendly like you're,
you're fucking high. But like I,
yeah, I feel good. It's stuff.
It's not like they not
freaking out. I like it a lot.
What's it called again? Purple.
What? A purple tongue? No,
a purple rain. Thank you. Geez.
Why does he know James Bond?
I know the great brain. That's
awesome. Purple Venom. Legit him.
Wow. All these speakers
you have the browns. Yeah.
And then there's like a subwoofer
that looks like an egg. Yeah.
And they're great cause it's,
I have my house kind of mid
century mod and mid century modern.
Oh, that's me. Trends. I think
it's hilarious. The first time.
I think I've said it out loud.
Yes. Sorry. That's wrong.
Just like mid century mod. That's
funny. Oh, you're going to love this.
The curtains are provided for, I'm,
you'll notice that the, the, the,
the overall layout is mid cinch mod. Um,
the only people I don't trust is when
I go over their house and they have a
minimalist set up,
like where they have like plastic chairs
that don't have any cushion and a flat
table with nothing on it. And everything's
small and there's nothing there.
I'm like, what are you doing? Yeah, I
know. You show me your clean brain. Yeah.
Fucking psychopath tone. What's
happening here? Where's the,
where's the soft surfaces? Where's
the place to chill? I, you know, I,
I like what I dig is that mid
century modern furniture, you know,
I don't even know what that is. You know,
like I'm a, was it jewel venn jewel?
Non Jewels? Uh, I forgot what his, it's a,
I think he's a Swedish or Danish
architect or furniture designer.
Fin Jewel. That's it. I
think. Um, and he makes these,
like you've seen these chairs
before, but the originals are just,
it's such a great work of
art. It's like sturdy, comfy,
but light enough that there's like a
bar in the back that's just made to grab
and you can just throw it around.
But when it is set up in a room,
it looks substantial and it looks
comfortable but super lightweight.
So their idea was like to be super
modular, really easy to move for company.
You know, this are right here. Uh,
that's not quite it typed in furniture.
Oh yeah, yeah. I, I was
his name a Finn Jewel,
spelled f I and then, yeah, jewel maybe j.
G. U. H L. Yeah.
Like that orange one right there.
Yeah. That's like one, one, one design.
But that one it has that, that extra
thing of, that's not how mine are minor.
Just like it's just a, a
back and uh, no arms and the,
but the same shape and you sit
in them and they're just great.
They're like firm but
comfortable. Like you feel active.
Like you could get out of it if
you needed to. That were there? Uh,
no. Uh, what does it say at the top?
That's his shit. Fin Fin try u h l maybe
try classic or something like that.
But look and stuff though. Yeah.
It's, I wonder if though the clicker,
the grasshopper chair. Yeah.
It's so weird when you have a chair
that's that low to the ground that's too
low.
Mine are not like that are like thing is
you can keep your feet in front of you.
Yeah. Like the stretch your legs out
like that one oh nine chair like that,
that kind of stuff. So it's
like normal chair height,
but it's beautifully designed, but
it's minimal. And for my living room,
like I like the idea that I could just
like move my furniture and if people want
to dance or whatever, we can just do
that. And you don't have to be the fuck,
you know, I'm gonna need help.
Like one person could literally
grab both chairs and move. Right.
And you don't have some bullshit sitting
there that could break. Yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah. Totally. Hey guys,
don't come near the end table guys.
I'm really sorry about that.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
I hate rock and roll music. It's Kinda
everybody crazy and shit. He says, Eric,
I told you the beat, the chill out
mixes only. Yeah, you need to chill out.
Mix for late night. We're like really
groovy Joe beam stuff. You know,
like in Brazilian Boston,
Nova. Do you, what do you,
what are your thoughts on like
streaming services, like music,
like title and stuff like that? You
will, things like Spotify and Pandora,
these street apple music, these streaming
services. I think they're convenient,
but uh,
I don't quite trust the quality yet
and I have a lot invested in iTunes.
Um,
but I started using title
only because it's the less,
that seems to be the least popular
of all the streaming services,
but as Jay z's company,
and not that I'm like a Jay z fan, I
just liked that it's owned by an artist.
Right. And that, um,
they focus on super high end
codex for their streaming.
So it's like the highest quality
possible for streaming since then.
Spotify claims to have it. I don't think
apple does it yet anyways, but I like,
I like the title. So I mean,
I guess the idea of being,
as long as it's fair for the,
the, the artist, you know,
the deal for streaming and how streaming's
streaming is calculated and how that
turns into revenue for our, on
the revenue side of things. Uh,
that's really important. Biggest
concerns, revenue side of things.
Cause it seems like that's where
this whole thing was like the wild,
wild west when it got started in the,
the way the parameters were established.
It's not in favor of the artist.
It's in favor of the people that
run the streaming companies.
They're the ones who make the substantial
profits. Yes, absolutely. Yeah.
The companies do because all they
have is the work of artists. I know.
Just why it's so crazy.
They make most of the money because they
provided a platform. Yes. They have.
You don't sell shit without artists.
If every artist is like, Nah,
fuck you and you don't have
anything. Yeah. You have nothing.
You don't sell anything. Yep.
Like year to selling tomatoes and
you don't even grow them. Yeah.
You want most of the money, like if you
were a tomato and you've got your tomato
from a farmer and the farmer to do all
this fucking work to make the tomatoes
and they sold them at your store,
but you got almost all the money.
Yeah. Those are amazing. I know. It's
totally crazy. It doesn't make any sense.
Well you couldn't grow tomatoes with
any other farmer for the next 10 years
afterwards cause they tie you up. Yeah.
And you have to make commercials
about these tomatoes,
but you have to pay for them now. They
know it all comes out of your profit,
not ours. Yeah. Fuck that. It's all about,
it's all about direct economy.
You know what I mean? Like that's,
that's the way, that's where we
are now, I think. Right? Yeah.
I think that's where we're,
where we are, where we're headed.
I think that's definitely, I
don't, you know, I, I can barely,
that's why I want to kind of do
my own streaming stuff like that.
I don't want to be in tied up and to uh,
with another company that utilize his
behavioral statistical data to increase
their algorithms for targeted advertising.
Like that's not really
interesting to me. Yeah.
I think would've gone like youtube, just
build it and they will come, you know,
and then advertisers who resonate
with your sort of mindset,
they'll find you. There's so many,
there's plenty of cool CBD brands and
fill in the blank of cool companies that'd
be more than happy to advertise
on something that, you know,
you'd have a guaranteed audience of a
certain kind of people. Yes, totally.
Totally. I think it's great. And I think
also just having a direct store too,
I just,
I love the idea of like whatever I make
that's just sold to the store and like
you're just paying me and I'm getting it
and you're getting the thing and that's
it. Yeah.
I mean you've worked for a bunch of
different companies before [inaudible] had
done things. It's like it can be great.
You can work with a bunch of
beautiful people or be a disaster.
You've got some time suck in the
middle of the fucking mix and they,
they just demand too much attention.
There's too much conflict and
nonsense and interpersonal drama.
And sometimes people
start fucking, oh yeah.
People that work together
and start fucking,
and then you have to hear the opinions
of bolted them while you pretend that you
don't know that they're fucking,
that this is weighing heavily on the
way they're communicating with everybody
else. Like, Oh yeah, that's uh,
supporting each other and you're
supposed to support them to now their
relationship has become
center stage in your office.
That's like one of the reasons why
people don't want office romances.
Not even just because women don't want
to be harassed by men that are trying to
fuck them all the time. So
would just say no one can do it.
But also because once it, a relationship
does happen, one of two things.
Either it'll grow, one's raped, yeah.
Either it would go great and
everyone's going to be a part of it.
So your relationship becomes a part of
the whole ecosystem of the office or
it'll go terrible and people have to
pick sides and or one of you has to leave
like so or bad Juju. You,
if you're amongst the
most miraculous people,
you have a amicable split and you
become really good friends afterwards.
You still work together with no problems.
Even like each other spouses. Yeah.
Right. It is possible. It is possible.
It's happened. I'm sure it's happened.
Yes, but much, much more rare. If I was
running a company, I'd be like, listen,
you guys can't bang each other. Yes,
I know it sounds gross. I know that
you're here all day, but problem is like,
what if you met the girl of your dreams
on a job that was your dream job?
You're like, Shit. What do you
do? You have to make the decision.
It's like a fucking Jennifer Lopez movie,
right? Yeah, totally. Like, like two.
It's called two successful. I don't
give a fuck about this job, Jennifer.
I want to be with you. Dot, dot, dot,
and play the music. It's like, no,
you don't have to quit. I'll quit.
Fuck this, but I've got to quit. No,
you can't. And then they decided
to start their own firm. Yeah.
If it was real chick movie,
the girl would have like the smaller
paycheck too and the guy would lose the
bigger paycheck and he
would, he would come,
she would come home from work and
he would be wearing a fucking like,
like an apron and he'd be mopping. Yes.
That'd be great. Well,
I guess I guess I should get used to
it like that's how it is. My lifestyle.
Michael Fell in love the perfect job.
I gave up my perfect job for
the perfect woman. Yeah, yeah.
That would suck if you had the dream
job, but you met a girl there who,
she was single and she was in the you
and you both knew each other and you're
like, God dammit. What do you do?
You start banging and don't tell
anybody that's what you do. Right.
Pro Probably. Or if you're like
super pro and super committed,
you just figured out a way not to and
just kind of maybe come up with an
agreement or something. I don't
know. Plot your exit. Yes.
You got to plot your eggs.
Always know your exits while you're lying
about banging each other. Yes. Yeah.
You've got a lie. You got to lie
and say, yeah, we're going to,
I'm going to the movies snipe,
my friend Melissa. Anyway,
going back to Todd's house
for some Dick, that sucks.
That's such a terrible way to live, guys.
Don't do it. It's not worth it. Well,
the most terrible is
probably live in the closet.
That's probably the most
terrible. That's the most,
it's a super unnecessary one I think.
Yeah. In some cases. Not at all.
Yeah. Well it's also like,
it's symbolic of, you know,
we all have things in like in
a closet. I mean that's like a,
that's like a pretty big level that's
noticeable by many, many people.
But in a way it is a metaphor for like,
there are a lot of things that we don't
allow ourselves to. Sure. You know,
like let people know about, and
especially in the corporate world, right?
You're, you're forced to present
a air quotes, professional image,
and this enhances your ability to earn
living and enhances your ability to be
successful inside that
corporate structure.
So you literally have to
play a role all the time,
which is why have you talked to women
who are dominatrix is one of the things
that they say is the,
the guys who really like to get kicked
in the balls and shit on are the guys who
run businesses, the guys who are like,
yeah, they need to feel it. It's fun.
It feel alive. They need
a kick in the balls.
They need someone pissing in their mouth.
They need so they need to get smacked.
They want to get crazy because
they're so buttoned down all day long.
They can barely take it. God,
they're so lucky. Reggie,
you're so lucky in the artist. So
lucky son of a bitch. I love it.
Sounds in a cubicle right
now. Mad at you. No, man,
you guys can live your dreams. I
mean, I don't know. I mean it's,
it's and people about credit card
loans. Yeah, I know. Well, you know,
we could be more of us,
could be more creative,
but we're not really designing or as
a society to support that. Yeah. We,
you and I can't fix the
streets fixing the streets,
but we can inspire people
to fix the streets. Yeah,
of course. I mean, you know,
sometimes it just takes a little
kick in the, in the yard bowls.
Like I was having a conversation with
my friend the other day. We were saying,
he was saying that, you know,
you kinda really need all kinds of people
cause there's all kinds of jobs that
you don't want to do.
And I was like, yeah,
we're having a problem with our
exterminator and I'm going to like,
but like could you imagine a dude who's
really cool, who's in the killing rats?
Like that's what he does for a
living. It's just flux rats up.
That's his whole deal. He
cares. Rats. I know, I know.
There are people that just sort stern
certain types of screws on an assembly
line all day long. That's what
they do. Somebody needs to do that,
otherwise it's not going to get done
right. You know, I mean theoretically,
you know, robotics stuff,
when people fear like robotics taking
over jobs and things like things like
that,
theoretically the positive side of that
is if societies organize themselves in a
way that ensures that people
remain productive, um,
aside from these automations because
it's taking away the menial tasks,
the repetitive tasks,
and then we were able to allocate more
brainpower to the economy if that's the
way it's viewed, it's Rad. I think it's
a welcome thing. And I think, um, yeah,
there's fear, you know, the
unknown and things like that.
But if the government helps or, you know,
there's a transition that's at least
considered, uh, it could be really,
really beneficial. Well,
how do you feel about things
like universal basic income?
How do you feel about that?
I mean, that's a cause.
That's what people are gonna need.
If we get to a point where millions
of jobs vanish overnight because of
automation, which could happen.
You're looking at a, uh,
I mean obviously I don't, I don't know
what I'm talking about, but if I did,
I would say you'd look at a nationwide
version of what happened in Detroit when
the auto industry backed out.
Well, yeah, I mean, I don't know.
I mean, I don't know like the universal,
I mean it kind of makes sense,
but I also don't know about the
successful models and the non successful
implementations because obviously
with societies it becomes a lot more
complicated because it's people
and people are complicated.
And so when you say there's
universal income for,
there's a base amount
that everybody will have.
You don't have to worry
about certain things. Right.
Well transitioning out of the current
state, the mind state that we're in,
some people are just going
to try to blow it, you know,
all and then they'll go into debt and
then you know maybe or maybe design the
system to be really foolproof and it's
just commodities based so people can only
get the value that they're
guaranteed as a, you know,
rent being paid, actual
food, you know, actual thing.
So they don't have access to the money.
I don't know that if you don't
give them access to the money,
then don't give them adequate choices in
terms of where they can get their food.
Like I'm not,
not in favor that because if you had
like a government place where they had
groceries, you can go get
your groceries for free.
That place is going to be disgusting.
So I'm going well cause
there's no competition. You
know what I'm saying? Yeah.
Well maybe no incentive for excellence.
Well maybe if it was like a, you know,
some kind of a card or something
associated like an apple pay type thing.
So you just, you go to
whatever store you want to.
Similar to like a welfare card or a food
stand, like food stamps. Yeah, exactly.
But a little bit more
framed differently. Right.
Like you'd have an account
with the government where
every month you'd get like
$1,000 cash and $500 in food. Yeah.
Like maybe something like that. Yeah.
And then there were rewards for
like, you know, moving out of that,
like phasing out of that. Right. The
Way Andrew Yang has it structured,
you would get, everyone would
get it, you could opt out of it,
like say if you were doing interesting
yourself, like you could opt out of it.
Oh, that's cool. Yeah,
I do like the everything thing because
as soon as you decide you make something
specifically for a certain population,
especially when you're talking about
that type of thing, it's not, it doesn't,
it doesn't work. I mean conceptually it
just better when everyone knows like,
oh, you have it. I have it.
There's something that binds all
of us that we're all in common.
Obviously this billionaire
doesn't need it,
but there's just a precedent for people
that make a certain amount of money.
They're suggested to like, you know,
offset that like put it back into the
system so that there's more money,
people that need it, whatever.
But I think like saying it's for
everybody is kind of a smart thing to do.
I like that everything everybody is that
you have equity in the corporation that
is the United States of America. Oh
that's interesting. Yeah, that's weird.
Particularly if you're thinking
about natural resources like a man,
when you imagine the enormous profits
that someone gets from natural resources.
I like the idea that you own
the oil that's under the ground.
Like is who's decided that like why have
we decided that you can go a mile off
the ocean, stick a fucking
tube in the ground,
suck out all the oil and make $1 trillion.
Like who said who said you could do that?
That's not even your ground. So the,
the what the government is giving
a license to BP and BP drills,
holes a mile off shore and then they
suck all the oil out and they make
billions.
And who's getting that money and how
much does the government get and how much
is it BP paying for that contract and
why doesn't that money go to the people
that live in the country? Because
if the people live in the country,
the countries, the corporation,
the corporation is the
one that owns this water.
Yeah, they're the ones us. So
the idea would be that you would,
we would all profit from it and they
would make substantially less than they
make now.
And then instead of these people making
billions and billions of dollars for
something that's not even theirs. Yeah.
Like that profit would be split
evenly around the country in terms of
infrastructure and replenishing
impoverished communities
and community centers
and trying to figure out a way to engineer
out all the horrific neighborhoods.
Use the natural resources.
Yes. I mean that would be
wonderful. They've had to
pay some people for fracking.
They've had to pay some people off
because they just ruined their, their,
their neighborhood.
Like there's people that live in
places like fully toxic now. Yes.
What do you have, Jamie?
I saw this the other day.
This is from the original spill and
2004 it's been going on consistently.
Oh yeah. It's still leaking.
They said the 14 year old Gulf oil spill
is leaking up to 4,500 gallons a day.
They found that it was
many, many times more. Um,
oil was leaking out then when they
thought it was. So that's still,
that's going into the ocean right
now from that stupid oil pipeline.
Yeah. The quicker that someone
figures out the alternative energy,
that's kind of what I'm saying.
It's like the, it needs to happen.
This is ridiculous. It's just, it's,
everyone's doing the easy thing right
now and it's just feeding the, again,
the capitalist mission machine
is just like, no, that's okay.
That's acceptable. Well,
you and I have righteous virtue because
we drive electric vehicles occasionally.
That's true. I do feel
a little bit better.
I feel better than people
when I drive my Tesla.
You assholes poisoning
the world, you know?
I feel I only feel better driving my
Tesla only in that it's just faster.
It's just faster than almost everything
on the road. It's like time machine.
That's the at. That's
exactly what I call it.
I always say like if there's a location
that I want to go to, I appear there.
I don't go June over there. It's
just like, and you have the 100 d,
which is the one I have, which
is the two monster one phrase.
Meanwhile that fucking new thing that
they're coming out with that the roaster.
I really want to get my second faster.
Zero to 60. Yeah. It's how well one,
1.9, 1.8 theoretically 1.8 seconds here.
the 60s changed his uh, his take on that.
I think he recently said it's
2.1 are you serious? Yes. Okay.
Who were very disciplined very this way.
Cause you got to break the two barriers.
What kind of nonsense is this? I know.
Where's my point? Where's my 10th
of a second? Ain't going to matter.
Kids fucking thing's ridiculous.
Kidding. It's just a fucking weapon.
It's insane. But it also has 600
mile range. Yes. That's what I heard.
Which is just insane to me. I
just love that it's a Tinier car.
It's like the fastest thing ever.
There's only going to be maybe three
other road legal cars that you could buy
that would get to that,
that level one car at night.
They're going to look obsolete compared
to that though. Oh yeah. I mean, well,
the thing I'm excited about is
dependent Farina Electric car. Ooh.
All designed completely in house.
And I don't know when it comes out,
but I don't know if you find a picture
of it. It is the nastiest piece of tech.
Don't let the Italians make the engine
though. Trust. Yeah, I don't think so.
I think they're leveraging like,
ah, let my people design things.
You let them design the way
it looks, but all the wires,
they're barely paying attention.
Standard Girls Asses Heaton Spaghetti.
I guarantee you. That's
so funny. That's so true.
You like Germans and Japanese
make reliable cars. Yes.
They make their engineers
out there get that woo. Damn.
That is a Goddamn Batmobile. Yeah.
She'd be nasty. Wow. That's a real car.
Oh yeah. When's that coming out? Um, I
think orders are happening. There you go.
That's like 5 million. Jesus.
That's it, right? Yeah.
Cause all this money coming active
eyras how many shakes are there?
I mean come on, look, get that fucking,
and it borrows a little bit of like
Ferrari La Ferrari has little bit of
Japanese styling. It has a,
it's the perfect blend of like all the
good things about like tech looking car
and what it's like. It's
like a Ferrari four 88 yes.
That but one that fuck
1900 Lexus LFA oh yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. That's, yeah, I
got that hundred 1900 how many Newton?
Uh, pounds of Torque. I don't
know what that is to say.
Whenever they say that Newton meters,
I don't get it. Those European ones.
And I'm like, what are you
saying? I don't feel that.
All I know is what is high.
And then I base it off of that.
It's funny too that we still use
horses. I know, I'm stupid as that.
I look at that I've seen is people
power less than two seconds.
So that's like the, but it's an
electric vehicle and I'm sure I'm,
Jeez biting has one coming out that looks
really cool. It was 180 miles an hour,
186 miles an hour and 12
seconds. She says, Chris,
so 12 seconds later you're
going to 186 miles an hour.
[inaudible] control cockpit. Uh, that's
what I like about cars like that.
I liked that look amazing. It's a
fucking house in the hills. They know it.
The types in the hills. I'd get
it. Wow. If I could, I'd get it.
What'd you oh yeah, easily. I
definitely want to get the roads.
I'm thinking about the roadster. I'm
getting that bitch. You got to man.
Come on. Got To, I mean it's not that.
I mean for 250 grand you're getting
a car that like, that's, that's a,
what does that, what was it
again? To keep chilling us. Jamie,
you're just flipping through clothes
now. Check out Jamie's on a rabbit hole.
You went down the youtube
rabbit hole. Lotus was doing,
what was the other one was roadster.
Oh yeah, that thinks about us.
What does the other one Rimac concept
to? Oh, I don't know what that, it's a,
I think there is downward handle
for the roadster. Oh yeah.
You slide your finger down.
Yeah. Tops. I mean who knows?
This is stranded in the pot. It's not,
it's not using that steering wheel.
I don't know why they do that.
They do that for concept cars.
That No side view mirrors, which now is
actually becoming legal, which is great.
Finally, No side view mirrors cause
it looks sexier. It looks more sleek.
Does it really bother you?
That's like if you get a dude and the
girl is really hot but she has a chip
tooth. Oh go. No, no, no. That makes,
that makes, that makes it better.
That's like, that's character man.
That's beautiful. So why do you need a,
why don't you want side mirrors? I want
to see it just creates a cleaner line.
Fuck a clean line. I want to see
what's going on. What have you die?
I want to see what's behind me, man. Well,
the new Honda all electric car
that's basically kind of like a,
like a kind of an eagle, but it's
a fully new car. It's got, uh,
it's got the camera system
with the side view mirrors.
They're just right on
the edge of the Dash,
right where the mirrors kind
of would be. And the guy,
the guy who was doing a review of it,
one of the few guys who's gotten to drive
it said that it just blows you away.
You're like, why haven't
cars been like this forever?
Because it gives you an accurate
fulltime view of what's going on.
And the rear view mirror is
also a screen. No pillars,
no pillars. What are you laughing? I make
fun of this car. What am I gonna Fuck?
No, go back to the hassle site. Looking
at us was only some Honda. It's cute.
E I like it. It's also got the
most ridiculous turning radius.
It's turns tighter than a
a London cab. Good. Yeah,
because it's got a stick
in the ground. Yeah.
Just it just plants the pole in the
ground and then it just rotates. Yeah.
Yeah. The road stairs is evil. I don't
think it's really gonna come out in 2020.
I don't think so either. I think
it's going to get pushed back,
but it's just such a gorgeous, it does
have some active Arrow, I think in the,
the spoilers active. It's cool looking.
It looks like what a car supposed
to look like in 2020. Exactly. Yes.
Reggie Watts. Let's wrap this
back. Way Up. Let's do it.
People want to follow you on
social media. Is that possible?
Only if they want to. And it said, um, uh,
Reggie Watts at Twitter and uh, Instagram.
It's Reggie watts and
sometimes Reggie watts.com.
That's about it. We gotta do this more
often for real. Let's do it. Yeah.
It's so much fun. Such a cool
journey, man. Really Fun. Really Fun.
Thanks for the awesome weed. Purple
Venom. Of course. Young Jamie.
I loot goodbye everybody.
Oh, that was good, man.