I believe it.
Yeah,
that's better.
All right.
Five,
four,
three,
two
kapow and we're live.
Shirley,
how are ya?
I'm feeling alive.
You look alive.
Thanks.
So to you.
Does anybody ever asks you,
are you really only happy when it rains
all the time?
Is that annoying?
Yeah,
I would imagine so.
I shouldn't have done it.
Couldn't help myself.
It was a little beneath you,
but that's okay.
I'll forgive you.
I panicked.
I never do.
Well,
at least you didn't ask me.
Are you really?
Really?
You know the sister of Marla Munson is
another one too.
Oh is that one that comes up that comes
up alone?
Yeah.
That guy's a freak.
I met him.
I love him.
He's an odd dude.
He's,
you think,
oh,
I was kind of shocked by how normal he
is.
Very smart.
Very nice.
Smart and really,
I thought really forthright.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
You say to them,
I love them.
Actually I,
I was,
I was crazy about him.
Well,
doesn't that in and of itself make him a
freak?
Yeah.
I guess in this world.
I mean,
we were just talking out there about how
many people are pilled up and that this
was while we were also talking about
people who can't tell the truth that
maybe even more weird.
Yeah.
We're,
we're talking about Trans Racial people.
You know,
the one folks,
we don't have to say her name,
you know that check for approval.
The one who thinks he's in and then that
dude who also did it,
it was a lot of weird people out there.
Yeah.
But uh,
also Jamie,
Jamie lies about being an Indian,
apparently not alive.
It's not a lie.
It's a joke.
It's not funny thing you can't,
Indian is actually kind of offensive to
some people now.
Yeah.
Where it was like standard for a long
time.
Well,
I'm ashamed to see you.
When I first came to America 20 years
ago,
I always cause it was the way we were
brought up to do.
We refer to native Americans as a Red
Indians.
We time I would see red,
Indian,
everybody in me,
my band would be gone.
You can't see that.
Stop that.
And I'm like,
Oh God,
I'm so sorry.
But you know,
I was 30 years in or whatever.
I was so used to seeing it.
The hose that a Scotland thing,
you say you this thing you say Red
Indian,
we used to see right Indian that has no
been completely changed.
But back then 20 odd years ago.
Yeah.
We always refer to native Americans as
Red Indian.
Yeah.
This,
I mean you can't say read people,
but you can say white people.
You can definitely say black people,
but you can't say yellow people.
Yeah,
it's complicated.
Yeah.
Two bills are complicated.
I get it.
You know,
if you did know,
it would be so like if you were just
learning this language,
like if you came from China or something
like that,
you can fees.
You'd be baffled.
Yes.
Yeah.
I spend my life baffled though.
That's okay.
I've just gone.
I just go with it.
No,
it's good for you to be baffled.
Good for you.
That is a good way to approach it.
Made me happier.
I'll tell you that.
It's definitely happy than trying to
control everything and a lot of people
that go down that rabbit hole,
that's not a good rabbit hole to go
down.
No,
but I think controlling things or it's
fear driven,
right?
Sure.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah,
definitely.
A lot of it.
I think I'm too old to be fearful
really,
but yeah.
Yeah,
but you are like a,
see there's a certain thing that happens
to people in show business when they get
to a certain age,
either they feel like it's slipping away
or they feel comfortable.
You seem like a comfortable person.
Yeah,
I'm a comfortable kind of kind of what's
uncomfortable?
I'm uncomfortable about a lot of,
let's get into it.
I'm sorry.
By lower your guard,
by giving you something really beneath
me first and then slip it in.
You don't even know it's coming.
No,
I'm uncomfortable about a lot of things,
but I hear what you're saying and yeah,
I feel like maybe if you feel like
you've failed and then you've stepped
back up,
then you start your,
you either crumble and you can't build
your life back up.
Or you find a place to stand and you
build your career again on your own
terms and then it is comfortable.
Is that what you're saying?
Like that's where you're at.
That's what I'm saying.
But you never failed.
I felt I did.
Well,
you know,
we haven't,
we in the 90s where so much I sort of
pop cultural,
Zig aced I guess,
you know,
and that can't last forever.
But when it stops,
I should speak for myself.
When it stopped,
I was,
it was desi and from you,
I didn't really know what to do with
myself.
I didn't really understand my identity,
you know what I mean?
I didn't know who it was,
was such a ride because it was such a
crazy ride.
And I,
I densified with myself as a successful
person and my idea of success was really
warped,
you know?
So your idea of success was commercial
success,
correct?
Yeah.
Did you take any comfort in the artistic
success?
I did eventually,
but at the time I felt like we were
being creatively adventurous and we were
getting punished for it and it made me
really angry.
Um,
so you feel like you're getting the
published,
I mean,
was it the publishers though,
the music publishers that we're
punishing you?
Like what was,
it wasn't even that person,
although I took it personally,
it was really much more a cultural
shift,
you know?
So that just,
it wasn't received as well.
Correct?
You are correct.
So,
yeah.
And so we'd been used to being on top of
the charts,
you know,
and then when that stops,
all of a sudden you're like,
well,
is everything we're doing?
All our ideas are rubbish.
But deep down,
you know,
they're not,
but you're being rejected anyway.
And so you have to find a way through
that.
And that's complicated,
I think was complicated for a simple
girl like me that,
well I would imagine anytime you are as
big as garbage was in the nineties I
mean,
you guys weren't gigantic.
I mean,
it was hard to go into a clothing store
without hearing your music blaring.
Yeah.
And just mad.
Mad.
Yeah.
I'm a huge fan.
I love you.
God,
thank you.
So it's kind of weird sitting across
from me.
It is.
I'm enjoying you seem to be.
Yeah,
but I would imagine that like as big as
you guys were the either stay that big
and then you become a crazy person,
you probably better off like doing what
you did like,
like taking our artistic chances,
settling in and then doing what you're
doing now.
Being more comfortable.
Yeah,
I guess so.
I mean we were lucky we had a manager,
a very wise manager,
okay.
Ki Prime management at the time who
said,
what do you want?
Do you want a long career,
a lower level or do you want a short
career,
a ridiculously high level.
And we were like,
we want the long career and Stina that's
exactly what we got in the end.
But um,
there was this mad blip that happened
for alternative music,
which I had never gotten really that
much pop cultural success I guess.
We were like,
we'd enjoyed this weird rush of
alternative music that for far blip
ruled the charts.
If you weren't under old bands,
you were nothing bad.
Yeah.
You guys caught that wave,
that post Novo Nirvana.
Yeah.
That's really what it was.
Right?
Yeah.
I would love to talk to Chris Cornell
like when,
remember when Chris Cornell did those
pop music songs?
Like you went from soundgarden dislike
deep crazy dark band too.
Yeah,
that's true.
Like weird poppy music.
Some stuff softer and I'm sure he was
just trying to figure out a way to
survive like we all do.
Yeah.
And it's complicated for anybody.
With a career yourself included.
You know,
you have to like adopt and figured out
well,
okay,
where does stick?
Yeah.
To know.
It's weird.
Well,
I think ultimately what you got to
figure out is what are you like?
Yeah,
dude,
it's hard to know what you like
sometimes.
No,
sure.
Because if you don't like something but
it's super successful for you and you
might keep doing that.
That's very confusing.
Yeah.
Surely.
Goodness for getting here.
Yeah.
We're going to meet my future husband.
My wife's coming up here soon to keep
that on the DL.
I'm sure my husband will be listening
and laughing his ass.
Yeah.
Your husband is named Billy Bush
different Billy Bush not to grab the
pussy.
Billy Bush.
Correct.
But he,
he really suffered.
Sure.
Tell him he got like an hailstorm of
abuse via twitter.
I mean,
we find it funny,
but it was also quite alarming because
we were like,
oh my God,
I hope somebody isn't common.
Punish you.
What?
What's crazy is that guy,
the re the real grab the pussy.
Billy Bush didn't really do anything.
He was just there.
Yeah.
He,
he kind of was a scapegoat and then go
from there some,
I mean,
I think he was just trying to be
conciliatory as a TV host,
you know?
And he got,
yeah,
he got,
he lost his job.
No,
yes.
Yeah.
And he was sitting next to this gigantic
tycoon,
billionaire character,
this flamboyant,
boisterous,
sort of a guy who was going on his usual
flamboyant,
boisterous tyrese.
He probably felt like it was funny.
You know,
you're listening to this guy.
Did to be fair,
but yeah,
boy,
did he have to pay the price?
My husband too by default.
But it's funny that you know,
your husband would get hate from it,
the or that that guy would get hate
from.
People seem to be like looking for
people to get mad at all.
I think what all Matt,
right,
that the whole world is currently angry
and we don't really know why,
but we get fed a lot of negative
information and I don't know if the
human brain knows how to cook with it.
So it's very early on and the sort of
technological revolution,
so to speak.
And I don't think our brains have quite
caught up with how much bad news we're
absorbing on a daily basis.
And so I think,
yeah,
I think people are angry and upset and
they don't know what to do with it.
And there are certain figures that
attract that,
you know,
that kind of rage or wrath and the
people use these people as hot rods for
the on
chaos in their brains.
I think you just nailed it.
I think that's absolutely it.
We've been talking about it a bunch
lately,
that there's just too many people.
There's 7 billion people and to get all
the information,
especially the bad information from 7
billion people,
it's on marriage.
It's intense.
Yeah.
I mean,
yeah.
Well said.
It's just crazy.
You flicked through twitter or you
flicked through instagram or look on
facebook,
every single thing from every corner of
the globe is your heating bad news.
You know,
you want to hear because like if you
will,
the good news is not news.
No.
It's like everybody got along great
today.
Yeah.
But it's not a stories can sell that.
I'm just going to be really curious as
to see where the human race schools have
had high,
we do manage with all this information
cause even if you stand up for a cause
like,
you know,
like today I was,
I did a post about um,
for Amnesty International who's standing
up for the Turkish journalists who are,
who are all in prison for just doing
their jobs.
And so you stand up for that cause
because I feel very strongly in a free
press and you just become inundated with
people saying,
well,
what about Venezuela?
And they have their legitimate concerns
about what's going on in their country,
right by the women in Argentina,
you know,
and so on and so forth.
And in Brazil and Mexico and I just
don't know even know what to do with all
the information.
There's a part of the problem too,
is that people expect you to comment on
every single thing.
And if you comment on one thing,
especially if you can't run a one funny,
silly thing,
they'll say,
well,
what about this?
Talking about this terrible things
happening.
It's almost like you have a
responsibility to alert people of your
state of consciousness that every step
of the day,
every second of the day,
I could,
I could definitely do that.
Not even I could do that just for the
emojis.
Yeah,
just as emojis.
I feel like emojis or the future,
I've been thinking a lot about this.
I think emojis,
I mean,
I think,
was it Eddie Brown with compared them to
hieroglyphs you?
It was Jamie.
Jamie,
Jamie.
Jamie was saying,
we were talking about it that like,
they are a lot like hieroglyphs.
Like if you,
if you send someone,
like I,
you one of the reasons why I thought it
was Eddie,
because Eddie always sends me like a
series of emojis like in a row,
you know?
And it's fine.
He's just being funny.
Like I'll send me a clown and a thumbs
up and a black fist.
Oprah Jean and my two favorites.
The obor Jean Jean.
When you come for gene,
an eggplant.
Oh,
I call it no,
Brazil.
Did you know what it is?
I know what you mean now,
but,
uh,
why is it an eggplant at the favorite
one?
I just like it.
It looks rude and funny.
See,
I'm,
I'm Italian,
so I feel like it's racist.
I see eggplants.
Oh,
of course.
You're like,
it's a direct your wrath on me.
I'm so sorry.
But,
uh,
I feel like,
there's like a racist term for black
people.
Okay.
Now you're just being,
no,
no.
It is amongst amongst Italians.
It really is.
Yeah.
Eggplants.
Why?
What is the word?
What's that word?
That Italian word that they use?
There's a,
see if he can google it.
Race,
Italian word for eggplant used.
It's like it's a common thing and like
the east coast.
What is,
I don't get the race thing.
I swear to God.
What does it,
a couple of choices I guess.
Yeah,
there's a word that they would always
use.
Miliion.
Yeah.
Moving Yon is an Italian derogatory
slang term for a black person and it's
derived from the word egg plant.
We're a melon Zion,
which is,
uh,
which is a term for eggplant spinets.
Right.
I'm so sorry.
I made it impossible for you to use
eggplant now without thinking about it.
Back to the lipstick Emoji.
So we've killed Red Indian and we've
killed eggplant on one podcast.
Yeah.
Indian was the thing that like you could
say all the time when I was a kid,
but now if he even accidentally like
slips out of my mouth,
like you don't say cowboys and Indians
anymore,
I suppose.
Say like cowboys and native Americans
but doesn't roll off the tongue as
quickly,
but we can make our habits can cause we
of all we are,
we're trying,
we're disciplined.
I know your discipline.
I'm trying.
We work at it.
How do you know,
cause I've read some stories about how
you hold yourself together over time and
that's,
that takes,
that takes discipline and I dunno,
I think it takes a lot of balls
actually.
Hmm.
I'll just leave it there.
Thank you sir.
Appreciate it.
Thank you.
Well,
you got to say bullocks though,
don't you?
Did you just say it in a positive way?
That it takes a lot of bullocks?
It takes a little bullets.
Did you say that would just hit that
way?
No,
I say bowls cause I,
I don't know.
I like the word bowls.
Yeah.
Something to do with Max and bullocks is
too hard for me to see.
But bollix is like bullshit too,
right?
Oh well yeah,
that I would use.
That's bullocks.
But that's also balls,
right?
Correct.
But it's used in a slightly different,
how could balls be bullshit.
I'm so confused,
but the confusion,
that's okay.
I'm going with it.
I'm totally going with it.
I'm flexible.
I tried to be more flexible as I get
older.
I work on that.
It's hard to remain flexible is really a
challenge and I think that's what
differentiates the sheep from the goats.
What's better?
Sheep or goat?
The goat.
The greatest of all time.
I love the gold,
but then I'm partial tear sheet.
I was reading this article,
uh,
yesterday about music and they were
talking about how people get very rigid
in their musical tastes like what they
liked when they were younger.
They get to a certain stage in their
life and then they just lock on and any
new music,
they just sort of reject a logical
reason for that.
Right?
Yeah.
What is it?
Do you know
it's something to do within the pathways
in your brain?
I don't know that the first,
when you first meet these insane
connections and it's usually during
adolescence apparently.
Yeah.
You make these connections with I
suppose,
adventure and you know,
independence.
I mean,
I don't know.
I don't know enough about it,
but they have done all these studies
during studies on the brain,
on dementia.
They've discovered all these incredible
neurological pathways that are formed by
music and somebody can't even remember
how to,
you know,
button their shirt,
but they can sing every single word and
every note perfectly to some opera that
they,
they performed when they were young.
I mean,
I don't know.
It's crazy.
Crazy.
There's,
there's definitely weird pathways that
get established in the brain and they
say that like there's something about
music and especially like musical
pathways that literally invoke these
physiological changes in a person that
are unlike anything else.
Like it.
Like when I was a kid that rocky I,
the tiger song would come on and he was
just the stairs,
you would just want to start running.
You would just want to lift weights or
just run up a hill or something like
that.
I mean it would make your body change.
It was like if that was a drug,
if you could take that drug,
if he could sniff it,
like and like feel how you felt when
that song came on.
And be like,
yeah,
right.
I mean,
what else does that,
there's nothing else it does.
No,
that's true.
There is nothing else that does that.
I'm currently on this mad obsession with
oliver sacks.
Oh.
And uh,
I was,
I'm reading his biography right now or
autobiographies dicey and he's talking
about some of his like really sick
patients who have dementia or there's
some other form weird vitus that shuts
them down completely and they can't even
stand really.
And then if they play a certain piece of
music,
someone who is essentially an
unconscious being snaps to,
stands up and can dance and like recite
words,
even though they'd been newt for years.
I mean,
really crazy,
crazy stuff.
Yeah.
There's something about that art form
about your art.
Music can heal you.
Don't put your hands,
feel it.
I felt it.
I felt in charge my whole body,
my hair stood up on him.
What hair I have left.
Yeah,
there's something to it.
There's something to it that's like,
I mean,
and it's also very bizarre because it's
something that people have created,
right?
And it's not something that exists in
nature.
It makes beautiful sounds in nature,
like birds chirping and certain animal
noises and things that are beautiful.
But music is like the,
the,
the ability to control notes,
right?
The ability to a symphony,
the ability to structure a song and put
it together with a beautiful voice like
yours.
Like that is something that's entirely
created by a human being.
Like,
that didn't exist before.
Human beings existed and it works only
on us.
He ever played music for a dog.
These fucking stare at you.
They don't give a shit.
Dogs have shitty music.
Tastes might talk with response to
music.
Well,
maybe your dog does make sense.
Yeah.
I suppose she's trained that way.
Most probably.
Maybe feels like it's important to you
to give me to like a shitty person.
You know,
usually they have a shitty dog because
the dog is getting much shitting on
really,
he's taught them shitty manners,
but then the dog becomes sure.
They like if a dog bite your face off,
that's shitty dog.
Okay.
Fair enough.
Although I would argue it's a scared
dog,
but I'll give you that.
I agree.
I or terribly trained dog.
Yeah.
It's a problem.
I agree.
Um,
but there's,
there,
there's,
there's something that we've done with
this that I think is really,
um,
I think it taps into the human reward
system in a way that the human reward
system,
like when people enjoy being around
certain people,
there's a,
there's like rewards,
just like social rewards.
You get from it.
Like say if we have like a leader.
Yeah,
yeah.
We're having a fun time having a fun
conversation and laugh.
But like say if like you were in a tribe
of people and there was this one leader
or this one,
uh,
you know,
warrior that saved you from the Jaguar
and you would look up to that person
like that,
that's like a hero in a movie right now
when we tap into these ancient reward
systems,
I think there were ways that human
beings could learn and ways that we
could share energy with each other that
existed before media,
before music,
and before movies and books.
And I think what we've done with media,
music and books and movies especially,
is tap into those human reward system
since really crazy that I'm really into,
I love this idea.
There is hope for the human race after
all.
Oh,
there's definitely hope were awesome
people that awesome them.
Yeah,
we suck sometimes,
but there's a few who suck,
but it's not even 1% is that tree.
I think it's maybe 1% I think that if
you get 300 million people like we have
in America,
you get about 3 million douche bags.
That's what I think.
That's fair.
And then you have also people that are
the same victims as your dog.
That's a bad dog.
Like give people that are born and
raised in horrible environments and
abused when they're young.
And I think that's a giant part of the
problem,
a giant part of what we are.
And if we,
we just addressed that.
It's one of the main problems that I
have with our culture is that we don't
address at really at all the raising of
children and the doing it from the
beginning as a culture.
But we don't address betty much.
That's painful or dark or complicated,
do we?
Not really.
We don't talk about death,
which I think is a big mistake because
then you have your people to not live
their lives fully because they're so
scared of dying.
They spend their whole lives wedding and
we'll get you can sick to talk about it.
My parents don't want to talk about it.
I just think that's so crazy.
It's as though if you don't talk about
it,
it's going to go away somehow.
Like I don't want to deal with it.
Let's talk about something else.
Let's go get dessert.
It's weird.
People just shut off.
You mentioned anything difficult just
shuts down a conversation.
Well that was one of the main problems
that a lot of psychologists had with
hiding caskets.
Like when they were bringing people back
from the war,
that they were taking these photographs
of the caskets and they wouldn't let
them be released.
Like it was a big thing during the Bush
administration in America and um,
psychologists were saying,
do you understand like this is your,
you are programming people to have a
very specific notion of war then because
you're not showing them the actual
consequences here.
I mean in a casket is almost a symbolic
consequence cause you're only seeing a
box and you know that a person,
a child's,
you know,
some parents child is in that box.
You're not,
you're not even seeing the body.
Like you're not even saying we should
see the body so people can understand
what a,
what a missile does to a person.
You're saying like the boxes themselves
are forbidden to be shown.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
Well it's just,
it's weird.
It's psychological warfare and a lot of
ways on the people because it allows
people to accept the consequences in
some sort of a weird,
almost abstract way.
They're not,
they're not seeing the consequences.
So sanitizing everything and allowing
people to grow and expand.
It shrinks our minds in a way.
The less we see,
the less we can think about it,
the less we're capable of thinking about
it in a way.
But it goes back to like the idea of,
of reading children and that goes back
to education as well and that we seem to
have fallen by the wayside there too.
Well I think we have,
but my feeling that human reward system,
it was much more uplifting.
Why think it's all connected?
Because I think that what we're doing
with technology in the form of music and
movies and media and all that thing is
just one step in this multifaceted
experience that we have integrating
technology and,
and the more,
the more sophisticated this technology
gets,
it seems like the closer it brings
people and ideas.
And I think that that's,
I honestly,
I mean people think that it's um,
I have too much of a utopian view of it,
but I really feel like that technology
is essentially going to balance it all
out.
I really feel like as much as we want to
try to hold back information and we try
to hold back education or try to program
people,
I feel like technology is ultimately
going to connect people instantaneously
with ideas and that you're not going to
be well yeah,
sort of,
but you could,
you could push it aside.
You could shut it off.
You could walk away.
If you have discipline,
you can leave your phone at home and go
for a walk in the woods.
But I feel like we're just one or two
generations away from being a completely
different thing than we are now.
That's the thing that bums me out about
dying.
That's the really,
pretty much the only thing is how much
we are going miss
of all the great technological advances.
Like how crazy is it gonna get it's
gonna get crazy.
I know and I'm so sad.
I'm going to miss so much of it.
You might not miss it because you're on
the tip right now of the scientific and
medical advancements that are going to
allow people to live to be 300 400 years
ago.
To hope not.
It's very possible.
Really,
really hope that cause you worry about
overpopulation and and yes,
and the calcification of the human mind.
I worry the Donald Trump's going to live
to be a thousand.
Oh God.
We all worry a wee bit.
It's got a lot of money.
Yeah,
sure it does.
It's pretty healthy for a fat guy too.
I was thinking that the other day he
goes out there super active.
Why is he so preoccupied with fast food?
It's really peculiar when you've got all
this money and you're stuffing your face
full of the cheapest food you can find
doesn't apparently he's got a huge fast
food preoccupation.
Maybe it's a president thing because
Bill Clinton did too.
There was a huge issue.
Clinton,
why he was up fast,
but he had no,
yeah,
all cut up with poor bill.
So what time press,
you can't eat fatty foods all time.
We're sloppy.
Well,
it's real.
Sugary and cheap crap is right.
Every and again,
every now and again to get one of those
Wendy's double doubles,
those double cheeseburgers.
They used to have the double
cheeseburger in my life ever.
Why?
I couldn't get my,
even I couldn't get my jobs right and
he really never had a double
cheeseburger.
I've never had a double tees,
but how long have you been in America?
Ooh,
I,
11 years and no nonsense.
No one 22 years.
Yes,
of course.
A good to know.
Get a single cheeseburger in and out.
Is that a double?
That'd be
my jobs.
Right.
That,
and I've never had a double level.
So what do you get?
I don't know.
I get,
I've never ordered it.
My husband's always the one that's sort
of what I want.
I wish he was,
maybe he was for like the first,
you know,
couple of weeks that we were together
when he's really trying hard to work kit
and that has long been left in the dust.
I can assure you like literally I have
to beg,
I had a friend of mine before,
he's,
he's married now,
but before he was married he had gone
through a series of like really horror
in this relationships.
And we were sitting around talking once
we were super high and he goes,
uh,
I think what I'm going to do is just
have two weak relationships.
He goes,
because two weeks is like the perfect
amount of time you're in love,
you're in love,
you want to spend all the time together,
it's great.
Then he goes and then somewhere around
them they just start expecting things
from you and then they get mad at you.
He's just picking the wrong partners
clearly.
Clearly cause he's married now.
Years I think is like a good honeymoon
pdf.
Two years.
Really.
Most things can go ogs in two years,
especially if you're dating an actor.
I've never dated an knocked her my life
for you.
Congratulations.
I couldn't deal with that.
Did you?
Actresses,
not no dudes,
but a girl be say actor like girls want
to be called actors now.
Like it's non gender specific these
days.
Fair enough.
I get that.
Yeah,
it makes sense.
totally get that I guess.
Yeah,
because actress or Comedienne,
that was a big one.
Can we like female comics do not like
that?
Don't like being called comedian.
Oh,
it makes you seem like a cheapened down
comic.
Like my funny comedian friends and
happen have vaginas.
They're all comedians.
Yeah,
I get that.
I really do get that out of respect that
the only thing is,
I love the word actress.
Actress is a pretty word word,
comedian sounds like a light version of
comedian.
Comedian doesn't have the same kind of
Gravitas.
Right?
Low Fat yogurt or something,
you know?
Yeah.
I never thought of it that way.
But yeah,
I think the more we get rid of gender
actually the better.
You think so?
But isn't it fun to be a girl?
It is fun to be a girl,
of course.
And I think it's fun to be all genders
and because whoever you hire,
whoever you are,
but I think when you are,
when you're,
you have to be called something.
It's like prison.
I don't think we should be living in
prisons.
Yeah,
but we're not living in prisons,
but we clearly are different.
Like especially you and I.
Of course you and I are very,
we're very different.
Very different.
It'd be super confused.
If you're anything like me,
I'd be like,
yeah,
no,
but I think you all humans,
we're all different,
right?
I mean,
I think it's crazy that we get put into
these generalized packs.
We kind of do.
Yeah.
But there's also just mean there's a
broad spectrum of behavior that is on
one side of the fence or the other side
of the fence,
whether it's male or female,
but there's definitely a male and female
when in in most people,
and then there's people that are,
you know,
then it gets real weird.
People that are born or in some way
don't want to be whatever gender they
are.
I think it's Kinda cool that they don't
want to be,
they just aren't.
I think some people just aren't and some
people don't want to be.
And I think it's like we were talking
about earlier about that Rachel Dolezal
willing to disagree here.
Well,
this is what I think.
I don't think we could ever possibly
know.
The motivation for every single person
was transgender or trans racial or
trans,
anything gender.
There was not,
as you knew yourself,
under no circumstances do you choose
your gender.
You don't.
You're not that powerful.
I don't think most people do,
but I think some people,
it's entirely possible that you could be
a woman and decide,
you know what?
I want to be a fucking man.
I'm tired of this.
I don't like it.
It's,
it's well within the realm of
possibility,
different thing,
isn't it?
I mean,
you're right and I'm sure that there are
circumstances like that,
but of that I think is a different thing
entirely maybe,
but would it be any less legitimate?
It'd be any less legitimate if a woman
felt compelled just by curiosity to
become a man versus compelled by her
feeling.
I think that's identity flirtation as
opposed to gender flirtation or gender
chilies or gender manifestation.
I'm using the wrong words here.
I think people could do whatever the
fuck they want to that.
I met that Lizard Dude once in Austin,
Texas.
Do you know that guy is?
He's turned himself into a lizard.
He's essentially tattooed his entire
body.
The split his tongue down the middle.
You sat in the front row of my show at
the Cap City comedy club and I was like,
well,
you don't need a lot of attention to you
buddy.
Yeah.
Sitting right in the fucking front row
looking like a lizard.
Very nice guy though.
Seemed like a super nice guy.
But he's a,
you know,
I mean look at this guy,
well that,
that's before he did his whole face.
He's got some amazing,
yeah.
Uh,
definitely weird.
I don't know about amazing.
If that was my kid.
And come on,
if you saw that in an art gallery,
he would be like,
that is amazing.
Maybe you and I have a different sense
of amazing.
Maybe we do.
Well that seems like a guy was drawing
on his face.
Uh Huh.
But Hey,
this is coming from a guy with drawing
all over his arms.
That's pretty incredible.
I mean,
who am I to say that it's,
this is like,
that's a cultural thing,
right?
Like why is it okay that I have tattoos
all over my arms and I don't think it's
right to tattoo your face.
I wouldn't say that like you should do,
be able to do whatever the fuck you
want.
Yeah.
And he has done,
but it's a cultural thing.
I mean,
for some people,
like I was in Japan and they made me,
I was in a gym and they made me go and
put a long sleeve shirt on because you
can't have exposed tattoos like this.
Well I guess cause their feelings
towards your arms at the same feelings
that you're having towards it.
For one second,
the Lizard has a little bit,
a little bit,
just for those of you who are not in the
studio right now who are listening to
just,
just take my word for it that Joe is
fucking with me right now.
No,
I'm not fucking with you guys.
Yes.
Ah,
fun.
That's a fun conversation.
When don't you think,
when someone's fucking with you,
that's like a negative thing,
right?
No.
Oh God,
no,
no.
I often fought for fun.
Okay.
Oh,
I think we just did a,
uh,
we just do a play on words there.
Hey,
life on us yet.
Exactly.
Yeah.
So,
um,
so what's the latest with you?
You guys are touring again?
Uh,
we're going on too in the summer.
Yeah.
That's the only like month away or
something like that way.
Yeah.
It's hot as fuck here now.
Last fucking minute.
Stop.
Yeah.
It used to rain.
I like it cold,
I must admit.
But we are going out into your,
we're good.
We're going to do something in my mind,
pretty sort of historical in a funny
way.
Like we go,
go going at now headline two or with a
blondie.
Whoa.
Legendary.
Debbie Harry.
Wow.
Do you know her?
I do know her actually.
I love,
and I love her and she's been somewhat
of a mentor to me in a way because she
was managed by a very famous music
manager called Geico first who managed
the ramones and talking heads and body
and so on,
so forth.
He was the one who basically start
plucked me from my band.
He saw him at that.
He thought I had potential and he just
let you know I,
I think you have potential to be in the
music business.
And he signed me in the end and blah,
blah,
blah.
And Anyway,
he introduced me to Debbie and Debbie
came and saw my band opened for the
ramones and the academy in New York
during the new music seminar one year.
And I was shaking like a leaf.
I've told this story a million times,
but it's one of my favorite memories of
stepping out on stage on the academy.
And of course ramones fans that were
pretty hardcore,
you know,
they weren't taking fools lately.
Yeah.
And you had to prove yourself.
So I was very,
very nervous and I looked down into the
mosh pit and Debbie Harry was there and
I just was like,
I will love you forever asking me.
I am your slave.
You are like for someone of that caliber
to do that,
it meant so much to me and as sort of
even in times of when I've doubted
myself,
I always think Debbie didn't take me.
Wow.
So yeah,
that excites typical night with our,
wow,
that's heavy.
I might tear up tier.
Come on to your butt a little bit.
Come on,
get into the,
you know,
the emotional thing.
She was a,
a very unique historical figure in
music.
There was no Debbie Harry before Debbie
Harry Caray.
It's like you can look
Debbie Hardy,
right?
There was no lady Gaga.
Yeah,
right.
She did it all really.
She's the archetype I think for a modern
pop girl.
And she was very authentic.
Like there was no questioning her
authenticity.
Like she was uniquely eccentric and it
still is.
Yeah,
I'd imagine.
70 and to be still making records,
thoughts,
incredible.
That's pretty bad ass.
It's really about us and really
inspiring for other women.
You know,
if we follow in our footsteps,
who you know,
will watch as the first time I can think
of like a woman has had a pop color you
over that long.
Well isn't it a new thing?
I mean if you really stop and think
about music,
really what we're talking about as
recorded music and recorded music in
modern times has really only been since
the late 20th century.
Right?
I mean when did people,
or the early 20th century rather,
when did people first start recording
music?
We've gone over this before.
They started doing it on wax and like
the 17 hundreds is that what it was?
Something along those lines?
I don't think it was that long.
I think it was in the early 19 hundreds
what's what's,
find out.
Let's see if he's going to set us and
add those wax cylinders that they were
recording talking and a little bit of
orchestra stuff on those.
Like right.
Those,
those,
you just pull that out of here?
No,
we've,
we've actually discussed this.
Yeah.
But yeah,
we were just one of your favorite
topics.
No,
we have discussed it like fairly
recently.
Within the last year we were talking
about how amazing it is that recording
things like,
like Mozart or Beethoven,
like there was no recording reading work
and you know,
people would duplicate that written work
and that's how you would get to see the
genius of their ideas here at 1877 oh
wow.
Okay.
That's a practical sign recording.
Yeah.
But when you compare that to like a
record,
a modern,
I mean we call it a record,
but I mean a recording,
a modern recording like blondie,
like rapture or something like that.
I mean that is this,
there's never been anything like that in
human history up until the 19th or the
20th century.
I mean it really didn't exist.
No.
So when you think about like pop stars,
you know,
I mean at a May or however far can you
can go back to where you can
legitimately say someone was a popular
music star.
It is so recent.
It's within a hundred years.
Like Elvis,
I think it was the first popular star.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
That's why I went fucking crazy.
He's no,
no roadmap.
Yeah,
well none of them had road maps.
That's what we forget.
Like we were talking about this recently
with a bunch of friends is highly
accomplished.
Young musicians are right now,
like if they can be 15 years old and you
can watch them perform and they've got
all the moves and they can sing
perfectly because they've practiced
singing along on youtube too,
you know,
digitally enhanced recordings so they
can do stuff with their voice that we
never could,
you know.
And so they're learning at an
accelerated rate.
Yeah.
But they don't understand what it means
to have any kind of motivation or like
have any authentic taste or you know,
it's really peculiar.
They don't have a struggle yet.
They're like terminators.
No,
you know,
they're,
they're perfect but they don't have any
no inside.
They,
well I'm sure they do have an inside to
develop to 15 no one.
You can abort that up.
Who is like,
it's just off the charts.
But it's true.
It's insane.
Like it is.
They can sing along to these mat records
that have been old sort of,
you know,
auto,
auto autotune this,
that,
the next thing.
And they can sing it.
Perfect.
Well,
I was reading about this 24 year old
motivational speaker and a,
I was like,
I want to go find that person.
Tell them to shut the fuck up.
Hi.
Couldn't what do you 24 yeah.
What do you know?
What do you know at 24 you got a nine I
think at 50 tell people about life at 24
that's preposterous.
Yeah,
it's preposterous.
It's like my friend Steve Maxwell says,
he said you should never listen to
anyone who is under 40 who is a personal
trainer.
He's a personal trainer.
He's like anyone who is under 40 was a
personal trainer is and what the fuck do
they know about injuries?
You yeah,
doing the running the long haul.
Yeah.
There's a lot to learn.
There's a lot.
There is I,
I am amazed.
I continue.
I thought I had also state by 30 I mean
I remember thinking I'm so old and I'm
so wise.
I mean I remember thinking that and then
you hit 50 and you're like,
oh my God,
I knew nothing.
Yeah.
And then you probably think that when
you're 70 my.claims.
That's the case.
He laughs at me and my dad laughs at me
when I,
you know,
say something that he thinks it's
absolutely ludicrous,
you know?
And he's like,
just you wait,
just wait.
You'll,
you'll eat those words,
you know?
Well,
I feel like that's a big part of what
you see today in social media with young
kids espousing really preposterous
ideas.
Just like there's so they have so little
experience,
actual life experience or them.
Yeah.
I feel sad
for all these like young hipsters that
get lauded by,
you know,
fashion magazines at literally at the
age of 15.
I think it's the fetishizing of young
people right now really gives me the
creeps and I feel very sad for these
young people who basically get,
are like these beautiful butterflies and
uh,
you know,
a glass jar gets shoved on top of them
and then they're stuck.
They're being cool and hip,
but not with no driver,
no,
no nothing to fight against,
nothing to be dissatisfied with.
I don't know,
it's just peculiar.
I think they're doing adderall and
having a great old time,
so I'm sure.
Oh,
so just because you made a bunch of
fucking hit records,
you think,
tell me how to live my life.
I live in this God damn glass jar.
Never for one moment would ever tell
somebody how to live their life.
What I don't like seeing is people not
being allowed to live their lives.
Oh,
I saw this kid,
somebody sent me this thing on twitter
at some kid,
I forget where it was,
some pop festival,
but he's like 12 years old playing the
guitar and he's fucking incredible.
I mean,
incredible.
And they were like saying he's the next
Jimmy Hendrix,
some little black kid.
It was amazing.
Like just like,
just unbelievably talented and I'm just
like,
boy,
he's checking with him 10 years.
He'll be fucking crazy.
That's what it feels like to me.
It's creepy.
It's like so many people send me,
you know,
uh,
recordings of young,
particularly young women,
um,
artists and they're like,
you know,
would you think about,
supporting this girl or what do you
think of this and that [inaudible] life,
right?
I think go like living your life.
Don't let your parents figured out your
career for you,
and that's what you're supposed to do.
You're not supposed to have your parents
who happens to have an end with a well
known singer or producer,
whatever,
pump pimping you,
you know,
that's,
that's how you learn is by actually
doing it yourself.
I don't know.
I just feel it's creepy and it feels
pedophilic to me and I don't like it.
It definitely can be right.
But when you were young,
when did you know that you wanted to be
a singer?
I don't think I ever knew I wanted to be
a singer and wants to be yes,
but fairly recently.
I mean,
literally in the last time I've seen and
the last 10 years,
I was like,
I'm really good at this actually.
And I enjoy it and I guess this is what
I do for a living.
This is my thing.
The last time,
the last 10 years,
I'm not going on with you.
Like when stupid girl was coming out.
Well,
I felt like I'd stumbled into that
opportunity,
which I did.
Um,
I wanted to be,
first of all,
I wanted to be a writer,
then I wanted to be an actress.
And then by total default I was in a
youth theater when I was young and I met
this guy and he was like,
oh,
would you come and play keyboards in my
band for a weekend because we've lost
our keyboard player.
And I joined the band and then I just
ended up being in that band for 10 years
playing keyboards and doing backup
vocals.
I was quite happy.
I didn't have,
I didn't harbor any ambition to be a
lead singer at all.
And then just 1,000,000,001 things
happened and I ended up being the lead
singer of this betty seen band just so
that we could survive cause we'd been
dropped by our record label for going to
Berlin and spending all our money on our
record advance on drugs coming back and
not have anything to show for it.
So the record company dropped us but
kept me.
And so then I pulled the band in as my
band.
So we just sort of shifted all the
rules.
Oh Wow.
By myself as the lead singer by default
and then our videos on drugs.
Oh,
it was mostly speed and ecstasy.
Speed.
How much money you're spending on speed.
Jesus Christ.
It was,
I was in the northern,
that might money that it was our entire
record events.
How much was it?
I can't remember.
I think it was something like a hundred
thousand pounds.
What does that like $50,000 thing
American,
somewhere on that.
I think it's double that.
Double the oats.
200,000 a stumble.
Oh,
I'm doing it the opposite.
Oh my God dude.
I told him no,
I don't know how we did it.
I mean it wasn't all on speed and it was
all Kahal and you know,
going and drink,
you know,
drinking and partying and just wasting
time.
And you have in America,
we call that going off.
We,
we went off,
you guys went off.
We went totally off too.
And I wasn't one of the,
the reason I was one of the sober ones
for the most part.
I mean,
you know,
and I know I did my share,
but by comparison I kept my shit
together.
But,
and we,
we,
we used to dark opportunity there,
but by default I became a lead singer.
Our video got played on mtv and then I
just chanced upon garbage.
The garbage boys needed a singer and I
got hired and,
and so I always felt I just fumbled into
it by going off,
so to speak.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
it was,
it was pretty mad.
And then I never believed in myself for
my whole first half of my,
I call the first phase of garbage.
Wow.
You know,
that's a really common thing that we
were just talking about this the other
day with somebody,
I forget who it was,
whether they were saying that so many
really talented people feel
illegitimate.
They've felt like they're not
legitimate.
Yeah.
Are they filming?
Everybody feels like,
I don't think it's even the artist.
I think it's everybody,
you know who won't pay it and it sits
there and goes,
yeah,
I'm my parent.
Yeah.
I know how to parent my children and
yeah,
I know how to pay the bills and get the
work done and keep the high school.
Nobody knows how to do anything.
Wow.
Well you definitely do question yourself
all the time.
Yeah.
Like you'll do your kids.
Well,
I have a,
I have three.
I have one that's 20.
I have one that's almost nine and one
that's almost eight.
Wow.
Yeah.
Or almost seven rather.
And I was hanging out all day with the
almost seven yesterday.
And uh,
you know,
we're just having a great old time.
Like we have days we split up where I
just hang out with one kid and my wife
will hang out with one kid because I
think sometimes when you get the two of
them together,
the young ones,
they don't get enough attention,
especially the little one suffers a
little bit.
So we have like specific days where it's
just,
and so the entire time we're trying to
have a good time,
we're having fun,
but I'm also thinking,
okay,
I've got to like figure we're kind of,
I'm kind of programming are here as this
go.
So every question I have to kind of
temper this question,
you have to think that these people
probably don't know any better.
So that's probably why they litter,
you know?
And see it like she gets mad when she
sees people throw cigarettes out the
window.
I saw a guy throw a cigarette out the
Did you see that Daddy?
He threw a cigarette out the window and
I'm like,
well,
it's definitely not good to throw
cigarettes out the window,
but you have to think like this poor
person.
Like what kind of a mind do they have
like this?
This the way their brain works.
They think it's okay.
They're not worried.
Like if I drop something on the ground,
I pick it up.
Do you pick it up?
She's like,
I always pick it up.
I go,
yeah,
we pick things up,
right?
We don't want to litter because if
everybody livered we would never be able
to get anywhere.
Just be garbage everywhere.
Stressful.
Being a parent,
it's stressful,
but when toward is theirs,
it's really,
you don't have kids.
I do.
It's very hard to describe to someone
the love that you experienced between
you and this little tiny person like me
and the six,
almost seven when when we talk like,
and she just jumps on me and hugs me,
like my whole body has this reaction,
like the love meter.
It's like,
you know a carnival thing where you hit
the thing on the bottom and the bell
goes Ding.
You know,
like the,
the,
the metal sudden shoots up and hits the
bell.
It hits the bell every time.
Whenever she gives me this big hug,
it's like I can't,
you can't love anybody anymore.
Of course the love that I have for hers,
it's Cray.
It's weird.
It's scary because you're worried about
losing them.
fucking it up.
It's scary because just because it's so
powerful,
really powerful changes you.
It changes who you are.
I mean it's just a hundred percent
changed me.
Just made me a different completely
different person and it does every day,
every day.
I'm a different person than I was like a
week ago and I talked to a lot of are
other my friends that have kids and it's
the same thing like the,
it changes your level of compassion,
the changes who you like.
Dave Chappelle said it best to me.
He said it didn't just change my how
much I love,
it changed my capacity for love.
And I was like,
that's it.
I think you nailed it.
I mean I had a tiny,
I have a tiny window into it cause my
sister,
my younger sister had two children and I
felt towards her children differently
than I do any other child.
So that's just a small window into how I
imagine it is for her with her children.
And we talk about this a lot.
I'm like,
I just don't think I could handle that.
It would be too,
I'm to sent to,
I'm to hypersensitive to,
I think take the responsibility on of
being a parent.
Yes.
I think though,
but you would,
it changes you.
Like you become more wherever you are
now once if a little person comes out of
your body,
you just,
you're like,
okay,
now I'm surely with a person.
There's like chapter two,
you know,
are surely 2.0 or whatever it is.
Yeah,
I'm sure it changes how you view
yourself and your function on Erath I
would imagine
it does.
It does.
And it also makes you appreciate like
my,
my time is fairly,
um,
it's flexible in terms of like I can
manipulate my time,
I can kind of choose what I do.
Like I don't really have to do anything.
I choose to do a lot of different
things,
but that do have
to do things like,
especially couples where both work and
they work long hours.
That's incredibly hard to raise
children.
I mean,
you see how tired they're too,
when they come home from a nine,
10 hour day and their kid has been in
daycare and the kid just can't wait to
see them.
And then you,
you literally only have an hour with
them before they go to bed.
Like you're not even raising them.
Relationship was like,
that was my dad's like when my mum died
a few years ago,
my dad came over here to Los Angeles to,
to stay with us and we went out for
lunch and I'm sitting across from my
dad,
I'm 45 years old and I'm thinking to
myself,
I have never sat alone with you in a
restaurant in my life ever.
And it was really weird.
Wow.
Because my dad worked hard,
you know,
and he was always busy and yeah,
it was,
it was an intense realization.
So it's,
I think it's great that you take time
one on one with your kids.
Cause I didn't have that with my dad.
I didn't have that either.
I try to,
well,
I mean,
I'm sure they're going to learn
something that I fuck up that they're
not going to do.
You just have to accept you're gonna
fuck up.
Just don't try to fuck up.
Don't try to try to do your best.
But I just,
sometimes the things that you do in
inverted commas get right are the things
that do I think the most damage and
sometimes the things that you do wrong.
The so called big mistakes can also be
really good for children.
And I'm not talking about when they're,
at no point should a child ever be hurt
in any way.
You know?
I'm not saying that's a good thing,
that that's a terrible thing and that
must never happen.
But I mean like,
you know,
I know a lot parents who sort of really
get down on themselves because the
divorce for a random example,
and I have seen children bloom through
divorce,
you know,
and I keep saying that some that to my,
some of my friends who are going through
that,
it's like you're not,
you're not making a big mistake.
You're teaching them to not settle and
this good things that can come from bad
things.
I guess it's what I'm trying to see.
Yeah,
no,
for sure.
My parents split up when I was five and
it was a very good thing and it,
it taught me that my mom was strong for
leaving my dad and that like you have to
make tough choices and then things are
going to suck for a while,
but there's a reason for it.
But you know,
pressure makes diamonds just,
I mean you said a much more articulately
than I did,
but we're getting to the same police I
guess.
Yeah,
well it's a really uncomfortable moment
that I have with a lot of my friends
that have children too because we sit
around and we think about it.
We say,
well,
you know what,
you try to protect your kids as much as
possible,
but everybody that we know that's
interesting came from a fucked up
background.
Like all of my friends had fucked up
childhoods.
Yeah,
all of them.
All my artistic friends,
all my friends that are musicians,
all my friends that are Comedians,
they just fucking came from chaos and
they emerged from this rubble.
Is this like this person with a purpose?
Absolutely.
But see,
I've,
I've gone quiet and I've gone quiet
because it's getting back to the,
the,
the moment that I have are the feeling I
have in myself that I am an inauthentic
artists.
Cause I didn't come from a fucked up
background.
All my friends,
every single one of my friends when I
was growing up from the age of five
onwards,
they came from broken homes.
Every single one maybe you learn from
them is set.
And I don't know.
But I came from a really happy family.
My mum would have penny.
She baked every day.
What's a penny?
A penny,
you know,
an apron.
Oh,
can I go?
I'm wearing right now.
But um,
yeah,
she bought a,
uh,
an apron.
She baked every single day.
She like warmed our clothes on the stove
before we went to school.
She cooked us dinner every single night.
They would always at home.
They were always there.
They loved us.
They know we're never cruel.
I mean,
I came from the most abnormal,
normal family ever.
And it's always made me think,
well that means that I'm not,
I'm just not,
not legit test.
I'm not so crazy.
Yeah,
I got fucked up anyway.
but it's not a,
it's not mandatory.
Like it's,
it,
it certainly happens a lot of the time,
but it can be mandatory all the time,
but I just don't,
uh,
yeah,
I like,
I,
I always sort of feel,
and this is really sick of mild envy,
when I hear my friends talk about,
you know,
they're fucked up upbringings cause I'm
like,
God,
I'm so normal.
I used to feel that way about people who
are drug addicts.
What do you mean?
I used to feel that way because all the
greats,
the were drug out of Richard Pryor,
Kennison Bill Hicks,
they were all drug addicts.
Yeah.
They're all had like huge cocaine
problems and they,
you know,
Hicks was the only one that got through
it.
But then he wound up not dying of
cancer.
You know,
who knows?
Maybe because of that.
But you know,
Kennison was a cocaine.
He kind says who's he?
You don't know Sam Kennison?
No,
I've never even heard of him.
Really?
Wow.
He's Mount Rushmore for sure.
He might be the greatest.
Well,
I think Richard Pryor was the greatest,
but he's surprised he's right up there.
Kinnisons like number two in my book.
I think that not heard of this person.
I don't know.
I don't know how easily it was a fast
break.
You never,
you never seen him and recognize him.
Oh my God.
This is like pull up
Sam Kinison uh,
homosexual necrophilia acts.
He did this pet,
this is a,
this bit was it?
This is a bit that got explained to me
by a girl that I used to work with.
This is a bit,
I found out about this as par.
Pause for a second.
I worked at a,
um,
this is one of the reasons why I got
into standup comedy.
I worked at an athletic club in South
Boston.
It's called the Boston athletic club and
I worked with this girl.
She was hilarious.
She was a volleyball player,
big giant girl.
She was like five,
11.
Big Athletic,
big personality,
easy,
easy.
She's hilarious.
But what I'm saying is she told me
about,
you've got to see this community of the
Holy Shit.
Was He funny?
She saw him on Hbo and so she starts
doing this bitch.
She's like,
she takes me out to the parking lot and
she's doing this bit about,
there's a real news story about these
homosexual necrophilia acts would pay
these morgues to spend a few hours
undisturbed but the freshest male
corpses,
so play a bit.
He played the bit,
we'll play the video [inaudible] paper.
They said okay.
That a group of homosexual necrophilia
acts and going around the mortuaries
offering them money,
let them come in at night.
She's been a couple hours undisturbed
with the fresh Ishmael quarter.
It wasn't trying to shell.
This is a fucking home game.
All right.
It's a story I read folks.
Jesus Christ,
give me a chance to do some journalistic
reporting here.
Well,
yeah,
I felt the same way.
I read this thing and what else?
Ah,
thanks for that batch.
I had to have five of these corpses,
man.
I mean you think death would be bad
enough when,
yeah.
The one thing that scares the shit out
of everybody is dead.
You don't want to think about it.
You don't joke about it.
You pull it out of your mind,
but you figure if you faced it,
that's it.
What can be worse than Fucking Dad?
He'd bring,
I got bashed.
Dad hated up.
She lived through it.
You know,
you got to buy it on shit.
I that's try.
But he's courses because I know these
guys were laying out on slabs.
They're,
and they're going well,
it was tough.
And uh,
well that was pretty hard to live up to
with the,
I have half page death and I'm glad I
went through it and,
uh,
well I'm just,
I'm ready to spend eternity in heaven
and be with Jesus and Ragab age.
Hey.
Oh,
I don't believe
so.
This girl,
she laid down in the parking lot and she
was gone.
He'd be alive.
Cube's fuck in this.
Even after you're dead.
And I'm crying,
laughing.
I was crying and I was like,
oh,
I got to see this.
And so I think I got it from a video
store,
I think it was back when you would rent
it from a vhs cassette.
And that's how I found out about Sam
kinison.
And that's one of the reasons why I got
into standup comedy because I didn't
know that common he was ever like that.
I thought comedy was a guy who just
stood in front of the microphone and
said,
did you ever notice that kind of stuff.
So what was,
what does well is being a comedian to
you mean?
No.
Oh it's a bunch of different
possibilities,
but it was so chaotic.
Like his,
his comedy was so wild and crazy.
Like there was,
he was a real ground breaker in that
way.
And why else did you get into being a
comedian?
I Dunno.
I got talking to,
you know,
I wasn't really very funny.
I wasn't teaching any siblings.
One sister.
Yeah.
So it's just you and your mom and
your sister?
Yeah,
well my mom remarried my Stepdad who
she's still with it.
And do you like him?
Yeah,
he's great guy.
Okay.
Yeah,
super lucky.
He's a real good guy.
Okay,
good.
But um,
it was uh,
I got talked into doing stand up by my
friends from martial arts
for real,
cause we would,
well you must've been funny.
Well,
I was only funny,
but I was glad gallows humor we would go
to compete like,
like,
or we would be about to spar and I would
be,
the guy would make everybody laugh
because everybody was so nervous because
it was scary.
You beat the shit out of each other,
you know?
And then we would go to these
competitions so he'd get on a bus and
travel across the country to go fight in
these tournaments.
And it was super nerve wracking.
Everyone was super nervous so you could
cut the tension with a knife.
So I would always like be doing
impressions of people having sex and
making jokes.
And just,
this was like long before ever thought
about being comedian.
I was just trying to lighten up the
mood.
Wow.
And that's how I got into stand up.
So hold on a minute.
So see,
this is a bit of a surprise to me
because when people fight,
you know,
semi professionally or otherwise,
or at school or what have you,
it's nerve wracking.
No,
it's terrifying because you're scared of
pain,
violence,
the anticipation of the possibility of
losing.
You're worried about the just all the
possibilities,
the,
there's just a full realm of things.
Why do you do it?
I know I'm sounding like a mortar on,
I just have never had the opportunity to
ask anyone who's ever done this.
Um,
I was very insecure and um,
I got bullied and I wasn't big.
I was a small kid and I was really
nervous and I did not like that feeling
at all.
And I,
I was always,
we were always moving around a lot.
We was moved to new places.
I was always the new kid.
No,
my,
my mom married my Stepdad.
We moved across the country from New
Jersey to San Francisco and then we
lived there for a while and then we
moved to Florida and then we moved to
Boston and he,
he switched careers and he was a
computer programmer and then we became
an architect.
And so there's a lot of work.
Yeah,
there's a lot of traveling and I just
was always the new kid in the new kid
gets fucked boys.
Yeah.
And most of the time was fine,
but as we started getting older,
that's when it got creepy.
Like most of the time it was no big
deal.
Like at nine and 10 it's no big deal,
but when it gets to be like 13 and 14
then it starts getting violent.
And so like kids would pick on me and I
didn't know how to fight.
And it drove me crazy.
Like I was like,
God,
I fucking,
I hate the fact that when these kids
want to fight me,
I don't know what to do and I'm,
I'm terrified.
So I'd be like,
go,
go home the long way around.
So I'd avoid everybody and that kind of
shit.
So I decided to learn martial arts.
I said,
well,
what am I afraid of?
I'm afraid of people that know how to
fight.
Well I'll,
I'm going to really know how to fight.
So I went into it.
Then it became my whole life,
like from,
from high school,
freshman year on really from 15 is when
I went crazy.
So from 15 on a,
that's all I did every day,
like six,
seven days a week.
I was teaching,
I was,
I,
I became a,
I was in,
I was teaching when I was 17,
I was a,
that's what I was doing.
Like every day I was teaching at Boston
University when I was 18 and 19.
And I was,
became my whole life.
Born in Boston.
No,
I was born in New Jersey.
I come,
you don't have the crazy accident.
Got Rid of it.
Hurt myself on TV.
I won the bay state games.
It was this big,
uh,
like an Olympic festival,
whether they had all the Olympic sports
and was,
taekwondo had not been in the Olympics
yet,
but it was about to be,
so they had it in the bay state games
and I won.
So they interviewed me on TV and I
remember Tom,
he was like very specifically say we
were working really hard.
And I was like,
oh,
I heard that accent.
It was so bad.
I heard the video and I was like,
oh my God,
what the Fuck is wrong with me?
Like I had taken on that accent out of
insecurity because I'd only lived there
since I was 13.
Right.
So from 13 to 19 and six years I
developed a stupid accent.
I fall,
wanted to finish it.
Yeah.
And then I realized I'd done it once so
I abandoned that.
But it will come out a little bit if I
get drunk like every now and then some
words because he didn't grow up in it.
Yeah,
of course it's gross when you hear
another girl.
In fact
it's just like,
it's like too many Ar.
The ar thing that stretches out.
Although the ice didn't speak like that.
No,
I wish as beautiful.
I like that accent is pretty,
there's something about the Boston
accent,
it's just particularly gross,
so please don't worry about it.
You are fighting.
And then your pile talked you into
becoming my friend Steve Graham to my
friends ed shorter and Steve Graham,
Steve Graham,
still one of my best friends today.
He was an ophthalmologist at the time
and still encourage you to walk.
Go to you told me I should be a comedian
of class or like literally grabbed me by
my shoulders and said you should be a
comedian.
So then what happened?
I went to an open mic night,
I watched a amateurs try it.
And one of the good things about
amateurs is,
uh,
if you go to watch,
like most of them don't know what
they're doing,
they're terrible.
So I was like,
okay,
well I can't be as,
you know,
at least I'm not going to be the only
one who sucks.
So like if,
if I go up and do that,
I can do what they're doing.
They suck.
I suck too,
but they suck.
So it's not like you're going up and
Richard Pryor's on Richard,
Jenny and all this,
you could take the competition.
Well,
no,
I felt like I wouldn't be the only one
who sucked.
Like people who really suck inspire you
to do it because they'll,
they lower the bar of expectations.
Cause like if I went up there and it was
all these really amazing comedians and
then to me,
I'd be like,
oh,
I can't do this.
I said,
I'm fucking terrible at it because the
learning curve of standup comedy is so
long.
And especially when you're 21 you don't
know shit.
I didn't know anything about life or
anything.
Well,
of course he didn't.
Exactly.
Yeah.
So I
was terrible.
But somehow or another,
these guys talked me into doing it.
So do you still do your stand up?
Yeah.
Constantly.
That's great.
Yeah.
You turn it around on me.
Sure.
Unless you're dead.
Yeah,
he does.
Clever girl
didn't know about that.
At worst you don't,
you don't think you're clever?
I don't think particularly clever.
I can think fast on my feet that makes
clever.
But I have serious attention deficit
disorder.
Yeah.
See,
I hear that a lot from people.
I usually think that what that means is
you really enjoy certain things so much
that other things suck for you and you
just get distracted.
I bet.
I bet you don't have an attention
deficit disorder when you're singing
your songs.
No,
of course not.
But that again is not a material you'll
have to retrieve.
It's just stuff in there.
You open your mouth,
it comes out.
Right.
But do you think that it's possible that
you achieve these high frequencies of
delight and of stimulation when you're
performing and when you're,
I mean,
you got to think that when you're
onstage,
like what's the biggest crowd you've
ever performed for this?
Sounds like I'm making up.
I don't,
I can hardly believe it,
but we played in front of 300,000 people
in some out of Russia and that was the
trippiest expedia
at the time.
It was the biggest music festival that
I'd ever been
like,
you couldn't see the end of the crowd.
Now I look at Glastonbury and go small.
You know how it goes.
So think of that.
Think of that experience and how many
people are ever going to feel that.
How many ever people,
people are ever going to rock out in
front of 300,000 people?
So I think that some people,
they're the,
the moments of brilliance that there's
moments of spectacular experience that
they have are so different than most
people's lives.
Most people disagree 100% because I know
that people's capacity for joy,
that it's a certain expedience that we
all have.
Like I can go out to dinner and if
you're having a really great meal and
you're with people that you love and are
really,
and you are laughing yourself sick.
I have the same feelings as I do when
I'm having a good shore.
I don't think it like,
it's not like my career is the highlight
of my life.
It's,
it's a joyous part of my life that plays
a rule in,
in my enjoyment of being on earth.
That sounds very balanced,
but I'm,
I'm not saying that doesn't.
So I think my point being is the,
I just think if you enjoy your job,
if you love your wife,
if you have great sex with your
boyfriend or your girlfriend,
if you have a baby,
you know that moment when they put the
baby in arms,
you know exactly
what it's like to play in front of
300,000 people,
you know?
No,
I don't think that's correct.
That is correct.
You're the only one to be able to tell
us though.
I'm telling you,
you must take it from an authority.
There's no denier.
You argue with,
again,
what I was going to say though is that
your experience in the intensity is so
high that your capacity to appreciate
boring shit is probably very low and
that's one of the reasons why people
would lay label it.
Like attention deficit.
You probably just don't want to pay
attention to shit that,
that you're not passionate about was the
case.
But there is moments when somebody is
telling me something and I'm thinking to
myself,
okay,
remember this cause this is important
and or this is really cool.
You could use it all the time.
I'm going to hold us information,
hold this fact,
hold this.
And then I try and tell somebody 24
hours later,
but this incredible story I was told and
I can't remember it.
That's called being a person.
Insane.
Yeah,
but you haven't slipped away at all
during this conversation.
No,
I'm intense.
You've been locked on.
I'm intense and I am a week.
You are or what you're woke.
I hear that.
And fucking expression.
One more time.
I might hit the next person might that
comes like,
oh,
that is an expression that never had its
day.
Oh
yes.
Joke from the moment I first came out
with fools.
Fools.
No,
no,
like person that I know.
Like ever said that word without being
in just joking.
No.
Well hang out with a lot of comedians.
Well they're fast and quick and funny.
They think it's ridiculous job as a
comedian to take the piss out of all us.
Norm norms.
That is one thing that I love that you
guys say.
Take the piss.
That is a great expression.
Scotland has some incredible like
incredible expressions and sort of the
most,
one of the best things that happened to
me lately was I got retweeted by William
Gibson
and he retweeted a Scottish,
a link that I'd done on,
or I'd done for the nme on Scottish
Sweden and the fact that he had re
posted my tutorial on Scottish sweating
and need my fucking life.
Call me side if you want.
But it was like the most glorious moment
of my career.
That's what I've sat at all.
There's nothing,
but yeah,
the scots are really funny.
You know,
it's a small culture because it's bad
weather.
I mean these are stupefying uh,
so cliches I'm spewing here,
but because it's a small country,
because it's bad weather because we
spend a lot of time talking to one
another,
passing one another in the street.
There's a lot of humor in America I find
is not quite as acute.
You know,
people are used to verbally spotting in
Scotland because you know,
against people all the time,
pushing past them in shops,
you know,
traveling and the tube,
being on the bus,
blah,
blah.
Whereas in America,
everything's more spread out and you're
not around people so much.
So when you are in face to face with
them,
people are a little more polite.
And Scotland,
there is absolutely no politeness.
We got shoved their big comedy festival
there every year.
The fridge.
Yeah.
Have you been there yet
to Ari?
Shaffir raves about it,
but that mother fucker goes everywhere.
He's crazy.
You should go there.
It's incredible.
It's an incredible circuit for funny men
like yourself.
You guys have billy connolly,
he's hilarious.
He kept calling me is great and hi
ladies.
Hi.
Hilarious.
Yeah.
Well not well though.
Really decide degenerative disease,
sadly.
Oh No.
What is it?
We're going to lose him soon I think.
Really?
What is it?
I think it's target
or or dementia.
I can't remember if it's one on one of
the two.
Anyway,
he's a brilliant mind.
Funny,
funny man.
But uh,
you should get your ass over there.
They would love you done bad weather
thing.
I think that's why Boston has so many
funny comedians.
I'm sure it does.
I'm serious.
I'm not,
I mean it is a ridiculous cliche,
but for sure it plays a small part and
it's not cliche at all.
100%.
Yeah.
I mean they've been Boston,
the same thing.
A lot of bad weather,
a lot of cold snow people indoors,
people the long winters.
I guess that's true.
No tolerance for stupid shit.
No tolerance.
Also work ethic,
like hard work ethic.
They're very hard.
You had no tolerance for meandering
bullshit.
No,
it's very different.
It's a different way of thinking
certainly than Los Angeles and my
expedience or soft out here,
push heart are very polite and they are
soft for one of a better term.
It's like I find that sometimes when I
make jokes people don't know how to flip
it back.
You know like it's going to be buddies
joking all the time and it's really fast
sort of dialogue.
People panic,
panic and they,
they're scared they're going to offend
you and say the wrong thing and
sometimes I have to go on double dates
with my wife and sometimes I'll crack a
joke and the whole table would be like,
what?
Yeah,
that's meeting.
I think all of us go home in the car.
I'll say to my husband,
I'm really sorry if I embarrassed you.
And he says he's always got this
classic.
He went and he didn't embarrass me.
You only embarrass yourself
serious or joking?
Kind of half and half.
I mean it's definitely,
we both know when I've said something
mildly inappropriate.
Do you feel like you're like because
you're from Scotland that you have like
to temper that all the time?
I do.
Try and temper it a lot,
but sometimes I forget,
you know,
and then there's the crickets.
Oh my God,
I'm might,
my poor husband who's fairly,
very assertive,
quiet,
like he's very quiet and he thinks a lot
before he speaks.
And,
uh,
I can just see him in his mind and he
loves me and he doesn't,
it doesn't bother him until he did.
He doesn't get embarrassed,
but he to,
hey,
you can see them guard thing,
his loins,
you know,
like God,
did she just say that was a good thing
as lawyers
dig as lawyers guard.
Dang.
I didn't even know what that means.
Gert thing.
What does curtin good clip bitch.
I think he,
the first person on this podcast ever
say to me,
oh,
that's hilarious.
Good thing.
How do you spell it?
Gerd.
Jimmy.
You never heard that before?
Have you?
As the first time,
I'm all my years.
I've heard girding girding your loins.
I would imagine be clenching.
Yes.
I just context put it together.
Occurred here you go and circle a with a
belt or a band.
The young woman,
a young man was a,
wants to be girded with a belt of
knighthood.
Oh,
okay.
Make Your Cup Scottish.
Hmm.
What makes sense?
Girding you're talking about
constricting.
Girding gird your loins,
get ready or gear up
your loins.
Wow,
that's a good one.
I'm here learning on this show.
This is a,
this is a show of it.
There's plenty more where that goes.
So are you fired up about this tour?
You excited about this?
Of course.
Yeah.
My God.
I love,
I love playing.
I mean,
I'm sure that as a certain kind of high
you get when you go off in the road and
you can stop worrying about bills.
You stop worrying about money,
stop worrying about,
you know,
the pain in your ankle.
You,
you know,
you just have no worries.
You just go on the tour bus and you get
bust for me to be,
you get a little email every day that
tells you exactly what you're doing.
You know,
at noon to a core manager,
there's the handles all your manager.
Yes.
Oh that's nice.
So,
um,
I love going on tour and it's an honor
to be playing with blondie and uh,
the fans are very excited.
And how many days do you go for it?
I think it's about seven weeks,
although,
which is a small tutor for us.
That was a long time.
We normally go out for a year.
A year.
A year,
yeah.
One off,
you know,
I mean you come home for bits,
but generally it's a sort of a year long
thing.
And it used to be two years,
but then the music industry got crushed
by music.
Final shading.
Yes.
So it's a slightly different game
though.
But isn't the touring business the same
or how does that work?
Well,
yes and no.
I mean the problem with a tutoring
business know is that it's the only way
a musician can make money.
Right.
So no,
the competition to score venues in which
you can play or it's getting higher and
higher and higher.
So I noticed that as a community really
difficult is a huge issue.
Like I have to book stuff like a year in
advance advance.
Yeah.
Edinburgh festival next year.
Come on,
you'll love it.
You'll learn all kinds of phrases that
you can employ in your stand up and ever
used in America.
Lots of original material.
Hmm.
So you guys though,
you were in the business when the money
was being made and then it was like,
what is it around like 2000 when the
floor dropped out,
the floor was beginning to drill pipe
and then 2001 came around and September,
September.
That was,
yeah,
that was the beginning of the end.
Yeah.
Did you see the writing on the wall?
Did you think they were going to be able
to,
I told her whole,
I totally saw the writing on the wall.
Actually rule a boater.
I at the time I run our blog,
a music blog,
which was,
you know,
one of the first,
back then,
because musicians didn't have blogs,
we didn't really use computers up to
that point.
So I had this blog and I was very vocal
about napster and I,
uh,
I was,
I could foresee the issues that,
you know,
that presented themselves,
but the industry itself was still
greedy.
It refused to adapt.
You know,
and as long as he could have died,
I don't know.
That's not my place to,
what about it really?
But,
um,
they just continued to want to make
money via cds and physical seals and the
refused sort of to make the kind of
deals that they really needed to,
and digital deals.
Yeah.
While before people started selling
things on itunes and what have you,
but there wasn't really a,
a venue for it before that they would
have had to create,
like they would have had to create it,
but the real,
the only ones who had the power and the
financial resources to do so,
you know,
so,
and,
and as a result,
now of course they're the only ones we
can money or any of the companies,
the record companies continue to make
vast amounts of money off artists,
youtube mix vast amounts of money off
artists.
And the artist makes nothing.
I don't think the general public are
fully aware of what a crime spree is.
Crime,
crime spree.
It's a crime spree.
But who's,
who's committing the crimes while
they're tiny crimes committed against
each artist,
that,
that con that compiles a vast library of
digital content that through which
massive companies conglomerates make
money from by just sheer mass.
But the artists themselves mixed,
you know,
less than a penny a pop less than a
penny a pop,
you know.
So I'll give you guys like,
I bought your albums on itunes.
Well we had a bad example too because we
are our own record label at this point.
You are your own records.
So when a bad example,
we're one of the lucky ones and when did
you figure this out by a lot of getting
fucked up.
They are.
So you know,
no lube was used and you know,
yeah,
we,
we are,
we were around long enough that at some
of our masters are very good to us and
so we could make really lucrative deals
for ourselves and protect our catalog
and you know,
it's blah,
blah blah.
It's so boring.
But boring is fascinating for young
artists.
I don't know,
I despair.
It's like,
you know,
you're,
you're hooked up to a record label.
The record label makes money by your
records getting plead on Youtube for an
example.
You don't,
not really,
I mean it's like a 0.0375 percentage of
a penny that you might get played after
by a thousand million plays on youtube.
I mean this,
it's bizarre,
but you know,
it's,
it is,
what is the justification for a record
company at this point?
It seems like what with distribution?
Yeah,
but like where are they distributing at
told one of the world,
but to where to what and in what,
in what manner?
In a variety of different manners.
I mean they know do three 60 degrees,
so they take a percentage of absolutely
everything.
A band,
errands,
which was not the case before.
Generally speaking,
the knife.
So up your publishing,
they saw up your performance rates,
they saw what your marriage,
they s any endorsements you get,
you know,
that seems fucked up to me.
It is fucked up.
Doesn't,
it doesn't seem like it's worth it.
Like what do they,
what do they bring to the table?
Just a bunch of people stealing money,
except if you're a massive pop star like
you know,
beyond Sierra Gaga or Kate Patty and a
bieber or what have you,
then that company can use its resources
to make you even bigger.
And that's why these,
these pop stars who continue to make
commercial signed music get bigger and
bigger and bigger and more and more
powerful until they can just buy their
way into the consciousness of the public
culture.
But radio is not much of a thing
anymore.
No,
no,
no.
It's not radio anymore.
But it's visibility.
You have to have visibility.
So what is it that's getting
people visible these days?
Like,
like it used to be a song would be a top
40 hit on the radio and then everybody
would hear about it and you'd want to go
out and buy the record.
Well I think most young people get it on
the web,
right?
But like how does,
but viral music,
like if you release a song and you're
with your label,
it's your own thing and you put it on
youtube and say someone like me comes
along and has a lot of twitter followers
and I say,
this is awesome and I retweet it.
And then a bunch of other people retweet
it.
That's all it takes today,
right?
Yes and no.
I mean,
you have to have a song though that's
easily digestible,
which is why there's so few musicians
now taking real risks because otherwise
if they take a risk,
they don't have a all song,
you know,
that appeals to the masses then.
So you day.
But I'll see what I mean.
I mean,
I'm not articulating myself anywhere.
Kendrick Lamar guy is that guy,
is he independent?
Is he the guy that's independent,
which got chance the rapper chance the
rapper.
He's the guy that's independent and he's
enormous,
right?
Yes.
So how the fuck did he do it?
Well,
there's obviously the always an
exception to the rule and he's
extraordinary.
You know,
he's an extraordinary talent.
And,
and usually when somebody hasn't reached
public consciousness yet,
there's a lot of hype around them.
You know,
people want to be in the know,
they want to talk about the new artists
that everybody doesn't know about so and
so forth.
So they enjoy like a massive swell
and hopefully he'll be able to build
upon that.
But it'll be harder for him the next
time round.
What I'm getting at is,
it is fascinating to me that the record
companies have managed to stay even
remotely relevant because what,
because they made all these deals with
all
these new companies,
but that's the media companies.
That's where it gets really creepy.
Right?
I think it's creepy.
It is creepy.
As someone who's not in the business,
it's creepy because I'm looking at like
what they bring to the table and there's
not a lot,
as I said,
distribution and if you don't,
I know this firsthand because it's very
difficult for us to get to distribute
our music because we don't have a
distribution label that can compete.
Right.
But when you say distribution,
like distributed,
where at are whenever they can.
So whether that's adds on the street,
whether that's ads on the television,
whether it's ads on the radio,
whether it's ads on youtube and so on,
so forth.
It's just an accumulative con like
awareness of an artist.
So they're almost manufacturing like
public interest kind of.
Yeah.
I mean they,
they have to have assemblance of
something good,
you know,
they can't,
you can't,
you can sell shit as it turns out.
But that's again,
the exception to the rule.
Generally speaking,
they'll have a catchy song and they can,
if they push it to enough minds eyes,
they can have a hip.
Wow.
What a weird transition.
They're like vampires.
They figured out how to remain indoors.
Yeah.
This fifth a strange and is kind of sad
really as it,
that's why you are seeing fewer and
fewer artists that have long careers
because like I said,
you can generate a lot of excitement
when it's your first record.
That's sort of the point.
It's easiest when by the time it comes
to your second record.
A lot of these artists that we hear
about are already dead and buried under
1,000,000,001 other new artists.
Yeah,
I'm sure you read that Courtney love
article that she wrote many,
many years ago about the music business,
about how complicated it is,
and this is pre all of this digital
stuff.
She wrote this way back in the day when
she was explaining how these artists get
fucked over by music companies about how
everything gets written off as an
expense.
So by the time they get paid,
everybody else has been paid.
Everybody else is like the,
the record companies made money,
the executives of big money and then the
artists get money and all the expenses
get written off as expenses that the
artists have to pay for.
But you have no control over the
expanding.
So for a random example,
you can turn up at an airport,
you flew in from La to London.
You arrive and there's a limousine
waiting for you and you don't even
question it.
You're like,
oh,
this is the transport,
the record company of scent.
They take you to this ridiculous hotel
that the posture than you've ever been
in your life.
You don't think about it because the
record companies paying for it,
they throw a huge big party.
Wow.
How generous our record companies.
So amazing.
Well,
look at this incredible party and then
charging you for every single thing.
And yet none of it gets run through you
for your approval.
So you have no power over the economic
spending,
but you get charged back.
Absolutely.
Every single expenditure.
Not only that,
the salaries of the people that run
these companies,
all of that is dependent upon you
selling your art.
That's right.
And
when things are going well,
everyone's,
they're going well,
then we do an amazing job.
You know,
worship me.
You're going to literally everyone in
the record companies like you owe us a
thank you and aren't we amazing?
And then we talk to,
you know,
be the,
it's an inference.
Like,
yeah,
I did that.
We did this look,
oh,
what a great job we did for you and your
band.
And you're like,
yeah,
great.
Thank you so much.
So it's wonderful.
And then the second something goes wrong
is you're on your own.
You guys need to figure this out.
We're just your record label.
We can't,
you know what I mean?
It's just like,
it's,
it's difficult to deal with,
uh,
first,
but then you get used to it.
Now,
in the early days,
did they take a piece of your tour?
No.
No,
they never have with us,
but they do know with young bands,
this is called a three 60 deal where
they take how much they take.
I don't know.
It's different for every band.
Every single band has to negotiate.
So instance,
you know what's a normal,
absolutely.
One day,
15,
20%,
20%.
So they would take 20% of all your
touring.
So they would be like,
if you on Chimera,
Bam,
they'd be like the fifth person in the
band.
Correct.
Boy,
the merge your fucking tee shirts.
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
They take everything.
It's pretty weird and pretty grim right
now.
If this is what's weird is like what are
the,
I don't understand what they're doing.
Well,
I don't think they do either.
I think,
I think to be honest,
they're still trying to figure out what
their rule can be in this new world.
You know,
it's difficult for them.
Wow.
Life is tough.
It's a fascinating time because this
digital thing that came along,
what's really interesting is that,
you know,
we saw when the economy fell apart,
right?
We saw banks getting bailed out and we
saw these music companies going under.
We saw like a lot of issues,
a lot of collapses and it's all because
of these emerging technologies.
But these emerging technologies also on
the flip side,
make it so much easier for people to
find out about it.
Yeah.
Yes.
And it slowly,
I think things will,
I think it will balance itself out
again.
Right?
I think younger artists are going to get
we smarter than we ever were and just
go,
hold on a minute.
We're not signing these rates.
Do you have to?
Because there's no reason for that
today.
It just doesn't make it.
That's what it's so confusing to me.
Like giving away your merge and you're
touring like unless they're booking the
tour for you,
unless they're acting.
See though,
how the fuck are they getting a piece?
That's what I'm saying.
The one that's me.
That's where an agent gets a piece
because they book it,
they set it up.
They,
they arranged the publicity.
They do all that.
Like they,
they deserve a piece.
Like that's a business deal.
Like did seems like they're just
stealing money.
Well it seems a little bit like that.
I would agree.
I mean what's,
what was like for,
for instance,
in the art business,
we make 10% of everything we earn.
So that's basically,
we know that what we can make a certain
amount of money and by the time we've
paid everybody,
we'll take 10% home for all
the band members.
Each band member gets 10% so 40% okay.
40% of what we make,
and this is not even taxes.
You're not even talking about todd
talking about tax,
but it's time.
The decimate it put,
you know,
you were decimated.
But we are one of the bands who don't
have to pay a percentage of our tooting
and our marriage.
And we're one of the bands who get a
very high,
um,
royalty on our records because we only,
we only give away a tiny,
tiny percentage of every record to our
distribution company.
So we're one of the lucky ones.
So we're always thinking,
well,
if this is how it is for us,
Oh,
I said,
for all these other young artists,
there's a big thing about young artists,
they have to pretend that they're rich.
So everybody has to drive around in a
Ferrari,
you have to have a free hour watch on
your wrist.
You have to walk around like a baller.
I really reject all that and I think I
advise everybody else to reject it too.
I think we're beginning to move towards
a new world order because the worshiping
of money we can sustain our lives and
our world that we things are right now.
Well,
it comes from people being poor and
wanting to aspire to be rich.
And then once you make it,
you have to sort of put that show on.
Right?
I mean that's,
but that's a huge thing in the rap
community,
right?
With rappers,
it's almost mandatory.
It's a very rare that someone bucks the
trend where they're not wearing a lot of
jewelry and driving around a Bentley.
Although I feel that,
again,
that's changing too,
you know?
But,
um,
yeah,
I've never fallen in love with those
kind of acts as far coats and limousines
and I dunno,
it's just not my style.
Yeah,
no,
it's uh,
well,
I mean it's,
it comes from,
you know,
economically deprived people that
finally break through.
And of course I understand it's always
been,
but it's a,
it's almost like the fun part of like
the rap business.
Like a big part of the fun part.
I mean,
how many fucking rap songs are about
jewelry and diamonds and cars and
mansions.
And you'll see when I was growing up,
as we were telling him about being the
same age earlier on,
it was really uncool to talk about money
and all the cultural hurdles where we
didn't have money and would never talk
about money.
And actually often it was heartbreaking
when you've discovered they were rich
because they were kind of our work in
men's huddles.
You know,
I work in man heroes,
go back to Kurt Cobain,
he wore like converse all stars and
shipped up jeans and flannel shirts
farther back than that.
You know,
like,
um,
like John Lennon or somebody and they
ran all these tests,
you know.
But that's what I was sort of
indoctrinated in when I was growing up
or which I'm actually,
it's grateful for it.
I don't,
I don't want to be somebody who worships
money.
Well,
it's a foolish thing to worship because
you know,
the,
the ultimately like what an artist is
doing is they're trying to express
themselves in the most unique way
possible and connect with people,
right?
You're supposed to,
you're just trying to show the world
through your eyes.
You're trying to express yourself and if
all you're trying to express is that you
want to stack checks,
stack,
what is it?
What do they call it?
Stack on deck when it,
how?
What's that?
Stacks on stacks on deck.
That's like a big thing.
The wrappers,
those kids today talking about stacks,
Stefan decks,
just to,
just to have a little cushion.
It's always nice to have a coupon.
Right?
But I feel like these days are long
gone.
It is crazy though,
that you guys only get 10% then you
really stop and think about it all and
then you pay taxes on the 10% I don't
think people understand that.
No,
I really don't think people understand
about the same time.
Like nobody wants to hear a musician
wine.
No,
but I know many people who live,
who will have very modest jobs,
who are wealthier than we are at this
point,
you know?
But you know,
that's,
that's life.
I never became an artist because I want
it to be rich.
Well,
you would be so much happier being who
you are then not being able to sing and
being wealthy.
Exactly.
Yeah.
And I also have met a lot of rich people
in my team and they're miserable.
So certainly can be chasing that very
isolated.
And I know I could count on my hands.
They might have really rich people I
know who live happy lives,
who seem like they know what to do with
their money and these people definitely
are out there.
You know,
they have all the happy marriages,
happy kids,
balanced kids,
you know,
they know when to have fun.
They know how to work hard,
you know,
Blah Blah Blah Blah.
But they're the exception to the rule.
Super Rare.
It's worth the pursuit is such a strange
pursuit because you know,
oftentimes when you're pursuing wealth,
you're pursuing wealth at all costs.
I mean that is the ultimate goal is the
score that you put on the board.
I mean that's the Gordon Gekko
philosophy.
Greed is good.
Greed will protect me.
I mean,
I understand it,
why people feel an,
and they're not always wrong either.
Where money can protect you from a lot
of presidencies go to our president.
I mean our president is essentially,
the greed is good guy.
I mean the he,
that is who he is.
I mean that's what he's done.
I mean,
he has pursued wealth at all costs,
but he was also born into wealth a
little bit.
Yeah.
And then I think it was a little bit,
I think it was a substantial amount of
money he inherited,
well,
he was given $2 million to start his
business,
his first business.
And he talks about it,
a small loan,
small loans to small loan of $2 million.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I mean it's,
he certainly has inherited quite a bit
of it would no doubt,
no doubt about it.
But my point is that his philosophy and
like what he's always pursued his
extravagance,
like the big gold letters on the side of
the skyscrapers.
That's his thing.
And it's a stain.
It's,
in a lot of ways it's a dangerous
ideology for our country to aspire to.
Oh,
because everybody can't,
you can attend that.
So what use then seeing two people who
have that,
who will never have that.
That's kind of what leaves me in great
dismay.
I understand the pursuit of money and
economic wellbeing.
But yeah,
I feel like what did we then see to the
people that don't have that and never
will have that,
that has to be something
else other than the worst,
right?
Yeah.
It's a hollow pursuit.
It's,
and it's a pursuit that's like,
it's not examined closely enough for
four.
It's hollow ness,
if that's a word.
I was having a conversation once with
this friend of mine who is,
uh,
is pretty radical black guy,
a pretty radical African American and
just very proud of African American
heritage.
And he,
uh,
he went on this thing about how black
people used to be kings.
He's like,
we were kings.
Do you understand that?
I go stop.
I go,
can't everybody can't be a king because
I see if you have a bunch of kings,
like to be a king has to be a dictator.
Okay.
That means you're dominating people who
aren't kings.
That's not a proud thing.
Like you gotta stop saying that.
Like you say it's the wrong thought
process,
but it's the thought process is his in
his,
uh,
he had examined it like his in his idea,
like at one point in time we were
Africans,
we were kings,
we were,
we were on top and then,
you know,
slavery and all this other stuff.
So his,
like,
his thought process was kind of
convoluted and by saying we were kings,
I was like,
you don't want to be a fucking king man.
Like nobody should be a fucking king.
Should be zero kings and you definitely
don't want to see,
we were kings like we can be kings
again,
like don't be a king.
Yeah,
I don't want to be king.
I don't want to be a queen.
Well,
it's a big thing with fighters.
Like some fighters call himself king,
this king that they like to part of
their name.
You know,
it's a weird,
it's only African American guys.
I don't know any white guys call himself
king.
Oh,
come on,
don't,
oh,
platers white fighters.
Oh,
you're talking about know about that
world with me.
Bobby King,
Greene King Bobby Green,
King Mo.
I know,
I know like five or six King Kevin
Casey.
When you feel that you're,
you're a disadvantage and us as society,
you know,
words are powerful and they can,
the words we tell ourselves are really
powerful and perhaps you can manifest a
power that you need.
Some times we all need it.
Sometimes I know I need it myself.
You know,
where you know,
you think to yourself,
okay,
you need to remember what you have done,
what you've accomplished,
who you are,
who your mother is.
You know,
I think that there's a lot to be said,
I guess for sure,
for the casual use of certain words.
But you're right.
I mean it is,
as we continue to use these words,
we have to examine their meaning.
Yeah.
I think I,
I definitely think that's the case.
I think that the,
the wealth at all costs is a,
a foolish pursuit that people look at
when they don't have the wealth.
I mean,
that's when it becomes an attractive
thing is the idea that,
you know,
you just got to get that paper.
Okay.
When you've got the wealth.
I think the greediest people are the
people who are,
I've got shitloads of money.
That's why we see a lot of these,
these people with money wanting to cut
their,
have their tuxes cut rather than inject
some taxes into the community.
I mean,
I'd much rather live in a more pleasant
community then sit in my golden tower by
myself with like riots going on in the
street.
You know what I mean?
I feel like if you make everybody happy
year,
yeah,
you can still be rich,
but you're going to have a nicer garden
to we'll cut into.
That's a very good attitude.
It's a very good attitude.
I think it's a weird game that people
play where it becomes just about getting
those points up on the board and they
become,
the numbers become meaningless.
Like you don't sing.
You don't think I have $30 million,
I can't spend this.
This is if I live a normal life,
I'm good.
They don't think that they think I need
50 million.
I need an island.
I want a jet.
How much is enough,
babe?
You know,
how much is enough.
And of course the more you accumulate,
the more your expenses are and the more
you want.
So it just goes on and on and on and on.
There's an amazing radio lab podcast.
It's out now about,
um,
Bernie madoff.
Oh,
there's a show coming to narrows playing
brain.
She's still hot.
It's fuck gotta be 80,
90 years old now.
He is still so beautiful,
so hot.
It's crazy.
So I'm looking forward to that.
But sorry.
No worries.
But it's just,
um,
the,
the interview him and you get to hear
him talk and the,
um,
the reporter called him in jail and it's
a really fascinating way they had their
communicate because they're only allowed
to communicate for 15 minutes and then
they have to,
the phone is disconnected and then they
have to wait 15 minutes for,
they can reconnect.
So he's doing this.
Yeah.
That's just the rules of the prison.
So they're doing it.
I mean,
he's in there for it ever.
He's never getting out of that fucking
cage.
Yeah.
But it's fascinating when you hear him.
He has zero empathy.
I mean,
none.
It's weird.
It's weird hearing him talk about these
people that he ripped off and finding
these like,
oh they're,
they're fine.
These people that you know,
they,
they had money.
It's like they're not,
it's no big deal.
Like you're listening to the way this
guy sort of rationalized.
But he is essentially the poster boy for
that greed at all costs because he was
just,
it was running a Ponzi scheme.
You stealing money from people.
Yeah.
It's funny.
I was again talking about this with my
husband.
They really don't.
Today we were talking about what is the
difference between a Republican and a
Democrat?
Like what is essentially the difference?
Cause I know lots,
I have very good friends who are
Republicans who I respect enormously
and,
and you know,
they have taught me a lot and they have
changed the way I view the world and so
on so forth.
But essentially I wonder is it that
Democrats are able to utilize their
imagination in an an a republican is
less imaginative.
I don't know.
I'm,
I'm using it light.
I have no answers.
I'm just curious about what drives
someone towards the left and what drives
someone towards the right because it's
certainly know that one site is good and
one side is bad.
One side is really smart and the other
side isn't it.
It's nothing to do with that.
So what is it that drives us towards
these embattled positions that are the
ins right now in America seems saw
acute,
you know,
there just seems to be new marriage of
the two sites and I'd love to know why.
I wish I knew about how
that all works.
I think people are very easily
influenced.
I think people are very tribal and I
think people,
it's very easy to influence someone to
get them to adopt a predetermined
pattern of thinking and if that
predetermined pattern of thinking is
right wing or left wing,
if you're around those people and you
seek social status by committing to a
certain ideology,
you get embedded in it,
it becomes a part of your thinking,
becomes a part of your life.
And then that is the pattern that you
bore.
You dig deep,
you dig deep trenches in terms of your
psychology.
You dig deep trenches in your mind that
are unwavering and whether there are
left wing or right wing,
it becomes very problematic when you
have two teams like that.
We were talking about Holland the other
day that Hollande has something like 17
different parties that viable parties,
you know,
unlike what we have where we have this
one too.
And then we have a few joke parties like
the Green party that no one takes
seriously libertarians,
nobody takes seriously,
they never even come close to winning.
And when you have one or two and one of
them is conservative and one of them is
liberal,
it just automatically people identify
with one or the other and they,
whether it's from upbringing or the
community that they're attached to or
what have you,
or life experiences past positive or
negative,
they just immediately gravitate towards
one or the other.
They dig in and then they start talking
shit about the left or they started
talking shit about the right.
And you know,
you've got salon.com and you've got Fox
News and everybody's lobbing bombs at
each other and it's just fucking weird.
Okay.
Why have we not seen any break?
I mean I get that.
Generally speaking,
like I understand on a,
totally agree with what you're saying
that that generally that is what occurs,
but surely on both sides of the fence
you have free thinkers.
There must be a few.
There's more now.
I think there's more now than ever
before,
but this is a very weird time in terms
of trump and trump winning because he's,
he's sort of engaged.
The like they,
they've sort of,
there's a bunch of people that are not
necessarily political that are really
into being a right wing or now it's
almost like online trolls and people
that just like to be a part of a team
and they just like to fuck with people
they call snowflakes are liberals.
It's weird.
It's weird time.
I think we're going to get through it.
I think it's like the gold water
republican days.
It's like I think we,
we need to have like bad examples that
we need to go,
well let's not do that again.
Yeah.
And then collectively
the arc of history is long.
It is.
And the age of the world is infinite.
But the America's young as fuck.
Yeah,
and that's part of the problem.
It's this weird new experiment in self
government.
It's really only been going on for a few
hundred years.
Yeah.
And it's easy to look at a few hundred
years as being a long time,
but it's really not.
It's not.
Especially you guys in Scotland,
you know,
you guys have been around forever.
You'd
be the right fucking braveheart days and
shit.
Yeah.
But the,
the thing about the free press,
that's what worries me as a foreigner
living in this country and seeing this,
this,
this surface stuff that's being spewed
about the free press is worrisome.
It's worrisome.
It comes from the president himself.
Yeah.
That's,
that's kind of,
yeah.
I mean,
yeah,
there's only been two presidents,
our history that have actually gone to
war with the press,
and one of them was Richard Nixon.
I mean,
this is just so unprecedented time that
someone disrespects the idea of the
press and,
and news.
This is where people can challenge.
Nobody likes getting challenged.
It doesn't feel very nice when somebody
goes,
no,
I disagree with you.
It doesn't feel good.
But you know,
aren't we all at the point where we're
willing to at least listen and start
like,
yeah.
But it's very scary,
I think.
Well,
he's a dictator in a lot of ways.
Yeah.
I mean,
and then he was challenged the other day
and by cbs they were asking them about
Obama wiretapping and the lie that he
made up.
Yeah.
And he wound up a multi,
see,
there's some you say he could say it was
a lie,
but there's some validity to it,
whether it was some surveillance being
going on,
but whether or not it was Obama or
whether or not it's standard
surveillance at the NSA has been
perpetrating for a long time,
which I think was the case.
I think it's more that the ne,
I think fucking everybody's getting
spied on.
I mean,
I think that's really what's going on.
So you can say I'm being spied on.
I think you'd be correct.
But you say Obama spying on me.
I don't think that's correct.
Yeah.
So I think the interview,
yeah.
He walked out when they were
challenging.
He doesn't like being challenged.
It wasn't like,
you know,
he doesn't like anybody questioning him
and he feels like he could just leave.
He doesn't feel like the press is
important.
He feels like he's got a strong enough
base and all these people that will just
yell out fake news.
I mean he's made this,
this sort of meme when he pointed that
CNN guy and said,
you are fake news.
Yeah.
Like what is,
this is a scary time for any disturbing.
But I think in some ways that's good.
And this is why I think,
I think we need,
as human beings need resistance.
We need something to push back against.
Yeah.
And it helps us,
it helps us sort of reinvigorate our,
our,
our collective ideas and re
reinvigorate,
knowing now that this is possible.
We didn't know that was possible before.
No,
we didn't think he was gonna win.
And if we did,
if he did,
when Jesus Christ,
we didn't think he was gonna win like
this.
And you didn't think that he was going
to sort of dismantle the EPA and do all
these different things he's doing
tikkaway the fucking satellites they use
for climate.
I mean there's a lot of shit that's
going on that's very problematic to
science and scientists and they are
being really frustrated right now.
So now they know.
Now they know and now we know.
No,
I totally agree.
And I think the,
the,
the US press since September 11th have
actually,
the standard of journalism has been
sliding know for a decade if not longer.
And now all of a sudden journalists are
being held to account and they are
having to step up their game again,
which I think is great for the American
people to have fun.
Enjoy good journalism.
Yeah,
I think you're right.
Yay.
So we managed to take something
relatively,
I think it's sad.
You don't want to think it is.
I think it's the same thing that's kind
of happened to the music business.
I think journalism experience,
this new wave of media and information
being distributed by anyone,
whether it's a breitbart or anyone who
just creates a blog.
And just starts pump pumping out their
agenda,
Huffington Post's,
salon.com,
whatever it is,
they become these aggregates for news
that they feel fits with their agenda,
the agenda that they would like to
promote and push.
And you know,
whether it's full left wing,
like a salon.com or full right wing like
Breitbart,
both of them are problematic.
And that's where the New York Times is
to really step up.
I see.
I think they're trying to,
I think you're right.
Yeah.
I think they are.
So,
yeah.
I mean it's,
it's weird times,
but we're times create great art.
No,
it does.
It really creates good people too.
Like it's good for it.
I think what you were saying earlier on
this is really too,
like when people are tested,
that's when you see them at their best.
So pressure creates diamonds.
Diamonds.
I'm stealing that from my mine.
He's still it.
I Dunno.
It's the old term.
I believe it's good.
Yeah,
it's good.
It's real.
It's legit working for fund in here on
our loins and shit.
A lot of,
lot of things happen.
Listen,
you gotta get Outta here.
Um,
so do you?
Yes,
I do.
So,
um,
where can people find out tour
information and garbage is your twitter
handle and does that,
do you handle all that?
Do you do that stuff
for the most part I do.
I try and I didn't like the feeling of
some dip tending to be me and putting
words into my mouth.
So generally speaking,
I do take care of the social media.
That's awesome.
Well,
it's a bit of a pain,
but I farmed mine out to China now my
farm,
my nights I'll do,
as I say,
just you read my tweets and whatever I
say like that.
Just say that say woke.
You swears lit.
Lit.
I don't use that one.
I was lit.
It was lit.
Yeah.
How about it was fire?
I haven't heard that one.
But that's a school.
That's Viking terminal,
is he?
Yeah.
Ooh.
You said it like you own it.
The people I do put 100% vikings,
100% a hundred percent hundred percent.
I've had a DNA test that was run by my
city of Edinburgh.
I'm super impressed.
You're fine.
Thank you.
I would like,
I'm sitting here trying to embrace it.
There it is.
Rage and raptured,
tour,
blondie and garbage and all of this.
It looks exciting as fuck.
And uh,
all of this is available online.
Where,
where can they
get no shame to see?
I would imagine it's on the faith on our
website,
which is garbage.call me people can find
it.
People can find it.
If you can't find it,
just don't show up.
You can't find it on my birthday.
You're going to be in Austin,
Texas.
What did you say?
August 11th.
That's my birthday.
You gonna be in Austin,
Texas.
Yeah,
I know this baby as well.
Oh,
shut the fuck up.
Shut the fuck up.
I am on crazy.
So hold on.
What sign are you a Leo?
You're such a Leo,
Leo.
I'm not.
I'm a virgo.
Shirley Manson.
You're awesome.
Thank you.
Thank you for being on.
All right fuckers.
We'll be back soon.
Bye.
I'm sweating here.