Hey everybody,
this episode of the Joe Rogan experience
podcast is brought to you by legal zoom.
Legal Zoom is an awesome way to take
care of things online that you would
ordinarily have to go to a lawyers
office for.
You'd have to make an appointment,
he'd have to get weirded out by going
there and just thinking about how much
money it's going to cost you,
and you can save a substantial amount of
money by using legal zoom.
You can incorporate or form an llc at
legal zoom for just 99 bucks.
You can make trademarks,
copyrights,
patents.
You can make your own will legally
protected will for just $69.
I mean,
that's amazing living trusts,
powers of attorney and more in the past
12 years,
over 2 million Americans have used legal
zoom.
They've saved a ton of money.
We have personal experience on it.
Um,
Arbor used legal zoom to incorporate on
it.
And Brian used legal zoom to for a desk
squad.
So it has been used by people that we
know.
It's excellent.
It works well.
And if you panic and you're like,
man,
I don't think this is right,
you can get connected to an independent
attorney.
So if you get to a point where you're
like,
this is not legal and you're freaking
out,
just don't worry about it.
They can.
They can connect you to someone who can
clean up your mess as well.
And it's easy to use though it's not
difficult.
It's very clear.
Step by step,
they're online process couldn't be much
easier and they'll take care of you from
start to finish and you get a special
discount from listening to this podcast.
Make sure you enter Rogan in the
referral box at checkout for more
savings.
Legalzoom is not a law firm.
They provide self-help services at your
specific direction.
That's legal zoom.com.
And remember and to Rogan in the
referral box.
We're also brought to you by,
what was the Ting Ting.
Oh,
she's Louisa's Ting is a mobile service
that has been a sponsor of this podcast
for quite a long time and I've never
heard one person say anything bad about
it.
We've had a few sponsors like that where
there's been zero controversy and Tang
is one where if you have a cell phone
provider that you use on a regular basis
and you switched over to Tang,
I guarantee you you're going to save
some money.
It's 98 percent of people would save
money with Ting.
I mean that's,
that's their statement and their
websites and number one thing they say
and they show you the numbers for why
people would save.
What they do is they use the sprint
network so they rent time on a sprint
network,
but they have their own rules.
Like you can cancel anytime you want.
If you don't use a certain amount of,
uh,
of service.
Say if you,
you have your phone set up for x amount
of minutes,
but use less than that.
They knock you down to the next level
and credit your,
the distance on your next bill.
It's beautiful.
Other people charge you.
If you go over your allocated minutes
for text or data.
If you have a heavier month with Ting,
you just pay for what you used.
You don't get like weird fines or
anything creepy.
Anything that makes you go,
oh,
come on man.
That's what Tim's trying to eliminate
the are come on man thing.
When you look at the bill and go,
what the fuck dude,
come on.
Kind of bullshit.
Is that also tim will you can no early
termination fees and there's an etf
relief program in ETF is an early
termination fee and if you're paying an
early termination fee,
come to ting and they'll give you credit
for 25 percent of that early termination
fee up to $75 per device.
So it's a.
it's an excellent deal all around.
If you go to [inaudible] dot ting.com,
you will save $25 on your first ting
device when you sign up.
So that's Rogan.ting.com.
They also have ting also has the ability
to transfer over your mobile devices
too.
If you have a mobile device,
I'm from sprint,
like an iphone four s or an iphone four.
You can start using those at sprint as
well.
So sprint is a really a beautiful cell
phone service.
It's a the way people should do things.
If the world was better,
that'd be more corporations like this
and we wouldn't have as many arguments
about shit,
ladies and gentlemen,
so he can also bring over the nexus
five,
which is some other sweet new device.
It's part of your bring your own device
offering.
So go to ting.com,
Rogan.ting.com
and save yourself some money.
We're also brought to you by on it.com.
It's and,
and it makers of Alpha brain and shroom
tech and all that good stuff.
And a large selection of strength and
conditioning equipment now including the
Zombie Kettlebells,
the primal bells which are apes and
chimpanzees,
orangutans and monkeys.
Just trying to give you something
interesting to work out with.
And also all stuff that I think is the
best as far as strength and conditioning
equipment is concerned.
All the things that I think,
you know,
benefit you the most as far as actual
real body strength for athletics and for
just keeping your body healthy and
strong.
Um,
my philosophy and the philosophy of a
lot of them,
this is where I got it from a lot of a
fitness trainers and especially strength
and conditioning guys in mixed martial
arts is treating your whole body.
Don't,
don't do like individual exercises like
preacher bench curls or anything that's
real isolation exercises.
A lot of those are kind of ridiculous
and what you really should do for
functional strength is do things where
you use your whole body as one unit,
like battle ropes or like kettle bells
or like we have club bells and there's
medicine ball drills,
and even bodyweight exercises like Chin
ups and pushups.
You want to use something,
do something that makes your body move
in an athletic way.
We also sell the best supplements we can
get our hands on,
the best stuff that we can buy as far as
like hemp protein or nootropics or any
different supplements that are enhancing
the that'll enhance your mood or enhance
your body's ability to perform.
We just try to sell you the best shit
that we could find online and if you use
the code name Rogan,
you can save 10 off any and all
supplements.
All right.
Lorenzo from psychedelic salon is here,
is the joining of the podcast minds.
So let's just get this thing on real
good experience.
Joe Rogan podcast.
One of the cool things about the
Internet,
um,
it's been getting to,
uh,
find out all these other people that
share these interests in and really kind
of what some people would think would be
obscure things.
And one of them is talks about
psychedelics.
You know,
the Terence Mckenna talks,
the Timothy leary talks.
It's so rare to find a place where you
can find a lot of those.
And in the case of your podcast to
psychedelic salon,
it's the best one I've ever found.
And when I found it,
I was so happy.
I was like,
this guy's got everything you have like
every mckenna recording,
like ever you,
all these Timothy leary,
recordings and Alan Watts.
I mean,
who,
who don't you have anybody essentially
who's ever said anything weird about
drugs?
Well,
I don't have Joe Rogan yet,
so
podcasts I don't really.
I could go on and we can talk about
them.
Let's see.
You started the podcast intentionally
and mine was just accidental.
No,
that was it.
That's the misconception.
We didn't start intentionally at all.
Oh,
I didn't know that.
Now we just turned on a Webcam once
we're doing it,
like at ustream broadcast.
Just screwing around just for a oof.
Well,
we started the same way then.
How did you get yours on?
I,
I'm kind of a Geeky guy and I was
looking at tech and we're actually up at
a mind states conference and I had
already produced this blanket and rj
talks at burning man and had them up on
the web and little 10 minute increments
to keep the file size down and we're up
at this mind states conference and a guy
comes up to me and says,
Hey,
I'm going to start a podcast.
Can I use all that stuff you have?
And I said,
sure,
go ahead.
I said,
I thought about it too,
but I don't have an ipod so I didn't
think so.
And he said,
you don't need one,
you can do it in your computer.
So I waited a couple months and he never
started his podcast.
And so I got ahold of him.
I said,
are you still going to do that?
And he said,
no.
And I said,
well,
if you don't mind,
I'm going to use them.
He said,
well,
they're yours.
So I made a pie.
I did a podcast of a talk I gave first.
And then I did one that a friend of mine
made of terrence.
The last one actually,
he gave him plenty or next to last.
And then,
uh,
I did those two and I was trying to
figure out how the tech worked.
And so then I put up my stuff from
blanket and rj and uh,
you know,
I was still just playing around with it
and I kind of looked in,
there's 10 people and maybe 20 and 30
years,
you know,
downloading it,
probably my friends and all of a sudden
I get contacted by this Guy Kmo and I'd
been up to maybe 100 downloads.
And he said,
Hey,
I love your podcast.
And you,
these guys over in England doing the
dope fiend is doing something and he
likes it.
And uh,
so I started kind of hookup doing the
dope fiend.
Oh,
you don't know about the dope fiend?
No.
What is that?
It's a great podcast to.
It's on the cannabis podcast network and
hilarious.
You can find it.
A dope fiend,
that code at UK and they're a great
podcast.
He's got a whole series of podcasts
there to the cannabis network.
But uh,
yeah,
he,
he has some good music shows.
In fact,
uh,
I,
I first found you,
uh,
during my,
stoner a bachelor days on news radio for
so and uh,
then I was lifting to lefties lounge
who's one of the podcasts on the dope
fiend network and he plays music and
comedy and all of a sudden there's some
cuts from you.
And,
and,
uh,
he says,
yeah,
Joe's got this podcast now.
And so that's how I found your podcast
was through theirs.
Oh,
that's so cool.
I don't,
I'm not even sure how I found out about
yours.
It was,
it was probably twitter,
someone suggesting it online or maybe my
message board.
It could have been,
I don't really remember who turned me
onto it,
but it was more than one person and I
think it was probably because like I
would occasionally post like a clip that
someone,
uh,
you know,
like on Youtube for like Mckenna lecture
or something like that,
or one of those really cool videos and
some people have done.
That's one of them are amazing things
about the internet is all these user
created videos.
Like I just posted one today that
someone made.
I have no idea who did it.
And they did it with things that I said
on a podcast.
And it's,
it's fantastic.
They did a fantastic job.
It's um,
it's a weird thing where you can,
you know,
you can a thing that you put out,
all the sudden it gets caught on by
these other people.
And then they add all these things to
it.
Music and visuals.
And it becomes even bigger.
Like some of these Mckenna ones were a,
him giving a lecture,
but they've put them to visuals and
sounds and they're just amazing and
they're super inspirational.
Oh yeah.
Every week I get links to some graphic
artists.
Is that Sunday I used the clip for your
podcast and,
and it's just wonderful to see it
because I think the visuals really
enhanced what terrance has to say or
anybody say,
you know,
and you know,
I know you had a lot of people spin off
podcast podcast after listening to you
and a few have done that with me and
some of them hadn't stuck around,
but like these two guys started a
podcast called black light in the attic.
It was really cool out of Chicago.
What they did is they did a 12 part,
a youtube video series in how to use
audacity and it's still the best thing
out there.
So what's audacity?
Audacity is a free open source,
a sound sa hardware software.
It's an audio multitrack.
Uh,
you can do lots and lots of stuff with
them,
but it's free open source.
It's probably a more used in podcasts
than anything.
Wow.
And,
but they did a 12 part youtube thing,
you know,
it's in every once in a while.
I want to learn something new in
audacity.
I go to one of those kids podcasts.
That's
so cool.
So you must do everything yourself.
Then you must edit.
You put all the clips together.
Yeah.
The,
the procedure is I,
I,
uh,
I listened to a talk first and a lot of,
um,
you know,
there's a question she can't hear so you
have to cut those out and you've got to
boost and adjust the sound.
So I get the sound as best I can and I'm
taking notes at the same time because I
put program notes,
noodles,
short quotes and all because Google and
Duckduckgo and those other search
engines don't search the audio.
And so I've made a,
you know,
I've tried to get like 15,
20 quotes of terrance and each one of
his lectures so that they're searchable.
But then once I have that done,
then I write a script where I introduce
it and then I close out and I write the
script out and rehearse it.
And then I read it so.
And then,
then of course,
you know,
you've got to cut the pieces together
and add the music and then,
uh,
turn into MP three file and put it on
the rss feed and put it out there.
So yeah,
I do the whole thing.
I respect that so much because I,
this podcast is so easy.
We don't ever edit it.
We go live.
We just let it roll SCO once it's gone,
it's gone.
I know.
Fuck up.
We fuck up.
You know,
it's,
it's got every bump possible.
It's all happening like that.
That's the magic of your podcast because
I have,
I've listened to quite a few of your
podcasts.
I listened to the comedians in my wife
listens to your serious interviews,
but uh,
you're every one of your podcasts.
I've wanted to jump in and talk and I've
talked to a lot of my friends that
listen to it too.
And they said,
yeah man,
he,
he's just like one of us and I want to
talk with them.
And I think that's the real genius of
this podcast.
It's just two guys or three or four or
whatever sitting around talking.
Isn't that hilarious?
But what kind of society who we become
were just a regular conversation is
novel,
regular conversations.
Like what the fuck are they doing?
What are they just talking?
Well,
you know,
years ago when I was living in Tampa,
will you on a Saturday night there's guy
named,
Carroll subtler who did a,
a chatterbox cafe and we go down from,
from 10 till two.
And uh,
what the,
the thing was it was about 12 of us sit
around a table like this and we all
drink and just talk and they could have
collins to and so people could
essentially go to a bar without leaving
their house and you wouldn't have to
drive drunk.
And so the sound effects were like a bar
and all and we'd all assume characters
and sit around and talk.
And it was a hugely popular show.
Wow.
That's interesting.
It's interesting,
the idea of audio theater,
which is basically what podcasts are,
is a completely new thing to me at
least.
I mean,
it kind of existed before because when I
was a child I listened to audio
recordings on a record on the large
vinyl,
you know,
like of course I would listen to standup
comedians and cheech and Chong and
things along those lines and you just
sit around and listen.
But the beautiful thing about podcast is
most of the time when people are tuning
into this,
enjoying this,
they're doing something else,
like you're at the gym or you're driving
your car and commuting to work or school
or what have you,
like you're doing something else.
Exactly.
And,
and it's like the old radio see grew up
in radio.
We
didn't have a TV until I was in like
sixth or seventh grade.
And so when I'd come home from school in
the afternoon,
my brother and I looked through the
radio listing just like TV guide and you
know,
was fibber mcgee and molly and the
shadow and,
and my dad and I on Sunday afternoon
down the basement would listen to all
these great shows.
We had an episode of a news radio where
Andy Dick became obsessed with fibber
mcgee.
And Molly,
I remember that listening to all the
recordings and laughing and like walking
into walls and stuff because he was
laughing so hard and that was the first
time I'd ever heard of them.
I can tell you where they lived.
Seventy nine wistful vista drive.
Wow.
I listened to all the February Mcgee and
molly,
that's silly,
you know,
it's such an interesting time in our,
in our society when the families used to
sit around the radio and listen to like
orson wells and those kinds of things.
You,
that's all we had,
you know,
that uh,
I'm 71 now so I can go back a little
ways.
But uh,
uh,
I don't feel like things have changed
that much because podcasts have sort of
turned into the old radio and people
walk around.
Like you said,
it's a little different.
You're not sitting at home,
you know,
looking at radio.
Well,
in my case it's far less professional,
you know,
I'm not very unprofessional podcasts,
I don't listen to any podcasts.
I don't know if there is such a thing as
there.
I guess.
Yeah,
there are actually.
I used to listen to a scientific
American and they had a good 20 minute
one that was a good,
but I kind of fell away from that.
A nurse at this hospital that I was
going to get this procedure done,
recommended radio lab and the first one
that I tuned into was this one about
these Kenyan runners from this very
specific village and she was just going
on in depth about it and then like to
hear her describe this intense thing and
then to actually listen to the show.
Like radial labs.
Really good.
They have like sound effects that they
play while they're giving their talk on
things.
They bring in people to have interviews
and they sort of interject in the
interview,
like build.
The guy will be talking and they'll
explain like why this is so significant
and like they'll.
And then let the guy talk more.
It's really interesting like the guy
talks,
but instead of interrupting him as he's
talking and he's just sort of edit
things in after the fact.
So they're having an interview with a
guy and they not just interview him but
also interject in the middle of what
he's doing,
various facts and information that
actually enhance the story and make it
richer,
really well done,
and it was all about this one tribe of
runners is just like unbelievably
awesome and it comes to this rite of
passage ritual that they do with
circumcision and I heard you talking
about that with grant at the same track,
so awful terrible stuff,
but they became like super immune to the
response of pain or or to responding to
pain or super determined or super
whatever it is.
Their level of either their level of
pain tolerance or their ability to
suppress it,
whatever the hell it is,
but they must be converting that pain to
new kinds of energy of some kind for
their long distance running.
Yeah.
I think that,
and I think it's also super critical in
their society that you get through this
ritual and if you don't get through this
ritual,
you're not thought of as a man.
Yeah.
We all have our rituals and there are a
lot less painful than most places.
That one sounds.
So what's really insane was that this
guy was talking about his sons and that
he didn't want his sons to go through
what he had to go through and he thought
personally as a person who did it,
that there was other ways to build
character and I thought that was really
interesting.
Yeah,
it is.
It's a,
it's a step in what we would call a more
civilized behavior,
but you know,
we'll have to take generations to see
what.
So also love,
you know,
when there's like,
if you love your children,
you don't want them to go to the same
kind of shit that you went through,
you know,
if you wanted to make an interesting
person,
what do you do?
You give them bad parenting and drop
them off in a shitty neighborhood.
That's what I want for my kids.
No,
I don't want.
My kid didn't want to grow up like I did
and I had a wonderful childhood,
but you know,
it wasn't perfect.
I think what we're working on now as a
society,
whether it's on purpose or not,
by by you putting out those kinds of
podcasts by me trying to have as many
podcasts as I can,
what we're all working on,
I think is a.
we're all looking at this world that
we're living in and going,
do we have to do things this way?
Is this,
this?
Is this really necessary?
And the more that word gets out,
it's not a violent word.
It's not.
It's just a realistic word.
It's,
it's,
we're,
we're all just going.
Come on.
Like,
what do you,
you know,
when we're not trying to run the world,
I don't want to hog up all the oil.
I want to steal anybody's natural gas,
but I also don't want to watch you do it
right.
I don't want to watch this crazy world
we're living in where it's really
obvious that what things are being done
are not fair.
It's really,
I don't think that you can have a
society the way our society is where
it's so big and so disconnected and not
have people that are acting in their own
self interest,
but I don't think that that's the only
way it can be done.
I think once we become more and more
connected,
and I think podcasts are a big part of
that,
psychedelics are a big part of that.
The Internet itself,
which is kind of Psychedelic,
is a big part of that.
As those things bring people closer and
closer together,
I just think less of that kind of
behaviors necessary.
Less of it is justified.
Let's have it is unexplained.
It's Kinda,
it's Kinda all out there now.
We understand people way better than we
ever did.
Well,
we're realizing that we're all alike.
When you get down to the operator,
you know,
below the operating system to machine
code.
Good.
One of my very closest friends in the
world is Vietnamese.
He was a eight year old orphan time.
I was over there.
I didn't know him then,
but we've become really close over the
years.
And uh,
once we got through all the culture and
the politics and the religion,
just talking about people's stuff,
you know,
and his problems with his wife were the
same as I was having with my girlfriend
at the time.
And,
and on a human level,
we realize how just identical we are,
no matter where you go in the world,
you know,
people are,
are the same except they get the
overlays of culture and religion and
family and all that stuff.
But if you can break through those
barriers and that's where psychedelics I
think are very helpful.
You'll find out that we're all alike and
we can figure out how to get along
both different and alike.
But our differences are external.
The,
the,
the actual human being like what does,
what does the person want out of this
life?
Right?
What is,
we want happiness,
right?
I,
I wouldn't want to get rid of any
culture.
I think they're there.
What added all the spice and the flavor
to the world.
We want to see the cultures,
but I think we need to quit fighting.
You know,
we never quit fighting.
Well,
there's also an issue that a lot of
cultures evolve around these ideas that
are outdated,
antiquated,
crazy.
In fact,
there's a lot of religious cultures that
are there.
He has a beautiful culture.
It's really interesting.
Their artworks fantastic.
They're the way they dress is really
fascinating,
but Jesus Christ,
look how progressive they are to each
other.
Look how they treat women.
Look at Saudi Arabia in 2013 women have
to protest for their right to drive a
car like Holy Shit,
and look on the way they have to dress
in that heat and they get the black
clothes,
not the white ones.
It's completely insane.
It's,
it's old as fuck.
It's ridiculous.
It was from a time when people didn't
know any better,
right?
The idea that your God wants you to do
that is beyond ridiculous.
You know,
religion is basically superstition when
you come down to it.
A huge part of it,
and I get the idea that I get that
people need a higher power or believe in
a higher power,
100 percent,
but if you can't see that there's the
hand of man and something that tells you
that you should stone homosexuals to
death.
You can't see the hand of man in that.
You really think that that's the way God
would handle it.
Why would it God invent homosexuals in
the first place if you don't think that
they're doing that because they're born
that way?
Look there I'm sure have been men who
are heterosexual who are like,
let's see what the fuss is all about and
went over and did some gay shit.
Why not?
I'm sure it happened.
Nothing.
Nothing wrong with that,
but the reality of being gay,
if you've ever met anybody who's gay,
is that most people who are gay always
knew it from the time they were born.
Now,
why would God create that?
What would you got to create someone who
was born in a way that makes them just
by nature of existing,
you're allowed to stone them to death.
You should stone them to death.
Well,
you know,
my youngest son is gay and when he
finally came out I said,
well,
you know,
I've been talking to your sister about
this for 10 years.
And he said,
he said,
well,
I knew I was gay that long too.
He said,
I just had to get the courage to come
out and just last January he got married
in Washington DC and it was a,
he was a kind of a big deal at the
Kennedy Center.
And so it was a big society wedding and
it was amazing social event with
hundreds of people there and people from
the State Department and everywhere.
And Wow.
And uh,
you could,
you could tell the tables that were the
old established straight people who came
just to be polite at first,
but it turned into such a wonderful
party and they had the wedding and then
a dinner and then the reception all in
the same place.
And everybody stayed until the thing
closed down.
They were having their.
Mainly the old people are watching.
The young people danced because,
uh,
well my,
my,
uh,
my son's husband is a principal dancer
at the Susan Farrell Valet.
Wait a minute.
Gay Ballet Dancer.
This story just doesn't make any sense.
You don't think there'd be whether
there's one or two.
Is it a funding that there's certain,
like,
like if you hear guys an interior
decorator,
Bam.
I mean,
how many straight dudes.
I'm sure there are some or they get mad
at me saying this right now,
but I don't know why it is,
but there's something about certain
professions
and uh,
you know what you were really,
you know,
they don't look gay or not gay.
But boy is he a hell of a dancer?
Well,
you know,
that's always been the rumor about John
Travolta.
He's probably not even gay.
People are excited about Saturday night
fever was still good.
It was too good.
It was just changed the way people
decided to mate.
But you know,
if mating dance,
if you want to
go to a fun wedding,
just go to a same sex marriage because
it's new for them.
It's something.
They're really celebrating something for
the first time.
It's a very joyous occasion.
They don't feel pressured into it.
Not like you guys have been together for
five years and he hasn't gotten your
ring.
This is bullshit,
right?
You need to let him know that this is
unacceptable.
All Gay guys don't have a girlfriend
like that.
They're doing it out of love there and
they're a wonderful couple.
Where's the.
Where is it legal now?
How many states is gay marriage?
About 15 or something like that.
It's happening right?
Slowly but surely.
Yeah.
See he had just moved to Florida taking
a new job and they'd already had all
these plans,
but he couldn't get married in Florida,
so they left everything in DC.
15 states.
We're seeing a legal same sex marriage
and then there's also more states were
34 that ban same sex marriage.
There's more than ban it,
but recently there's been a federal
decision.
The tax department is going to recognize
it no matter what state they live in.
This is fascinating though.
There's states where it's banned.
It's like they have banned same sex
marriages,
34 of them.
That's amazing.
I really had to go out of the way there.
What?
It's so stupid.
It's hard to believe.
It's so stupid that people in this day
and age decide what two people can't do
because of their sex.
Like if she.
If marriage is legal,
okay,
and I'm not sure it should be,
but if marriage is legal,
why shouldn't it be legal for gay
people?
It's just so sensible.
It's so dumb.
It's such a weird thing to get behind.
It's like,
what's your end game here?
I don't understand how you're getting
behind anybody who would be getting
behind this outside of some crazy
religious belief.
You've lost me.
What do you care?
And the idea that somehow know that it's
going to eventually cost us money or
there's tracks was it was some stupid
arguments that you see the convoluted
about why people being gang getting
married would make any difference or
cost any more or less than them not
getting married or them or straight
people getting.
This is w.
What studies are you talking about?
What do you know who studies on this and
these homophobes that are just insane
for what they're saying,
you know,
that that gave Mary or same sex marriage
now is going to cause everybody to go
out and rape children.
I mean,
they're making this stuff up that's just
unbelievable.
If that's maybe like,
just information,
maybe like the,
maybe the,
the gay marriage people who are pro gay
marriage are saying shit like that.
Just to make it such a retarded
argument.
Clever move.
You know?
It is,
it is.
Um,
yeah.
It's,
it's one of those weird things where I,
I can't believe it's still around.
It's like I remember when I was a kid,
I've told this story,
but in the interest of this particular
discussion when I was like,
I guess I was 11 years old and I had
moved from San Francisco to Florida and
there's a lot of things that I didn't
know.
San Francisco.
He was incredibly open minded and I
really remember being very aware of the
difference immediately upon moving to
Florida because I had a friend from Mark
Cuban Friends Name Candy and his Dad,
ca candy.
Escondido or something like that is
crazy.
Last name,
I forget his last name,
but his dad was screaming and yelling,
slamming the newspaper on the table.
I can't believe this shit.
And I was like trying to figure out what
was going on,
you know,
and I was like,
what's Your Dad Mad?
And He goes,
like,
Dad,
what are you mad at?
Darlington?
Fag,
Mary,
you believe this shit,
they're going to let those homos marry
each other.
He was mad.
He was throwing the newspaper down.
I was 11.
And I was like,
what a silly man you are.
You're a grown man and this is something
that bothers you and concerns you.
I remember thinking that an 11 year old
boy,
like,
wow,
there's a lot of weak ass bitches out
there posing as men.
Like you dummy.
Yeah.
Like what do you care like you were,
you were at tough guy because you care.
The two guys want to kiss each other.
Like,
what the fuck is wrong with you?
It's just a stupid.
It's such a dumb thing to get behind.
You know,
our little granddaughters,
uh,
last January they were like four and a
half and uh,
just turned eight and I came back from
the wedding and they were still saying
no two boys got married.
Did they kiss?
And I said,
yeah,
let we show the pictures of them.
And so now they're really cool with it.
And uh,
one of them the other day told her
teacher about a,
yeah,
bob was a little boy,
is married to a boy,
so it's going to be normal for these
people.
It should have been normal.
Long time ago when I was a kid,
I lived in San Francisco next to this
gay couple.
It was a black guy and his boyfriend is
white dude.
And my aunt used to go down there and
they would smoke pot and play bongos
naked.
They would all get together.
I was like,
fucking seven.
They would all go next door to the gay
couples house.
It was totally,
completely normal.
It was like,
there's a black guy,
there's an Asian guy,
there was a gay guy.
It's like good another guy.
It's like,
it's no big deal.
I didn't even know what the word nigger
meant when I moved to Florida.
I asked mother and she
got mad at me because she thought I was
playing games and I said,
I don't know what it means.
What does it mean?
Because someone said it at school and
she just.
She said it's a derogatory term for
black people.
I was like,
wow.
Really?
And you were,
what?
Seven years old?
I was 11.
Eleven is when I first moved to Florida.
I was,
because I couldn't believe it.
I hadn't experienced hardly any racism.
And in San Francisco,
San Francisco in the seventies,
it was just the,
the,
the age of Utopia had expired.
Right.
Which is like the 19 sixties,
the late 19 sixties in San Francisco.
But there was still an echo of like
understanding and progressive thinking
in San Francisco,
like no other place.
Right.
So it was a big difference to go from
San Francisco in the seventies to
fucking Gainesville,
Florida.
Right.
Which is just back ass retarded.
They were feeding the alligators
marshmallows and this fucking lake near
my house.
I mean,
it was ridiculous.
The difference,
I moved from California,
from Florida and that's where all my
kids live,
but it's not fit for human habitation.
I wouldn't not go back.
It's a crazy fucking state.
And you know,
I lived in San Francisco in the late 66,
early [inaudible] 67 and I had just
gotten married my now ex wife,
but she was a Texan,
born and raised in Houston.
And,
and uh,
she had a three year old son who's my
son.
He's my oldest son and uh,
you know,
adopted him and he was in the navy,
but uh,
we're in San Francisco,
is our first a month living together and
she grew up in the south and called
black people narrows.
And I said,
you know,
we're going to have more kids.
We just can't have that.
And she said,
well,
that's just what we do.
And,
and I said,
well,
let's make a deal.
Not Do that.
And she said,
well,
you're smoking.
I don't want them smoking.
And that's the day I quit smoking.
And she never said nigger again.
Quit smoking cigarettes.
But our kids are pretty well balanced.
Wow.
That's a great story.
That's a,
you know,
sometimes it just takes one thing to get
you to quit something as stupid as small
group.
One realization I had,
I have a really important reason and I
didn't want my kids growing up like
that.
It's
beautiful.
Well,
you shouldn't want them growing up
around someone who smoked cigarettes
too,
right?
Well,
that's true.
It's a weird thing that they did where
they got that through.
I mean,
if you want to really look at problems
that we have right now in our culture,
there's a big one and there's a big one
that all these people who run for office
who get into office,
they're all concerned with the loss of
lives.
They're all concerned with health and
safety.
They're all concerned with environmental
pollution.
They're concerned with economic growth,
are concerned with all these different
things to benefit human beings,
but yet they never mentioned cigarettes.
I mean,
you want to talk about one of the
biggest and most obvious pieces of
evidence for conspiracy,
a conspiracy where half a fucking
billion people die every year.
I mean,
how many fucking people die every year
from cigarettes?
It's like 4,000
in America,
just in this country.
We would.
I don't know what it is worldwide,
but it's got to be something crazy.
Now we find out what the number is.
Nobody's ever died from cannabis and Odi
of cannabis.
It just imagine that there was an issue
where 400,000
people died in your,
in your country a year,
$400,000,
and yet no one brings it up ever.
That's insanity.
That's so hard to believe that you're
not talking about 400,000
lifetime,
which is an insane body account.
That's an insane body count for more
than all the wars civil thing about like
19.
You know,
whenever the.
They found out that cigarettes are bad
for you.
It was the 19 fifties or sixties or
whatever it was where they first started
going,
hey,
I think there's a connection between
these people dying of fucking cancer and
smoking on these burning chemical soaked
rags.
You know,
there might be a connection there that
think about how many people have died
since then.
Millions,
many,
many things.
And then each,
you're an estimated 443,000
people and other pushing them on,
uh,
on the Asian kids,
you know,
that's,
they're really pushing cigarettes over
there because it's not growing here.
Put that backups here.
It says each year an estimated 443,000
die prematurely from smoking or exposure
to secondhand smoke,
which is even darker.
And another eight point 6 million live
with a serious illness caused by
smoking.
Wow.
Approximately 46 point 6 million US
adults smoked cigarettes.
Wow,
that's scary.
But both my father and my brother died
from smoking cigarettes.
That's an insane number.
I didn't know it was that high.
Wow.
That's like under 4 million a decade.
Just.
It's also like knowing that you've been,
like your society has been infiltrated
by like aliens that are designed to kill
people.
If it was aliens that were killing
people and not cigarettes,
we would be terrified.
We'd feel like we're under attack.
It will be a war and cigarettes.
Yeah.
There's these aliens are killing 400,000
people every year.
What do we do that making 800 million
people sick as well?
Like fuck,
what do we do?
And you know,
people that say,
well,
I'm going to smoke until I'm 45 or 50 or
whatever.
My father and my brother both spoke
until they were about 50 and they each
only lived about 10 years after they
quit smoking.
They both died at 63.
So,
uh,
you know,
it's all smoking.
I did it,
you know,
it's,
it's horrible.
It's amazing how many people go for
that.
It's so hard to quit.
You know,
you have to have some kind of really big
motivation because it's.
Nicotine is more addicting than heroin.
I've heard that before.
Um,
it sounds like it makes sense,
but you know,
the heroin addiction is and what
everybody thinks is not 100 percent.
This is closer to only about 30 percent
really good.
Physically addicted.
Really?
Yeah.
It's low nicotine's,
but 75 percent and heroines about 30
percent.
We need to find out who those lucky
bitches are that are like 25 percent non
addicted to cigarettes,
30 percent non addicted to heroin.
Figuring out who those guys are.
Check their jeans.
Yeah.
What an awesome fucking trait to have.
Not get addicted,
you know,
it's,
it's really sad.
It's really sad because it's just
evidence that as long as money is
around,
you're not looking at people's health
and welfare
and,
and most of us are addicted to caffeine
like it or not know when you do a diet
for Iowasca,
you have to go off caffeine for at least
a week ahead of time as well in our
tradition that I'm involved in or was
involved in that caffeine was one of the
things you gave up for at least a week
ahead of time.
And I had to start weaning myself a
month ahead of time.
Just cutting it down and less and less
because when I go cold Turkey on
caffeine,
within three days,
I'm up standing up all night with cramps
in my legs.
Not just the headaches.
Really at caffeine that takes go cold
Turkey on caffeine for just even if you
only drink two or three cups a day.
Well I used to,
um,
when I would stay up late writing,
I would drink a shitload of coffee and
all I was concerned with was getting the
writing done.
And then I realized one day I woke up
and the next morning got out fucking
pounding headache and I was like,
oh my head,
or then I realized they're just hadn't
had a cup of coffee yet and I went no
way.
Like I allowed myself to get this hooked
on this shit.
So I quit.
And then I took like several months off.
Then I started drinking coffee
conservatively since then.
But I went without it for quite a while
because it was just like,
that's.
I don't like that.
Like I had a headache from not having
something that didn't make any sense.
That's stupid.
Well,
after I had been off,
you know,
we do a week before and the week after
and after I'd been off it for two weeks,
a half a cup of coffee,
lammy buzzing all day.
I mean,
it's a real drug.
It's a great drug if you only use it
once in a while,
it's legit.
You know,
it's another thing about coffee is it's
everywhere.
I mean,
you want to talk about a drug that you
can just tap into every five steps.
It's the only drug that labor contracts
require.
You have to have a coffee break.
Yeah.
That's interesting,
isn't it?
Yeah.
When,
you know,
back in the old days,
they used to smoke cigarettes in the
office.
Oh,
the old days.
Uh,
let's see.
Well,
I guess it was a while ago,
but about 18 years ago is when they
finally got rid of it where I was,
where.
Oh Wow.
And rise in 18 years.
It wasn't verizon,
those Gtd then.
But uh,
yeah.
And you know,
cubicle hell and there was one corner.
They put all the.
See all the people in the one corner
there were smokers,
you know.
And of course it filled the whole room
any hours.
So you could see this little cloud over
this one area.
What year was it where they did it with
airplanes because I remember the
airplane thing.
I remember if I,
I remember a lot of airplane rides and
smoking though.
It's so weird.
The airplane thing was so weird because
I had to sit and smoke and a couple of
times with the only seats that were
available.
What was the difference between smoking?
It didn't matter,
but you know when you're trying to get a
seat and that's all they have.
The sorry.
Oh,
you a know,
but I mean the.
The smoke was the same no matter where
you were in the plane,
you know,
what I felt like and how much filtration
are they even doing?
I mean,
how much can they do?
Where are they getting there for them?
I know there's been some lawsuits by
flight attendants who got cancer from
secondhand smoke.
Oh,
I would imagine that the flight
attendants are smoking in this picture.
What happened to our world where people
just smoked up a fucking storm like
this?
Well also there's some improvement.
Yeah,
but what a weird,
weird,
weird habit.
Their habit that kills half a fucking
million people every year,
just in one country,
country world.
What is the worldwide?
Did we find out what the worldwide
cigarette deaths are?
Let me find out right here because I
need to know this.
This just doesn't even make sense.
No,
and I don't think we're still
subsidizing tobacco farmers,
but we may be.
We had been up until very recently.
I know.
It's hilarious.
Isn't it?
Well,
we subsidized oil companies.
I didn't know about that until Ana
Kasparian told me about it.
I.
I heard her talking about that and I'll
tell you what,
the oil depletion allowance is.
Part of the reason Kennedy was murdered,
the oil depletion allowance in Texas is
huge.
Tobacco use Kilz.
Five point 4 million a year.
Oh my God.
What does that one say?
Eight dollars million.
$5 million deaths by 20.
30.
The one I'm looking at is I'm a World
Health Organization.
I'm on the CDC.
Don't know which one's more legit.
Which ones more legit?
It was $5 million.
$5.
Million deaths per year.
That is so many God damn people.
Can you work for that company?
How do you be that company?
You know,
but.
But you know what?
Here's the other problem.
I'm pro you doing whatever you want to
do.
I don't have a problem with as long as
it doesn't.
Yeah.
In harm.
Somebody else.
Well,
you know,
when my dad died that harmed my mother.
Yes.
Smoking is harming people no matter what
you're doing and that secondhand smoke.
A lot of people get cancer because they
live with a small group.
There are some studies to say it's even
worse than smoking itself,
so that's ridiculous.
And you know,
I grew up in a house with a secondhand
smoke.
My Dad was a smoker and uh,
my mom was a smoker when I was really
young.
She gave it up,
I think by the time I was seven.
We had a basement workbench and back
then and all the beer was in tall
bottles and uh,
my dad would be down there working in
the basement and my little brother who
was four and a half years younger than
me,
he had a habit of going around draining
the bottles.
And my dad had,
well when he,
he left a little bit of beer and the
bottom one for his cigarette thing and
he'd dropped about three or four bullets
in it.
My brother,
he can still see him spewing his puke as
he ran up the stairs.
Yeah,
I'd imagine what that must have tasted
like.
I don't think he drank beer as a
teenager.
He had a bad tasting.
That's hilarious.
That doesn't even seem real does doesn't
mean that seems like something.
If you had to explain to someone who
didn't understand human beings,
you know,
the expression always used.
If an alien came here and was viewing
our culture and they saw this aspect of
it,
they'd be like,
what the fuck are you people doing?
Well,
I,
I started smoking in freshman year in
high school.
You know,
that's the thing everybody had to do.
My sister did as well.
I tried it.
I was a year older than her.
I tried a cigarette.
I'm was marco.
This is stupid.
Oh,
I hated it.
It took me a long time.
I feel like it,
but I wanted to be in the crowd,
you know,
peer pressure.
Well,
I know a lot of people.
Brian Read Ben who is on this show,
he,
um,
he's quit a couple of times and he just
can't do it.
He quits.
Then he gets right back to it.
He got sick recently.
We took off like nine days and going
right back to it,
he just,
he just gets pulled right back into it.
Even those e-cigarettes,
like he doesn't even use those,
you know,
I don't,
I just,
I don't understand how people can,
can see all these numbers and not,
not think it applies to them.
That's,
that's an addiction that's I know,
but it's a weird one.
Like why would you kill yourself like
that?
That's the weirdest one ever because
it's so slow.
God,
but it's gotta be.
It's gotta be pretty fast though.
It's inevitable.
You say slow,
but those people,
they feel like shit when they walk
upstairs and stuff like that's not slow
man,
because that's like diminishing your
life right now.
What it means to me,
if you can't go up the stairs fast,
if you're a normal person and you,
you're not old,
you're not a,
you're not injured and you can't walk up
a flight of stairs without being out of
breath.
Right?
Like your life is on like real,
like low water.
You've got something wrong and you're
not.
You know,
if you don't,
that's all the energy you have.
You're missing energy.
Like something has robbed you of energy.
I don't know if you realize it because
this new life that you have,
this is just your reality.
It's like having water in your ears and
then you cleaned the water out and
you're like,
oh,
now I can hear like your.
When you pop your ears and coming home
from an airplane ride and you're,
you know,
you feel stopped up and you pinch your
nose and then blow on it so the air
can't get out.
Your ears pop and you go,
oh,
this is what it sounds like.
Well,
you know,
my,
my aunt and uncle,
she lived into her nineties but my poor
uncle died a lot younger and they were
both smokers.
He finally quit because he had
emphysema.
He'd be sitting there with the oxygen
and she'd be smoking right next to him,
outlived him by 20 years.
Of course she did poisoned them.
It's just what a weird thing.
Yeah.
People poison each other,
you know,
it's poison wives.
There's a Bob newhart stand up or it's
one of his old things where he'd sit on
the stage and put is that Jamie's?
That their lungs,
black lung,
Lachlan's,
black lungs are smokers and the other
ones are,
what is it?
Why is it,
why is it hooked up to a machine?
Is making them inflate,
inflate,
and here's.
Oh,
so it's showing you what a,
an actual black cigarette smoking
[inaudible] lung is like,
wow,
this is a wild long,
a healthy lung.
Oh my God.
What a difference.
A difference.
That's insane.
You need to put your wallpaper on your
computer if you're a smoker.
Just the color.
So horrifying.
So you know,
they're not working very well.
Oh my God.
That aren't working well.
Yeah,
I know.
Smart
people that love cigarettes.
It's so weird.
You know,
this is gold Bob newhart routine.
You'd sit in a chair and put a shooter
here.
And he was Sir Walter Raleigh,
uh,
or he was a guy in England and Sir
Walter Raleigh was calling him,
telling him about the stuff you sent him
back and he says it's called tobacco and
and it's a leaf and you light it on fire
and what do you do with it?
It's really a classic non smoking a bit.
That's funny.
And that was probably from 1960 or
something.
Probably the fifties maybe.
Maybe.
I don't know when he started his.
One of his early things.
This,
it.
There it is.
Yeah.
You pick up your extension.
What?
What'd you.
It's not in wall again.
I love baby gets good air.
And Your Hawaii,
they're fine.
Heroin while they got a.
bought all the turkeys over here last
November.
There are still A.
Yeah,
they're walking all over London.
See that in my holiday over here while
in America you've got another winter for
us.
So while told faculty what's tobacco?
While a late.
You've got tons of it.
You probably 80 tons of leads while
you're building for awhile.
But I don't know if you noticed last
time.
We have plenty of leads over here in
England.
We're up to.
It's a special kind of leave it some
kind of folded as it was.
Not Exactly.
Uh,
what,
what do you do with Elise Wall?
Lots of different things.
I do things now.
And once you take a pinch of tobacco,
I imagine it was.
Yeah.
Baghdad.
Golden rods seems to do it over here.
While tobacco has to use it,
if you can feel it mentally,
but other than that little piece of
paper,
roll it up.
You don't have to tell me why you stick
it in your ear.
Right.
Okay.
Well,
and I want to get people in it.
Oh,
you want to get on the inner go the
boys.
I was just so funny.
Build your coffee.
What coffee was at the drink you make
out of beans and then you know,
you drink it in the morning.
Why do you.
Yeah.
One time I was on the ball.
If you can help them with branding lead,
I'm sure they'll go for the beat.
You
don't call me anymore.
Oh,
that's great.
From
I saw it actually on the Ed Sullivan
show.
We used to watch that every Sunday
night.
Jackie gleason the Saturday Ed Sullivan
on Sunday.
Wow,
that's fascinating.
That's a.
the,
the just the way he broke,
broke it down was really interesting
without even bringing up the deaths.
It's still hilarious.
Yeah.
It's like,
why would you do that?
He didn't have,
he didn't state any of the health
concerns and this was before they were
really known too.
Isn't that funny?
You know,
his early sixties,
late fifties,
something like,
did you ever see the lean narrow
Leonardo dicaprio movie about,
um,
J Edgar Hoover?
No,
I haven't seen that.
When j Edgar Hoover was a young,
he was kind of sickly and so his doctor
prescribed cigarettes.
That's what made him somewhere and
wanted him to smoke cigarettes.
We knew as a young man,
like his mother in the movie is like
saying to him and I listened to the
doctorate and smoke those cigarettes.
Wow.
Yeah,
it's weird
that,
you know,
that was a peer pressure cultural thing
you started at when you're really young
because other guys were doing or the
movies,
you know,
the movies really pushed cigarettes.
You can't see any of his old black and
white movies.
I'm smoking.
That's true.
Right.
And TV shows everybody always smoke
cigarettes.
It was like a part of being cool.
So newscasters use to smoke,
you know,
that's so weird.
News casters,
they are,
that's the one of the weirdest rungs of
show business is the newscaster.
To me,
when I look at news casting,
I feel like it's like I'm watching a
silent movie,
you know,
this is like some antiquated form of
entertainment that we don't need
anymore.
Like the way if you watch an old like
animated or an old.
I'm a black and white film where,
where it has subtitles and like,
like Nosferatu.
It's kind of fascinating because it's a
time capsule,
you know,
you're looking into this time where this
was the relevant form of medium.
This is,
this is how the,
they got their film out.
It had to be like this,
there was no sound.
So they would play some music and then
there will be a,
like a script and the script would be
red and you know,
break in between scenes and the screen
would go and be alive.
Piano playing and yeah.
Yeah.
But if someone tried to do that today,
you'd be like,
what the fuck are you doing?
Like this is so stupid.
Why don't you just make a movie?
Like why are you doing this?
Like let them talk like why you just,
why is it only written?
That's so dumb.
And that's sort of what it's like when
you watch a newscast.
It's like why are doing it like this?
They
read the news,
you read the news,
but you,
you barely cover anything.
You cover these little tiny three minute
chunks on super complex issues where a
minute of that is telling you what
they're gonna do next.
Oh yeah,
let's.
And then there's just also a lot of
nonsense and things that they know that
people want to listen to and tune in.
Like whether it's like,
you know,
Alex Baldwin grabbed a Paparazzi by the
neck or something like that.
It's like infotainment now.
Not In.
It's weird.
It's weird that they're still doing it.
It seems like something that they should
have stopped doing a long time ago.
We're come up with a new way to do it
where I don't feel like you're
bullshitting me.
I don't know anybody who talks like
that.
There's only one new show I watched and
that's a John Stewart daily show.
Yes.
That's a great new share.
The only mean I liked him because he
calls out both people.
He's very consistent on his pretty equal
opportunity.
I mean if the Obama administration does
some silly,
if the Bush administration did something
silly,
he,
he's,
he's really.
He'll go after he.
He definitely leans left.
Oh sure.
But he,
he'll go after Obama just as quickly as
anybody else,
but they can't rely on that for news.
It's more closest I get to watch a new
show me.
It's the Internet by far the Internet in
a big leap,
but it then becomes a matter of like if
you ever seen people getting into
discussion on the Internet and someone
will put up an article from the Daily
Mail and then they'll go and the other
person arguing with them be like the
Daily Mail.
Really,
you believe in fucking link from the
Daily Mail.
And then it becomes,
all right,
well what,
what,
where can I get my God damn information
from like.
And it becomes an issue of what's the
source?
And you know,
who's,
uh,
where's the money behind this,
this organization?
Because these organizations are going to
be eventually chest,
like CBS or NBC or Fox News.
It's gonna be there's gonna to be
influences buying them so that they're
not going to be like,
this is the raw data that we're
collecting from all around the world.
Here it is,
but also some commercials during the
peak of the occupied movement.
I spent hundreds of hours watching a
ustream tv because you were watching the
Ra thing taking place.
Yeah,
you were really interested in your
podcast was really interesting.
During that time you did a lot of social
commentary where you might not
ordinarily do that and you were talking
about how important that the occupy
movement was.
I feel like that's the.
The discussion about the occupy movement
has dwindled dramatically.
It has,
but I'll tell you the way I look at the
occupy movement of what we've seen,
if they had announced in the beginning
saying,
okay,
we're going to do phase one and what
we're going to do is raise awareness
around the world that there's a big
income distribution problem that we have
one percent 99 percent and we're going
to show that this is true everywhere in
the world and that we're living in a
police state because the police are
going to shut us down.
If that's.
That's our only objective.
That's phase one.
If that was put out that way,
I think they'd say,
oh,
it was a big success.
Now,
just the other day,
there's a thing in the news that the
occupy New York people had $400,000
left in their account
donations and they took that 400,000
and they bought $15,000,000
with a credit card debt that people
would run up on medical bills and for
gave it all and now they're using that
knowledge that they've learned to do
videos and stuff to teach people how
they can do that for themselves.
To buy their credit card debt for
pennies on the dollar instead of what
they're going after him for.
So the,
and you know,
I've got friends in,
in uh,
Australia and the UK and a couple of
places here in the states,
friends I say Internet friends.
I've never met him in person that are
still very interested or involved,
I should say in occupy type activities.
But what we know now is that we're not
alone,
that they're all around the world.
There's people that are thinking like
this.
So it's more about consciousness
awakening than a movement,
but I think it's still a simmering under
the surface.
And uh,
you know,
I've got a lot of bad press obviously,
but like I was starting to say,
I,
I spent hundreds of hours watching and
interacting and chat rooms with these
people and all.
So I felt like,
you know,
I knew a little bit better what was
going on then what was coming out in the
press and stuff like that because that
was all slanted.
And uh,
these people are really on top of
things.
And we do now.
No one percent 99 percent.
So nothing else,
it was pretty successful as movement
that way.
Well,
yeah.
I'm pretty successful as a,
as a like a talking point.
And it became the talking point because
he used to be talked about like the top
percent,
right?
Several percent,
five percent,
whatever it is.
But then when it became the one
percenters,
the 99 percent,
then it became a real thing.
Everybody was like,
oh,
okay.
Yeah,
that's David Graver I think is the one
that got credit for coming out with
that.
Yeah.
That becomes a viral idea and people
start discussing it.
Do you know that 99 percent of the
people in this country don't.
Only one percent owns 50 percent of the
wealth or whatever the fuck it is.
And you're like,
what?
Well,
it's actually 300 people own 45.
Well that's amazing.
Yeah,
those guys are ballers.
they.
When I think that.
What's interesting about all this,
I have a very optimistic view of the
human race,
I think.
I think ultimately people want to live a
life that's harmonious and happy.
I think if that's true with you,
and that's true with me and that's true
with pretty much everybody that I know,
it's got to be true with all people,
so it's a matter of spreading that idea
through the population as quickly as
possible to as many people as possible
and let them understand that the way
that we've been living our lives for
decades and generation after generation
is just the momentum of an ignorant
past.
It doesn't have to be that way anymore
and it doesn't mean that you can have
government and it doesn't mean you can't
have corporations and it doesn't mean
that you can't have people who have more
wealth and other people.
It just means everything should be done
fairly and if you guys are putting laws
into place that allow you to fuck people
over,
allow you to move your factories to
Mexico and have people work for pennies
on the dollar,
allow.
There's a lot of shit that you're being
allowed to do.
As far as like polluting the
environment.
That shouldn't be kosher and there.
There should be a way to resolve that
and the to resolve that is not you spend
money to change the law,
to make it legal for you to do something
that's horrible.
The would should be is figure out what
the fuck you can do to make sure that
you don't pollute the environment.
Structure your loss so that you don't
rip people off.
Figure out a way to make it so that
you're not in control of a giant chunk
of of,
of this river,
that your factories by the pollution
that leaks into it.
Figure out how to make it so that you're
not poisoning the wells of of people in
town because you're fracking and you're
pulling a natural gas out of the ground
and destroy these people's wells.
Figure out how to do it without doing
that,
and if you can't do it,
don't do it.
Just don't do anything when you put
money in front of humanity.
It seems to me like we can still have
competition.
Seems to me we can still have
capitalism.
It just needs to be a moral capitalism
and ethical capitalism where humanity
and people and just caring about people
and realizing we're not going to be in
here forever.
It's a fairly short ride to be fucking
nice to people and all the money that
you make.
Being an asshole and putting people out
of work.
You're not gonna.
Appreciate that money.
Most likely,
if you're in a position to put a bunch
of people out of work and make a fuck
load of money and fuck someone over,
you probably already have a lot of
money.
You're already in a sweet spot,
in some weird position of influence,
but enjoy what you got.
You fucking stranger.
He a weird person trying to pollute the
river.
You weird asshole who doesn't care about
polluting someone's wells.
You should be devastated if that
happens.
You should stop operations,
but no,
because they know they can pull billions
of dollars worth of natural resources
out of the ground by still continuing
these practices.
They're like,
they don't even consider not doing it.
They just do it.
They just keep doing it and they find
ways to do it where it harms last or it
has less of an environmental impact,
allegedly,
you know,
I mean,
I don't even know what the numbers are,
but the raw data shows that they fucked
up a lot of areas doing this stuff,
but no one's talking about stopping
doing it.
They're just going for it.
See,
you're,
you've hit the nail on the head is that
it's not about regulating things from
the top down and trying to get people to
change your ways is getting people to
change themselves.
And one,
a good examples of a corporation is a
Dr.
Bronner's soap company.
Dr Bonner as the hemp soap.
Yes.
Yeah.
They might be hippies.
What do you think?
Well,
he has went with the guy,
I think he's like 25 years old when his
dad died and he had to take over the
company and didn't really want to.
But he,
uh,
for one of the first things he did,
it says nobody in the company can make
more than five times the lowest paid
person in the company.
And he's,
he's got a really.
You know,
very conscientious conscious company and
I've read,
you know,
there's a lot of others like that and
it's got to be from the bottom up where
they just start doing it and they're
successful.
He's competing in the soap business.
And uh,
in fact if you go to burning man,
it's the only soap that'll get all that
dust off your hands.
If you go to burning man,
you've got other problems.
Somebody,
somebody on twitter,
me,
I should get you to go to burning.
Yeah.
People keep asking me to go to burning
man.
Look,
I meet plenty of dirty hippies in my
everyday life.
There's too many of them there.
Well,
you know,
I don't like camping.
I don't enjoy the desert.
Had to,
can't stand the heat.
And I couldn't wait to get back,
but I stopped going.
I haven't gone since 2007 now.
Good move.
Let's become commercialized.
Oh yeah.
And this is so expensive and in,
in,
in your offline for like two months
afterwards trying to recover.
But it,
it was,
uh,
the times I went where some of the most
spectacular time.
I'm obviously talking shit because I've
never been,
I don't want all the people that
actually go and enjoy it.
Don't think I'm being serious.
I go have a good time and I know that
most of you are probably cool as fuck.
The problem is there's that small
percentage that's going to be so
annoying that I can't go
know a percentage.
That's one of the things that was kind
of unique about burning man I thought is
that uh,
in fact it was the first year we went a
camp across from us was starting in the
afternoon,
some loud music and all and we had a
bunch of people just sitting around
talking.
And so one of the ladies in our camp
took up a tray full of cold beers and
popsicles over to him and said,
can we bribe you to turn the music off
for a couple of hours?
And Oh sure.
And they turned it off and you know,
it's a functioning anarchy is what it
is.
Well,
that's very nice.
That's a great.
And you're right,
it's gotten a,
I wouldn't say commercial,
but it's gotten really big.
But one of the,
one of the people who I know a was at
this year's camp and she's been there I
think 19 years in a row and said this
was the best year she'd ever been.
Now when I started going,
it was like 25,000
people and it was much more manageable
than 60 some now.
Well for the most part,
I mean this is pretty much almost
anywhere I go when I run into people
that want to talk about things,
it's a cool conversation for the most
part,
99 percent of the time.
But there's always that one percent,
maybe one out of 100,
it's my might be even less than that.
Or someone just gives you a brutal ear
beating on the power of crystals and
you're like,
oh Jesus,
we stop.
Or someone who they know who's a healer,
you're like,
oh Christ.
Someone who they know that's that
channels.
I tell this guy fucking talking to me
about a channel or the other day I was
like,
please stop by.
They used to call them schizophrenia,
but whatever it is,
it's like,
you know,
come on man.
If you're not channeling,
shut the fuck up.
If you are channeling,
let me see it because if you're not
channeling,
if you'd never channeled,
how do you know what's going on there?
You don't know what's going on.
There is.
It could be a lot of factors.
You know that that guy might be losing
his marbles right there.
You might be watching an act to be
watching a crazy person who needs a lot
of attention.
I guess.
I miss those people at burning man.
I was into drugs and booze.
Well,
this wasn't even at burning man.
This is just a conversation with someone
was.
One of the weird things about the
podcast is so many people have to talk
to me about something.
They have this idea that they have to
tell me and you know,
many times it's very interesting,
but many times it's not.
And many times it's just brutal
nonsense.
Feel like,
okay,
I have this friend of mine who believes
in psychics and he's going on and on
about the psychic who,
uh,
who told him everything about his life
and I go everything about your life.
And he goes,
yeah,
I go,
did he tell you any shit you don't know?
He goes,
no,
and I go,
well,
don't you think that's weird?
He goes to and he knew about my
grandmother.
I go,
don't you know about your grandmother?
Why do you want someone to tell you shit
you already know?
Did you ever think that maybe you've
been manipulated and maybe he structured
questions in a way that got you to
reveal certain information or think that
you were.
We're not answering it for him,
but he was leading you in a certain
direction.
Did you ever think that that might be
possible?
And he likes pause and like,
no,
because I never even thought about it.
I go,
well,
you should probably think about that.
Yeah.
A lot of people get sucked into these
things without giving it thought.
And then some of them,
the psychedelic grommets,
it's,
it's even goofy or people come up to
you.
But at one time at a conference,
a friend of mine had just given his
presentation and I went up to say
something to him and he was surrounded
by a bunch of people and there's this
one girl who was obviously just really
whacked out on something.
She had spiked purple hair and she's
piercings everywhere and she couldn't
stand still and she's bouncing around
and she says,
well,
how come people don't approve of
psychedelics?
And he said,
well,
they're afraid they're going to turn out
like you.
That is an issue.
Yeah.
It's an issue of potheads too.
Oh yeah.
A lot of them are lazy,
sloppy potheads that just,
you know,
they're there.
So loathsome to be around that they make
you connect that behavior to marijuana.
When I was a kid,
I thought that marijuana made you lazy
and I had all these negative things
attached to it until I met my friend
Eddie Bravo,
who was a smart guy.
He was very articulate and he liked to
smoke pot and talk about all these crazy
things and and like to make his music.
When he was high,
I was like,
you make music with you.
I thought it was something that turned
you into a moron.
He's like,
drew,
like,
I didn't want to get like that.
And he was like,
no,
no.
It enhances your creativity.
And,
and once I immediately started smoking
pot or once I started smoking pot,
I immediately started presenting all the
dopey stereotypical pot ads.
I was like,
God damn,
you guys ruined something.
That's amazing.
Fuck you.
You ruined the image of something that's
amazing by being a knucklehead.
You know,
I had experienced when I was working
back in the phone company and one of the
guys I worked for was a vice president.
He was pretty far up there and we worked
really closely together for almost a
year and a,
I won't go into the whole story,
but after about a year,
we're at dinner one night and he says he
was making a confession for a reason and
he said,
well,
I smoked pot.
And I said,
really?
Let's go to my house right now.
Now we'd worked together for a year in a
really high powered environment and I
found out later that he's going up to
the car two or three times during the
day to have few Tokes,
so you can function pretty highly if you
know what you're doing.
Oh,
you can definitely function pretty
highly,
especially if you get used to it.
The way,
the way I describe it as it's like
surfing.
You watch a guy who's a really good
surfer or girls are really good surfer,
madigan bride,
some crazy ways,
but if you put me on a surfboard,
fallen flat on my fucking stupid face.
I can't serve at all.
I've never done it.
So if I tried it,
I'm sure I would suck at it.
I tried it once and I sucked at it.
Marijuana smoking is like riding a
psychedelic wave and there's A.
There's a wave of the substance,
the thc that hits your body and you can
either ride that wave or you can trip
out on the fact that you're on this wave
and freak out and started getting
paranoid or going down dark places in
your mind or you know,
just spiral.
That's possible too,
but once you get good at it,
you don't.
That doesn't happen very often.
It's like you're standing there smoking
pot longer than I have.
That's impossible.
I had my first token 1985.
No,
I started smoking pot in 2001.
Oh,
okay.
Well,
yeah.
You're another late bloomer.
I thought it was.
Yeah,
I thought it was stupid until I was 30
or something like that.
I thought it was so dumb.
I was like,
this is the stupidest thing ever.
These people are wasting their lives.
Smoking Pot.
I didn't know how at first.
Yeah,
I'd been a smoker and you know,
I,
I got this pot and I,
I wasn't inhaling proper really.
And,
and I spoke last on my third joint and
it was like over a period of three or
four weeks and finally I got really all
of a sudden I figured it out.
You're going to inhale.
And the women that have given me the
cigarettes,
I called her at work or at work,
I was off and I called her at work.
I said it works.
I got stone and she says,
don't shout,
that's Funky,
but down the laws.
But it took me a while to even learn
how.
And uh,
yeah,
there's a lot of people that are worried
about people finding out they smoke pot.
Oh yeah.
I think that's,
you know,
not out here anymore,
but not as much,
but still in a lot of ways,
like I've had conversations with people.
They go,
you know,
hey,
you ever face any repercussions because
you talk about pot.
And I'm like,
realistically anybody that would be
upset with me because they found out
that I smoke pot,
I really don't want to talk to them
anyway.
Right.
Like if they don't like me,
I probably wouldn't like them anyway.
Like that's such a stupid stance to
take.
I just listen to what I have to say
about it and if it doesn't make sense to
you,
that's one thing.
But if you're upset at me because he
found out that I smoke pot.
Okay,
take care.
I worried about that at one time.
But finally,
you know,
I've done the podcast now and I'm pretty
much out of the closet,
but I still get a little resistance from
people in the family that are unhappy
with it.
Well,
I've had friends that have had some
serious drug issues and I've also had
people that I've talked to that were
like real straight edge and one of the
reason why they were straight edge,
like maybe they lost a family member to
addiction and I've had conversations
with them about it before where I
totally understand that and I totally
get that mindset and I probably would
have been in that mindset and myself if
it not for several people that I've met
in my life because I,
I'd,
I'd lost a friend to heroin and I lost a
friend in high school to here to people
to heroin.
Actually that I know more than that,
I think I lost at least one other ones
to take pills to like opiate pills.
So I guess he's a that that would be
considered along the same lines.
And I could get the idea where people
would be upset at people that smoke pot
or what anything because he would think
that would connect it to,
you know,
losing their family members.
But man,
it's unfortunate that the word drug is
such a broad term.
Let's see.
That's one of the reasons I'm doing what
I'm doing is because we it with proper
drug education,
those guys might still be alive,
you know,
that we don't educate.
We just say no instead of k,
n,
O,
w and uh,
so,
you know,
I think that if we can just get a couple
more generations behind us where people
are,
are not so oppressed by,
uh,
my,
one of my favorite stories I got from a,
a kid and listen to the podcast when he
was like,
he just got out of high school.
He's 18.
His father caught him growing mushrooms
in his closet and turned them into the
police.
And the kid wound up doing a hard time
of felony and so he came back out of
jail and he just went,
started going to church with them three
or four times a week and became a
fundamentalist Christian again and just
went through the exercises.
Then he found the salon and realize
that,
hey,
he wasn't crazy.
There's other people that do this tune.
He got himself a fast food job,
saved up his money.
He's out in the west coast working as an
artist right now.
And so he got out of that oppressive
atmosphere.
So that's fascinating.
Gate kids tell me they've come out of
the closet being gay,
but they're afraid to tell their parents
that their psychedelic or they smoke
pot.
Wow.
Think about that.
That's fascinating.
Did you to have a great smoke pot or
smoke pulled joke there,
but don't do it.
It's not worth it.
Don't go for it.
Yeah,
I did it.
I did a podcast,
Daniel for a young man up in San
Francisco,
Cisco that started the psychedelic
society up there.
He started just two years ago and he's
got 4,000
members already and stuff and he's a
young guy,
mid twenties and he said he went to
college and never smoked pot until he
got to college and got into pot and
mushrooms and now he started the
Psychedelic Society of San Francisco and
has 4,000
members and he's a drug,
a advocate and activist and,
but anyhow,
he has a.
He did a talk that I podcast called
coming out of the psychedelic closet and
I got a letter in the mail the other day
from a kid that,
uh,
he,
he sent a little drawing.
He did it in the closet with his name on
it and he says,
I just can't come out of it yet.
Wow.
But if I was still in the workaday world
working in the belly of the beast,
I,
uh,
now in California or someplace with
medical marijuana,
I'd probably be honest about that,
but I would never talk about
psychedelics in the corporate world.
I mean,
that's a quick way to get fired.
Yeah.
It's fascinating that you can't talk
about an experience that you've had 10
years ago.
Right.
They'll label you as some crazy hippie
that's trying to clean his act up.
You know,
you're trying to pretend you're one of
us.
Normally you just fucking dirty,
hippie doing acid and your lunch break,
right?
Yeah.
I missed the hippie thing.
I was in the navy then,
so I'm doing mine at this stage of my
life.
And today you were in the navy and the
sixties?
Yeah,
66 to 70.
I was in Vietnam and off the coast with
the navy and actually my wife was a navy
nurse too.
So we're both in the navy then.
That's amazing,
man.
What,
what did you do back then?
Was there any uh,
substances?
Okay.
Alcohol and alcohol.
Lots.
Lots and lots of alcohol.
In fact,
uh,
I can tell you where I was and the day
you were born,
you were born in [inaudible].
Sixty seven?
Yes.
I was in the officer's club,
had Subic Bay in the Philippines.
We're on a break from the gumline.
And the reason I remember it because I
was drinking my first flaming flagging,
celebrating my 25th birthday.
Wow.
You're born on the same day.
That's amazing.
And the reason that the flaming flag and
was one of the traditions in our
boardroom and it was a brandy snifter
and you'd light the brandy on fire and
then yet sip it down with a brand new on
fire.
Well,
it was in the afternoon.
We didn't realize that brandy had been
burning a while.
And by the time I didn't have any
problem getting liquid down by burnt my
lip on the damn glass it was.
But anyhow,
I'm on my 25th birthday.
Was your born day so.
Wow.
And you're out getting fucked up when
celebration in the world.
Hey world.
Joe Rogan has arrived.
The whole wardroom went out and
celebrated their lips and only me.
They didn't.
They weren't dumb enough to do that.
But no,
I didn't have anything until I was 42
years old.
Was it around you at all?
Did you see it anywhere?
You know,
I went through college without even
hearing the word marijuana.
What would you a school.
The Moon?
I graduated in [inaudible] 64.
I went to a small boys' college in the
Midwest called Notre Dame.
You went to Notre Dame and you never
heard about weed?
Not In.
Not In 60 to 64.
That's insane.
How is that possible?
It wasn't there.
Oh my God.
That's amazing.
It wasn't there.
And what was that like?
Oh,
well,
he was very repressive.
Would imagine it'd be very,
very.
There were no girls there.
And uh,
we had to get up at least three days a
week.
You had to sign in outside the chapel
between seven and 7:30,
fully dressed a lights out.
We're at 10:30
and lights out was pretty serious.
You couldn't have an electric clock or
an electric blanket because they cut off
the electricity to your room.
And I had a classmate kicked out of
school for studying by candle light.
I mean,
that's how repressive it was.
It was,
it was really a backward place studying
by candlelight.
Got You kicked out of school probably
because he stole the candles from the
grotto or something.
Oh,
no,
no.
It was for studying by candlelight,
so I got kicked out of school.
That's so dumb.
Oh,
it was a crazy place.
So insanely dumb.
We were the only class up until
recently,
I think that a never once saw a winning
football team for years of losses.
Wow.
And so I parlayed that by selling my
four year books on Ebay and I marketed
it that way and somebody bought them for
156 bucks.
That's funny.
That's interesting.
What a weird time.
But I was,
I was living in Dallas in and I was 42
years old when ecstasy hit the streets,
mgma.
And uh,
I,
I'd never taken any drugs.
I didn't even smoke pot.
Came out of the navy and everything in
that store and attorney,
right?
Yeah.
In,
in Houston I was an attorney then in
Dallas I started a computer company.
I had a personal computer company that
was in 1981.
We outgrows Microsoft,
you know,
I had four color picture in Forbes
magazine,
made the front page of the Wall Street
Journal.
Really?
Then ibm came in and crushed us like a
bug.
Wow.
What was the name of your computer
company ready for?
This is in Dallas,
Texas named it Dynasty Dynasty Computer
Corporation,
but Seattle area,
it was a,
we were the amway of computers.
I had like 3000 distributors around the
country.
And uh,
it was,
it was crazy.
And we sold.
We sold this machine.
You want to hear this?
I don't know.
Yeah,
it was an eight k machine,
the 16 K of Ram and it was a 12 inch
black and white monitor and a cassette
tape deck is what we use for input and
output.
And you'd have to load your,
your,
uh,
your boot program and then you'd get a
crc error.
So you're just the tone and rewind it
and then loaded again.
And,
and we sold hundreds of these for 3000
bucks each y and,
and parents would say,
you know,
why do I need this?
You know,
you've got recipe program and,
and Pong and a couple games.
And I said,
I don't know why you need it,
but if your kids don't have this,
they're going to be left behind.
Why?
When they're 30 years old.
And,
uh,
later,
I was talking at one of the Java
conventions in San Francisco and a guy
came up to me and gave me his card and
he's CEO of a company like 100
programmers and all.
And he said,
you don't remember me,
do you?
And I said,
no.
He says,
my dad bought a computer from you and
you told him that it would help me.
Wow.
So I don't know if anybody else got
help,
but at least one customer turned out
with.
What year was this?
Uh,
let's see.
We went out of business.
I started in [inaudible] 79,
79 and we made it to lady for while.
And it was,
it was great.
It was,
you know,
you heard of the DOTCOM bubble.
Well this was the PC bubble.
It was before ibm got in and you know,
we'd run short on memory chips and I'd
call up my friend at Osborne and he'd
shoot me some.
And then when I got some back I shipped
him and it was a closed network is
pretty good old boy thing,
you know,
fascinated.
And there's a lot of fun.
It was great fun,
but,
uh,
we didn't know what we're doing.
We're geeks and,
and uh,
I didn't know anything about cash flow
or business unit had been an electrical
engineer and a lawyer,
but I didn't know anything about
business.
And so we,
we just sort of sold ourselves out of
business.
And by the time we were done the last
six or eight,
nine months,
I was a financing the thing by selling
ecstasy,
ecstasy come into play.
I was a,
I was doing this computer thing and a
close friend of mine,
a lawyer in Biloxi,
he called me one day and he says,
what do you know about ecstasy?
And I said,
what do you mean?
He said,
well,
it's a drug.
And I said,
well,
I don't do drugs.
And he says it's legal,
you know,
now this isn't Texas and at that time
you're getting 30 years to life for a
single joint.
And so there's no way I touched
something like that,
you know,
and I get to join for one joint.
And so,
uh,
he says,
no,
this is legal.
And I had a friend,
a friend of my wife's,
actually,
she was a model in town,
ran with the fast crowd and I met with
her and she fixed me up.
And uh,
so I got involved in and uh,
then my friend wanted some.
I sent him 50 and I started telling
friends about it and I became really
evangelical about it.
And uh,
pretty soon I'm buying hundreds and 500,
600 and,
and uh,
I didn't realize it at the time.
The Guy I was buying from was actually
the main man.
And uh,
the big guy that started see ecstasy hit
the street in Dallas,
had been out here in west coast for
several years with the therapist and all
but Dallas and the stork club was the
ground zero.
And uh,
the stork club was just,
the stark club was so big.
Madonna moved to Dallas to be close to
that club.
There's a documentary going to be coming
out soon,
called the stark project.
And,
uh,
it,
it was an insane place.
It's really the,
the genesis of house music before,
or even Chicago is called Stark club
music.
And then it,
and,
and there were bowls of ecstasy on the
bar where you can go by,
you know,
giving 20 bucks and get a,
get a hit because it was all legal and
uh,
you know,
they had chill space.
It was a crazy place that you would,
it was like burning man in a building.
In fact,
Larry Hagman was a regular there.
And,
and,
uh,
in the,
in this movie that's coming out,
he's quoted as saying he lights up and
he says,
oh,
it was the greatest party on earth.
He says,
the only better parties burning man.
But that's like putting the star club in
the middle of a desert.
But some people would get all dressed up
burning man type.
And we're talking name brand people,
you know,
the talking heads and people like that.
And Madonna even was showed up.
George W dot been there and uh,
it was just wild and crazy and they
played this house music and they had a
chill space and coed bathrooms.
It's just a wild place.
And uh,
that's,
that's really where ecstasy starts
spreading.
Now I was selling to all of my friends
and,
and a lot of coworkers and everybody and
we were really serious about it that I
would make people read all whatever
literature there was,
you know,
there wasn't very much.
So there's a speech.
Sasha gave a talk that Rick Doblin had
given up the international health
organization,
but not much,
but we were really serious and I was
sort of not in the club scene.
I was getting people together in small
groups and doing it,
but I still have a lot of ex and I was
getting deep discounts and so I was
using that money to cash flow of my
business.
When you say Sasha,
do you mean Sasha shoulder that a lot of
folks don't know that he talked about?
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Sasha.
Sasha Shogun is the guy that he didn't
invent Mbma but he a resurrected it.
It is patented in the early 19 hundreds.
And He,
uh,
resynthesize didn't wrote a paper about
it that,
uh,
hit the underground,
but most of what I call the ABC
chemicals are,
came from Sasha Shogun,
noon to cb to see all of those things.
Do you ever see the vice documentary
where Hamilton Morris Interviews Sasha
Shogun?
I don't think I saw that one.
No,
by the way,
I think that's the only time I've ever
said that word in my life.
Shogun shogun.
Sasha Shogun.
I've never said he's one of those names
that I've read his name 100 times,
but I never said it.
Um,
yeah,
the really interesting vice documentary
where Hamilton Morris went and met with
them and had a long day with them and he
went over different compounds with them
and talked about discoveries and know
what he found.
And you know,
Sasha was a regular at the [inaudible]
seminars and we'd sit down and,
and,
and uh,
we have a whole bunch of us.
I,
uh,
I've had a few one on one conversations
with them,
but we always talked about things like
the navy.
He was in the navy in World War Two,
but the chemists would come on and they
would start talking ABC Xyz and what are
his acronym books.
He has these books up p and t calls.
Then fla means I have known and loved
and tryptamines I have known and loved
for the two acronyms.
And the first parts of the book are like
a novel and with the use fictional names
was about an and Sasha and their
friends.
And then the last half of the book is as
a recipe section and there are literally
probably over well over a thousand
chemicals there.
And if you look in the index,
the ones in bold are the ones that are
psychoactive.
And so,
uh,
actually before nine slash 11 happened,
I was a part of a study group where
we're kind of working our way through it
and every two weeks we get this little
powder in the mail and experiment with
it and try it.
And then,
uh,
you know,
nine slash 11 came and they started
sending a smallpox or whatever it was
through the mail.
The anthrax.
Anthrax.
Yeah.
And so,
you know,
this chemist was out of the country and
he says,
I'm not sending any more powder through
the US mail.
So that ended that experiment.
But a lot of things you're hearing about
now are things that are coming off his
books.
He,
he,
he is,
he's,
he's really declining now.
But uh,
he's,
he should have gotten a Nobel prize now.
The way he would do this as he'd,
he'd get an idea for a chemical.
They say,
well,
what if I moved this Adam over to this
part of the ring?
And then he'd synthesize that and then
he'd start out with what he would think
to be a sub,
you know,
standard dose or real low dose.
And he'd work his way up over the period
of a month or so.
And he did this with like a thousand
chemicals himself until he finally found
out what the active dose was.
And then he,
he had a group of people,
which I've met several of them.
There's only one or two of them still
alive actually,
but they're all in their sixties and
seventies.
And they're.
And they're,
they're the ones that are talked about
in the front part of the book and then
in the back part where he synthesizes
it,
there's all these comments of what
people,
it took them and I've seen the original
documents for these comments for each
paragraph.
There's like 16 pages,
single spaced,
typed A.
I mean this was in depth research that
they did for a number of years over
hundreds of compounds
she imagined being friends with that guy
while this was all going on every day.
What are you doing today?
We're going to the center of the
university.
What a godly man.
I did that yesterday,
don't you guys take a day off
and,
and I'll tell you what,
if you sat down and talked with them
when you know he's,
he's declining mentally a little bit and
he's blind now.
But if you sat down and talked with him,
you would think that he'd been your next
door neighbor growing up.
You know,
he could talk to you about anything.
And he's.
He was one of the hat is one of the
happiest people I know.
I'm sure he's probably never been filled
it up now,
but he's.
He's a serious scientists,
a very serious,
just nothing wrong with that as well,
you know,
in the idea of being a serious scientist
and not experimenting with your
consciousness being mutually.
You might be able to find a picture of
Sasha and lab.
His lab was an old,
a potting shed out behind his house is
still there and again,
they've now bottled up everything.
Anyone get to the Smithsonian or
something,
but it's.
If you look at it and you say,
God,
this,
you know,
this is a mad scientist place.
You know,
it's it.
All this stuff came out of just such a
small little shed.
Yeah.
Hamilton Morris actually went in the
shed viewing.
Yeah,
that's it right there.
there it is.
I mean this is a leaky old potting shed.
That's what your shed looks like.
If you'd done drugs a million times,
just starts looking like that.
I mean that guy has done every drug
there is a million times over.
Yeah,
but you know,
he,
he doesn't like pot that I put out a
podcast once worked area.
He and his wife were talking and he's
talking about this one experience that
they had and he says,
oh,
it was awesome.
You know,
we stopped time and we actually stopped
it.
He says,
I don't know why we started that clock
again.
And she said,
well,
you chickened out.
And he said,
what were we on that time?
She said,
brownies,
but normally,
uh,
he,
he doesn't like pot.
It doesn't,
you know,
I know probably about 25 percent of the
psychedelic people just don't get along
with pot.
That's interesting.
What's the number one concern?
Or if they don't like it,
they just,
they don't like it.
Just I wonder if it's the self examined
atory aspects of it.
Well,
some of these chemicals get pretty self
explanatory inventory.
It's true.
Acid.
Sure.
Mushrooms for sure.
Yeah.
I don't know.
There's a,
there's a real abrasive quality to
eating pot.
It was an abrasive self examined Tory
thing that a lot of people find very
uncomfortable and you've got to really
practice with each dose until you get
the right amount to.
Yes,
you do and you don't really don't know,
like you're getting a cookie from
somebody unless you've been.
Even if you made them yourself,
you know,
you have to like test out east batch and
go,
well this is a strong batch or this is
not a strong writer.
This one,
you know.
Well we had a friend who had a going
away party last night.
We're in blinking.
Uh,
we had this little party and somebody
made some brownies and they said don't
eat more than a quarter of one.
And she got there late famous last words
and she ate two brownies.
That was on a Saturday night and the
following Tuesday she was still too soon
to go to work.
Oh my God,
that's an excuse.
So Lazy Bitch didn't want to go to work.
I got,
I got stone one time that it lasted over
24 hours.
They were,
we had a friend that was just making
this delta nine.
It was just pure.
They take over a pound of Hash and it go
down to like one gram,
oh my God.
And it was in these little bottles and
you'd have to take it out with a pinhead
and titrate it with you.
Could,
you could smoke it or you could titrate
it into alcohol?
Well,
I,
you know,
it's all stuck in the bottom of the
bottle and it wasn't coming out.
So I thought,
well microwave it just a little bit.
And I was doing five seconds,
five seconds,
nothing.
So I went to 11 seconds and it shot out
like a volcano and I had it on a piece
of paper,
paper towel.
I was living in Florida then.
And,
and uh,
the woman who's now my wife was in
California.
And anyhow I took the towel in.
I didn't want to waste it.
So I ate it.
I swallowed it.
You ate the whole towel?
Well,
it was just a little part of the tile
that had the pot on.
And then I called her and I told her
what I did and she said,
oh,
that tall has chlorine.
And she wasn't worried about the pot and
she's a nurse with a master's in health,
you know.
So I took her advice seriously.
She said all that chlorine and stuff,
that's the towel.
You shouldn't have eaten the towel.
And of course by then I'm starting to
get kind of panicky.
So I took some pepto Basey,
which kind of activated the whole thing
and I was stoned for good.
Forty eight hours.
I was functional after 24,
but I couldn't tell.
Oh,
I could tell I was still high.
It's very uncomfortable.
This is not fun.
So this person,
your friend was,
was high,
she said until Tuesday.
What Day did she started on?
Saturday night.
Late.
So Sunday,
Monday.
And then Tuesday she,
she went to work Tuesday,
but she said she was not feeling too
good.
Oh my goodness.
No,
you don't want to do that.
It seems so crazy.
Oh it is.
And that's.
Both of those were accidents,
you know,
that's only when you eat it,
but it didn't kill us.
Yeah,
of course.
No,
it doesn't kill anybody unless you do
something really stupid while you're in
that state.
It won't be the drug that kills you
though.
Well,
it could be.
It could be.
If you're really stupid,
right?
I mean,
you wouldn't overdose,
you can't overdose on can overdose for
sure.
Yeah.
It's,
it's one of those things where should
you be able to go to the hardware store
and buy a saw?
I say you sure,
sure.
But if enough people cut their hands off
with saws.
Well we have like protests,
you know,
make it so that it's very difficult to
get a solid.
You have to get a license to get a saw.
He should wear a sign saying I'm stupid.
I used to solve when I'm stoned.
All the same argument really can be used
about firearms,
etc.
The fact that people use them against
other people,
but the idea that if you have a firearm
that it's dangerous.
Like is iT,
is it really dangerous if you know what
you're doing,
it seems like you can control a lot of
what's dangerous and not dangerous about
a firearm and then because,
well,
bad people can have guns and bad things
can happen.
that is true,
but does that mean that good people
can't have them?
Like that seems to be a weird sort of an
argument.
No,
I,
I was trained with guns,
you know,
I went hunting with my dad and in high
school the marine corps had a gun club
that we joined in and we'd go out and
shoot a 30 caliber machine guns and
browning automatics and stuff like that.
But we learned gun safety.
We,
we learned a lot about it.
Yeah,
I.
people are just,
we have a very detached society and I
have a friend.
No names will be named who gets mad at
ugg boots because they're made out of
sheep skin.
He thinks that's fucked up.
Did they take these sheets and they skin
them and they make boots out.
I'm like,
why the fuck would you wear that?
But meanwhile he eats meat.
Here's his fucking car.
Has leather seats.
Like,
I mean it,
it's,
it's so bizarre.
It's not even vegetarian like,
but this is the draw the line at the
sheepskin boots like this is fucked up
to using the sheepskin like,
okay,
but you're
getting in hunting now and you know,
you're,
you're talk about deer hunting.
I mean it's calling a herd if somebody's
going to die in the forest.
anyhow.
And why not you them rather than the
wolf eat
him or something?
Yeah,
you're gonna.
You're not mean dear.
Don't live forever.
They die.
They don't last very long.
Either freeze to death.
That happens a lot to the place where I
went,
Montana,
they freeze a lot or they get killed by
predators,
but they never reach old.
Age just doesn't happen.
There's no oLd age for a deer,
and if you live in some place that that
deer,
is there a problem or deer are a
problem,
you want to shoot him if he,
even if you're not against hunting
because they couldn't be a real problem,
we don't think of them as rats.
Erad is just an animal and an animal
that has infiltrated entire cities and
entire population areas where they know
people are.
They know there's a food source and
they've infiltrated the deer the exact
same way.
And the idea that,
well,
you know,
it's all our fault.
We came to where the deer are.
Actually,
there's more deer today than there was
in 1492 when columbus didn't land here.
There's,
there's more deer today than they've
been ever ever in the recorded history
of this country and that's just because
of land management and because also
there's very few predators and so the
only way they get killed as by people
killing them and there's a lot of areas
where there's just too much space.
You can't kill them all like go through
like rural Pennsylvania.
My god,
they're everywhere.
Upstate New York.
Insane.
How many?
We lived out in long island for a while
doing a house,
sitting job and they were all over the
place,
all over the place.
There.
They literally,
Oregon has a serious problem.
You know when people don't understand
well,
what would be the problem?
The problem is,
first of all,
car accidents have a huge amount of
people get in car accidents with deer
and deer can go through your windshield
and kill you.
The whole.
The antlers can.
They've killed people before,
not just once.
It's happened many times and god forbid
you live in an area that has fucking
moose because that will kill.
That will land on you.
A lot of pressure.
That would just gear though.
Yes they did.
Did you ever hear that funny?
Nine slash 11 call with the guy that hit
a deer,
put it in his back seat and then the
deer bit him,
he,
he escaped who's in a phone booth and
the dog had smelled blood and he was
kept him in the phone booth.
Oh,
it's a whole areas phone call.
Yeah.
No,
I never heard that one.
But I did hear the one where the cops
took someone's pot and made pot brownies
and then they called the cops on
themselves.
They were saying they're dying and he
was like,
can you please hurry up?
Time's going really,
really slow as someone who's been there
before and has it been like,
you know,
like way too high on a cookie going,
shit,
I fucked up man.
I know what it must have been like.
And there is proof.
It makes you stupid.
can twists your reality.
Yeah,
that's.
They knew.
I don't think they knew what they were
getting into.
People that don't understand it.
It's actually kind of ironic because if
you look at the,
uh,
the idea behind it is,
I mean,
I just don't think they understand that
when you keep something illegal,
you restrict the information that gets
out when he's tricked,
the information that gets out a lot of
misinformation,
gets out a lot of confusion and it
actually is worse for people.
That's where this eating pot comes into
place because they don't understand that
when you eat pot it gets processed by
your liver and it produces something
called 11 hydroxy metabolite,
which is four to five times more
psychoactive than thc.
It's a completely different psychedelic
experience and so they eat it and they
think someone poisoned them or they
think that someone laced in laced it as
I've heard laced a bunch of times like
this is just laced man,
so lays this because they're freaking
out.
Like,
oh,
we're going to die.
They haven't been done before.
I've never been that stone before.
I think I'm having an overdose.
And so it,
my wife,
he says,
pot.
You'd be the first ever buddy.
Well,
you know,
the other thing about eating it is we
all have such a different metabolism.
You know,
some people start coming out in an hour
and a half,
two hours.
For me it takes almost three and a half
hours to come on,
so you have to be careful in that time
and not lose your patients and say,
well it didn't have enough and then you
eat another part and then yeah,
much and it doesn't really.
It depends on many,
many,
many factors and that's another issue
with the illegality of it is you're not
getting the same sort of standardized
doses you get.
If you ordered tylenol or you were to
vitamin c capsule or something like
that,
you're getting this,
you're getting weirdness and unless you
know the guy who makes the product that
you use,
you're just guessing it's not worth it.
Stay sober.
Don't show your pants where there's a
lot of really in depth research going on
with cannabis oils and things like that
that we know one scientist that's doing
some amazing things with it and working
with cancer patients and all that.
You know,
there's.
There's so much information about being
an anti aging and anticancer and I mean
we're talking about intensive studies,
thousands of them that show all the
benefits of it and that's not even
mentioning the hemp benefit,
which is even more important really when
you think about the forest and what the
hemp could do.
Yeah.
It's,
um,
it's a weird time where we have all this
information about what could be
beneficial for our society,
how much money could be generated by
having legal cannabis,
how much tax dollars will be generated
just in sales tax alone was pretty
substantial and that these transactions
are still going on today.
They're going,
I mean,
there might be an increase in pot use.
If pot were made illegal,
they probably would be an increase,
but the reality is if you just got what
we have today,
what people are doing,
where people are doing it illegally and
made it legal,
you would.
The states and the cities would get a
tremendous amount of money.
But see,
they're getting money through the war
and drugs.
I'd only found out recently three
quarters of all the arrests are pot
possession.
Primarily three quarters and so three
quarters of all the money that's gone
into the war on drugs and think of all
the drug testing goes on.
They're not testing for lsd.
They're testing for pot and it's a big
industry.
The prison industry,
such a big industry.
That's why they're fighting it because
in guard union.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
When I heard prison guard unions lobby
against making drugs,
illegal drugs,
legal rather partnership for drug free
America and I think that's a seagram's
and a few other liquor companies are the
ones who fund that used to be
pharmaceutical company probably there.
They had a big part of it as well.
I was actually,
I think
pharmaceuticals,
alcohol,
tobacco and pharmaceutical companies
where the.
The primary drug pushers or again,
the way I described it was the them
doing commercials against paul was like
hookers doing commercials against
strippers.
It's like,
that's a good analogy.
That one.
Yeah,
so stupid.
It just doesn't make any sense.
Like how can you have a partnership for
a drug free America that's sponsored by
drugs like drugs?
Give them millions dot not just a couple
of bucks,
not just drugs.
A look,
I like what you're doing about pot.
We disagree about alcohol and tobacco.
I think they're awesome products and
great from humanity,
so I'm going to send you some money.
Alcohol and tobacco are given drugs,
a bad name.
That's just so ridiculous.
We're just a weird time.
We're in a really,
really weird time in human history where
again,
we have so much information and yet
there's so much contradictory behavior
going on.
Contradictory to the evidence that's in
place.
Contradictory to logic or contradictory
to reason like why are you arresting
somebody for a plant ever?
What does anybody get hurt by this?
Didn't stop.
STop.
What do you do when you were a cop?
For who?
For the corporations.
You're supposed to be a cop to protect
the people,
enforced the law and protect the people
and the law should protect the people.
So the idea is what?
Cops are only supposed to enforce the
law.
They're not here to protect people.
Will the laws that don't protect people
are fucking stupid and you don't protect
people by locking them in jail because
they have plants on them.
That's just dumb.
Exactly.
So we've got other shit to do,
you know,
this is a good,
good place to put up the item about jury
nullification.
You know,
uh,
people don't realize this,
but it used to be part of the judge's
instruction to the jury that if you
don't find this law appropriate,
you can find the person not guilty and
they don't know.
They keep that.
Now if you hand out a literature or a
piece of literature about that at a
courthouse,
you'll get arrested.
They won't let you say it,
but it's still the law jury
nullification.
And,
and I've actually been in one case where
I did this as a juror that in fact if
I'm ever on any kind of a pot case,
unless there was violence,
you know,
that'll look different.
But if it's just a simple possession
case,
I don't care what the facts are and what
the judge says,
you can still say not guilty and there
is nothing that can be done about it.
Wow.
And people need to know that.
I mean there's a big jury nullification,
a movement on the web you can find out
about.
But it's hard to get your head around
because you know,
people hear the judge's instruction and
they say,
well,
I had to find them guilty.
Oh you don't?
Yeah.
It should all be legal.
It's really simple.
We should hire people to study it.
Use the government funds that you would
normally spend on law enforcement.
Use those in a better way to hire people
to study what are the actual effects of
this stuff and inform people not by
basis of your prejudice in one way or
another or what your biased opinion
would be one way,
but the actual facts like here's the
facts.
It might fuck up your memory.
It seems like when you get high messes
with your short term memory,
you might get tongue tied,
might get locked up.
If you know how to do here,
here's the negative.
Here's the current smoking.
Something in general,
probably not the best thing for eating
it.
You might freak the fuck out.
Jump off a building.
I mean eating is a little scary.
You could have some nightmares.
You have to know what you're doing.
Show people what it is.
Well,
vaporizer,
probably a really good move as far as
health wise,
probably the safest bet.
Here's what happens,
here's what a good dose is.
Here's what happens when you have half
that dose,
here's what happens.
If you have a quarter of that dose,
knock yourself out,
do what you want to do,
but no one's going to die and that would
be that simple and then start taxing the
shit out of it and my goodness,
would we have money?
We wouLd have money for everything if we
started making marijuana legal and have
a high tax shit.
Let's make the tax 10 percent,
25 percent in Colorado in denver or
something like that.
I love Colorado.
Colorado is always on the ball.
We're always ahead of everybody there.
They're animals.
they're living up there with bears and
shit at that altitude.
They don't have the oppression of which
is awesome.
That's just an awesome state.
Says all around awesome.
Colorado's one of my all time favorite
states.
You lived there for awhile.
That 25 percent a smart move because I
don't mind paying if I have to pay four
bucks for a joint or whatever it is and
I'm paying a dollar know I don't mind
that it's probably gonna be less
expensive than the black market and
it'll be fine.
Like look,
marijuana's not that expensive.
When you think about what alcohol costs,
if you go to a bar and try to have a few
drinks,
look if you grow your own cheapest,
fuck,
but if you buy it,
it's really not that expensive for how
much you use.
You use a vaporizer,
you can get about three or four to one
on thing,
you know?
Yeah.
ANd look in comparison to so many other
things that are really expensive.
It's kind of silly to talk about it.
Yeah,
and that's now,
whIle it's fairly illegal,
no pot,
I can see that the war on drugs is
making money off of it.
Psychedelics?
I think it's because they're afraid.
You might start your thinking,
you know,
that you know,
for.
I used mgma,
I was an irish catholic republican
lawyer and afterwards I was still irish
and everything else went away.
Wow.
That's what a weird.
How long did that transition take?
Was it from the first hit you took?
You knew something was up.
I think it took from the night that I
ingested it until the next morning
sometime and you know,
all of a sudden I realized a whole.
I just had a real awakening and I felt
like I did when I was a young boy,
you know,
that I've had,
I've helped a lot of people on their
first trips and almost invariably they
say the same thing.
well,
I felt like this before.
I mean you don't go crazy or anything
and it's really not a psychedelic and,
and so you,
it's a gentle way to get in and it's so
good for therapy.
You know,
michael and annie,
mid offer in the,
uh,
in South Carolina are now,
I think entering the second phase of an
mdm,
a test,
but he was.
So the first phase one was uh,
treating,
uh,
rape victims with serious ptsd and they
had a,
an,
an amazing amount of recovery.
I'm actual recovery.
One woman hadn't left the house in 15
years and now she's got a job and I
think something like that.
But the pentagon has now approved this
study for post dramatic stress disorder
and they're looking at,
uh,
some other studies with the pentagon
because ptsd is such a huge problem.
And mtma see,
here's why the drug coMpanies don't want
it.
What michael and annie do,
I think they only do maybe two sessions
with mtma is psychol,
psychiatrist assisted and guided and all
psyChoanalysts or um,
I dunno,
maybe not that high a level,
but uh,
there's a lot of counseling goes on with
it and see when you take him,
dmh lowers so many barriers that you and
your therapist can really talk honestly.
and they have had like spec.
The phase one study is just to prove it
won't kill somebody.
And still they had some amazing
recoveries.
And now phase two,
they want to do the extended therapy
with the thing.
But see,
the drug companies don't like it because
you only need one or two pills ever.
Then you're done.
You don't keep taking it.
They want things that they can keep you
taking.
It's interesting because it seems like
there would be able to make some money
using that stuff if you get an.
But you know,
they're going to be abuse with that.
There's,
there's abuse with mdm may for sure.
Ravers,
you know,
people are dying because they get
dehydrated in dance.
And most of us,
because it's adulterated,
you know,
it's not pure mma.
And what do they cut it with?
I don't know.
Uh,
I think all kinds of things and it could
just be impurities in their processes.
But uh,
probably some sort of,
you know,
it's,
it is an infection and so they probably
cut it with a little speed so you can
feel something.
But uh,
you know,
originally back in the early days when
we were getting it,
it was either in cap form and a lot of
it was in powder,
but it was pure mtma.
And of course we,
we knew the source and stuff like that.
But today,
you know,
they used to be a group called dance
safe and I don't think they're active
anymore because they were the government
shutting them down,
but they were doing free drug testing at
raves,
uh,
to tell you if you have pure mdm,
shut that down,
that's so rude and short sighted.
They thought it was encouraging drug
use,
but instead it was saving lives,
saving lives.
how could you,
that's such an illogical stance to take
how you should never put something in
your mouth that you got from somebody
you don't know.
That's a good,
good thing to say,
except if you want to put your penis in
someone's mouth,
well,
and you barely know them.
You know,
I've never had anybody any stranger than
that.
I've always gotten to know him at least
for a half hour.
I'm not saying that it's going to
happen.
It always leaves that day.
I,
yeah,
I'll go along with it.
Especially if you're on ecstasy.
Think about it.
What you know in dallas,
we,
some of our customers,
there were some swinger clubs in dallas
and so we would sell it to these cluBs
because you can,
you can have an erection for hours on
it,
but you can't come and so the swinger's
clubs loved it,
but people,
I come out here to the west coast and
the word is,
oh,
you're going to have a third day let
down hangover and,
and you can't have sex on it.
And I thought wow,
that's a completely different story.
and everybody bought into it out here.
But in dallas it was a totally different
story.
Nobody was having that third second,
third day blahs or anything.
So in dallas you were getting pure mtma
right.
And here they're getting this.
I don't know if places getting it
pure unless you really doing it,
you know,
know the chemist.
But it was a veteran.
Yeah,
it was,
it was definitely pure and you know,
that was legal at that time.
There's no reason to cut it and you
know,
it was a.
Do you remember when five meo dmt was
legal and you could buy it?
I'll buy like a coffee cup filled with
online and get the whole.
It was like $30.
I know some people that have.
That's what I heard.
I heard,
you know,
I heard you know things.
It's weird.
What was still legal.
Like salvia is legal in a lot of places
still.
Yeah.
And then they have this Bath salts issue
which is really nutty.
They'd take a compound like crystal man
fade.
They alter it so it becomes a different
new compound.
It's not categorized.
Then they say not for human consumption
so that it's bath salts,
but everybody knows you're supposed to
smoke it because it's like crack or meth
or whatever the hell it is and they
can't do anything about it.
It's amazing that there's been something
like a.
I don't want to use the number because I
don't have it in front of me,
but close to maybe 70 new compounds that
have been introduced in england this
year.
Whoa.
england knows how to party well.
Worldwide is probably higher.
It might only be 20,
it might have been 70 last year in 2010,
but there are there.
There's just no way to stop these things
coming.
Now.
What are you doing in england?
Why?
While you going crazy when they look.
Look,
look,
if you had to live there,
you'd have to do something new.
It's raining right now.
It's snowing right now.
Yeah,
it gets.
By the way,
there's a bunch of people in england
watching us right now live,
but yeah,
for sure.
I love england.
I was just a manchester just to two
shows.
Manchester.
Yeah,
dance house theater was awesome.
It's just fun.
I love england.
I liked the people there as audience
members.
They're amazing.
Are some of the best audience members
you ever get?
They're polite.
TheY listened.
They get things.
They understand where you're going and
stuff.
Yeah.
You know they,
they,
they're sharp.
They know what's goIng on.
Well,
I think,
I don't know what it is.
I mean,
is it.
Are they more educated in the school
systems?
Definitely better that.
Even not the Private schools,
but public schools or even better than.
The one thing that irks me,
the most advanced society is that
there's such a minimal amount of
finances that are dedicated towards
school systems.
The minimum,
they're always trying to cut the school
budget.
There was cutting things.
They should be pouring money into the
public education system,
pouring money into community centers,
pouring money into anything that
benefits young people in there cutting
and things like music and art and the
grand sports cutting wrestling and a lot
of places,
you know,
it's.
It makes me sick because people need
these things and it's greedy old people
that had these things in there,
a younger.
They're designed deciding that these are
the things that should be cut.
Those things should be uncut.
A bowl that should be like,
look,
here's your budget.
You need to spend a $100,
million dollars on the school systems.
After that.
You can do whatever the fuck you want as
far as cleaning the streets up and doing
all that,
but number one,
you need to do this because this is
what's going to take care of everything.
I'll go along with that.
This is what's going to make the people
that
are babies become cool adults have you
don't get that right.
The whole society scrapped the whole
generation,
gone a whole generation that has to
figure it out for themselves and there's
that,
that attitude of pull yourself up by
your own bootstraps and you know,
I figured it out.
You should figure it out too.
Like man,
if you did figure it out,
then you should know how god damn hard
it is to figure out and you should also
know this is not the only way to do it.
This is a silly way to do it.
To have unmotivated teachers that get
paid $25,000
a year.
I mean,
how can you feed yourself?
How can you,
how can you expect these people who
you're entrusting to educate your
children to be motivated when they can
barely eat?
Right?
And,
and you know,
some of our best teachers are just so
amazing because they're working in the
inner city voluntarily.
They could go other places,
some of them junior college and all,
but they're there.
I have one friend who worked in the
inner city in san francisco for a while,
another one here in la,
and they were amazing men and they just,
you know,
they did it because they wanted to help
these kids.
Well,
that's a beautiful notion and it's
beautiful when you meet people like that
and it's beautiful that they still
exist.
It's just sad that corporations have
controlled the political process to the
point where when a person gets into
power,
when a person becomes president,
they they need never have a chance to do
a real overhaul.
you never really are like the one person
who's in control.
You have a million people that you owe
that got you into that position that you
have to pay back or do their bidding or
meet their interests before you do
anything.
Right,
and so that's.
That's what you know.
That's where all these different laws
come from.
They're so confusing and don't make any
sense to people.
We've got to figure out a way to govern
people by actually governing people.
It's like we accept that there's going
to be so much,
so much bullshit and so much corruption
and so much thievery and so many slanted
Ideas.
We just accept that there's going to be
a certain amount of that because it's
always been that way and if you looked
at that,
you know,
it looked at a lot of the decisions that
get made at the highest levels of
government and like who they benefit.
You would say,
this could never happen.
This could never happen if we all had
the right attitude.
This caN only happen when money gets
involved.
This can only happen when someone puts
money ahead of humanity and that's like
the real core part of our society that's
fucked up his education.
I mean education,
not just in the small sense of teaching
people that don't know how to read,
how to read,
but teaching people who are brilliant,
how to think about life.
Exactly.
Not just how to count and how to,
you know,
calculate the dates of fossils that you
find,
but how to think about humans and how
they engage with each other.
How to look at this temporary existence
in a correct way.
Well,
you know,
corporations set a lot of the agenda for
schools as far as the curriculum,
things like that because they're looking
to to get passive little cubicle workers
and see that was one of the lessons that
the power elite learned to the sixties.
So it was all these young kids got
educated because your parents got
educated from the gi bill and,
and uh,
now
we're educating these kids and they're
getting too smart for Us and I think
they intentionally been dumbing down the
school system.
How do they do that though?
Just by underfunding.
Well,
look at Texas a,
the school books in Texas are teaching
creationism and they're trying to get
evolution out of the textbooks
completely.
Right.
But you don't think that that's because
they're dumb,
right?
They're just there.
Their religion.
I mean,
not,
not that they're dumb dumbs down the
people though,
but I'm sorry,
let me rephrase that.
You don't think that they're doing that
because they're trying to make people
dumb there are.
There are people using those people to
do that?
I think.
I think the corporations want people who
aren't really thinking out of the box
too much,
they can get those from the elite
private schools,
but isn't there like always going to be
like a large base of fundamental people
in places like Texas that they could
just,
they could capitalize on by,
by leaning in as far as like their
decision making towards them because
they know that that's going to aid them
to get into office.
Well,
yeaH,
and of course I'm pretty cynical about
that.
I think the voting is pretty rigged
anyhow with electronic voting,
but a while there certainly has been
shown in textually sexist.
You know,
I practice law in Texas,
lived there for awhile and it's a pretty
a bible time kind.
A very fundamentalist.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
I was doing some jokes last time I was
in houston,
my friends.
So this girl walked to the bathroom and
said,
if he talks about jesus one more time,
we are out of here,
barely talked about jesus.
Then that be throw out a title of a
book,
caesar's messiah,
a book that's out that talks about the
jesus jesus actually being fictional.
It's pretty interesting book.
Yeah.
I read a thing about that.
You just like something to drink.
Yeah,
I got it here.
You got some.
You want some coffee to keep me awake
all day?
Oh,
how dare you.
That's right.
You tolD me already.
Sorry.
Um,
I,
yeah.
I read a summary of that online or they
were talking about this new study that
said that jesus may have been created
and they found new documents that
suggest he was either way.
It doesn't matter.
I don't know if jesus was real or if
jesus was artificial.
My point is it doesn't make sense that
he died and came back to life three days
later and as long as you believe that we
have a problem,
we've got a problem.
We have a disconnect in communication.
We have a why would that be real?
We have that.
We have.
Why?
What happened there?
He turned water into wine.
Were you there when this happened?
Do you know how dumb people are?
Do you know how much people lie you do?
Did you imagine what that must've been
like back when people couldn't even
write shit down and it was 50 years
after the so called event that somebody
wrote it down for the first time?
Of course,
and the way later than that,
that constantine and a bunch of bishops
decided what goes in the book and what
doesn't.
Right?
You know when they wrote the new
testament,
I'm like,
holy jesus.
Like they left stuff out.
They added stuff that there's so many
different people's fingerprints on that.
It's just nonsense,
but it's about control.
They can't control the people,
but the idea also that this is
absolutely not saying that there's no
god if you've done psychedelics,
I think you've realized after a certain
amount of those
quote unquote breakthrough experiences,
I think you realize that you have no
idea what's going on in this other
realm.
Whatever these other realms are,
whether they're individually different,
whether they're all connected,
whether they're just frequencies on a
dial,
whether it's five meo,
whether it's dmt,
whether it's psilocybin,
whatever these realms are that you enter
into there is so fantastic and special
and strange and beyond description that
the idea of god does not seem nearly as
ridiculous once you've had them.
I there's a video of me out there and
interview they did where I told the
stories about x hitting the street in
dallas and I mentioned about the fact
that when I got to two,
at one point in my life in Florida,
I decided I was going to be an atheist.
I really wanted to get rid of everything
and so I was trying really hard to be an
atheist,
but I had this friend lived on the edge
of town with a farm and he get mushrooms
from the cow patties in his colleague
halyard and bring them into me.
So I'd be an atheist during the week and
then I'd eat these mushrooms and
saturday you can't be an atheist with
five grams of dried mushrooms in your
stomach.
Well,
you can't be sure.
No,
that's the real problem is that you
can't be sure.
And my problem with religion is that
when people are sure about something
that they've never seen,
never experienced,
you're sure because you read it.
Are you sure?
Because someone told it to you?
Sure.
Because it's your tradition,
like you gotta.
Tell me why.
You're sure if you're sure.
Because it's some demonstratable
science.
Okay,
I got it.
But if you're sure just because you're
sure that god wants you to throw rocks
at homosexuals because you saw that
written down somewhere like,
wow,
that doesn't make sense.
Why would he tell us now why?
Why?
How come god only tells one person like,
doesn't god know that game?
The game of telephone doesn't know that
game.
He must know that that games,
he made everything.
He's got to know that game sucks.
So why would you tell one person like a
few thousand years right now?
Why wouldn't you tell us all the time
when someBody asked me if I believe in
god,
I just say,
okay,
define what you mean by the word god,
and we really never get much past that
because people,
a few people say,
old man with a long white beard sitting
on a throne.
I said,
well,
no,
I don't believe in that.
see,
that's where I differ from you.
Really?
Yeah.
Because of the shit I've seen on
mushrooms or way weirder than a guy
living in the clouds.
You know,
I've seen tHings on dmt that made a guy
in the clouds with a harp and a bunch of
people around him with a,
with bird wings.
That wasn't even.
No,
I,
I agree with that.
I'm saying I'm just,
you know,
the old,
the catholic image of the guy in the
throne with the white beard.
It could be.
This is why because life is so stupid
and contradictory and weird and humans
are so bizarre and so hypocritical and
so strange and self destructive in our
ax collectively make no sense to the
individual,
and yet we all feel helpless in the
momentum of the united species and its
movement,
whether it's the polluting the ocean of
the fucking up of the ozone layer and
shit flying around in space,
slamming into each other because we've
got so many things floating around above
our earth.
WHatever is that.
It's.
It's so bizarre and contradictory and
crazy that it aLmost seems like the work
of a madman.
It almost seems like the work of a god,
like just one crazy motherfucker that's
designed to control this planet.
Maybe acid trip.
He's just crazy asshoLe.
He's like anybody else that gets into a
position of power.
He gets his fucking head,
gets bIg.
It gets crazy.
He starts ordering people around,
started doing nutty shit.
Like if you eat that apple,
everyone's fucked.
That's it.
I said it.
You did it.
So over done.
But all of humanity forever has to
suffer.
Yes.
Sorry,
[inaudible].
I said so.
Yeah,
and the only way to fix that is you
gotta get a guy who his son to sacrifice
his life,
like what?
Come on.
You know,
we get all wrapped up in the affairs of
the world,
but you've had an intense dreams.
You wake up and the only last for a few
moments you can't hold on to some of
these dreams.
I have a feeling that when we die,
it could be just like that.
You say,
god,
I,
I felt like I was on a planet earth or
something I can't remember.
And you don't remember a damn thing
about all this stuff we went through.
It's certainly possible.
Sure.
There's,
there's thoughts we don't know.
Yeah,
you live an infinite life that's
interconnected one life to another and
that's one of the reasons why you meet
someone and they're an old soul or you
meet someone and they're particularly
fortunate,
like,
why is this guy particularly fortunate?
Why?
Why is it,
why are people drawn to them initially
from the get go,
maybe this is things that they figured
out in past existences that we're not
calculating in this existence.
Maybe you have a certain amount of work
that you can do in this existence,
but you're basically still riding on the
momentum of fucking and ian have
different lives that you've lived over
and over and over again.
One of the things we can do in this life
that I don't know or they're not,
we can do it in another life,
but as with a human body,
there's a lot of physical pleasure that
you can experience and I think that part
of what we should be doing here is
having some physical pleasure and not
just getting into the spiritual world.
Sounds like someone's starting a cult.
No,
I know how you do it.
I know I used psychedelic people think
or a commune or maybe like a new,
a new situation.
Now actually,
I'm assuming it.
I seldom leave my k.
You seem like a very personable guy.
Well,
I can be,
but I save it all up for a rare
occasion.
That's funny.
You're personable in small doses that,
that's actually,
there's a,
there's a reality to that,
that you,
uh,
the overwhelming amounts of people.
If you're around overwhelming amounts of
people,
you can be like overstimulated,
right?
Some people believe that the result of
living in cities and living in high
population areas is like this,
this same thing that you're experiencing
when you see people getting into road
rage,
the same thing that you're experiencing
when people see people fly off the
handle at counter help or what have you,
it's just like they're just overwhelmed.
There's just too much stimulation and
just need to sit by yourself,
watch a little tv,
read a book,
relax.
You need to be out in nature,
going for a walk.
We don't feel anything or hear anything.
Just see squirrels and a couple of
little kids,
you know,
that's.
We just don't
feel like we need that because we're so
trapped in this momentum of
accomplishment is constantly pushing
forward,
but not realizing that we don't.
We don't stay here forever.
You only get a certaIn amount of times.
I've quit doing conferences and
workshops because afterwards people come
up and they asked me all these questions
that are so deep.
I don't really quite understand the
questions.
You know,
and I'm not.
I'm a carnival barker,
that's my role,
all the actions in the tent and you're
in the center,
ring yourself in the main tent,
but I just,
I like to point to a lot of things and I
go broad,
but I don't go very deep and so I can't
answer questions and these people want
me to solve their life problems.
I don't even understand what they're
asking me,
so I've just quit making appearances.
Well,
there's always gonna be people that want
you to figure it out for them.
There's always going to be people that
don't just want to discuss things that
people have said,
which is absolutely fascinating,
but they want you to help them.
It's a very selfish point of view and
it's very common and I'm just not up to
it.
That's not what I do.
I don't think anybody has quite honestly
and,
and especially if you go up to them and
ask them for advice,
hey,
I need your advice like,
man,
listen,
would you need to do is you need to look
at your own life and figure out what
you're doing and why.
If you want to talk about like specific
things like in order for someone to give
you advice,
like should I marry this girl?
Like,
oh my god,
where do we begin?
You know,
I'm going to have to like if you wanted
me to give an honest answer,
if she should get married to someone,
I would have to see you guys interact
for like weeks,
right?
Have to like get to know you
individually.
I would have to really say that yes,
you should sign a legal contract where
you give up 50 percent of all your
earnings.
One person just go do it,
do it,
and then if it doesn't work out,
you're gonna get mad at me.
Like I've people like I'm thinking about
taking extra.
What do you think?
I don't know.
You man.
Have you started in the library?
That's where you go first.
Go to arrowhead.
The idea that you would be able to tell
someone what to do or not to do or what
did like you're asking too many weird
questions which we should.
You should be doing is figuring it out
for yourself.
That's a big part of life and then
surrounding yourself with people that
you meet,
that you become friends with and you can
share.
I have some history.
Yeah.
You can't just run up to lorenzo and ask
them to solve your problems.
You shit in order.
I've got a friend up crew in houston
who's a lawyer friend of mine and
actually we were in the navy together
too and he has a big brass plaque on the
front of his desk that says,
frankly,
I'd rather not get involved so you know
you're going to pay top dollar with him.
Well,
there's people that just want to drag
you into their world and you don't want
to be in their world.
And it's like,
listen,
you heard your own bridge.
New people helped you like,
are you sure about that?
Because there's definitely wasn't this.
It wasn't running up to people and
telling them the fixed my life,
you know,
but there's a lot of that going on out
there and unfortunately it all goes down
to the same issue.
People that haven't been explained how
to think too,
they haven't been instructed on what's
the most productive way to think.
What's the best way to men?
I don't mean by things like form your
own opinions or creatively or anything.
I mean manage your consciousness.
What's the debate?
What best way to how you look
at yourself in relation to the people
around you and if you're being too
goddamn needy,
you're ruining it for everybody.
If it's always about you,
you,
mimi,
me.
That might be while you're in that
situation in the first place because
nobody wants to fucking help you and no
one's helped you up to now because
you're exhausting
that you know,
I used to be on the motivational speaker
circuit for awhile and we had all these
pat things.
When you're pointing at somebody,
you've got three fingers pointing back
at yourself.
The other one is you can walk through a
room full of people laying on the floor
and give your hand each one and help
them to their feet,
but you let one of them climb on your
back and you're going to be down on the
floor with them,
and so that's.
That's what you're saying.
Don't get involved in helping people.
You just tell them what you can help
them with.
Some ideas that they got to work on
themselves,
but you can't solve them.
Yeah.
It's not that I don't get involved with
helping people.
It's a.
People have to realize that taking their
version on,
yeah,
you as an individual have your own
unique burden.
If you want to learn things,
if you want to fail,
then you've got to start doing research.
You got to start reading books.
You've got to start communicating,
but going up to someone like you and
saying,
hey,
I need you to fix my life.
You know,
what do I do?
Like I don't know what the fuck you do,
except I barely know what the fuck I do.
Like,
come on man,
you gotta find somebody,
and the other problem is that what I've
found is that people who are needy,
they never recover.
If you keep them in your life,
god dammit,
they're needy.
Ten years later,
like,
hey man,
we've gotten 10 years and you're still
at god damn wreck.
Like why?
Why,
why?
Why have you not figured this out yet?
You asked me for advice 10 goddamn years
ago,
we spent a lot of time talking about
shit and now 10 years later you're doing
the same.
Same thing.
You're sucking me into a world of a
bullshit.
You're just trapping me like a little
vortex
and being honest,
like that's probably the best thing you
can do for now
than they hate you and talk shit about
you online under fake names.
That's what they do.
They are,
they get fake accounts and It just turn
it off.
Well,
it's just,
you know,
life is beautiful when everybody's
trying to do their part,
but life becomes a real pain in the ass,
but no one wants to do the dishes.
You know,
like that.
If you live in a house with a bunch of
people and no one does the dishes,
it becomes that,
hey,
what the fuck are we doing?
Everybody get together here.
Let's come on.
I did the dishes last night.
There's 10 of them in here today.
Well,
it wasn't more food.
I didn't need to.
You get into that kind of nonsense,
but then you get a shitty communication
system.
You got a shitty commune,
you got a shitty culture.
Just goes downhill from there.
I mean that's a real issue is a real
issue is that there's too many people
out there that do that.
Not just want attention but demanded for
nothing.
Right.
You know,
it's not that that's who they become.
People like,
hey man,
I've got to get you to listen to my cd.
Do you know what that would be like if
the whole world,
you know,
had someone,
it was like 5 billion people that wanted
you to listen to their cd.
Would you ever have time for anything
else?
It's like email right now.
We don't even know each other.
Why am I listening to your cd?
I think it would just.
You think you could help me.
Do you think it really.
I can help you by listening to your cd.
I'm not a music producer.
Like what the fuck are you doing man,
this,
this.
There's not that much time in the world.
I cAn't help everybody.
You know,
if you have
something that's interesting,
send a link.
You know,
if someone wants to help you that it'll,
it'll spread virally.
Put something online to people,
find it,
they'll send it to four And then it gets
going from there.
I mean this the only way today and
there's ways they can do it.
They've got youtube and places they can
put their music.
You know,
and that's the only issue that I ever
have in communicating with people is
sometimes people get exhausting.
I want you to read this script.
Do you know how long that takes?
I don't even know you,
man.
I'm going to read your script.
People want me to read their books all
the time and I've got books I need to
read.
It's flattering,
right?
It's.
Yeah,
but I would never do that.
I would never send someone a book and
say,
I want you to read this and then
critique it for me.
I'm not that needy.
I think that's a needy thing.
The other reason I don't do it besides
the time is first of all,
I'm not sure I know what they're talking
about.
I'm not sure I know the subject,
but then what if I don't like it?
You know?
I don't want to just say,
hey,
this really sucks.
Yeah,
I've heard that happen before people
have sent me stand up before,
review this and then get back to me
like,
oh,
christ son,
you know,
I,
I thought during my bachelor stoner days
I want to stand up,
but the time you're doing news radio
and,
and I,
I thought it was really funny.
I worked for weeks and weeks to get like
five minutes.
So you're in your fifties,
wow.
Days and your fifth.
Couldn't even get my girlfriend to laugh
at more than one or two of the jokes and
I thought,
you know,
there's no way I'm going to an open mic
with this is that I need a new
girlfriend.
Well,
that happened to it,
but it wasn't her fault.
It wasn't her fault,
but that's hard work to do that I.
I really admire you guys.
It's hard work when it's not going well.
That's when it's hard work.
It's hard work when you're trying to
come up with new material that it's hard
work,
but when it's working it's not hard.
I,
although I love music,
I always think comedy is just a step
above because laughing actually can heal
you and so I've,
I've learned more comedians through your
show and one time I heard you say
something like,
you thought joey diaz was the funniest
guy alive and so the next morning,
and I usually listen to your podcast at
the gym,
you know,
it makes the gym time goes faster and I
came home from the gym and I got youtube
and I looked at joy dia's channel and
6:00
that night I got stoned right.
Then at 6:00
that night I had seen almost all of
july.
I haven't seen it all yet,
but he,
he hits the tone with me.
He and mark marin,
a couple of those guys really are in the
same group I'm in and so I just,
you know,
I just couldn't get,
get google get lost.
So it is an animal.
He's an and he seems to do,
you know,
adlib roofs a lot in his best stuff is
ad libbing.
Yeah.
When he.
The best thing that I ever saw,
the funniest thing I ever saw was joey
diaz on the Alex Jones show.
It was me and joey diaz and Alex Jones.
Alex wants to talk conspiracies and joey
hates that shit.
He doesn't want to talk about ufo was at
chem trails.
Get the fuck out of here with your
bullshit.
So he just hijack the whole show.
Did you see that?
Or theY stuff on youtube?
Yes,
I got to see that will pull it up.
Jamie.
Pull it.
Oh,
it's joey on the Alex Jones show
and he went on this rant for like a
couple minutes towards the end when he
left the podcast and I could.
I literally couldn't breathe and my face
was beet red.
I've got to see what just killing it.
And Alex Jones tried to jump in and he
fucking,
he stops him from jumping in,
just gets louder and crazier and hit the
point.
One of the few people that could stop.
I like and saY,
oh,
Alex Jones had no idea what they're just
better at covering up with know don't
know.
He was dancing and singing,
always oxygen,
no junk,
junk,
junk.
He,
every day he doesn't wake up singing
dance and then he has oxygen tanks at
night.
Something's not right there.
I might taste like you're worth more
dead than what you are alive.
You understand me?
He ain't.
And now they got a new record coming out
that no more.
He's Doing a tour next year with the
people from vegas that jump up and down
the blue band group.
But the how that is,
I mean he's the more than he's ever been
killed.
Michael jackson.
Knowing what I know.
I smoke another joint.
I'll break it down.
What the music from paul mccartney
didn't want to get back.
And all of a sudden they put paul
mccartney,
the soup bowl.
They tried to build up the beatles to
get the thing going and all sudden
Michael Jackson circling the building.
Right now,
we've gotten confirmation.
The documents right here.
Obama strategy.
Let me show you,
but when alex isn't even talking now,
but not only 20 percent of my crazy.
Boy,
you know whaT?
I'm [inaudible].
No,
but I'm shango.
I love you,
but I'm saying you're a character too.
On top of it.
This is talking about.
He's way more fun.
I know,
I know.
You don't want to talk about yourself.
Okay,
well,
let's get back to a free country state.
Let's get all chinese.
We need joey diaz so we can poinT the
finger and say,
there's no bad man.
What is art?
What is our model to,
you know how we say the n word.
What are the chinese say about us?
You know how they call us?
They call us boolei.
Whatever that word is.
You know what that means?
White ghost.
We are white fucking ghosts.
That's what we are.
We're here to destroy the fucking world.
Trust montonya,
but at the same time were built.
They call us that low.
That's what they call us,
a white ghost.
They call black people something else,
but it's also a black ghosts.
I don't know if it's why low it goes and
I say,
but that's the point,
man.
These.
It's not people like me and you're going
to work this world.
It's the suits.
It's the fucking bankers.
It's that fucking guy that locked people
up in thousand prisoners all like giving
money to go to the very end of it when
he goes crazy.
This is like a real short clip is what I
thought we were gonna apply.
This is actually the whole thing,
isn't it?
This is the whole time.
HE was on a minute.
Yeah,
this is it.
This is it.
A baggy clothes on.
They didn't know it was great.
They said,
we're going to put you through the x ray
machine.
I'm standing there sweating bullets with
this baggy under my fucking nuts than
the writing because I'm a stuff people
don't know that.
I told I had cancer for a couple of
weeks.
Know the opposite hand is under his
balls going to the airport thinking
they're like rodney dangerfield.
Rodney was sticking up a storm,
not to mention my balls.
I'm sweating now because I'm going to go
to jail.
Goes,
he's clear and he shook my hand.
I'm like,
tax payers are hard at work to your
politician who's talking to you like a
christian.
He's lying.
So you follow him saying,
no,
we're talking about naked body scanners
were talking about children being
molested by tsa.
We're taught.
We will listen to a politician with the
same story every four years with that.
Sorry ass line of shit,
but these pockets of almost get offended
because I say the word fuck.
That's why the camps and stupid to
understand what's in front of them.
Forget about the curse words.
At least the kids not fucking lion.
So next time you listen to your bullshit
congressmen or your bullshit governor or
even the bullshit presence,
somebody who's running for president and
he's kicking you with that.
Same for shit that they give you every
four fucking years and you still vote
for the fucking momo and then you get
mad.
Think about me saying the word fuck with
that.
Amadea I got to go smoke a cigar.
Very solid points.
Don't do the I don't know.
I know joey,
you,
you get it.
But then just to let the american public
know that every four years they buy the
same shit they've been buying it for
years at the same people with their
harvard articulation and the holiday
don't curse and they're christians and
they had a family and these are the same
people that shove it up your fucking ass
every year.
The one thing that you'll get it
video,
there's an end to it where he goes crazy
and says,
check yourself before you wreck
yourself.
Hold on,
hold on one second.
Here it is.
Take the shuttle.
Joey,
did facebook,
twitter,
check yourself before you wreck
yourself.
Big dixon gas.
Get outta here.
You're in Trouble.
You know I love that
guy because he says what I'm thinking,
but he says,
it's so much better.
We've so crazy.
It's so funny,
so entertaining.
It's just a maniac.
It's fine.
Having maniacs for friends just gives
you a different perspective on things
you realize,
oh,
that's a way to live to know.
Exactly.
No,
there's a lot of us that are different.
Yeah,
he's just a.
He's one of a kind and I hadn't heard of
them until I heard him on your show and
now I'm a huge fan.
Yeah,
well the internet has really been very
kind to joey diaz because people,
you know,
it was very hard for a guy like that to
show you what he can do without the
internet.
Can't do that on a radio show.
We just go off and crazy.
his comedy,
it's very hard to see on regular tv,
unless It's showtime or hbo.
So he was in a lot of.
It was in a weird category and then the
internet came along and podcasting came
along and then people just got to see
who this lady's.
He's riding high.
Yeah.
Finally.
It's like he deserved it.
Yeah.
Oh,
without a doubt.
It's the,
the,
you know,
the internet is just sort of catching up
to the derricks,
but there's so Many things you get
exposed because of the internet that,
I mean,
your podcast would never be on a radio
show.
How could you ever have that on late
night radio?
There's no way they would ever play
that.
It'd be impossible.
No,
there's no way.
Well,
if you coast to coast or something,
you know,
terrence is on there a lot,
but you know,
it's,
it's not,
it's still too long,
too late.
Stuff like that.
And yours.
I mean yours is a very specifically pro
drug to.
Oh yeah,
that would be a real issue for sponsors.
I mean every now and then art bell would
have mckenna on.
They would discuss the,
been the stoned ape theory and what
happened and it would be very
fascinating,
but the amount of just raw information
over and over and over again talking
about talking in a positive way about
psychedelic experiences.
Like there's never been anything like
your show.
And if you think about it,
you know,
they,
they don't talk about doing the drugs as
much as about what they think about the
thoughts that come back.
You know,
the show really it would be called
philosophy,
but you know,
can you imagine having hundreds of
thousands of young people listening to a
philosophy podcast.
But that's the category it's in.
It is.
If you stop and think about it,
like most philosophical people,
if you call yourself a philosopher
there,
there blowhards yeah,
know there are people who pontificate
and philosophy without the drugs sucks.
It's very rare that it's right.
It's often overbearing,
often self centered,
often not self aware,
not objective and introspective.
It's missing an element.
That's a terrible thing to say,
but I think that without control of the
ego,
it's very good.
Difficult to get philosophy,
right?
Right.
It's very difficult to have unique ideas
that are that express like the the,
the,
the way that people want.
When someone wants to express a profound
thought to you.
If someone wants to express some sort of
a life changing idea that they've come
upon,
realize themselves.
It's very difficult to do that
sincerely.
Right?
Without coming off like a blowhard and
an asshole.
there's something about expressing
yourself in ways that it seems like when
people were trying to make profound
statements,
they're not just trying to make profound
statements.
They're also trying to sound awesome.
They're also trying to impress people
with their capturing of the english
language and their,
their use of prose,
but when someone like says something
like mckenna or someone says something
like,
um,
I mean there's been a million people
that have said brilliant things.
Alan watts is another one.
They,
they,
they've said something that just really
rings true in an honest and unique way.
It's a little bit more than psych than,
than just philosophy.
It's a little bit more than just
psychedelic.
It's like a combination of the two that
sparks a conversation,
period.
It sparks thinking.
It's like it's a seed of an idea that
gets planted and when you hear it or
especially when you watch it,
which is one the beautiful things about
these user created youtube videos.
They're so visually stunning.
They draw you in in that form as well.
The music they attached to them and then
the actual words themselves.
It's like the combinAtion of them is so
entertaining and captivating and
inspiring that it becomes something way
bigger than just philosophy,
right?
It becomes philosophy.
That's affective,
becomes philosophy that may actually
change the way you think.
It's very difficult to go to a
philosophy class and then change your
way of life.
Yeah.
sometimes it's boring and dull,
but sometimes they just talk too much
and they don't see anything interesting.
Like that's a big part of what people
like when they like podcasts,
like a guy like joey diaz per se,
or a guy like duncan trussell.
They're entertained people.
It's not just that they're saying cool
shit.
They're entertaining people and when
you're not entertaining and you're just
saying shit,
you're doing it wrong,
you're missing a big percentage of what
makes people listen to you.
right.
and retain it and retain it.
Yeah,
I mean that is the medium of the
fireside chat.
You know that that's where it came from.
One person would know or several people
would share stories,
but when you learned how to do it
correctly,
it became exciting for the people that
do are engaged in it and it became a,
you know,
an educational experience as well as an
entertaining experience.
Well,
that's the way we started doing mtma in
dallas back in the eighties is is either
a couple or maybe three couples at most
and we'd all take it.
We'd get together with our spouse or our
significant other for awhile and then
we'd get together in the last several
hours.
We'd just be talking and it would be,
you know,
philosophical life changing and I
noticed you're doing this,
see it lowers your bear.
It's like like lowering your fear
barrier where you can say something to
somebody and know you're not going to
hurt their feelings and so you,
the truth serum comes out and you can
talk to your friends and your spouse or
whatever and say,
you know,
this has been bothering me lately.
Well,
you know,
I thought maybe you know,
it's really a healing proposition that
you do for yourselves and each other.
Yeah.
I had a conversation with a friend when
I did ecstasy with him where he's asking
me why wouldn't lend them money to start
his business?
It was like,
ordinarily I would have avoided that
conversation like the plague because I
want to stay.
Your friend can't,
he can't do that difference.
It never works.
I'm not a bank.
Banks.
Banks are there for a reason and nobody
ever pays a friend's back.
No,
they just.
I mean,
I don't,
I shouldn't say nobody maybe.
But when somebody borrows 25 grand from
you,
most likely that shit's gone.
You know,
when I started my computer company,
the guy who was my mentor,
he loaned me a loan.
Did he loaned me some money.
I need to get home and have it took.
Uh,
he,
uh,
he loaned me some money to start the
business and then years later before I
paid him back about half of it and then
we went upside down and I was really
upset about it and it wasn't a lot of
money on them.
About $7,000
I guess.
It was a lot to me.
And I was lamenting the fact that,
you know,
I couldn't pay him,
I would eventually he says no.
He says,
and he,
he had a big tugboat business now.
he said,
when I started this business 25 years
ago,
my wife's father in law or father loaned
me the money and uh,
that business went broke in.
Two others went broke in.
He died before I could pay them back.
So that's his money.
You've got to find somebody to pay that
to you in the future.
But now,
well,
that's a very cool guy.
He was,
he was amazing guy.
That's a very cool guy and it's very
cool that you wanted to pay him back
early.
You making attempts to pay them back.
It's,
it's brutal though.
I've had several friends that have lost
friendships because they somebody money
and this one friend boy it,
it drove him crazy.
Like he would talk about it,
like this guy would come over his house
and this guy would hang out with them
and think I would never bring up the
fact that he owed them all this money
and you know,
and it would drive them crazy and they
was like,
look man,
I'm going to pay you when I can pay it.
But he would find out the guy just
bought a new this or that.
It'd be like,
what's this?
And so it became like a big part of his
life.
It became like this thing is this guy
who was a friend and he didn't want to
lose his friendship,
but he realized that the friendship was.
Now all of a sudden there's like really
negative thing where it was constantly
thinking,
hey,
I fucking pulled out money out of my
account.
I lent it to you.
You have no intentions of puking,
pain me back because I don't do anything
because I don't threaten you.
I can't repossess your car.
I can't do anything that a bank can do.
It's a fascinating thing when you see
people that just.
They don't go all the way with stuff
like they promise things they don't
follow through.
They get an idea in their head and then
they just fucking shut down and never
finish it.
You know,
well,
I'm going to start this business and
within,
let me tell you something.
Within six months I'm going to pay you
back with 25 percent interest.
It's impossible to lose.
and then six months later what happened,
man,
you're not going to believe this.
He got fucked bar manufacturer,
this and that.
So I'm out of business.
I don't know what you want to do.
What do I want to do?
You owe me a lot of money,
man.
Hey look,
you knew going in here.
This would be.
I took,
I took a loss like,
oh jesus christ.
And now you go right.
We can't pay you back.
I mean,
it happens over and over and over again.
There's a lot of people out there.
Just like when you were talking about
people that need people to help them,
you know,
like people coming up to you,
hey man,
help me.
This is,
hey man,
you just gotta let me some money.
Like there's other ways you know there's
other ways a guarantee you the best way
is not borrowing money from your
friends.
there's got to be a better way than
that.
You need to figure out how to get some
of that fucking money on your own.
It's not like we're in a totally closed
system or it's impossible to get a job.
It may bE difficult,
I understand,
but other people have figured it out.
It might be possible for you to figure
it out.
This is not like something like holding
your breath under water for an hour.
It seems like it can be done.
It's like,
you know,
do you ever have people come up to you
and say,
hey,
make me laugh and tell really,
because what I was thinking of your job,
are you.
Are your kids old enough for nimo yet?
Yes.
So the little clown fish,
clown fish make me laugh.
Make me laugh.
Yeah.
no,
no.
I mean people have said like it's worth.
The worst thing is when you're doing an
interview and like I feel like do a
radio or something like that.
Radio and they
go give us an example of your material
and like,
oh,
christ yet 15 minutes.
She will know.
It's like you can't.
Yeah,
you can't just do the cold.
it's stupid.
It's gross.
It's like just inept,
inept interviewing.
I had a friend that was a drummer and we
are in an after hours club down and
kima,
Texas and my mentor actually got him a
wanting to play the drums in this band
and he didn't want to,
he didn't want to and he's in,
oh,
I'm here to party.
And finally my,
my friend bribes the band,
gives them some money and tim gets on
the drums and,
and he's just kind of playing a little
bit and all of a sudden the guitarist
says,
okay,
take it.
And he hits the drum one time.
Bang.
He gets up and he says,
you'd take it back now.
That was funny.
Yeah.
it's uh,
I think,
uh,
one of the things about psychedelics
that really aids people is they get a
chance to see how annoying they can be.
You know?
Um,
I've,
I've met people that have changed a lot
of their behavior and have apologized to
friends and stuff or being an asshole or
doing whatever just because of
psychedelic trips.
I,
I won't trip with anybody anymore.
You do it by yourself.
I've,
I've had so many and I don't do hardly
any psychedelics anymore.
You start worrying about my heart now
and all that,
but you know,
uh,
I eyewash goes different,
you know,
if I was,
if I had,
you know,
I had cancer years ago,
if I had a recurrence,
I,
I'd go down to the jungle and spend a
couple of weeks,
but I think that can fix you when you do
that.
I think I lost,
can fix anything,
you know,
I'm,
I'm a huge wire and it's,
it's,
it's a miracle,
you know,
it has changed my life more than
anything else I've ever done.
Wow.
That's pretty awesome.
Yeah,
it is pretty awesome,
isn't it?
It's another thing that we've pretty
sweet.
If it was here,
it was legal.
We had iowasca centers,
right?
Yeah.
You know,
iT's,
it's,
it's such a weird state because it is
legal with some of the churches now.
But,
uh,
the,
you know,
it took me,
I was actively searching for it for
about 10 years until all of a sudden I
found it and,
and uh,
that's happened to so many people when
you don't find it until you're ready for
it and then it finds you.
And uh,
you know,
I've had,
had,
you know,
a lot of amazing experiences on some
difficult ones,
but that all,
all in all there,
it gives me more positive feeling about
this life and any other potential life
than I've ever had.
It's a,
but it's very earth centered.
You know,
I heard you talking to graham hancock
about how everybody gets ecological on
it and you know,
whereas acid is more mechanical,
you know,
you can do all kinds of problems and
code and stuff like that.
And mushrooms are pretty mystical.
But I will ask us earth centered,
you know,
it's,
it's an earth spirit that you're a
playing were engaged with and uh,
and it,
it can be a frightening and scary,
but you know,
amazing things that happened to me.
I,
I tried not to think too much about what
happens after death because I'm close
enough to find out sooner than I want
to,
but uh,
and,
and at times I,
I say,
well,
there's nothing there.
And other times I say there's something
there.
But uh,
as it happened four days after my mother
died,
I had an iowasca experience with the
circle that I've been with for quite
awhile and I didn't tell anybody that I,
that my mother had just died before the
ceremony.
I didn't tell I didn't want bum people
out or anything.
And occasionally the ios carol will call
individual people up to the front for a
healing or something.
And this night he happened to call me
and I go up to the front and it was
amazing.
You know,
my mother,
I actually saw the,
an image,
a huge image of my mother floating over
us that then,
well,
the next morning,
you know,
we all stay in the same room and sleep
on the floor at night and the next
morning we have breakfast together.
And then we go around the circle and
talk.
It's three different people said,
who was that spirit that appeared over
your head when you're up there?
And that just really freaked me out
because I thought,
well,
I'm imagining it and I'm making up my
head or whatever.
Three other people synced in some regArd
that there was a spirit there.
And I said,
well,
I think it was my mother.
She just died.
Is that possible that it's also both?
Oh,
it could be,
you know,
I,
I was thinking about it.
I could have projected it into the,
uh,
you know,
there's no question about,
I don't buy one way or the other.
I'm open ended on it.
So all I know is that was a very moving
experience for me.
And then other people saw something
happen.
Now maybe they were just feeling the
vibration of what I was going through
for wonder.
Um,
I wonder if you could.
I mean,
I don't understand exactly what's going
on when you're having any sort of a
psychedelic experience,
but I would imagine that if you are both
in the same mindset,
like if you and the person who was also
on [inaudible] in the room and you're
all in the same sort of psychedelic
mindset,
there's gotta be some sort of an
exchange of,
of information that's coming from your
head to their heads.
I mean,
that's why they wanted to call it
telepathy to let the thing.
Yeah.
Before they discovered that it was
already named and was called harming.
I have a friend that had some really,
really demonstrable,
a experiment like that that happened to
him.
And so he and another person who were
thinking the same thing at the same
time,
having the same vision,
what they did.
Well it wasn't,
uh,
they had uh,
this one guy is on one corner of the
room and he's thinking he was having
some ufo experience where there was a
spaceship.
And,
and,
uh,
he was thinking about getting on this
spaceship and just as he's thinking at
the guy on the other side of the room
and says,
hey,
don't forget there's only room for 10
people.
They're opposite sides of the room,
quiet
and stuff like that.
I've heard people have really like a
unique visuals that everyone in the room
had.
And I alWays wonder if maybe you can
conjure up something with your
imagination or with your focus,
your ideas.
You can conjure up sort of a psychic
image in your mind.
And because everyone's tuned into this
thing,
they see it in their hallucinogenic
imagination as well.
It's definitely possible.
It's possible.
right?
I know.
And yet on the most intense experience
I've ever had,
I was really,
I'd never had an experience is
transformative.
This is this An osca.
And,
and I can't even quite describe it,
but I was shocked the next morning that
the world had ended and everybody
experienced this.
Nobody in the room was even close to
this and I'd had the most transformative
experience of my life.
And to them it was just another night,
you know,
the,
yeah,
that's the weirdest thing about doing
dmt,
that you're sitting on a couch and
outside your house,
nothing's changed,
but inside your head,
a whirlwind of possibilities have opened
and you've all of a sudden seeing a
world that couldn't possibly have ever
existed,
even in your imagination just a few
minutes before,
even in your imagination as a strong
statement.
But it's absolutely true.
Once you do dmt,
if you've never done it and you have a
breakthrough experience,
the one thing that everybody always says
is,
I never saw that coming.
Right?
Never would have imagined that that was
possible.
Yeah.
It's,
it's,
it's pretty awesome.
Some of the things that do happen,
but whether they're happening in your
head or somewhere else,
it's just hard to say.
But they're both are both iowasca,
you know,
there's,
I think a lot of what happens is what
your intention is going in.
Yeah.
And uh,
you know,
I had had one x one experience where I
want to get rid of my fear.
that was really,
you know,
I couldn't watch the fear factor because
it was just so made me fearful a,
I'm a wimp,
ya know what I'm saying?
I'm making the wine.
But uh,
so I deCided that that was the night I
want to get rid of fear.
And you know,
you fast watching fear factor,
you decided you want to deny Alaska.
It was my intention that night.
No,
it wasn't fear factor.
I'd never go on it.
But uh,
the.
So you,
you,
you fast the day before.
And I'd been fasting since around eight
in the morning.
Only had a few sips of water.
So there's nothing in my stomach.
Sometimes you purge,
you vomit,
and sometimes you don't.
The first half dozen times I did it,
I did not vomit.
And,
and you get disappointed too.
Once you,
once you get into the purging,
then you realize it's like being inside
a fireworks display.
It's really spectacular.
sounds gross.
But really,
so as you throwing up,
it's amazing.
Oh,
It's,
it just amps the whole experience up.
It's close to an orgasm.
Not real close,
but it's that that's what it'll bring to
mind.
So anyhow,
uh,
you sit there and,
and all of a sudden a little voice will
come into your head and said,
grab your bucket because you sit with an
empty bucket and I can grab your bucket.
And whenever I hear that little voice,
I grabbed my bucket because I know I'm
excited to throw up the first few times,
but after awhile I got into it and it
said,
grab your bucket and said,
we're getting rid of your fear tonight.
And so I've started purging and purging
and purging and I said,
oh wow.
I finally goT rid of,
oh no,
you got more to go.
And I purged for 45 minutes and the next
morning I go to empty the bucket.
There's a couple inches of black crap in
this bucket,
you know?
And I didn't have hardly anything in my
stomach.
And,
and according to the way the shamans
speak is your psychic energy,
you're purging.
And so I really had a visual pouring my
fear down the toilet in the morning.
Damn,
I would've saved that shit and sanitary
lab.
Do you imagine the isolated a new
compounds?
I never thought of that.
That fear is actually.
Something exists in your body can be
removed.
She's.
I wish I'd thought of that.
I don't know what lab,
but send it to.
What was it?
Maybe we'll find out.
I was just like spaghetti.
You have some old spaghetti ingestion is
not fear.
During the years when you were smoking
cigarettes.
Left some stuff on the walls of some,
some cigarette graffiti.
That's fascinating.
You should have taken pictures of it or
something.
Well,
you know at the time you don't really
think of those things.
Could.
Is it possible that it was just all like
[inaudible]?
He drank.
He drank too much.
He only drink a little shot.
A little shot glass.
Yeah.
So how was it two inches of liquid?
What was in it was just.
It was,
it was.
It was not real thick and it was just
bile.
I guess it looked black.
What it smelled like.
Puke.
Hmm.
Interesting.
Wow.
You should've taken a picture of that.
That sounds like pretty intense stuff
and then once it was,
is it possible you were still high when
you saw two inches of a.
Yes,
I mean that was awesome.
Yeah.
So you,
you,
you take,
you drink it about eight,
8:00
at night or so.
Right.
And then by two in the morning,
three in the morning,
you're your most of the people that are
down to base,
back to baseline and sometimes say,
oh yeah,
I'm back to baseline and you find you
can't stand up,
but then you sleep on the floor there
and get up in the morning.
By the next morning you're,
you're pretty much back to baseline as
far as the chemical,
but you're still in the thrall of the
thing and,
and uh,
you know,
you're,
you're somewhere else.
So yeah,
it might've been two millimeters,
but either way there was something in
there.
I'm not going to change my memory of it
though.
That's a good idea.
Just hang onto it.
That's how jesus got started.
Write it down in about a year.
he lasted for awhile.
Tell it to a bunch of people.
Let it get crazier and crazier every
time you tell it that a few years later,
write it down,
but write it down in like metaphors,
right?
Right.
Damn,
latin and parables and you know,
because I speak very well,
there's a guy in a,
there's a scholar in jerusalem that,
uh,
in a,
in Israel who wants to,
um,
he,
he's trying to push the idea that moses
was on psychedelics when he found the
tablets and that the burning bush was
actually the acacia bush,
which is rich and dmt.
And that's why it's burning.
Like in burning the bush,
he saw god.
He's trying to say that this.
What this meant was they burned the
contents of this plant.
You're just getting many,
many,
many translations from ancient hebrew to
latin to greek.
The fact that to this day in ancient
hebrew,
there's a lot of dispute about what
things mean in the first place.
Like for folks who don't know,
ancient hebrew didn't have,
they didn't have numbers,
so letters doubled his numbers.
So the letter a was also the number one,
right?
So words had numerical value,
like the word and the word god have the
same numerical value.
It's a really strange system that we
lost the context of all these magical
sort of definitions of things and
descriptions of things because there was
a mathematical qualities to these words
that we went to this to this day we.
It's,
it's such a unique way of looking at
things in comparison to how we look at
things today.
We look at words and then we look at
mathematics is being completely
separate.
They had it all kind of combined
together in some sort of a weird ancient
language that doesn't exist anymore.
So when people try to translate it and
then you go from that to latin and greek
and it's gone.
It's all weird now.
Right?
So when these guys are trying to go back
and look at these original descriptions,
they said,
well,
one burning bush might very well be the
acacia bushes.
It makes sense.
It's prominent in the area.
And if they had figured out a way to get
dmt from this bush,
they had figured out a way to do some
kind of a process.
And extracted,
that could be how they described it and
that was one of the things that mark
john,
margo allegro,
it said about the bible when they had
studied the dead sea scrolls and he
wrote that book,
the sacred mushroom in the cross.
He was saying that they were trying to
hide these things from the romans when
they were capturing.
People were originally writing these
things down and what they really were
were descriptions of psychedelic
mushroom consumption and of fertility
cults that they hit all these stories
and in parables because they wanted to
keep the information,
but they didn't want other people to be
able to access it.
By the way,
I heard you mentioned that book we have
before and you said you got an old
coffee,
but you know,
I've got a couple of young urban health
republished it,
so it's still a bit.
You can get it on amazon.
Yeah.
It's very cool to
done that.
Yeah,
you can get it now.
When I bought it,
I bought it many,
many years ago because of jack herer yon
introduced me to jack hair and jack
herer was working on a book with this
other guy who turned out to be a
pedophile like wind up murdered in jail
or something like that.
Really crazy stuff,
but they were working on this book about
santa claus and the connection between a
santa claus and the amanita miscarry.
A mushroom and the crank have read all
that.
That was.
Yeah.
That was basically all his work and then
it was the connection between psilocybin
mushrooms and religious experiences and
jack had all these old images like
really old images of ancient paintings
that showed naked people dancing under
this translucent mushroom and that there
was.
There was their way of describing being
under the excess and then he showed me
all these different religious religious
institutions and buildings and places
that had mushroom shaped doorways and
had mushroom iconography and the
mushrooms all over the place.
So you didn't even think of with
mushrooms like the way a cardinals ca
outfit is red and white and the whole
like saying like signifies the ancient
images of halos.
You've seen the ancient images of halos
is a mushroom cap.
I mean it is a mushroom cap.
Literally.
I've seen a lot of those old images in
the first century.
The so called christian churches had a
lot of mushrooms.
Yeah.
They art.
They didn't have that,
that hulu thing floating or above their
head.
They have this thing behind them which
showed this mushroom.
Yeah.
I mean with literally all the lines
underneath the app,
pull it,
pull up images if you can.
There's an article where I linked to it.
It was a santa claus was a mushroom.
It was,
I wrote it in like 2007 from my website.
It's on joe rogan.net.
And I put in it a bunch of photographs.
A couple of them have ancient people
that had mushroom caps for,
for their,
uh,
their.
yeah,
it's only about the last few thousand
years that this has been suppressed,
but it was pretty active psychodelic,
uh,
in the ancient time.
It's amazing that this is all true.
this sounds like nonsense.
I mean,
this sounds like some flat earth shit,
like when you hear,
if you don't know any better and you're,
you know,
you're listening to you and I talk about
this quite a bit in one,
but it's well documented.
There's a lot of documentation about it.
There's a lot of information that shows
that there was,
you know,
not just the christian religion,
but many,
many,
many religions were aware of psychedelic
mushrooms here.
Jamie's going to pull up this.
Did you find it yet?
Um,
the,
uh,
the images that Jack Harris showed me
were really unique and I haven't been
able to locate him since he was in the
middle of a book before he had a stroke.
Right.
That's a shame.
Yeah.
I was really sad.
He,
I met him and then he had a,
he had a stroke and then he had a second
stroke as well.
I met him,
I believe after the first one he was,
because he was having difficulty talking
then,
but it wasn't as bad and then apparently
a bad one,
but they were in the middle of creating
this book and his,
you know,
he,
his story was fascinating because jack
hair,
like you was a republican,
he was a goldwater republican as you
described it.
And then he got divorced and met a girl
in the world.
Opened up,
do,
but you know,
a lot of the ufo thing may be a dmt
released about 10 or 12 years ago.
I corresponded with quit whitney driver
because in one of his books he had said
something that to me sounded just like a
dmt trip.
And he allowed his,
hey,
that might be possible.
And then about a year or so later,
he did a radio show with a straussman
that you were in his movie,
a spirit molecule.
And uh,
he,
they,
the two agreed that this could,
some of the abduction experiences could
be a spontaneous release of dmt.
Yeah.
It makes sense to me why,
when you think about it,
why are all these experiences where
people are getting abducted all
happening in the middle of the night and
that's when your brain is producing the
most dmt allegedly mean they know for a
fact now that's been proven by the
cottonwood research work that
strassman's done cottonwood research
foundation.
They've found dmt and a live rats pineal
gland.
They found that regional,
so they know for a fact that the pineal
gland is a source of.
That's the first I've heard that.
A real research because it has been
speculated on,
but had really turned it
down.
Yeah.
That's,
uh,
I'll,
I'll pull up the article because it's
pretty interesting found and live rats,
pineal gland.
It's um,
I mean it's one thing that they've
always pointed to it.
There's a lot of anecdotal evidence,
especially the ancient,
the ancient religious work of the third
eye itself,
symbol of mysticism,
much like the mushroom cap being the,
the halo why,
right.
But we're just now getting back and,
and unfortunately we've lost so much
information that humans had at one time
about these substances.
But I think part of the transition that
took place was,
you know,
the,
the rights of looses a were,
you know,
so many thousands of people went through
that.
That lasted for a couple thousand Years.
But in about 300 bc,
the state took over control of the
rights and once the government took over
control,
things changed.
This is the article on the cottonwood
research.org
website,
which is strassman's foundation says
we're excited to announce the acceptance
of for publication of a paper
documenting the presence of dmt and the
pineal gland of live rodents.
The paperwork will appear in the journal
biomedical chromatography and describes
experiments that took place in dr joe
schmo bore.
Wow.
This guy is a weird name.
B o r g I,
g I,
j I g I n,
b o r j I g I n.
How do you say that?
Or does aj and a g together.
Bitch,
what are you trying to do to people?
Why the fuck would you put aj and a g
together?
One of the other.
You greedy bitch.
They're both sound.
What is that saying?
See those images you see the one mean?
That is about as clear as day.
That's the bottom of a goddamn machines
where the spores will come.
Well,
there's one.
Don't go to youtube.
There's one on my website.
Get to it.
Did you google it?
Okay,
the fuck happened.
So have you ever seen a machine elf or a
self transforming basketball?
No,
I haven't either.
But you know what?
I finally figured out those self
transforming basketballs,
I figured out I'm seeing the same thing,
but I wouldn't call it that.
I'd call it something else.
Excuse me.
And that's,
that's why I never described what I see
because then you plant that seed in
somebody's head and terrence did Plant
the seed of the self transforming
machine elves and the basketball's a
jeweled basketballs.
And I think that if you get rid of those
words,
those labels,
you'll see things that you could say,
well,
I could say that,
but I'd rather say this about it.
So a lot of people get disappointed when
they smoked dmt and they don't see the
machine elves in the basketballs.
Yeah,
I don't know what that means.
The machine elves,
the basketballs on this stuff is,
is my,
my website down or some point that it
was linking back to the new podcast side
for some reason.
Oh,
so the links are bad.
Is that what it is?
No way.
Really.
HM.
Okay.
Well I found it in two seconds.
If you Go to wordpress,
you can still find it.
But the images there I found that didn't
have any images flow was looking for.
So I've got to get these guys to fix my
website.
That's bullshit that although that stuff
should be up there with photographs none
up there and none of it's up there.
Oh great.
Not that way.
At least somewhere else.
How dare they?
Um,
but I think it's probably pretty obvious
that if you're dealing with people that
lived a long time ago and we know for a
fact that these substances existed a
long time ago.
They've been here forever.
So people would have found them,
they would have ate them.
They were freaked out and they would
have told everybody or try to tell
people that they cared about or just
information just like we do.
I mean,
it's withoUt a doubt,
it's got to be like one of the most
powerful things that can happeN to a
person outside of dying.
Yeah.
Outside of having,
having children dying,
losing a loved one,
what have You.
One of the most powerful things and
experiences that you can have is a
second.
It shouldn't be missed whether you never
have a second one or not.
You should at least have one.
Yeah,
it's.
Well,
it's just amazing that it's illegal
still.
It's amazing that they've been able to
hold on this long with everything that
we know now about what is legal.
We talked about before,
cIgarettes,
cremini,
what are you trying to do?
Trying to keep everybody week.
You know,
if I was inclined to believe that
that's.
There's the evidence right there.
If I was inclined to believe tHat they
are trying to keep people stupid and
weak,
I buy into terrence's a theory that
nobody's in charge.
You know,
there's a bunch of competing groups that
have a lot of power,
but not any one of them is in charge of
calling the shots and most of them are
pretty stupid people that we think some
of these people are maybe smart because
they have money or something.
Most of them inherited it or they got it
as a derivatives trader or something,
but most people in congress and politics
and no matter who you meet,
you know there's like you and I were all
you,
all.
Some of them have experience in these
jobs,
but we shouldn't give them all this
credence of being.
Knowing all.
No.
They live a life that's.
That's the momentum of what they've done
in the past and what their ancestors
have done and how they've gotten to this
position because of their family name
and the business that they grew up in,
in what happened and it's just a
momentous thing and once the family
controls a certain amount,
whether it's the world bank or whether
it's whatever the fuck you get all your
corporation,
your,
your family owns.
Once someone has that kind of power and
control,
they're not very,
it's not very likely that they're going
to be willing to let that go
and they bring their children up in that
same moment,
you know,
they're going to private schools are
meeting the same friends who are from
the same kinds of families and so it's,
it's a inbreeding kind of thing.
It's one of the problems with
capitalism,
but I also think it's one of the ins and
the yang of life and one of the reasons
why there's so much motivation for
people to get things together today
because we see so much evil and
corruption and the hypocrisy.
We see it.
So we get motivated.
Well,
the internet's changed everything.
We can see things without going through
a corporate sense or not to.
That's never happened before.
It's a.
And I think people are way more informed
now because of the,
oh,
the internet's changed all the rules.
You know,
if the internet was around in the
sixties,
there would have been a different
outcome.
But,
uh,
I think,
I think that what's going on now is
gonna make the sixties look like the
fifties,
you know,
the thing.
I think slowly but surely people are
waking up to the idea that we aren't the
same people that we were in 1994.
Oh,
seven years ago.
There was no iphone that has changed a
lot of things.
Yes.
Apps,
you know,
twitter and facebook and all that jazz.
Just the ability to get like,
I love twitter because I get link sent
to me like,
check out this new scientific findings,
look at this new discovery,
check out this video,
this is amazing.
This guy made this and look at that.
And it's like,
the amount of interesting information
that comes to you directly on your
phone,
a daily basis is pretty staggering.
When we were first trying to get the
internet going and the phone companies
that,
uh,
there wasn't a lot of acceptance.
Nobody,
the banks wouldn't talk to us,
the government wouldn't talk to us.
But our company bought bbn which,
uh,
built the original routers and have
control about a third of the backbone.
And we were watching,
you know,
say,
oh,
there's already a million people
connected to the internet.
Oh,
there's 2 million now.
There's $5 million and we're comparing
with how fast phones a rolled out.
And it was just several orders of
magnitude faster.
But to get to where we are today,
I don't think anybody 10 years ago would
have predicted to have a billion people
connected already.
Nobody saw it coming and nobody knows
what's going to be here in 10 years.
Yeah,
there's,
it'd be crazy to try to predict it.
It's gonna be way weirder,
but you know,
and,
and the iphone and the ipad and all the
wireless,
you know,
that when I was in the business,
I was at the dinner afterwards we get
to.
I was representing the phone company so
they'd take me out to wine and dine me.
And uh,
talking to this one guy who's the
president of a new combination of
netflix and netscape and a son,
they form an alliance and their senior
vice president was saying,
hey,
you need to start doing more research
and development in wifi.
And this was before why,
you know,
there was essentially no wireless and
this is the only like,
I don't know,
14 years ago or something.
And I said,
oh,
the wireless,
that's not gonna work.
He says we're putting all of our r and d
money into it because we're all living
up in the hills over san jose.
And there was no internet connectivity.
And by the time we retire we want high
speed wireless internet in their home.
That was a lot of the motivation for
dol.
That's interest,
personal interest in,
you know,
one of the things people don't want to
talk about about the internet,
but since we were running part of the
backbone,
I could go to watch it through the
network,
the knock and watch them,
uh,
manage the traffic on the backbone of
the internet.
And it was in an a week day,
around 3:30
or 4:00,
a big spike would hit of usage on the
east coast.
Here's me.
And as the time would go four or five by
6:00,
the east coast spike would go down and
the midwest would be up.
And then it was like a pig going through
a python and it was young kids coming
home from school before their parents
where they're downloading porn without
porn.
The,
the phone companies wouldn't put all
that money into the backbone because it
huge business,
you know,
they're not always works though.
That's how the video recorder videotape
came out,
you know,
because people go to watch porn at home.
Yeah.
Vhs,
remember those bought a beta.
Does you really?
You're one of those guys.
They Were supposed to be better though.
Weren't saying.
Well the.
Yeah.
But they couldn't get many titles on.
The quality was better.
It was better.
You got to go with whatever the mass
produced thing is.
Do you remember those things that used
to have to go through to look at the
porn?
You still have to go through beads or a
oh,
the doors and you go in a little cubby
hole or something like that.
Yeah.
To have to go through so doors in order
to answer the warrants.
And then in the afternoon she could see
the cars from all the salesmen's cars
are parked out there,
you know.
And people just look at you so squirrely
like,
oh,
I can't believe I'm in this place.
You know,
you don't sit down on the seat.
The people were interesting like that.
They,
they,
they don't want you to know that they
like sex or like masturbating.
Like they want to pretend like they
never do it.
That's.
Yeah.
It's a fascinating aspect of us were so
weird.
I don't think that humans have always
been that way.
You know?
I think really,
I,
I think,
you know,
the last 2000 years had been pretty
repressive.
What happened?
Christianity largely I think organized
religion,
you know,
the sex thing was weird because we know
there's a lot of sex going on in the
clergy,
you know,
but uh,
the boy boy sex,
etc.
But I think it's been,
you know,
you read about the borgia pope's and
stuff like that,
you know,
if the higher elevations of the church
have always been big involved in sex,
but they'd been telling the people no,
no,
no.
Well,
they used to have sex like popes and
priests and bishops.
These to have sex with women.
Oh,
used to be like totally normal that they
had kids,
some of the pope's.
Yeah,
but they had,
they were getting so much pussy guts,
so out of control.
Hey,
I'm the pope,
you know,
who's going to say no,
exactly.
So people go and you know what,
listen,
that's it.
You can't have sex anymore unless you
become a priest and join our little
group here.
And uh,
but even then there wasn't even an
undercover sex with kids.
You know,
like how the idea that an undercover
group of kid fuckers could run a
gigantic cult that would encapture like
a billion people worldwide.
That 2013 is in one of the most
incredible facts about our,
our reality.
Yeah.
You know,
I,
I was,
uh,
I was raised catholic and a altar boy.
I served mass all,
all through four years of college even.
And uh,
did you ever get touched?
Never once,
never will.
Never approached,
never touched nobody often just
cigarette or it's not a thing for a
drink.
You know,
all those four years I was an altar boy
in college.
I never went to communion because I
wouldn't go to confession because I
didn't want to tell him I masturbated,
but uh,
you know,
during all that time I was never once
approach.
But a guy he became a priest was a close
friend of mine when
he was a kid.
We went to boy scout camp together.
Now he turned out to be a pedophile
priest,
you know,
it's a real tragedy for the family.
You know,
we knew all of these and
yeah,
there you think that that happens just
because of repression that someone has
an access to know sex and then when they
were on kids,
they just almost are overwhelmed.
Yeah,
I know.
You know how you are when you're 20
years old and it's all you think about
and if you're,
if you're repressed,
you know,
maybe go wherever the first option is.
And the opportunity is.
But I don't think he was actually
molested as a child because he and I
went through the same priests and
everything and I'm pretty sure he wasn't
molested a.
This happened to him after he got to the
seminary.
Wow.
That's horrible.
yeah,
it's,
it's even more horrible if,
if the actual act of making someone
celibate sorta perpetrates this turns
people in some ways towards having sex
with almost basically anybody that can
celibacy is going to go away eventually.
I hope so.
It hasn't been here only a few hundred
years.
The.
Yeah,
I mean,
but this,
the idea that peOple have done that
throughout time is also another
disturbing fact of,
of,
of civilization when you find out about
socrates and they had sex with young
boys on a regular basis
in some countries.
I know that we had a friend who told us
some real what I considered horror
stories that they considered serving
normal behavior,
you know?
Yeah.
I've had friends who've gone to
Afghanistan described,
you know what they call man loved
thursdays are a boy loved thursdays or I
don't know how much is true now.
It's not,
but you know the idea that people have
sex with young boys for pleasure and
women for procreation.
Right.
And that this is practice has been.
I can't get my head,
I can't get my head around that.
Well,
hopefully the internet will expose that
as well.
I mean,
I,
I wonder what it would take to
psychically clean us up of all our weird
patterns that were caught up in
entrapped in regular and frequent
psychedelic experiences that could help
and also communication and the
communication in a way.
Good.
Alex.
Lubricate communications.
CertainlY.
First of all,
there's a lot of things that you can't
even put words around and so you get
together and you start trying to do art
or music or some way to do that and
let's communicate and get a new
language.
Looking at what all alex grey is done.
Yeah.
You know,
in getting that message out there.
So you're right,
we're,
we're local.
how far we've come in our lifetime.
We're nowhere near where I want to be,
but I've been in new orleans when I had
to look white drinking fountain,
black drinking fountain,
where to sit on the street car and you
know,
that,
that segregation is still here,
but it's not nearly as bad as it was.
It's not quite as sanctioned as it was.
And uh,
you know,
women's rights are a little bit little
bit better and my son was able to get
married to the man he loved,
you know,
so we are making some social progress
and probably making a lot more in a
short period of time than we realize.
Yeah,
that's where the exponential growth
really kicks in is in social progress.
And you know,
like,
I've,
I've made fun of a lot of like really
heavy duty lefties,
people that are like ultra progressive
to the point of being ridiculous.
But I kind of appreciate the effort
because this powerful strong effort for
whatever it is.
I mean,
I've gotten in trouble for saying that I
don't think a transgender man we came,
a woman should be able to fight and
women's mma it.
My point is from the safety of the
athletes,
but people have defended transgender
people because of the fact that they
automatically stand up for someone they
feel like is being oppressed.
And I appreciate that.
I appreciate the idea behind that.
I think I appreciate the sentiment
behind that.
And I think that's fascinating as a
culture that there are people that if
you repress gay rights,
they will go after you and they will.
I think that's a good thing,
whether it's misguided or not.
And a lot of times it is when it comes
to certain aspects of progressive
thinking,
the fact that heavy duty lefty behavior
exists and exists in like big groups and
big organized groups I think is very
important.
I think it's very important because it
balances out the heavy duty,
right end right wing and right leaning
groups.
I think all those things eventually with
education and with the undeniable truth
at the internet presents,
we'll find some sort of a comfortable
medium of truth were really self
aggrandizement,
douchey behavior.
No laughed is just as gross as self
aggrandizement,
douchey behavior on the right.
And people realize that compassion does
not have to have an ideology attached to
it.
It should be a part of how human beings
behave.
You know,
when I was a rep republican,
I was not a bad person.
I was very misinformed.
I,
you know,
and I came up from the poor side of the
street,
you know,
my dad didn't have a car when I was
growing up and stuff and so I,
I,
you know,
I made a lot of money.
I thought,
oh this is great.
I did this on my own,
but I didn't,
you know,
I,
I've decided that an until everybody has
the same advantages as a white college
educated american male,
I'm not allowed to complain that it's
not.
Even then it's not,
you know,
I've had.
So even though we didn't have money,
I was,
I had so many advantages.
Oh,
we're running out of time here.
So.
But we.
But I would like to talk to you a little
bit more.
Do you want to talk some more?
WhaT's his end this and we'll talk a
little bit more.
So,
uh,
we'll say thanks to everybody for tuning
into the podcast.
Thanks to legal zoom.com.
Go to legalzoom.com.
Use the code rogan and save yourself
some cash.
Thanks.
Also to go to [inaudible] dot ting.com
and save yourself 25 bucks off of any
new phone on tang.
Bring your iphone over from sprint and
you can use them there.
And thanks also to onnit.com.
Go to o,
n n I to use the code name brogan.
Save 10 percent off any and all
supplements.
Alright freaks.
We're seeing a minute.