Four,
three,
two,
one.
Kelly slater,
we've been talking about doing this for
how long?
Couple of years.
While for having me.
Thanks for being here.
I'm glad we finally got a chance to do
it.
What are you in California for?
I know you broke your foot,
right?
I broke my foot real bad.
I have to do that.
Might.
Well my girlfriend's from San Clemente
and her family lives there and uh,
so we kind of live here.
We're not moving around too much so I'm
just going to here right now.
I'm not competing.
I broke my foot.
I was surfing in South Africa about 15
months ago and I was just on a wave that
I wouldn't consider a very big wave.
Nobody would really considered dangerous
and it all kind of closed out,
which is,
you know,
when it all breaks at once,
I just pulled into thing because I was
going to sort of wash on the rocks right
where that was and change boards and uh,
I was practicing.
I had to compete and about two hours
from then.
So I was just testing out different
boards for some reason I wasn't riding
the board,
I was planning on writing competition so
I was going to come in and change and
switch to my norm board and I just
pulled this wave and just,
I kinda hesitated like usually you
either ride those out and stay on your
board or you jump off and I was kind of
between the two and I kind of lifted my
front foot off my back foot.
My leg was straight because I was kinda
going to think I was going to jump off
and as my foot got my leg got locked
back straight.
The board flipped in.
Oh,
against the toes.
And it just broke the top of my foot and
a half.
Like immediate.
Like there was my guy.
Yeah,
we're looking at a photograph of the
expert right now and it's like every
bone it's snapped.
Well what you can't see.
So do you know,
are you aware of the Liz Frank joint
niches?
Like that's where the first big
metatarsal comes together.
So that first big joint on top of the
foot there.
Why is it called a Liz frank joint list?
Frank was a doctor,
I think is what I am.
I could,
we could look this up.
I think that was the person that did the
original surgery when you used to break
your foot in a stirrup back 100 years
ago.
They used to cut your foot off.
Oh God damn it.
Ah,
so,
so that was,
what was it?
Uh,
that was kind of how this sort of joint
got famous.
But normally what happens is those toes,
those two bones right there,
the first and second metatarsal can
either spread or converge one way or the
other.
And that's usually what a liz frank
fracture is.
I had the best of the three,
which is,
I had a crack.
You can just see on the right side of.
Yeah,
if you go down with the cursor right
there,
just a little lower.
There's a little crack right there,
uh,
right there on that corner.
And then the next one broke across.
You can just see right there.
It's cracked across.
And then so it kind of went in a line up
and across the foot.
And then the other two are just
destroyed.
The third one displaced the fourth when
shattered into eight pieces.
The doctor said he lost count putting
them back together and then,
you know,
you,
you would know from injuries.
The problem with when the shatters of
bone,
they're not getting the blood flow.
So it's not like a four or five week
repair job.
It's like,
that was like nine months before that
thing was together properly.
So when they do that,
how do they piece that shattered one
back together again?
A delicately and they put like a mesh
over.
So I got to kind of like figure out how
to.
Well I had,
I had a plate on the list,
frank,
and then it had a plant play,
a kind of a bridge across the third and
fourth.
And so they kind of meshed it all
together.
And then,
uh,
I think I had 16 screws combined in all
that.
God Damn.
Um,
it was,
it was brutal.
The problem with it was I did it in
South Africa where I wasn't going to get
surgery,
so I had to wait for the swelling to go
down for about six days before I could
fly.
Oh God.
Because they thought it was going to
swell too much because it was already
swollen from the event.
So I shit on my foot for like five days
and sat there and watched.
Unfortunately the waves were perfect,
so I was sitting on the beach as
watching perfect waves and you know,
it's like,
that's like as painful as the injury to
a surfer,
you know,
it's like watching a bunch of elk walked
by in front of you and,
and not,
not scared of you.
And uh,
um,
so I sat there because the whole time
prior to me being injured while I was
there for like two weeks,
the ways weren't very good.
So I broke my foot in the way he's got
great.
Oh.
So I had to watch it,
so it's,
that's painful for us.
But uh,
so then I waited for the swelling to go
down and then it's too red eyes to get
back.
Was there no way you could get it fixed
in South Africa?
I maybe could have,
but then I was probably looking at St
Africa for a month or more in and also I
didn't know that the quality sort of
level of quality of doctor I was going
to get there.
And I got a doctor I work with here and
I called him straightaway.
I said,
look,
it's my fourth broken foot,
but I've never broken it like this.
Usually it's like let it heal for four
weeks.
And you're surfing and it's all from
surfing.
Yeah.
In offering the same way.
I'll really,
really pretty much the board going back
against the foot fall.
Um,
because.
And usually it happens when I'm,
you know,
I don't know how well versed you are in
surfing,
but when I'm tube riding and usually
with my back to the wave,
which has happened two or three times.
So I'm in the wave,
the lip pitches over and lands.
But when that lands it sends a shock
back into the way.
Like,
you know,
when the lip hits flatwater that lip,
some of the energy goes down and some
disperses out and up and some comes back
into the tube,
so if it does that and you're in the
wrong spot,
the board will flip into your feet,
but oh wow.
Normally what we do is we were,
when you rubbed backside barrel ride,
a lot of times you're grabbing the rail
so you kind of have both your feet and
your hand on it so you can handle that
shock,
but if you're just going no hand
backside,
it's usually pretty big intense barrel
and so that lip has a lot of energy and
it shoots a ton of force back towards
you.
And if,
if it hits your board just rolling,
it can flip in your foot and break it.
Do you know anybody else's broken their
foot like you like that?
Not this bad.
I'm one guy on tour broke his foot.
Pretty bad knee requiring surgery this
year.
That looks horrible,
man.
How long was it before you can walk?
You're walking.
Totally normal now.
So how long has it been since the
surgery?
I had surgery in July last year and then
walking normal wasn't until maybe
December,
January.
Well,
December I competed again,
but I probably shouldn't have,
but we're,
we're at pipeline in Hawaii,
which is,
you're not doing maneuvers.
It's not a small wave kind of
competence.
If the waves are small,
I wouldn't have served since it's
bigger.
It's a little easier because you take
off and kind of trim a straight line.
So you're kind of going straight,
you know,
even though you're writing the barrel,
you're kind of going straight,
but are you conscious of your foot being
compromised?
Yeah.
Wow.
I don't know.
I just,
that's my favorite event in the world,
so I just didn't want to miss it.
But fuck.
If you broke your foot again.
Yeah.
But then you know,
the bones were pretty good back together
then.
And I could walk somewhat without pain
and if I put myself in a real
vulnerable,
vulnerable position on a wave,
I would kind of maybe jump off,
you know,
I wouldn't really push it.
It's not worth winning a contest,
dillon foot again,
but I'm sure to be able to surf pipeline
with no one out is kind of worth the
risk.
Now when you are healing,
is there anything they give you that can
accelerate bone healing or is there any.
Supplements are.
A lot of.
It is kind of.
I mean it's the furthest place from your
heart,
right?
So.
And it's,
it's down at the bottom of your body,
so you got to kind of get that foot up.
Like a lot of times I'll sit against a
wall and elevate my foot and let it
completely flush out.
You know when you're a kid and you kind
of hold your hand and somebody pushed
all the blood out of your hand,
you ever do that one?
No.
It's like this trick where somebody hold
your,
your arteries.
So No blood's going in,
you push all the hands,
all the blood out and then you let it go
and it's like a little spider web feels
like if somebody goes like that,
it was killing a spider web.
I did do that when I was a kid.
So it was forgotten,
I just kind of imagined that's what I
was doing with my foot up and like,
oh,
okay,
all the blood's getting out of my foot
now and I'm a.
But did you like research whether
there's something that accelerates bone
healing or you can use magnets.
Magnets,
yes.
Some people believe magnets help
increase the circulation and thus the,
the uh,
especially,
uh,
rotating magnet because it kind of
creates a force field around your foot.
Really?
Yeah.
Supposedly,
I mean,
around the magnets.
Is this like,
are these legit people are,
these days are like theories healer's
healer,
energy healer.
While I'm just saying what I've heard
people.
So the first time I broke my foot,
a guy,
a chiropractor,
Guy I had gone to,
he's like,
just when you go to sleep,
it's not going to hurt,
you just put her on your foot.
And I was actually competing,
uh,
five weeks after I broke that foot.
So I don't know if it helped or not,
but I just asleep and it was near my
foot and maybe it helped.
That takes six weeks for a bone heal,
right?
Doesn't it?
When you're on to take four weeks and
then it takes two more weeks for the
calcium to properly fill in.
So like the.
If you take an extra after four weeks
it'll still look like there's a whole,
like a break there,
but apparently the bone has sutured
itself back.
But if calcium has not filled in to make
it totally strong.
That's what I was told by my doctor on
this last one because I asked every
question possible why is it still look
broken?
Why is it.
And he was telling me,
you know,
it's not till you get enough blood flow
and then it's.
And then it's once there's the proper
blood flow in the bone,
then you get the calcium coming back.
And the only thing that I've heard too
that really is supposed to accelerate
healing is a hyperbaric chamber.
Which I didn't do.
I had one sort of at hand in Hawaii I
could have gone to,
but I didn't know I was supposed to.
I know that Uriah Faber use that a lot
after he fought Josie Aldo,
although kick the shit out of his leg
and his leg was really badly.
Swollen was horrible.
No Bra.
Did he break the bone?
No,
it didn't break the bone,
but it was.
It was so bad.
It was like his left leg was literally
twice the size.
And remember Paul,
I've seen the.
I've seen the flight photo.
Are you talking there it is right there.
There's a photo and in the fight you're
talking about.
Look at the color on his leg.
It was so nasty.
That was.
Although when he was in his prime and he
didn't see those kicks,
you couldn't see his kicks coming.
He was just like,
he doesn't even load up it just there.
That's probably right afterwards.
It must've felt broken.
It feels fucking horrible just to get
hit once,
man.
I mean,
you're right.
It's so tough to just take that over and
over and over again.
Like he did.
Was He.
Can you check those and what it can you
turn it into?
Um,
the problem is when you get hit what
just getting hit once by a guy who's
really good,
like a peter or,
or someone who's like a really good leg
kicker,
they hit you once and you're,
you're not even going to lift your leg
upright.
Well,
think of a Charlie horse,
that guy gives you in school when you're
a kid and how bad that,
that's probably 10 times out of 10 times
whatever it is.
There's a Nesto who's probably one of
the greatest lessons,
not probably,
definitely one of the greatest lake
carriers of all time.
And there's a video called the perfect
leg kick by Ernesto,
who's then it just shows you like a
compilation of him landing leg kicks in
people and you just see like you see
their,
their legs buckle.
And,
and he would walk with him.
He would whip it down like he had this
angle.
They said,
yeah,
he's a long,
tall guy.
And his technique was just perfect.
Oh no video of him.
He was so good.
Watch his left,
left kick or left kick and then left
hooked rather than the right leg kick.
The way he goes,
you're covering up top and you don't
mind maybe even see it.
Hook.
Look at this though.
Being the,
just the,
the whip into it.
He was so good,
man.
He was so fucking good and he would
always do it.
Left,
left hook to the body.
And then right leg kick afterwards.
Uh,
Ricardo Arona a buddy of mine.
You Know Ricardo?
No Ricardo pretty well.
Yeah.
CSR for.
Yeah,
he surfs a lot of Brazilian guys surfing
now.
But who did he kick rampage or somebody
in the lower leg?
Like I think Vendrell a,
I don't know,
back in the pride days and uh,
I think he killed,
broke someone's lower leg or something.
Sure.
He was the victim of the worst slam I've
ever seen in my life.
Well,
he told me,
he's like,
I don't know why I didn't grab the leg.
Yeah.
And the thing I didn't realize because I
had watched the fight before and I
didn't pick this up.
I wasn't very well versed at that time
in watching fights,
but he goes,
he goes,
Kelly,
you know,
the thing was I put him to sleep in the
fight before that and I let him go and
then told the rep,
you sleeping,
he's sleeping.
And he goes,
and then he woke back up and the rough
kind of you can watch it and it touched
them.
Goes okay.
Keep fighting.
Yeah.
What?
Did he catch them with?
A triangle or something?
I'm kind of trying.
Yeah.
Uh,
no it wasn't a triangle was a teen or
something.
Might have been a good team.
They were on the ground.
So yeah.
You like or maybe knocked him out,
know I thought he put him to sleep or
something.
I don't know if it was.
Anyways.
Yeah.
But then rampage woke up.
And then kept finding rough like,
oh yeah,
we'll pride was crazy.
Yeah.
They would have let you fight to the
death.
If I went to a.
was it a k?
One?
I watched Kitty Yamamoto and an inhaler
fight.
Oh Wow.
And uh,
you know,
I had run into hoist the night before.
Just saw him at a bar and he's like,
what's up?
And I'm like,
I'm leaving.
I'm going to fly out tomorrow.
He goes,
no,
you've got to come to my brother's
flight.
So I went to the fight and then got
knocked out.
Man.
It was.
It was hard to walk.
What did he fight?
Hitler fought.
Could Yamamoto.
Yeah,
that's right.
That's when it was five.
Yeah.
He was getting involved in mma and he
really didn't have any striking.
Yeah,
he was out cold for a couple of minutes.
I was like,
did they just offer him a shit load of
money?
Like why did he decide to take?
I don't know.
I,
I had never met earlier at that time he
fought.
He fought a bunch of people.
Sakharova,
which is really crazy.
And Sakharova had him in a Kamora with
his arm way behind his back and they
stopped the fight rather than let him
get his arm broken because he wasn't
tapping.
Yeah.
But he was like,
mom,
really flexible.
Like I wasn't gonna tap.
I can,
I can do that.
Yeah.
I see some of these yogis.
I follow this guy,
this Yogi guy,
and I think this guy named,
uh,
go Kula chondral or something and he,
he,
um,
he puts these poses up and I think if
this guy did Jujitsu,
there's no way somebody could tap him
out because he,
he's doing,
he's the craziest.
I don't know how you put your.
I've never seen somebody put their body
in these contortionists positions and
you just wonder if somebody who's a real
true contortionists if they knew Jujitsu
and how to escape things.
If they could ever really get tagged
with like arms,
I'm sure next or gay teens or whatever.
But what do you got here,
Jamie?
Oh,
there was a guy thought we were showing
us some.
There's a guy named Ray who was,
oh,
look at this guy did follow this guy.
Yeah,
he's,
my God.
It's insane.
He does these poses where he's,
he's balancing on his elbow and he said,
and then the rest of his bodies in these
poses.
It's insane poses and stuff.
One go above that,
right there on the far right.
Jamie.
That one when he's on one hand,
it's amazing.
That's fucking nuts,
man.
Yeah.
This kind of stuff and the strengths and
the amount of time you had to take to
learn these things.
It's like,
it's.
I mean,
that's sort of a martial art in itself.
Oh yeah.
Well,
um,
there's a guy who's a famous Jujitsu guy
who once said that yoga is a martial art
that you do against yourself.
Yeah.
There's,
my friend Ray is a,
he was a lead singer of a band re Capo.
He was a lead singer of some punk band
and then became a Yogi.
Hm.
Yeah.
And we called Yoga Ray and uh,
he would uh,
come to 10th planet and he would just,
he could move in ways he likes without
fuck.
Are you doing man?
Like his body was.
So he had so much dexterity and
flexibility.
It was impossible to like hold them in
positions.
Like he just could move.
Segue your two belts below me,
but I can't pin you.
Well,
he was actually a very high ranking guy.
He was really good at Jujitsu.
He had this crazy yo and he also had
amazing breath work.
Like he,
he,
he never got tired,
like his cardio is incredible,
but it was all because of his,
his breathing techniques.
Hixson hixson would work on a lot of
breathing stuff.
Yeah.
He was like,
I've,
uh,
I've known Hickson quite a long time and
he always talks about that when you
breathe through your nose and how you
calm your heart and you have to panic
breathing through your mouth is what
they would call know when you panic.
Breathe.
Yeah.
Most people in their title.
But he was always about control,
controlling your breath,
go.
And he was like,
you know,
prior to him doing his thing and
becoming sort of,
well known,
he hixon would go sit and cold ice cold
streams and just real calm through the
nose and control,
you know?
Yeah.
That's in that movie choke.
He's in a glacial river and he's just
sitting,
we're neck deep in and everybody else
just dipped their foot.
And I'm like,
fuck this.
Yeah,
he's in,
in the freezing cold water.
Just loving it.
Yeah.
He's a fascinating guy and he was really
the first guy that sort of introduced
martial artists to the power of yoga
because he was the best that stomach
work he could do,
you know?
Yeah.
It's like freaky freaky.
We've played that.
It's from the movie choke.
Yeah,
that's what it's called.
A fire breathing or some blank breath of
fire.
There's like a word for that kind of
breathing.
It's probably more just if you'll go to
a class and they'll go,
okay,
breath of fire is right.
That's just like that.
But he had his.
He could pull his stomach in and move it
side to side in some weird way.
He said like he could use every muscle
in his body individually,
like move it independent of other
muscles.
That's a weird one.
He also loves surfing.
I Love Surfing.
Given boards to for a long time.
Really?
Yeah.
That's so cool.
Yeah,
it's amazing.
How many Jujitsu Guys Love Surfing.
Yeah,
there's an endless.
Is it just because of Rio and Rio is
like just a place.
It's they all sorta and and sort of
played soccer and serve there on the
beach.
So they're kind of doing these things
and some volleyball with their feet,
whatever you call that thing.
Right,
right,
right.
What is that?
Slams are sick.
It's crazy.
But I posted a video of these guys in
Thailand that we're doing that.
They were playing volleyball,
a version of volleyball with their feet
and it's fucking wild man.
It's like the ultimate hacky sack.
It's the craziest shit.
Like the dexterity they have with their
feet where they're whacking the ball
over and then the other guy on the other
side is whacking it back and it's like
they're catching it with their foot.
Oh look at this angle is they get.
Yeah.
I mean the flexibility to.
And these guys are really close to each
other too.
Yeah.
That's must be some good fails that
kicks into face.
Sure.
I'm sure there's a lot of that.
What's it called?
Well this is Koreans are.
Boom,
look at that kid.
Oh my God.
That's insane.
And then you have to fall in your hands
and hope you don't break your wrists
falling.
I wonder if they got added a floor like
a,
you know,
like a mat on Dojo.
This is pretty impressive stuff.
But Jamie,
see if you find that video that I posted
on my instagram page,
I reposted somebody else posting it.
It's fucking bananas because these guys
are using this little shitty ball in the
jungle and just the ability that they
have with their feet is just out of this
world.
You ever hear of a guy named Sir Donald
Brat?
Uh,
Gosh,
I forget his name.
Bradman.
I believe it was.
He used the best crooked player of all
time.
No,
that's cricketer of all time.
So he grew up in Australia.
Outback and he,
he,
I guess from what I heard,
there wasn't many people around and he
used to play,
uh,
he would take a stick,
just a random stick and he would hit a
ball against a corrugated,
curved a wall,
corrugated aluminum,
you know,
one of those kind of bended walls and
they use for roofing and uh,
so the ball would just bounce off at all
these different angles and uh,
hit his hand.
Eye Coordination became like,
you know,
as good as you could possibly ever have
because it was like his fun thing to do.
Check these guys out,
look at this crazy shit and I saw you
look at this and off the head and it
looks like these perfect shots,
but they keep firing it back at each
other.
Look at that off the head and it sounds
hard.
It sounds like a coconut or something,
you know?
Right.
It sounds like they made it at a like,
like a rock and some fucking.
Oh,
how was that?
How was that kicks?
That was just straight up martial arts.
It was like a push,
kick,
push kick,
but a roundhouse kick at the same time.
Like a push crescent kick.
This guy.
I mean.
Oh,
and the block if you can get good at
doing that.
I guess it is tie because those are tie
writing,
but if you could get good at that man.
I mean there's certain guys that just
when you see them in Moitai they have.
Oh,
that's what it's called me.
Seapak top gras.
It's Burmese.
Oh,
okay.
Soccer and volleyball put together.
Yeah.
Those guys would be awesome fighters.
There's certain guys that have just
insane leg dexterity that you see in
martial arts.
Like do you know sunshine is ever see
Sanchez Sanchez leg kicks would be
insane.
Yeah.
Well he's everything.
He's,
he's.
There's a famous highlight reel of him
where he throws this like fake knee off
the right and then jumping roundhouse
kicks this guy in the face and chaos and
with his left and it's just the,
the,
the ability that he has to place his
foot like anywhere he wants.
His dexterity just out the world is a
range.
Would just be other worldly.
Right?
Yeah.
Well that's.
I mean,
Tisha slept there.
He is.
Oh yeah.
No,
definitely younger guy.
And he was essentially.
I was talking about.
They're asking about connor fighting.
Conor.
He ever see that thing?
He's like,
no,
I'd kill this guy.
Fuck him up so bad.
Like he probably let it go.
Okay,
kick me a few times on this trade.
Let's try it.
A couple.
He's so hard to hit to Sanchez.
Just so elusive.
Why wouldn't someone like him in,
in a UFC fight?
He doesn't know how to fight on the
ground.
I mean,
that's all it is.
It's just they just pin him with another
standup guy.
If they were smart,
yeah,
that would be the smart thing to do,
but I'm not going to put Sam punk and
gets another ground guy,
are Ya?
Well,
that's.
That would be a disaster.
Cm punk.
That whole thing was everybody's like,
I could do it.
You know,
you watch cm punk.
You're like,
fuck,
I'll fucking fight.
Like I guarantee you,
Sam,
Sam punks probably a lot tougher than
the average guy anyway.
I mean,
I don't know.
I don't know fighting,
but you know,
even in the average fighter,
no nothing.
Average fighter,
but maybe the average guy in a bar,
right?
Cm punk is a real nice guy and I don't
want to say anything bad about them
because I mean the guy gave it his all.
He really did.
Totally,
totally dedicated.
I don't have some humble pie and he was
totally cool about it.
He was in these cool about it the first
time and he was cool about the second
time.
He's a real good guy,
but he doesn't have what I would call
talent.
The skill just moves wrong.
He doesn't see them against.
When Mickey Golar came in and just went
over the top and he was probably so
nervous to never being in that situation
of a real flight.
I mean,
he's been in front of the crowds,
but that was a nightmare that micky gall
fight was so ridiculous.
Micky gall is fucking good.
He's really good.
He's fucking.
And to have a guy like cm punk that
doesn't have a back.
It's not like brock Lesnar Brock Lesnar
came to the UFC.
He was a wrestler.
He's a fucking gorilla.
As a human being,
just a freak athlete.
Cm punk is a regular guy like he's not.
There's nothing freaky about it.
He doesn't have crazy power or weird
speed.
You don't see them and go,
that guy looks super scary for a guy his
size.
I mean there's guys that don't look like
sand.
Chai himself does not look like a freak
freaky so frequently,
but when you see him,
he looks,
he looks like an athlete,
but he doesn't look like you know.
It's not like Roy Jones Jr and his prime
or something.
When you see them,
you just go,
Jesus,
so you're this fucking guy.
He was just,
I mean he's just so good.
But a guy like cm punk,
he didn't have a background and he tried
martial arts when he was like 30.
So he had no background.
Not Real in the even wrestling
background.
No,
he didn't even wrestle.
It was all theatrical.
Wrestling was all entertainment,
you know,
you would think though that those guys
would even,
even the theatrical reffing,
they would go and work on the skill like
day in,
day out mean that's all you have to be
as a wrestler.
Right.
This is such a difference,
but you can work on the scale day in,
day out and then work on skill and
someone doesn't want you to do it to
them.
Yeah.
That's the thing.
And then when they're trying to do
things to you,
like,
just fucking you up.
Yeah.
And just nothing you can do about it.
Like in your mouth breathing.
Everything's wrong.
But I mean,
I'm sure he made a ton of money and he,
oh,
he tested himself,
the guy,
I mean give the guy credit.
He really did test himself.
I think it was a good thing for,
for Dan and everyone to see,
to like,
oh okay,
we're not going to do that.
Let's not,
let's not put someone in that position
that's not put ourselves in that
position.
But they were talking about like Logan,
Paul Logan,
Paul fighting in the UFC,
and he was like,
Logan Paul and get killed.
Logan.
Paul is fucking way better,
way better than cm punk.
Logan Paul like actually knows how to
fight.
He had a boxing match with another
youtube guy.
But I was watching him throw punches in
that fight.
I'm like,
this is a guy who actually knows how to
punch like kids punches looked good.
He gassed out.
He got a little tired first real fight
like that.
But he has a background in wrestling and
he,
he actually can punch.
Like I was watching him punch this guy.
I was like,
that's a guy who actually knows how to
throw punches.
He now he knows how to,
he knows distance and timing,
he knows how to connect and he doesn't
look like Canelo Alvarez or anything
crazy,
but he looks like a guy who can actually
punch more.
You can give him a break on that.
But Dana is like,
you know,
have him fight in the UFC would be,
he would get killed.
Like I'd fucking cm punk fight.
This guy is way better than him.
He really has a background in fighting.
How,
how does that dynamic work for you and
Dana were,
you know,
with something like that that,
that can be seen if somebody is a little
triggered,
are a little sensitive,
they might get a little bit like angry
at you saying something like that.
Dana is the easiest going guy ever with
that kind of shit.
He doesn't give a fuck.
He looked.
Me and him have been friends for like
almost 20 years.
We've been friends for a long time and
I've been working for the UFC.
I mean I started working for the old
company in [inaudible] 97.
I started working for that long ago.
Yeah.
And then the new company,
I started working for them in 2002 and I
was friends with Dana before that.
It's just he,
he knows my heart's in the right place,
but he also knows that if I wasn't
honest nobody would listen to me.
Yeah.
That's the thing.
I enjoy watching the fights and
listening to your,
your critical in a fairway with people I
think,
you know.
Yeah.
When you,
when you critique what somebody is
doing,
it's like if they listened the right way
it's probably going to help them.
Well I definitely don't say things that
if I don't know what I'm talking about
and I don't say things that I don't
mean,
you know,
but if I see something and I've watched,
I mean I've called at least a thousand
fights.
I don't know how many times or probably
more.
Yeah.
And I've seen some of the greatest
fights of all time up live in close.
Right?
Right next to the cage.
You know,
I seen a lot of shit.
So if I'm saying something it's probably
because it's right.
I mean it.
But if I don't know what I'm talking
about,
like it's one of the good things about
having Daniel cormier there or dominick
Cruz,
if there's some aspect of fighting that
maybe I'm not exactly sure about,
I can defer to them and I could say
like,
wow,
what's so important about getting the
under hook here?
You know?
And then cormier could go off about
like,
why this?
And then you go,
oh,
okay,
I get that.
Okay,
I see.
I like that was a big thing in the fight
with Steve and Daniel Cormier.
Dominick Cruz was explaining how
important it was that caught me a kept
pummeling.
He kept shifting positions and pummeling
for under hooks and that was one of the
reasons why I was able to land that big
right hand because he was never static.
He also had to wear something to get in
there too.
Then yeah.
I mean he was writing Steve based face
and she pays like,
I mean that was such a great match.
Even though obviously it didn't last
very long,
but I mean he,
he took a few on the chin real hard to
get in there.
And uh,
for Steve Bay has got to drive him
fucking crazy.
Like she's been tweeting a lot.
Why wouldn't he get a straight rematch
straight away?
I mean there's even supposedly talk at
mcgregor getting rematch when he got
pretty much handled everywhere.
I don't think there's real talk of
mcgregor getting a rematch.
I think the real smart money is on Tony
Ferguson fighting Khabib next that Dane
has been saying that I,
I 100 percent believe that Tony
Ferguson.
I don't think Tony Ferguson should have
ever been stripped.
I think he should still be the interim
champion.
I mean,
the guy fell while he was doing press
and tore his knee apart.
Six months later it comes back and
destroys Anthony Pettis and spectacular
performance.
Fight.
Pettis was great too.
Fuck you.
It was Tony's.
Tony's just a warrior.
I mean he's,
he's cardio,
never runs out.
He throws weird stuff with everything
you can throw currently got upset that
we call them a Weirdo.
Like he's,
I guess he's sensitive.
He apparently got upset.
I said it was a brilliant Weirdo like
when he was on his way to the cage,
but I meant that 100 percent
complimentary ankle weights at the weigh
ins,
like I don't even know what I mean.
He uses a wing Chung dummy.
He sets up his,
all of his camp,
his training,
and he sets it up himself.
He puts the mats down.
He builds his own like heavy bag
hangers.
He puts,
he puts up Chin up bars,
all that shit does it himself.
He's like,
he does construction like it's
unfamiliar to the average training
regimen.
Yes.
That's what I'm.
I'm in a complimentary way.
I'm a huge fan of that guy.
I am too.
I thought.
I think he's awesome.
I also think that he is the toughest
test for Khabib because of his cardio
and because of its versatility,
because he could fight really well off
his back when he submitted Kevin Lee off
his back to win the title.
He's got a fantastic darce choke and his
ability to hold guys in his guard and
recover if he gets clipped.
I mean he's.
He's the most dangerous guy.
Lightweight.
For Khabib.
I think,
in my opinion,
yeah,
he just never gets fucking tired.
It doesn't even make sense.
And Eddie,
Eddie trains them.
He's one of Eddie's students.
Eddie says he's never seen anything like
it.
He said,
this guy work out six hours a day,
full clip,
everybody else's exhausted.
He keeps going there doing sprints up
the hill,
20 laps.
Everybody keeps going.
He's just.
Cardio is off the charts.
I wonder if that's a Mexican thing too.
I think there's a lot of Mexicans that
have amazing cardio,
right?
I don't know what it is,
man.
I mean if it's a running thing for sure,
but I mean if you go back to Julio,
Cesar Chavez,
Aka baby,
I think,
I mean Gilbert Belinda said that wants
to that.
It's a Mexican thing.
It's cardio because Gilbert's always
been known for his crazy cardio.
I really wonder if there's like certain
ethnicities that have an advantage or at
least a better starting point and then
it's all hard work from there.
Yeah.
That must.
Maybe there's some genetic thing you can
prove and the way that blood holds on to
Diego Sanchez.
He's another one.
You go insane cardio.
Yeah,
I mean,
I don't know.
I mean it's a,
it's a,
it's a fun thing to think about.
I mean,
you,
you go,
like,
you go to back to boxing in particular.
I mean,
how many great boxers had fantastic
cardio from Mexico,
you know,
Chavez in particular,
Julio,
Cesar Chavez,
which is where guys down the volume of
his punching.
It was just never stopped.
Just constantly on.
You constantly moving forward,
bobbing and weaving and throwing shots.
And sometimes as an athlete,
like if you're a boxer,
you'd have to,
even if you didn't have that,
you'd have to dig deep and pretend you
had that,
you know what I mean?
Because then it starts wearing another
guy.
Like,
this guy's never stop.
You know,
like I had a,
uh,
I had a situation once I was super
winded,
I was really tired in a,
in a heat surfing in Tahiti and uh,
this,
this heat ended up sort of being like a
world title heat for me.
And um,
I was losing with like two minutes ago
and I ended up in this paddle battle
against a guy and he's a good paddler
and pretty fit guy and we're like head
to head.
And what happens,
we,
whoever gets back out first deemed by
the judges gets priority over the next
wave.
They can have whatever the way they
want.
And with two minutes,
three minutes left and a heat surfing,
there's,
that's not a lot of time to get a wave
if uh,
if the wave comes,
you got to be the guy that has priority
for it and we're.
And
I could feel him just for half a second
kind of lit up when his paddle like,
okay,
I'm getting ahead on this guy.
And as soon as he did I paddle harder.
And I was like,
I,
you know,
to show him.
Like I got more and he gave up and I got
it.
And then I got,
then I needed like a score out of 10
points and I needed like a nine.
I got like a nine point four with 30
seconds ago or something.
It was just.
But it was,
I didn't have that in me,
like physically I was like,
I don't want to quit too,
you know,
but I was like,
I got a poker face,
this guy,
I think I got more,
you know,
and I,
I really didn't.
It was just that choice.
Like I don't care.
I'm going to get out there with the
lungs burning and I'll feel bad for 30
seconds,
whatever,
you know.
But sometimes I would imagine boxers,
pro tribe or may guys for sure.
Sometimes you can't bluff that,
but sometimes you can't bluff it.
But yeah,
for sure it does come up where there's
an edge one way or the other.
That's a big thing with Ferguson,
that pressure that he puts on guys.
Yeah.
He just never gets slow.
You know,
if you watched the Gustafson,
a Jon Jones fight to John late,
that fight,
did you know?
There could've been some doubt.
And so people who winning that fight or
it close fight,
but look like John just started pouring
it.
He was three.
Yup.
Strikes in the last couple rounds.
Yeah.
The last rounds one him that fight.
And by all accounts,
John Wasn't in shape by all accounts.
John Really didn't train for that fight
and didn't take Gustafson seriously and
kind of half assed his training camp and
still pulled it off in the championship
rounds.
That guy's livable and they're going to
rematch.
That's right.
Yeah.
That's anyway.
Yup.
The December card,
it's January,
New Year's Eve,
you know,
basically I think it's the December 29,
29 things.
Fantastic fight.
And because I think Gustafson's way
better now.
You see when Gustafson knocked out
globally to share.
I mean he just looked like there was
like a video game.
Combinational.
Yeah.
So I think that fight is a,
that's going to be one for the ages.
And then for John,
his comeback fight for Gustafson to be
the rematch he's asking for forever.
And it will be for the light heavyweight
title.
They're going to strip cormier.
Are they going to fight heavyweight in?
Yeah,
I mean he's gonna.
He's fighting Derrick Lewis in December
and weird flight.
Well he's number two.
I mean if you look at the rankings,
it's not.
If you look at Derrick Lewis is
obviously unorthodox,
but he was,
he was just getting mauled in that last
flight.
He doesn't matter when you go in,
I guess in Madden when you get that last
punch and the power that he has with his
finger,
you know,
why am I,
why am I even talking about this?
But I'm just a fan.
He really was the number two contender
headed into that fight and then wins.
I think that guy was the dark horse,
that division.
So for him to knock off Alexander like
that,
that's a jet was a giant knockout and to
get his ass kicked for three rounds.
Respect to to Alexander though.
Yeah,
for,
for staying in the pocket.
Fighting out with 30 seconds to go when
he clearly winning Netflix.
Well,
he got hurt.
He got hurt a couple of times in that
fight.
Did he just.
Yeah.
There was one time where he lost his
mouth piece and he tried to give it to
Derek.
Yeah,
that's right.
I think he was on Queer Street.
I didn't.
I don't think he knew what the fuck was
going on because Derek hits so hard.
He,
if you don't get knocked out,
you're probably like,
oh,
even a glancing blow.
Right.
Hey,
you probably like,
what in the fuck me thinking about the
way he knocked out Travis Brown when he
knocked out Gonzaga and Derek would be
even better if he didn't have a bad
back.
Derek's got a fucked up back.
So why does he want it?
That's three fights in six months.
Or what was the last flight within
Ghana?
Um,
well he fought in Ghana and that was the
fight where it was just like,
what the fuck?
That was barely a fight.
It was like five punches thrown the
entire as a fan watching it.
I felt like c one against in Ghana.
Um,
yeah.
Yeah.
But as a fan,
I.
Did you feel like that was more on in
Ghana than it was on Derek?
Yeah,
I don't know.
I always felt that way.
Well,
in Ghana who didn't do anything and
Derek one,
you know,
he didn't win by much,
but I mean he was basically waiting for
in Ghana,
you know,
you gotta be careful with in Ghana
because in Ghana punches so fucking hard
but steep a fuck.
That dude's head up.
He really did steep ages.
Fucked his head up.
He,
he.
Yeah.
That was even talking about in Ghana
anymore.
That's what's weird in Ghana.
Before the steep a fight,
everybody's like,
this is the second common cited for that
thing.
Oh my God.
When he knocked Alistair overeem into
another dimension,
everybody was like,
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
That was,
that was like,
that looked like a career ending.
Punch.
Her Dad was like a break your neck with
this.
Meanwhile overeem ready to fight again.
Didn't he fight again after that?
Against Curtis Blades.
I feel like you did.
I feel like he fought curtis please
after that and lost and got stopped in
that fight too.
Yeah,
I mean,
look in Ghana hits Falk in hard,
harder than anybody has ever fought.
I mean,
he's not.
When he's mouth breathing in the fifth
round,
it didn't matter because he gassed
himself out in the first and he really
wasn't prepared for a full game.
You really didn't think was going gonna
go to the ground.
From what I heard.
Yeah.
I thought I'd catch this guy.
That's what I thought.
He.
He thought he hit so hard that steep.
It was going to be in front of him.
He's going to hit Steve Bay's going to
be the heavyweight champ I was going to
ask you.
Do you,
do you have your absolute dream job?
But I mean you do a few things,
but like you,
you get to talk UFC.
You're a black belt under Eddie,
right?
Yeah.
And so like you've kind of found the
perfect job for yourself because you
just can't tell when you're talking
about.
You just love it so much.
Like I love surfing.
I just,
I live,
eat and breathe surf everyday I wake up
and the first thing I do is look at
where's the waves in the world.
Whereas when you retire,
you'll do commentary.
Uh,
maybe a little bit.
Yeah,
But I don't want to,
I don't really want a job whenever you
die.
You know,
I've been,
I've been on a pro tour pretty much
since I was 19 and 46.
I took about three years off,
but I would still compete a little bit
those years.
What are the,
what?
It's the high end of the age limit in
terms of like where does that can really
compete?
Like right now,
no one's ever been my age on tour.
Yeah,
no,
I think the
next oldest grand towards 38 and he's
retiring this year.
Wow.
When I've gone on tour,
the oldest guy was 28 years old.
Holy Shit.
It was like there was a real,
you know,
that I would say in the eighties there
wasn't like,
it didn't look like you could make some
money and if you were a top five guy but
it didn't look like you could have like
this crazy career.
So guys weren't thinking longevity.
They're like let's go have a freaking
good time.
Travel around the world and get paid for
it for a few years and then we'll figure
out a job after or maybe we'll have
enough money to kind of live real
humbly.
What is the difference between how you
prepare and other guys?
Is that your diet strength and
conditioning?
Like what is it?
I don't overexert myself very much so
my,
my training aside from surfing isn't a
lot.
I retain.
I feel like I retain enough strength to
be good at what I need to.
So to find.
Burn yourself out.
I don't burn myself out,
you know,
cause like the oldest people in the
world weren't athletes and they're kind
of people who didn't burn themselves out
too much.
So I,
my theory on longevity is like don't
overdo it.
I don't need to necessarily be
overtrained for what I do.
A lot of the skill.
A lot of the,
the winning that I do competitively is
from a skill.
It's not so much from being super strong
having crazy cardio.
It's making a choice about which wave,
how I'm gonna approach and ride that
wave.
And I have to get two scores every 30
minutes when they compete.
So it's like I got this 30 minute window
I need to be ready for.
I don't need to be like in crazy,
crazy shape [inaudible].
So what is it that held other guys back
in the past?
I think there's a number of factors.
I think you have to naturally be really
competitive.
Like in your,
when you were born in your home,
somehow you had to,
maybe you needed something to prove.
You know,
I,
I was Kinda like,
you know,
growing up I started of back at it and
kind of laugh.
Like I maybe I couldn't get the girl I
liked because she liked an older guy or
you know,
I didn't have,
we didn't really have any money in my
family so I wanted to make some money.
I had an older brother who kind of
picked on me,
but I hung out with him and played
football with his friends that were all
three years older than me.
So I had to be strong,
you know,
I had to be tough and fast.
I had to be smart.
That's the case with a lot of guys,
older brothers,
you know,
brothers that they couldn't really
compete with them like this
motherfucker.
And so every night we would just eat
away at the end.
I think it,
I think it did and there was always
that,
you know,
my brother and I have,
I think we have a pretty good
relationship now and I don't think he
would disagree with me that we kind of
didn't get along for 20 years or more
resort hate each other a long time.
But you know,
from the time we were teenagers we kind
of grew apart,
you know,
I,
I sorta started doing real well
competing on the world stage and he sort
of stagnated and we just,
you know,
people and families have different
dynamics,
you know,
each child has a different dynamic,
whether the first,
I'm in the middle of three,
all boys are younger.
Brother was three or six years younger
than me,
so he was kind of out of the loop when
we were teenagers.
He still a little kid so we,
we're really competing with him.
But he saw us competing against each
other.
And maybe a few ways and it kind of
turned him off to surfing so he didn't
start surfing until he was a teenager
and when he did he wrote long boards and
we're all,
we're both short boarders like you know,
more competition kind of guys.
And He loved kind of the old throwback,
the sixties and seventies surfers on
long boards or on single fins,
which is not a modern board at all.
And why would someone choose one or the
other?
Longboards are short word.
Yeah,
it's a,
it's a real different skill.
Longboards are kind of easier to just
get up and ride a wave.
But the skill you have on a long board
is more.
It's more ballet than it is a gym or
something,
you know,
it's not like big maneuvers.
It's more like gliding on the wave,
looking like you're not trying hard.
It's,
it's more of a,
a dance if you will.
Then it is like a,
some kind of an athletic skill and short
boarding is just,
you know,
you're going for aerials and lots of
different sort of fast maneuvers.
Really riding in the pocket of the wave
as long boarding,
you're looking for a different kind of
you.
You write a different kind of way of
altogether.
You really don't.
Most of the waves we ride for modern
shortboarding and competition aren't
waves.
You would ride along board because
they're too hollowed there too quick and
fast and you can't fit a board in the
same way.
So your brother just kinda took it up
more for the fun of it and the aesthetic
of it.
He literally was at the beach one day,
his story and he was about 14 or 15 and
we always try to get them to surf and
when he was about eight or 10,
I took him surfing one day at our local,
a break at Sebastian in Florida and I
pushed him on this wave and he.
He ate.
It was underwater.
Long time.
It kind of freaked them out.
Not a long time,
a long time for an eight year old,
like maybe 10 seconds or eight seconds.
You know when you're out of breath,
a little freaky like you don't know
which way's up.
And he kind of quit surfing and then
when he was like 14 or 15 years at the
beach and this guy,
he,
he really respected this kind of older
guys.
Like,
Hey,
I'm going to run somewhere.
We watched my board,
he had a longboard and he said,
we watched my board.
And Steven said,
oh yeah,
watch it.
And the guy said,
or you can go use it if you want.
And you paddle out and caught a few
waves.
And he just sort of fell in love with at
minute with surfing.
And it was something unique for him
because we didn't long board.
So it was like,
it was that beach life and thing we
love,
but it was different,
you know?
Right.
He got his own thing.
Yeah.
And then me and my brother,
we,
you know,
I got more and more into competition and
getting sponsored and stuff and he sort
of,
he,
he just kinda started fading out of
doing competition fulltime and stuff.
And,
and,
uh,
and uh,
then when I was a teenager,
when I was in of a freshman in high
school,
this guy moved into town,
a kid named drew and he had sort of got
kicked out of a couple of schools
elsewhere and I got himself into some
trouble and when he came he came over to
the beach.
He was kind of in these inland schools,
but he was good at football and go to
baseball.
He was kind of a really good athlete.
Uh,
he became the quarterback on a football
team.
He was a baseball player,
all this kind of stuff.
So he was,
he was a total jock,
not a surfer at all.
And somehow he and I became best buddies
and you know,
I liked,
I liked all the sports.
I grew up playing football,
basketball,
baseball,
a little bit tennis.
Um,
and,
and he and I ultimately where we got to
is he sort of became my big brother
competitively and we used to battle and
it didn't matter whose feelings got
hurt,
you know,
like we competed at absolutely
everything from horseshoes to bowling to
pull on my birthday.
Every year on my birthday we made it a
pack to where we'd go play every kind of
game we could possibly.
And we keep a tally of who won wide.
It was many,
it was Putt,
Putt,
golf,
it was go carts,
it was basketball,
it was shuffleboard,
it was like literally everything air,
you know,
everything we could think of.
And uh,
we just keep a tally and we,
we used to be in the millions of dollars
real well.
Yeah,
of course.
So,
you know,
at some point somebody owed somebody a
hundreds of millions of dollars,
but you never paid no.
Of course when it came down to like
actual money,
then it was like five bucks.
And at one point he,
he was uh,
he got really into horse shoes and he
called me out one day and he's like,
meet me at the beach.
We're gonna play some horseshoes.
I'm like,
all right,
bye bye.
I'm like,
but I'm not playing you unless we're
getting some money,
some real money.
And he's like,
all right,
bring some money.
And at the end of the day,
he ended up owing me about 160 bucks.
He's like,
you fucking tell my wife I owe you,
I'll fucking kill you now.
Never pay you because I don't have the
money.
I can't pay you that.
And he was like,
so I'll pay you like 20 bucks here and
there as we go.
But drew used to,
he beat me at everything.
He was better than me.
Uh,
basically everything.
And so it was like that.
A pingpong too on my 18th birthday that
I like to call it the night upsets
because it was a night that Mike Tyson
last the buster douglas and it was,
it was,
uh,
the night of February 10th.
My birthday's in the limit on the 11th,
but they were in Tokyo.
So they were on the 11th fighting.
Tyson last drew shows up in my house
with the ping pong table and he says
that it was like my birthday gifts.
All my friends want me to ping pong
table.
My mom,
my three buddies and drew beat me 17
straight games in a row.
And I started crying.
I think he ended up letting me finally
win the last game so we could go to bed
at two in the morning and man,
I've never been.
I've really honestly never been so
frustrated and just outright beaten by
somebody at anything and he just owned.
I just knew he owned me and he would
just tell me where he's going to hit the
ball on the table and beat me.
Ping Pong is a serious skill.
It's a really good at it.
Oh,
follow.
You should go on Pol affinity on
instagram and watch these things.
These guys do.
It's out of hand.
I'm scared.
Yeah.
Ping Pong is one of those games where I
was like,
if I ever got into that,
I think it would eat your life.
It seems like we used to stay up the
night and you know,
we sucked and we thought we were pretty
good.
You know,
we'd,
uh,
use soap and
water to make our or paddles a little
stickier.
You know,
we thought we had all this pain and
stuff.
The guys are playing three way.
That is crazy.
I mean that's another kind of way you
like it's a street and they're just
smashing the ball and it,
this is crazy and low behind the back.
And is there money in Ping Pong?
I don't,
I,
I think there are,
you know,
in China or something.
Right?
I don't think in the states there really
is,
but that's the same thing with pool now,
but I don't know.
I don't see some white guy going to
China and beaten all those guys.
You see these guys are masters.
They don't move,
you know,
they just,
they're the risk moves it,
there's no dancing,
you know?
Yeah.
It seems like one of those sports where
there's just,
there's a whole,
there's a whole world out there that
you're not aware of of like elite killer
ping pong players.
Like most people aren't even thinking
about it.
Yeah,
it's funny.
We could talk about ping pong and it's
like everyone can kind of join in.
Like if I ever talk about fighting
people are shut your ass man.
You stay in your lane,
but you know,
it's just like,
I'm a fan of pink pong too.
I'll talk about ping pong.
That's a funny thing that stay in your
lane thing like,
you know,
have to have an opinion on things.
Yeah.
So then why can we vote?
You know,
about somebody who's going to handle
everything.
Why are we allowed to.
Can we only just vote be about something
that has to do with surfing or fighting
is a weird one.
Like people want you have for,
for some people,
like you have to know how to fight to be
able to talk about fighting.
Yeah,
they take it real serious about that.
Like you hear that about journalists,
like look at this fucking guy.
Probably never trained in Dana's life.
You know,
they look at a guy and he's fat or tiny
or whatever and they just don't want to
listen to anything that they say.
But meanwhile they could be an expert.
Yeah,
I mean fight Roy Nelson.
Yeah.
Okay.
Go,
have fun.
Have Fun with that one.
But it's a,
it's.
I was a kid I trained with Don the
Dragon Wilson.
Oh,
did you really?
I did for about a year.
I got a chance to spar him once.
Did you.
It was awesome.
Yeah,
it was.
So to me it was like,
I'm such a fan of that guy.
He was totally ambidextrous Whitney.
Oh yeah.
He could fight any style and he,
I mean he also had that weird,
a sideways stance where,
you know,
he had like kickboxing skills,
boxing skills,
more skills,
but he also had like a traditional
karate and Kung Fu background.
So we'd stand sideways on you and you
didn't know what was coming at you then,
right?
Yeah.
Now he was awesome.
And I remember when he fought Dennis
Alexio,
Dennis,
Alexia,
he moved to the west side of Oahu and
that was like all the news back and then
I,
and he fucked Alexio up with leg kicks.
He was like one of the first guys that
punished Alexia with leg kicks.
He did a thing on youtube about defense
defense for self defense for women.
And they were saying like,
you're,
it was part of this group.
And the,
they talked about like,
you know,
if you're gonna,
teach a woman something,
kick,
kick the leg because that's the biggest
target,
you know,
bad advice before Jujitsu.
People kick the balls,
but your legs carry you around.
I mean,
that's the thing about a woman.
If a woman weighs 135 pounds,
she's walking around with 135 pounds
carrying it.
It's like,
how,
uh,
how long could you walk on your hands?
Yeah,
I mean I heard that brock lesnar could
walk into his hands like a mile,
which is kind of crazy.
Yeah.
Really?
He's a freak,
like a legitimate free.
He walks in his hands all around the
gym.
Yeah.
He wanted to do a video,
like walking up the stairs.
I had a buddy,
a surf buddy from.
I'm from Santa Cruz.
He unfortunately passed away gun.
He and Barney a good friend of all of
ours and he used to do these surf video
clips and he would walk downstairs and
then walk upstairs and he did all.
He could literally just walk anywhere
and his hand.
It was so cool to see.
Well,
I mean,
I guess you would build it.
It's all about how often you use it,
right?
You use your legs constantly.
Don't use your arms constantly,
but if you did and you built up over
years of time,
I would imagine.
I mean there's obviously the shipping is
quick to,
you know,
I mean I started doing hand actually
right before I broke my foot.
I started when I was a kid.
I used to be able to pretty much walk in
and listen on my hands.
Like when you walk on your hands while
your foot was broken?
Uh,
no,
but that week I was like,
you know what?
When I was a kid I could walk for
minutes at a time.
My hands,
I'm going to get back into that.
So I started training that week.
Like I just started doing handstands
everyday with my friend's daughter.
You broke your foot right?
The week I broke my leg for the two
weeks before I broke my foot and I
started like quickly I could feel the
skill coming back,
you know,
I mean I probably should have kept with
it because then I could have walked
around for a while and kept my foot
high.
But uh,
no,
but I mean,
my point is that like pretty quickly
your body starts to attune to that
thing.
Like I used to do pushups on the back of
my wrist,
this buddy of mine who was into martial
arts,
he's like,
do risk pushups.
And what's the benefit of the.
He was just saying to strengthen your
risks.
I don't know.
He used to do it,
but the first time I did it it really
hurt my wrists.
And then after about a week of doing it
didn't hurt my wrists anymore.
Your body just kind of adjust?
Definitely.
Yeah.
But I dunno,
I think I'm going to start doing
handstands and doing that.
The Burmese a volleyball thing.
How long did it take?
I mean,
what were you on crutches or you want a
wheelchair?
Like how long did it take before you
could actually walk a broken foot?
While I was walking a little too soon.
Oh yeah.
How long I didn't.
I didn't break it,
but I didn't displace the bones any.
But I mean I actually wrote,
I wrote a couple of ways,
like six weeks later.
No.
Yeah,
I probably would you do that?
Well because we built this wave of like
a up in your fresno.
We built a manmade wave and um,
are those a good way to learn?
Yeah.
Well,
yeah,
they can be.
I mean it depends on how long the wave
lasts and what size wave and how fast
and all that kind of thing,
but our way,
it's pretty easy to learn on,
but our wave lasts on the low speed for
a beginner.
It lasts over a minute long.
That would seem to me that,
that would be a great way to like just
get your feet wet.
Yeah,
no,
you should come up.
Is that it right there?
Yeah,
but that's not the low side at least
what's like the,
uh,
as the high setting.
Yeah.
This was.
And this was actually.
Where is that like,
is that a like 40 minutes south of
Fresno area?
Yeah,
it's a big.
It used to be a ski like,
so it's long narrow lake.
Oh Wow.
That is crazy.
Yeah,
that's all manmade.
This is manmade.
That's so weird.
This isn't the newest version of it.
If you were to google,
if you were to search,
like,
um,
uh,
there was a contest called,
we had a couple of contests.
We had one called the surf ranch pro
about six weeks ago and that's,
we changed the waves since then and uh,
we remodeled that we had to rebuild it,
but,
um,
anyways,
the reason I surfed was because we were
having the first competition at this
wave and I wanted to ride the first way
like,
oh,
I didn't want get to compete.
I just like,
symbolically I wanted to ride the wave
at the thing.
So how does this work?
What's making that wave?
This is a coil,
a wave foil,
like a in the back it looks sometimes
you'll see in the back behind the wave,
not there,
but to the left side more you would see
this thing.
It's a,
it's basically a super inefficient boat
hole and it pushes through the water.
And so it's pushing water instead of
planning on the water.
Like you would want a boat too.
So it's pushing all the water sideways
and it's just this foil shape.
It's almost like the shape of a finn or
a wing straight up and down in the water
is that blue thing in the back and it
rides.
It's like a rollercoaster and uh,
it gets pulled on a pulley system with a
4,000
horsepower engine.
There's two of them actually wanted to
go either direction.
So you see it's now they've got their
back to the wave when they're riding,
but the first few ways they showed me
this is Stephanie Gilmore.
She's like six time world champ.
Um,
this is a,
that's me obviously.
And this was just about six weeks ago in
September.
And um,
so yeah,
I mean,
I,
I designed the technology with the
scientist and then design the actual
brief bottom or concrete bottom that,
that makes the wave break.
Yeah.
Because this seems way more advanced
than the ones that I've seen.
Yeah.
This is,
it's a really advanced way.
It's actually longer than it needs to
be.
Also [inaudible] at a fast speed.
The waste to like 45 seconds and your
legs are fried.
This is Philippe Toledo,
who's number two in the world right now.
He's unbelievable.
That's crazy fast.
Great Surfer.
Where's he from?
Brazil.
A lot of surfers come from Brazil.
All the new good guys are from Brazil.
It's like the flight or fight game,
you know,
this is a Gabriel Medina guy's
incredible.
He's a,
he's unbelievable.
Whoa.
And he's a fucking balanced.
That's,
that's probably shove it.
Yeah.
Um,
and I think that was a corrupt flip.
He did super high tech moves,
but he.
Gabriel Medina is one time world champ
from few years ago,
but I thought he was,
you know,
I thought he was just going to win year
after year after year after his first
title.
I don't know if it got complacent or
what happened and he and I aren't super
just like,
how do they judge like it's,
it's a subjective.
Yeah.
Um,
that's the probably the tough thing for
our sport,
but I mean gymnastics is subjective.
Um,
ice skating,
you know,
that kind of thing.
So it's not too different to me.
It's not too dissimilar to that.
So,
you know,
the judges are all good surfers,
relatively good surfers.
Maybe not exposed,
but you know,
guys who know what is possible.
On a wave and I'm there,
it's pretty easy for them to compare
apples to oranges,
a different person skills over the other
one.
Um,
but it would be interesting in UFC,
you know,
if,
if you had judges subjectively judging,
not,
not necessarily like who won the round
or looking at counts,
but like who styled it.
I like how fast and how much power did
he have,
how did he link is,
you know,
strikes together.
Just a subjective element to it.
But unfortunately,
unlike surfing the is not the judges,
they're not,
it's not comprised of former fighters
were people that really know a lot of,
which is wrong,
totally wrong.
It's awful.
I mean some,
some surfers really believed that the
judges should just be x pros that were
tour level guys that make those calls.
It seems like there's enough of those
guys out there.
There are,
there may be,
but you know,
getting back to why that kind of leads
me back to like you asked why guys
didn't have the longevity that people
get married,
have kids and have a life back home.
All of that kind of stuff.
So,
you know,
I was sort of not quite the traditional
route with all that stuff.
Um,
so I had a lot more time focused
dedication into what I was doing and I
wanted to do it for a long time because
I just love surfing and I mean it.
If I had my druthers every day I'm gonna
wake up and go ride waves.
Now is there a point system that this
Koran Yep.
Out of 10 out of 10 boxing,
not everybody gets a nine.
If they lose that battle,
you know,
it's um,
10 is the Max tens Max,
but I mean more average.
You're seeing threes and fours than you
are eights and nines because you know,
it's just a certain wave in a certain
skill set gets you up to that excellent
category.
So we consider eight and up.
Excellent.
And you know,
sort of six,
five to eight is like really good.
And is there a lot of debate about
whether or not I have a nine?
Is,
is,
is accurate for someone's Rod?
Yeah,
yeah,
there is.
Well,
if,
if it's early,
there's a lot to it,
you know,
like if it's early in a heat and a guy
gets a nine or a girl gets a nine and
then you think that there's a lot more
that could have been done either on that
day in those types of waves or on that
wave specifically.
Like some occasionally you see somebody
get 10 perfect.
Why as good as you can possibly do.
It's the ultimate,
you should remember that way forever
kind of thing.
You know,
it's like the perfect knockout but then
won't,
they'll kick off the wave when there's
more to ride or they'll fall and they
still get a 10.
So like sometimes you'll see somebody
get a really good score and you know,
a lot more could have been done.
They could've been deeper in that tube,
they could have been higher in that
area,
they could have rotated it kind of,
you know,
more they could in the air,
they could have written out like
smoother.
It could have linked a couple different,
more difficult turns together,
added more variety.
So you have to kind of like if anything
scaled down,
I think as a judge as opposed to scale
up because then you,
if,
if you're surfing in really great waves,
which makes it easier to get a good
score.
So like Tropo in Tahiti,
if you,
if you pull up Tahiti,
I'm show poor t a h u t o m contest
2014.
So we had really unbelievable waves in
this contest.
I'm almost every wave looked like it
could be a 10.
Then it comes down to like how late did
you drop in?
How critical was it?
How deep were you,
how did you maximize your time in there
by slowing your speed,
how much risk did you take?
So even though they've only lasted about
five seconds,
there was a whole lot that can be
condensed into that five seconds.
And did you wait for one of the biggest
waves or did you take a smaller wave and
take and go,
you know,
a little bit easier?
What is it like when one of those giant
tubes crashes down on top of you?
Um,
yeah.
So this game,
Medina,
he,
he ended up winning the contest.
Um,
it's not super fun when you eat.
It could imagine that you've probably
talked to Shane.
That's me actually.
Yeah,
I've talked to Shannon about it.
Yeah.
And I mean,
look,
Shane,
no one's more of an authority than Shane
is.
Maybe not in the super hollow,
crazy stuff.
Whatever.
Shane writes everything.
But the biggest waves in the world
changes the authority.
Like he's had wipe outs that he came
close to dying.
He probably talked to about their vest
he created because of that,
he almost drowned.
He created a vest that you pull the co
two cartridge and it bless,
you know,
this big bladder and lift you to the
surface.
Even if you get knocked out or taken
water,
someone's going to find you and probably
save you.
Um,
but yeah,
this is me there.
So I didn't make that,
but that wasn't even a big one.
You're not that for that day.
That was a small way of fucking huge.
The one that's coming down to see where
I'm at.
I'm kind of in blue water.
Right.
So I was able to dive and kind of get
under it and not get sucked back over.
So there's a little bit of a skill that
goes with wiping out.
So you understand that energy.
It's,
you know,
it's like a,
it's like a tornado or a hurricane.
Like the eye wall is the worst.
But your fear in the center,
you're fine.
You know,
I always,
I've always wondered like,
could you follow a hurricane inside the
center of the eye?
Like could you just stay with it and be
okay?
I bet you could.
If you moved to a really slow speed
right there,
don't move them.
They only move about 10 to 20 miles an
hour.
Sometimes less kind of playing go that
slow.
No,
but maybe you could stay in the car,
run,
kind of like know,
find a road.
If you had a really good gps system,
you've got to go,
no,
no.
Go northwest,
go northeast.
Yeah,
I'm okay.
You're going to have to go off road or
you'll die.
But.
So that energy,
all that energy is in where the lip,
where the,
you know,
if you're in the center that you're
pretty safe.
But as soon as you get sucked in right
into the wall,
that,
and you get pitched in the limb,
that's when the lips spreads the water
that it hits and it sends you right down
to the,
especially in a place like this where
it's,
when you see a way that's real hollow,
it's generally a lot shallower than it
is high.
So the wave will be 15 feet in the
water,
might only be five or six feet deep.
So think of all that energy it's going
to hit.
Most of it's going to hit the reef at
some point.
So that's a,
you want to,
you want to try to kind of fall like
where that lives landing and then escape
under it into blue water.
What do you do?
You know you're going to hit a reef,
you kind of just breaks,
you don't want to hit your head.
Um,
for the most part you can tell up and
down.
I mean,
sometimes you lose your equilibrium a
little bit underwater.
But for the most part you can tell what
is up and down so you can feel it
coming.
And I'm going to put my arms there
before I take it on my head.
And so I'm,
I'm like trying to be like a cat,
like when I hit,
I want to be able to,
I'll break my hands or feet or whatever,
you know,
I'm not worried about that.
I don't want to get knocked out.
Right,
right,
right.
So I think everyone,
a default is to try to cover your head.
Um,
you know,
if you hit anywhere else you're kind of
okay.
You just don't want to hit your head.
And when the waves come crashing down on
you,
do you lose your sense of up and down?
You can.
Yeah.
But you know,
you,
you also have your board connected from
the leash and that's usually,
that's generally going to pull up.
So you kind of know,
um,
if you don't feel you're aboard pulling,
you're kind of worried like,
shit,
my board might hit me,
might spare me underwater.
You know,
you can occasionally get spirit in the
face with your board or fin or something
that's kind of spooky.
Um,
I was surfing with a guy who's like a
big brother and I used to travel with
Tom Carroll.
He's a two time world champion.
We're surfing Tahiti one time together
and he used to wear a helmet.
A lot of guys,
don't worry,
most people don't wear a helmet,
but tom used to wear a helmet.
He was real really used to it.
But having something,
you know,
an extra say inch around your head or
half inch,
it's like,
it changes your judgment a little.
So you got to be used to it.
I always felt like it was weird.
It's weird for aspiring to.
It fucks with your peripheral vision.
Yeah.
So it would mess with me when I tried to
wear them and that extra weight and like
when we're trying to,
on a critical way of.
We're trying to pull in the barrel,
we're,
we are dealing with inches,
you know,
percentage of inches.
Like just tucking your head into that
lip.
And so you gotta you gotta kind of be
really aware of your range and your,
your ability to like Tuck your head at
certain places and I was never
comfortable with it but certainly with
Tom and he wiped out and his board
spirit him in the ear and it broke,
it broke the helmet and broke his ear
drum Jesus.
So we were just wondering like,
what the hell would have happened if he
didn't have his helmet on?
You know,
like probably would've killed him,
you know,
would it definitely knocked them out and
we didn't have a jet ski with us that
day or anything.
We were,
you know,
500 yards or more off the beach,
half mile off the beach somewhere at
this wreath.
And blow your ear drum like that.
Do you have to get it surgically
repaired?
Uh,
no.
I don't think so.
I think I've never just let it heal up.
I almost busted my eardrum like six
weeks ago in Hawaii.
Just free dive in.
I felt it like,
like a pinhole leak.
I could feel it like going and I kind of
got dizzy and I just came up and stop
diving.
But um,
there was a guy,
I'm like,
I've got a buddy named Greg Long.
He's,
he has drowned and he been attacked by a
shark.
Not Too many people can say those things
and he's life.
How do you get saved when he drowned?
A,
that's a really crazy story,
but I'll just talk about one sec.
But he did break his ear drum at
mavericks up in northern California and
he just,
you just flounder.
You don't know what you think.
You're swimming one direction.
You're,
it's like you have,
it's like your boats turn in and you
don't know which there was no rudder,
you know,
and you don't know what's up and down
and you know,
you think you're something up and you're
going sideways and it's really
dangerous.
There was a,
there was guy in Hawaii a couple of
years ago that drone surfing an outer
reef.
He and a friend of mine caught a wave
and this guy wiped out.
He didn't have all he had with surf
trunks and generally will wear like even
a wetsuit,
which is just then,
but it keeps you warm and even that's
enough flotation to where if you'd got
knocked out,
you'd probably come to the surface.
So this guy wiped out his leash broke,
so he lost his board and then we think,
you know,
the guys who are out there think that he
popped his eardrum because they said
they saw him hit the surface and start
like his feet were coming up and his
hand was coming up and you know,
he was kind of just floundering around
and then the next wave hit and they
never saw him again,
but he was only in surf trunks.
So they didn't ever find the body.
Um,
because he didn't float up.
But if he just had it,
even just a wet suit,
just some neoprene ever found the bomb,
didn't find him.
The waves were huge.
It was,
you know,
it was like 40,
50 foot,
whatever.
But it was really unfortunate.
It was a real.
Those things are really like sobering in
the surf community because we all know
each other and um,
and you know,
ultimately you're doing this for fun and
you know,
it's,
it's a,
it's a heavy thing,
but it's crazy that your eardrum affects
you that much.
Yeah,
I mean I've seen,
I've seen people that have inner ear
infections and they'll get dizzy
walking.
I just don't know what they're doing
while they're one front in front of the
other,
they want to fall sideways.
It's very strange.
Yeah.
Well,
so greg,
Greg Long,
he drowned actually at a place called
Cortez Bank,
which is about 120 miles off the coast
of Dana Point.
It's just a re.
It's basically that the top of a
mountain on an island that never hit the
surface.
And it was discovered when,
I think it was a nuclear ship actually
grounded itself on that reef back,
I don't know,
30 years ago or something and caused a
lot of,
caused tens of millions of dollars of
damage to the ship navy ship.
Um,
and yeah,
I don't know if they had sounded the
bottom by then.
It must not have known it was there,
but um,
anyways,
this wave breaks when it's really big
and I'm,
Shane's been out there.
Shane was actually,
I think Shane was out there this day,
not positive,
but I'm pretty sure Shane was out during
this session.
There's about 15 guys out,
doesn't guys out and Greg took off on a
wave and a,
somebody who in front of him on the
wave,
which kind of changed his angle a little
bit,
but he,
I don't think he would've made the wave
anyhow,
but it just puts them in a little bit of
a precarious situation.
Um,
and he ate it.
It was down a long time.
This wave has just so much energy in it
because there's nothing between where
the wave started and this break,
like it's thousands and thousands of
feet deep that,
you know,
over the whole Pacific.
So there's no continental shelf to slow
the wave down.
Know if you can imagine the east coast.
We have small waves.
A big part of that,
part of that is because most of the
storms go west to east and they don't
come towards us.
But even on a hurricane are our surf,
not that big because we have a
continental shelf that goes,
you can go out,
you can go out 20 miles and it's 70 feet
deep someplaces.
So the swells just drag in the Pacific.
They don't drag,
there's just nothing to get in the way.
So these wells are going 35 miles an
hour when they hit.
So it's a lot faster than a normal wave.
So there's all this energy and the wave.
And so when Greg went down and this wave
is probably a 40 foot face or whatever,
50 face,
he was underwater and he's really
calling.
He's,
you know,
he's probably as,
as ready for anybody in big surf.
He's totally prepared.
He's done all the CPR and breathing
courses and everything and he was real
calm and he said he pulled his vest and
it didn't work.
And then he pulled another one and it
didn't work and he pulled it a third
time and it didn't work.
And so he's like,
Oh fuck,
I'm screwed.
You know,
that kind of thing.
But he,
at that point,
you're,
when you start to pull it,
you,
you're already in a little bit of a,
some,
some guys pull it right away just to be
safe when a big wave.
But some guys kind of wait and go,
I'll see if I'm able to pull this one
off and I'll save my little canister
because you only have like some of the
vets have to earth two canisters,
some have four.
So you don't want to have to change your
canisters over.
So if you're thinking going to make
that,
you're going to get back to the surface.
Are you okay?
You can handle it and you got a good
breath.
You're like,
I'll just,
I won't pull it.
But he pulled three times and then he
blacked out and they,
luckily it had really good water safety
crew and um,
I don't know that it was his brother
that saved them.
But a couple of the guys went and
grabbed dove in and pull them up by the
leash.
Luckily he was to the least because he
wasn't floating because he didn't have
the CEO too.
And then he had taken a lot of water and
uh,
they had to airlift him off the boat in
height and big seas that night after
dark and got him back to the mainland.
So did they do cpr on him?
They did CPR.
Yeah.
And then the come back to consciousness
came back to consciousness,
but he was like awake when the airlift
and nobody gets fucked up.
Yeah.
But guys can have secondary drowning.
Um,
we still have water in the lungs and
you're not aware of the symptoms or
whatever.
Get it out.
Um,
I don't know.
They pump it off it out.
They can't just hang by your ankles or
anything.
Yeah,
I think they pump it out.
I was with a buddy in Australia a year
and a half ago and then he almost
drowned,
got knocked out his board,
hit him in the chin,
knocked him out cold.
And uh,
I was,
I was sitting out the back waiting for a
wave and I heard everyone kind of,
I heard another friend screaming.
Luckily the waves kind of stopped and
they were able to get to them,
pull them up on a jet ski and he had
taken it in some water and he's puking
and coffin and all this stuff and I came
up from behind and I didn't see his
neck.
Um,
and I heard,
I heard one of the guys say,
Oh,
he got his board,
hit him in the neck and the throat,
and so I was expecting this artery be
cut or like the throat to be open.
Like I was like,
okay,
I don't want to look yet,
you know,
because I was behind him.
I didn't want to get it to go around him
and try to look.
I'm like,
okay,
let's get him into the beach.
Luckily we had a jet ski because we were
about a mile off shore.
And um,
I just,
I held on the jet ski and kind of,
I just squeezed on behalf on the.
We have a sled on the back of the jet
ski,
like a body big giant bodyboard with
handles.
So I just kind of straddled him.
My other friend rode the ski all the way
up on the beach and then I thought,
okay,
when we get the beach I'm going to have
to see,
this is going to be gory.
But luckily he wasn't opened up.
He just had a huge hematoma here on his
neck and he,
it didn't slice him.
It just like contusion,
like blunt force.
That's very lucky.
Yeah.
But he spent two or three days in the
hospital because they were worried about
secondary drowning,
which I don't exactly know what
secondary drowning means,
but I guess when you have water,
salt,
water in your lungs,
it can.
I don't know,
maybe from the way you laid down or I
don't know,
I should probably be super school
mistakes you're living.
Right?
But uh,
yeah,
you must see a lot of crazy shit in the
water.
Like I'm seeing some crazy stuff.
Yeah.
Wildlife.
And I mean,
you must see an amazing amount of fish
and the shark copics super.
It never ends,
you know,
like,
I mean anyone in the world I meet is
Oh,
I'm scared of sharks.
Told me about that story.
Doesn't ever end that story like it's a
primal fear,
like getting eaten by a monster,
you know,
you feel so vulnerable in the water.
I mean maybe you feel less vulnerable
because you're bored and you have a
board knew so quick with the board,
but like someone like,
oh,
you,
you are totally vulnerable if a great
white one too.
Oh yeah,
completely.
If you're,
if a shark over,
I mean,
even if a six foot shark wants you,
but that's the,
that's the misconception.
You know,
everyone thinks,
oh,
shark death,
you know,
jaws just fucked everybody up.
So I was seven or something when,
when I was six,
I think when jaws came out and I watched
it,
you know,
I watched brick poltergeist when I was
10.
My parents let me watch everything and
mine to.
Maybe that's why I always thought there
was some boogeyman in the closet,
you know,
or whatever.
But yeah,
it keeps your prepared.
Maybe that's why I started training with
a dragon,
you know?
But uh,
um,
so jaws,
I wouldn't even go in the deep end of a
pool.
I was so freaked out that I was like,
there's going to be a shark at the deep
end somewhere and you know,
I would only stay in the shallow end for
a couple of years when I was like five
or six,
you know.
But uh,
yeah.
So anyway,
so greg got to the hospital.
He was all right.
Um,
what about a year and a half ago,
a friend of ours who's a great big wave,
got like,
this guy is completely,
totally fearless.
He drowned in Fiji and Greg,
who had,
who I talked about it,
Cortez Greg actually did CPR and brought
him back.
Wow.
And um,
they're,
you know,
the,
the big wave guys are a tight.
It's a tight bond of camaraderie with
these guys because I mean,
yeah,
everyone wants that big wave.
They want that biggest way.
They want something they have never had,
but they want their,
they're all really close friends.
Like they're,
they know that there's life and death
having each other's backs and pretty
much everyone knows cpr.
Most.
Yeah.
Most everybody that.
There's courses that the big wave guys
run every year.
They put these courses together a couple
times a year,
um,
specifically to train for the situations
that we could be in and um,
yeah,
so it's really,
really great because they bring in a lot
of,
you know,
breath hold deep freediving people and
the best cpr and lifeguard guys in the
world,
a lot of the best life guard guys in the
world are already surfers.
Anyway,
on the north shore of Awahoo.
I'm in Maui and uh,
I mean those are the guys you want to
have your back when there's in the surf
zone.
Some guy in the coast guard's probably
not gonna be able to do the same.
Like they might help your boat,
but they're not.
And I'm not trying to put coast guard
guys down at all in any way.
I'm just saying like these guys trained
specifically for in the Whitewater,
in big surf,
you know,
they train the seal team,
six guys in Hawaii every year,
so it for heavy situations.
So how often do you actually see shorts?
Depends where you're at.
In Florida,
I see sharks almost daily.
Real.
Yeah.
I live in Florida.
I'm from Florida.
I still go back there and most days you
surf,
you'll see in certain places you'll see
a lot of why I live here.
I live in Hawaii,
I live on Australia.
Oh Damn.
You're.
I'm a nomad.
I'm not going to modern nomad,
you know,
but I'm cheap apartments in different
places.
So when I,
when I first started making money,
I thought that would be cool to have a
little place in each place I go that I
kind of based out of so I can be feeling
like home on the roads.
That's another thing is like I've
always,
I've,
I wanted to make the world like my home
when I was a kid.
I just love traveling.
I love meeting people everywhere.
I love having these sort of household
feeling,
uh,
you know,
families everywhere and stuff.
So in Australia I bought a place in
Sydney when I was 20.
I'm with a friend,
you know,
I just bought this real humble two
bedroom,
tiny little two bedroom on the beach,
like just back from the beach.
My old roommate and I talk about it now,
we're like,
why don't we buy that whole freaking
apartment block,
you know,
because it was cheap back then.
It was like 150 bucks,
150,000
bucks per apartment Australia,
which was like $100,000
us at the time.
So I bought I own half of that for about
15 years and then I sold that and I
bought another place up near.
I'm on the Gold Coast in Australia.
Australia has a lot of dangerous shit,
right?
Because they have every dangerous shit
box.
Jelly fish.
Yeah.
They box jelly fish,
salt,
water crocs.
Lots of great whites while you're
surfing.
No,
I.
Well I have.
Yeah,
I have Costa Rica Do.
That's scary.
That's those things.
People talk about sharks.
Sharks don't hunt you.
They might bite you if they see you,
you know,
like,
but uh,
uh,
a saltwater croc.
That thing is watching you.
It can feel you walking in.
It knows from that vibration how close
you are to the water's edge.
It knows exactly.
I can pinpoint it.
Can pinpoint to the waters edge where
you're at.
Yeah.
That noise,
my friend Adam Green tree lives in
Australia and he's not all over
Australia.
They're everywhere.
No,
no.
Do Your House.
No,
no.
They're waiting for you at the
supermarket.
But they do keep track.
Like I know that the closest one to the
Gold Coast where I'm from is like,
it's still like 300 miles north or
something like 200,
whatever.
It's like the closest saltwater crocs.
Yeah.
They keep a track,
like,
you know,
they're pretty visual and about how,
where they are,
what rivers they would be.
Because I got to warn people like,
don't swim here.
Some people don't listen,
they're stupid and they die.
But like a crock snuck on to just sort
of give you an exploratory bite like a
great white might in review.
They're going to snatch you and there,
you know,
and they're not going to get the
surfboard in the way from the underbite,
you know,
they're gonna.
There was a horrible story that I read
it.
I think it was a national geographic
about this.
These two people that were kayaking in
the river in Africa and this guy was the
guy went with them.
Did you?
This might be a different story.
I don't know what story did you hear?
This one was like,
these two guys were going to do a first
descent down this thing and they were
contacting another guy who had done that
river,
an American guy,
and the American guy was like,
I can't miss this descent.
I got to do this.
I got to do that whole river.
And then the three of them got into the
zone where they're just everywhere in
the river was real slow and wide and as
soon as they got there,
all the river,
all the crux came off the river bank and
they were like,
oh shit.
There's like tons of them.
And this guy's theory was to take his
helmet and throw it off to the side so
it would be like movement and distract
them.
And they'd attack that and he paddled to
shore and all three of them got together
and the American guy was on the right
side and the other two guys were
together and they were so close.
They see like the guy in the middle like
couldn't really paddle.
He would just kinda like,
you know,
trying to move along with them.
And so they figured if the bigger we
are,
the bigger we look and more
intimidating,
like maybe it will be okay.
Fifteen,
18 foot crop comes up,
grabs the guy,
takes him out of his,
pulls them out,
as Kayak disappears,
they never see him again.
His backpack floats up.
And then this stuff's floating down
downstream.
The other two guys get out of the water.
And um,
I think I'm telling the story pretty
good because I read it like five times
online too.
And they got other water and then there
was a little village just down and there
was a little bridge over and they had,
there were some boats when the boats
were all dry docked and they went down
and in broken English it was one person
that could talk to him or whatever.
And they said,
we know our boats are not in the water
because there's too many crocs here.
Like we know not to go in the water
because they were like,
we need a boat.
We got to find his body,
we got to try and save him,
you know?
And then they went to the bridge and
watch this stuff like float by.
That's the same story.
It's.
And the guy wasn't supposed to be on the
trip and there was about the,
the,
the Kayak flipping and then pulling
his body out under the Kayak.
Yeah.
Brutal.
They're monsters.
It's a,
there's a show called.
They really are.
There's a show called uncharted by what
you've seen that show.
My friend Jim shockey is Florida.
Yeah.
That's 15 foot fucking alligator they
found in Florida was strolling across
the golf course.
And the next day they found a giant
snake,
a giant rattlesnake strolling across a
golf course.
Look at the size of that thing I fed,
you know,
I was friends with Steve Irwin.
So you said go to look at the size of
that thing on a golf course.
Here's the thing.
I,
I think there's a misconstrued
misconception about the crocs.
And they actually talked about this
because I used to be friends with Steve
Irwin before he passed away.
He took,
he actually had me hand feet,
a 13 foot crock,
scary,
scariest thing I've ever done in my
life.
Terrified he would you do that?
I don't know.
He,
he told me,
you know,
you got to feed a crock because like,
Kelly,
you're ready.
You got a fee.
Crock got to Viagra.
So for two nights so crazy for two
nights I had nightmares.
Look at it.
What is this guy doing?
I told you I saw this a few weeks ago.
This guy doing.
He's feeding them by hand of these
things.
Look at their heads,
kid.
Good Lord.
And these are wild crocs.
Well,
they look like they know this guy is
going to feed him something.
They know something like that.
Bad Man.
Look at the heads on these things,
but see,
this is like the conception we.
The concept we have about these animals,
right?
We just think that they're just killers
and whatever.
Do you ever see the guy and limone Costa
Rica who had a pet?
15 foot crock?
Yeah,
they did say that guy's an asshole.
This is crazy.
It's a crazy animal man.
It's a crock.
Freaked me out.
But I like,
I kind of miss when I'm playing.
When I'm playing golf.
I played a lot of golf when I'm in
Florida.
I always messed with the gators.
Like I'll grab him by the tail.
Yeah.
Why?
It's kind of.
I don't know.
It's just like,
it's fun until you get your arm bit off
I guess,
but this guy's not even.
He doesn't even need to backstep,
you know?
He's like,
well those are smaller.
Yeah,
but that means that going to rip your
arm off death roles,
but that's so small in comparison to
those other ones.
I was fishing in Australia in this fresh
water,
a river,
but it goes down to the ocean.
So salt water crocs come up to a certain
point.
There's like this dam and they don't go
past that.
So you know,
down here,
up here,
appears all the fresh water down here is
fresh and salt water.
And we saw a few 15 foot crocs this day
and we're in a boat there was six feet
wide and 18 feet long,
15,
18 feet long.
And um,
you know,
the guy taking us,
he said,
you know,
we don't have problem in this boat,
but you know,
if you fill out the boat,
there was a problem.
But he was telling us a story.
One day I was fishing with these guys,
this one guy standing up in the boat
fishing.
He falls out of it and the guy was about
250 pounds or something,
like
a big dude,
like maybe 300 pounds.
He was like a big overweight guy and he
fell the boat and the guy said the guy
was in the water for about two minutes
and he was just like,
any second,
this guy is dead.
He's like,
there's nothing I can do.
And he said it was all they could do to
hit dead to get him from the front of
the boat.
He was trying to pull up up the side and
he couldn't and he was panicking.
So He's,
you know,
when people go into panic mode,
like when people are drowning and
they're panicking and they say you got
to punch them in the face and try to
knock them out and calm down and they
couldn't punch this guy like they were.
They were trying to get them to calm
down and then to get them all the way to
the back of the boat because they had to
get him up the transom and they said
from there they could get leverage and
lifting and it wouldn't flip the boat or
whatever.
But he said this guy was in the water
for a couple minutes and he's like,
at any time there is a crock that's big
enough to eat you within sight of us
here at all times.
But this guy said that he said that I'm
the biggest,
you know,
I said what's the biggest one you ever
seen?
Because we've seen 15 foot crocs like
every 20 minutes,
every half an hour.
15 foot.
Yeah.
No Julian fricking.
And we're,
we're fishing.
Oh my God.
I'm,
we're fishing for bear Monday.
That's a crazy fish.
Yeah.
And um,
and uh,
so we're fishing for money and I keep
thinking like,
I don't know when you got one in the
line is like a shark bite,
that thing or whatever.
And anyways,
we start asking the guy,
what's the biggest one you ever saw?
And he said,
mate,
the biggest one I ever saw was about 28
feet.
20.
Yeah.
Twenty nine feet maybe.
And he said he's only seen it once.
And he sought from about a kilometer
away and the estimate of the size.
And he said,
this guy,
these guys in a helicopter salt at once
and it doesn't stay in the river,
it stays out in the ocean.
And he said,
it's so smart,
it knows it's in silty water where
nothing can see it.
There's nothing as big as it.
It owns its territory,
you know,
one the eight feet.
Yeah.
And he said that he said that the back,
we're in the six foot boat.
And he said,
if this thing,
he goes,
I tell you this,
how big they are.
He goes,
this one would be,
he said if it was under our boat,
it would be sticking out about four to
six feet on either side across his back,
sideways.
And we're in a six foot wide boat.
So he said it'd be like 15 foot across
the back.
It's back,
like that's how fucked up.
So think of the girth.
So something that big 15 feet across the
back.
Yeah,
that's what this guy told me.
I don't know,
we didn't see it.
Oh my God.
I mean we're seeing,
you know,
15 footers that are like,
it's girth close to that,
you know,
like a great white.
When you see a 15 foot great white,
it's girth is 15 feet pretty much.
They're so fat.
Yeah.
Once they get like 10 feet,
then they start getting fat and the
growth gets about the length them.
So if you see a 15 or 20 foot 18 foot
great white and you measure their girth,
it's pretty much their length.
How big the crocs get.
I don't know.
This guy said,
I don't know,
this guy's claiming it's like mostly the
biggest crock in the world,
but there was one they called gus or
something in Africa.
I used to go late night just youtube
this stuff when they were saying this is
the one that had eaten,
like they think it's eaten over 100 or
200 people in these villages and they
think it's like 23 feet long or
something.
Well this Jim shockey show that I was
talking to you about uncharted
Gustavo's.
Turn him loose.
Look at that fucking thing.
The Savannah King.
Is that a perspective shot though?
Look how far back those of you wonder.
You wonder.
Yeah,
but people do that with pigs and they
make them.
I do that with my 28 when I catch a
fish,
put it right where it says 28 feet,
four inches.
So that makes sense.
Like what's that?
That's a replica of how big it was.
Fuck that thing.
Fuck that thing in.
Everything that was alive before that
made this worse to,
you know,
go back to that picture jamie.
That replica,
make that larger the replica and just
make that larger.
Look at the size of that fucking thing.
Oh well what is the largest confirmed
ones?
Because if that one is 28 feet,
four inches.
The thing about that,
when they said 28 feet,
four inches,
that's like back when people were full
of Shit.
Yeah.
I mean this guy who told me this guy
might've been trying to freak me out
too.
I mean because that thing is 20 feet and
it's not 20 feet across his back or 12
feet,
you know?
Yeah.
But another eight foot long,
it's pretty.
It's a lot bigger.
And why you see when you see like a five
foot crop or alligator and then you see
a 10 foot the girth relative to the
length changes at that point is.
It's like a.
What he's talking about the ratio in the
size.
It's at one point.
What does it say?
Number one.
What the say?
Number one candidate.
This was a list of the top 10.
So I think their largest crunch.
Cambodia crocodiles,
seven me.
Now,
is this just the species they're talking
about?
Yeah.
This is just the five largest crocodiles
ever recorded.
Oh,
okay.
Cambodia show the picture of the
Cambodia 1:23
feet.
That doesn't have a pen.
Oh,
it doesn't.
So there's only one that had a picture.
Did you not take a picture of a 23 foot
long crocodile?
Trust me,
bro.
Shit was big.
Yeah,
I mean I would imagine that there's
probably bigger ones out there.
I know there was a super killer croc
that went extinct that far.
Dwarfed those.
Those were 60 feet are enormously
extinct.
Pull up that extinct.
Giant crocodile.
I had a friend who was a commercial
fisherman in South Africa and he was
like,
he told me,
he's like the biggest check,
so way bigger than you think.
He's like,
I want to see a picture or something.
He said,
I'll tell you this.
I was on a 60 foot boat with 10 guys
fishing almost a.
He said like everybody in the boat saw
the shark he had at camp next to their
boat.
There were 20 miles off of Port
Elizabeth where there's this reef,
they fish and he's claiming the thing
was more than half the length of their
60 foot boat.
Yeah.
He's like,
it was 35 feet.
That's what he tells me.
What is the biggest great white like 20,
but he's saying there's big jock who's
stoke supposedly filled one and Cape
Verde that they didn't have anything.
They couldn't tell the size because they
didn't have something next to it.
He said it was close to 10 meters,
which is 30 feet,
but this guy's.
This guy's telling me,
he goes,
no.
He goes,
I've seen this shark twice out there is
what he told me,
but I dunno.
They're out there every day.
That's the thing.
How many people are out there?
You know?
I don't know know.
It's like people are the biggest ones.
The biggest ones are smart,
you know?
Yeah.
Like I don't,
I rarely see a big shark.
Rarely I'll see.
Like I've seen a couple of great whites
in South Africa jump look at that thing,
that,
that is the replica of something that
used to exist.
12 animals.
You're glad his fucking skull.
This guy's basically standing inside the
skull.
This crocodile.
So freaky.
Fuck that man.
Well that's that.
That's the premise of that stupid movie.
The Meg,
meg,
Meg,
A.
I won't even watch it like that.
Do you remember that movie?
That deep blue.
Is that what it's called?
There was a shark that they were,
there were sharks.
They were training.
They were like Gmo sharks are.
So these genetically cloned sharks and
they were supposedly training them and
then they got too smart and they started
eating everyone and then there's like,
you know the girl in the Bikini and she
has to take off her wetsuit because it's
rubber.
I don't know.
There's,
you see these movies and you just like
the artistic license on these things are
so bizarre.
There's no truth to it.
It's like Samuel Jackson was in a rico
and he starts talking about.
He goes,
you know what,
you know what?
Dangerous waters,
not dangerous use as dangerous.
We're going to pull together and we're
gonna find a way to get out.
Good moving.
See that?
I mean,
I wouldn't,
I wouldn't see that coming at all.
I wouldn't go in the water for seconds
after that.
So that movie,
you know,
I actually was with Samuel l Jackson
like three weeks ago in Paris.
Golf together.
How big I wanted to ask him about that,
but I didn't.
I didn't know the balls.
I mean,
how big do you think they could be?
And people don't know.
I mean 30 feet sounds reasonable.
If they think they're 25 feet,
there could be one that's 30 feet maybe.
Yeah.
I mean I think it's reasonable to go
and.
But that's a lot more years and eating
and like no one saw it during that time.
I mean it's Kinda like Ufo is I got to
see one.
Yeah.
I got to see an alien sharks and we know
they get big and we're not just how many
people are out there looking for them?
That's the thing.
But they filmed one they call big blue
last year I think in Guadalupe Island.
I think it was.
And it was 22 feet.
Yeah,
the videos online and it's,
you know,
a big day look,
right?
Yeah.
This thing's face and nose looks small
because the body is so huge.
It must've been a pregnant female or
something,
but it's body looks like even bigger
around in the length.
And they said it was 20.
She like it's face almost looks like
small to fuck.
Oh my God.
See the girth girth is so foiled.
Smartest Shark.
Seven meters.
So that's 20,
22 feet,
23 feet.
What the,
this guy touches it.
Comes out of the cage and touch it.
Look at the size of this thing.
That's another thing.
That's the shark feeding freaks me out.
There's this guy touched it,
watch.
He just comes out and he's like,
I gotta touch this creature and I got to
get out of there bitch,
but she like his face almost like small
compared to how a massive so scary that
is so big.
It looks like a whale.
It literally looks like a whale.
Oh my God.
And to think that there's something out
there that's 10 feet bigger than that.
Well,
a killer whale can eat that things liver
without thinking about it in half.
And killer whales,
just a dolphin.
It's so weird to think that that thing
has dominance over that thing.
It is,
but there's just so much smarter.
It's not even close.
There's so much more agile,
so much smarter.
For how often.
What?
This is a seven year old,
what do they call that?
Oh,
Greenland.
Shark.
Yeah.
They think isn't.
Wasn't that one of the speculations of
what the Loch ness monster was?
I think it was some sort of a landlocked
green or not.
Landlord wouldn't have been in the lock.
Now the thing was the lock because it
was trapped because the law is used to
be connected to.
That was a twig that was terrific.
Woodman,
or it could be like a sturgeon or some
shit like that.
Like there was one of.
One of those was a lake champlain or one
of those surgeons are huge.
Sturgeons are crazy.
That's another dynamic alligator.
Gar.
You seen those things?
My friends went fishing for them.
Yeah.
They haven't made Texas.
You can catch them in Texas.
Those things are bizarre.
I don't think you're noodling for those
things.
That's another thing.
It's hundreds of millions of years old,
right?
I mean that would be.
I'd love to go take my friends and just
go.
Newland sometimes sounds kind of creepy
or girlfriend.
Be like,
what noodling.
Oh,
for catfish,
you get accidentally get turtle.
Sometimes they're snapping turtles and
bite your arm off is Gary's.
I feel fucking.
We just break your arm in half.
Probably.
Fuck you up.
I mean,
I'm sure dudes are probably lost
fingers.
Snapping Turtle.
Those.
What's that?
Yeah.
Actually I googled that and the snapping
turtle incidents popped up.
Guys losing their hands.
Don't show me this because that's like
razors.
They're like two razors that go garden
sheers.
Taking your fucking arm off.
Oh,
what?
How often have you encountered workers?
I've never seen an Orca.
Really?
No,
not.
No.
I mean not other than two worlds.
Kidnapping of them.
Foxy world.
Yeah.
I'm with Ya.
I just don't understand.
I mean,
I guess I understand because I was a kid
once and I went there,
but I don't understand how a rational,
logical thinking adult could take their
kids to see world after all the
information that's out there about,
about the social behaviors,
about how smart these animals are about
how gotten to a lot of people.
Unfortunately,
I agree with you if you did get the
information,
but a lot of people just don't know.
They think,
well they're.
They're fed.
They're healthy.
Yeah.
They don't.
I got in this battle with and look,
I'm no scientist.
I debate people all the time,
but I'm no scientist obviously.
I just,
I think I have a pretty good heart and I
feel bad for animals that are up,
that need to travel a hundred miles a
day in their social pacts and they need
to have interaction with other animals
and they need a certain amount of space.
I mean,
imagine you think about solitary
confinement for a prison,
a prisoner who's,
who's in,
who's in a room that's no wider than
they are tall and maybe twice as twice
as long as they are tall,
you know,
and,
and there's no interaction with other
people.
They go crazy.
Most people will come out of prisons and
jails worse than they went in because of
this kind of thing that happens to them.
But I think of being in there for 30
years,
just wondering,
God,
there's another whale and the other side
of that wall.
Can I get some fish?
And I mean,
you go nuts and you see these videos of
that,
the trainer that was killed,
um,
and a trainer,
one trainer,
luckily the guy was a great free diver
and he lived through a,
basically an attack by an Orca.
And the thing he knew,
he wanted to get over to that wall and
he went,
Nope,
I'm not gonna play with you and I'm just
going to keep pulling you down and
pulling you down.
And the guy was good enough freedom to
be able to know,
okay,
I've got to conserve my energy.
I gotta bring my heart rate down.
I'm going to have to hold my breath
against my will when I don't know what's
going to happen.
A friend of mine used to work at marine
land in Canada.
My friend would fill,
filled demars and he was an Orca trainer
and you know,
and he's trying to get marine land
closed down.
There was this big lawsuit with them and
he's been involved in a lawsuit with
them for over five years now.
I was just hanging out with him in
Toronto and he was a Walrus trainer and
this is Walrus that he was taken care
of.
It's the only one that's left there that
survived.
And marine land is like slowly going
bankrupt.
The guy who was the original owner is
now quickly go bankrupt.
That's why it's so dark,
man.
The whole,
the whole business is so dark because,
you know,
a lot of them say,
oh,
we won't take any,
you know,
orcas are dolphins from captivity,
but they'll get them from people that
stole them in the wild and they,
they,
uh,
breed,
you know,
I think there's no more breeding a lot
in America.
Yeah.
But they'll get them from someone that
bred them in Canada or Russia or China
or wherever,
someplace where there's not as many
rules.
You know,
John Lilly,
who was the guy who actually invented
the isolation tank,
is a,
he was a pioneer in interspecies
communication,
which is a,
it's a weird field.
He was a scientist.
That was also.
He took like extreme liberties with his
scientific research,
took a lot of acid,
gave asset to dolphins,
did a lot of dolphin research in the
flotation tank,
did a lot of really,
really wacky shit.
But he believed that one day dolphins,
we're gonna have a seat in the United
Nations.
He believes we're going to be able to
communicate with dolphins and that
dolphins were going to be recognized as
water people.
He thought they were going to be
literally the thought there was smartest
human beings.
Amazing.
If we could figure out how to
communicate with them,
they would have the same rights as human
beings.
Yeah.
And Guy was a genius.
I mean,
just he and I,
I agree with them.
I think there's just a level of
communication.
There's a way that they have of
communicating that we don't understand,
but it's super complex,
very of their own dialects.
They,
they,
they have this crazy social code that
mean they,
they have something like incredibly
dynamic about their environment and
their,
you know,
their social groups.
To be,
uh,
to be able to speak a language you need
to know,
like 150 words.
There was a dolphin that new like 700
words,
300 words,
I don't know,
like 100 commands.
Standard human words.
You know how many dolphin words we know?
Zero.
A fucking clue.
We have no idea.
We don't know what the fuck they're
saying,
but they're so goddamn stupid.
Fucking stop giving me macro level.
They're like,
they don't know,
were making fun of them for 100 years.
I don't think they know what to do with
them.
Well,
one of the things that Phil was working
with was there's a group,
what was that group that where they're
trying to,
they're going to create a boundary out
in the ocean and slowly released these
dolphins and orcas out into this
boundary and then you know,
and keep feeding them,
but then slowly released them out open
ocean pens.
Yeah.
They're talking about doing that
possibly,
and that would be a way for people to
actually experience it because the idea
is that you and I,
I had a debate with his trainer.
I watched blackfish and it just freaked
me out and of course it's.
There's probably a lot of confirmation
bias.
There's probably some information in
there that is not totally unbiased.
Right.
Obviously they're trying to make a
point,
but this woman was.
She talked to all the different trainers
and stuff.
I got in contact,
a guy got in contact with me that was a
trainer and he said,
Kelly,
the whole movie is Bs.
I think.
I believe this guy was actually in the
movie.
He's like,
it was all bs.
Orcas live longer in,
in captivity in indeed they do.
In the wild.
He told me that orcas haven't been in
captivity as long as they live yet,
so we don't know that.
So that's completely a lie.
It's.
He has no idea if that's true.
He said they're more healthy.
He told me all these things and I just
finally went,
this guy's just full of shit.
I Dunno,
I,
I can't buy what he's telling me.
And He.
But he said I'm a trainer.
I've been a trainer for it.
I looked him up and biased because
that's what makes his living exactly.
And I know some dolphin trainers and I
actually went to seaworld a few times in
Australia.
I used to know a few of the trainers
back in the late nineties and I went
there a few times when I'm with the
dolphins.
The first day I was there,
one of the things I asked him was like,
do they?
Well these guys ever get set free and
right.
Then I could feel a little pull back.
You know,
like straight away I could feel like
maybe,
and I released my slaves.
Yeah,
I felt a little uncomfortable with keep
asking questions because it is their
livelihood and I had a respect for that
and I know that all these trainers love
these animals.
They really,
truly,
probably loved them more than most
people.
Um,
but that doesn't make it right at all.
and there are probably some animals that
can handle being in a zoo or they're
happy.
They're giraffes,
giraffes,
and a bit about that,
that just walking around going on was no
lions,
Kangaroos,
you know,
they get fed well,
they don't really need to migrate
Predator that's going after them.
There's,
I mean they let babies feed giraffes at
the zoo.
Yeah.
Because there's so calm.
My friend has a draft in Malibu.
Really?
Your friend as a giraffe has a draft.
How ballers your friends fucking
awesome.
And bitches come over your house.
You got to right?
They bought it for like 30 grand or 20
grand.
Yeah,
his Ferrari got a bunch of that.
That's my giraffe.
They got some emus and the mind inside
our chef will be cooking for you or
we'll fly to Jamaica.
My private jet motherfuckers got a
giraffe can be poor and they got a
winery.
They got a giraffe.
They got.
He's got his own winery.
Yeah.
Their family has like all this acres,
but anyways,
this draft,
super cool.
He come up and eat at her house in
Malibu,
Malibu Hill.
It's called Malibu wine wine or Malibu
winery or something.
Man.
Wake up with a mountain lion eating
lunch around.
I know they got to watch out.
There's a mountain lion that killed 11
alpacas up there.
My friend lives in Topanga Canyon and
he,
uh,
he came home one day or one night a
mountain lion got into his pig pen or
pen or something Kinda ugly.
There's a lot of them were talking about
that anymore and it had to figure out
like he had this,
the way he had his thing,
it couldn't climb up the fencing or
break under it.
It had tried apparently the thing new to
climb up this tree and drop from like 12
feet or 15 feet down into the pin.
What's.
Yeah,
yeah.
It had to climb this tree he had.
He has cameras and stuff.
He figured it out.
Figured it out.
Yeah.
Fuck those things man.
You know,
I went to muscle bay and in South
Africa,
so I was interested to do one of those
shark dive feeding tours.
I thought I'll go check it out.
Got there,
get on the boat and you go out and you
don't want to.
I didn't want to bring my own wetsuit
because I didn't want all this fish
slime all over it.
You know what I mean?
So like I don't want to go back to
surfing the next day at some back of
Jeffery's bay.
Smelled like fish.
Yeah.
And uh,
so um,
get on the boat,
go out there and where they feed them,
there's like these couple of little rock
islands that stick up right there.
And they'd just parked the boat.
As soon as they parked the boat,
boom.
The sharks are on you.
Sharks are pretty inquisitive anyways.
Even when I've been on boats out in the
ocean,
fishing or diving,
wasn't Papa New Guinea one time.
We pulled up everywhere.
We anchored immediately be three to
five,
maybe more sharks on the boat.
Did you come up from the deep check out?
What is that?
And to kind of disappeared.
Then they're probably watching because
they can,
they know what's going on.
But the great whites pop up.
I think that day we saw about eight or
10 great whites,
different sizes and ages and whatever.
And uh,
what about 500 yards away?
There were guys surfing and I was like,
this is fucking weird man.
Like there's no way I'd be surfing and
these guys surf there every day.
And then there's a couple other spots.
A couple of friends of mine like grew up
in that area and they surf these reefs
that are like right back where we came a
mile a mile from there and the boat just
on just on the outside of this harbor.
And
there's kind kinda two ways of thinking.
Like number one thing that bothers me
with it is that dish,
like sharks know where they got,
they got a meal,
sharks,
they tagged sharks,
they know they come back to a hunting
place where they got a seal the year
before or whatever and they're there at
the same time.
You know,
they're,
they're the same month or whatever.
So like September,
October,
they're like here on the coast of
California.
Internal.
Yeah.
And then they go down to Guadalupe
Island and then then they go out about a
thousand miles off the coast and they
believe they breed out there and then a
lot of the females will go to Hawaii in
the males that come back and kind of do
that route,
pick up the coast.
But they,
they.
The craziest thing about these animals,
they,
they know how to just free swim.
Like even if I'm swimming on the
surface,
I got to like put my head up and go,
okay,
where's the beach?
Whereas the,
you know which direction I'm going.
Imagine like they can just swim out in
the ocean and find each other thousand
miles from shore and breed out in the
middle of nowhere.
How do they,
how do they do that and they all know to
get to this place.
You can imagine like fish smell.
Imagine how bad shark pussy smells like
real distinct.
I don't know.
I mean animals have crazy smells each
other when they're breeding in.
Oregon knows that there's a liver in
that great white and he's gonna smash it
and eat the liver out of that and leave
the shark.
How they smell that.
That's what all Alpha males like in the
packs,
when they kill a thing,
the Alpha male always eats to deliver.
Wow.
It's the most nutrient dense Oregon.
Yeah.
Well the.
So what I don't like is that sharks I
believe are equating,
okay,
I see a boat,
I see a person,
whatever that thing is,
and he's got food,
right?
I just don't like that equation.
It's,
it sucks.
And all these shark week's and stuff,
they're all filming off of Cape Town and
they're,
they're.
I think they're educating the sharks
that,
like you said,
human,
it's not fear,
it's just not necessarily the person's
food,
but they have food and if they don't
give it,
it's like a spear fisherman shooting a
fish.
You don't give up.
Your fish will bite you sometimes.
Well,
you know,
that's the case in Kodiak Island with
grizzly bears.
They said the grizzly bears have gotten
so used to the sound of a gunshot,
meaning a deer's dead.
Oh,
they'll look towards the sound of a
gunshot.
Yeah.
There's no.
So they hear a gunshot.
If someone shot a moose or someone shot
a deer,
that means that the dinner bill.
Yeah.
So they run towards gunshot sounds.
You know,
there's an island up in the Aleutians
that has a bunch of Caribou on it.
You know about them,
you know,
and no bears.
Yeah.
I was going to go home,
my friend Adam Adam Green tree that
we're just talking about a shot that a
water buffalo about my head just shot a
giant Moose and a grizzly bear stolen.
No,
in the Yukon last week.
Wow.
Not even last week.
Three days ago.
It might be still in his instagram
story,
but they took some meal eating that
thing right now.
Will the bear buried it?
Buried it buried a jog and fucking
magic?
Well,
it's an enormous bear.
It's a bear in the Yukon.
So you talked about and bear.
Yeah,
easily.
11 foot bear.
So this bear buried his entire moves and
it's all fucking huge.
Moves.
Like an 1800 try moving that moose one
foot.
Yeah.
This bay or just picked it up and dug
it?
Yeah,
like a front loader or one of those
cranes just digs foundations for houses.
They just like,
like the meat to rotten and they grind
it well,
they also want to cover it so the birds
don't find it and then nothing else can
see it.
So they did giant.
They'll cover the Moose and the Gi.
He just decided it was his and so they
were terrified.
When they got there they found the Moose
was covered.
They knew it was a grizzly that did it
because it was so big.
So they just took some of the meat and
ran pleasure.
So primal,
because they can only do so much at a
time,
but why would you even take any?
I just get the fuck out of.
I mean nothing comes back or smells you
look at.
That's the moose that shot size,
that fucking thing.
I mean that is a massive moves.
A friend of mine got a moose last year,
but he's got photos.
Go to the photo of what he got out of
the Moose from the bear.
He got a bag.
A small
bag might be that.
What does it say?
This is not my kid anymore.
Yeah,
click on that.
You can see the video like play that
very the whole mood.
Come on,
look at this whole booth is buried.
Oh my gosh.
That's my.
Are you sure it wasn't a skunk ape.
The detail.
Look at that.
Look,
look,
okay.
I don't like this.
I would feel like we got the fuck out
here.
Plus their bow bowhunting.
Don't even have guns.
No guns.
You ever hear that story of the guy who,
the kid who was getting attacked by the
bear,
the grizzly running down a hill and his
dad was looking up with a bow.
You hear the story?
No.
You got to find this story.
It's so sick.
The Dad was looking at,
the guy decides to go up this Ridge,
this kid,
he's like 25 years,
20 year old kid or whatever,
and he's going up the ridge and he sees
a couple bear cubs or whatever.
And then,
oh no,
there's mom think comes after him.
Just charge and he comes running back
down the hill,
but he straightened line with the,
with the bear that dad is looking at
him,
pulled back,
ready to let,
let an arrow fly.
And the kids exactly in line with the
bear.
Oh my God.
And as the bears like getting to him,
the kids kind of sidesteps and the dad
lets it fly and it hits the bear in the
heart and the baird falls on.
The kid starts ripping at him and dies.
Whoa.
Outdoor life.
September 25,
2:37.
So yeah.
Wow.
Elk Hunting?
Yeah,
Naomi pig got him and started tearing at
him and died on him.
Jesus Christ,
I passed my dad and I saw an arrow fly
by my leg about two feet away.
Dad kept it together.
Tell you what.
There's some serious target panic there.
Yeah.
You better go charging at you and your
sons in front of you.
Oh my God.
I hate to wrap this up and I got to get
out of here.
It's already 6:30.
I had a question for you please.
I was talking about this with a couple
of friends of mine that you are exposed
to probably more information and people
and and all that and more walks of life
than maybe anybody in the world.
You realize that everything about that
because you get such a diverse group of
people to come talk to you from
politicians to chemists and scientists
and athletes and you just know so much
information about so many topics.
It's really no light scattering.
Little for you know a little bit about
everything.
Sort of like sometimes.
Sometimes I don't remember anyone being
humble,
but I mean I think it's cool because
you're just in this sort of,
in this,
you're in this place where now that
information is so readily available to
you firsthand and definitely have
learned a lot,
but what's interesting is that this was
never the plan.
This is all just complete happenstance
and good fortune.
I mean there's this whole thing just
started out talking shit with comedian
friends.
Yeah.
And then slowly but surely someone was
like,
I want to go on.
I'm like,
okay,
come on.
And then you know,
I got like Anthony Bourdain was one of
the first guests that was like a guest
guest.
And then were you buddies with him?
Did you become friends?
I was friends with him and sad thing
it's fucking beyonce.
But like,
yeah.
So your experience now is your flow
state.
It's just like it's just happening.
And is it you enjoy it?
You know,
I love it.
I love watching into it.
I look forward to meeting interesting
people and meeting people like you and
people like Neil degrasse Tyson or
Graham Hancock or there's so many
different people that can come on and
talk about so many different fascinating
things that maybe a lot of people just
weren't exposed to the information for
that.
Um,
just to wrap up that foot thing because
I didn't enter,
it'll be super short.
I got a second surgery in February,
put me off for about six weeks.
I for about six weeks and I started
getting good again and then I taught
because my foot was so tight.
I did like a turf toe terror on the
bottom and I ripped the plantar
fasciitis or whatever.
So I've been fighting that,
but I'm,
I'm right back now.
I'm going to start competing in December
again.
Nice.
Um,
so yeah,
I wanted to go to one of those live
where,
where's.
Is there anyone live around here?
Any.
Any competition that I could see a.
not really around here.
What would it have to go?
Hawaii?
Yeah,
come to Hawaii when I went to the second
week of December.
Second Week?
Yeah.
It's in between.
It's in between your fcs.
I,
there's actually,
there's actually a billet door that week
in Hawaii.
Honolulu.
That's right.
Yeah.
A friend of my card.
Oh,
I forget the card.
My friend Dustin Barca is fighting on it
though,
man.
I was planning on seeing fate or versus
Ryan Bader.
It was going to be at the bay door.
Is that what happened in?
Yeah,
on the 26th.
But now,
um,
what is it?
November?
No,
December 26.
Well,
whatever the date is,
there's a UFC now.
Bummer.
Yeah.
I wanted to see him live,
but there's a Bella tour.
I mean,
I don't know if you're.
Are you contractually obligated to not
go to those now?
I can go.
Yeah.
Can Go.
So there was one that week and the.
We have a surf contest at pipeline.
Who's on that belt or card?
Because Michael Chandler,
the main is Valerie laterno verse.
I can't say her name.
Mcfarland.
You can say it.
Go ahead.
I don't know how to pronounce that.
Lima,
farlane and Lima lay.
Mcfarland.
She must be how,
what?
In what?
We should probably the local and the
local car.
Machida,
I can't figure out this website,
man.
Liotta was great guy when he was
undefeated and it was a bad
motherfucker.
That's a good fight.
Even gracie and Ed Ruth.
Ooh,
that's a good fight.
King.
Oh,
and Liam mcgeary.
That's a good fight to Kona.
He's a friend of mine.
Kona.
Olivera Oh,
okay.
He's a surfer guy.
What a weird bell towards.
Got a very strange website.
Yeah.
15th.
Is this car?
This one.
So that's the same week.
And what island is this surf contest on
a while?
Husein.
Ms Dot Lou.
Oh,
okay.
That's on the north shore.
I'll send you a sincere for cat.
I'll tell you what days is running.
Okay.
If you want to try.
If I can,
I wouldn't try.
I really want to see one live.
Yeah,
I think it would be cool to be there.
He's probably won't compete,
but he'll probably do commentary for
Shane's.
Going to be here real soon.
He's here the day of sober October.
November fifth show.
He got me in here early.
You got you got me in.
I did that.
I don't drink,
I don't drink much,
but I was like,
I was in Paris that we tobar started and
I'll let you know,
I'm just like going to my friend's
restaurant every night and having a
drink or two and stupid,
you know,
and so I just feel so much better not
having even a beer,
you know,
it's just,
it's a good look.
I enjoyed it.
Last year,
last year we did 15 days of hot yoga.
We had to do 15 hot yoga classes.
Ninety minute classes.
Yeah.
That was kind of a pain in the ass.
This year is way more of a pain in the
ass.
This year we're doing this crazy fitness
competition where we're wearing this my
zone heart rate monitor and you get a
certain amount of points for every
minute you're in,
you know,
like 80 percent of your max heart rate.
Seventy percent of your max heart rates
every day.
You're just,
dude,
I worked out for five and a half hours
today.
Five and a half hours.
I'm trying to kill my friend.
I served for five hours yesterday and
I'm not dead.
I just haven't served much later.
I'm not bullshitting.
I worked for.
Worked out for five people.
You're exaggerating.
No,
it's documented.
I did.
Much of that is 913 points.
How many shitting their pants right now?
How many?
Nine.
Twenty nine.
Before I quit.
How many minutes?
Do you know how many minutes today you
were?
Eighty percent heart rate or whatever
hours.
All those yellow hours this month?
Yes.
No,
today.
Today I was at ours at 80 percent of
couple hours.
More like three.
Wow.
Because the reality is at 80 percent of
my max heart rate,
it had to be because 913 you get 240.
What's the per minute to end game is I
win nobody.
I mean do you go do a triathlon
afterwards?
I'm in fucking crazy shape right now.
I'll tell you that you are.
I may go on and I'm like freaking
ripped,
but I mean I've,
I've,
I've literally never been in better
cardiovascular shape in my life when it
works out for five and a half fucking
hours today.
So what do you do?
Anything with that besides just feel
good like like just trying to get my
belt.
Will we have a championship belt,
like a wwe belt at the end of this
intergalactic champion to sober October
and I'm just trying right now.
I'm trying to literally kill my friends
that are trying to compete you at me.
I want,
I want them to regret getting into this
competition with me because I don't
think they totally understood how
fucking crazy I am.
And so this thing started heating up and
I told them I'm going to do 929 points
everyday.
Right now.
1,600
points ahead of second place.
Do you ever fast.
Have you fasted fuckers?
No.
No,
no.
I've done intermittent fasting fast,
like 16 hours but never liked the master
cleanse for 10 days or so.
No.
I like food too much,
but I do enjoy intermittent fasting.
I like to do 16 hours.
I've done like nine,
10 day fasts.
Master cleanse,
but do that.
I recommend it just because you get all
this stuff out of your colon that looks
like your colon.
It's like old poop and it real.
I swear to God,
I came out of my body,
I thought I pooped out my colon.
So it's like when you haven't eaten in
like two days now,
how much you shitting?
You still know that y'all used to poop
the poop everyday.
A little bit.
Yeah.
Wow.
That's crazy.
That's got to.
This stuff comes out of your gut.
They call mucoid plaque.
You can google that and it.
It is like 20,
30,
40 years of stuff built up from the
mucus your body creates when it doesn't
like what you're eating and that goes
down and it gets stuck on this,
on the walls of your intestines and it's
like tire rubber and you poop it out.
It looks exactly like the shape of your
intestine.
I thought it was my intestines.
So you thought you should out part of
your body.
I did.
It was freaky.
And how how good you feel and this is
over.
You look,
latency,
pull it up,
pull it up.
I didn't believe it was real and I got
it and it's like weird flap.
That is nuts.
Yeah.
I got something that does look like
intestine.
Yeah,
it looks like intestine dude.
It's gross.
So that's what comes after your
nutrients.
Have to go through that to get Kiddo.
How long?
Well maybe I'll do that right after I'm
done with sober October.
When Google the master class,
because you're drinking a tea of like
maple syrup,
lemon and Cayenne pepper for how many
times?
I kinda like it.
I did it for 10 days.
Ten days.
No food.
Just that.
Whoa.
Yeah,
but I got that stuff coming out after
about five days because I was really
aggressive with the.
You do a salt water flush every day,
every morning and then you take this
smooth move tea that makes you kind of
like go to the bathroom.
Well,
I'll tell you one thing that I had been
doing because I've been sweating so
much.
I videotaped one day the sweat puddles
that are left in the jar.
I watched that and then I set off my
alarm fire alarm in my gym from my sweat
and today it was so bad.
That was when you lapped the field of
your friends?
Yeah.
Today was so bad too because today I did
the longest that I've ever worked out,
but um,
I know your nutrition is good too,
so I mean,
but you gotta be thinking about what's
going out in what you got to put back
in.
That's one of the things I've been
drinking water with electrolytes and I'm
adding salt.
I'm adding Himalayan salt to the water,
but I may be added too much and when I
talk about just forget diarrhea,
not really diarrhea kids,
it's basically water coming out of my
ass because it's,
I mean it would be like,
I would feel it be like you don't pay it
all.
Oh boom.
It was like opening flood gates and
gallons of water would come out of my
ass.
Most people should do that like once or
twice a month.
Two tables,
two teaspoons of salt in one liter of
water or a quarter water,
banging it.
Your body sees it as food,
not as P,
right?
It just means you have to stay home for
that one.
I wasn't staying home.
I would just jump off the treadmill for
five minutes.
Take a volume is shit of water was
basically water coming out of my
asshole,
but it probably cleans up a lot.
Right.
It cleans.
It cleans you out.
Yeah.
There was stuff.
Weird stuff floating around in there.
I didn't know what that was.
Maybe body uses so much energy for
digestion.
Yeah,
but I got these guys that fall in line
to do water fast,
like every month and they're doing a
five to 10 day water fast coming up this
week.
I'm not going to participate in that
one,
but I want to do a fast soon.
So.
Great.
How much did you look forward to that
drink,
that tea with the law?
I mean if you're not.
I really enjoyed calories.
Yeah,
really enjoyed it.
It was a lot of weight.
I lost.
Yeah.
I didn't weigh myself,
but I think I lost 10 to 12 pounds.
That's a lot.
I really appreciated.
I was pretty sure I did,
but I was thin too,
you know.
But then you build back at that first
date I ate afterwards,
you know,
it was like the best food I ever had my
gun,
you know,
just like you've never deep 10 whole
days of just the tea.
Yeah.
Wow.
And,
and uh,
and a salt water flush every day and the
smooth move tea,
which I was doubling up on.
So I was,
because I didn't have the full 14 days,
so I'm like I got to go fast.
But I was getting stomach cramps because
I was eating,
drinking too much of that tea.
I'll try that.
Yeah,
I'll give that a shot.
At least Google it and look and,
and,
but when you can,
when you can abstain from food,
it's,
it's like you could quit heroin or some
people are so addicted to food.
Look at people thing because of this.
Like I'm the amount of calories that I'm
consuming.
Like let me tell you how much I burned
today because it's so goddamn insane.
Today I burned.
I mean this doesn't even,
it doesn't even seem real.
But I burned 4,217
calories during this workout.
Yeah.
That's a or you just circuiting the
whole time,
ran the hills around two miles with my
dog in the hills,
which believe it or not,
you don't get many fucking points for it
because it's think sucks.
It's way harder than the other things
that I'm doing because it's basically
straight up,
but I'm just trying to.
I have a two year old golden retriever
and he's got so much goddamn energy.
He's the best,
but I got to wear his ass out.
Otherwise he annoys.
Everybody jumps up on people who just
needs attention,
but when I run with them he's just
chill.
So I'll do two miles in the.
What do you got here and just give you.
I'm going to plug my buddy sunlife.
I love this stuff.
What is this one that's a dawn patrol.
It's like cold brew coffee,
coconut,
a coconut cream,
coconut sugar.
Anyways,
you go into my time,
but I do.
I go in there all the time in depth.
Courageous.
I.
They have great everything.
Yeah,
just awesome.
I really live there.
Sometimes they'll spend half the day
there and get to my meals.
Got Bone Broth to enbrel.
I love the bone broth that he.
It's like his Kahleel special style.
Yeah.
With the Cayenne pepper and that's
fucking sensational.
Was I saying,
oh,
but that's not good for that many
points.
No system.
Not Gauging the going up hill.
It's like it's more grinding.
It's like just if you get to 80 percent
of your max heart rate and just grind.
You guys got money on this thing?
No,
just the belt just to built.
Yeah.
And bragging rights.
You'll be like Khabib.
You're like,
where's my belt?
Give me my belt.
Me By keeping me is number one bullshit.
Send me a location.
Me Location.
Kelly,
I'm glad we finally did this.
You too,
man.
Thanks a lot.
Yeah,
it's been awesome.
Thanks you guys.
We'll be back tomorrow folks.
We got to two tomorrow in my round earth
shirt.
Thank you.
Yeah,
round Earth Shill.
Marcus.
Marcus Brownley will be here at 10 and
Kyle Kalinsky will be here at one,
so see you tomorrow.
Bye.