Boom, and we're alive. Kevin Lee. Yes.
It's about as fresh off of a fight
as you can get, man. Yeah, just about
barely slept. Yeah. It must've
been a crazy, first of all,
like after a fight it's probably you
probably so wired and like can't believe
it's over. Right. What does it like? It
takes you a minute for it to hit you.
Really? Uh, I didn't sleep at
all after the fight. I just,
I laid there for a little bit. Mind kind
of racing, didn't really settle down. Uh,
I just ended up just getting up,
getting some breakfast and then
a right on the plane over here.
Densely ball and on playing came over
here. Three Aum. I'd been up all morning.
But you, what do you like 25? Yeah.
Yeah. Keep going. Yeah, keep going.
Rockstar lifestyle, baby.
I've got to live it at 25.
You can do that for like two days in a
row before it really starts to settle it.
Yeah. No, I'll be good for a minute. I
mean, besides getting kicked in the head,
I'm all good. Other than that did that,
that was the, first of all, it was a very,
very, very impressive performance. I mean,
Edson Barboza is no fucking joke and
notoriously difficult to take down.
Even Khabib struggled getting him down
the early parts of the first round,
but you got them down quick. Yeah. I
think a lot of people underestimate that,
especially how technical my
wrestling can get. Um, I,
I just feel like Edison was really strong.
Uh,
he was probably the strongest guy that
I've ever faced. Physically. It just,
his body is just,
it moved a little bit different,
but technically I just had to
the aspect there. And when,
when you add those two things up, I'm
equally as strong, you know? Yeah.
I'm just going to blow him off the water.
Well,
he's just a bundle of fast twitch
muscle fiber, man. That dude,
I mean, people, you know,
they'll see the cubby fight and
they'll see this fight with you.
They might not understand how good that
guy really is. He's very, very good.
He's obese and he's going to come back
and he's going to knock some people out.
He's only gonna get better from here.
I think it's just he,
it's the styles make the fights too in me.
I feel like I can fight any style,
you know, that that was my number
one goal when I got into this sport,
just to be the most well rounded,
complete fighter that there is an,
and I feel like I can take advantage of
some of his things that he's not good
and good at, but he's going to
get better at him. He's going to,
he's going to be back.
He's a beast.
Well that focus in that mindset of being
well rounded was very obvious in that
fight.
I was very impressed by the fact you,
you fight just as good south southpaw as
you do orthodox, you switch up easily.
I've, I've been, uh, I've only been
going south for maybe the past year,
year and a half or so, uh, and just
kind of getting a filler for a down.
But I feel like that could be one of the,
when you listen to a lot of the
great fighters in, in the past,
they talk about a right hand,
a softball.
There's so many advantages they
can be there. Uh, and it's just,
it's just always great to be able
to switch up and change timings,
especially when you've got a god that's,
that's trying to time you like Edson, uh,
because he say that,
I'm sorry,
but they say that if you
work on the opposite side,
it actually makes the other
side better. Yeah. Yeah.
It makes it a little bit easier when
you switch back. And I've noticed that,
I mean, still some, some
kinks and twist that I want to kind of
get out of there. You know what you see,
I study a lot of people. I study a lot of
switch fighters, especially in MMA. Uh,
recently,
I want to say about the last two years.
He hasn't been doing it more often,
but some guys do it better than others.
I try to get the perfect mix,
you know?
Well, some guys do it, but there's a
twist, right? Like wonder boy does it.
But when Wonderboy does it, you know that
the front leg is coming and then he's,
you know, he's, he can fight any style.
I mean he could fight left or right,
but when he switches,
when he goes right,
you know that front leg side kicks coming,
that front leg roundhouse kick is
coming and then when he stands Orthodox,
he's much more likely to throw a
punch or you know, maybe even spin,
he mixes it up.
But he,
he's limited maybe in the way he attacks
blending of it.
I think Wonderboy is one of those guys
that his switches are like really, uh,
you could see him coming, you know, he,
he makes them really pronounced, you know,
they're big switches and you know,
the, the attacks that are coming,
there are certain guys like Tj
Dillashaw who was great at mixing it up
completely. I feel like he doesn't sit
down on his punches too much or, you know,
he gets in spots where he can get clip
and between those with your feet off the
ground. So I tried to find the
happy medium between those two,
switching up too much and uh, being
able to make those hard switches too.
Teachers really been doing that style
for just like three or four years now
since he's been with bang. Maybe it
was about, I want to say three years,
four years.
Yeah. Probably some of that. It
takes some time to get used to it,
get used to the time in and everything.
And, and that's one of the things with me,
like I try and beat the most consistent
a guy that there is out there.
So the more consistently
I'm getting in there,
the more I'm seeing things come in. Um,
um, um, reading the angles and, you know,
getting a lot of different looks, a lot
of different bodies being thrown at me.
Uh, so all that adds up to
experience and you know,
it's only gonna get better from there.
Yeah. It's also one of those things
when you're 25 years old, you,
you still are like realistically five
years away from your athletic prime.
Yeah. I kept that. I keep that in the back
of my mind sometimes because you know,
you obviously don't want to
overwork the body too much.
You don't want to burn out. Uh, but
I think it's just staying consistent,
is staying healthy as long as
I'm healthy through it. You know,
I got through that fight. No,
no serious damages at all. Uh,
and that's the most important thing is
just staying healthy when I'm young. Uh,
and uh,
you know,
tail him back when I'm starting to
get more damages are more injuries,
but I do a great job with keeping my
body all the, I think more than anything.
What do you like when you were in,
I know Robert Follis was your
coach for quite a long time and uh,
we both miss him. I'm sure you,
you were very close with him.
He was such a great guy. Yeah.
Yeah. Was he the guy that,
like did he sort of map out your training
program when you were in camp or,
you know, I had, uh, we,
we kind of structured it,
or at least I try and structure it
like a full team, uh, aspect. You know,
rob was kind of like, I think of
it like a race car, you know, I'm,
I'm the race car itself. Uh, but Robert
was like the hit driver, you know,
rob is telling me where to go, what to do
a Dewey was kind of like my horsepower,
you know, he's, yeah. Do
Cooper, uh, phenomenal striking
coach. If you ever, you know,
task fighter with him. He,
he was a smaller heavyweight,
but he would fight giant guys like
Peter Arts and a dude that you got to,
you know, you look at him, he's
only about two 26 foot one.
Maybe he's fighting six
foot, seven, 300 pound guys.
So he has to be extra technical in there.
Uh, not rely on his speed and power.
That's why I think he,
he makes such a great coaching
and he pushes me through it.
But I had another guy,
I've been working with Cory Goodwin for
the last four or five years since I've
been on Vegas. He's kind of like
the mechanic, you know, he keeps me,
he keeps my body fresh and going is he,
or strength and conditioning,
but we call it that.
But what we do is a lot different than,
than strength and condition. And,
you know, it's, it's not a lot of,
I don't lift any weights and people
when people are seating. Yeah.
I haven't touched on weight since college.
You know,
the only time I did was when I went over
and I started working with the UFC PR
guys a little bit. They wanted me
to touch weights, but, uh, I, I,
it's just not a good fit for me.
Are you doing,
what are you doing plyometrics or you're
doing is he'd have to explain it to you
more. You know, that's his,
that's what he does. He,
he worked through as xls for a long time,
so he took a lot of their,
their physiology or xls.
What's exos? The, uh,
I think they just signed a deal with
the UFC to a lot of guys been going over
and uh, they're a big strength and
conditioning program. They'd get,
they've got a big
facility down in Arizona,
but they used to be based out of Vegas.
Uh,
so he worked for them where he gets a lot
of his training philosophies and stuff
from a, but it's not, it's not any,
any wait, listen, calisthenics.
Chatting a lot of calisthenics,
lot of movement, a lot of,
we work a lot of the joints especially,
you know, where he overextends my joints,
he pushes them past, past the limit,
and then we work out from there.
So it's not very heavy lift
and it's maybe 15 pounds.
Do you mean by pushing them past the
limit? Like, like a hyper extended? Yeah,
I mean, well, it's like you
getting onboard. So, uh,
one of the things we do
is he takes a band and he,
and he stretches it out so it really pulls
my shoulder and I was telling you, I,
I very rarely have shoulder problems
and I think a large reason he,
he pulls it all the way out,
kind of out the socket.
And then we work out from there
to build strength from those,
those little muscles. Uh,
which I felt like is, is,
that's the part where I get my
true strength from. You know,
I do that a lot of yoga, a
lot, a lot of things that just,
all the strength comes from within me.
Not Lifting weights or anything.
How often are you doing yoga when you're
in camp? A two to three times a week.
I've only been doing it for like four
or five months since, since the 25. Uh,
it's been helping me out a lot. When I,
when I started doing it guys, we're like,
oh, what are you lifting or something?
I'm like, Nah, just I should, it's hard.
I'm like, Oh fuck it. Just do it. Yoga
like isn't it crazy how hard it is?
Like you just fucking off like,
yeah, I'm doing yoga. You Lazy Bitch,
stretch and touching your toes.
Maybe for like the first two months,
like I'd be like ashamed to tell people.
They're like, where are you going to,
you know, going into this one class we're
going to be lifting a lot of weights.
We're going to be great. Like Shit. Nah,
I'm in there with like dumb fucking know.
Housewives, housewives and nick killing
me. It's crazy, right? They killing me,
killing me. I've done
good now though, but a,
I do a couple of different state,
even the Vinyasa a little bit.
I try and dabble, but I've only been
doing it for a couple months now.
Now when you do,
how do you structure your camp?
Like it terms of like how much
strength and conditioning you doing,
how much skill work,
how much? So it kind of depended
on, it depends on the opponent to,
but generally I'm doing three times
a week of, of some type of grappling,
whether it has wrestling
or, or, uh, Nogi uh,
then I only s spar once a week
at the end of the weeks, uh,
we pick our spar partners that
we pay, that we choose, you know,
we flogged guys in or guys that
are in town, cause I'm in Vegas.
All gods are always in and out. Right.
Um, but then, uh, you know, I only,
I only do strength conditioning
maybe two times a week. Not Too much.
Now when you say, um, you spar once
a week and you bring guys in, um,
are you sparring hard or
do you far more technical?
Don't make camp, uh,
maybe four or five. Good.
But I go pretty hard and it ruins me
sometimes cause I run out of sparring
partners and guys don't want to
show up and all this. But uh,
I ended up having to start paying guys
just come on man, give me some words.
Right. Yeah, we try and make some money.
Do you think that that's the way to go?
Like, um, for longevity there's
a, there's a big debate, right?
Whether or not you should sparse skill
wise and then save it up for the fight or
whether you should just fucking go to
war. I think, I think you need that,
that reaction time, you know, with a
god that's seriously throwing at you.
And I mean we're, we're not trying
to hurt each other for sure.
The smart partners, 80%, maybe
70%, something like that.
W W we go pretty hard up
until you obviously can see
that there's an injury or
somebody is hurt or you know,
you backed down.
And even on like some of
my takedowns I bagged down,
obviously I'm not trying
to knock the guy out,
but I am trying to give them some good
work. And I hope he does the same return,
but we picked smart guys that will do it.
That's what it's about at that level.
When you got two very high level
guys going against each other,
we can go hard and not injure. If I'm
going with like a new guy or you know,
it's a newer team, like I
don't even try. I gonna make
a name off a few fuck around this.
There's a lot of that man. Too much. Yeah.
I remember I ran into [inaudible] once
and his hand was in a cast and he hadn't
had a fight in a while. I
said, what happened? He said,
some new guy came into the gym and he's
sparring with this new guy and this new
guy is trying to kill him and he
broke his hand on this dude's for it.
And I was thinking, your Vito
Belfort, I mean, and this is Vito.
Or like I want to say like eight,
nine years ago. I was like, man,
like that's crazy. But that's the
kind of shit that happens. Right.
And guys are very tough in a gym. I
mean, especially something illegal,
like they tougher than you think.
[inaudible] 16 and they're tough.
They're coming out with, with,
you know, newest. I think
each dinner generation has a new
style to that. You're, you, you,
you don't get used to it. And if it, you
know, if the boys are catch you, if they,
they'd be hungry or they knew,
uh,
what you're seeing all these new guys
that are coming up that can do everything.
You know, they, they have like taekwondo
skills. They've got Moyie Thai,
they can wrestle, they do flying
armbars and shit. There's just kids are,
because MMA is such a part of like the
zeitgeists now and everybody understands
it and kids know,
if you want to be a really tough fighter,
it's not about boxing,
it's about MMA.
And so you're getting these wild ass kids
that have really young age practicing
this shit on each other, learning it,
trying going to gyms when they're nine,
10 years old. By the time they're in high
school, they're killers. Yeah. I mean,
and we have so many of them that
come through Vegas especially.
And I think that's what,
that's my favorite part about
living there is, is the,
the training partners. And
like you said, the new kids.
I try and even though I'm only 25,
I'm trying to see what they
doing that's coming up next.
That's smart because they,
they're going to come with something that
UAC before it is some out there. Like,
like even my younger brother,
uh,
my younger brothers just getting started
in his America where he's only got five
profiles now, uh, eight in total.
So not that many fights, but the,
some of the things that he do,
I'm like, you know, let me try it.
Let me learn from you a little bit.
Well, the pot bows a fight. Um,
you got clipped was a third round.
The beginning of the third round,
he got clipped with that. We'll kick
that. Recovery was amazing though, man.
That's an amazing
recovery mean Barbara was,
it puts people out with that shit
and your legs completely gave out.
But man, that's a weird moment,
right, where like anything,
if he wasn't near you right,
where you could grab a hold of him and
take him down if he just stepped back a
little bit, you know? Interesting. Right?
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, I was still there.
Uh, you know, I never went
away. And I think a lot of,
even the way I moved it,
when somebody showed me that video
after I cracked though, I was,
I was dying laughing because
when I'm in there, I don't,
I don't know what happened.
You know,
I see the video and I see my legs just
go see the music is a cup of love of Bro.
They ain't pretty good though. I've
been laughing a lot though all morning.
Cause you won. It's funny.
It's funny, it's funny,
but I think a lot of you see my, a lot
of what I was, my focus going into,
this one was really on my footwork,
uh, my balance, you know, doing yoga.
I've been dancing to a
little bit. Okay. Awesome.
Some ballet. I mean, I, you
know, I've heard a lot of
guys, look, Loma Chenko was uh,
you know, his dad had him enrolled
in dance for four fucking years,
traditional Russian dancing and he
credits that for his foot work. Yeah.
I mean I've, I've only been doing
it for a short amount of time,
but still I can tell right off the bat
and I think a lot of what you saw there
was that, you know, uh,
when I looked at before,
the only other fight I've ever got
dropped in her hurt seriously was uh,
the Leonardo Santos fight.
And really it was me drop him back on
my ankle and I broke my ankle in that
fight. When I tried to stand back
up, it looked like a wobble to,
and that's why John Know
John McCarthy stepped in.
So a lot of what I focused on was
the balance. So when my, you know,
that equilibrium gave off and you see
how it saw four guys in front of me,
I'm just like, let me just keep my
eyes on this motherfucker right here.
Cause you think of how hard Barboza is
usually to take down. You just got you.
It was very fortunate that he was right
there for you to grab him because he was
trying to move in for the kill. Yeah.
Yeah. I mean it's, if you were his coach,
you would have been screaming,
get the fuck away from him. Right.
His coaches was not doing them no
favors by, I felt bad for the guy.
What do you mean they could, if
they could have did them better, uh,
through the sec, he, I probably could
have put them away in the second row. Um,
but he was panicking and I could see it
in them, you know, and this coach is like,
cause them to panic a little bit more.
You know,
they just kept screaming at him the time.
Like,
you only got two minutes to survivor.
And I was like, let me not, you know,
new Barboza Nice Guy. He
really is. And uh, you know,
I didn't want to hurt them too bad.
That's too very similar fights for him
in a row, two mornings in a row. That's,
you know, when you're that guy who
wants to stand up and you know,
you got guys that are just, just
constant pressure, constant pressure,
know people don't realize
how much endurance it takes
to move away to you moving
backwards. It's a lot more difficult to
do. Yeah, true. I mean, I feel like it,
everything kind of pushed,
you know,
it's about who controls
the pace of the fight.
And I felt like I did a good
job of that. And again, I, I,
I thought even after I got wobbled
with the, with the kick and the third,
I still came back and ground. Yeah. I
tried to make it a point to finish the,
in that moment you weren't around,
you know,
and you heard him bad in the second round,
two with a kick to the body.
Like you see him cover up and tense
in that, but you could see it,
it was a strong right kick to the body.
One of the reporters he asked me like,
why was that standing at at range
with them? Uh, and it's just like,
I feel like I can do it all, you
know? And that's my true sense.
It's like I can stand at range with with,
I mean he's definitely the
most explosive dynamic. Uh,
all those things that you want to say
that the best kicker in the lightweight
division and I and I can stand at range
with them and kick just as well with
them. I can wrestle with
the best wrestlers I can.
I can kick with the kick best kickbox is,
I could punch with the best boxers.
So A, why not test myself? I'm not one
of these guys who shy away from Shit.
He's an interesting case because
he's really primarily a kicker.
He will throw punches, but that's
not his strong suit. I mean,
he's not a god that just wants to, you
know, just, just digging and throw bombs.
Yeah. But he got some bombs
hit me with that left.
He hit me with a, a Matias left hook
and the fifth round I was like, man,
he's still there. The kid now, he
never gave up. He was taking a beating.
He hit me with a Matias left hook.
So I gave him one back and buses orbital
up. Pretty good plan. Uh, you know,
she was still there till the very
end. He, he, he can box to eat.
He's got some power in his hand. Yeah.
And the cut was a pretty nasty cut.
Pretty nasty cut over his right
eye when it stopped the fight.
When you were you shocked that they stop?
Nah,
I thought, I thought it was
the right call. You know,
I think more coaches in MMA to definitely
get in there and a little bit sooner.
And I think, I think that's what the, some
of our problem with his corner was to,
uh,
you know,
you see some of these fights and you can
kind of tell when a guy just doesn't,
you know, it, it doesn't make
sense to make them take more beats.
Not somebody like barbels. Barboza
is explosive to the very, very end.
You have to give that to them. That's
the thing. You never know. Right. I mean,
if he connected with that left hook,
perfect. And you went out and then,
and then he's a hero, then you know, I
guess you, then you look like the asshole.
But uh, you know, I don't know
is it's a deadline. Cross.
Yeah.
It's a tough decision.
You don't want to be there when you
guys getting beaten up like that and you
have to make that call.
Yeah, yeah. No, I mean, maybe I'm just
speaking from, cause I'm not a coach yet.
Maybe, you know, my stance will change
when him, when I am a coach, but you know,
or if I have a coach, but
we'll see. Yeah. It's uh, it's,
it's different with D.
I mean,
the same thing with referees and Keith
Peterson did a great job in that fight.
He's a God that doesn't get enough credit.
There's a, there's a few like, you know,
Herb Dean,
I think because John McCarthy is retired,
I think he's the gold standard. Josh
Rosenthal, there's a bunch of really,
really good guys, but that's a
tough call to decide when to stop.
I think even Yamasaki, you
know, Yamasaki takes a lot of,
it takes on a lot of bullshit, especially
in front of me from, from Dana.
Don't like him at all. He ate them. But
uh, he, he does a great job in there.
Even that, that fight where he let
the girl take a lot of punches,
a lot of damage.
She was still moving.
She was still showing
that she was in the fight.
I think you got to put that on her
coaches and her inner trainers.
They know that she's, if she's
really in there, you know,
some guys are just too tough
or they aren't good. Like,
like Barboza well she was
vinyl found shift Cenk coach.
It just shits been in there.
She just shouldn't have been there and
it was awful lot in the first UFC fight
and she's fighting a woman who's
just a straight up assassin.
Yeah. And it can't be on the breath. You
can't put it on the ref to know that,
you know, or to to make that call.
The Rep has to be completely, uh,
you know, non, not
objective at all. Um, it's,
I think it's got to put it on the coaches.
They should know what weight do
you walk around at about one,
if I'm completely just kinda like bullshit
and doing whatever I've gotten to as
high as like one 95.
Uh,
when you're in training,
like when you get like save your four
weeks out where you're at 85 usually when
85, 85, eight, you're cutting a lot of
weight man. Yeah. Yeah. I mean that's a,
do you see yourself ever moving to 70 or
[inaudible] 70 necessarily?
Just because though those guys there at
that point you're talking about a frame
issue, right. You know, you got guys had
like six foot one and you know, they're,
they're just, it's a, it's a
different, it's a different body style.
I trained with a lot of them. High
level welterweights tool, you knows,
it's a different body style that I'm more
suited for one 55. It's just, you know,
some of the things that I got to play
around with I think will keep happening in
the upcoming months. I didn't project
that I would fight again until July or so.
So a lot of the things that I was doing
diet wise was kind of getting to that
and they approached me with this barbells,
a fight
maybe like eight weeks earlier than that.
So I just had to do with that and to
do so is it a matter of just you didn't
taper off quick enough or you just
came in too heavy before you started?
You know, it was just, it was
just the timing wise. You know,
I missed it by one pound. Yeah. Yeah.
It's, it's some non that time and that I,
that I've really got to figure out.
And that was the biggest problem with,
with the, uh, Tony Ferguson fight. Uh,
you know, I can break it down for you. It,
so usually, uh, you know,
I'm normally about one 85 through six
weeks of diet and I can usually die it
down until about 76 77.
That's where I'm optimal. Uh,
and then from there I start their
water cuts. So the week of the fight,
the Tuesday, I'm 76, uh, you know,
I saved that all the way until,
you know,
I overload my body with
water and you know,
cause a flush out some of the sodium
and the carbs and all that. Um,
I saved the rest of that up until the
day before and I try and cut as much as I
can as he has.
I want to spend as little time
dehydrated that dehydrated as possible.
And I think that's some of the problem
with having these early morning Wayans is
the timing issue of it as you wake up
and then you have to start from the time
you wake up rather than if it's at four
o'clock in the afternoon and like it
used to be, you'd be able to do it
all throughout the day. Yeah, yeah.
I can cut more, you know, reasonably
through the morning, you know,
you can wake up whenever you had more
time, you would have been able to make it.
Oh yeah, absolutely.
1%. Yeah. My body was,
I got confused when they were
doing this early morning wins.
I thought you had like like from
8:00 AM to four o'clock right? Yeah.
I thought if you could weigh in early,
go ahead way in early.
But they gave you the time.
Yeah, I mean I, I'm not really,
I don't really know the solution either.
You know?
I don't think nobody really knows
the solution to that problem, the,
the timeframe because you are seeing a
lot of guys miss weight because of that
and I think that's, that's one of the
biggest problems and not only that,
but guys are going asleep completely
dehydrated and sleeping through the night,
20 pounds, the hydrated, that's a
lot of water coming from your blood.
Your blood gets thicker, your heart rate
slows down when you, when you sleep.
I mean, you know, I try my best not to
spend as much time dehydrated as possible.
So it's just a timing
issue on that last one.
Especially when you see guys like those
on Joe's that just can't do it anymore
and he goes up to 70 he looks better
than ever. What do you think about that?
It is, it's always an option for me. It
would be an option now, like I, I would,
I would entertain the right fight at
it for sure. It's just right now at,
at the state of it is,
you know,
they're doing this bullshit
interim title and you know,
Tyron sitting right there and just,
it's a lot of movement.
It's not a lot of movement
at the top right now.
So one 55 just more fights interests me.
It's bigger challenges.
I think the guys are honestly better
at one 55 one 70 maybe in a future,
but you know, it's gotta be the right
type of fight or something. Yeah.
Well there's so many good fighters now
from, I mean, you go all across the board.
I mean pretty much every week class.
It's strong now. But yeah, I agree.
I think 55 is probably the strongest
way class right now and it's,
and it's so strong that you can
make a one 65 I don't mean, I don't,
I really don't see what
the holdup is on it.
Do a 65 to a 75 because we have so many
guys that can bounce between those.
And you'll have a whole new top 15 whole
new champion in the be just as strong
as any of the two weight classes
next to it. I couldn't agree more.
I think it's very important
that we spread it out better.
I think 10 pounds is reasonable then. I
mean the way boxing has it, they just,
you know, they have a 54 and then they
have a 60 that seems a little ridiculous.
47 and then they have a 54 I think
you'd be better off with 10 just said
straight up 10 pounds.
That's reasonable.
But when you go from like 85 to two
oh five, that shit's crazy. Big Boys.
What's up big? Some of them to
even 55 to 70 because most guys,
uh, you know, like a normal sized guy,
he's about my size, 180 590 pounds.
That puts you in that,
in that middle, you know,
you got guys like me with a lot of muscle
where I'm not going to lose a lot of
fat in between. You know, even
for this one, I was one 77,
but I was four and a half percent body
fat. You know, I couldn't really lean.
He can't get too much more lean
in that uh, uh, 64 and a half.
Somebody fighting when
you wait in. Yeah. Before,
well I was four and a half percent maybe
two weeks before the fight actually.
But are you getting calipers?
Are you doing the how they,
how they tested in over at the
few in the water? Not all over it.
The Pi they have. Especially the
scanning. Yeah. They've got like,
so the scales aren't that good yet.
Here's the thing about those scales,
those scales when you hold onto those
things and some of them are okay,
but the best way they
say is submerging you.
There's a submerge one and there's
another one that uses some sort of like
electricity thing,
like you lying in a bed and then I think
the performance institute has that too.
There explain that shit to me. Yeah. Yeah.
The, the, the, the full scanner. Yeah.
I've done that a few times, but
it's much quicker, much easier.
Just to get on the scale and
as long as it's real low,
four and a half percent sounds a
does. But as long as it's, it's uh,
still the same measurement.
You know what I'm saying?
As my last fight for the Tony Fight,
I was five and a half percent on.
So as long as it's in the same with the
same calipers, I mean they're using,
you know that you're basically on point.
Yeah, exactly. I can compare it at least.
Uh, but again I can't get much
that much leaner. You know,
it's mostly just going to come out of
water. If they added 65, then you know, I,
I've got 10 more pounds of water
that I don't have to cut out.
Fucking ridiculous.
How frustrating was it for you going
into that Tony Ferguson fight with that
staph infection because that was a,
that was a serious fall.
I didn't notice it at the weigh ins but
then the moment you walked into the cage,
it was funny man because they were
telling DC don't talk about it cause I was
going that staff that that is fucking
staff. And then they said to DC,
don't talk about it. He goes,
Yup, that looks like staff
to me. He just ignored him.
He was like, fuck you. That's that man.
I don't know why they didn't want
anybody breaking it up because it's an
important point.
It's an unfortunate thing that
happens during training sometimes.
Yeah. Eight a, I kind of noticed
him on a Sunday, you know,
and then Tuesday we do the check ins
and everything and uh, I had the girl,
I'm like, ew, you know,
put some makeup on it because I
didn't want nobody to find out.
And even Tony, you know, I, if he
would have saw it, he would have no,
he knew our compromise all that.
Um, but yeah, it frustrated things.
They make things a lot more complicated.
It put me,
it made the weight cut terrible.
Uh, just to go back to it, I mean,
I'm cutting from 76 to to fifties.
I had to be 55 for that fight and
I try my best to skim it down, uh,
in about 12 hours.
So I woke up at 5:00 AM
with at about one 62.
Uh, and Wayne's are
between nine and 11. Um,
and from 5:00 AM til 8:00 AM I had only
cut one pound compare to in other cuts
that have gone really well.
I'll normally cut by four or five
pounds in that time. But because I,
I just was feeling good and I
wasn't worried about it. And thus,
and I was using the same temperature of
water, I was using the same everything,
but the staff may my
body hold onto the water.
So when I went down and checked and saw
that it was still like five pounds up
with like two hours ago,
they started like throwing a boiling
hot water on me to get my botany. Yeah.
To give me sweat and to get it
off. It was brutal. That's a for,
for know for someone who doesn't,
never, never experienced staff.
Explain what it does to your body.
Yeah.
It makes it feel the next day I just,
I felt so tired. I never felt as
tired in my life. And it felt,
I felt so tired to the point where I tried
to counteract it by getting myself as
pumped as I can. And the, you know,
would you normally get there
two hours before the fight?
When I walked into the arena that night,
two hours before I was in a sweat,
you know,
my body was like full of adrenaline.
Like I wasn't taking any medication.
You weren't going on in antibiotics.
He figured I do have to decide whether
you should take antibiotics and then,
you know,
that compromises your endurance for sure.
Or just let your body fight it off.
I had it before,
so I had been on the antibiotics and
they just make terrible, you know,
if you've ever been through it,
I mean, it's a terrible feeling.
So I'd just like,
you know what,
I think I can just push through it
and I'm young and I was like, fuck it.
Let's just go like,
did you try any like a natural remedies?
You know,
it wasn't a whole lot I could take,
cause I also got to cut the weight still.
Uh, there's not some topical stuff that,
one of the things they say that
works really well, topical,
believe it or not is mince garlic.
Very Long.
Garlic apparently has a tremendous
effect on staph infections.
I was swallowing whole cloves of ginger.
I remember I would take ginger,
I would chop it up and I'll swallow
it to see if that would do some,
but it's hard. Yeah, it's a
heart. There's a lot other cause.
Some real strong antibacterial properties
and one of the people that have been
on the podcast many times
Doctor Rhonda Patrick said she,
she had dealt with some persistent staph
infection and she had like a, you know,
hole in her skin and what she did was
she took garlic and packed it into that
hole. Jen and fucking killed
it. I mean Jesus, I wish I
would've known that before.
I just kind of just fought
through it. I was like, fuck it.
I'm just going to defense soap makes
some really good stuff for that too.
They make us these essential oils.
It's tea tree oil and eucalyptus oil
and you put it on like right where they
have an issue.
Where were you in in October would have
been there for anybody else there that
has that staff.
Anytime you have any sort of a
ring warm or staff or anything,
there's some natural stuff. Not like
some bullshit homeopathic nonsense,
but some actual real natural
stuff that can help you.
And Defense soap specializes
in that because a guy sacco,
the guy who owns the
company, he is, you know,
coaches wrestling and deals with kids
that always have ringworm and staph
infection. So she can, he
came out with these soaps.
He's natural soaps that are
just designed for grapplers.
That's why it's called defense soap.
No.
And then I'll have him send you some and
then the essential oils and balms and
stuff like ointments for
scratches and shit like that.
So they don't get infected.
That's, you know, Jim's, it's,
you're always getting an
infected. Yeah. And that's it.
That was one of the biggest
focuses of this canvas.
Like make sure I stay healthy because
they, if you don't have your health,
you don't have nothing.
And that was what it was at that
Tony fight and it's just, it,
it became something I didn't want to.
It was such a big event and it was my
first real big event to a that I just
wanted it all just to go ride and go over.
But it ended up being just a lot of my,
by the staff originally.
I think it came from mental
stress, you know, it,
it was so many stresses going on,
you know, you really sure. Yeah.
And you look at the three
biggest stressors, you know,
I was going through a divorce and
I had just moved into a house.
You look at those in a normal day to day
life that though those are like the two
biggest stressors,
you can have a then to add on fighting
for a world title in six weeks.
So I'm just like, oh, that's fucking
go. Like I was like, you know,
I wasn't expecting to, I was thinking
maybe a, they was gonna give me Tony,
but maybe in December. Indeed and in
Detroit or if something like that,
but he was like six weeks. I was
like, hi, what fog does, right.
They were thinking about doing you in
Detroit. Right. That was a, that was,
that was the talk. And you were requesting
a big fight in Detroit? Yeah, yeah.
That's where all my life,
you know,
every year I kind of Chore
Plan Out my year and a and a,
and I got my vision in my head.
I got to call them water bulls in there.
That was one of them.
But yeah,
it ended up putting a little bit too much
stress on me all at once and I took on
a lot for that one. But you
did learn, tell you what man,
when you took him down and mounted him
and the first round I was like Holy Shit.
Cause I know how good Tony
is on the ground. You know,
it's interesting because you don't,
you look at someone when they fight,
and this is one of the things that
I've been saying about Khabib. Um,
it's because it's so hard because
he's doing what people do, right?
He's taking people down this
mountain and grounding, pounding.
But he's doing it to people that
other people can't do it too.
And he's doing it in a way that it's like,
wow,
how good is this motherfucker like
when he was mall and Michael Johnson,
I was like, how fucking good
is he? Cause this is crazy.
Like he's in that moment
several better than anybody.
Michael had fought before on the ground.
And when I'm seeing you first of all see
the chaos of fight in right to this day,
I'm like, Jesus fucking Christ. Just
let them go out. Let them go out.
And we would have known, but that
minor controversy from that moment,
you've got to fully locked in rear
naked choke. And he still conscious.
Let them go out. He doesn't want to tap.
Let 'em go out. He, he was going lip.
He was maybe but let them go out. But
you know the fit is it, you can't,
you can't some guys 10 but the
thing is what you're saying,
but I know Hixon camp. Yeah.
But the thing is that the ref,
you can't put that on a Rep.
You know,
it's defend yourself and Ted Intelligent
Mario was that Mario, Mario. But it's,
it's defend yourself.
Defend yourself intelligently.
It all, you can't,
you can't say I'm blocking punches
with my face until the guy gets tired,
you know, you can't say, oh, I'm just
going to try to sleep in this choke.
The guy trying to concentrate on his neck
and just completely tensed up his neck
and try to push blood through. I've
seen guys do that. I know. I feel you,
but only to a point, right. Only to a
point. Right. And then you go to sleep,
go to sleep. Yeah. I mean, yeah, I'm with
you. He could have let them go. But uh,
I think as soon as he,
as soon as Mario saw that his hands went
from fighting the hands to doing this,
Mario stopped it. I mean, and, and I
thought it was a good stop. I mean,
it's not a bad stop it as such,
but it was controversial.
You can call it odd things. Controversy's
always good. I said that right after,
like keep it up, keep it going. Like I
love it. They got you to talk about it.
So about,
this is an undercard fight,
but it became like bigger even then a lot
of the other fights on the car because
of the, yeah, yeah. No, no,
we uh, we headlined that, that
event, you know, that wasn't,
it wasn't, I thought that was like a paper
view. That's right. Yeah, you're right.
I'm sorry it's doing my thing.
But that fight was really like a
top contender for mean chaos. Uh,
had been on a roll.
He's very strong on the ground,
which is one of the reasons why it was
so impressive that you took his back and
choked him like that. Yeah.
I mean, I think I have a
different style than, than, uh,
a lot of people can see, you
know, you, you, you go back
to Khabib and, and all this.
I like, his style is, it's
good. It's obviously very good,
but I can see a lot of holes in it.
And I saw those holes many years ago.
I've been called how big could beat for
years I've been wanting to fight them
just because people got those questions.
I've got those questions too.
So I'm like, let's see what this
motherfucker got like, because I see it,
I see them hoes, you know, I don't really
focus on too much of the good. I'm like,
what holes? I got that boy number.
I'll tell you what are the holes?
What do you see it,
you know,
even though some of his take
on a lot of his takedowns, he,
he misses a lot of them. You know, he's
very square. He kinda just bum rushes.
You know, people were talking about the
Barboza fight before and they're like,
are you looking at that fight and you're
going to try and build off that one?
I'm like, yeah. I mean he
did okay. The fight was good.
He'd beat the hell out of Barboza,
but I saw the holes in it. You know,
he's just running a square for
Adam, you know, he's, he
got hit with a lot of shots.
I didn't see it for people in the outside
watching him because the way he just
came forward on Barboza was like,
he was indestructable
it didn't matter. I'm just going to
get you. It's just a matter of time.
Keep throwing your kicks. I'm going
to get you. I'm going to get you. Ooh,
I got you.
You got those guys. But the body gives
up. You know you got Justin Gates,
you as the same way the body
will give up and met with you.
You can't keep putting your body
on the line like that. I mean,
if he wants to run at me square
four square like that, that's
what I'm getting paid.
I'm getting paid. Oh sorry. I love
the, I love watching him fight,
but part of me is like Jesus man,
just if he mixed what he can do,
cause he's one of the very best
at leg kicks and close that too,
to be in the middle of a combination
like chest to chest with you and then
somehow or another he whips a leg kick
straight down on your leg. I mean,
he's nasty with that.
He's, he's got a couple of things
that he does real good. You know, I,
I've been studying get you too. He's
just, he, he's just hardheaded than him.
He like, he don't, he don't care.
We'll take it. Yeah. He'll just take it
and just walk right into it. But it's,
it seems like we, when you look
at all the skills that he has,
like that would be better represented
with some movement and some foot work and
some other things.
Yeah. Especially with a guy like Trevor
Whitman in this morning and you know,
Trevor's a great, great
coach. He did the rose.
He's been there. I think their
styles are, are very opposite. Uh,
you know, he should probably listen
to him a little bit more, like a,
even one of the things with
me and Robert Falls, you know,
I had been with brother Robert was the,
the pretty much the only reason why
I moved to Vegas, uh, because he,
there's a, there's a weird bond between
a, like a fighter and a coach, you know,
and, and he just got me more
than any other coach before or,
or since we'll, you know,
uh, we were very different,
but he just understood me as
an athlete a little bit more.
And even some of the things that he
would tell me, I wouldn't listen to it.
Like he, you know, maybe like, you know,
he tried to tell me to stay smart and,
you know, not bra, because at the end
of the day, Joe, I could, I'm like,
fuck this, I'm a fight. You know,
I'm a buy down on my mouthpiece.
He tried to get me to be smarter.
Uh,
and just some of the things that he
would say to me resonated way more than
anybody else.
So I think now that he's gone,
I've put what he said, it's still
in my head and it, you know,
I try and follow it even more
now, you know? Uh, and I,
I wish somebody like gates you
wouldn't listen because, you know,
Whitman is telling them what to do,
the right thing to do. He should,
he should probably listen to him.
Well, I think Trevor just
tries to compliment your
style and gauge you styles.
Just savage. He's just, he's just
going to war. We're going to
war every time you go to war.
I guess I get it. Yeah. But you
know, I watch, I think you can,
I think you'd learn from learning
from somebody else, you know,
I think everybody has what
they do that that's like say I,
I try and create a strong team around
me where everybody has what they do and
I'm just going to try and
listen to him, you know, and,
and even more so now it's not,
I understand that a little bit more
as I'm getting older and you know,
going through life too with it. I said,
well rob, you know what, one of the,
one of the reporters there,
he asked me, he was like,
we seen you in there talking and they
thought I was talking to Barboza. Uh,
but I was really just talking to myself
like I was saying things that he would
say or the Robert.
Yeah. Robert was saying,
and I'm saying them to myself
and I guess my mouth was moving.
I don't really know. I thought it was
in my head the whole time, but, uh,
I guess like some of the reporters
could see it. Uh, but you know,
I really tried to make that a focus on.
Interesting.
So do you do that in sparring
too? Uh, I don't, I don't know.
I usually try. And did you realize you
were doing it until they brought it up?
I didn't realize. I know and not
because he, when he asked me that,
it kind of caught me off guard
because I remember in the fight I'm,
I'm very cerebral. I, I, I
remember everything about it. Uh,
but I remember I was going to say
something to Barboza to, you know,
I talking my shit, you know, I
do it in quite some time to time,
but it didn't cause he was a nice guy.
I didn't realize that I was
talking to myself too on it. Even.
So you were just kind of going through
the things that you wanted to focus on in
the fight while it was happening and
like stay, you're saying even the kick,
the kick that he landed,
if you see like a microsecond before
that I was nodding my head because I was,
I was, I took my mind off them for a
split second. I saw the knock out there,
I seen him dip to his left and I'm
like, oh, next time he did, so I'm,
I'm about to get it.
So I started to talk and I was like,
ah.
I like,
I got this and I took my mind off of him
and he hit me with that fucking spin.
But what it should have said was stay
sharp, you know, stay, stay focused.
Like that's what I was saying in the
fourth and the fifth round after that kick
landed, I was like, stay
sharp. Stay focused on him.
I'm just saying that to myself
because that's what Robert told me.
He wouldn't tell me to
look for the knockout.
What was the thought process when you're
going to face a guy like Barboza that's
such a dangerous kicker.
Was it a lot of faints plus pressure?
Like what was the thought process about
getting close to him with a guy like
Barboza, he throws everything
so hard and so explosive.
I knew I was going to have
to eat some of that, uh,
and just keep pushing forward and
just not take my eyes off of him.
Even when I got wobbled and I was wrong,
I just try not take my eyes off of him,
you know, with, with a, with a guy like
that, that's such a great athlete. Uh,
which is what I considered Barboza as
you know, rob had these three things.
He put everybody in an athlete,
a competitor or fighter category,
and Barboza was like apitomy of
an athlete. Uh, but with that,
you can't show him no,
you can't show him that he's doing good.
You know what I'm saying? So every
time you was stolen, and I'm just like,
that fucking switch kick is ridiculous.
He's got the most ridiculous,
which kicking the game so fast,
Mark Della Grotto,
who's seen some of the best of
the best fight in Thailand, in,
in real, you know, in life. And
like right there in person, he said,
I've never seen a guy with a faster
switch kick. He was even the top,
the most elite of the ties. He
goes, that's the fastest way.
Everyone's saying they're tired tire.
I'm, I beat the hell out of him.
And he was still thought,
I was like,
how is this even possible to even
in the third and fourth round swap?
And some of it, I'm kind of like
looking while I'm in there, I'm like,
what is he doing that can make
him do that? You know? Uh,
I try and steal a little bit from
every guy that a fight especially,
and I'm like, what is he doing as allowing
him to be that Goddamn fast with it?
But you know, I prepare, I prepare with
a lot of high level kickboxers that,
you know, they got that
style, that kicking it.
Just kick it fucking block
off if you let them. Yeah.
You're going to get something from that.
Right?
Like the little [inaudible] calls
it the rub and then your fight.
Someone's real good. You get that rub from
him, from him. You just realize now, oh,
those kids could come at you that
fast. Yeah. Yeah. I mean, and,
and you get that in a lot of different
ways. Uh, like, like with Tony, you know,
Tony did a lot of things in there
that I didn't expect and I didn't,
you know,
didn't really plan for it.
It's only so much planning that you can
do until you get in there and you need
that experience to rely back on.
And I feel like that's what I'm
building up at a young age. Even.
It's possible for you to rematch with
Tony Ain't got to get touch with Tony now
coming off of that very disappointing
fall, you know when he was,
which is crazy. I feel bad for her to do
say something to, this is very important.
And I actually have pictures
too. I'm going to send them
to you right now, Jamie.
So we could put it online because uh,
everybody was repeating the,
the,
the thought that he had worn sunglasses.
Um, and that's why he fell down,
um, that he was wearing sunglasses,
his little AP wearing them
little misspoke. He misspoke.
And he said it too.
I think he said my prescription
sunglasses to Ariel Helwani.
I think that's what they were saying.
The square ones that he wears a,
I'll send it. I'm going to send it
to Jamie right now, but it wasn't,
but he was probably wearing sunglasses.
No photos.
Totally. I'll find it. God Damn
it. Tony loves those songs.
I know. He does love the,
okay. I know where it is. Um,
he does love the sunglasses.
Don't, he's a smart guy. You
know, I, I don't, I don't, I
don't hold that against him.
He was probably something that was already
injured in his leg and I feel bad for
the guy and I really do.
I don't think you'll ever be the same.
Coming back off that one. The, that's
a big, you know, I hear detached.
It detached them for the
loan. I mean, that's huge.
Especially at 34 to try and come
back off that that's it's going to,
and it kind of sucks for me too,
because I think I fought the best.
Tony Ferguson that you're going to
see a period. Really? You think so?
Because it was before that injury.
Yeah.
I don't think he's going to
be the same again after any,
he'll come back and he'll still beat
a great guys. You know, he's still,
he's still going to do very good. But
you know, I don't think it be the same.
And you know,
dammit, I got this photo in
here somewhere. I'm going
to find it. I can't find it.
I'll send it to you later.
But in the photo he's wearing glasses.
He's not wearing per se.
He's not wearing prescription sunglasses.
He said he misspoke and said
prescription sunglasses.
That's why Dana told me Shane is ruthless.
Dana goes,
everybody who wears sunglasses should
have inside should have that happen.
This is after this huge fight fell apart.
What probably about right dude.
It was funny though. Yeah. But um,
it wasn't,
he wasn't wearing sunglasses.
Yeah. I mean I just want to clear it up
for Tony that I, like I say, I mean I,
I feel bad for them.
I really do.
I think the good news is you can come
back from that injury. That's an injury.
You can come back at 34 especially with
the way he trains. I mean, I think he,
I think the body can come back.
It's just,
I don't know if his mind will
let him be as free as it.
That was one of Tony's biggest assets
to the style is he was, I mean,
he just does whatever the fuck he wants,
you know?
And now when he gets back in here, is
he going to be thinking about, is knee,
even if that's in the back of
your mind, it's still, it's,
it's limited on that type of style
that he, that he likes to fight
maybe, or maybe you just
fucking with his head right now.
He planted some seeds. Kevin
Lee, you never know. Here's
some money to be made. Joe.
I gotta be, I gotta
get it. I understand it
be out for quite a while.
I would imagine he won't be able to
even really train hard for six months.
Yeah. At least. At least. Yeah. He's
at least a year or so. Uh, I'll, I'll,
I'll let us send me when I look at
that and I see that fight and just,
you know, how much different
shit could be now. You know, uh,
head I went into that fight healthy.
Especially I think the,
the entire division would look different,
but I'm a correct all that in a little
bit. Let me, let me get my hands. Oh,
could be first.
Yeah.
Well it's interesting me,
you're in the running now for sure.
And before this fight, I think you were
a slight underdog in the Barboza fight.
Yeah. But after that
domination, I mean, you,
you for sure more moved up and
you're in the running now 100%.
So you got poor Yay.
Who just looked real good against Gagey
and won that fight after getting his
legs chewed up. Yup. Um, and
then you've got, but you know,
poor Yay of course was knocked
out by Michael Johnson.
And then you've got you coming off of the
loss to Tony Storm the gates with this
fight.
And then you've got Eddie Alvarez who
look great against Justin Gagey that it's
very hot. Yeah. And
Connor is going to jail.
Wait,
who knows what's happened?
I think that's the x factor is what's
happening. What Kotter. Yeah. Uh,
I mean Dustin is out there. He,
he, but I just don't see, no,
I'm speaking as it from a fan.
You know, I just don't see no, uh,
upsize today. You know what I mean? To
you fighting him? No, no, no. To, to,
to him make a beep. I mean, they
can make it happen and it can be,
we'll go out there and he'll smoke them.
I mean, they should be real here, but uh,
I just don't see many
fans getting behind that.
Just from what does [inaudible] bring
to the table that could be made already
seen.
This is big fight right
now. I mean, just being completely honest,
the big fire right now is Khabib and
con 100% sure. That's the big fight.
Whatever. Take five or either Madison
Square Garden. I mean, they, they can,
they can make that happen.
I don't think New York has ever letting
that mother fucker fuck there again.
I just don't think they're going to
do that. They don't play games, man.
Then athletic commissions,
a different commission and they're new to
MMA and that was embarrassing for them.
I mean him throwing the fucking Dolly
and the fact that they let them get in
there with all his boys and the whole
thing was just so thuggish and didn't,
the thing at Bella [inaudible] happened
in was that in New York? In New Jersey,
what thing happened in Beltour where he,
where he went over and slap
Goddard and audit a cop.
People bitches and hoes and it was that,
I want to say that was an Ireland
or England. Was it an Ireland?
I think it was in England.
I want to say it was in London.
Wasn't that the bell toward London Card?
I don't know.
But that got her thing was crazy.
I felt like that happened.
Don't on the east coast too, but I mean
if that was one, neither waist too.
It's like he just keeps fucking up with
this kind of stuff and and you know,
no one's saying get rid of him, you know,
he's just, he's worth so much money.
It's really fascinating.
What I was saying is,
imagine if Ray Borg and him switch sides.
If Ray pour it showed up with all his
boys and was screaming and yelling and
through a Dolly at the window.
It's done. Done deal for. Yeah.
Ray Paul Daley.
Paul Daley must be at home going,
hey, look, it's starting phase.
It's certain things that we just,
Kay, do you know Paul, I'm sorry,
until you get to that
stratosphere that Conor McGregor,
it's like there's so much money
to be made. That's the problem.
It's like the rules get
Bet Paul Paul Daley was,
did was throw a punch as he was Josh
Koscheck after it didn't even connect.
That could have been sorted out.
Yeah. And you even heck, I was like,
we'll Brooks kinda got the hammer
put down on them. Dinny uh,
after he got knocked out
and then push the ref. Uh,
I think what that will Brooks, I'm
sorry. I don't know. I don't know.
You're looking at me funny
on it. I'm thinking, right.
It was somebody, you know,
he got knocked out and then push the rep
right out there and it's like they put
a lot on. Oh No, it wasn't well
books. I'm sorry it was a god.
What's that many ponder. Hmm. I
know who you're talking about.
God dammit. Who was that?
God, this is going to kill me.
Sorry.
Yeah.
And they held them against him and he
was concussed. You know, you didn't know.
You barely know where you
at. He said, Jason, I it's,
that's what it was. Yeah. See,
great fighter too.
He's a very good fighter and when people
don't understand is that once you get
knocked out and then you come back, you
really don't know what happened. You're,
you're really out of it. Yeah. Who knocked
him out? It was no soft gels. Right.
So Angelo's welterweight
debut, right? 55 still.
She had 55 still. Yeah. Yeah. But
again, he was great fighter on me.
It's just certain things that,
oh, well we just can't do Jo.
We meaning people of color.
I don't want to say it that way.
They can do it though.
I do think it's people with that there's
a level to the game where you are so
valuable that you like if Conor
McGregor does a pay per view fight,
especially if they do,
you heard all that crazy nonsense
they're going to do with Mcgregor.
Like no shoes. You can clinch
but no kicks, no take downs.
Know if they ever did that. Greg going to
digital printing money, printing money,
but so hard for them to
not take that money. But
I mean, and it, and I don't
hold that against them.
And I always said that about the UFC.
Do you see about the green? And I,
and I understand that and uh, that's
kind of where I'm coming from it from,
but he, you know, it's just
consistency. Yeah. Well you,
I think you just have to realize as a,
as a, as a black man in America really,
like there's two ways to
approach the situation.
You need to be the victim or you
can just say it is what it is.
That some circumstances, you know, uh,
by people just don't support other black
people to way to iris support the Irish,
the Russia support. I mean, I'm
just being real with you. That's
reality is white people in America don't
support white Americans the way the
Irish support Connor, nobody does
100% and it's an American thing.
I mean when he was fighting,
when he was fighting Mayweather,
did you see the fucking,
the people that were in Mandalay bay,
which wasn't even where
the was taking place,
the entire place was flooded
with people singing together.
When he fought dust import. Yay.
At one 78 they kept me up all for,
I was on the undercard it up by,
it kept me up all fucking
night sitting in the MGM.
They were running up and down the,
the, the, the halls of the MGM leads.
The security couldn't stop them. I mean
they had to crazy to rabbit, but that's,
that's what's gonna.
I mean obviously he had a great
performance is on top of it for sure.
But that definitely helps.
You know what I mean?
When your first fight in
the UFC debut is in Boston.
Nick going crazy for you
like that. You just don't see
that much. Uh, and it's sad.
Really. Uh, you, you talk
about Floyd Mayweather,
really how Floyd got big like that is he
had to go against the Mexicans and you
know, he had to get them to really
hate them in order to get big.
Exactly, yes. But that's also his style.
Whereas Connor style's very
different cause he knocks guys dead.
It's a different style. You know, like
may remember when Tyson was in his prime,
you knew no one was kind of beat them.
It was just,
you're waiting to see the executions
where you were just a little boy at the
time. Probably weren't even
born. My pops was like,
what time were you born in [inaudible]
92. Yeah. See Jesus Christ,
you missed everything. Well, my positive,
they used my title. I'm a huge boxing fan,
so you know, I go back, I would have
92. That's a huge boxing fan. Yeah.
Just all of these, the UFC
actually, so that's crazy right.
It pretty much a year after you
were born. It started. Yeah man.
But the Tyson days, he was the biggest
paper you draw it, but it was really just,
you were watching an execution
and there was also like,
people were thinking like, man,
is this going to be worth it?
How long has this one going to last?
He's still, but he's still, he was, he
had to be the a little bit, you know,
and that's the every, and it, I mean, I,
it sucks to say it was just like
every real big black fighter.
Is it usually the villain, you know, and,
and that, that's the way that it was not,
but that's not American. He's, and he's
British. That's different, you know,
he's totally different. Totally
different. Totally different atmosphere.
And I mean,
this was the last time we had a really
loved African American fighter in
America. I mean, they're there,
they're out there. I mean,
for sure people love roadshows.
Peter Jones love.
And people love Muhammad
Ali after, uh, you know,
but even Roy Johnson Shit for
being cocky. Oh, for sure.
Because he was so dominant. But that's
the culture though. You gotta be cocky.
You gotta be,
you gotta be all those things.
Like even the way I talk a lot of shit.
But that's just,
that's just because that's the culture.
Like that's what I do. I mean, well,
it's also an effective mind,
mind games strategy,
like a guy who's talking shit to you.
It makes you more anxious,
more nervous, more emotions,
more everything. Certain guys,
you know, there's certain guys that
you can play that too. Like I said,
everybody's got like those three
categories, you know, with athletes,
especially athletes and competitors,
you know, they Kinda, you know,
get more shooken up by stuff like that.
Fall fire ideas. He don't give a fuck.
Like, he likes me. I like
it a little bit more.
Connor, you could tell he
likes it a little bit more. Uh,
it gets my mind off the actual fight
itself because that's what we grew up like
talking shit, you know, so it's, some
guys do, it rattles them. You know,
the best I've ever seen the best response
to someone. Shit-Talking Rose Nama.
Eunice. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. She,
she massive, full dark master full.
She went like that like a month. I'm
a huge role is fair. She's, yeah,
she's dope.
Might be the best looking girl in the UFC.
And she shaves her fucking head and never
wears makeup. She doesn't give a fuck.
I mean it's crazy. Yeah. And she, I mean,
and a phenomenal, phenomenal fighter.
I,
but just when she was standing in front
of Yolanda and she was citing the Lord's
prayer,
gangster man coming to get you
and the boogie man and she's like,
our father in heaven, hallowed be thy
name of gangster shit. You ever light?
It's like crazy. She made me
nervous. I'm a big fan of next door.
That's where the thing with, uh, you know,
people look at my style even of the way
I promoted her and all the talk fights
and, you know, Talk Shit or whatever.
Uh, but there's so many ways to do it.
You know, there's so many ways to like
entertain at hit, have fun with it.
You don't always have to be almost smack
the shit out of your Mama and all that.
Right. You know, it's, there's
so many different ways you get,
you can not say anything.
It'd be come off just as fucking is.
You know the dude this screaming from
across the room with there is a pressure,
right?
Isn't there a pressure on fighters to sal
and hype fights to talk a lot of shit.
I mean, you see seen Colby Covington
taking it off the deep end. He goes,
he goes so crazy. I don't even
think they let him go to Brazil.
Like when I heard he was
gonna Fight Dos Anjos
in Brazil, I was like, no, Colby.
I was thinking of reaching out and
telling people like to call it,
bring your own water, whatever you do. I
mean, I guess he's doing his thing. He,
he's still winning fights.
Yeah. So at the end of the day,
that's what really matters is that
he's winning fights. But yeah,
I mean that's got us talking about him.
He's got us talking about that too.
But that style on me is, is that should
get played out and you could just,
you could just tell it when it,
when it's forced is not good.
You know what I mean?
He just goes, he goes against
people. He doesn't have to, like,
he was talking some shit about Jon Jones.
Jon Jones will smack you in your fucking
face and there's not much you're going
to be able to do about it.
One day you might be in front of him and
then when are you going to do, you know,
I mean just that you're not
even fighting Jon Jones.
Why you talking Shit about John?
Yeah. I don't make any sense. I don't
know a couple people, even even females,
like he started to, I
mean, I guess he's, he,
he's just trying to get the
noise running or whatever.
I just think it's so many
different ways to do it. That's,
that's like the most primitive way of,
you know,
kind of trying to sell yourself and
sell a fight. It's like so many ways.
Like even me, like I came up with a lot
of the shit that I started doing it.
I just like kind of came up with, you
know, like in the moment. Yeah. Just,
well before the, the, the, the, the
first big one was the [inaudible] thing,
you know, where I kind of hit him at the
press conference. Uh, but going into that,
my mindset wasn't like all let me,
you know, talk as much shit as I can
about them, you know, or let me, you know,
jump up and down and all
this, you know, it just was,
I did have that I wanted to stand out,
not necessarily that I want to entertain.
I just was like, I'm on, I wanted to stay.
I'm sitting behind fucking Jon Jones and
Daniel Cormier like I'm like a kid in a
candy store, you know? Uh, so I just,
I wanted to stand out as much as possible.
And you know,
now the dom had a few of these big fights,
right?
The Kia sulfite was a high profile fight
and then of course the 25 was a very
high profile. And then this last
Barboza fight was a real big fight.
Do you feel like now you've like settled
more into the fact that not only do you
do, do you belong here,
you deserve to be here,
but you're more comfortable being here.
Yeah, there's a, there's that saying
like the fake it till you make it
hyper real,
like that's not a joke in it.
When did you feel like you were fee?
We obviously you would never really
faking it because you were winning fights.
I exaggerate. It is her, you know,
like I exaggerated shorty, this shit.
Like I was having fun with it,
but I was kind of learning on the job
too because like doing interviews and
stuff like that, it takes some,
it's, it's hard to get to your level.
Like you are very likely I listen to
your show all the time. Like I love it.
Thank you. But you are like
very good at it, you know?
And it takes a long time to do that. I
had to kind of learn on the job. So yeah,
I would exaggerate a little bit
too much here and there. But, uh,
the fake it till you make it thing like
I think it's a lot of people hear that
and they like take it, take it like
negatively all the time. You know,
I always heard that not to
get positive, you know, uh,
I've read George Saint Pierre his
book and he talked about that a lot.
He texted me two days before this fight
with Barboza and he was talking about,
you know, giving me some tips
and pointers and all that.
But the last thing he said to me was,
you know,
you're going to have that fear
when you go before you go in there,
but once you get in there, your body's
just going to turn the autopilot.
Just fake it till you make it fake
the confidence until you make it.
That's how he approaches it. That's
interesting. That's interesting. Fight.
What it was is like I said, going
into that press conference especially,
I wanted it to stand out and through the
rest of my life in Detroit especially,
I was always taught like, don't stand
out as much as you can. Like I was like,
I was like stay low and keep moving.
Chill. Like keep your head now like that,
you know, don't focus business businesses,
done folks, business, you know,
I always stayed on what I'm doing,
you know, always kind of had a vision,
always had to go.
So it,
my opposite was to stand out so I
had to kind of fake it till I am not
necessarily fake it till you make it,
fake it til I became it,
you know what I'm saying?
And I think it was right after the Tony
fight where I was like maybe the two
months it took me to get over it.
At that moment I was like, man,
I really like to have that confidence
to to, you know, I do have like,
I don't have to fake it. You know what
I'm saying? The Tony that Tony Fight,
I mean your, your podcast
too. I mean you'll park has,
has been huge to me.
I mean this and it's,
it's hard for me to really explain
it. You know, when me just growing up,
like I didn't have a lot of confidence,
you know,
like people see me and see me in
interviews and they just think that just,
that's how it was.
But I would lose a lot of my wrestling
matches as a kid just because I thought
that,
and this might like alienator alienates
some people and it might sound like off,
but it's just the way I grew up is
the white boys above eight mile,
you know, they got the money that
they're working harder than you,
they're better than you. So that was
kind of like my mentality kind of.
Even when I started wrestling and like
these kids start wrestling with your five,
I started wanting to 16 and they
just would beat me and then be like,
I couldn't even, I wouldn't even
really compete with them, you know,
it took me to go to
college, uh, B because I,
that was my first real explosion
of white people. That's how,
like I obviously knew white
people went out to get, you know,
we the teachers and stuff, you
know, but nobody around my same age,
you know what I'm saying?
So when I got around and there,
there's one school in particular,
Detroit Catholic Central,
they were number one school in, in, in
Michigan at the time, but they were, uh,
so in Detroit, every mile is, is numbered.
I was born and raised
pretty much all seven mile,
eight mile is like the divider
between the suburbs and the city.
These kids were like on 26 miles. So they
were like, wait, he'll tell like with,
you know, rich regional are,
uh, so I just, I don't know,
for some reason I just didn't
have the confidence. Uh,
but when I got around them and I started
living in kind of training together
every day and I realized, I'm
like, we all the same, you know,
like he works as just as hard as I
can see him every day, you know, he's,
I see him going, it's a class and
I see them going through it too.
Is Allison it that moment gave me
the confidence to be like, okay,
I can't compete with them. W W
W with other people, you know,
I can't compete with anybody.
Really.
Your podcast was like the
next step to that, you know,
that was me at the collegiate level.
The of the first podcast I heard
from you was the Lance Armstrong one.
And I was like, this is
like world level, you know?
And when I hear him talking, I hear
him talk so candidly and I'm like, oh,
he's just a normal dude. You
know what I mean? He's just,
I guess in my head I didn't
have that before. You know?
And it's like we all the same and that
really has allowed me to go over to
Ireland and compete to go down
to Brazil and get Pete to,
to fight the best kick boxer in the world
and not have that and still had that
same confidence. You know
what I'm saying? Right.
I see what you're saying.
Like you just hearing people talk and
realizing that we're all just human. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. But all the sudden you
see some superstar and whatever,
whatever their field is,
whether it's a musician or whatever,
you just assume that person has got to
be like a different thing than you. This,
you know, if you see Mick
Jagger or something like that,
that gets gotta be a different thing than
me. Yeah. He's not the same thing as me.
And, and the thing with, uh,
and I started the Hashtag like 25 to life
and all that be mostly because the way
I grew up, I didn't get to
see many successful people.
You know what I'm saying?
I didn't have him. I, it's, it's,
uh, nobody ever told me, Oh,
you can't do this. You know what I'm
saying? But nobody ever told me. Yeah.
Could either.
And nobody showed you other people
that were doing it right around you,
where you could learn from them,
had no examples. You know,
the only examples, literally,
only examples I had was,
was the dope man. You know, the,
the, the Jag Boys, you know, the,
the pimps and you know,
you didn't really have much else to
really look forward to. So when I was,
I thought when I was 25 like burning
him now, I thought for sure I'm
just going to be in
jail like that is that,
that's one of the most important points
when people talk about people being able
to pull themselves up by their bootstraps
and they should just get a job and
they should just do this. Like you say
that because you grew up around that,
but if you didn't grow up
around anybody doing that,
like your feeling that you feeling
the way you felt when you were around
wrestlers that had been
competing their whole lives.
You didn't feel like you belong there.
You didn't have any of
that at success around you.
That's that is one of the most important
things in life is surrounding yourself
with positive people. It's so difficult
to do if you're in a bad place.
If you grew up in a bad neighborhood
and you're surrounded by bad people,
very few people have the vision to see
past that and they have no examples.
Yeah, I mean you see someone on
television again, you're going to think,
that's not me. Like, still to
this day when I meet a rock star,
I still get word of it. I still
get weirded out. Doesn't matter how
famous you get, you get weirded
out and run other famous people.
They just don't seem like you,
you know?
And especially when you kind of grow
up in that environment and you know,
is you don't really, you know, you
see a doctor on TV and you don't,
you just don't connect with
it, you know, at least for me,
like that's what I wanted to be. I wanted
to be a doctor, uh, first, but I didn't,
you know, I didn't live in
neighborhoods with doctors. You know,
I didn't meet a doctor when I did.
He was like some old dude and it's like
he didn't really give a fuck. Like,
he's like, you know, your mom, you know,
you're on Medicaid motherfucker. Like,
you know, take it 35 bucks and
get the fuck off. But, you know,
uh, Eh, I,
I think that is a big point of it is just
to have somebody to tell you that you
can, you know what I'm
saying? So at least I tried.
And then to see people around
you that are working hard,
succeeding and emulate them
and learn from them people,
we don't exist in a vacuum. We
exist in communities. And that's,
this is something that it's very difficult
to people for people to understand if
they're in a good community,
if you're in a good community
or if you're in a bad community,
it's difficult to understand to the
value of a good community, 100%.
And I think one of the biggest things
is just that integration is like really
important.
Like,
and I'm starting to see that the more
I'm getting out and kind of seeing the
world and seeing the way things run and
kind of comparing that to the way I grew
up. And it's just like there
was no, there was so much.
It's just seems so segregated to me.
Uh,
which is a weird term to use
and this day and age, you know?
But it just did like literally not the,
I remember because my mom, she did a
good job of keeping us in good schools,
you know, so our school was on 10
mile, which was in the suburbs.
I went to Southfield high. Uh, I remember
a couple of times, me and my brother,
we would try and walk to the school.
So you had to walk pass through eight
mile and a policeman had pulled over three
or four times,
picked us up in the car and took us back
across and they dropped us off and just
like you don't, and it's like we go
to school there, you know what I mean?
Like they didn't believe you and
not a [inaudible]. We, you know, we,
we were also like, the best I can give is
probably starting to solve it. You know,
you're up to no good. Yeah, yeah,
we do. But you know, I have to,
but I feel like that integration,
if it's just, it's just really,
really important and I'm starting to
see that the more I'm getting out and
learning in the world, it's all
the same. Literally all the same.
All the same like, and everything
for sure, but we're all just people,
you know,
and,
and sometimes having all those advantages
when you're young is a disadvantage
because the hungriest most determined
people are the people that had nothing at
one point in their life when they
understand what nothing means. Yeah. Yeah.
And I mean, I think I attribute that to
a lot of my success and that's what I,
I always keep in the back of my head,
you know,
it's especially going through college,
like such a rough, like, you know,
20 bucks a week as a vibe. Delpha. And
I was, I was fighting for the time.
I was taking 15 credits.
Uh, I was wrestling still at
the same time, like, and I just was on the
hustle. I was moving up the grind. Yeah.
Super Grind, but on nothing.
Like, you know, I had like a, uh,
1996,
a Thunderbird would like 300,000 miles
and I was Bernadette Shit over here every
day. Uh, but I keep that in the back of
my head. Even now. Like, I don't, I don't,
I don't never get comfortable,
never get contented.
When I think about that with having kids
because I have young kids and I think
my kids have never known like
that kind of financial struggle.
Like I think financial
struggle in particular,
something that just to this day I still
think about being broken. It just, it, it,
it motivates me. Like I'll, I'll
never slack off because I just,
I think if you haven't,
but also like when you have kids,
you don't want your kids to struggle.
It's like all my friends that are
interesting, all I've fucked up lives,
all of them, everyone,
everything went crazy.
Everyone was fucking abused
or someone was an asshole.
The alcoholics or drug addicts and
their family. Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah.
They're on the fun ones and they're all
my favorite people and they use it as
motivation to learn the
world and learn things.
And that's what I kind of did as a,
as a kid.
I kind of took a look
around when I was maybe 15.
I was probably like the,
the time that really clicked for
me when I found him in May and I,
and I kind of saw that this
is what I want to do. Uh,
that's when it kinda
clicked how she's like,
I don't want to be around like light
the rest of these motherfuckers here.
How'd you get started? Where'd
you, where'd you find a
good gym? So when I was 15,
I just,
uh,
I saw George Saint Pierre and Bj Penn
was the first time I'd seen a fight.
And you know,
there was no MMA gyms
or anything like that.
I had just went out for
the rest of the team at,
at the high school because I was
already there and all that. So, uh,
I didn't start really getting into MMA
and until I came back from college or one
year from college and,
uh,
I wanted to sign up for a Jujitsu
tournament and I had never trained it or
anything. I went and signed up for a
Jujitsu tournament and the guy's like,
oh yeah, we do some fights on, on the,
the sermon was Sunday. And he was like,
we do some fights on Saturday and uh,
there's nobody, uh, you know, for this,
for this guy. I was like, fuck
that motherfucker right now. Like,
and I never tried before. I just wrestled.
So I was like, yeah, please sign.
It was like Tuesday. I had,
how old are you? 18. Yeah.
So I just showed up, you
know, no mouthpiece. No,
I didn't know you needed a
mouthpiece or cup or anything,
like have a car yet to do that fall.
It was like 26 and I just went, well,
they went to a Walmart,
uh, because as I've,
as I'm getting ready to step into
the octagon to go, it was like,
where's your mouthpiece and
cup? And I was like, what?
Like prepare for a wrestling match, I
guess. And they ran through Walmart,
grabbed me one it,
I'll beat the fuck out it.
Did you have any striking at all?
What I saw on the TV?
Oh my God, I didn't really have real
training until I got into the, uh,
until I got over to, I mean,
I trained hard, uh, with,
with one of my coaches.
I had,
Sean did say he was my first true coaching
in Michigan and we trained hard, uh,
and he, he showed me a lot
of things. He was a boxer,
so he showed me a lot of things. Um, but
I didn't really have a real, you know,
I was still a full time student and when
I got the call from the UFC, you know,
I got the call in like December and
finals. I got the call like finals week.
And I was like, well shit, let me,
let me go ahead and bust out
these vitals and then, you know,
I'm done with this shit. Uh, and then
the fight was like late January, I think,
or so. So I was like a full
time student when I took the,
I was taking 15 credits as a med student.
So you really only had like a couple of
years of striking at that point. Yeah,
yeah. If that, yeah. You know, a lot
of wrestling and a lot of, you know,
I didn't really get it really good.
It's a striking until I got over to
Vegas and work with Dewey Cooper.
That makes it even more impressive man.
You know that you've been able to make
such a big leap in such a short amount of
time. I mean that's your were
talking about like seven years that,
I mean that's really,
that's really crazy
consistency. I think consistency
is the key. Like I love,
I actually love this shit.
Like I got the most fights, uh,
in the lightweight division
since my debut, the anybody else.
And it's just cause I stay consistent. I
keep my body healthy, I keep showing up.
And you know, the more you see things
coming at you, the, the, the better gift.
You know,
that's definitely a factor. But I
think it's also intelligence, the,
the understanding of your also,
like there's,
there's different kinds
of intelligence too.
And there's intelligence of like how to
get good at things. And some people just,
I don't know if it's a physical thing,
if their body works better or if it's
just that they are able to see how someone
does something and listen to instruction
and then break it down and put it
together. But I've seen in little kids,
man, when I used to teach little kids,
there was little kids that weren't even
like physically town does not like the,
they were gymnasts.
They could do back flips and shit.
They do crazy shit with their body.
There's some kids where you would
show him like, see this foot,
this foot's got pivot, and then
you're, it's all about your hips.
And they would see you and they would go,
okay.
And then you'd see them breaking it down.
And then other kids, oh, the fucking,
they just couldn't see
what you were doing there.
Throw their feet up in their air,
their foot would never pivot.
They're putting all this pressure on the
knee. Like, what? Whoa, Whoa, whoa. Don't,
don't do that. Don't do that.
You got to turn your hips,
your foot's got to go with it.
And then some people just could
mirror you see in Jujitsu too.
Yeah, yeah, for sure. Big Time and Jujitsu
and grapple and especially, you know,
grappling, wrestling it. They just see
it. I think it's, I think it's come,
like you said, it's a,
it's an intelligence there.
There's people think it's just a brute, no
thing that you're doing. But it's, it's,
it's very, you know, at least
from me, like our approach,
it kind of like a science.
It's almost is a, B, c, d, e
you know, I go from here. If,
if, if not, then I branch off.
I have different systems for every
kind of a situation that will arise,
but I, I kind of approach
it like a scientist. Like I
went to school if a biomed,
like that kind of stuff interests me,
you know what I mean?
Like there's art to it. There's a,
there's a huge, huge portion of it.
That's our expression. Yeah. The
expression part is his art and I
think it's one of the pure as art forms
fighting this, make sure that there is,
you know, if someone looks great
doing it, that is like a form of art.
Oh 100% a hundred percent I think it's,
I,
I get so irritated whenever somebody
says is not there because I get so
irritated. Like, did you see Beltour
when Gaston Bolanos landed that uh,
insane spinning elbow. It's like one of
the greatest spinning elbows of all time.
She said Shit about 80 times.
I just play it back like I'm watching a
flower bloom or watching a fucking eagle
soar. It's just, he lands this,
he just, the dude's coming at him,
he steps and she's had the perfect face
plants. I'm like, that shit is just art.
That's art.
But even when you see like a really,
really high level fighter move around,
every one of our bodies moves different,
you know, every, you know, yeah.
You, you, you go back to, you know,
being able to see somebody in emulate it,
but you still will put your own
style on it. You still put you on.
Nobody moves the same,
you know?
And I think that's what
makes it a pure art form.
And I think MMA is more so even the
boxing because in boxing you only got two
hands, right? It's a science,
you know, it's the sweet science.
There's only so many combinations
that you can even put together that.
But when you, when you talk about
something that you know, without limit,
then there's so much art that goes
into, it's like dance. It's like,
it's like yoga.
It's like all these things that are really
the truest form of art I think. Yeah.
I couldn't agree more, you
know? And that's why I was
mad at Mel's Meryl Streep.
Yeah.
Know she doesn't know anything
about mixed martial arts,
not VR.
They are the arts 100%.
And I think the most purest form of it
to, uh, what else did you call arts,
if not that it's not simply
to understand what it is.
And one of the things that they don't
understand is that it's so difficult to do
and that your,
when you see the finished product,
when the person steps into the
cage and competes that night,
you're not just seeing these brutish
moves. You're seeing their soul.
You're seeing how much focus,
where they are as a human
in their life at this point.
Where's the vitality of their body?
What kind of martial arts
education have they gotten?
How technically aware then how much did
they think about the training? Did they,
if they're a wrestler, did they
only concentrate on the wrestling?
Did they stay away from striking cause
they don't like getting hit if they're a
striker,
did they only concentrate on staying up
or did they learn how to fight on the
ground?
Did they absorb it all?
Did they develop a full repertoire
of expression with their body,
throwing bones and choking each other?
I mean,
and at the same time going through life
through the whole situation, you know,
kind of because the hardest part,
like at the end of the day I was
still a 25 year old dude. Like,
I'm still like learning and shit and try
to keep it together like everybody else.
So,
and I'd be like that when you're 80 men
rally and we look at these 80 year old
people who say, well that guy
should have his shit together,
that fucking guys better today than he
was yesterday. If I was paying attention,
I think that he had to go back. And I
think that's what it is to at the of it.
I always think that everybody
else has their shit together.
I just saw sold everybody all
childhood, 100%. I think one it was,
I had the same problem.
I think everybody has their shit
together and everybody can see that.
I don't feel like they can see my flaws.
And it keeps me sharp though.
Like it translates to fight and too,
it's like if my hand calls
here for a split second,
I feel like the guy can see it, you know
what I mean? Or why not throw something.
I'm, I feel like he's gonna be there
to block it or, you know, it makes,
it makes me stay sharp, but, uh, it's,
it goes up from sometimes outside
of life too, you know? Well,
it's good that you think like this because
clearly you're a very confident guy
and you're obviously successful and
you're mixed martial arts career.
But to have just a little bit
of that insecurity is fuel.
It's just like, he keeps you sharp.
It keeps you aware, you know,
like to be confident is good, to
be delusional is terrible. Yeah.
100% terrible.
Everybody knows that one guy that thinks
he can beat a guy that he's not ever
going to fucking be able to be. You know?
I mean, there's a lot of people like,
give me that fight. I'll, oh yeah,
wait, no, that's why
you don't see, you know,
you never see me say some outlandish
shit. Like, oh, I can't never be beat or,
you know, or I'm, oh, I can go out there
and, you know, our bar, Cain Velasquez,
you know, or something like that. I
mean, not meaning to pick on Ron, but uh,
I know he was saying, yeah, but
you know, but I think, you know,
the Rhonda thing was there was a lot
going on there, man. Coaching wise,
there's a lot going on there.
What?
She just came along at a time when there
was no one like her when she was a real
Olympic caliber athlete and her
judo was at such a high level.
No one could fuck with him and shit,
throwing people around until someone
could fuck with her until she ran into
someone like Holly Holm.
And then,
then we really saw the holes in
the preparation, the distractions,
the fact that she had, you
know, movie deals going on.
They wanted her to do road house and
she's scripts and this and agent meetings
and all the bullshit man.
It's like a fucking Hollywood.
It was like a Hollywood script.
Like,
this is what happens to you
and this is how it look rocky.
When rocky went soft and this
is literally what happens.
And then all of a sudden you've got this
bad ass Holly Holm sitting there ready
to fucking head kick you into another
dimension. And that's what happened.
And like you said,
I think,
I think most of it is just trying to stay
aware and not get the delusional about
it. Cause it's, it is very easy to kind
of slip into that and fall into that.
And you know, sometimes she will hit
you. And that's what happened in my,
in my second fight that I lost,
uh, to Leonardo Santos and,
and each fight I can always
see myself losing. You know,
and people ask me that and they're like,
you talk about all this
visualization that you do.
Like sometimes I visualize
myself getting hurt too.
When fights do you do that to see how
you recover? How do you, what do you do?
So it's not a new experience.
I Went Barboza fucking spinning
heel kicks me in the head
like his, it's not, uh, it's not, it's
always the punch that don't hurt you.
It hurts. You were texting before that
fight and we were setting up this podcast.
You, I just listen, I just got to
concentrate on making sure I do.
Don't kick me in the head.
And then after the pilot, Dan,
we fucking kicked me in the head.
You have definitely, definitely prepare
yourself for the possibility it because,
because it has to be,
be there. That's the only fight
that it wasn't there for me was uh,
Leonardo Santos because he,
he was,
I mean he multiple times a
champion on the ground and Jujitsu.
So I was only really worried about his
ground game. I kind of just dismissed his,
his, uh, his standup and I was like,
no way this guy's going to beat me.
And the worst thing happened in the fight.
Like the first minute he
got me down and I got all,
I got him off me and like 30 seconds or
something. Then after that I was like,
whew, this about to be a cakewalk.
I'm might just run through this man.
Like he don't, you know, I'm like,
it was 17,000 people in an arena.
I'm like, we all just waiting on
him to fall, you know, only him.
He was the only one that sought it.
He could clip me
and I'd be dead.
But how valuable was that fight for you?
I mean it was probably one of the
most important ones in my career.
I mean there there's been a couple of
the losses are have always been the ones
that I feel like I will look back and say,
damn,
that was the one that really made it.
That fight in particular I
think really made it because it,
it kind of drilled home.
Some of the things that Robert follows
was sounding to me that's the only fight
since I've been in Vegas.
Well obviously since before this fight,
but that Robert Follis wasn't
in my corner and it was,
if I'm being honest with save some
money, you know, saved the 10% that he,
that he wasn't wanted or whatever, and
I was like, I'm going to smoke this kid.
I'm like, rob, just sit back, you know,
you watch it from home and joy and I'm
gonna go out there and I'm a smoke this
kid.
And I didn't have his voice of reason
to make me say, this kid is dangerous
everywhere. You know what I mean?
Stay sharp everywhere and I let my
guard down any and he hit me with a good
punch. Uh, but it was
that one where I was like,
I've never had robbed, not in my
corner again or that voice, you know,
and now I have to make do without it.
But you know, now usually was that boy.
So yeah,
he was,
but to go back and he was just that
voice of reason not to get delusional.
You know what I mean?
Cause it's because it is easy,
especially when you're young and you got
the no hormones line or you feel like
you would a man, like, you know, you
competent like shit, I'm the man.
Like he can't touch me. But you got
to have somebody like, hey bro, bro,
you know, you are very good, but
you still gotta be sharp to the,
these men that you fighting are very,
very good too.
Do you think that sometimes
someone can't tell it to you?
You just have to learn it.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
You got to go through those
experiences and I think doesn't,
that's an all walks of everything,
you know, and, and, and,
and that's kind of what I bring to a year.
Like I don't,
I don't want to just be a,
just a great fighter, you know,
I want to be graded everything.
I want to be a chef and I want to
be a dancer and I want to be a,
science isn't a doctor. And like
that's just the way my brain works.
I just wanted to be a better fucking
everything the right way to think, man.
I've done that. It's kind of
inner sometimes, but you know,
but, uh, you know, there's
a great, I need that
depression. The way you do anything
is the way you do everything.
Yeah. Well probably. Yeah.
Yeah. I mean, I, I think, I
think there's something to that.
If you have fast things mean you can
get away with being a great fighter and
still half ass things you live,
but maybe you would be better if you
didn't like maybe you would be even in an
even better fighter or better whatever
you are, fucking tennis player,
whatever it is. If you didn't half ass
other things in your life, maybe you,
you would really reach your full potential
100%. And I think that even even
in the fighting realm, you know,
that that's what a lot of
this last fight was for me.
A is getting back to making
the fight first, doing,
focusing on the fight before anything
else and relieving some of the mental
stress off me before I stepped into
the, when I stepped in for that Co, uh,
Tony Fight, I was already tired. I
was already, my body was already,
my brain was just overloaded and I
was already broken down and you know,
I'd made the fight second or I
made the fight last, you know, uh,
I put everything else before, you
know, it. We went and race car,
drive it the week of the fight and, and
looking back on it after, I was like,
oh my God. Yeah. You go to one of
those exotic places during races,
shout out to them like they, I mean
they look me up. I have fun too.
I think it's also important to have some
recreation. Yeah. Yeah. But you know,
that's, that sounds like it was
too much. A little too much.
And mostly because they were like filming
it and I wanted to make it good and
then, you know, we have fun with it and Oh
for like the countdown shows. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. But you know, so you
get that balance. Right.
How hard is that?
The press obligations and all the
constant interviews and all that shit.
Joy. I mean, I enjoy them.
I honestly enjoy doing media for
the most part is just, you know,
on a certain it can be
too much sometimes
organize it around your training or
did you have to organize your training
around media obligate? I usually
organize it around my training. Uh,
and that's good.
It was when,
when you hear that the training has to
be organized around media obligations and
like, Oh yeah, that's not true.
I mean maybe I've heard of people having
to get up at six in the morning and do
a write blocker radio calls and shit.
I'm like, well I don't like that.
I don't like that shit.
Yeah. I mean, yeah, you have to do
that, but you know, I still, I kinda,
I just make do with it,
you know what I mean?
I think as long as you enjoying it and
you just kind of going with the flow is
not a hindrance necessarily.
If you, if you like, fuck,
I don't want to fucking be here. I want
to get up at 6:00 AM and do this shit.
You know? Then when you get to all that
want to do is train, the whole time,
you know, is it can be a
hindrance. Even Morrison. Right?
Yeah, I guess, right. Like the way
you approach something will change,
like what that thing is.
Yeah. And it's gotta be
natural for you to, you know,
I actually liked liked doing it, so,
uh, I think it's just something that,
you know, if you, if, if I could see
myself, if I forced it or if I, you know,
was one of these guys that didn't at all,
then yeah,
I could see it being even a
bigger hindrance, but since
I get at me, it's fine.
Does great. Well, as long as it
doesn't fuck with your training.
One of the things I was really impressed
about Saturday night is your endurance.
I mean, you were, you were fresh
as a daisy even in the fifth round,
and that was a grueling pace,
you know? And, uh, we didn't really focus
too much on, on too much conditioning.
You know, I did a lot of long
runs to, to kind of thin the,
my muscles out a little bit. Uh, I
did a lot of like longer distance,
longer cardio stuff,
kind of got away from like a lot of the
explosiveness that I used to do on the,
especially for the Tony Fight,
Tony fight was all explosion.
It was all like big movements. It was all
like, you know, I'm out there, I'm a nut,
this motherfucker out. Uh, but this
fight. And I realized like during it,
I was like, you know, I got to
approach it smarter and, and,
and in that it actually became better
cardio then me pushing myself too hard,
you know what I'm saying?
You know,
I'm torn on that because I see guys
preparing that way where they do a lot of
long runs and you know,
that's a big Nate Diaz thing and
his brother Nick and you know,
they do ultra marathons and triathlons
and I feel like there's some real benefit
to having that deep bass and cardio
100%. But I mean, it's, it's balanced,
balanced, like anything else would life,
you know, you gotta, you gotta be able
to, to balance those really strong, tough,
you know, you can't explore every
time. He has spread the whole time.
But I can't run a marathon the whole time.
So I try my best to,
that's how I want to be as well
rounded as I possibly can be. And,
and having great cardio in and
understanding what that's like. Uh,
as part of that, yes. It's hard for
people don't understand,
but you're not throwing a hundred
percent of your power all the time.
Yeah. You can't, you can't.
No, you can't. Especially not
with a guy like Barboza, uh,
who is in there the whole time.
There was some spots that I got him and
it's like, guys, normally we'll, we'll,
we'll give up. They'll quit or, you know,
I'm hitting them with big shots and
he's just steady showing the ref day.
I'm still in this thing. I'm still moving.
And then he stands up and he can spit.
It will get you in. You know, he's still
got that explosiveness and uh, you know,
you, you can't go 100% right out the gate.
You, you got to pick him, be kind of,
be smarter.
You can't wear out how to be smart.
And that's one of the things that
rob would always tell me. And again,
that's one of the things I'm
telling myself during the
fights. Be Smart, be smart.
Barboza is also the,
I think the first guy and the only
guy to stop to people with leg.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Vicious. Like Kit Kat,
my shit, my shit is on fire right now.
I checked a couple of them up,
but did you bring in anybody that does
wheel kicks or anything to get used to
the timing of that? Yeah. A couple
of guys, a really good taekwondo,
a specialist, and his name
is, I mean, you wouldn't know.
Notice a flash out off the black.
I know he,
he's probably the best at easy, little
bit better than marbles. The marbles is,
no, no, no.
It just on that not telegraphic portion
of it because that's what really gets
you hurt, which Barboza is
very non telegraphy. But
those taekwondo guys, they,
they can move a little bit different. You
know, Chris Bang is a, is another one, uh,
that, that uh, like
woolly brought out for,
for wonder boy because he's
got that same style day.
Th that taekwondo style of spinning is,
it's a little bit different.
I brought up like three or four guys.
Well it's the guy when they,
when you train like that,
you're not throwing punches to the face.
So the kicks have to be ultra fast. It's,
and there's also, I think there's, uh,
there's this,
this is some benefit to learning like
Kyoko Shin for that and talk window for
that. W when they, they take
out those punches to the face.
There's something about leg dexterity.
Those guys have crazy leg like Yaya
Rodriguez style, like crazy leg dexterity.
Yeah, man. Yeah. You've got to spar a
couple of times before this last fight,
you know, and he, he's another
one of those. I mean he,
he's got that same type of style and not,
and I steal a lot from those guys. Uh,
I kind of started picking it up when I
fought a kid named James Mutasa re very
good. He was married champion champion a
couple of times I think, uh, for, for uh,
Korea.
But I mean he's just super underrated,
especially as kicking but
prepared for that fight.
I had to work with a lot of taekwondo
guys and right off the back I'm like, oh,
this is a different style. Like
it's, it's like four different,
four or five different
styles of kicking up.
Think there's this like wanted a
better mixes of speed and power and not
telegraphic.
And I try to blend that a little bit more.
What Moy Tai and find the best style.
I feel like more is absolutely the best,
but there's some shit that those taekwondo
guys can do that'll catch you off
guard. And if you know those other
things, you can do those things. Yeah,
100% like the wheel kicks. And that's what
what you see with the eds. I mean the,
the Thai style has probably the hardest
kicks and the, the most technical,
uh, from it. But you know, you can kind
of see some of them come in, you know,
you could see unless you got free
speed light like Barboza you know,
but actual technical wise,
you know,
you can kind of see it coming a little
bit more time is more effective because
it's just more effective. This chopping
the legs, it just brutally effective.
And obviously in taekwondo there's none
of that. Yeah. So those guys wouldn't,
if you were seeing like matches we're
talking with no guys fight Moy Thai guys,
they get a blood red.
Yeah, yeah. No for sure.
If you allow the Moy Thai
guy to kick the legs,
taekwondo guys just really don't
know what to do. Once they learn it,
then they have the taekwondo too.
But it's a matter of whether or not,
like we were talking about before,
like if you're a wrestler,
do you really learn how to try? Could you
just try take everybody? But you know,
it's, if the taekwondo guys really
learn how to check leg kicks,
they already know how
to kick. Yeah. They'll,
they'll be able to pick up the style way
quicker than the Thai guys are going to
be able to do jumping wheel kicks and
shit like that. That stuff is already
ingrained in their wheelhouse.
It's in their synapses.
They know what to do.
Yeah.
And that's that.
I think that's one of the things that
the beauties about MMA being such a young
sport is, you know, you still seeing guys
evolving and, and you know, like, like me,
I'm trying to take that, the best of
those styles and make them great for MMA.
You know, because there are certain, you
know, you can't chop down the leg if,
if a guy's trying to take you down,
you know,
but you could steal a chopped the leg.
But there's certain ways that
you can change that up. And, uh,
that's one of the beauties about the sport
being so youngest. Still figuring out,
people ask me, I sat right next to a Oh
area, what shall I sat right next to,
to Demetrius Johnson and they asked me
who's the best pound for pound fighter.
And you know,
I think people like expected me to
say me or something or to say Dj.
And I honestly don't think that
he's been testing yet. You know,
I think he's still like a 16 year old
kid out there somewhere that's going to
find the best guy out. That really, yeah.
You don't think Demetrius is the best
guy? No, I didn't meet you as hell.
I mean Demetrius does a, I mean
he's great, he does a lot of things,
but he gets away with a lot of stuff
that he does because the guys that he's
going against our 25 pounders,
you know,
they don't have a whole lot of explosive
one punch power to really make you pay
for something to mistakes.
You know, the like as far as,
especially as far as like the hop
switching and stuff, you know,
that's why I got like,
like Tj can get away with it a lot more
at 35 I think then a 55 pound fighter
would, you know, Tj crews, a lot of those
35 years that can kind of, that style
leave opening the consequences could be
so much more devastating because they
hit so much harder.
Yeah. I mean your legs are your,
your shock absorbers. You know, when,
when I get the wall,
the leg or the shotguns doors,
if your legs are in the air while you
get hit by somebody that's explosive like
that you going night night, you
know, the only thing that's eaten,
all the shock of your brain,
Duane Ludwig would disagree with you
if you sat down and talked to him.
Cause I think the idea is to present a
very complex target and to overload the
brain with positive
buildings. I feel that, you know, and,
and, and, and I try and do that too.
I try and uh, you know,
I've taken Dwayne's a,
a couple of the ways seminars actually,
and he's a wizard. Yeah. Yeah.
He comes over to extreme, but 200 does
some things. So, you know, I liked,
I like his style. Shout out to
Duane Ludwig. Yeah, no, I, I,
I love the way you style and it's
just a different style to be had,
but I feel like that's not even, it's
still not the best out. You know,
I don't think the best style has been,
Demetrius Johnson has a great style,
but I don't think it's the
best style has been seen yet.
Hmm. Especially for him, it, but out of
what you've seen, he's got the best style.
Yeah. I mean, everybody's
different. Everybody's different,
you know what I'm saying is the argument
is him and Jon Jones, the two arguments,
and I feel like John Jones, as far
as the level of talent, no question.
John's faced for show
gone d c twice Gustafson.
I mean, yeah, Vito Belfort.
I mean, Jesus Christ do,
you could just keep going and going and,
and gone
Glover to sharer. You know, he's got, he's
got the resume, but I don't know, I think,
I think George Saint Pierre, uh, right
steel, you know, Georgia is a little bit,
uh, you know, behind the
times now a little bit.
Do you think so a little bit, man. I
don't know. After that that's been fired.
I would never say that. Yeah.
Yeah. But, but you know,
Bisping is also from the
same era. I think. Um,
I think Georgia, if Jason,
George Saint Pierre for sure,
I think is the greatest fighter
that there's been. I don't, I mean,
when you look at the resumes, I don't
think nobody else compares really. Uh,
you know, he's got two losses to binge
both those losses and devastatingly,
you know,
came back after four years and won the
title at a higher weight class and he's
never really been in too much
trouble in a fight. Uh, you know,
I look at his style. He's one of those
guys, he's one of the very first guys.
He's really what got me into the sport
because I saw his fight with Bj and I
just, I can see it. I'm like, Oh,
this guy is, you know, he's smart.
He's approaching it smart like a,
like a true athlete,
you know, like a true artist,
like true athlete. And uh, there,
there are people that do it too.
You know, Demetrius does too.
But I just don't think to the level
that George has done well, again,
it's the level of
competition that he faced.
I mean judge George face some
seriously stiff competition.
Not that Demetrius didn't,
I mean he fought Dominick Cruz.
He's fought some tough cause I was really
looking forward to Demetrius versus Tj
and I know they were trying
to put that together,
but that would have been the one love
that fight. And it still might be the one,
they might still do it.
I mean,
if a Tj can defeat Cody or even if he
doesn't and if he decides to go down to
25, he can make it. He says,
yeah, he says he can make it.
Yeah, I think you can in a,
I think he can give them
some real problems. Oh,
it'll be the biggest fight of his life.
100% sure he's fast. He hits hard,
he knocks guys out at 35,
what the fuck is he going to
do to people at 25 if he can,
if his body will stay healthy
with that weight cut, you know,
and you know as good as anybody that
that's very difficult to do because you
just feel weaker. Yeah. Yeah.
I mean there's that, uh,
I, I know the guys that he,
that he trains down in South California
with um, uh, the training lab.
That man approaches it like
a scientist for real. He,
I think he's a mathematician over at
UC Berkeley. I want to change this guy.
I sat down with them for about, we
talked for maybe about five, six hours.
It was mostly him just talking.
It may just sitting there absorbing all
the shit that he could tell me about,
you know, exactly. He, I mean,
he measures those guys to,
to a t. Uh, so if he feels like he
can, who's training with him? Uh,
Dillashaw and is he a strength
and conditioning guys? Sam, uh,
cal cal veto. If I'm saying that Right Sam
Cup or you know, down to train and lap.
Okay. Brilliant. Brilliant man. He,
he's, he's one of the very few guys that,
that I think in MMA especially that
really, he, he trained a lot of uh,
he trains David Taylor, a lot of the, the
u s uh, Olympic wrestling team. He
worked with those guys for a long time.
What are you seeing?
Some mad scientists get into the game now,
right when they realize that there's
real money in it and it's just mad.
Is what 55 56 does a those iron mans,
you know where you got to like,
I think it's like something crazy like
bike 120 miles and then you swim 20 miles
and then you run a full marathon and
he's doing it like 53 54 years old.
I'm like, God, I went over and
train with them before and it is,
is something is another level of
like strength and conditioning.
So if he says he can get TJ down to 25,
I mean I would,
I would think he could do it.
And if he's confident in it,
then he can do it in the right
way. At least. I spoke to Tj,
he was a hundred percent confident
that it could make the way and he just,
well you got also realize Dj
Dimitris just got shoulder surgery,
so he's still rehabbing from that,
you know,
and who knows how long
that's going to take.
I don't know how complex this shoulder
surgery was, but yeah, that's, you know,
still interested in that fight. I
mean that's, it's a big one for, uh,
for Demetrius Johnson
especially, you know, he needs
that extra little push over.
You know how Shannon gave him some tips,
some tricks when we were
still in the media tours
together for the talk shit. No,
not necessarily to talk shit,
but, you know, cause he, he,
he's not going to be able to come
out and just talk shit. You know,
he's kind of style. It's not his
style. It don't work, you know. Uh,
but to round out his game a little bit.
Boy, let's say that I know he says,
because I'm going to go back to
the most well rounded fighter.
You got to be able to promote to, you
know, you've got to be able to see,
people want to want to see you fight
to, uh, and that thing is a stress.
It's a, it's a stressor on you and you're
on your, you're training, like you said,
you've got to get up at 6:00
AM because when you do it,
you get more media requests.
So you get,
you get to have those interviews more
and that's a stress and it's something
that you, Barron at your opponent
don't necessarily have to, you know, a,
a guy like Conor does a lot more media
than, than his opponent though of course,
it's,
it's a bigger stress and you know,
if you can handle all those stresses
and still go out there and compete, uh,
then if you shy away from that,
I got to take that away from you as far
as being the best power file pod fighter.
You know what I mean? That's
interesting. But if it's not Demetrius,
and who the fuck is it other than
George and George isn't really fighting
[inaudible] for short.
John Jones, you know,
I think George really fighting right
now either. Oh you saying right,
right now in this sport it was hard
because John, I mean it's up there.
I mean I don't think John took PDDs and
people give me a hard time about that.
I don't think he did.
I think he took something tainted just
based on what you saw to has said about
the levels pre and post test.
I think you fucked up and tell us.
I'm that muddy up mass man.
I was roof too fucked up money.
But he could still, they could still come
back and be much bigger. Uh, you know,
like I said, controversy,
especially when you know,
especially when you're black in
America, controversy is, is, is,
is one of the best things they can
have until you really, well John,
when he's loose and when you know,
like when
him and Daniel were in that
press conference and Danny
was talking shit, he goes,
I beat you after I did cocaine.
Yeah.
What jaws. Just himself. I mean,
he's huge. He's, he's, he's,
he's going to be the biggest, uh, he
could have already been the biggest star.
V You're just on the beginning.
If they don't really suspend him for
very long when he comes back within a few
months, it's entirely possible
that he could come back, you know,
and be the biggest still of all time. I
think he's going to be way bigger. Uh,
especially after, like I said,
controversies is a great one.
Where you black in America, they really,
dad, it's like for John, like how much,
how much more focus will there,
I mean my fear is that he's going to s
somehow another sabotage again and that,
that this is not just this,
that these lessons aren't sinking in
because there's been so many of them.
The car accident where the broke the
lady's arm and she's pregnant and he runs
away and then slamming the car
into the tree. There was so many.
And then there's, you know, the first
test positive and then the second test,
positive like, fuck the brawl, the
press conference. Fuck. It's like,
there's so many things
I think that goes back to,
you know,
not being delusional and having the right
team around you and somebody that you
really listened to, that's that you
really truly listened to, you know,
not just somebody that you just kind
of hard. Right. Yeah, I hear you. Uh,
because it's easy to get that way.
It really is. I'm sure like in,
I've approached it a couple of
times, you know, you get that,
especially when you got that confidence
in the thing that made you great in the
first place. It can be like a
hindrance to you too. And I think
a lot of it has been,
or at least a lot of my growth in the
past couple of months has been me getting
in my own head and understanding it
and, and kind of breaking it down. Uh,
you know,
smoke weed helps
a lot to you that God is legal now.
Yeah.
I didn't start until after my last,
uh, to Leonardo. Really? Yeah.
First Time that idea. But honestly it
was probably like the best thing that,
because I was angry at the fight. I
was angry at everything, you know, the,
I was like, fuck, how can
I, you know, this guy,
I was like a 10 to one
favorite going into that fight.
That was the one fight without never saw
him. I was like, don't you smoke them? Uh,
so I just had this anger and the only way
I saw my dad can I deal with it was it
was alcohol. So I kind of turned to
that and you know that it's no good.
It's really, it's the worst way
to do it. Worst way to do it.
It just makes the delusions bigger.
You know what I'm saying?
It just makes you angry or
in, and it just, it just kind
of compounded everything.
But honestly, like what I smoke weed was
like, cause at that point hasn't like,
you know what,
I had tuned it out for so long because
that's what folks did that I kind of
associated with being lazy and the hospice
as well. And you know, these fucking,
you know, you know, I don't want
to be on a corner, right? Like, uh,
but when I did it, it kind of
opened up the anger towards myself.
You know what I mean? It kind of opened
up my mom for the first time and, and,
and I think that actually did help a
lot of help with any, you know, I don't,
I don't like karate or nothing, but you
know, I know what you're saying. Yeah.
I think that's what people were afraid
of with it too,
is that paranoia.
I would say paranoia is just you looking
at things realistically and even the
possibilities of things
happening realistically. I
mean, some people for sure,
if they have tendencies to be
schizophrenia in particular
and then they smoke a
lot of weed,
it could spiral them.
Cool. Yeah, it does sound like anything
else I spoke, it's not a good idea that,
you know, isn't doing too much of any
one thing is not a good idea. I mean,
he's the same way. You have to,
you have to be able to, to balance,
you know what I mean? You can't just
fucking sit on the couch all day,
but I'm glad.
Yeah.
You're saying that there's a real
benefit to it too. There's some,
there's a benefit to it
mentally and exposing that
vulnerability and just making
you aware of who you really are.
Like maybe to other people.
We all,
especially men,
I think we puff our chests up and we like
to look at ourselves as a baby better
than we really are because it's,
it's,
it's like a shield that like a false
confidence shield that you put up to
protect yourself from your vulnerability.
But marijuana says not enough.
Fuck that.
Why don't you just look at whatever
the fuck your vulnerability and stopped
doing that stupid like this is,
this is your problem,
this is what you're scared of
me. Like Shit. The weeds, right?
Yeah. It can help you. Yeah.
And it, and it Kinda Alexa App,
especially after that fight, I
remember it. That really made me,
that really helped me to get
over and not just get over it,
but to understand it and understand
what I was doing. Uh, because again,
you just don't, you know, you get that
the informal is maybe it's testosterone.
You get that fucking, yeah.
Puppy. He's just all, you know,
you don't give a fuck
you part of it for sure.
It's just, it's also think about what
you're doing for a living man, ma'am.
It's the most,
one of the most risky propositions you
could do as a human being outside of war.
That, that too. That too. And I
took that into, you know, you,
you obviously you take that
into consideration when you,
when you start doing something like this,
I'd taken into consideration every fight.
Um, you know, once slight one slip up,
you could be bad news. Sure. Injury
can take you out forever, you know,
especially when the EU was,
and when I was in my situation and
even when I was signed with the UFC,
it was like, okay, do I go and try and be
a doctor and you know, or you know, I was,
I was going into bio mat so I was like,
I was really,
that seemed more secure.
You know what I mean?
That seems more like
attainable easier or do I like,
I can't like throw caution to the wind.
And you know,
at the time when I was 18 or
19, uh, no, I guess I'm a yeah,
19. Uh, you know, that was like
a hard, you know what I'm saying?
I'm one of those ones that
was hard for me to make,
but it turned out well I guess at least.
Well it's,
you're going to have more
than one interest too. That's
also part of the problem.
There's probably,
there's a lot of people out there that
like doing different things and you,
you know,
you might be leaning more towards one
than the other and you just got to kind of
soul search and nobody could
answer that other than you.
That's why it's terrible when
people tell people what to do.
When people tell people what you need to
do is get a good job or you need to go
with something that's going to be saved,
go with what's attainable. Go with that.
And I'm like, man, that's not
right. Well, everybody's different.
100% and I think that's the,
I mean to go back just to rob desk,
that's what he did so well he didn't,
he didn't tell me what to do.
He just showed me the truth kind
of, you know what I mean? He just,
he was that voice. Am I, it was
like the conscious and I mean,
and it hit your show. It too, like you do
a good job, you do a great job of it. Uh,
and I mean I know you've heard it before,
like you just are very truthful in
what you say and instead of being like
preachy because nobody listened to
fucking preachy. You know what I mean?
She's usually,
well I try not to be,
but sometimes it comes off maybe
sounding preachy if you don't know me,
but it's just honest and that,
you know,
there's what you said about Robert,
one of the most important things
about it is that he shows you,
he's just showing you and you
could trust him. You know, those,
those two things are very important.
Someone who would just show you things,
show you what's wrong, showing and that
you can trust. He's not bullshitting you.
When as soon as you think that someone
is bullshitting you are bullshitting
themselves or being Dell,
you're like, fuck man,
I can't cause they might have good
information about other things.
That's a real problem
when someone's an idiot,
but also a genius like that that exists.
There's people out there
and those people you can,
that's how fucking puzzle you got to go.
Okay,
how much of this do what
he's saying is stupid?
How much of what he's saying is genius
and sometimes it's a weird mixture.
Yeah. This is, I think that's one
of the things that I'm learning,
especially as I'm kind of going forward
and cause you may get to meet so many
people and uh,
so many people want to be a friend.
All of a sudden there's so many people,
everybody's got,
they want to tell you how to do your job.
Like everybody want to tell me how to
fight and everybody wanted to tell me like
what to do and how to
do this awesome thing.
But some people really know what
they're talking about actually though.
So you have to be able to,
you know,
I think you got to find that
yellow bullshit meter in there and,
and kind of pick it apart. It for me,
rob was dead and you know, he, but the,
the shit that he's still says this is,
you know,
I mean, you still get information on
how to fight from your yoga instructor.
She could say something to you and that
one thing will just sit in your head. Oh
yeah. I had a, uh, a girl named, you
call it a little Japanese girl, uh,
that was giving me privates and,
and Yoga.
But the way she broke it
down was like anatomy almost.
She knew the exact,
you know,
position that I was here instead of being
here where I was losing my balance or
I was losing something of power or it
was putting more strain on one area the
other and making it harder. And I'm just
like, this translates so well, you know,
even when I do ballet,
it's like, you know,
I can see when I'm off balance when um,
you know,
as one of the things and ballets
as you spend in, you know,
keep your eyes on there
so you don't get dizzy.
So even when proposal he kicked me,
I just made sure I saw four of them,
but I'm like, let me keep my eyes
on this motherfucker. He's like,
stay on of it.
But it all,
it all translate because it's all the
human body is called the same thing. Yeah.
You know,
it's just different ways of expressing
the way your body moves and what it does.
But it's the same shit. It says it's
only one, it's like a giant computer.
And I would think that learning all
these different ways to move would just
enhance your overall understanding of
how your body works and it makes you,
I think it like makes you more in
tune with it too. You know what,
I may get healthy.
That's one of the biggest keys.
I think it's just being as healthy as
as possible. And not, uh, you know,
tamper on with that too much for sure.
And also flexibility.
I think having flexibility is so
important. They are a fighter, you know,
being able to move your body. Like there's
some people that just aren't flexible,
they just can't move in certain ways.
And you know,
I can tell from watching you throw
head kicks and not fight. Like you're,
you're flexible.
You don't have a lot of tension in your
legs when you're doing that. You know,
I think tension is that,
is that it's like the perfect word for
it really is because that's what causes
you to tighten to, yeah. Like
when you got, when a guys,
it's difficult for him
to throw a body kick.
Can you see him kind of like lean
in and you see the instructor?
I loved Dan Henderson,
big fan. I've got to say,
you can even touch his toes when he
threw a head kick in the Hector lumbar
finals. Like Holy Shit.
But it's the way he
takes a lot of,
you know,
whereas some people throw head kicks and
you don't even see it coming. Yeah. Yeah.
And, and also Lynn and
grappling into, you know,
you have to be able to have
strength I think in every direction.
That's one of the biggest reason why I
don't lift weights as cause you get so
used to in that one uniform direction,
you have to be able to move.
I have to be just as strong
here as I am here as I am there.
Do you get all your resistance
from just grappling or from these,
these calisthenics and plow metrics
and different things? Grappling a lot.
Just pick guys up and put them
down. So it's concise. It does 100%.
A lot of body weight to 100% exercise.
Now did they concentrate on like
specific core exercises or do you know,
do you, do you have days where you
concentrate on just using your legs or uh,
yeah, different, different days dependent.
We do. We do do a lot of core stuff,
especially recently. Uh, probably
like the last year or so,
we've been doing a lot more, uh, with
the core. Uh, legs is a, is a huge one.
You know, your legs carry pretty much
the whole way. Kills. Yeah. Yeah. I mean,
I live in Henderson, so it's like,
you know, a lot of hills, but, um,
legs is one of the biggest,
just even my movement,
like the way you move to a lot of times
I'll notice how I'll be to, you know,
up on the balls on my feet or
I'll be too flat on, on my heels.
So as you know, I think that came
from wrestling a little bit though.
The stances are different.
Um,
but it's just rounding out me as a
individual is going to round out me as a
fighter, which has just
gone make it bigger, better.
Do you watch fights outside of MMA?
Do you watch kickbox 100%.
What do you like to
watch? Love Him. I mean,
I watch a lot of the big box and
fights, especially, I barely,
I only got to see like little clips and
pieces of the Broner and, and, and uh,
I was paying more attention
to his arguments with fits
rapper kid. That's six EA.
You're going back and forth and look
what the fuck is wrong with Andrew Brown
and he's entertaining this. The week
of the fight talking shit on Instagram.
I think they were just doing their
thing, making it, making media. Uh,
I think it was bullshit because he came
out to six nines a song and it's six,
nine kind of like shouted it out for
Broner. Came out to six, nine songs,
came out to the solid during the fight.
I haven't seen the video yet.
I got to go back and listen and go
on, go on. Six, nine, his Instagram,
he posted it up. Hilarious. So 69
changes to now. He likes Broner. I mean,
look at it. He was shouting, Gopros,
smart move. I mean they did they pay.
He actually, you know,
brought her is a he,
I mean he did his thing
and in that fight too,
he outworked Jesse Vargas
that that's hard to do. Uh,
I heard he beat the hell out of
them at the after eight rounds. Uh,
he beat out the hell out of him for
the last four, so I have to watch it,
watch it to home. I wanted to watch
your fight and Frankie's fight and um,
and uh, David Branch man knocking out
to, I'll go Santos like that. Holy Shit.
Branch is tough, but he's a bad
motherfucker. Do People Sleep on branch?
Cause he lost to Luke Rockhold.
Luke Rockhold is a fucking beast,
especially on top.
He got Weidman down on the
ground. By the way. Luke Rockhold,
we fought Weidman had staff. He was, yeah,
he was going through his fucking the
antibiotics. He was two weeks out. He's,
he's in like serious fucking IV
antibiotics. The whole deal. He was,
he was really hurting man. And that's no
joke. I mean he had the fight with Tony.
I was out for six weeks. I couldn't do
anything. I was, I got stabbed twice,
but I got it once and they caught it
real early when I got it the second time.
The second time barely even affected
me because it caught it so early.
But the first time I got it,
I got on the heavy medication and man,
I was like dizzy and I wasn't even
train and I stopped training after I,
I got on the medication. I just just, just
hung around and I was just like, Jesus,
the first couple of days on
the medication, I'm dizzy.
I'm like, I feel terrible.
It destroys your body. I mean,
especially when you talk to, I mean,
you've taught so many
microbiologists that,
that tell you what it does to the gut
flora. I didn't know back then either.
I got it back in like 2010.
What the fuck?
Y'All don't know shit
about gut flora back then.
I literally didn't know what it was.
So I just took the medication,
just ate what I always ate.
Took some vitamins like I
always did and that was it.
But I was like, wow, like lightheaded.
Yeah. Yeah. No, it's no, it's no joke. Uh,
none of the body and it's,
that shit scares the fuck out of me,
Marissa and staff and those
fucking infections. They
scared the shit out of me,
man. Anything from within you?
It's Kinda, it's Kinda scary. Yeah.
That was fucking little monsters. Just
want to take over your body and eat it.
You know, that's what it is. There's
more of them than there are of us.
I mean there's more,
there's more bacteria in your body than
there are human cells. Yeah. I mean it's,
it's crazy to think about
it, but it, but it just,
it's all about balance. You know what I
mean? You, you careful with your diet.
Like do you take in a lot
of probiotics and, yeah.
Especially when they can't make very,
very careful or maybe outside of it.
Recently I've been going a lot more,
uh, Kido a little bit, you know,
I still eat carbs obviously because I
have to for to have that explosion still.
I feel like,
just think you do,
I think you have to eat more carbs and
you probably still stay key to genic.
I think that when people look
at carbs and they say like,
you only have 25 to 50 grams
of carbs during the day.
Like that's great if you're not doing
two a days and fucking wrestling and run
and hills and shit. Like you body probably
needs more carbohydrates than that.
Yeah. I mean definitely.
Uh, and that, that's kind of
where I try and supplement it,
especially before I trained,
you know,
trying to eat more carbs and then I kind
of cut them back towards the end of the
day. Is it, what are you eating? A lot
of chicken is a lot of, uh, because I,
I can't eat fish or shellfish.
So a lot of chicken. A lot
of, uh, yeah, largely. Yeah,
completely. Oh really? Wow.
Yeah. It's a lobster shit. Yeah.
I mean, I just convince myself it
takes like shit anyway, but it doesn't,
I mean I could, I could look at it,
I'm sure with melted butter. Ooh.
It tastes like melted
butter. Oh, it's so good.
Lobster with either melted butter
on like some, some grass fed steak.
Well that was pretty fucking good too.
I love to cook. I love it. Cause I mean,
I think there's a real
art to cook it into. Uh,
that could probably be me
and another life. A chef.
He was saying that one person, that's a
hard to it. Right? Yeah. I would love to,
uh, you know, eventually
maybe we'll see. I Cook a lot.
I love cooking and it makes
me feel good, man. I like,
I like knowing that I prepared a meal
together. It's just, it's a nice thing,
especially if it's healthy and
especially when you, you know, I don't,
I don't get people that are, I mean,
I don't want to say I don't get Vegas.
Like I have a lot of friends
that are Vegan and, and you know,
I never kinda down,
but the fact that they don't want to
eat meat for, there are certain people,
like my brother tried to do this too.
He's like,
he don't want to eat meat because he's
like afraid of the animal, you know,
or feel bad for the animal itself.
It's just like you said,
we've got more not us
sales then we do us sales.
Like we're all the same shit.
You know what I mean? Even the,
even the animals like we are the same,
you know?
So I mean it's the same as the plants
don't want animal cruelty. I mean,
I think of course that's what
most, the, the most noble aspects
of becoming a Vegan is to avoid
animal cruelty and factory farming.
And I think that that in that way,
I agree with them.
The real problem with vegans is that
there's a certain percentage of them that
are just fucking idiots and it's just
a certain percentage of any group of
people. It's not most vegans,
most vegans are kind people.
It's a certain percentage of them that
are using being a Vegan as an excuse to
be a fucking asshole. And that's
what it is. And they just,
they have this thing and most of
them use Vegan in their screen name.
They always have like the vegans a part
of their identity and then they attack
people who aren't vegans.
There's a few people that have followed.
I literally go to their Twitter page
and just watch them attack people who
aren't vegans. Yeah. I mean it's crazy to
watch. It's just like that's all they do.
And, and like you said, it's, it's,
that's why I don't want to say like I
don't understand Vegas cause that's just
people in general. You get
that. Yeah. You're going to
get that in any walk Sjoberg
be fucking idiots.
And it's almost like when I've said that,
like veganism is sort of a religion.
It's an ideology in the sense of the way
some people practice it that they want
to go after. There's some people that are
Catholic that Hate Protestants, right?
So they think the Protestants are
the enemy. And then this is just,
I mean this is obviously something that
went on for a long time in human history,
but I think it's just groups of people
get real tribal. And then, you know,
the fucking Yankees hate the red
sox and this is just how it goes.
And these people just decide that
you're on the other team, so fuck you.
And no one can see any middle ground.
You know,
there's this guy from this restaurant,
uh,
antler from Toronto I had on last week
and these people are protesting his
restaurant, these vegans. Oh, I seen that.
They want him to put a sign in
the window saying something like,
no animal should die so that we live and
it's not our right to take their lives
on like, and so they're like the
protest every week until he does it.
But he's not going to do it. Yeah.
So what the fuck are you doing?
Like what is this like where's this,
they've just asked. There's, there's,
there's an ideological battle going on,
you know, and they're not, it's not,
it doesn't,
it's not a thought,
well like examined objective thing in my,
in my opinion.
Yeah. But it's so natural
though, like you said,
is it's almost like communities
[inaudible] you know, is,
is you have your, your, your thoughts.
I've got my thoughts and we're part of
two separate communities and it's just
like with anything else,
I think that integration between the two
and that balance is like the most key
to everybody really. You kind of will
grow everybody, you know, the, the,
the bounty hunters can learn
something from the vegans.
Just much the vegans can learn
from the bombing hunters.
You know what I'm saying?
I think so too. You know,
and I think that really the problem is
when people don't want to hear the other
side and they want to shout people down,
they don't,
they're not willing to listen.
And there's,
there's common ground across the board.
And some of it probably is just learnt,
I think a lot about like how you grew up.
And I think it's important to like
understand that it's like I said,
just to go back to march,
how old it is,
just that's the way I grew up
and that's what I understood.
But when I look at like
my dad, you know, like my,
my dad didn't have his dad so, and
he was out the house by 15, you know,
he and I try and put myself
there sometimes being a 15
year old kid that didn't
have a place to go. Like,
what are you going to do?
And the only people you see around you
is, is drug dealers and, and in, in on us.
So like a lot of it I give credit to
him for sticking around for me because I
would have no, I've hit people over
Todd to hit. Right, right. You know,
you know what I mean? Uh,
and that's why people do it.
Because those people that are doing that
are just like you and me, everybody's,
we're all just human beings.
And we very genetically and we vary,
but we very more bar environment, how much
love we get. Yeah, yeah. That, that's a,
that's a big part of it is like
it's just the culture is, it's just,
you know,
and I think it stems from one culture
being separated from others and not having
that integration.
Then you get that like even more of a
disconnect and then once you get the even
bigger than, you know, it's, it's
all like downhill, more insecurity,
which leads to more tribalism and it's,
the whole thing is just,
it's so disappointing that
people still operate like this,
but I think people were opening
up to that more now than before.
I just think it's a slow process.
Slowly but surely,
slowly but surely we still working at it.
Yeah.
Know we were talking before about
the Rosa parks picture out there.
That wasn't that long ago man. No,
no, no. It really wasn't in it.
And that'd be the thing with certain,
there's certain white people too
that just be like, all right,
just get over it already. And
it's like, come on, like it,
they didn't have to get over it. Exactly.
They don't understand. Then you don't,
you truly don't understand.
Uh,
and you've don't even like take the time
to try and understand their tribal to,
they'd talked to other people that say
the same shit and like, yeah, well,
and they'll just start rattling off the
statistics about the instances of crime
in the black community and how the
Asians don't do this, but the blacks do.
It's like, it's fucking cultural.
If you don't think it's cultural,
you haven't been enough around enough
people and it does not go back.
A lot of generations. It's like you said,
the parts is not very long ago. You know,
my dad didn't have his dad.
He didn't have that person to teach him
what not to do and what to do. You know,
it's, it's, that's a, that's a, that's
a hard road, especially for a young,
like you go back earlier, like young
guys get delusional real quick. You know,
they feel invincible. He felt like, oh,
I can do this and I'm
never going to get caught.
You don't have that voice of reason
to tell you right from wrong when you,
when you that kind of age and it's because
he didn't have his dad and then why
didn't have his dad because he didn't
have his dad. You know what I mean?
And that only goes back two,
three generations.
And you know what's crazy is you are
talking about 1865 is when slavery was
abolished.
So we're talking about a small amount
of time in human history where there
haven't been slave.
So all your isolation when you,
you felt as a kid where you felt separate
from the people that were in those,
the miles
that were higher than yours.
Think about that times a hundred is if
you were a slave and maybe a million
remediate,
insurmountable gap between a slave that
has no chance of ever not being a slave.
And someone who can go to school wherever
they want and travel abroad abroad and
do whatever the fuck they want.
And then the idea that some of these white
people think that these people should
just get over it with the amount
of time is so fucking short.
You're talking about we just had
black panther, the lifestyle,
we just had it beat Avatar.
It's beating
one of the number one biggest
movies of all time. Stupid, big.
That should help.
Believe it or not,
I really think it would help.
It was a beautiful movie and it
was a beautiful movie to describe.
Even like when you say 1865 I feel
like we so disconnected from even that,
and this is,
I've talked to a lot of people about this,
the difference between being called a
black American and African American,
you know, I don't, I hate being
called an African American. I just,
that's what everybody says, but we know
it's just bothers it. Taped it to me, it,
it makes you seem, because you put
me in Francis' next to each other,
Frances and an African American, you
know what I mean? He's, he's from Africa.
He has ties to African. Who else is
in African American? Elon Musk. Yeah.
I mean, yeah. Really when you were ill.
But I think even more now it Kinda like
I just, why can't we be, the black
comes in so many different shades.
You know what I mean?
And this is African obviously,
so maybe black Americans
a better way to put it.
But Africans have ties to African,
you know what I'm saying?
Like black American slavery,
like we feel,
I feel we should have our ties in America.
Like I should be proud
to just be in American,
not be called the an
African American woman.
Well it's with every generation.
I mean it's,
it's going to take a long time before
we just abandoned all this nonsense and
just treat people based on
who they are as a human being.
But my grandparents came from Italy
and they were treated like dog shit.
And my grandfather always talked about
the racism that he encountered when he
came over from Italy to America.
And they didn't think of
Italians as white people.
Now they think of Italians is white
people 100% and Mexicans are experiencing
that. Like, you know, if you're from
Spain, you're basically white. Like,
nobody thinks of a guy
from Spain as being like,
you don't think of in the same
way you think of Mexicans,
but one day all that shit will go away.
One day we'll get past this,
whether it's who knows how
many generations it will take.
But I think it's changing now because of
the Internet. I think there's, there's,
there's definitely like more hate
groups that consolidate and they'd get
together and they, they, they, you know,
they, they live in an echo chamber online.
They talk, you know, and they agree
with each other. You see it on Twitter.
And Twitter's trying to stop that.
And maybe that's misguided
because maybe it strengthens it.
But I think that ultimately is the ability
to exchange information is going to
allow more and more people
to compare notes and, and,
and understand that there's no,
there's no benefit to describe or to,
to,
to thinking of people as being inferior
or superior or better or worse.
We're just all different. But we're
all human. We're all just humans
of all the same. I mean really, you
see that when you, when you see people,
you know, you can really see
somebody that you really know them.
You really see them. Yeah. It
is. We literally all the same
but all different too, because that's
one of the beautiful things is that you,
you see these little different
aspects of individual's personalities,
but to lump people in a group, Oh,
you know, you're a Chinese guy. Oh,
I know what the fuck you
are. You're this, oh,
you're an African guy on what the fuck
you are. You're this. No, that's nonsense.
There's a broad spectrum in each and
every classification, but at the,
at the end of the day, we're all the
same thing because we're all just people.
Yeah. Wait, what, 100% I mean, it's
just when you talk about heaven,
like pride in, in, in it I feel
like helps a little bit more if I,
if I identify with like as a black
American, you know, instead of,
instead of like an African American,
it's just see what you're saying.
You know what I mean? I feel like
I said a little more, you know,
I just look different,
you know what I mean?
Like I'm more integrated and it
would give me more pride to beat it.
You know what I'm saying?
And, and I think that's still,
you were obviously all the same
in there needs to be integration,
but you still have to have some type
of identity. You know what I'm saying?
I know what you're saying. Yeah. I mean,
and I think that the movie in itself
did a good job. Uh, I don't know.
I just went back to Black Panther,
Black Panther.
I think it did a great job in
describing like the differences,
there are differences between the black
community and the African and African
Community. You know what I mean?
Or African Africa itself and it,
because you get that,
you get that like anger,
you know what I mean?
Like that's like the stereotype
is like the black angry black man.
But some of it stems from not no one
where you're from and not having that core
identity.
And I feel like we can just do that
again here in America as black Americans
instead of,
I hope. Yeah. I hope
what it represents is a,
it's a meter to register
that racism is dying. Yeah.
And that this is,
this is also people in,
there's a lot of like white people that
were going way out of their way to go
see it because they wanted to show
everybody that they're not racist.
But I think that's good
too. Yeah. Ultimately it's,
it's showing that this is something that
people recognize as a stupid problem
and we should get past it.
It took God damn long enough.
You done, I mean, what,
we're probably going to be telling this
to our grandchildren and they're still
going to be experiencing some of it.
And then there's going to be something
new comes out and be like, God,
we just now doing this. Like, you know,
that's the way it's just going to be. Uh,
but for me personally, you know,
he's just eight cause everybody,
every kid wants to be a sober here. I'm
like, oh, how are you doing? You know? So
a lot of them, you can be half
of the empire and be blade.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, yeah, but played was
like a hit man. You know what I mean?
It goes back to what you see
around me. If I only see the, the,
the drug dealers and the,
you know, in every, you know,
there was never a black superhero and it
was like, all right, well shit. All right.
You know, we didn't go
up there, Huh? Yeah.
And it portrayed us as scientists
or, you know, it was a loud, I just
white get over it guys. That doesn't
register for you cause they're all white.
Every fucking superhero. Batman,
spider man. Even the Hawk is white oak
first. Yeah. And I mean, I, and
I, I get it from a lot of it.
I mean there's just, it's just
culture. You know what I mean?
And it's not better or worse than one
thing or another. You know, there,
there's Hawaiian culture,
there's, there's, you know,
it's just culture and it just,
that needs to be celebrated too,
because the more you celebrate culture,
the more you can integrate between
all of them. Right. And then
there's the real problem with,
I don't want those cultures to go away.
Yeah.
I was in Chinatown in Boston this
weekend and we went and ate dinner at two
o'clock in the morning. It's Chinese
restaurant. It's China town, right? Jamie?
What that place was? China
town, they got like fucking, uh,
Alaskan king crabs and a fish tank. Like,
how the fuck did you even get that here?
It's still alive.
All these fish on top of each other and
they pull the fish out of the tank and
cook it up for you. I mean, it's like
they barely speak English. I mean,
this is their culture and I want that to
still exist too. You know what I mean?
I just want them to be accepted
100% I mean, and, and
that's the beauty about it.
And I think you need to keep that alive.
You know,
there's two different spectrums to it.
There's the, there's the, the person,
it's just like, oh, just go
ahead and get over it. Right.
And there is a person that just like,
okay, what you don't even have, like,
they don't want even like,
uh,
like I did it or acknowledge your culture,
you know what I mean?
They just want to like, just
shun it or just not, you know,
just put it in a closet somewhere
and you know that that's almost the,
it's the opposite, but it's just
as bad as just needs to be though.
A buddy of mine who lives on
the big island about that,
he's a white guy and he lives in Hawaii
and he grew up in Hawaii and I said,
did you experience a lot of racism
against white people? He's like, no,
cause I'm not a fucking asshole. And I
said, that's what it is, right? It's like,
yeah, man. He goes, you can't be a white
guy coming over here trying to push your,
uh, you know, mainland culture is like,
this is the fucking culture dude. He goes,
if you just accept the culture
the way it is out here, he goes,
they're not racist.
Let's see if you can get a good,
you could gonna run into a few,
but for the most part you're
going to run into a few eight everywhere
you go. Because people were like,
you got to go back to it. Like people are
fucking idiots in every walks of it. Uh,
but for the most part it's always, you're
not. It has no you good. Right. I mean,
and this,
it's the same way across the board.
And I've kind of realized that as I'm,
as I'm getting older,
because before I just thought, you
know, we've just what we are. Right.
You know what I mean? I've got family
members that only will ever see Detroit.
They will only ever see those same blocks.
They will only ever see the same people.
And that's just what you think it is.
And it's just like, oh, so much
now there's so much, much more.
And it's not that different that you
think is different is it's different.
But you know what I'm saying? It's
not, it's not alien. It's just,
it's just different. It's just different.
It's not better. It's not worse.
One of the things that I really enjoyed
about traveling so much with the UFC,
as you got to see all these different
cultures and you got to see all these
different styles of life that
these people live in and you know,
you kind of like put it all together
and you, you, it just gives you,
I think this is one of the best things
about traveling is that it gives you this
more rounded perspective.
Like if you lived in Italy,
you'd be like one of these people, if this
is how they live, they live like this.
You know, if you lived in Dublin,
you'd be like this, this is,
this is their style of living.
Yeah.
And it's,
and it's important to acknowledge I
think all those different styles until,
you know, and of living.
Uh, and that, and,
and I think if you really want to like
cure racism in American, all that,
and it's just being open about it
and just talking and, you know,
people understand other
people's upbringing is,
and what they went through and what they
do because that makes you understand it
more if you try and just shun it away or
just say if you even bring up the word
black or white or it's anything like
people get, you know, you kind of see it.
Sometimes people get tense and
it's just like, just, just,
just be honest about it and just be open
about it. And that will make it go away.
It's not, it's not, you know, shun it.
Well,
don't want to be uncomfortable.
They don't want to talk
about uncomfortable shit.
So if something comes up that's a, well,
you know, as a black man, you're like, oh,
here we go. I didn't do it.
Okay. I never had a slave. Okay.
You know, and you're like, all right man,
you just super uncomfortable
with being uncomfortable. You,
I think that makes you that more
of the ass over there. You know,
you're talking to a human being.
If you really want to have
a conversation with them,
you want to know their actual experience.
You know?
And if their experience is as a Puerto
Rican that came from Puerto Rico,
that feels disc,
a lot of Puerto Ricans feel
super disconnected with
the United States because
they're not really United States citizens,
but they are, it's like a weird thing.
It's Kinda like, it's not
really a state, but it's,
it's of protected by the United States.
And so they're disconnected.
And there's a, like on the east
coast growing up with Puerto Ricans,
there's a weird,
they have a weird alienation.
If you don't want to talk to them and
you don't want to hear about that from
them,
that's fine,
but you're just going to miss out on
that part of what life is for them.
You're never going to get it.
Yeah. And all the things that
they bring to it, and you know,
the food that they bring that to
different arts, you know what I mean?
The different styles of fighting that
they bring, the different dances,
like everything is about the culture.
You're going to miss if you try and just,
you know,
shy away from it.
Martial arts is a perfect example of
like all these different cultures coming
together as one boiling pot.
Yeah.
Yeah. I mean, and,
and that does help me get us one of
the most beautiful things about it.
It's just I can go over to Ireland and
fight a Russian in Ireland and you know,
is, it's different than going down to
Brazil then find the Brazilian, you know,
or something like that.
It's just sure.
But it's at the core of it is still is
fighting. It's just different styles of,
of being able to do it.
But everybody does it.
What's crazy to me is how when you go
to these other places like Brazil or
Ireland or something like that, like how
rabid they are for their local people.
Yeah, yeah. Well you find someone
who's Brazilian in Brazil.
I mean maybe it's
relaxed a little bit now,
but I was there for some of
the earlier years as well.
And I've made the mistake of
flipping off the crowd before, uh,
at the way is because, because
Lou, you down there, uh,
for Cisco Toronado Oh,
bottom. Yeah. So he, you know,
three times a Brazilian
kickboxing champion, a monstrous,
that was one of the, at the
height of his, you know,
he's on a seven fight win streak. He
was feeling good. He was, you know,
Kinda had his labs were on until he was,
he wasn't tough at a one 85 pound,
two big gates, big guru. A hit
like a truck too. But you know,
before the way is they, they scream at
you gonna die. And I'm like, all right,
you know, I, I'm a shit talker. So you,
you, you've talked that shit to be,
I'm giving it back to you.
I love loving it.
It was a good Dewey too.
I'm loving it,
but I mean they were rabid for that when
people were throwing stuff at me as I
was walking out, uh, I kinda just threw
my headphones in and just went to town.
But yeah, they got a lot of
pride in Brazil and they love it.
But lot around the world,
a lot of the the,
because I think they truly
appreciate the art of what they do.
And it is a representation of
the culture there. You know,
for sure what Jujitsu for
sure, for sure. When they,
when they get somebody that's Damien Maia,
you know,
they kind of stand behind that man because
he represents the art of it or just
MMA, a general, like they,
they appreciate the art of it.
Russia is appreciate the art of what
they do, you know, the Sabo and you know,
it's so deep rooted in a culture,
uh, in a, in American is due to,
I mean for the most part he's just,
we don't get as behind our
own fighters I think is, yeah,
we have a certain amount
of loyalty but we're,
so this is such an ambitious
country. Yeah. Hello. Hey,
you gotta win some money.
Know we're shy talks of shit.
And we're like,
well listen man, you're doing all
those things right now. Hello.
I'm trying to do it slowly but surely.
I think there was a good conversation
too cause I think people understand you
more now. Yeah. Get a better sense of
who you are. I got, I got a couple of,
you know, I've got a couple of layers
to view you got to do. You do, Kevin.
I really appreciate it,
man. I really enjoyed this
conversation puffers. All right.
That's it. Fuckers. See Ya.
Okay.
Hmm.