Trying my day,
Joe Rogan podcast by night all day.
There's very few things that are as
painful as listening to bad corner work.
Oh,
that's fun.
Oh yeah.
I went down to his liver and a quarter I
go,
he just read.
You don't want him to throw a right hand
right now.
You know.
Let him keep that here so the liver is
protected and I go,
yeah,
that's an idiot.
Exactly.
Who Does it see that?
Did you watch the fights this weekend?
Yeah,
I did.
What did you think about steep and
Allison?
That was crazy.
So crazy.
I might differ.
Or three or four last punches you gave
there on an inch.
They're all exact at the same spot.
It's got really good precision.
Yeah,
just stopped him and he got hit hard.
He waved it off,
but then that guillotine and we know 11
guillotines.
I believe that he had beats right and
tight once.
People being a one time I say,
I want to feel it.
I go,
Whoa,
this is a really tight guilty.
But he got out.
He's in a.
he's a freak athlete.
He really is,
and he's a very likable guy.
He's awesome.
Steve is a good guy.
We were talking about his composure.
Yes sir.
Yes.
So composed like in Brazil when he
fought for breach you to stare down.
He's just dead faced.
He's got his own dead face.
It's not like a fade or dead face or
cane dead phase.
He's got his own dead phase,
but those guys that can just stay
completely calm,
you know,
in that incredible environment of being
there in Brazil.
Forty 5,000 plus people screaming for
breezy overdue and he just shuts his
lights out.
One of the things on our own or our main
battle right,
is being able to,
to control ourselves and he's looks to
have mastered that ability to control
his own emotions,
to make sure he's directing the energy
in the right path.
So Steep Bay,
good job.
Could ask Papa.
Oh,
he's a bad motherfucker.
Would it be interesting to see if
someone got into his head the way like
you and dominic were going after each
other or the way connor got into all
those head?
I guess that was a masterclass and fuck,
and when someone's head absolutely mean
connor took,
although completely out of his element
where he was just so frazzled by the
time they actually met each other inside
the octagon.
It was just,
I think we're at the overeem and the
just shameless Hoven Rosie.
Rosie's intimidating everybody the way
she is and she wants.
She stood at the stare down.
That's when she lost because she
realized holly didn't care at all.
She was just there.
I'm going to hurt you.
That was.
And that's the same as everybody's
intimidated by overeem and you shouldn't
be because he's a monster.
But I think over and could see in his
face already hit.
He's not intimidated.
This guy has absolutely no.
And then when you fight a guy like that,
that,
that little voice starts playing in
your,
in your mind when it gets bad,
you know,
and that's why maybe we saw these crazy
things of running away,
you know,
which I,
I say it's a good thing because I said
the same thing.
I guess Cortland Mcgregor,
but you know,
for a big,
huge heavy weight,
it doesn't look good,
you know,
and now you,
you set yourself up more as effective
because he's following you in fact.
And that all is an input in your,
in your own brain because now you start
telling yourself,
oh,
everybody thinks I'm a,
uh,
I'm hurt or that I'm afraid of.
Am I afraid I'm,
you know,
there's the whole cow thing that goes on
in the mind.
There's always these two forces I say to
one force wants to quit,
that Yoda voice wants to go,
right?
You know,
you're a really bad situation.
And then say,
okay,
call it quits Colloquy,
wait,
wait to know that.
Let's just,
let's just see what happens,
you know,
and then suddenly you come out of the
situation like I was.
I was about to step in my second fight
and then the audience started cheering
for him and then my ego to go over.
I go,
okay,
I get out of the situation.
And then 30 seconds later I knocked him
out with the need to deliver and I go,
okay,
this is the last time I'm going to think
like that because before the I stay away
from the bad voice.