Okay,
we get a bunch of gigs in my house,
ladies.
Gentlemen.
Legion of skanks.
Yeah,
very excited.
All you guys together.
This was a good move.
Good idea.
What's all credit to praise?
Praise to big J.
fucked it up.
You do.
But I'm,
I'm glad this is a.
This is fun.
Longtime coming.
Fuck yeah.
Thanks for having us.
My pleasure.
I'm very excited to be here.
Mr.
Rogen Legion to Sancton the house.
I'm going to tell you right now what we
really mean.
This,
this has been a very,
very long time comment.
All of the fans have been,
uh,
have been kind of looking for this
moment.
So this is a very,
very big deal for me personally.
So I want to say thanks for having a
song,
a sentence away from crying.
We're all so big.
We probably shouldn't be talking in
public.
Cheers.
Gentleman.
You wrote that last night.
Little Mr.
Rogen,
how I spent my summer was good and we
went to the park and we got to ride all
the rides.
It's true.
What do you want me to say here these
days?
Yeah.
Pretend that it's not a big deal.
It's a huge deal.
Lewis.
Rarely impressed.
Very unimpressed guy and he's really
impressed today.
Yeah.
This is a fucking Disneyland for dudes
that we're in right now.
It we're in an airport hangar and
there's just bow and arrows and dead
animals and pool tables and a job
battlebots the.
I feel most men live lives that are
very,
very suppressed.
Sure.
Most men,
if they were left to their own devices
and someone said,
yeah,
you do whatever you want in the
building.
Wait a minute.
I can just decide what to put in the
building,
whatever to pull whatever in the
building.
You do the exact same shit for archery.
Set up things that I wanted.
I wanted to make sure there was room for
an indoor range.
That was when you went into buying a
place.
Interesting conversation with a real
estate agent.
What I need at least 40 yards insurance
for that.
I said,
can I virtual Hunt Dana?
Is it requests that virtual hunt game is
a very popular game,
that techno hunt thing.
That thing is.
It's so cool.
Addictive.
Addictive though he can give you bad
habits to get a little punchy with your
trigger.
I do like that they have some of the,
uh,
animations,
not the where the real life things or
the deer or the elk.
They're looking at you.
They really do give you a sad face.
Now you do it.
Can you do it?
Yeah,
you can probably get it with other
things too,
right?
Like,
couldn't you get it with superheroes?
Couldn't you get it like you were that
archer dude from the avengers and
fucking those monsters are coming after
your children because I don't want to do
it for me.
Can we upload everyone who bullied Lewis
in the third grade?
Kids.
That's the,
uh,
that's the same kids.
That's like when they give the uh,
pedophiles like little,
like underage fuck dollars to try to
keep him from doing it.
For Real.
She murdered kids with a bow and arrow.
She'd never do that.
Give it to them.
Now they're available in Asia.
Some control box.
I've heard you can match up up robots
and not in this country.
I found out.
It's a weird moral thing though,
right?
Like would you or would you rather have
them fuck a little robot in their closet
somewhere because your first instinct is
always like,
oh,
that's horrible,
but then you're like,
it's Kinda like giving someone with
anger issues a punching bag.
Maybe.
It's not the worst thing.
It's like they've got that thing,
whatever it is.
Like how do you get it out on that
little sweet,
sweet,
beautiful punching bags.
So fucked up feature lists.
Robots don't punch back.
Do you want to like meet in the middle
and you're like,
okay,
it's legal,
but you can't name it.
Well,
do you think that you could fuck a real
doll?
I mean you definitely could if you had
to,
but would that be something you'd be
interested in?
I think I couldn't stop laughing at how
ridiculous this situation rather just
jerk off and think about things.
I fucked a.
We had as a sponsor,
a flush left.
I've had a flashlight forever.
It's very utilitarian.
You're not confusing yourself.
Nobody's ever said that word before
describing she's the girl of my dreams.
I've never even used it.
I've had it forever.
I've never even thought about it.
I couldn't guess why I would want to use
it.
Seems Weird.
It's weird.
It feels good though.
Does it way better than jerking off
sculpture whole Dick.
Yeah,
and you put it in warm water and you get
it like to attempt to a body and your
life somehow or another.
There's like a portal,
like this tube is a portal to another
woman or another dementia,
but all you can get at is her vagina.
Just hold it.
That's it.
Feels real.
The name of this dimension is called
awesome.
Do you jerk off with a fleshlight or do
you hold it and fuck it now?
He jerked off.
Jerked me off with the flashlight.
Yeah,
but that was for show.
That was on camera behind the curt
green.
This interview.
We did this on the podcast.
I swear to God.
He jerked me off for the producer now.
I couldn't get hard.
There was a female comic.
Whoa.
What's that about?
Is that a real.
That's a real real though.
They get pretty good man.
They were red head though.
It was a documentary on Netflix.
About sex robots really have come far
because there are people who fall in
love with these sex robots and it looks
like the fucking taxi driver,
Johnny on the spot from total recall.
It's like,
it's crazy like animatronic chucky
cheese,
bass player was kind of get to a point
where it can totally mimic you and he's
going to get to a point where it really
is like blade runner,
is that what they are now?
That's the one I thought about buying a
dude one to do Jujitsu with.
I was going to order clearly.
No.
Jake and butthole
proportions are perfect because I have a
doll.
It's Bubba dummy the practice
submissions on,
but it's super stiff.
It's like this,
but he beat you.
You basically can drill the moves,
but it's not the same as drilling and on
an anatomically correct body.
If you had an AMA anatomically correct
body to practice Jujitsu on,
you can get some fucking tight moves.
Can't wait,
can't wait til the day.
When you're announcing for robot fights,
no,
the zero interest.
There's nothing at stake.
If they live or die,
it doesn't matter.
The whole thing about fighting is that
there's some horrible,
gigantic thing at stake.
You can fuck one though.
Yeah,
you can fuck with him.
Fight.
Would you watch two robots?
Fuck.
I would.
I would if there was like some sort of a
program that they were running,
I'd want to see like what the program
was,
how they could do it.
Yeah.
It wouldn't be a jack material.
We completely be fascinated.
They would probably talk to each other
and numbers and they would both be dudes
that would both be.
There was one that they just made a fuck
dollar.
Right.
And this,
this just happened that there's videos
of it.
The robot sort of speaking like a weird
code to each other.
These were like fucking like straight up
fuck dolls.
Skynet,
dude.
And they would turn them on and then
they sort of speaking and would seem
like a code and people were like
freaking out about this.
Oh I know what you're talking about.
Yeah.
They had these computers,
computer.
There were there were linked together
and they started communicating to each
other in a language that the coders
didn't understand and they shut it off.
They're like,
what?
Just simply tell them plugged in,
but I heard that my version of it that I
just said might be the most spectacular
version sounding but might not be
accurate and that what do they might've
gotten is like they might have got stuck
in like a feedback loop and just been
making jibberish.
Right.
I heard that too.
So I don't know.
No one's confirmed way too fucking
stupid to know who's right.
Let's just hope it's that second one.
The first one I just want sounds like a
opening scene in terminator,
but at the same terms as the solution
being like,
don't plug that in.
And again man,
like what the fuck are we going to do?
Like I had a podcast with Sam Harris
about it and he is terrified of ai and
he's far smarter than me.
So whenever I talked to him about shit,
I go,
oh,
okay.
And he's terrified.
Terrified.
That's what freaks me out is when people
way smarter than me are terrified about
it.
Like,
uh,
what's his name?
Eli muskets.
Terrified Stephen Hawkins,
Stephen.
I'm like,
no,
this is going bad.
And then you're like,
Shit.
Sometimes they're too close to it,
you know?
I feel like some people also get too
bogged down to the details when you live
your life very ignorantly,
like I do,
I have no fear of AI technology guy.
So I'll be honest with you.
Just self driving tesla already kill
somebody or just self driving.
Taxi rower.
She did something very reckless.
She walked right into traffic and she
might've been homeless lady.
She might've been on drugs.
They're not,
they're not exactly sure.
I don't think the results of the autopsy
route yet.
But uh,
you watched the video,
she basically just walks right in
front of the car.
The car is going down the road.
So a person driving wouldn't have made
much difference maybe.
I don't know,
man.
It was hard to tell whether or not you'd
be able to react.
But I guess the technology is,
does it have,
you know,
the technology of stopping quick enough
to not hit somebody.
They want to make it safer?
Right.
That's the idea.
But I think it is right.
I think there's more human error when
you're dealing with people drinking,
smoking weed,
paying attention to their cell phones.
I almost would rather just trust,
you know,
even if there's a few deaths per year,
there's way more deaths per year with
just laid out the logic for why the
robots are going to the lady in black.
I trust them.
Was a black lady.
I don't know.
It will be fine.
There's another video,
but just stopping perfectly for a white
woman who ran the test needs to reflect
on anything dark in the Mediterranean.
It just fucking run.
The Tesla stops it all of stops it
Persian.
It turns out just through science it has
like the same racism of like the 18
nineties where they're like,
we'll give the Italians have passed the
rest of you guys.
There's two different types of Mexicans
is those Oscar de la Hoya Mascot
Mexicans.
And then there's other Mexicans that
look like Indian or the mustache starts
on the edge of the lip.
Where would it,
where would it go with them?
You know?
You know,
that's what the comment.
That's what Mexico is essentially,
right?
It was a combination of the native
Americans and Spanish.
Yeah.
And I think.
And then the Spanish ones are like,
uh,
you know,
they're the ones who are like,
look down at the locals,
but at this point they're all kind of
mixed I think.
But there's still just a different
shape.
That's a real Canelo Alvarez.
Yeah.
Right.
Fucking red headed.
Very bizarre.
Looking at ck is another one.
He's already had a Mexican dude.
Yeah.
Crazy.
I never even think about that.
Louise should have started playing that
card a lot harder after the New York.
His first,
his apology letter should have been
like,
well,
as a Mexican girl Jag,
I believe he was born in Mexico.
I'm not sure about that though.
He was either born in Mexico.
He definitely lived in Mexico.
Really?
I would never have guessed that.
Yeah.
My family lives in Mexico.
They retired to Mexico.
My parents did really want to fucking
chill out.
Jesse the body Ventura talks about
Mexico.
It's a lot of reverence.
Lived there.
I've got a buddy of mine who's got a
place in Cabo and he loves it.
He loves it.
It's okay.
Cop was a particularly do.
She said he,
like,
I went there to do comedy festival and
it's like straight up the worst people
from like thinking about the worst,
like 40 year old couple from like your
hometown,
just like fake Tan assholes.
Florida city,
Florida.
But then they all go and meet up in one
town.
So it's just like thousands of fucking
awful people in hot ass.
Mexico.
Um,
I don't get it.
I don't get any.
I don't understand.
If you smoke weed,
why you would go to the Caribbean and
not just go to Jamaica every single
time.
Is Jamaica the spot dog dog.
He loves it.
I love it.
Cool.
He's pushing it hard on us.
Preface with dog.
He's being serious.
I've never been.
Well actually I was,
but it was just like a stop on a cruise
and I didn't really thought about doing
a skanks cruise.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
We have to actually do that.
We do our comedy festival every summer
and we thought about doing your weight.
It's funny,
the festival was influenced by the
cruise because we did these cruises and
the idea is you can't escape the,
you know,
the bands can't escape the cruise ship.
You're hanging out the whole fucking
time.
So it's not like you're going to a
comedy festivals in 10 different
locations.
It's,
you're going to see a shell.
Right.
Skank fest is all one location.
It's a party,
you know,
two and a half days nonstop.
You're in one location.
So everybody's hanging out and drinking.
We're doing it this year at a place
called Brooklyn bazaar in greenpoint.
Brooklyn.
It's like a huge.
It's an old Polish catering hall.
It has like four different rooms.
We're gonna have three different stages
going on simultaneously.
It's really good.
And how did red should fear get the
publicity scoop?
I believe he organized the festival
rightly.
He's a piece of shit.
He got the scoop on.
You did that motherfucker now already.
I fucking love already to death,
but he.
How many pills I love already.
Death,
but however he's a motherfucker crushers
podcast,
burt's wife hated red May.
Still we were talking about before the
podcast that all of our friends that got
fuck you money already said fuck you.
The hardest.
Like he does what he wants to do.
It's amazing.
No,
it's fucking beautiful man.
Everyday that I'm running around,
he's like Asian food at a place
somewhere to an escape room in the
middle of the day.
He's like playful.
I think as kids we're all trying to grow
up and uh,
you know,
make money and do what we do.
But I think the idea is we're all
supposed to be playing this.
Why I,
you know,
I'm joking when I say this,
like a do Disneyland,
but you come in here and you created an
environment to play every day and
that's,
that's success today,
right?
Like it to do what you want to do every
single day.
Play with the toys you want to play
with.
Hanging out the people you want to play
And I think everyone thinks like when
you don't have money,
you think when you get money.
Yeah,
that's what I'll be like.
But then I've watched so many people who
do get money and then they're like,
yeah,
but gotta have retirement money.
Got To make sure I have this,
got to make sure I do that.
You know what I mean?
And like artist lives the way you
thought you would have before you had
it?
Yeah.
He's not,
he's not like flashy either.
Like he won't even buy a new car that
fuck,
he's got a flip phone and he's got like,
he's like a minimalist addiction.
He's,
he's definitely a minimalist for sure.
But the flip phones a decision because
it was like the fucking he sees he's,
he's a very smart guy.
He's looking around and all these other
people with their cell phones looking at
himself and he's like,
oh,
that thing's just stealing your time and
you're addicted to it.
You know?
Everyone's definitely.
I'm definitely addicted to my phone.
But the bad thing is that reo just
texted me a googleable question.
What's the weather in Philly or
something?
And you're like,
alright,
this is.
He said he mixes it up between his
friends.
So it doesn't get too annoying to anyone
person.
Smart.
But it was funny as if he has to listen
to music,
he has to carry around like an extra
large ipad to hold his headphones.
So that's hilarious.
Oh yeah,
that's hilarious.
Yeah.
The ipad in the back of his,
in the back of his pants,
like a fucking,
like a gun.
He like inspiring.
He's,
I would have myself a like at a comedy
club of looking at it and are able to
literally come and take his hand and put
it over the phone and be like,
dude,
what are you doing?
Stop.
We hang out,
talk to us.
And it kind of inspired,
made me self conscious around other
people doing it.
And now every time I see people doing
it,
I sort of judged them now.
And it,
it really is true.
I mean people live in their cell phone
every single day and you lose the
connection.
People are,
it sends a message like,
fuck you dude,
this person over here is more important
than the person that's sitting right in
front of me.
Well,
it's just the phone.
This,
that light is addictive.
It's addictive.
Looking at the images,
it's like,
you know what happens when a little kid
sees a TV.
You ever see that little kid walks in a
room with a TV and commercials going on
in the kids like this,
just staring at it because it fucks with
the way you take in like visual
information.
There's nothing like that in the wild.
There's something like a big screen tv
in the wild,
right?
Like that image of Super Bowl on a big
screen,
TV and hd and you're like,
Holy Shit.
You're looking all the green light.
All the guys running around smashing
into each other.
It's intense.
You don't get that in a real life thing
unless you're about to get eaten.
Yeah.
We'd like to take that serious,
but we've evolved to like see that and
treat it like a big cat running at you
or something.
Right?
That's what it is,
but it's on your phone and you're
watching youtube videos like,
look at all that shit.
Moving around on my phone.
I also like to kill time of a.
to where my trick pointed out the other
day,
if we.
If we ever sit down at a restaurant,
like don't take food to go and sit down,
how quickly I pull out,
like we're playing family feud so it's
not even just like a pulling back into
my phone,
but there's still a part of like the
let's do something right.
Does anybody have a topic?
No.
Alright,
let's talk about.
Let's just play family feud.
If you give yourself a day in a weird
way,
you ended up,
you make it even worse.
And I live in New York,
said we all do and like they sort of
doing like little signs in the subway
that lets you know how long it is before
the subway is going to come.
And that's pretty.
No.
Um,
when I first moved there in 2001,
you would just go.
I'm like,
dude,
I might be here for 30 minutes.
I might be here for two minutes.
Who knows when the next subway is going
to come.
But now for subway sign is broken.
I can't wait on that platform.
I have to got to get up and leave and
get a taxi or whatever because I'll lose
my mind.
Just wondering when that calf is going
to come,
whereas before you would just chill out
and wait because you had to,
you didn't have the option to.
So now I feel like you have that option
to be on your phone at all times,
distract yourself,
used to take a shit and you know the
bathroom reader,
it was my favorite thing in the world.
It was a little facts like thousands of
them in this fat book that you just was
covered in.
Shit stands ever fucking fuck you out of
the bathroom.
And it was called uncle John's bathroom
reader and it was just basically snapple
facts about everything in the world and
handling 20th and it was the coolest
thing in the world.
But now you have your cell phone so you
know,
I mean it
right?
But how do you.
There's just certain shit.
You want to know what's going on in the
world.
So how do you check in on that?
Jesus do it from a computer or like when
you want to read the news,
like I don't know.
How do you get your news?
Oh,
I,
I'm on the laptop on the phone all the
time and yeah,
and then I just tell these guys what
they need to know.
Just go get it straight from the trump
ban.
Yeah.
But I'm on the Paul Band.
Really come down to taxes.
Are you guys,
do you know that?
Very few legit
comics who are as knowledgeable.
I mean you guys have Dave's a very
valuable resource.
Very much so.
Really standing.
He's brilliant Dave.
He's like literally the only person that
I know that actually reads the books
puts in the time in and it's kind of
funny.
We say where,
where people get their news,
they don't really get their news.
They read the headline and then they act
like they're getting their fucking news.
They're not putting in the time that
aren't reading the books and actually
going and reading a real newspaper
reading you,
you know,
that gentleman pisses what pisses me off
about politics.
I feel like it's the only thing where
like if you don't like.
So if you don't,
uh,
if,
if Lewis doesn't watch
basketball@allandj.watches
every single sixers game,
but then there's like a thing coming up
where like something about a basketball
game,
Louis won't just start arguing with you
like,
Nah,
they need to play this defense.
They need to go into a zone because
you're like,
yeah,
I just,
I don't really know about that.
But for some reason with politics,
yeah.
No matter how much anybody's not read
anything,
they don't know anything.
They have no problem.
Just having a hard core strong opinion
like,
oh,
use.
Because I'll see you
know about it.
Right?
So when someone's like super
argumentative about it,
like,
oh,
you're not even well informed,
which is most of the case with people
that are really super aggressive about
it.
It seems like.
I mean,
do they have this thing where they were
interviewing people at the fucking march
for life?
I think they called it the gun control
march.
How feel just now?
Well,
no,
they were like all owners in a bunch of
different cities that we saw it,
but it happened at a bunch of different
cities.
I think the big ones were in DC and I
think there was one out here like that.
There was this guy just interviewing
people and he'd go around and ask them
if they,
uh,
if they are for an assault weapons ban
and they'd be like,
yes,
and then he'd go,
what's an assault weapon?
And it's amazing how many people just
didn't know.
Now I'm not even.
Whatever your take on an assault weapon
ban is,
it's like,
how could you be for banning something
that you can't even define as?
Just hold on a second.
Yeah,
exactly.
You're like,
they know that this is what it does.
They,
you know,
a rifle that shoots people.
It's like a semiautomatic.
It's on a hunting gun.
So rifle is designed to shoot people,
like in a military situation,
that's what it looks like.
So they're raw,
they don't know what an ar 15 versus an
or whatever versus like what's legal,
what's semiautomatic,
what's.
They'll know all the details,
but they do know that these are guns
that kill people with.
Okay,
sure.
Fair enough.
But I feel like there's like a thing
where there'll be like one for a ban on
semiautomatic weapons,
so you want to ban handguns soon.
They're like,
no,
we want a bad hand guns,
but guns are semiautomatic weapons.
It's just like if you're gonna protest,
read a book on it.
It's not just having a passive opinion.
You're like out marching to.
You know,
they want to move the ball down the
field though,
and the more people that come here,
they have kids,
literally kids that are in the fifth
grade walking out of their classrooms.
They don't fucking know what they're
talking about or what they're doing.
Their task sometimes.
There was a girl with armpit hair,
you want to fuck me?
That's true or dirty Harry.
Harry.
Every tone mean.
But how many of these kids,
this is a big one.
How many kids are against putting kids
on psychotropic drugs,
putting kids on unnecessary psychiatric
medications.
Parents dope their kids up all the time
because they don't want to deal with
some hyperactive kid.
Some kid has got some fucking power,
some energy.
He said I saw the walls on.
I was in.
We were embracing the other day right
before the show we did.
And there was a kid,
I mean he must've had autism or or
something or some extreme case of it.
Uh,
but he was like,
you know,
he was having some sort of violent
episode,
I'm assuming,
but it was just a dad,
like calm as day just sitting on a
corner with this kid with the kid face
down as a kids,
like screaming and shaking and kicking
his arms and legs.
And then I was just holding the kid down
and it was so hard to like,
I almost wanted to say something like,
I didn't know.
I know they don't ever really tell you
what to do,
like,
what's going on in that situation.
And I kind of watched it for a minute
because it looked like he was abusing
the kid for a second,
but then you kind of realize that like,
oh,
this kid was gonna like hurt himself or
whatever it was.
But that's like a,
that's like a really,
really hard thing.
Yeah,
I can,
I can accept more in the real extreme
cases where kids have like severe,
severe,
severe problems,
but it seems like they're just happy to
like anyone's like,
hyperactive,
just this kind of loose thing.
So no matter all,
it's not a one or a zero.
Right.
It's like there's,
there's varying stages of issues that
kids are going to have and some kids are
going to need some kind of medication,
but they're definitely over prescribing.
Definitely.
I knew my neighbor had a kid.
There was nothing wrong with them.
It's just a fucking kid.
And they put him on Ritalin or adderall
is a drug man.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
That's,
it's not.
I give it to my five year old.
We snorted together.
If people don't get enough attention or
they don't have an outlet and they don't
know what to do with themselves,
they get wacky.
It doesn't mean you need to give them
drugs.
Some of these people have legitimate
issues and they probably do need
medication and some of these people just
need to find something that's
interesting in life.
Yeah.
Well I think what you were saying before
about like,
why don't these kids look into that
stuff?
I think a lot of times it's just like
people want the simple thing and got to
actually.
This is a really difficult question to
get into this stuff.
Whereas if you're just like,
oh,
I'm against guns,
that's easy.
I think it's the same thing as when
people are just offended it.
It's like you don't really have to like
read a lot.
You don't have to know a lot.
You just easy to be right and you've got
the answer.
It's laziness.
People can just pick a side very easily
and go,
cool.
Everyone's already defined was on that
side,
so yeah,
I'm on that side.
I did my work right,
and it's the same being a parent parent.
A lot of parents are really lazy and
you,
you watch it happen when they give their
kid an ipad or I,
you know,
or you know,
put them in front of the computer.
That whole thing just happened with Elsa
Gate,
which was,
you know,
borderline hilarious that parents were
getting trolled into their kids watching
really fucked up like cartoon.
I forgot the name of it.
That's the name of it.
Yeah.
That was crazy.
We've talked about that a bunch of times
about the babies with the broken bottles
over their head up,
having the same scene play out.
Kids would get drunk whether they were a
kid,
mice or kill ducks or they would get
drunk.
A bottle would go flying through the air
and hit the baby in the head and blood
would be everywhere.
It was like a baby's nightmare to.
Those videos were so crazy.
David Lynch,
it was a punishment for shitty parents
who weren't watching their kids and what
they're putting on their tv because if
you were just paying attention for a
minute you.
I'm saying right it you have to stop
paying attention for a couple of hours
for a kid to get there,
so it was only really shitty parents
that we're dealing with that.
Is that really true?
It's dude.
Yeah.
There was no way to like land on that
just by googling spiderman.
That wasn't the first one was coming up.
It was.
They would.
I think there were like paying to get in
like a loop of certain videos.
Like it was really.
I was obsessed with it for like a week
and I just couldn't stop going on under
that subreddit page and it was freaky
dude.
They weren't really porn spiderman ones
and all these.
I think they took some of them down but
it's.
But then it gets to this place where
you're like,
okay,
are you taking it down because it's
targeting children.
Are you taking it down because you can't
show cartoon babies getting hit in the
head with bottles because if that's what
you're saying,
boy,
there's a lot of fucking south parks
that you're not gonna be able to show.
There's a lot,
a lot,
a lot of different things.
You know,
little show.
So yeah.
Where's the line?
Because you think this is creepy and is
luring kids in versus the just the act
of it was a funny,
you know Tim and Eric Sketch.
Sure.
And a cartoon baby got hit in the head
with a bottle.
You'd be like,
what the fuck?
These guys are nuts.
That's what you'd say.
But you wouldn't be like saying this has
got to be removed off of Youtube.
Yeah.
It's hard to see the intention because
you could easily say like,
oh well South Park is a cartoon,
right?
So is that appealing to kids?
But I think to Lewis his point that the
solution isn't that this shit needs to
be banned.
The solution is just like let parents
know always the solution.
Every single time we talk about Louis.
What was the other one we watched?
Oh father your father with two kids and
it's really just creepy issue happen.
All right,
so this is another one of those like
that.
The kids are watching that.
If you watch it for a second,
you're like,
this is.
I pulled it off.
It was a dad and his channel,
um,
I'm sorry,
I forget the name of the channel,
but he had his two little girls who were
probably seven and nine years old and
they were doing like,
just kind of weird shit dude.
They're like eating chocolate bars and
it'd be chocolate all over their face
and you know,
they'd make weird sounds and they'd
climb up stairs and they'd show it from
like,
behind there.
But it was very fucking pedophilia cut.
Don't even know
it was fucked up dude.
And this guy is channel got taken down
and the guy's like doing interviews,
like,
Nah,
dude,
whatever.
We also millions of subscribers to the
channel making tons of money paying for
his house with this channel.
Whoa.
And they shut the whole channel now.
And what did he say when you interviewed
them?
I don't know,
I read some thing when it was just kinda
like,
yeah,
we're trying to get our channel back and
you know,
he was just like very innocent.
There was another thing the same again.
So fuck,
I'm on my own time.
I got to go to Vimeo.
Um,
but the same when we were talking about
this stuff that was mom's,
they were regular like mom bloggers.
Right?
And they bring like their daughter to
Kmart.
Right?
This is the channel,
by the way.
I'm youtube terminates toy freaks
channel amid broader crackdown on
disturbing kids content.
Okay.
It is very,
like what Jay said,
it's a very David Lynch type vibe.
Like you feel like you're in some
nightmare world where everyone's just
acting not the right human way.
That eight point $5 million subscribers,
gold plaques that you have amongst her
top most 100 most viewed channels on
youtube.
That's incredible.
Either pacifiers in their mouth.
It.
Dude,
it's fucking bizarre.
You gotta somehow somehow got to that
level before.
Can we watch some of this and I can't
show it.
You can't show it on TV.
Can we watch it?
Is there a way we can not see it?
We're about to get rated.
You get what you figured out?
Okay.
Yeah.
Don't know what the problem is.
Whenever we put something on youtube
that shouldn't be on youtube,
we get flagged this.
It was like mommy bloggers and they
would like have a video of them and
their daughter going to the supermarket
and it'd be like 500 views.
Yeah,
don't do it.
Jamie.
If I was thinking of Youtube flags it so
no one else could see it on another
website.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Louis what?
Okay.
I see.
So then they do another,
the same mommy blogger would do one
called bath time and she's like bathing
her five year old and it's not anything
more than her like sitting in the
bathtub.
But those videos were getting millions
of views and then the mom would disable
the comments and turn off the thumbs up
and the thumbs downs.
So they were just monetizing pedophiles
jerking off to their daughters in a
bathtub and it was just like a whole
subculture that was happening on youtube
that was sort of just.
Nobody was really talking about it and
they kind of made it go away.
It wasn't even a big deal.
So this,
I'm watching this.
It's not disturbing it all.
It's just dumb.
They just eating weird food and then and
getting like whip cream and ice cream
and cake and nachos altogether.
Well here's what happens.
Babies.
This is really targeted towards babies.
They liked the colors.
So what happened?
Like they see these flashing crazy
colors.
Then I'm packaging candy and cake and
eating cake and two year olds love this
shit.
They keep on clicking on it,
but pedophiles are also jerking off to
these girls putting chocolate bananas in
there.
So that was sort of the issue.
So they got the parents will subscribe
to whatever because the kids,
they want to put their kid in front of
the TV and have the TV babysit them,
but it was also another big part of the
people who are watching this.
You see the comments and sometimes the
comments were like encrypted and like in
different languages and they were using
code words.
Are they using that pizza gate yet?
It's all connected.
It's fucking crazy.
If you make a big complaint though about
something you have to draw a conclusion
to,
it really makes it seem like you're the
person thinking that you're like,
come on.
You don't think that's hot.
Yeah,
exactly.
You wouldn't want to jerk off to this.
C'Mon.
We're all jerking off to this day.
Who didn't jerk off to that little early
Mitchell that a cheetah with sour cream
on it.
I'll just go up to anybody and you're
just in it for the food.
Get these kids out of here family.
I didn't notice.
You say what can and can't be on TV
though or on video or on,
you know?
When do you say they're going to want
this,
but I know.
Right,
but whose day?
Right?
Because we've all.
We've all got this weird thing about
free speech because if it wasn't for
free speech,
we wouldn't be able to do anything,
wouldn't be able to do podcasts,
wouldn't be able to do comedy,
get in trouble for everything.
It's very important to be able to
express your ideas,
but what if those ideas are,
you're a.
you're a pedophile.
Like what if?
What about that?
Are you allowed to do pedophile anime?
Like how it would.
Where's the,
where's the line and why?
Why are we able to draw that line?
You know,
I draw a Dick Right now when I will
drive deck.
Here's a deck.
Now if I say this is a four year old
Dick.
Okay,
there you go.
Well,
I'll just say that four year olds got a
big Dick.
Just got a giant happy man.
He put a four year old posts around it
too soon.
But you read,
you raised a really good question.
It's like,
I think the way it's working now is it's
kind of whatever youtube decides or
facebook decides because truly we
decide,
right?
Yep.
Like they'll have these kind of like
vague policy guidelines,
but then you'll see some people violate
it and it's not a problem,
but if it's a message that they don't
like,
then that seems to be the one that gets
taken off.
I just,
I don't know,
man.
It's hard.
I,
I honestly,
I'm,
I would defend free speech toward
anything.
Like,
I don't care what you're saying,
unless you're inciting violence,
just legally speaking,
a defendant like you got to be allowed
to say anything.
Even if it's like I wanna fuck kids or
something that's really disgusting like
that.
As long as you're not actually fucking
kids,
you're not doing anything.
When I,
you gotTa have fuel,
do you think you should always employee
you're free ability for free speech
though?
Like sometimes just don't know.
Of course there's lots of things you
shouldn't say that place is different.
That's not like a park.
You see?
Here's the thing.
I think in our lifetime there's going to
be words that are bad that you're not
gonna be able to say in public spaces
like parks and shit like that.
I can say parks.
Rosa parks.
Yes.
It could be.
That's one of the ones that ask Jamie
Google something.
What was that?
Um,
the store recently where they were
talking about child brides somewhere in
some country where they were trying to
allow people to be married as young as
11 and that up until recently they could
do that.
They could be married as young as 11
pounds.
It's A.
Yeah,
it's a state.
Where's that just?
Is it.
Is it a state?
No.
Sierra Leone.
Is that what it is?
The article I just came up from
yesterday?
Yes,
that's it.
What age is it?
Didn't pop up.
I'm trying to see.
What I'm trying to say is like,
this is obviously just ask.
Sorry.
There's actually another one for
Missouri.
What's two hours ago?
I built to restrict child marriage and
Missouri moves forward.
It says,
oh,
I didn't see that one child marriage in
Missouri because people are fighting for
it.
That like,
yeah,
my baby should be able to get married at
12 years old.
Yeah.
Once you get married and he's not having
sex anymore,
so it's all day fucking parents idea.
It's not little kids clamoring to get
married.
Bill to restrict child marriage.
Missouri moves forward.
Whoa.
Hold the 15 year old.
Wow.
The only state that requires only of one
parent for 15 year old to marry has made
the state a popular destination for
child bride.
That is so good job to the best child.
Broad Getaway,
Missouri in Missouri is defense.
That's the only time they've ever been
referred to as a popular destination.
So they're.
They're doing what they can to attract
tourists.
Yeah,
that's dark.
That's dark because those places where
like,
you know,
professions are like moss gathering and
making some sort of sap juice.
You don't.
I'm like,
you can't marry a 15 year old though.
They can marry each other.
I'd imagine it's statutory rape is that,
you know,
there was a state where male to female,
the girl had to be 18,
but male to male,
the boiling had to be 13.
Well,
that's a little bit of a gap.
It was one of the states where they were
pedophiles.
The Catholic Church was sending
pedophiles kind of want to say it's New
Mexico.
New Mexico had some super fucking
squirrely laws.
Hundreds of childhood brides in Arizona.
Wow.
Arizona as child brides.
There's a bum fuck of every state.
I don't know how to Google this because
I think that is one of those states want
to say it's New Mexico,
but it might not have been where you.
The mail could be 18 or the male.
Could be a 13 man.
Jamie's computers just going to have the
most fucked up search history on the
computer.
Where can I find a 13 year old boy to
Mary.
How about,
what about male to female?
Shouldn't that be different?
I kind of like boy to girl,
meaning like woman to to 14 year old
kid.
I do.
I think that's kind of different like
the dogma of like there's no difference
between the sexes or shit like that.
It's ridiculous.
And then like I don't,
I definitely don't think.
I'm not saying it's cool,
but when you hear about some hot chick
teacher who was fucking her teenage
students,
I definitely don't look at that the same
way that I look at some dude who's
fucking teenage.
Like that's just a more fucked up.
I look at it as like she's a little bit
more fucked up because I don't ever talk
to women that are like,
oh young dude,
that's what I'm into.
And you are you talking to every dude
behind the scenes?
Like,
Oh yeah,
19 year old tractor,
that'll be hot.
You know,
she's definitely fucked up,
but those women play very important
roles in,
in taking a young man's hand reading of
sexuality.
It's not like I got molested by a 21
year old when I was 13.
She was hot and it was great.
Period.
Dick.
She made out with me like the whole
deal.
I,
I didn't,
I couldn't get a hard on.
I was a full panic.
I couldn't lose.
I was making out with this lady.
What was she babysitting?
You know,
she lived down the street.
Nice,
nice person.
She played softball with us and was
fucked a bunch of us when she was 21 and
the thing is,
man,
she was pretty.
It was weird.
She was fucked when she was a kid I
think could be anything.
It's always passed down from a another
generation.
No,
you're probably right.
You know,
whatever.
She was very nice.
She was very.
She was a fun person.
She was fun to be around.
We all,
we all liked her,
but she fucked everybody.
Yeah.
So I just adore now.
I didn't,
I didn't know.
She just grabbed my dick.
Like I said,
I couldn't even get it up.
I panicked,
but I didn't.
I mean they didn't even know what
getting it up was like.
I think she was the first person ever
kissed.
You didn't come back around to her
though later to see where you stepped up
and moved.
We moved,
we wound up moving into the next year
and I went to high school in a different
part of town.
I was already jerking off for years at
that point it's giving it up.
Literally jerking off from where I was,
like nine or eight.
He started jerking off at night.
Hey,
I about my teddy bears and my pillows.
Is that the same as jerking off to it?
Because then I would use my hand.
I was like 10 and I remember I remember
the transition of not coming anything to
when I actually shot a liquid and it was
like I graduated in masturbation because
I'd watched porn at that point,
but it's like an eighth grade
graduation.
It's not the real graduated,
just kinda like,
you know,
we're trying to make them feel good
about himself.
So I just jerk off until after I'd had
sex.
No,
really?
I didn't start jerking off until after I
had sex.
I have no idea why either.
Somewhere between 15 and 16.
It might've been 16.
It might've been 15.
I'm not sure.
Then you were like,
I want to feel this again.
I don't have time to find a chicken.
Everything is like I.
When I started jerking off I went,
oh this is what's going on.
Like I'm a junkie.
Like my body is like,
like completely addicted to the idea of
girls.
Right?
You're 17 years old or whatever the fuck
I was 15 years old.
Your body's just like girls,
girls.
But if you jerk off it's like Oh,
they're just just people without the
need for coming.
Like then you'd like them based on their
merits,
their job.
But if you just.
Joe,
I realized that literally
when I was 16 years old,
if I just jerked off like what I was
willing to tolerate with so much less we
will do.
When you go.
We talking about the sexual robots
before and if,
if we kind of got off on a.
If pedophiles should be able to fuck,
I mean,
you kind of think about that.
Do they have that built up pedophile,
full balls,
walking around just seeing kids just
given up on them.
There's no way to fix that.
I think their disease,
I think there's like a sickness.
I don't know if you could like,
I don't know if be able to fix them.
I think when you even chemical
castration show like that.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I mean,
uh,
I don't,
I don't know what the.
Like there are people that have this
inclination that would never act on it
and an ethics and morals they want to
fuck anybody up,
which is also crazy.
It's like,
wow.
Okay.
So it's like a nuclear suitcase.
He just walking around neighborhoods
just ready to detonate buildings and we
just trust that he's never going to use
it.
Right.
It's a weird thing to want.
Or if you can get like a weird video
game,
like you're hunting video game and he
just swallow up a building with a
suitcase once in a while.
But here's the thing,
like if he doesn't do anything,
he's not a criminal,
like if he has this thing and he fights
this demon every day and he successfully
slays at every day,
who are we to come in and say,
you shouldn't have these thoughts.
No.
If anything I look at that is probably.
It's somebody who was abused as a child,
is had a horrible life and isn't harming
anybody else.
You almost kind of are like,
honestly,
it's chemical castration,
two wolves.
We've got to find the dexter of
terrorists terror,
a terrorist who only terrorizes
terrorists.
Pedophiles who only goes after,
like located deserve to be a quantum
leap to another city.
Like quantum leap.
What a crazy sickness that you can
implant in someone's mind that if you
can molest them,
they will want to molest others.
Vampires.
Yeah.
I mean really is.
It really is like a vampire thing.
Do not invite a pedophile into your home
to probably is where it comes from.
Right?
Like stealing your joy,
sucking the life out of your family less
than your kid and just being violent in
general.
I think it's like that.
I think most people who are like,
like a not violent and like the criminal
sentence,
not in like,
you know,
being like in martial arts or something
like that,
but like people who like,
you know,
assault and Kale and shit like that.
It's like I think 99 percent of the time
they were fucking beaten as a child.
They always kicks his ass,
but those guys can go play a video game
where they shoot people in the fucking
head and they get off on that and
pedophiles don't have that same type of
outlet that those guys have.
Yeah,
that's interesting,
isn't it?
So isn't.
It's we look at pedophiles is almost
being worse than murder,
right?
Like somebody wants to commit murder.
We understand it kind of is worse than
murder and we're like,
I had a five year old.
I'm telling you right now,
like is it worse than somebody killing
him?
It's,
it's no,
not making him crazy.
Like if someone just killed,
like if someone has a distressing,
so sexy
you blue hair,
it was like who is making the sexy
clothes
into one of those beauty pageants?
Never been to a little,
little tiny kids.
What Diaz and Duncan were in Dallas
wants and we're going.
We were working at the Addison Improv
and while we're in Dallas,
in our hotel,
they had this childhood beauty pageant.
It was the craziest shit you've ever
seen in your life.
I'm talking about like five year olds
with full makeup and like dresses,
but they're dressed like a woman with
high heels.
They're walking around in high heels.
He's little tiny kids.
I mean high heels come fuck me.
Pumps like it's crazy looking at them
and you're,
you're looking at these like super
dolled up and that's essentially the
Jonbenet Ramsey story.
Right?
You know when,
when Jonbenet Ramsey where they did an
autopsy on her,
they found out that she had been
sexually active.
Yes.
And she was,
what,
seven or something like on killed her.
It was something like seven killed her.
Some say it was the dad.
Some say it was someone out brother,
the brother.
He said that stories horseshit.
He's like,
you guys are monsters.
My sister was fucking killed and you're,
you're blaming me and I didn't do a
goddamn thing.
Well,
he should really be upset at God because
it doesn't look like a guy who fucked
and killed his sister.
For sure.
Poor bastard.
Magic grown up your whole life knowing
that someone fucked and killed your
sister.
Yeah,
he's got a crazy big uh,
yeah.
No,
it be jealous too because they give her
more attention the whole time.
It's like Marcia,
Marcia,
the end,
my favorite.
My favorite theory is the brother did it
by accident and the parents try to cover
it up,
but that's just my favorite documentary
answer.
They connected the handwriting.
They were trying to connect the
handwriting of the ransom note or
whatever the fuck it was.
The one whatever note was left behind.
There was a note left behind and they
said it was really similar to the
mother's handwriting.
They cuddled ticket.
They made a conclusive decision about
that,
but that's like what if you have normal
hand writing somebody else's normal
handwriting and they kill your kid and
now people think you killed your kid
because you're right.
Normal.
You know what I mean?
How,
like you got to defend the fact that you
like put a little curve on the younger
your is handwriting Shit.
I mean does it.
That is it that good?
I didn't find a handwriting expert that
if you pay them enough they'll say that
it's not sure,
but that's all bullshit guys and whoever
you get.
But there's gotta be some science behind
it.
There must be looped if you ever like
seen them analyze.
It's I've seen like undocumented is and
how they analyze it,
it's like they loop it that way the same
way.
It's all at the same angles,
but they will,
they will use that in courts.
Right.
But I don't think it's substantial
evidence.
Polygraphs,
like there's some science to it,
but it's not like you can't get
convicted off that.
I couldn't believe anybody that passed a
polygraph test.
You'd see it up on the screen up.
There's
a Jonbenet Ramsey,
John Ramsey's ransom note and patty
Ramsey and you watch how she writes and
you watch how rent Patty Patsy,
Patsy Ramsey writes and you're like,
oh yeah,
of this.
She didn't even try to hide it.
Well,
I mean she writes the same way,
the ages of the same.
If you look at the end of the age yet,
we'll look at the size of the a's and
the seas.
They're very,
very uniform in size from hers to the
ransom note,
but very different than John's
like it's a,
it's a like,
it's her handwriting.
Like now I see it.
She killed us.
Have those words and it looks.
I mean it really,
really looks like she wrote that note.
So the one,
the patsy Ramsey at ransom note in the
middle is the one where she said,
look,
it's not my handwriting.
Right?
Is that what you're saying?
Yes.
They made her write.
The brands like that started talking
about it.
The sheet of paper.
Yeah.
They said here's some words we'd like
you to write them out.
And she wrote them out pretty much
exactly the same way.
I mean she didn't even try to hide it.
That's crazy.
Now I get it.
Okay.
So then,
I mean I'm sure if we had an expert in
here that he explained that there's some
sort of science behind it.
Yeah.
That house,
I lived in boulder nine fucking years
ago and that house is still for sale.
Oh,
you can't sell it.
It's a nice house.
They can't sell that house.
He changed the name of the street like
Trent Reznor.
Marilyn Manson donor doesn't want to buy
you.
Like rockstars are like really weird,
like eccentric people that want to like
have something like that.
No,
nobody wants to buy a house where a kid
was killed.
Good enough deal.
How expensive is it?
It's a good deal.
Not a great deal.
A great deal,
but you might be able to negotiate the
deal.
Mike.
Dude,
I know you mentioned a crazy fucking
like you're on stage in the middle of
the show and you see like things behind
you.
Ghosts.
You know,
that's the thing about the comedy store
podcasts down that basement,
like debate that paid millions of people
been killed in that piece of it.
That was like Bugsy Siegel's place,
those Ciro's nightclub.
So like for sure if you're going to kill
somebody,
you kill him in the basement.
Right?
How many guys do you think they killed
in that basement?
Bugsy Siegel with a nightclub on sunset
for sure.
A gang of people.
There's probably a bunch of people
killed as it since it's been the comedy
store.
Well,
there's probably been.
we know there's one that took place in
the base patio or the front pad.
Yeah.
That was.
I was on my way there that night.
That was crazy.
Yeah.
Great Alibi,
Jay.
I was on my way.
Me and Louis go holding a newspaper and
a car near the streets are many miles
away.
Louis j Gomez get
it right for the press release and
right.
Yeah.
I,
whenever some reason their documentary
comes out about an old thing that I've
heard a thousand things about.
I'll still watch them again.
I've got way deep into Charles Manson
again because I was going to say Charles
Manson was.
People have bought those houses for
sure.
Houses sold over and over again.
I'm telling you right now.
Yeah,
that's true.
They haven't marketed that fucking house
the right way because they could get
some Weirdo to buy it in Amityville
horror house.
Those bullshit,
like nothing ever really happened there,
right?
It depends on what document are you.
I mean,
some people are like,
the whole thing is fake.
It's all fake.
I think it's kind of bullshit.
I think they just sort of concocted it
for that movie.
I went to see that movie.
I was scared out of my fucking mind.
I was thinking,
oh my God,
these people,
they bought this house and it's haunted.
Fuck man.
That sucks.
What if that was us?
If you're a little kid and then you
found it.
What based on true events means,
like I heard a weird creek in the middle
of the night,
like bees came out of your toilet.
I'm gonna.
Go ahead and change them.
But then at a bees came out of the wall,
started bleeding.
I grew up so poor that like just the
idea of buying a house.
I was watching those movies.
I was like,
I don't know.
What do you want me to say guys?
I'm renting.
We're on section eight.
I would fucking deal with the ghosts
telling them something.
Yeah,
I know right where you scared a few
ghosts would have ever done and never
killed anybody.
A little bit of a fucking ghost killed
them.
No one's ever died from a ghost.
Yeah.
It's always like they moved the toy car
like across a table or something like
that.
How you get past that shit.
People.
I had my mom,
my roommate back when I was 21,
my buddy Jimmy detail you,
me and him got a [inaudible] board once.
We said,
all right,
we're going to find out this bullshit,
and he's like,
you're not going to move it right.
And I go,
I'm not going to move it.
I go,
you're not going to move it as I'm not
gonna move that fucking thing.
It was where to find out this is
bullshit.
And we sat around for like an hour and
45 minutes of this fucking stupid weegee
board ask any questions.
Sitting there looking at me and he
wasn't even.
He wasn't even budget at the end of it.
My friend Jimmy,
he folds everything off,
stuffs it in a garbage bag.
He goes,
I'm taking this piece of shit out to the
trash right now.
I mean,
people convince themselves of
everything.
You know,
the start moving that thing like,
oh my God,
it's going to the a I can't believe.
And the end and the d is telling us
something,
Andy from beyond the grave.
It's like fake martial arts where
they're using fucking knock you down and
they all just fits it.
It's the same people that,
uh,
that prey on them are predators.
Do you think like,
the people who go,
I'm talking to you.
It's too,
that's the problem.
They actually pieces of shit.
They're both,
there's pieces of shit that,
some of them are just con artists.
Some of them are idiots who are fooled
by it as what they're teaching.
I mean,
that's Sylvia Brown,
wasn't she the one that told the girls
they found in Cleveland,
like told one of her parents.
She's moved on to a better place now and
right?
Yeah.
Did they have stop looking for your
daughter was dead and she was at a
fucking.
That's crazy.
She made them stop looking for
different.
Is that than religion though?
So I,
you know,
I can sit there and the person that's
doing that on a dumb fucking stage more
personal.
Yeah,
no religion.
You are basically,
you're,
you're projecting these ancient stories,
right?
That's what you're doing.
You're,
you're giving lessons in these ancient
stories,
but when you're actually doing it to a
single person that seems way worse.
Right?
It's very focused and also religion
people get,
there are good intentions.
Sometimes the people doing it.
That's tradition and stuff where you
grow up that way and you just kind of
like.
But I know that's like,
that's,
that's predatory.
They're looking for someone to make
money by exploring like the worst
possible thing about their life in terms
of is it truth?
They're both equally probably,
you know,
like bullshit,
but one is directly targeting and
fucking with somebody also probably
killed millions and millions and
millions of people and these people are
just fucking stupid.
A few idiots out of there.
But those idiots deserve to be duped.
I mean,
look,
wounded antelopes should not go to the
waterhole.
That's just how it goes.
You get jack everything isn't antelope
analogy.
You Gel well.
This is dumb as they're supposed to get
taken out.
Did you,
uh,
did you watch the documentary and honest
liar about the amazing.
Randy would go pick apart those
televangelists and like interrupt their
frequency and expose their tricks.
Well,
he's one of those to a Uri Geller.
He just tried to end him.
Peter,
Steve Martin.
That's the entire.
No,
no,
it's all based off of it.
So they try to intercept that signal,
but he did it with a lot of things.
Uri Geller,
the bending spoons guy made him go away
for about 20 years.
Well,
he's got this a million dollar challenge
and I believe Said,
look up the randy challenge.
It's to show him any evidence of any
sort of telekinetic powers or psychic
abilities,
any measurable psychic abilities and you
can win a million bucks because nobody
can show shit.
Well,
he did.
He did.
He did a study,
I believe at Princeton University that
gave him all this money to have these
guys come.
Anyhow,
he just,
he hired three other magicians and it
was to have them come sit there for days
and try to figure out how to do this
crazy telekinetic thing and then they
ended up doing it and there was a big
press conference and he was like,
they're all magicians.
There's no telekinesis goes,
hey,
just show that it was a trick.
They all did and they got like 10 guys.
Some of those guys are fucking
incredible.
Well,
I did that show Joe Rogan questions,
everything.
We did an episode on psychics and we got
this guy named bandit check and he's a
vegas magician.
He's a wizard dude.
He does all the spoon bending shit in
front of you and you know what it is,
man.
I mean,
he didn't explain it to me.
I had to go and Google it.
It's not really the same metal.
It's some metal that if you just heat it
up by moving your hands back and forth,
it just bends.
I used to want to be a magician as a
kid.
I really did.
And there's,
if you take it like a cheap enough spoon
and you literally just a,
you could bend
it like a few times and it'll just look
straight.
That's one of the trucks.
We'll just use your finger and you make
it melt away.
But this is a very specific kind of
metal.
They do this too.
It's like,
you know.
But aluminum is like super weak in some.
Some forms,
not like car frame forms,
but in some forms of not alloys.
Aluminum is it scratches easier.
It's like there's metals that are like
our lead.
I was thinking of lead scratches easier.
It's like a,
it's kind of metal that's pliable.
You can bite into a gold coin,
right?
You can actually see teeth marks.
That's all people knew.
The goal was real.
This shit.
He just rubbed your fingers and it just
droops.
It just gives in.
I spent.
But no,
you guys made this remarkably well for
four microphones,
podcast.
That would've never happened in a
million years.
It was just screaming at each other.
Faggot for them.
We're on our best behavior right now to
this is church Sunday for us.
After you faggots first.
No,
I'm just saying,
can you imagine like precise science,
how much people got freaked out by
people who like new magic or new,
some type of slight of hand like that.
When you can look at Google,
you can google that.
Oh,
there's a different type of metal that
you can burn them and just like he is
communicating with those people didn't
know how to ask you questions that are
leading you into telling them the
answers.
Right?
Those techniques to that.
You know,
I talked to Penn Jillette about that
once and he was explaining to me how
when someone talks to you,
they get you to give them the answer and
then they say the answer and it makes
them look like a wizard,
but they're just,
they've gone through these patterns so
many times.
I mean,
how many people have problems with their
dad?
How many people have a brother that
died?
How many people you know,
they like,
there's someone missing.
Who is my brother?
Yes,
I see.
And this is not a good thing.
Oh yes,
I see.
Yeah,
I see that he loves you.
And he misses you and he's very sad that
he didn't get to say goodbye.
He doesn't.
And then he comes home.
He goes,
dude,
she knew about my brother getting out
fucking dummy.
You knew about your brother.
She was.
She'd tell you about some shit that
hasn't happened yet.
She's telling you about some shit you
already know because you're a dumb ass
and you're playing checkers with the
ladies playing chess on you.
My friend who I stayed with when I'm out
here has a very good friend who's a
psychic medium.
He's a very nice guy,
but she,
she really wants to believe in him so
much and I'm farm the way he does is an
entertaining thing.
And she's like,
you don't believe it at all.
I go,
here's why I don't believe it.
If you have fucking powers.
And then also like,
you know,
you go to target because you need
shampoo.
I don't know.
It seems like it would be a burden to
live with the gift of magic powers.
And then you're just like,
oh yeah,
I'll swing by Mcdonald's.
I'm a little hungry for a snack.
It all stems from US walking around,
wouldn't
it be much if I knew exactly
what was going to happen,
knew who these people who's good and
who's bad when that'd be better than
everybody has that feeling,
but nobody has those abilities.
So you go on knowledge and instincts and
life experience and you compile it
altogether and some people are really
good at it and some people suck at it
and the people that suck at it,
they'd go to someone else for advice and
one of the ways they go to advice that
lady with the neon sign,
Psychic,
oh look at the palm.
She must be a magician.
I go in there and this is you.
I see it in New York City.
You'll walk down the street,
there's a psychic,
has a window of storefront palm glowing
in the and you're like,
well,
I don't have them.
How are you affording the fucking rent
here?
They get a bunch of suckers and the one
thing about is is if they're good,
if you have a good connection with that
sucker,
that soccer wants to come back next
week.
Soccer wants to keep coming to you like
you.
We have to discuss this.
Can you be here Thursday also part of
the job.
No problem.
And then this fucking Dork,
he's all excited about Thursday on
Thursday,
the Magnum is going to take my company
and this fucking Dude Shit have gotten
taken out by a Hyena high initiative,
clipped his ankles,
dragged him,
and they all would have jumped out of
nowhere and mall this fucking asshole
because he didn't listen to anybody,
but no,
we survive in this world.
Yes.
Nature had an answer for this guy.
But then the one smart guy who was
supposed to survive invented some shit
and then told everyone else about it.
And now these guys have that invention.
It you wrote like an old bit of yours
where you touched on this.
I really fucking love that joke where
you're like,
uh,
when you realize there's no such thing
as adults like everyone else.
That was a real moment with me because
people.
But that's what it is.
That none of us really know what the
fuck's going on.
We all like to to comfort ourselves by
thinking we know what's going on,
and then if someone else can convince
you,
they kind of know what's going on.
It's like we look for that.
Like were like,
oh,
thank God I found someone now.
Now I know what's going on,
but we're all full of shit.
People are followers.
That's what it is.
We should look at these psychics like we
look at coyotes,
they take out the dummies.
They just take.
They get into the system.
They find cracks.
They expose weakness and dummies hanging
out with dummies.
Right?
So it's like the referral business and
world.
Everything dude.
Oh,
and everybody wants to think that they
have the person.
Oh my God,
she is amazing.
She knows so much about me.
First of all,
when I knew her,
when I walked in the room,
she touched both my shoulders and I knew
her for my whole life.
Incredible.
She's an incredible and they all want to
convince themselves that this fucking
crazy bitch that they keep paying money
to isn't just lying to them.
That's right.
Because it's not just that you're being
conned.
It's like you're the accomplice in the
con you want because you're causing
yourself with just those kung fu videos.
Those guys want to be conned by this
touch and the guy goes flying across the
room.
They want.
They want to be for you to have.
You're working with this master.
No problem,
Dave.
I always make the sidekick to automate
brown and I just pretend my ex wife is
dead and I want to make.
What's that one where you remember about
ghosts to automate?
Brown pretended to be a patrick swayze
and they made out with Demi Moore will
be a boy,
but they wouldn't show.
We'll be making out with leaning in and
then it turned into Patrick swayze,
which was weak shit.
Realistically,
Whoopi Goldberg was fucking French and
heart that's making that movie today.
I want to go about.
That will be Goldberg now I'm too heavy.
It would just be all checks that Xyz is
a check tail.
That's the reboot Ronda Rousey.
Ronda Rousey is.
Yeah.
They could remake that movie.
It probably.
Well one day.
They definitely could.
They can make anything so doing some
shitty ones coming up soon.
I'm trying to remember what they are,
but there's some real like,
it's too soon.
Why would you farmers from my liking?
Like a few more of those please.
Yeah,
they really thought that was going to.
It was so cool.
The first one,
when they made that truck turn into that
fucking robot,
it was the coolest thing.
Guys are making some money.
They're making some money
in a fucking shit ton of money.
It's like when the fast and furious 89
came out,
you know,
you're like,
what?
How many have they have?
They sound like I've never watched more
than 14 minutes of one of these
lobbyists.
I have no idea.
Did you ever hear Vin diesel talk about,
uh,
the movies?
Like the reference where he's like,
we made a multicultural movie that
showed races working together too long.
Dudes of just about like Bikini.
It's Maxim magazine,
man.
It's fast cars.
A Bikini to one point.
One six,
$3,000,000,000.
Just the last one.
Oh my God.
And the budget was $250.
Million Dollars.
Wow.
So they made three quarters a male solid
budget on.
It's not even fucking crazy.
It's cars driving fast.
You got ludicrous.
He must have a lot of special effects.
Budget.
That's shit's expensive.
You want to launch cars through the air.
The stuff that they do is fucking
insane.
I mean,
I don't know how much of it's CGI and
how much of it they're really dealing
with cars,
but as a person who loves muscle cars,
it hurts my heart.
Watching those cars get fucking launched
through the air.
Much more so many of these.
They only made so many 1969 chargers,
right?
He feels that they're destroying them.
I like the Dukes of hazard.
How many fucking chargers did they wreck
for the Dukes of Hazzard?
Launching them across a bridge landing.
I'm nose down.
You see the car bend drive away like
nothing's happening.
How Louis Myeloma noticed and they kill
like 15 years.
It's so funny.
That movie.
You remember the movie my own Otis?
Yes.
Pug nose pop,
little orange cat.
Fucking grateful that I got to be honest
with you.
I don't think it holds up the amount of
pugs and kittens that died during the
making of this film.
You have to watch it because otherwise
otherwise they died in vain.
They took the,
like it was
another movie that was made in like
Japan or China or somewhere in Asia.
Uh,
and they didn't give a fuck.
There was no walls.
I'm like,
how you treat a cats and dogs in that
country.
They don't care how you treat humans
back there.
So there's a scene where the dog is
fighting off a bear and this bear,
I mean they must have just went through
30 pugs with this bear scene alone,
but there's no confirm numbers of
deaths.
But there was like a bunch of other.
When you watched the movie,
you're like,
oh man,
how did they get that dog to fight with
that bear?
And it's like,
well,
we lost like $300.
That's how we did a Jesus Christ.
Really a bunch of.
There's a scene where he's in the water
swimming,
maybe eight of them right there.
How many dogs tied?
We looked it up one time.
I forget a lot.
I know Dudley Moore narrated at the
eight in that scene.
Jesus Christ.
That is so crazy.
Holy Fuck,
I'm looking at the elks head behind you.
Damage more value that elc has done a
puppy.
Why don't we put so much more value when
a puppy's life versus that elk slide.
Cute,
cute,
cute privilege.
But like you'll swap out mosquito.
Yeah.
I only care about human swat mosquitoes.
Yeah,
that's a good point.
I know.
Kill plants which are living right and
that's.
I only care about humans and dogs.
Love peanut butter off your dead cats
too.
I do enjoy cats.
I never liked cats,
but then my girlfriend brought her mom's
cat to live with us for a little bit and
I got attached to that fucking cat
fiance kind of animals.
I love them in the wild.
I love them and I just love them in
their environment.
I think it's.
Look,
it is a weird thing that we've gotten
totally accustomed to that you could
just get out of this studio right now.
You could drive 15,
20 minutes over to Pang cane.
Get out of your car,
walk 300 yards into the woods and you're
just living with animals,
eating animals.
You are basically in another dimension.
There's eagles when there's not too many
eagles,
but a lot of hawks that fly around,
they're just constantly looking for some
shit to Jack and if either there at the
right time you could see it happen.
You can see a coyote snatch a rabbit or
you know,
different animals just constantly
looking for something else to eat.
It's right there.
Yeah.
We're so removed from it.
Like if you,
if you want to be like,
well you put yourself out there and
that's a big difference between New York
and La.
Like la is the city where there's
beautiful nature within it.
New York's like just the city and then
you've got to leave to go to any
beautiful.
Right.
So it's almost like you can be,
but I mean just the fact that we just
go,
you go to a grocery store and my
relationship with animals is like,
there's a steak.
Let me pick it up and buy it.
And it's not.
None of them like,
oh,
this came from fucking killing a cow in
someone.
Do you ever go to Malibu once?
There's places in Malibu that it,
like ranches,
like they're really long.
I think it's something like 30 something
miles of coast and along the way,
like up in the hill,
there's like Alpaca farms and shit like
that and that shit.
You could just get in your car and then
boom,
you're in La and
then get in your car and boom,
you're in the Alpaca farm.
That nature you're describing those
scares the shit out of the hamster ball.
No,
they're going to show the dog tell that
none of this is the movie.
This is from the movie,
but this is actually having that bear
killed that dog.
Yeah.
That is so crazy.
And the movie,
the bear dog fights off the bear.
I know,
but that's so crazy that they allowed
this crazy.
I don't know.
Like you're just like,
oh man,
they must have had the best animal
trainers.
Like,
nope.
They just.
We threw a dog versus a bad God.
That's so crazy.
Imagine what the fucking pugs looked
like to after bears just ripping apart.
Like twitching.
My Buddy John.
John Dudley saw a bear.
He saw a grizzly bear,
killed a moose with one swat.
He said he had never seen anything like
it that it was.
He was looking through his by nose and
he saw this bear swat,
this moose in the back and it just
broke.
It's back and the Moose just goes down.
A Moose.
Moose are so big.
Huge.
There are so big.
Matt said this Grizzly just fucking
swatted it and they saw it happen and
that they're so powerful that swatting
it in the back broke it's back and the
thing went down and then he's just
ripping it apart.
One of my favorite pranks on my friends
is I send them a video and I say,
Watch A.
Watch this.
He's got a moose by the neck.
Just dragging it through the woods.
Those fucking animals.
Do you want.
Everyone's looking for monsters.
There's a God damn monster.
That thing just killed a moose talking
about Bj dragged into the woods.
Hey,
bear [inaudible].
My favorite pranks planned paypal is I
send them an email and say,
check out this video of this deer,
a beating up this bear,
and then it's.
There's a famous video of a bear just
killing a deer in the backyard,
like in the deer is making them as
awful,
horrible sound you'll ever hear her
entire life and Louis goes,
the deere makes a come back,
wait for it,
and just gets people to watch the video,
watch the deer being mauled alive with
the most horrible sound and then let it
go.
That's the old frank.
I was hoping there was like a dude's
dick somewhere in the help too.
To be fair,
most of has pranks.
Do have a dude's Dick and it somewhere,
but this one is just barren,
dear.
Yeah.
That's how it goes.
Bears are different than other animals
in that they eat a lot of shit.
They eat a lot of berries,
a lot of plants,
and they also eat animals.
Whatever they get ahold of so they don't
kill the animal first.
There are also real sturdy.
They're.
They're not like a cat,
like cats are really powerful,
but cats are more flexible and pliable.
A bears more of a just a fucking machine
or bears more of like a like cats are
like hoists.
Gracie,
a bear's,
Dan Henderson.
He's just coming in there throwing
overhand rights.
Maybe even taking people on the back.
Melvin manhoef.
Just a powerhouse.
Dave Henderson,
a hairy gay guy.
No,
that's not the different kind
of bare pro.
Oh,
nature bears.
You guys say nature.
Me Don't try to get me in trouble with
Dan Henderson.
I'm actually more like brock because
I've learned with Frank Mir describe
rockland.
Top of him.
He was like,
it was like a car that was slowly onto
him and he couldn't push it off.
Like,
you know,
imagine a bears on you.
You're just like sitting there like,
dude,
it's got my shoulder blade and it's just
knowing that my shoulder blade and I'm.
I know I'm going to die.
Nothing you can do.
Holy Fuck.
Do you think you went,
you're the adrenaline will kick in where
you wouldn't feel the pain or do you
think it would be the most horrible
fucking.
He definitely wouldn't feel it.
You'd feel it.
It would hurt,
but you would be so terrified of death
and you'd be so overwhelmed with all
these fucking neurochemicals to be
flying through your synapses.
You'd be out of your mind.
You'd feel like the pressure of that.
It's happening.
You would.
You'd.
There'd be so much adrenaline.
You'd be in another dimension before you
knew it.
That's probably a trigger that seems
like the worst way to die.
Just a guy who got bit real bad and came
back and had a video.
He did a selfie and talked about what
happened.
He was just walking,
hiking down a trail,
scouting,
and he came upon A.
I'm a female grizzly and her cubs,
which is the worst scenario.
A male grizzly doesn't really,
unless he's really old and it's really
late in the season.
Usually they'll just get the fuck away
from you,
but the females will fuck you up and
this female fucked him up and tore his
scalp right off of his skull and he had
it like packed down with a baseball hat,
like try to try to hold it in place and
his arm snapped and he had big bite
marks in his arm,
but this guy was like a Montana dude
like in the Montana.
Tough.
So he's like,
well,
vitals are intact.
Might be broken.
I don't know what's going on up there.
Holy Shit.
Fucking yoga teacher in La.
Safe space.
There he is.
Oh my God.
Down his head.
The grizzly with two cubs you can barely
see,
but the right side of his ear,
his head is basically ripped apart.
I'll save my watch though.
He put the hat on to make himself like,
you know my fucking kidding.
I never got my daddy's wash.
He drove himself to the hospital after
walking three miles to his car.
That's a fucking man.
I'll.
I'll be damned if I'm not going to get
the gosh darn best facebook live video
out of this.
There's literally look at the size of
the hole in his head.
My God,
mother.
Fuck.
He's smiling in the picture because he's
a fucking Montana dude.
There are different humans.
Do you remember the,
uh,
the bear with the karate suit guy?
He just fucking knocks out the lady
specials.
You have a joke about that.
He remembers that.
He tears his bitch apart.
It's horrible.
And the other guy with the karate
uniform is just decided out of nowhere.
Yes sir.
He just decided out of nowhere that he
was going to fuck that lady up.
There was no town and nobody feels bad
because you put a fucking party and I
met bear man.
That ain't working.
Yeah,
that's simple.
Simple as that I'm scared of animals do.
And now that I have a kid too,
like is this,
is the video going at the karate and
sits down.
Oh,
this is fun.
Look at the size of the thing.
Like,
look at the power in it.
When it grabs her lunch,
imagine how terrified she must've been.
And everyone's slapping it,
bitch slapping it.
The host is getting in there.
Why would the host get in there?
Are you crazy dudes wrestling with a
bear that is a Russian who's that good
technique?
That guy has to be rushed and look at
the power in his fucking getting.
He's almost got the bear.
He's almost got the bear out.
Jesus Christ.
This is so crazy.
And the bear still holding onto that
person was fucking that personnel also,
not even the hardest day of her life in
Russia.
Oh my God.
She made.
She must've got fucked up by that bear
dude.
I mean really fucked up.
The bear.
Didn't use great technique to get out of
the team,
but he just kind of powered out.
The only thing that saved her life is
that that bear had a muzzle on.
I love that.
He looks at her like she said something
offensive you can't predict and that's a
brown bear that's similar to a grizzly
bear.
Probably the Russian version of a brown
They have big ass bears over there.
Yeah.
Fuck that dude.
Fuck bears,
dude.
I've,
I saw a real grizzly bear in the wild
and it wasn't that far away.
There was like 30,
40 yards and looked me in the eyes and I
remember thinking,
Whoa,
that's a different look.
He went,
Oh shit.
It's jewelry wasn't even a big one.
It was only like a six foot tall
grizzly,
which is not a big grizzly,
but it looked at me.
It looked.
They looked through you like,
what am I going to do?
Am I going to eat?
You know,
what am I doing?
Is it safe to safe?
They have their brains calculated.
Do you have a weapon on you or you have
two shotguns and two bows and arrows,
but still I'd probably take a while to
shotguns and one bone arrow.
I got a shotgun.
My Tas.
Yeah.
Yes.
It would take a while.
Yeah,
it's not.
It's not that easy.
It's a big animal.
Even a six foot one is probably probably
300 pounds.
I mean,
it's a big animal,
but it's the way they look at you that's
different.
Like I've.
I've seen black bears in the wild and
they look at you like,
what are you,
what's going on over here?
What's happening?
Grizzlies look right through you.
They look right through you.
It's a weird look.
It's a weird like dead look like there's
no fear of you at all.
Like what do I do here?
They just trying to figure out whether
or not you're a meal.
You're just wandering.
Imagined piano.
300 pound animal that just has to wander
around looking for shit to eat.
Welcome to the life of big Joe.
Can you please stop describing the wild
animals conventions I've been in my
life.
I mean this is a fucking crazy bear.
Like you see this thing come and run
because it will eat.
You are human being 300 pounds that's
coming at you.
All you can do is put it down,
put it out of their misery animal.
Three hundred pounds that is hungry.
Imaginary,
no stores
looking for hunters and slipping.
Limps.
It just like a.
well we,
um,
I was with my friend Jen,
she's the guide and she smacked a
fucking tree with the stick.
She picked up the stick and crack this
fucking tree and screamed and I screamed
and we cocked our guns and that thing
took off.
They new fuck bitch ass.
Bear Shit,
we saw a couple of them,
so one of them we think on the side of
the road,
it's got to be terrible,
but with the weapons,
you're like it sorta on still,
you know,
you don't know how many are out there
and you have them out there,
you know,
they've,
they've seen one way bigger than the
ones I've seen.
Well,
what about people that say this?
It's always like the people that are
like,
well,
yeah,
if you think you're a real man,
how about this?
We'll give you a knife and you go out
there and then you try to hunt a bear.
I always feel like even if you have a
gun,
it's going to not be that easy to just
go and fucking kill a bear.
But you know why all these people say
that shit is because they don't
understand what a bear really is.
Like in their head.
They feel like a bear is like some
mythical creature who lives in the
forest so she'd be left alone.
The problem is you can't just leave them
alone because they're so powerful and
they're so hungry and they eat so much
that if there's nothing that keeps them
in check,
they're gonna just run rampant and
destroy all the deer and the Moose and
all those other things you like to look
at as well.
They're going to kill all of you.
They were to kill 50 percent of
just you can
kill them.
Well,
you're also like,
you want to keep the populations
healthy,
like it's very tricky and humans are
supposed to play a part in this.
I mean there's.
We don't like to think we play a part in
it because we can communicate and we
discuss things and we rationalize.
We have culture and those are all those
things are all correct,
but we've always kept predators and
check because when they start killing us
that means,
oh,
we have to do something now,
and then we killed them.
That's always been the case with
villages and Jaguars and people who live
in towns and wolves.
It's always been the case.
There is a food chain.
We're a part of it.
We just have insulated ourselves from it
with cities so thoroughly that we've
forgot about this connection,
so all these people that are peta
people,
a good percentage of them are living in
cities.
You're,
you're,
you're talking about a culture that you
don't understand talking about a world
that you I don't idealize.
And when you say like we kept the
predators and check like not nearly as
well
as we do now.
We always tried to do it and then after
thousands of years of this struggle
where we fucking got the upper hand and
started dominating,
it was easy to sit in a city and be
like,
hey,
you know,
you read your kids these books about
nature and it's like the frog made
friends with the squirrel and
everything's just nice and nature were
the assholes.
Like people are the assholes because we
pollute and we do this.
And it's like,
no,
you know,
what's the real fucking asshole is the
state of nature where your fucking kid
gets ripped apart by a fucking predator.
That's real.
That's the shit you don't want to do.
Where's that fucking?
Bye.
The answer is,
man,
I think the answer is comes in the
middle that people have to realize the
real problem on the side of people that
eat meat and people that don't think
Peta people are ridiculous,
is factory farming.
That's what's against us.
The most horrific evidence is not
impeded side.
I mean in terms of like something that
they're accused of the most horrific
evidenced by far.
It's coming out of these factory farms.
Like if you had to pick like which side.
If you look at the two of them,
like which side makes more sense with
the pizza side makes way more sense than
the fucking factory farm people bolt are
extremists.
You see those videos where it's like
Auschwitz of cows and doing numbers into
their forearms.
It's terrific.
So I think the,
if the meeting population doesn't accept
the fact that this is,
it's not just,
it's should be impossible.
It should be impossible for a civilized,
healthy person to accept this as a
reality for those animals.
So the Peta people are right about that.
They just.
But the idea that you shouldn't be able
to eat any animals.
Like mmm.
I don't agree because what are you going
to do with all these animals and the
best way in terms of like health,
the best way to live is eating mammals,
animals,
eating animals and vegetables together
seems to be the best way to exist seems
to be when you look at all these
objective scientific studies that talk
about nutrients and plants versus
nutrients and animal products or leans
very heavily towards a diet that's rich
in of those,
there's no people in the world that are
fed that eat a meat,
vegetables and fruit juice responsible
here,
dude,
fucked up man.
I know you guys are aggressive at home.
That shit.
I like meat and vegetables and fruits.
Joe,
he's getting your shotgun,
right?
Like all those things.
But so six foot son of a bitches coming
right at Jason.
Being a stick on the tree.
Guys,
don't nobody.
You're right.
And then it's also like there's some
weird shit that happens to you when they
go in those fucking Vegan soy diets like
Jamie Kilstein started eating meat again
and he's fucking making sense again.
Finally.
Well,
he also tasted the wrath of his improper
inclinations.
Me,
improper meaning he wasn't being honest.
He went along with his ideology because
he was terrified of the repercussions of
being against the stream and you know,
he saw like Jay,
I've talked about Jamie 100 times on
this podcast now after we did a podcast
together because he's a way more normal
person now.
He's way more rational.
Like when he was in that world,
he was frantic checking his twitter
constantly,
like constantly arguing with people,
calling people out of being a bigot or a
racist.
It's like you're always trying to get
street cred for calling people out.
You're always constantly checking your
phone and see what horrible shit they
said back to you and whether or not that
stings
you're in a battle and that you almost
get addicted to that.
I quit.
I literally stopped using facebook like
six months ago.
I just deleted it because it was a lot
of that.
I don't really publicly battle as much
on twitter with dummies,
but on facebook I was really getting
into it with people for stupid shit and
I was just like,
now that I don't do that at all,
like just that weird,
nasty whatever vial feeling that that
gives you that you live in and you get
addicted to,
you want to go back to it.
It just feels so much better and Jamie
was definitely a victim of that,
but now you talk to them because I had
lunch with them before he even came
back.
We talked,
we had lunch in La and he almost seemed
broken.
Dude.
He seemed like he definitely seemed like
he was beaten down and had been through
some real fucking shit.
I think the social industry,
I think being a social justice warrior
is like exhausting.
You have to be looking at that hearing
is exhausting,
period.
If inside of you give a fuck that much,
it's pretty nice.
But I mean it really is like when people
get angry about something like calming
people get angry back comedy.
It's so like,
wow,
you've had to.
You've already through so many layers of
things to actually be angry about and
then some other things you shouldn't be
angry about to get to comedy.
They're almost always not successful or
not as successful as they think they
should be.
Almost always no one who's successful
complaints about comedy.
No one who is successful is pissed off
to.
Kevin Hart has a fucking $50,000,000
mansion,
right?
No,
you're absolutely right that aren't
doing well.
And I think,
uh,
and,
and just kind of on a similar note,
I think no one who's been through real
shit in their life gives a fuck about
microaggressions.
Like it's literally like a privileged
thing and you don't have anything going
on that you actually are taking this as
a major issue,
but you know what it also is,
it's evidence that you're in competition
with that person and unnecessarily so
and that you are deeming them to be
unworthy of their success.
So you get angry,
you're lashing out.
And it's entirely because you feel like
it's a race and you're so far behind the
regular folk,
the folk hart or whatever it is.
It's like whoever the fuck if the person
is that's way ahead of you instead of
just looking at it for what it is.
Wow.
That guy works hard.
Hold on.
Stressful at all in comedy.
You Go,
oh,
this is a really fucking fair thing.
Either way,
whether you have a,
you know the guys that have millions of
millions of dollars,
that's great.
If you're successful in comedy.
Yeah.
But if you're a guy coming off as like,
you know,
it's easy.
I mean,
how many times when you were around gods
were just starting out.
Would they talk crazy shit on some
headlines or they work with.
Yeah man,
he couldn't even follow me,
Bro.
Everybody this room probably was
guilty of doing that as a young comment
on that.
Me and Dave on the phone,
I got called a audit by a Keith
Robinson,
the committee,
Keith Robinson.
I called him the shit talking another
comic or say that I like some booker had
called and said he liked me on the show
and he kept talking about me and another
comic that he liked.
This guy's gonna be comedy anymore,
but he kept acknowledging.
He's like,
oh,
just you and that guy were my two
favorites.
I like youtube both.
And eventually I was like,
hey man.
Yeah.
It's just like,
that guy's terrible.
I was like,
you keep saying the same thing.
It's so weird.
And I called,
uh,
my friend Keith Robinson,
Flight Brag,
not brag would almost be like,
isn't this funny?
He kept saying,
I did this for a young comedy and he was
like,
dude,
don't ever fucking do that because it's
not your job,
not your job to take money out of
someone's pocket for a or just slouched
and whatever it goes,
if they suck that much,
it'll people will find out or maybe
they'll get better or whatever,
but it's not your job to like cut
somebody else off at the knees.
And I was,
I took that soda.
I was like,
Oh shit.
I was,
I was a real asshole doing that.
Dialyze it.
You get caught.
I've heard that before too.
You get caught up in what you think is a
competition,
but you knew and all the other people
that are trying to make it,
but there a nice point when you get to
at least where you're.
You're not miserably broke all the time
or you're in some at least path or lane
of where you want to go.
It's nice to be.
It does change your appreciation for
comedy.
It brings it back again.
It brings it back.
You can just like somebody like somebody
who's funny,
who's way younger than you.
You can like somebody who's funny who's
passing you.
You know what I mean?
It doesn't matter.
You can just like a.
well,
that was the thing that me.
Why them,
not me?
Why them?
I want you to like laughing at like
guitar acts where I think when we all
came up in New York,
there's like our experts,
you dumb fucking hacky shit and I'm
watching you the other way.
Washington Reagan and mock up Jeremiah
and just laughing your Dick off because
you let go after a little while ago and
it's not you,
but it's not about your ego.
It's about what's going to tickle you.
There is not about the,
we've had this conversation a lot and I
said,
I think what New York lax,
la embrace as much more is the silly
even,
you know what I mean?
There's just,
there's not enough like silly,
uh,
in New York,
I feel like everyone's,
if you do something silly or even pull
out a guitar for whatever reason on
stage,
I think there's not even a chance of
maybe wait,
this might be like a unique or guitar,
you know,
people will like I watched Sebastian
Maniscalco in Vegas and do it.
I like I watch in that hour,
I don't know Sebastian or all but
watching him for that hour,
this is like a year ago was the most I
learned in comedy and a really,
really long time.
He's so physical and like what he does
with his body and his eyes,
like he's making eye contact with almost
everybody in the audience.
And I was like,
Holy Shit Dude.
And he's got to really use that space.
And I feel like in New York,
if anybody was at physical,
people will be like,
what's this guy fucking dylan?
Colin Quinn was saying this at,
um,
at just for laughs in 2013 he gave the
keynote address to pee.
So bad.
I'm sorry.
You're going to come back and this
show's going to be off the fucking
rails.
Legion escapes.
Takes over the
Joe Rogan experience.
Alright Jamie,
I need you to pull up this baby and
raping video.
Alright Jamie,
I'm going to need you to start pawning
things off in the studio.
Can you look up ahead of Phelia hot
spock's bookmark.
And we really do have Joe Rogan's
podcast for about one minute by
ourselves.
Guys,
we need to do something with it.
Oh man,
I feel like it's going good.
What do you guys think?
We should probably just bring it up.
He has put up until like youtube.
Oh remember?
Uh,
one of the first episodes.
What's that?
Which one do you remember the name of
Jay?
One of the first episodes of the Legion
of skanks podcast,
which is available on gas digital
network.com
plugs.
Zach subscribers go subscribe gas
digital network Dot Com.
Right now you use the Promo Code Lms,
you get a 14 day free trial.
You get access to the entire archive is
over 350 episodes on demand.
Whatever you guys want them in hd or you
could watch live for free on Wednesday
nights.
Camping.
Escaped us.
Coming up July 14th and 15th.
Guys,
you got to listen to me.
It's a nonstop,
two and a half day comedy party.
Everyone that you want to fucking hang
out with,
the comedy is going to be there.
It's no joke.
Skank mic.com.
April,
second,
presale.
Oh Shit.
Let me do one guys.
We got to end the war in Yemen.
They're going to do libertas coach
special called Libertas.
Go check it out.
It was so incredible.
Guys.
Joe Rogan specifically said himself that
it's his favorite comedy,
especially he's ever seen off air.
He said that.
Don't mention it again when he comes
back in the room,
but I'm pretty sure he said that.
Tweet that Adam.
I'm almost certain that's what he said.
I said that he gave me a look that kind
of said that in the look,
but he never actually verbalized no,
but really go by days comedy,
special libertas available right
now@gasdigitalnetwork.com.
We're not plugging everything in our
lives right now.
Don't worry.
Hey,
what's up the bears man.
Bears are crazy.
I drank way too much water today.
Quite an issue.
Water is so hard for me to drink.
It's so boring.
I fucking hate it.
It is boring,
but it's not boring.
If you were fucking dying of thirst,
you gotta think if you were in a desert
and you just like barely hanging on,
your lips are cracked and bleeding and
your skin is sore with sun blisters all
over it and just wandering and you just
see a fucking one of those,
uh,
Fiji water's in a bucket of ice for
those giant ones was the nicest one.
Big Ones brought a crystal light packet
shut.
Shut splenda.
I got some emergency scorebig.
Casad gotta.
Keep Koolaid in my.
Go back to what I had like a couple of
weeks ago for the first time and fucking
20 years or some shit.
When was the last time I had koolaid
before that,
but I was at a barbecue place and it was
so good.
I had to go with the Koolaid was fuck.
It was sort of racist for a drink to
offer at a barbecue place?
No,
it was a black owned business.
Yeah.
Yeah,
they.
They were doing.
They were serious about it.
It was in Fresno and then you've got to
be careful because you want to see on
the menu you go to.
You guys have coined music.
Yeah.
It was like the first drink.
It's like,
yeah,
the all that other bullshit like Pepsi
root beer if you're really interested,
but she want Koolaid.
You'd want to do this shit right.
You can eat oxtails might as wives or
Koolaid has ever Koolaid guy and I was
poor.
We were always like a shitty ice tea,
like scoopable sugary ice tea into the.
I remember that Shit.
We used to do a lot of that in my home.
The lemonade and the ice to realize
flavored makes no sense to me.
Yeah.
See,
I don't even know what that makes.
T just cold water garbage in this tea.
Iced tea.
I drink unsweetened iced tea all the
time.
I hate it.
It's like vegetable water,
some phytonutrients in it.
Apparently.
I'd rather drink water.
Yeah,
the water is good man.
Maybe just drink a little sparkling
water.
Mix it up and get a little fucking
Pellegrino in your system.
We have the sets of fucks you up.
You know,
just water or whiskey either.
What's a cheat day?
I'm telling you right now in the best
shape I was ever in my entire life.
Dude.
I was drinking diet coke like a
motherfucker,
right?
ABS.
And I'm sure my body on the inside is a
Goddamn nightmare.
Um,
but I was drinking like an insane amount
of diet soda.
It was a problem.
Really.
That was how hydrate they say that Shit
fucks you up in so many different ways.
And one of the ways does the,
all those chemicals,
they're fucking terrible for your gut
flora.
Like even sugar's bad for your gut flora
if you drink regular coke,
but apparently if you drink diet coke.
My Gut Flora is pretty dope though.
So you say so you don't know anything
about my gut flora Joe Rogan.
I'm always suspicious of people were
bragging about their right and I bet my
uncle is a straight up psychic bro.
I'm telling her mind reader,
you don't have any secrets from him Bro.
He looks into your eyes and she's
window.
Yeah.
He's got a neon sign in front of his
house and everything.
It's always the guy who's bragging the
most.
Got Some farty gas gut flora.
What the fuck is Gut Flora?
You don't know what that is for real.
Are you kidding?
Yeah.
Gut Flora.
Your um,
your stomach has living organisms.
I'm sorry.
Don't act like you guys fucking.
No.
A Gut Flora was sure he knows I was
going to explain it,
but joe got it.
Oh,
joe do it.
It's a show that please check the
lighting.
It's the Flores Flores.
Am I pronouncing it right?
But pronounced.
It might be your actual life forms.
There's more eco lie in your gut than
they've ever been.
People ever.
That's fact.
Your Gut,
your gut sign.
We are.
We're a ecosystem.
Every human being is an ecosystem.
We're not a one thing.
You cannot exist without the bacteria in
your system,
without what's on your skin,
protecting you from other invading
bacteria.
We're in a sea of life forms that are
floating through the air and we ca.
That's why you get sick.
If you touch things and you touch your
face,
you're literally taking life forms in
your body that wants to go to war with
your immune system.
Somewhere like deep there when you're
getting just like a rash,
there's just like some dude arguing with
his check or it was like,
get off my back.
All right.
And leaving and the rash,
that's what it is.
They had a fucking gang fight in the
middle of your face and became a Zit.
That's where cancer.
I've said this for the longest time.
That's where cancer comes from.
You put shit in your body that's not
supposed to be there.
And when they,
uh,
what's his name?
Said he got mouth cancer for being now.
Catherine said,
yeah,
dude,
I'm talking.
We're not.
We're not supposed to get it from her.
Well,
he said that he got it from eating a lot
of.
First of all,
he said he didn't really say that and
that people have distorted what he
originally said.
Well,
because he was talking like this,
it would be like the first guy ever.
Imagine if it was Michael Douglas was
the first guy ever to get mouth cancer
from eating pussy.
Be like,
whoa.
I think that's a real thing,
but it's the best.
It's the best reason to give for having
mouth cancer.
Like how'd you get that mouth?
Camels.
Bad Ass was eating tons of lack a
motherfucker.
Remember that trap and trailer has
sucked it right out of that square to
cancer.
All over my face,
hot and in the mouth like right down the
hatch,
a carnival clown mouth or once every six
weeks ago.
Grind off what's in there.
Go ahead.
Getting back to work in the morning,
Sammy Down Lyoto came gargle to smooth
that bitch down.
Always play.
Give me a cortisone shot in this thing.
I got an 11 at home,
crawling off the walls.
This bitch is crazy and she's hot as the
sun,
so I'm going back to work once that
pussy sucked.
Your doctor wants to know because
without warning,
wanting to get too specific,
this particular cancers caused by HPV,
which actually comes from cunnilingus
amongst other things,
but he took it back,
so don't worry if stress caused my son's
income.
Oh,
stress caused by my son's incarceration.
Didn't help trigger it.
But yeah,
it's a sexually transmitted disease.
It causes cancer.
Interesting.
I'm telling you,
dude,
HP,
you're not supposed to put our dicks and
are and shut your mouth.
Shut your mouth.
Fun.
Killer platform.
Get every time.
I'm 60,
90 with my check.
I'm like,
we're just given each other kids right
now and it makes me a little bit harder.
If you didn't,
you have like a cancer doctor has to
charge you like smoking cigarettes and
be like,
Louis,
if you're going to keep eating pussy,
I can't see you anymore.
That's probably exactly what it's going
to be.
One day I just picked kiss their clit
the whole time.
That's a good move.
See,
the thing is now they have a vaccine,
so now you get that hpv vaccine you
never have to worry about.
You have to go.
Yeah,
so they're giving it to young.
Yup.
Good dudes and girls.
Oh Man,
it's a vaccine,
but it come a risky one.
It's
like there's some side effects and some
people had,
you know,
depending on your biology.
Some people are pretty extreme side
effects apparently.
Like people who have gotten really sick
from that.
A HPV vaccine that happens with almost
all the vaccines.
Those certain people get really sick
them.
Yeah.
I mean this is the problem with this
whole anti vaccine movement is like
they're not.
They don't understand the nuanced
details of what it means to take an
entire population of 300 million people
and try to figure out a vaccine that's
going to protect them from disease.
It's not going to work on everybody.
There's going to be people that don't
jive with it.
There's going to be people that are
allergic to some of the stuff that's in
it is going to be people that have weird
biological reactions.
These are the outliers and like you have
to be willing to accept a certain amount
of outliers.
Unfortunately,
if you want to protect people from polio
and and all these different fucking
crazy diseases that they've really got a
good grip on measles.
Up until recently measles,
they had it locked down.
Nobody was getting measles anymore,
but all these fucking hippies decided
not to vaccinate their kids and now
measles are coming back because they're
worried about autism,
but at the same time dads are getting
older and older.
These 54 year old dudes are having
babies and you're like,
hey man,
like this.
This is.
This is way more of your problem than
probably most vaccinations.
As soon as we statistically old sperm
mix,
kids will left hands but to vaccinations
have fuck people up to.
It's like both things are true.
Like vaccinations are very important
numbers though.
Take.
You have to look at it and go,
all right dude.
You know,
but there's also been like,
I mean there's been a real extensive
research to disprove the idea that the
vaccinations are the reason for the
autism,
but I can understand it just like a
human instinctual way.
Imagine you have a baby,
you get your baby vaccinated.
There's nothing goes more against your
instincts than to give your baby to a
stranger and let them prick you with
like everything in you is telling you
this is a bad idea and then your kid's
sick over the next year.
I think it's very easy.
Just psychologically it'd be like,
well that's what fucking happened.
When I gave him to that guy and he
fucking prick them.
That's the reason my son isn't
circumcised was because he was born at
three in the morning and they were going
to do it the next day.
And when I brought,
I had held him and I loved them.
I looked at him in the face if they were
going to do it right away,
I like take them.
I cut them.
I don't give a fuck.
I don't want that.
But now he hit anyway.
Squeezed at the beginning to have the
kids had a look at the top of squeezy
pussy.
All you want to do with that pussy
squeeze,
squeeze my son's fucking head.
You can't help it.
You gotta squeeze it tight.
Fucking ramp head hanging out.
They came back the next day.
They're like,
are we going to take them now?
And I mean I,
I mean I had fucking hung out with him.
He's my son.
I loved him at that point so much.
So take me to a strip club already.
Chicken also implanted in my mind all of
these babies circumcision videos where
she made me watch and it's a thing dude.
Yeah.
And it's terrible.
It's a barbaric practice that people
only do because it was done to them and
because we feel like it's part of
tradition and I agree.
They have these bullshit stories.
Bell or goal hope or are you trying to
shut up?
You're not getting HIV that they did
that.
They did a study in Africa where they
took like a few hundred people in a
fucking straight up a place in Africa
where it was like one out of every four
people had aids and they proved that
circumcising them was stopping the
transmission of aids because there's not
as many breaks in the for skin,
so it's not as easy to transmit the
disease.
But we were talking about a third world
country where they're cleaning their
bodies.
We don't live in that same type of
poverty or fucked up like disease.
If you look at any of the justifications
for circumcision,
they're all super weak.
None of them actually,
you know,
they'll say these things where it's
like,
well,
you can't get cancer in,
in your for skin or something like that.
And you're like,
yeah,
and if you just lopped off chicks
breasts,
they can't get breast cancer,
but we're still not going to just
preemptively be like,
let's just fucking start castrating
people.
It changes the sensitivity of your Dick.
Uh,
Dick supposed to be slippery at the top.
I mean,
while you pull that for skin away,
it just dries up like an old piece of
gum.
Not supposed to be like that.
We've lived with literally change with
Dick's feel like when they go into
people's bodies,
it is gross.
When you describe an uncircumcised Dick
is self-lubricating you.
That's how they got the business done
back in the day.
It is a,
but that's the way my Dick Hangs soft.
I could.
I would hate having for skin.
You'd get over it.
Just that.
Would you rather that or no deck that or
no deck for a new force come back or.
No.
Oh,
of course.
Yeah,
so just let it go too.
Extreme ends of the rainbow.
That's how I live.
If I take it back,
I don't know if I can go back now and
just write what.
I just take my.
If a genie came out,
the gas.
Jeanie,
Eric came in and said,
we're gonna have one wish and it's just
about your pretty specific wishes back.
Let's see what's up.
You're going to get cut again if you're
a crazy asshole or they also to do it in
less than it would be your decision
reconstructive surgery they have for it
to pull shit.
I've seen what they do.
They take clothes,
pins,
they pull your dick apart down,
stretch the skin out around your Dick,
and it becomes kinda like a forest.
Like instead of like being one piece of
meat,
it's like a double piece in a rolled up.
Like ghostface killer webster was
hanging in his closet to try to make
himself taller.
All the grocer shit about four skin is
accentuated by the fact that it's a
double.
It's essentially like the whole skin of
the deck has to go over the top of the
deck.
It's outrageous.
They did it.
They did a penn and teller bullshit
about that.
Oh,
that's easy.
They're so into it,
but here's the thing we should do and
congratulations to you for doing that.
Don't circumcise your kids anymore.
It's crazy.
Got To stop.
That's really weird and fucked up.
It's dangerous.
It's not 100 percent dangerous,
but it might
be one out of a thousand kids.
Get some sort of an infection and they
could lose their dick that happens to
you,
and then they do a session that's a
regular thing that happens when it
happens.
They fuck up their dicks circumcision,
they get the infection and then they
say,
all right,
well now you can have a baby with no
dick and have it be a boy or we can
sexual sexual reassignment to be a girl.
And kids find out years later that they
were born a boy.
And that's why that happened.
There's actually a famous case,
there's a famous case about that where
they did a botched circumcision.
The kids penis was removed and then they
decided to give him a sexual
reassignment and everyone was fucking
terrified of it.
It didn't work.
The kid became massively,
massively depressed and then wound up
committing suicide,
uh,
as an adult and just just felt robbed of
reality.
You know,
by what,
by some crazy,
stupid,
avoidable ritual.
Are you going to cut baby dicks because
you think it looks better.
And,
and in the best case scenario,
even when all that shit doesn't happen,
you're torturing a baby.
I mean,
how else could you describe using
Novacane?
We're not saying like you're not,
but if anyone,
if you ever had a surgery like that and
they were like,
oh,
we're just going to put some local.
I mean like no one does gang.
So bad.
You're so sensitive.
You don't even know what pain is.
Your little tiny one dale person when
someone's cutting your dick already,
like what kind of a world of I've been
fucking does to you in that moment where
you're like,
we don't know the type of psychological
damage that that causes in that moment.
There's a real intense pain there in the
world.
They want their mom.
They want to be held against her mom's
breast.
They want to be feeding with their mom.
They want the love right now.
That's what they're supposed to get and
you take them and you fucking mutilate
them.
Who knows what type of switch you turn
on in that fucking babies had in that
moment.
Yeah.
You make Jewish people start all the
wars.
They decided they decided to fucking
really good at finance and the diamond
business and they were like one of the
first people to be circumcised.
Like the Jewish people you always assume
were circumcised.
Right?
Why is that?
It's just part of the code,
but there's no.
No one really knows.
Any reason where I was trying to save a
little,
you know,
is the most horrific you ever watched
the circumcision rituals they do in
Africa.
It.
I've seen a few of them.
Oh my God,
there's a video of this dude just
standing there,
balls ass naked,
and the guy comes over,
grabs his dick,
grabs this with one swipe of the blade,
shoot,
takes off the forest,
can pulls on his dick and slices away
and yanks it off and the guy stands
there completely.
Stone face doesn't react,
and that's part of the ritual is Dana
White Wilson.
So you want to be an ultimate fighter.
His Dick is bleeding and he's just
standing there.
He's not looking at it and it's not a
good circumcision cut either.
It's totally fuck.
It's like peeling an orange,
right?
You're never going to get a straight
line.
It's really lit and looks like this poor
guy's Dick.
It's,
it's.
So if you see the Jamie,
do you know the video saved on my
fingers,
the Jewish ceremony where the rabbi
isn't the right by like suck blood or
something.
That's a dick.
Yeah,
like every.
It's not that every Jew doesn't do that,
but there's Dick sucked by a rabbi.
Yeah.
I might've.
Have you done any babysitter,
Dick Sucking cock.
I brought this up three years ago
on the show and I'm the only person
doing any research on our show.
I may seem like I'm the dumbest one,
but I promise you right now you're
almost prepared.
Dumbest one.
I'm the one doing the research.
I brought this up and everyone looked at
me like I'm an asshole.
And I'm like,
no,
I swear to God.
Rabbis are out there sucking babies.
Dicks and you guys were your
videos.
Are you justifying it?
You gave a headline thing because they
had to.
There was some serious problems with it.
Oddly enough,
because of herpes,
because babies were getting herpes and
dying from herpes,
from rabbi sucking their Dick after they
performed this circumcision and
apparently in some versions of Judaism
it's part of the ritual and that this
guy was explaining it and like in
Yiddish and he was explaining all the
different things that what's important
that the rabbi or the WHO have the mo l
performs this.
I think he said it to tsetse.
He had like a word for it.
Oh,
you mean the bulls?
He says a nice old word for sucking baby
dicks.
You just cut.
I mean it's,
it's so the only in religion.
Do you have a youtube video where you're
dressed like a wizard talking about
sucking baby dixit.
You just cut and.
Well this is a part of our tradition,
but do you think it's an argument like
you're not just some fucking like dress
and like making like singing some song.
You're actually going like,
well this is what I have to.
Have you seen it?
Do you think it's definitely sinister?
No,
it's retarded always.
Or is it just like it's fucking stupid.
They're stuck in it and someone did it
to him and someone did it to his dad and
they feel like they're a part of this
clan.
It's fucking.
And you feel like if you were to give up
on that,
you're giving up on your dad,
your family.
Everything's alive,
so you got to just blindly believe that
this is what you did to retard the
progress.
It retards progress.
It is.
It literally is retarded.
Like in that sense,
like forget about the derogatory term
you used for people.
It's a retarded idea.
It retards logic.
You're cutting a baby dick and sucking
on it.
Then you're making a youtube video
saying,
well,
but when we thought the world was flat,
this is how we do.
We still do it this way and we like to
cut it and we like to fuck when we have
a name for it.
It's not that I make with my mouth
that's different than sucking cut baby.
I've judged is very important.
A rose by any other name I say.
Yeah,
I mean it was crazy that someone could
sit around and justify doing some shit
to a baby's deck.
Just because they've always done it,
but I think all but two have Jackie
Mason to it,
like a reasonable rate.
Just a little bit.
I mean is if it's any better to cut it
and not suck it,
like at least maybe it feels better for
the kid to.
Honestly,
if you're going to stick,
give a blowjob
standpoint.
You would definitely want somebody to
suck your Dick after you got to cut.
But how,
what kind of a person just sucks baby
dicks all the time.
Like how many baby you took an average
rabbi.
There's done this or what it was it a
moral moral oil more was my.
Well,
so like a shoe company or something
that's close to whale,
but these how many baby dicks in a
lifetime and a strong career?
Thirty five year career working for the
synagogue.
How many baby dicks have you started
going to college and have numbers?
Imagine that you go to college in
Arizona.
Is that matter?
She's got license,
particularly sledding.
Could you imagine if she testifies like
a Nazi and Nuremberg goes.
I was following orders.
I had to was a website and you just see
like it just scrolled and you know that
bar on the right side.
The dot was really tiny.
A lot to do.
It's all the baby dixie sucked over the
years.
I kept an elbow,
but he told me it was the best chicken,
my page,
my.
Anyway,
so Jamie do not show us that son of a
bitch.
Her check.
How's that online?
Is that on youtube and it's.
There's blood everywhere.
There's a cut it.
There's blood everywhere and the baby's
screaming and the guy sucks.
The baby's Dick.
Congratulations.
You're an idiot.
Sorry for cutting your Dick though.
This is one of those things that because
it's a part of a religion,
people get mad if you take it down.
People get mad if you shit on it,
but you.
This is one of the.
If you see,
there's no clear indication that your
religion is gone completely off the
track.
That if you're cutting baby dixon,
then sucking them.
Anybody in their right mind outside of
that religion saying we can do to
Charlie.
Thinking about cutting David Dixon,
sucking him.
What's it called?
The MTI and the CIA.
Yeah.
Here's what's fucked up.
That's on youtube.
Look,
yeah,
there's a lot of Jewish people that are
watching their families,
babies getting their dicks cut and then
such,
but then there's also a whole set of
pedophile vampires that are watching
that and just beating off to it all day
long.
Some fucking guy who taught his dog to
Heil Hitler and he's looking at jail
time.
But you could suck a baby's Dick on
youtube.
It's your fucking video.
Go Up.
Yes.
You want to stop baby dicks,
but I want to go to jail.
Oh,
become a rabbi Jamie.
Get that down.
Show you.
There's a bunch of son of a bitch.
There's hundreds of them.
Hundreds of guys suck.
And Baby Dick's when it's 2018.
This is not a Jewish religion.
We're not living in the barbarian times,
but today people are cutting in sucking
baby dick.
How about genital female genital
mutilation for it?
How much act for two.
Please say that anymore,
man.
Yes,
you can march.
It's march.
I'll wait.
Oh,
it's a female as of April.
It's off and mutilation month.
What month is it a female empowerment
month?
What is it?
Is it.
Is there one of those nights of Hispanic
month,
Hispanic heritage month.
There was a.
There was a national woman's Day.
Right.
I stayed off every year and I'm not
saying Shit,
don't play in traffic.
I'm definitely not going to say
anything.
Just snotty,
you know,
trying to be cute.
You don't need to say anything.
I wouldn't.
Benjamin is handling it for all of us.
Women's history month,
Hispanic Saturday,
March 30.
First we're celebrating.
So this is women's history month.
The fucked up thing is black history
month.
The shortest month.
Yeah.
That was definitely some passive
aggressive racist shit.
Percent hundred percent keep dam an
extra bone in the wreck.
What makes them history harder?
So like at what point in time is that
going to end?
Like how,
how long in the future would it be
before we didn't have black history
month.
Like we're not going to have like a
Moore's history month for people.
Right?
So you're saying black people are going
to go extinct at a certain point and we
won't have to.
I think all people are going to go
extinct at a certain point and I pray.
I bet it's probably within a thousand
years.
I just don't think so.
I hope you don't feel are months like
fucking frat parties.
That's true too,
but I just think like what point in time
we're going to not care.
I mean if you.
If there's a way like let's just imagine
is it even humanly possible to engineer
the education of human beings to the
point where there's no more.
Racism doesn't exist anymore.
No more sexism,
no more homophobia.
Naturally we were tribes and we
gravitate toward people that look like
us and we're comfortable with.
I remember in kindergarten shore,
this is 1987,
we were allowed to just choose our
tables because it didn't make you sit
where you no assigned seats or whatever
and I remember all the white kids just
sat with the white kids and the black
kids sit with the black kids and
Hispanic and says with the Hispanic kids
and I'm half white and I was raised by
white people and you see little Puerto
Rican may just plopped in the middle of
this white table and all these little
kids probably like,
what the fuck is this kid doing here?
But it was very much like everyone's
segregated racially and it was very
natural.
You're a kid.
I'm talking about as a grown adult who's
already examined the world,
don't you think it's possible to people
to get to the point where they don't do
that anymore?
I just let it go.
I think individuals can,
but the idea that in terms of large
demographic groups,
there won't be any in group preference
and there won't be any.
Maybe I'm not closed off to it,
but it seems like a real tough goal.
I agree with you 100 percent,
but I'm more,
I'm more leaning towards that now than
ever before because of the Internet
because I think people are accelerating,
accelerating what they understand about
what's going on in the world.
It's just,
it's way more deep like for you've
talked to average 20 year old today and
they're just way more knowledgeable than
I was when I was 20,
like stunningly.
So like even if they believe ridiculous
shit,
they.
Yeah,
because they have the information.
I mean because it's like if I like it
for me to have,
I wouldn't know half the shit.
I know if I grew up,
you know,
decades before I did,
I wasn't going to go to the library
every fucking care.
Yeah.
It's like I wasn't going to put that in,
but when it's right in front of you,
it's
like,
all right,
well I guess I can spend two to 5:00
AM,
but I think we're going towards that.
It seems like the sharing of information
is sort of making us move away from
that.
It seems like it's making us more
erratic and more kind of crazy.
You know,
I feel like we don't know how to like,
you know,
people don't know how to quickly share
an idea and deal with people reacting to
that idea.
Um,
as fast as it's happening.
I think it's creating a lot of people
like that are,
you know,
we speak of friends who like,
like this,
owning each other on facebook and
publicly been like,
fuck you dude,
if you believe this,
I don't ever want to talk to you again.
You're like,
dude,
Whoa,
where am I supposed to talk about some
of the Shit I thought whatever happen to
like water cooler conversation.
You weren't supposed to talk about
politics or religion or any of this
stuff.
You're kind of supposed to just leave
each other's lives and,
and sort of like live with each other
and,
you know.
Yeah.
Well,
I remember thinking about this when the,
um,
the thing with a chick filet,
which by the way is delicious,
but uh,
when they,
yes,
solid my favorite class,
but when they,
when they were like against gay marriage
and people are like boycotting chick
filet and you're just kinda like,
well,
what,
what is the precedent that you're
setting here?
Like if I pull up to a gas station and I
go to like a snack,
do I have to go?
Like,
so where do you stand on the Iraq war?
Where do you stand on?
It isn't the point that we all can kind
of get along even if we have wild.
Yeah.
But we would like to spend our money
wisely knows the ideas that people are
voting with their dollars.
Right?
I get that.
But it's almost like now we can have all
that knowledge and,
and like I get your point,
but it can work toward us being
inclusive or it can work toward us being
like,
well no,
I'm not gonna fuck with anybody who
doesn't meet x,
Y,
z beliefs going on,
which isn't,
isn't necessarily great.
No,
because it's like there's something
beautiful about like,
uh,
the market where like I'm,
I'm a Jew,
but I can like,
you know,
get a cab in New York from a Muslim and
I'm just like,
oh,
I'm going up here,
and then he drops me off and he's like,
have a good night.
God bless.
And I'm like,
thank you.
And we give each other money.
Happy place is such a melting pot
though.
It's so different than la La.
Everybody's in their own car.
They go to their own building and
insulated.
In New York,
you're forced to walk with people,
getting the train with people.
Everybody's all together.
The subway,
9:00
AM at
34th street.
You have a million people in one small
area where it's like one person's a
homeless person.
Next person is a multimillionaire,
supermodel actor from every different
area life and they're all squished
together in La.
You got to go to the party to hang out
with that model or actor to,
to interact with them really in any way.
You don't have a lot of examples outside
of actor and model.
You said that in home construction
workers?
Never found like just like a cashier or
somebody living the dream.
I feel battles.
If you guys want to take an uber back,
if you guys are going to stay and hang
out and keep.
Sorry I have to go because I have to go
through bonfire.
I have to go to series six.
Seven.
What time do you gotta be there?
Uh,
we have to be there like,
like 2:40.
Oh,
zero k
dude.
Yeah.
Okay.
That's a Dan soder show isn't deep.
Sirius Xm radio program.
Yes.
Yeah.
I love that show.
On the side.
On the satellite radio.
Well we can either keep going for a
little bit and talk mad shit about Jay.
Oh,
I'd love that.
That'd be fun.
He'll be fine.
Well we can just wrap this up then.
I can keep going on their I podcast.
I got a lot of shit about Jay to talk.
Thanks very much for having this
facilitating this.
Absolutely mad you guys have together.
I love you brother.
So she's been a prick all week.
The door.
That was poor etiquette.
I liked his half hair red better by
buddy jamie.
Did you get the release people try and
make sure I don't have any.
Your car.
That's.
I like how you rocking the old school
chain with the keys.
It's not connected to a wallet.
Let it go.
It's not connected to anything.
It's just a fashion accessory.
I swear to God,
no wallet.
It's got a chain,
uh,
marches to the beat of his own drum
living in Greece movie.
It's fucking dudes that like would wear
those like 19 fifties type clothes.
Like roll the cuffs up.
Their jeans.
Were those old school shoes?
Yeah.
Sometimes I get a little like,
you just kind of wish you lived one life
in every generation.
We don't want to just experience that a
little bit and know what that's about.
Oh my God,
it must have been amazing.
Sixties would've been so cool.
Just like when I get like the
counterculture movement first happened
and like music was just awesome and like
the late sixties was like,
that was just like a cool time to be on
it.
But I have fat thighs so I could never
wear the pants that were available from
it at the time.
You could wear them,
bro.
You just got to get him going to plead
it out.
Yeah.
That was tougher to do in the seventies
and sixties before the Internet.
You couldn't find your specific.
Very true.
What's up with people that want to go
back to those arrows so bad.
They get those really bad tattoos.
You know those like Ed Hardy look and
tattoos.
Like what the fuck are you drawing on
yourself?
It's like some of those are so bad,
but it's like purposely bad artwork.
It's supposed to mimic a time period,
but it's like your body is not a museum
though.
Okay.
If you want to mimic that time period,
she get a fucking picture from that time
period and put it on the wall.
There's creativity,
pirate ship on your ass.
People know people I've been established
for almost like before any of that time
period.
Like where it's just like you'll see the
pictures from the fifties or something
where it's just like the dudes wore
suits.
The girls that these dresses like almost
like.
I'd like to experience that for a little
bit.
Just wearing a suit and a top hat,
flipping a quarter of all my fucking six
foot four and 120 pounds.
We want to wear a suit to exact
measurements.
Were watching this Jack Jack Johnson
fight on on video from like,
what was it like the early 19 hundreds
and everyone in the audience had a one
of those hats.
Those gentlemen hats that they wear.
They all wear the same hat.
Everybody had
a hat on.
Like every guy,
every guy in the audience has thousands
of people.
They all those dress up hats on.
Oh,
Jack Jones has got to find a ground out
there.
Look at all the hats to the same hat.
I'll tell you right now,
everybody's got the same hat on even
today.
It's like accessorizing for a dude is
like the best look.
You throw in like a watch and like a
nice like hat and like just little
things they make.
It puts a dude together like a check.
You want his little shit on her
responsible.
You want it to be as close to naked as
possible,
but we don't give a shit about
accessories.
None of that stuff,
but a woman,
when they look at us and they see like a
watch to like,
oh,
this guy's got money.
Louis J dot Gomes.
Lights.
Fucking dudes were a lot of jewelry.
If I'm going to fuck him,
man.
Accessorize very well.
I have twoish.
Rewatch,
jokey.
Stop when Jay until listed on continuing
to tell the world is on accessorizing.
Nah,
man.
Jay can leave.
We'll keep this magic going.
So what's I say?
That's a good point.
What is harder than to do with the
watch?
You guys get what I'm saying?
Sure.
Jay Calls me later.
He's like,
hey,
how'd the rest of the show go?
Go.
We all just started sucking each others'
time in earrings and shit.
Scarves and 19 fifties.
Tattoos.
Roller girls.
Roller Derby girls.
Yeah.
I think people that get those tags,
that style,
like if they go,
I want to,
uh,
you know,
this old style tattoo,
it's a lack of creativity.
They just want to fit into a certain
type of thing.
They want to look like a type of person
with that Tattoo.
They saw another dude at one point and
they were like,
I want to look like that guy,
and then so it's like you're saying it's
the same thing as the shirts and the
hats.
Basically it's the same thing.
It's just trying to look like the next
guy or just trying to like fit into the
fucking thing.
It's like whether it's a suit and a hat,
it's just a fucking,
oh no,
now I'll get a tattoo.
Now I'll get this.
And you see that with a lot of people.
It was a lot of people in la,
in New York,
you see that a lot where someone's got
like a crazy different look,
but you're like,
but you were just trying to fit into
that girl.
Yeah,
but it's all the same thing,
man.
You're just high school and I was
nominated.
We're not goth,
but it was borderline goth in high
school can be borderline goth.
It was because there was a goth kids.
It didn't really accept me.
He's on the spectrum.
You've got spectrum three five.
That's what I used to wear,
like Marilyn Manson tee shirts and I had
long hair and eyeliner,
Europe of the world,
but the goth kids weren't really like
taken in.
There were those my crew.
Okay.
Um,
but yeah,
you want it to just be a part of
something and everyone was like,
oh that guy so unique or weird,
but I just looked like 100 other kids at
the mall that shop at hot topic.
That's a big problem with young people
wanting to be a part of something.
You know?
I was listening to Sam Harris podcast
with Christian ecoline.
He was a white power guy who was
recruited into these white nationalist
when he was like 14.
Just the podcast detailing these
horrific fucking events that this
guy went through and horrific violence
against black people.
He just got sucked into being in a group
when he was 14 and here he is now in his
40 years after leaving super open and
honest about it and talking about it,
you're like,
wow.
And it makes you realize like this smart
guy that you're hearing talking at 40
could have been that guy at 14.
They got sucked into the group.
Like it's not.
It isn't really not even whether or not
you're smart.
It's whether or not you have life
experience where you,
you know,
the path you go down.
Because this luck,
dude,
I'm telling you right now,
you are just a product of your
environment.
You could turn left when you should've
turned right one day and then your whole
fucking life is a whole different thing.
APPS,
you know,
died some fucked up shit as a teenager
that it's like it just,
I happened to land here but I could have
easily just been in jail or a bit of
criminal or are legitimately hurt.
People went down a much different path.
Well that's the crazy thing when people
like kind of a like they have so much
like hatred towards someone else for
having a different view than them or
being in a different situation and
you're like,
dude,
just understand.
You were like two little circumstances
away from being mad at God.
I see that a lot with people and I'm on
the side of like gun rights,
like I'm not for gun,
but the people who are like really
shitty to these teenage kids who are
like becoming famous and you're like,
dude,
if you were a fucking teenager and you
could have just been on the fucking news
and everyone's praising you because you
take this position,
sub,
we'd all fucking do that exact same
thing.
Yesterday I was talking about one of
these nra guys that was mocking these
kids.
I'm like,
you're out of your fucking mind.
If anybody should be talking about.
We got to do something.
It's kids that got shot at.
I mean this is.
They got.
They have the floor now.
I understand.
You're supposed to have the floor.
I mean they just got shot at.
They lost their friends and they are
standing up and maybe they're not
informed about a lot of issues.
Maybe they don't know what a
semiautomatic or an ar 15 is.
Maybe they don't know those details,
but they know that no one's doing shit
and people keep getting shots and the
kind of biomass because they survived.
They got lucky.
They just fucking one on the right
place,
but I was talking about that Maryland
one and we like.
You don't talk about the positive ones.
Yes,
but you know,
because again,
tell the story.
So more or less.
In Maryland there was,
there was a school shooting or a kid
came into school with a gun,
but they had an armed security guard.
He took them out.
Nobody died.
Military Training Guy got rid of him
quick and that's what the NRA advocates
are saying like,
hey,
this is a good thing.
We should.
We should have someone who's an armed
and ready responder at the school to
prevent this kind of shit from happening
and there's a lot of veterans that would
take that job happily and you would have
your kids 100 percent safe and people
are like,
no,
that's not the solution.
The solution is take the guns away.
I don't like the idea of armed security
at school.
I don't like the idea of doctors,
I don't like the idea of arming
teachers,
but it's like to just dismiss that and
be like,
no gun control.
The only reasonable measure I think is
naive.
But just to the point,
like you were saying before,
I have no problem with people being
like,
hey,
cnn shouldn't just be putting these kids
on without having someone to rebut it or
they shouldn't be putting this on and
just say,
but to go at the
kid and be like,
oh,
this kid's fucking,
you know,
just milking this experience like
whatever.
Any of us would do a thing like that.
Look,
I,
you know,
I don't,
I don't have a horse in the race.
I don't really give a shit.
I don't really shoot guns and I know
he's the only one I've shot guns.
It's just been really fun.
There's no part of me that like,
I think I would swallow it a little more
of people that like were really a big
gun advocates,
which is kind of admit that like,
dude,
it's pretty awesome.
We want to blow shit up.
It's fucking great.
You know?
Um,
but you get this other sort of thing
where I just think that you should have
people that are really trained,
really responsible and we should have
specific measures in place in order and
I know we do have that,
but maybe we should look at it and push
that line back even a little bit more
because yeah,
you're right.
Even in the example of the dude,
you know,
taking out that kid in that school,
I don't necessarily have an issue with
having an armed security guard at the
school to protect children,
but I kind of have an issue with
somebody who you don't know when his
girlfriend broke up with him and when
this dude went bat shit.
Right.
So even when you have to get people's
psychological exams,
like when do they go crazy?
When is there a moment where somebody
snaps and now they're fucking crazy,
right?
I actually,
I'm
really against gun control of just about
any kind.
I know.
I actually think when people,
a lot of times Republicans will go,
it's not about gun control,
it's about mental health.
I think that's even more of a copout
because you're like,
what the fuck are you even saying by
that?
Like what do you,
you know,
there's lots of,
when you say mental health,
it's like there's lots of people who
suffer from anxiety and depression,
all these things.
It doesn't mean they're a risk to
others.
Like what?
What are you actually going to say?
Like I'm for unfettered gun rights,
but everyone has to have like a
psychological exam and it's as if
there's some way that we can predict
who's going to shoot up a fucking
school.
And the truth of the matter is it's
really fucking tough.
It definitely is.
But what you're saying is entirely
correct because it is absolutely about
mental health and you have to be fucking
crazy to be a school shooter.
Yeah.
And most of these people are on some
sort of psychiatric medicine.
There's a giant percentage of them.
So it is in fact a mental health issue
because there are there literally on
most of them,
like the vast percentage of them are on
mental health medication.
So the question is whether or not it's
the mental health medication that's
causing them to do this shit or whether
or not they were already crazy and that
medication was just trying to treat this
disease and they got ahold of guns and
that's the problem is the guns.
Yeah.
So maybe I didn't say that like
precisely enough because I agree with
everything you just said.
I'm just making the point that the idea
that it's like,
oh all we know is that there's this
category of people who have mental
health issues and they shouldn't be
allowed to get guns is way too broad.
But no,
I actually,
I think again,
like you mentioned earlier,
it's like dude,
they say these.
Anyone who's real fucked up nowadays as
a lot of mental health issues a lot and
is in school,
they're going to put them on trucks.
They put anyone who's borderline on
drugs.
So the really fucked up kids on like a
cocktail of drugs and no admit with a
lot of these antidepressants,
anti psychotics that they can cause
suicidal tendencies.
Some of you will even say they cause
homicidal tendencies.
So I think it's pretty reasonable that
maybe in some very small percentage of
them they cause you to just fucking
want to go,
or they push you at least in the
direction of wanting to go,
just shoot up a bunch of people to
relief the,
relieve you of the feeling of
consequences.
There's,
they're there,
they disassociate you from whatever
you're experiencing.
That's one of the most disconcerting
things about the idea that if someone
has homicidal thoughts but they're
keeping them at bay,
and then they take some pill that
saying,
hey,
fuck it,
let's do this.
Let's do this.
You're not exercising the whatever,
the mental processes of not killing
people on your own.
You need this thing to do it and then
you don't have your medication.
One day I heard you talk about this the
other day was kind of interesting.
I forget who was on people whose metzker
or somebody,
but you were talking about people that
she was very calm,
cool and collected,
relaxed on that episode.
It was weird.
The best,
uh,
the best advertisement for Caveman
nitrile you could possibly,
it will make you into a raving madman.
The Maryland school shooter was killed
by his own bullet,
not the school resource officer.
Police said,
oh,
he shot himself in the head when the guy
was coming after him.
Okay.
But still kind of a similar moral of the
story that maybe the guy behind him made
him shoot himself and this is definitely
not the same story.
The story was that this arm,
God took him out.
Yes.
That's what.
That's what I heard as well.
That's what I had heard.
I had heard a deceptive version of it
then because I heard that this guy
engaged in a firefight with this kid and
killed him instantly.
Yeah.
That's what I read.
Like six different articles that said
that.
Yeah.
Okay.
So that maybe that's incorrect or
there's too many things to pay attention
to.
Is a shot.
Hit the shooters gun in his hand.
His shot hit the shooters gun before
having to shoot.
Shoot her,
shot himself.
He shot himself with a gun that got
shot.
I said the officer,
the officer shot struck rollins gun,
which was in the teens hand.
The sheriff's office said,
nevertheless,
his quick action confronting rollins.
Just three minutes after the shot to
students has been credited with bringing
the incident to a quicker.
So the guy did shoot the kid.
Yeah,
but they,
he hit his gun.
Killed him.
Yeah.
So he,
he shot him and then when the.
After the guy shot him,
he just shot himself while he's still
could praise.
Praise came even when it was unclear
which shot killed the teen,
but he definitely seems like he shot
him.
I mean,
he was in the fire.
He really wasn't a firefight with this
fucking guy.
I don't know,
Dude.
I look,
I think there's not a single answer to
any of this.
I think it is definitely a mental health
issue.
I think you're not gonna.
Nobody's gonna come up with a law that's
going to figure all this shit out.
I just,
I don't live.
I joked about it before,
but I,
I kind of lived my life in a sort of
ignorance is bliss state with this type
of shit.
I mean,
I don't know.
I,
I have to guess my kid's not going to be
shot to death in a school one day.
Knock on wood.
Right.
I know,
and it's,
and it's a horrible,
horrible thing.
Um,
but the reality is I don't know if these
people that are so obsessed with
everything and just they're making it
their lives,
I almost feel like they're kind of
missing the point if I,
my,
my kid isn't gonna be out at a rally
holding a sign and I'm not spending my
days doing that with them.
I'm spending my days creating memories
with him and just trying to spend my
life making a good life
and I'm not really politicizing anything
with my five year old.
Well,
well,
there's people that feel like they want
to do something to want change.
They don't want this to happen again.
And if you lost your kid,
he'd probably feel that way to me.
Oh yeah,
sure.
I mean there's,
there's,
there's way too many of these things is
way too many of them.
So we got to figure out what it is.
I think the real issue resolved realize
rather,
um,
it,
it lies.
Here's one,
one giant part of the problem.
Everybody's looking at the final piece
of the puzzle,
the final piece of the puzzle.
It all comes together.
Is the school shooting?
What gets someone to that position?
How do they get to that?
You gotta go to step one,
not to step 10.
Step 10 is a school shooting you gotta,
you gotTa.
Figure out how do we get less people to
go from step one to step two?
How do we keep more people happy as
young people?
How do we give more people support
headed when we give more people therapy
or exercise or recreation or friendship
or community guidance or whatever the
fuck we're doing,
where we alienate people to the point
where they literally want to go and
shoot everybody else.
It's like the,
the,
the physical equivalent of like flipping
over a game when you're losing,
you know,
I,
I think,
yeah,
that's a great analogy by the way.
I think that's exactly what it is.
It's like,
oh,
this world is so bad for me.
Well Fuck,
you can make it for everybody.
Fuck that.
Nice teacher.
I've thought I completely agree with
what you're saying and I think maybe the
silver lining in this,
like the best thing that could come out
of this and it has nothing to do with
the law,
is just that kids in high school will
think twice before they're brutally
ostracizing some other kid because
you're like,
hey,
watch out.
That kid might be the one who
maybe not people.
Kids think they're invincible.
They're not thinking about that.
I remember when I,
you know,
columbine was so such a big news story
when I was.
I was in high school,
I believe at the time.
I'm sure.
Yeah.
It's your birthday.
Actually.
My birthday real fucked up and dude,
it was fucking,
it was such a big deal.
I had never seen anything like that
before.
Um,
this is before nine slash 11.
Nine slash 11 was the next big,
big thing.
But it happens so often now that because
of the Internet,
I almost feel like people are also
desensitized to like how crazy it was
because columbine dude,
it was bizarre watching the images on
the news of the people of running out of
that school.
It was like haunting and I remember
watching it and my mom made this point
and shoot my mom a fucking drug addict,
lunatic.
But she had these weird little moments
in her life when she said some crazy
shit.
And she was like,
yeah.
She like,
you know what?
Yeah,
maybe they shouldn't have fucked with
those kids just in a weird way.
And I was like,
Oh damn,
I'm really good at defending these like,
but you just kinda.
It wasn't defending the active people
getting killed,
but it was sort of looking at the root
with which is what you're saying.
And,
and she,
you know,
she's kind of made that point.
I kind of always stuck with me
even more than like,
which I get the point,
but even more than other kids bullying
him.
The truth is if you want to get it the
route you want to be like,
Hey,
parents fucking love your kids and give
them a really good childhood.
But it's like,
how do you actually make that happen?
There's a narrative,
difficult natural inclination that
animals have to pick on the weaker ones.
It's a terrible natural of the human
beings have to avoid because chickens do
it.
I've chickens,
chickens,
fuck.
With the smaller chickens and the less
aggressive chickens,
they fucked them up.
They have a pecking order.
You know,
I've seen it with dogs would one dog
becomes the alpha of the pack,
takes over,
dominates the other dogs is a natural
thing.
It's natural.
It's natural in every single animal
community and it's natural with people.
But we're smart and we understand the
consequences of that and you've got to
give those kids a reason to not do that,
you know?
But there's also the problem with like
if you're going to school with Lebron
James,
okay,
like standing next to this fucking giant
super athlete,
you're like,
shit,
kinda bullshit.
Genetic roll the dice that I can get.
This motherfucker got all aces.
He's got five aces,
like seven feet tall.
He weighs 300 pounds and he moves like a
pant.
There's no,
there's no basis to win.
And that's.
I love that analogy specifically because
it's so stupid.
I have a tattoo on my arm and it's just
a to seven off suit.
I'm a poker player,
but it's.
That's the analogy.
It's like,
take it off.
Take that tattoo man.
Fuck.
It's such to such a bad client.
No,
you have no idea,
dude.
It's the worst and you thought about
doing anything about it.
I have one cover up.
I have one that says Lou dog.
My first one ever,
boy,
nobody even call me Lou dog.
They just did sarcastically.
After I got that nickname it introducing
myself a nickname.
I was 18.
I was like,
I need a tattoo.
What can I get in my mind?
Could only go to Lou dog.
That is one of the juiciest thing a
human being could do,
is give themselves a neck tattoo on
their body.
If you just decide.
I mean,
I'm not talking about like a pro
wrestler mean for fighters.
It's pretty commonplace,
but for the average person,
my friends call me Lou dog.
Nobody calls told me their friend at
that point.
It wasn't good at defending any of this
shit.
Already been a good.
Like everything is fat.
Arms was a fat kid,
so I said Lou dog and really small
because I could only afford a $60
tattoo,
a little petite Lou dog and then below
it,
it wasn't even the full thing that could
connect around my arm.
It was just a little bit of tribal,
just like a slipper,
like a two inch sliver of tribal.
What?
How is a kid in high school?
Most of the guys that were doing tattoos
weren't good artists.
There was a few good artists.
You would find them in magazines and
Shit and he'd have to travel to
Connecticut to get a tattoo done.
It was.
It was weird.
It wasn't like it is now.
Like now the artists are going from art
school right into tattooing and you're
getting these amazing pieces.
I mean it's.
I've never seen tattoos like today in my
life.
I saw one the other day.
Some guy had Michael Jordan tattooed.
It looked like a leg or an arm.
I couldn't tell what it was,
but it's like they took a photograph and
just wrapped around this guy's okay
leg.
It's insane.
Yeah.
Now you go on the Internet and you can
actually see all the art and just
compare it and pick and choose and
they're just way more artists and way
more people getting tattoos are
so much bigger market because the gun,
the guns they use.
Like my buddy tattoos me a shout out,
Keith Carmelo Tattoos.
Shout out to Karen Mellow Keith.
He's the fucking man.
Great Tattoo artist kid.
Now he's got a nickname.
He didn't give it to himself so it's not
out of long island,
dude.
And he's got these guns.
Whatever he does.
He was an expensive,
like German fucking engineered gun and
it just doesn't look at that.
That's cool.
Cool.
Somebody got Tom Segura tattooed with
some sort of a viking hat on.
What does that have?
Samurai Samurai hat.
Oh right.
That's an Okinawan symbol on his
forehead.
We get a lot of the legion of Skanks
Logo Tattoo or a Samurai artists just
like made a thing and he offered to give
someone a deal if they like tatted it on
them.
Dad is hilarious.
That's amazing.
Look how good the microphone looks.
Fuck this guy's good.
What's.
What is this name?
Jamie Lee Parker.
Hidden Los Angeles Tattoo.
West Hills,
California.
Damn,
that guy's good.
That guy's really good.
Holy Shit.
See,
that's what I'm talking about.
Like these are real artists.
Like look how good that joke or is.
That's insane.
Yeah.
These are real artists who are really.
Like when I was a kid there was a lot of
guys who would just take one of those
things off the wall and they'll go,
oh,
you want a black panther on your.
I'm sticking it on your arm and pull it
down,
and then they would just start tracing
that line.
They do a shitty job of doing it.
A lot of my friends got these dog shit
tattoos.
A lot of them was the Black Panther with
the claws cutting into the skin and the
clause would be red bull.
So students are like stupid things like
tweety bird tattoos on the wall.
I was like,
who the fuck would ever choose that?
Lot of people.
My mom had like straight up jailhouse
tattoo,
so my mom had a money sign that was done
with a ash with a needle into her hand.
Get to get that paper.
I understand that.
It's ironic,
right?
We gotta do what you gotTa do to get
that paper.
Let everybody know there's this weird
tattoos that just like own a period in
time,
like the barbwire tramp stamp.
Even a little bit like that.
Like the nineties kind of thing that
you're like,
oh no.
Was a dude with a tramp stamp.
He's got a butterfly.
Tramp stamp.
Thank God.
Why?
I don't know.
And there were no.
Yeah,
he just got it.
It's kind of funny,
I guess.
It's funny.
Kind of funny.
What is Russian prison?
Prison Tattoos?
Yeah.
Books about in a pretty dope.
Well,
there's one fader million acre,
his brother fair to Faye doors,
brother Alex Alexander,
a million acres.
He's got a bunch of crazy Russian
tattoos on his body and he had mob
tattoos on his chest,
on his,
uh,
right in front of his doubts and he got
them both redone and switched over.
He's fucking Jack now,
Jack.
Really?
Yeah,
because they were never really.
Jacqueline Alexander,
a million inco recent muscles picture.
He just came back because that was part
of their charm and those guys,
he doesn't drink.
Yeah,
I just stretch for rate.
Yeah.
Yeah,
and he came out,
was fighting with Hep c.
he's like a fucking.
Just a bad,
scary look.
Oh yeah.
He's Super Jack.
That's a good picture.
But there's a better picture of him,
like facing head on where you go,
Holy Shit.
Like he's like legitimate now that's on
it.
Whatever.
But you get the point.
That's what he used to look like.
I used to look like a bear.
He used to have like,
like our got a little bit of that right
here.
A little bit of fat right here.
He's got like a little bit of that like
right there.
So he's.
Yeah,
because that's the part of the charm of
the Mammalian NGOs was that they were
almost kind of like,
just looked like that.
Like we don't even give a fuck.
We're just tough.
Russians didn't care.
Yeah.
He got ahold of that fucking shit.
Look at his left in Israel.
Go back to that picture real quick.
Look at those.
The tattoos on his pack on his right and
his left side.
Like you see him there.
Those,
that's when they were a Russian gang
tattoo and he's got a woman on his back
like I know a skeleton holding a baby
tattooed on his back.
Have you seen his back?
Is the creepy shit?
Go See.
Go Up.
Pull up back tattoo.
That'll get us back.
It's fucking crazy skeleton holding a
baby.
Like what?
Okay.
I just don't do only one thing.
Only skittled holding babies.
That's the scariest image you can think
of.
The holding baby,
his life.
This is what they want to tell the
world.
When you see my back,
I am skeleton holding.
Baby.
Baby has soared to it.
Now do it and up bat.
It does for the baby kill skeleton and
this buts of the moon in the butts in
the moon and the bats fly.
You mess up just in south beach
describing the fucking tattoo.
Then it's so evil.
Mullins.
What does that mean?
Well,
it's.
I don't think it's American.
I think that's a Russian words.
Right?
So who knows what it says?
Yeah.
Yeah man.
That Russian language.
It's a trip to look at it,
man.
When you see Russian type down,
you like what?
You guys?
How long have you been doing this?
How cold hungry were you,
but you came up with this shit.
This is the Third Reich.
God with us.
It says it's Third Reich Shit.
Oh fuck.
Alexander on the Whoa.
God with us as a phrase commonly used in
Harold.
Harold in Prussia from 17.
Oh,
one and later.
Okay.
Per pressure first.
So does it has its roots in Prussia?
Yeah.
Okay.
The German military during period
spanning the German empire.
Eighteen 71 to 1918.
And so it was World War One and then the
Third Reich 1933 to 45.
So it was in the first two bikes on.
It wasn't just the third,
but the most important thing is that the
origins are pressure.
Right.
And so he's very nationalistic,
I'm sure.
Yeah.
I still couldn't be you to be luck,
dude.
Oh,
today's Day and age,
you know,
we all know the swastika.
It has other meetings before the Germans
took over,
but you can't get a swastika tattoo.
Nah,
but it's a good one I'm talking about is
the cry of the Swedish army.
See it's in 16,
31.
It was done.
It was saying got men on Owens by
sabotage during the battle of Britain
field and 1631 God with us with the war
cry of the Swedish,
the Swedish army.
It was the last time Sweden was picking
wars with anybody.
So this is probably like some Russian
gang shit is what we were missing.
Like God is with us,
meaning God is with the Russian gang
members and we're just jumping into
conclusions because the Nazis liked it
too.
Yeah.
And we're also like in America,
like Nazis are such a symbol of evil
shit.
I don't know exactly in his culture in
Russia where they're from,
if that's like fucking,
you know,
Hitler is this,
the,
the antichrist that we can make them out
to beat the Nazis didn't get along very
well.
They also had their own guy.
They had stolen just starving people and
he was responsible for one more deaths
and he was responsible for their deaths.
Like dabs on people.
Yeah.
I mean,
Hitler killed a lot of Russians to
everybody killed Russians.
Russians get fucked up,
man.
That's why they're so hardy.
That's why they're so dangerous as like
fighters.
Those are the survivors man.
So when you got some cream of the crop
genetics over in Russia,
no bullshit in fucking in like a hundred
year period.
Russia,
not because,
you know,
like America was in two world wars,
but it wasn't here.
It was like we went and we send our boys
to go fight over there.
Russia had two world wars.
They're country straight up collapsed
twice.
They had the Bolshevik revolution and
then the collapse of the Soviet Union
and then they had like just genocidal
dictatorship inbetween that.
Yeah.
There was just a bad time to be rushing.
Well,
they've gone through a whole bunch of
those in the past.
When you go look at Russian history,
like what the fuck?
We went to the gang is con exhibit at
the Reagan Library out here.
And you get to see how much of Russia
they captured and how much of like I
didn't know that gang is Khan had the
biggest empire ever.
Like they literally owned all of Eurasia
and he was fucking like 40 percent of
the people and I mean that dude,
there's some insane number of people
that are genetically related to him in
Asia,
like insane number at that he would
like,
they would do this shit where they would
like send like a fuck.
It's been a while since I read about
this.
But like they would like send it,
like when they were going to conquer
like a village,
they'd like sending a note is basically
kind of like,
well look,
just give up all your shit right now and
you'll be okay.
And then some of the villages would be
like,
no,
we're not giving up all their shapes.
And then they just come in.
Yeah.
And then they do that just to like send
a fucking message.
Like even people who agreed to it,
they were brutal.
Brutal Shit.
Have you listened to Dan Carlin's wrath
of the cons?
I've talked about it.
If you're a regular listener to this
podcast,
I apologize for the next couple of
minutes,
the greatest fucking podcast series
ever.
It's all about Gaviscon.
I have no idea.
I knew he's a bad guy,
but it's like my knowledge of gang is
con was similar to my current knowledge
of Alexander the Great.
It's like hurt.
He was gay.
He killed a lot of people.
I don't really know.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's in modern Afghanistan that that
area,
I don't know Jack Shit about Alexander
the Great and that was the same thing
with gangs con and he was a bad guy.
Conquered a lot of people you know who
owned the world for awhile,
but Dan Carlin's five part series is so
God damn good that you just get.
You just.
You just really get a really accurate
sense of how insane life was back then
about what these fucking people did.
This one story about the corps,
me and Shaw who sent an envoy to Gin
China and along the way they saw in the
distance what they thought was a snow
covered mountain,
but as they got closer they realize that
it was a pile of bones.
They killed everyone in the city.
They killed a million people and stack
them up and these people were.
They had abandoned the road because the
road was so overrun with bodies that had
rotten decade that people are getting
sick and dying because there were so
many bodies had abandoned the road.
That's with anything anyone cares about.
Today,
and this goes for myself too,
like anyone who's into like issues or
politics.
It's like you should always just keep in
mind we have.
It's so fucking good.
Oh good.
We have it so good compared to what?
Everybody's happy,
but that's what progress is all about.
We want it so good.
We want it better.
We want better,
we want better.
We want to know no this no that,
no violence,
no sexism,
no racism,
no nothing.
You want a better and better and better
and better,
and we're going to.
Well now we got some ground.
People are getting more and more excited
about gaining more new ground yet,
but it's like we're never going to have
it be perfect.
So I almost was like,
why though?
Because that's that.
The concept of never being any sort of
racism,
sexism,
racism or sexism or you know,
somebody's always going to perceive
something as being that.
Right?
So it's gonna.
It's the onus is almost on the quote
unquote victims sometimes to take the
step back and go like,
okay,
I'm not a victim right now.
I'm a brown person.
Dude,
if I want to call it racism,
I can do it every single day of my life
if I really want to.
Okay.
And I feel like we're never going to
have that because it's very addictive to
be a victim.
It's very addictive to feel like you
were wronged in some way.
And it's also very addicted to look for
reasons for it that aren't really
necessarily your fault,
you know,
doesn't necessarily revenues of a very.
Like I'm helping the world that idea.
And people feel like they're doing
something good.
You'll never convince them that no
matter how ridiculous they might be,
you'll never convince them with my
thing.
My biggest beef,
and I agree with you,
I agree with you too though.
I think there's.
That's how progress happens.
Like you have to keep wanting to make it
better and better.
My biggest problem with say like the,
the like left wing activists of today is
that it's like they'll just go.
It's almost like they want to burn it
down because it's not perfect.
I just appreciate how the steps that
we've come and let's go the next step,
but don't burn it down because it can be
a lot worse with way we hold on to ideas
and beliefs.
It takes several generations for real
progress to occur.
The problem right now is there's so much
technological progress that's aiding the
physical progress.
The progress is taking place far faster
than they can handle.
It's almost like going down hill in the
snow and you're like,
oh Jesus.
Like you're in a car,
a drive,
a downhill,
and the smells like you kinda can hit
the brakes,
but are they really going to work?
You're ahead of yourself.
You don't have full control.
And I think as a human species,
that's the currently the state we're at
where,
where people were trying to force things
down people and we're trying to force
change and change normally takes a long
ass time to really settle in and it's
happening so quick,
we can't really keep up with it.
Yeah,
that's the old rules.
So it's like,
you know,
we didn't have the same way to
communicate.
You can get an idea across the world
instantly the same way.
Um,
so I think that people are reacting to
that and they don't know how to really
deal with it,
you know,
they don't have to know how to share an
idea with somebody that might not agree
the same way,
but we do because you turn up yourself
when you go to the supermarket,
whoever's,
you know,
I'm standing next to online,
we get along,
we're cool no matter what.
Our backgrounds are,
what we believe.
We're just coexisting.
Yeah,
well that's like the shit I was saying
before about chick flavors,
other businesses,
well just I'm sure there's some guy who
just believes shit that I find
horrifying,
but I'm just like,
Hey,
let me get a water.
Let me get a dog.
It's like you don't even think about
that shit,
and it's like,
yeah,
we all,
we do exist in this world.
We like come together and do all this
shit all the time,
but then you can kind of like pretend
online that you have this like we're
worlds apart and I would never do
business with this problem is
communicating online.
It's a shitty way of communicating.
People shouldn't have conversations in
front of each other where they look each
other and you can work through stuff,
podcast for real,
your harvest and write about it because
you have an opportunity to be wrong.
Find out why you're wrong,
think about it,
process it as opposed to editing your
opinion down and going.
Here it is.
This is a very specific,
perfect version where it's not even
really what your opinion is.
It's just how people are going to
perceive it.
It's a game you play in a word game.
Yes,
the word games,
playing board sports in trying to when
you know,
and this is a real problem with people
that aren't good at communicating one on
one because that's really the most
valuable form of communication used to
people in front of each other.
You're like,
well I'm going to write you an email
because I can't really talk to you about
this.
And then you get this crazy email
accusing you of all sorts of shit and
you know,
you're reading the tone.
Definitely.
You could call him up.
Hey Man,
what the fuck is this email?
Like this is nonsense.
Like this shit didn't happen.
Then you get together and have a
conversation about it.
Like let's talk person to person big
Jay.
We just got into the thing one time.
I don't know what it was and we just as
we've been like fucking brothers for
like,
you know,
a decade and a half almost,
right?
We're like real close friends.
We've got to a thing where I just wrote
him a long email so I'm going to write
it in form of an email and then he's
taking the tone like very wrong,
so then he writes me back and email kind
of shitty and now we're like in a
fucking fight and the reality was it was
just trying to communicate like road
dates or something.
It was so stupid.
You're like one conversation away from
getting the whole thing and just like
text messages,
emails,
so much is left to interpretation and
depending upon how you're receiving
that,
if you're in a good mood,
I guess he's just busy.
No big deal.
He's a good guy.
He'll get back to me.
Downplay.
So like this motherfucker,
it's always on,
on,
always on your terms to man call you and
you don't want to talk to me.
Don't talk to me.
I'll be okay.
I don't want to hear this bitch ass shit
like people where people get angry if
you're busy like oh my God,
it's always on your terms.
Don't know I'm busy.
And while you're saying it's on their
terms,
so much of that has to do with like your
fucking lie,
like if you're in a fight with your
chick and you don't have the job you
want to have and you know,
and then some guy doesn't return your.
It's like,
fuck him,
man,
he's doing this.
But if everything's going good,
you see what I was like,
oh,
he's probably on that back country hike.
But I really appreciate you getting into
cell phone service.
I need to work out the stuff with
Michelle and she's fucking freaked me
out.
I'm a,
it might be a bro.
I hope you were there when I do that.
You Bro.
And you weren't people on the phone
anymore either.
I called.
I'm a color.
I have fat thumbs.
I fuck it.
If I text you,
I'm angry.
I'm going to start.
I'm going to end a friendship with you
because it be so frustrated with my fat
thumbs,
texting,
shittily.
I can't believe.
Lewis just called me a fag.
What?
Texas weak.
It's weak.
It's just not a good.
It's good.
Like,
Hey,
here's the address.
See tomorrow it's good for that kind of
shit,
but that's all.
That's all.
It's good for it.
It's not good for express.
I mean it's good for fun to say shitty
things to each other.
If you know for a fact that you real
good friends and yes,
you're right.
It's like twitter or something like that
is good for like,
you know,
it's good for like,
Hey,
if you want to check out something cool,
go to www.cool
stuff.com,
but it's not good for like,
let me explain to you my take on
taxation or worse,
your take on a person.
The thing about your take on a person,
it's you,
you're allowed to have.
You're obviously you like to say some
politician or what have you.
You are absolutely related to have your
opinion on them,
but you're not really talking to them.
Like if you really do know them,
we just sit like there's always a
limitation if looking at someone from
afar.
Right?
And if you could sit down in front of
someone,
some politician that you agree with or
disagree with,
and then have a conversation with them,
then you would find out who the fuck
they really are.
Then you'd find out who the fuck you
really are in respect to this argument
and that makes sense.
But you can't do that.
There's not enough people.
There's no way.
There's no way that everybody who has an
idea about anybody else can be with
them.
But we have to respect that gap.
Like if you like sports guys are the
worst at it,
the worst when they talk about a certain
player being lazy or certain fighter
being a pussy.
Like what in?
What are you going on about?
You're talking about a professional cage
fighter and you're calling him a pussy.
But I've read that shit all day.
Read it all the time.
And it's that thing where you would
never say that if you were in front of
them,
you would never say that in front of
them.
I weirdly think that like as a fan,
you sorta,
you're buying the right to express that
opinion.
In a weird way though,
not that they're a pussy,
but like,
like when people get mad at people
booing at UFC events,
I'm going like,
I don't know,
they're kind of buying that experience,
you know,
and I can't hate on them if
they want to express themselves that
way.
Um,
you know,
it's sort of sort of a thing.
I mean,
look,
I,
I got very humbled doing the podcast
with Michael bisping because I was doing
radio on Sirius Xm for awhile and
talking about mma,
like I fucking knew anything and they're
starting to show bisque bake.
And then I was like,
oh,
I don't know,
Shit.
I'm not even going to pretend like I
know shit.
And um,
it's so much better at it now.
I'm not trying to fit into this fucking
like mold or,
or whatever.
But yeah,
I think that from a fan's perspective,
I don't really get mad at them when they
start talking shit or start to like,
it's kind of like,
it's part of the experience,
you know?
Yeah.
No,
I mean I get it,
but you shouldn't,
shouldn't be disrespectful to people for
no reason like that.
Like there's,
there's a lot of guys that get into it
just because it's like they feel like
they're behind a wall and they could lob
bombs.
It's a pussy move.
It's a weird.
It's not,
it's not healthy for me going,
it's like if you go to an event and
there's two guys getting in a cage,
fucking fighting to start booing them
just seems to me.
It's like,
dude,
I mean,
come on man,
they're fucking to entertain you guys
getting in there and,
and putting it all on the line.
Like yeah,
they have a right to know I would never
in a million years,
but at the same time I kind of
understand it.
It's almost like,
well they should be able to build your
comedy shows to then.
Yeah,
but I'll tell you,
I'll tell you what,
I'll tell you why not?
Because they're not.
I don't believe that at a comedy show,
if they're booing you during your set,
they're completely taking out the
experience for everybody else and I feel
like it'll a live sporting event.
It's just not the same thing.
They're not,
they're not getting into the fighters
had.
I mean,
maybe they are a little bit,
but you know,
I talked to Mike about this.
He says,
people booed me.
They fucking love my fault.
He's a different type of person that is
wearing champion.
He's got a different kind of mental
strength.
He can you.
He doesn't give a fuck.
I can plow through everything and that's
why I became a champion.
I mean,
he's like one of the most mentally
strong guys to ever fight in mma because
he's a god that when he started out,
he was good.
He was very good.
He won the ultimate fighter season two
and was a good fighter,
but willed himself in the position of
being a champion and was knocked out,
was stopped,
was beaten,
had his momentum stopped,
restart it right back up again with the
same or better enthusiasm every time and
deep into his thirties.
Did it all clean.
No steroids,
no allegations,
no bullshit.
Just worked hard and was tough as fuck
and won the fucking middleweight title.
It's a different type of mind,
dude.
I know,
I know.
He lost two in a row,
but the fact that he went out there and
had a fight that I thought he was going
to win until GSP called him with that
left,
I thought he was gonna,
win the fight and then loses the GSP for
the title and the biggest middleweight
fight probably ever and then just goes,
I want fight Kevin Gas,
lemon to week Kelvin.
Kelvin so cheese us,
man.
You.
Yeah.
He's such a fucking straight up ass dude
logic.
He's like,
it was like,
yeah,
I already did a training camp.
Why not get two paychecks?
It was a rough fight though.
I don't think it was a smart,
smarter than.
I agree with you on that.
Still up that George George,
St Pierre,
you know,
he took
four years off and everything like that,
but he's still one of the greatest,
if not the greatest of all time.
And you saw that in that fight?
Yeah,
I don't think he was.
I mean Michael cut them.
He caught him with those elbows,
particularly from the bottom.
But you know George St Pierre is,
he's a special guy.
He really is a special athlete.
People were really underestimating how
great George St Pierre was.
He's the guy who beat every person that
was ever put in front of them.
The losses that he had avenged.
So butte,
dominantly George Saint Pierre is a
monster and you know,
I think that everyone,
including myself,
you know,
really didn't think he was going to be
able to come back with that long of a
layoff and compete the way that you set
yourself.
Mike was just mentally push himself for
getting better and better.
Michael bisping today destroys Michael
Bisping a younger Michael bisping seven
years ago.
That's crazy.
He's an old man now.
Maybe it's entirely possible.
I mean,
the fighting is such a crazy proposition
that even with like elite guys,
like even when someone won a fight,
like if you make them fight again,
would they win 100 percent of the time?
But I don't think they would.
Not at all.
No.
So there's things in weird events that
can change your fortunate a fight.
I said,
Steve,
I think if in Ghana,
in Ghana could beat him a few times if
they fought 10 times,
he could not come out 10 times steep.
A definitely doesn't win all.
Ten is definitely a few that haven't
gone for sure.
If they have a rematch,
see the thing about like what would you
have to restart it with a time machine
where there's no memory whatsoever by
experiencing each other because you
know,
you get,
you understand patterns.
That's why it's weird when you see guys
fight training partners.
It's like there's guys that just know
each other so well that when they get in
there they've already got established a
pattern.
One guy's always bullied.
The other guy in training one guys beat
the other guy up and you could see it
when they actually fight.
Yeah.
Well actually,
and the other thing,
just as we're saying this,
I go,
yeah,
George St Pierre was the greatest ever I
had to make a case for.
If you have to make a case,
I don't think there's a stronger case
for anyone.
Then for George sounds crazy coming
back.
He,
yes,
he beat everyone.
Whoever he ever faced,
he had two losses that were Matt Hughes
and Matt Serra Right and came back and
destroyed them in the rematches Matt,
Matt Hughes twice,
and Matt Serra just came back and beat
him in the third rubber match.
Never happened.
Then after retiring,
comes back and wins the championship.
A division up,
not just that,
but Michael Bisping and chokes him
unconscious with a rear naked choke.
That was one of the tightest,
most cinched up rear naked choke I've
ever seen anybody perform ever.
I mean he,
he had it like a Jujitsu guy,
like a lot of MMA guys.
They have a harder time getting those
gloves fully locked into position.
Like there's a difference between
there's this,
there's an a rear naked choke with the
palm is touching the back of the head,
which a lot of people opt for because
you don't have to make as much space for
the arm.
You can get back there,
you can grab that head,
but the real way to do it as like this,
the real way to do it as a karate chop
where you go to the back of the neck
with the karate chop and once you have
that in place,
then there's this crazy leverage and it
just
squeezes the fuck out of someone's neck
on someone really gets one of those
locked in and that's what George did.
And the way he did it was like as tight
and sweet and four star black belt
level,
rear naked choke the you ever seen the
God damn it.
It's hard to listen to you describe.
It's a beautiful.
That's another thing didn't.
I never gave a shit at all the same way
like me and Michael [inaudible] at this
point to become friends to where it's
like you start to fucking care about
these guys.
If you imagine being a family member,
you imagine having somebody that you,
like,
your blood is in there.
Um,
you know,
being a fan of somebody is one thing,
but then you know somebody and that,
that was,
that was hard to watch.
Shops,
one of my best friends and I had to do
commentary on some of his fights because
it was a real hard time.
It real hard.
Last couple of fights in particular was
very hard for me.
Very hard to to like I have to be as
equally enthusiastic about him getting
hit as I am about him hitting somebody
and I know the guy very well.
Show us their shirt mass shooting for
sure.
I even said like everybody knew that I
was really good friends with them.
It was a,
you know,
we had done a bunch of podcasts
together,
but I was also the guy who talked him
into retiring because I was like,
look,
I know what's going on.
Like you know,
I've seen this with other people and I'm
not friends with them and it's not my
position to tell people to stop and I
don't know them that well.
You'd have to know someone real well to
know where their head's at,
you know,
but that's a sport where proof see like
if you're billing a basketball game,
maybe.
I guess I guess like there's something
that's so much more intense about a
fight,
especially like there's smart blues,
like when someone does something illegal
or someone does something or someone
does something that's fucked up,
there's smart boost,
but then there's booze where guys were
facing each other and they're canceling
each other out like you're watching a
really high level thing,
what these guys are trying to solve,
what do,
what do I have to do to connect on this
guy's fucking brainstem and knock his
lights out,
but the UFC is marketing toward these
casual fans who are basketball fans and
football fans who aren't really the
people who are hardcore who appreciate
the martial arts side of it.
What these guys are putting into it.
You think so?
I think they're just marketing.
I don't think they're marketing towards
any specific fan.
They're not marketing towards.
People don't understand that,
but I think that's the almost the same
thing because they're just trying to get
a mass audience and the majority of
people aren't.
People who really understand.
What makes you say that though?
What makes you say they're trying?
Like what are they doing specifically?
Um,
I feel like when they put together,
you know,
fights that don't necessarily make sense
in terms of rankings when they put the
interim belts on,
flights were don't really need to be
there.
You just know it's a marketing move.
Because I think a title on a poster,
we'll probably sell that many tickets.
Good point.
It definitely juices it up.
When you have an interim title,
something like a marketing dude.
It's going like,
oh yeah,
we saw this many more paper version
because the title and you know the
difference between the interim title or
a regular title.
A lot of the casuals don't know the
difference between Michael Bisbing or
fucking doors Api.
Look,
I'm with your set of bar.
I almost feel conflicted because I have
this part me that's like a purist that's
like,
no,
it should be just like whoever number
one is versus the champion and we should
never fuck around that same time.
If they were just like,
oh,
you know what,
we just set up Nick Diaz versus conor
Mcgregor.
I'd be like,
that's the greatest thing that's ever
happened and I don't care.
I don't care.
I don't care if Khabib's one slash 72
fights in a row.
Camp Bucca I'm flying a 100 out of 100
times.
I don't give a fuck where he's fighting
who he's fighting.
It's just fun and it's exciting,
but let's get real.
I think there was something really pure
and what's beautiful about mma is that
it's always going to kind of figure
itself out.
It is the greatest sport because it's
the greatest sport.
Anything can happen any given Sunday.
It's inherently built.
The marketing is sort of built in
already,
right?
So you can,
you can create a pecking order,
you can create rankings and I think you
can kind of just say,
hey,
the pieces are gonna fall where they're
going to fall and it's always going to
be super exciting and you see what the
way they handle connor or certain guys,
they definitely,
they threw that to the side and I think
conor is a great example of it as well.
Why?
They don't really care.
They're like,
all right,
fuck it,
dude.
Go Do may whether they had it for a
little while because they were part of
the promotion.
Yeah.
Hundreds of millions of dollars off that
thing.
Everybody made a fuck load of money.
I mean may,
whether made hundreds of millions.
Connor made $100,
million.
I don't know what the UFC made.
Everybody got fucking crazy paid and
then they started zoo for boxing and now
there are other offering a Joshua and
Joshua.
You're offering 100 million.
I'm crazy contract.
Apparently that might people.
Shit,
I don't know.
I haven't asked anybody if that's real,
but I'm not surprised.
They realize there's a lot of money and
promoting fights,
whether it's promoting mma.
Dana has a big background in boxing.
You know?
His son actually just had a,
an amateur boxing fight.
I saw that and it's instagram.
Fuck.
Dana loves boxing,
so I always loved it so it's not unusual
that they decided to go into it,
but with connor was like one of those
things where you're like,
yeah,
that's what you're supposed to do.
If may with a really wants to fight
conor and college never had a
professional fighting.
You make 100 million bucks.
Let's see,
let's see,
let's see who buys it,
but I'm just saying that the MMA purists
were what's best for the sport of MMA.
That's not necessarily the best move and
oh,
it's not bad move.
It doesn't hurt it at all because first
of all it shows you that in the
specialties that there are people that
have skills and techniques and abilities
that far exceed the very best mma
fighters and you saw that with conor and
floyd.
Floyd just fucked him up.
Just fucked him up.
But Connor caught them a little bit and
he tagged him in the beginning and you
can say that floyd wasn't going full
tilt and he probably wasn't.
I would say definitely wasn't.
He was definitely trying to wear him out
and get him tired because he knew that
he relied on kinetic energy for the
first round or two,
but you still got clipped with a shot.
He did want to get clipped with.
Sure.
I think floyd wanted to see what connor
was doing and he spent the first few
rounds,
like kind of taking in data and like
seeing like,
okay,
what are you doing here?
What Weird Shit are you trying?
But still I was like,
I did not think connor was going to do
that good teaching.
I thought it would be over within three
or four rounds and made whether it would
knock him out and he would just
outclassed him in the fact that it went
10 and then even landed some shots.
I was pretty impressed.
Fight itself.
That's like,
it's not bad for as a purist I'm saying
it's almost like it's the way they're
sort of letting connor run the show.
I just Kinda feel like the UFC sort of
always built this brand UFC,
it's,
you know,
it's a coca cola of MMA and I feel like
connor has basically become bigger or at
the very least as big as the UFC and he
doesn't do,
he doesn't give a shit tweet.
He tweeted out the other day,
I'm the boss when he was promoting the
video game,
like they did a diploma with Dana White
is one of the characters,
but I just feel like that wasn't
necessarily the best thing for mixed
martial arts as a sport.
I almost feel like what they were doing,
which doesn't hurt at all.
Yeah,
maybe,
maybe not.
I think it made it bigger.
I mean it's like,
dude,
what connor created was like a thing
that's like really hard to.
Even when he,
when he fought a marcus bridge as his
first fight in the UFC and I remember
already there was like an energy in the
crowd about connor fighting.
She to know who this guy was angry,
like why is this such a big thing?
And that every fight was just a bigger
and bigger and bigger thing.
And then we create this thing where like
Dustin [inaudible] biggest fight ever is
against conor mcgregor and Dustin had
way more big fights than him,
but still the big deal was that you're
fighting this guy.
Like he just,
he would create these stages.
Just that it was the results.
Like you put moccasins for him and he
starts dust employee in the first round
he slept Josie Aldo in 13 seconds.
Swayze was all real accomplishments.
Why him fighting?
Floyd Mayweather.
It was interesting because he was so
exceptional as a striker.
But do you think that uh,
uh,
this.
I,
I give the UFC so much credit with
building conor conor mcgregor because he
wouldn't have been able to do that
anywhere else.
Like the UFC is such a big brand that he
couldn't have been a war fighter and
become a,
you know,
a worldwide name the way he is now,
probably not in bits which is weird to
bell towards a stupid name.
They need to accept facts.
Thought about that until you just said
that.
I wouldn't let him make an sucks balls.
The regency box say it's time for
regency boxing on HBO.
What is this nonsense?
Why would you call a regency boxing mma?
Just call it mma.
MMA.
That's what it is.
Just like when you watch Hbo Boxing,
it's on Hbo and it's boxing.
Think good that the UFC is sort of built
this brand around it because I think
it's,
but for the sport in itself,
because in boxing even,
you know,
you don't really know the difference
between any of the title or the,
uh,
the organizations or the titles.
You don't really.
I don't know.
The WBC,
the W.
I don't know.
Even fans don't really know the
difference.
Well,
they know who the big guys are.
They know Anthony.
Joshua,
they know as Klitschko forever.
You know,
everybody knows about deontay wilder
now.
So there's a few guy,
but there's a couple of other champions
that are out there.
They,
they're like,
who?
Who's this guy?
The guy you've never heard of has like
six belts on his championship chapters,
intercontinental championships.
Everybody gets belts.
It's like ugly boxing titles that
fucking
big old.
The UFC nailed it with that belt belt
champion belt connor had two of them.
He goes with my other fucking belt.
I want to be the champ champ.
And he's got his arms look,
man,
it's,
there's no sport like it.
There's nothing like it.
Nothing is going to hurt it as long as
it's as long as people are interested,
like as long as people enjoy it.
As much as I enjoy it,
as much as I enjoy watching it so much
as I enjoyed calling it,
as long as that's going to be the case,
there's always going to be kids coming
up like this.
Sean o'malley kid,
that wild motherfucker kid,
we saw them on instagram.
It's just all him smoking weed.
He's a fucking savage.
She's out there just doing bong hits,
kick people in the face,
don't Afro.
I love it.
I love that guy.
He's an animal and that fucking kid is
like,
this is this new breed.
There's this new guy.
They love it so much and when they're
doing it,
they love it so much and they're so good
and they're going to be better the next
generation that just going to keep
getting better and better and better,
and that's what connor did as well as he
opened up that window because everyone's
going to get paid a lot more money now
that there's so much.
You see people talking about hundreds of
millions of dollars at stake.
It's like everyone's gone,
Huh?
Okay.
That's sugar.
Sean o'malley could be a fucking
multimin multimillionaire and a couple
of years I'm not bullshitting.
That kid could be huge and that's just
the CBD oil company.
He's a wild man.
He's a fucking wild man too.
The way fights.
Was He gaming?
He's got one of them.
Gaming chairs.
He's fucking hilarious,
but he's good man.
And He.
The thing about him is he's like super
creative.
What does that thing down that low go to
the lefthand side and scroll down to
that video of him working out.
What is he doing there?
What is he doing here?
He does a lot of weird,
crazy shit like that.
Yeah,
like he's practicing and he does that
threesixty take down to the back control
like guess.
I mean he might not ever do that in real
life,
but he might hit that all the time.
So he does that high kick but leave the
spin.
So that spans for the guard pass.
That's very confused because a lot of
times guys dive straight in and guys who
are good,
especially the half guard wind up
wrapping them up real quick,
but he does a spin around it.
I wonder if he gave me the way he hits
that.
If he does that over and over and over
again,
I bet he can do that in a fight.
Well,
that's a cool thing about now it's like,
can we watch it with like Anthony Pettis
was at first like holy fuck moment with
the,
you know,
the less wgc event ever.
Um,
the,
the jumping kick or whatever,
but you get guys that are so athletic
now that and now there's so much money
in the sport guys that might've went
into like football or basketball.
Now we're looking at MMA as an option.
Whereas you kind of weren't getting that
years ago.
So there's super athletes.
Think about that dude.
How dangerous are these guys going to
get?
I was wondering about that like are they
ever going to get too dangerous where
they're gonna have to alter the rules
because there's two athletic they can do
it cause too much damage.
They're not going to be much different
than the best of the best now like a
Francis and gone to or a steep meo chick
or you know,
the Tyron Woodley.
We'll look at a guy like tyron woodley
that is about as explosive as a man who
can step on a scale of 170 pounds for a
brief amount of time can get.
Yeah.
And as good as they get,
the competition kind of gets better too.
So yeah,
Tyron Woodley people from UFC two,
you'd be like,
this should be illegal.
Versus Tyrone Woodley could fight 60
people in a row.
Seen 10.
Taiwan is only one 70.
I mean he wouldn't be,
but if they had real world 70 fighters
voice was one 70.
Yeah,
he's bigger than toys.
He's really about two five ish,
but those have been having problems
won't be the UFC Frye.
Once you got into don fraud,
Don Frye was a big fella.
He's very much just landed knockout shot
before don frye could also take a
tremendous punch fight with Don Frye and
talking Yama where they just did in
front of each other and wailed on each
other.
Bam,
Bam.
Football.
Just landed right hand after right hand
like a fucking movie.
It was one of the craziest things
anybody ever saw.
I won't go down as a man.
He's hilarious.
He's got on the podcast.
No,
I have not.
I would love to though.
He was a boss and he's a great
personality.
It.
We had them calling a few times the
animal.
He doesn't give a fuck.
He's hilarious.
And he paid the price physically for
that career,
you know,
he said some serious health consequences
like real neck injuries and his body
just got beat the fuck up.
Like he had real neck and back problems
from all those punches and take downs
and net cranks and all that shit.
You know,
he was there the early,
early,
early days to now this is the one like
he gets hit with a knee and they get an
email and each other.
It's crazy dude,
but this is why we got into mma.
Jesus.
Fucking crazy.
I mean,
look at these guys.
it doesn't seem real.
It literally doesn't seem real that they
could just stand and wail on each other
and talking how his face is just a
swollen mass.
After this don fries caught on the
forehead.
It was fucking crazy.
But Don fry,
he was one of the first guys to figure
out a way to shut down.
We're talking about the other day with
Pat Miletich,
shut down Brazilian Jujitsu.
Guys like this look,
look at his fucking mount.
Like he was a real good wrestler and he
had a very good top game and he also was
a good boxer too,
and just a fucking stud just to start
and just tell the guy in the world
either,
you know,
he first,
when he first fought in the UFC,
I believe he was only 200 pounds and he
fought a guy who was like three
something and fucked him up in like six
seconds.
He fought some big overweight guy and he
cracked him with a jab and dropped him
with a jab.
Is just beat them down real quick.
I think you'd beat everyone until he ran
into Mark Coleman in the UFC and then
that was just like just to client
wrestler who too big,
too strong.
Literally how many in Dave Smith became
friends.
We were roommates and we sort of renting
UFC like that's how we got into UFC.
Yeah,
best stuff.
Knock out videos together,
smoking blunts,
Bruce back days,
you know.
It was weird is that we got into it and
like right around the time that we were
getting into UFC,
the ultimate fighter dropped so it was
almost like we got into it at the same
time that the country got into it when
we got into it a few months earlier and
then all of a sudden this thing no one
gave a shit about was just like blowing
up.
I remember we got to do during season
one so much that season to the fire was
coming out.
We were like,
do it this season to ultimate fighter.
This is fucking nuts.
Fights on TV.
Let's do it.
And there wasn't a fight in the first
episode of season two.
We were furious,
we almost broke our tv,
we watch old episodes.
That's funny,
but it was also like a perfect storm of
like people getting interested in it and
then having that ultimate fighter
reality show back in the days where
people,
you know,
I still watch reality shows back then,
now you can't even fucking holding a gun
to my head and get me to watch a reality
show unless they're trying to survive in
Alaska.
I got like five of those saved.
I love those shows like life below zero.
That's my jam dude.
I love that show.
But out there finding salmon shit to eat
and just chopping down trees,
try to stay alive that,
that I could maybe get into,
but I will say I think there's something
interesting about the post reality show
world.
Like we got over reality shows,
but I feel like we're never the same.
Like you never quite go back to like
even just like in like what you do with
this show versus a radio show.
Like you're not starting to like Hello
Ladies and gentlemen,
a little shake,
Hobo.
We don't want any of that.
Now.
We just want like an honest
conversation.
I feel like in,
in,
in entertainment in general,
you want something that it just seems
it's not as showy.
It's more just like what real life would
be.
Yeah,
that's a,
that's what people want for sure.
You know what I mean?
And the thing about it is it's like it's
led to a guy who was a reality star was
the president.
That's as weird as it gets.
I mean that,
that is a reality star president.
He's not a politician,
just a businessman got on a TV show,
was a big time celebrity and now he won
a popularity contest.
So he's the runner of the country,
you know,
like that isn't an advertisement for
just fucking motivation.
I don't know what you want to say.
Like he just said,
I want that,
or just an advertisement for how much
fucking system sucks.
My favorite thing about Donald Trump is
like,
I've never.
I used to have to really argue with
lefties about butthead.
Democracy is a flawed system,
but now you just look at it.
You're like,
no.
So how about that?
Yeah.
He was able to convince more fucking
than your person was Christina.
Now he's your leader.
Awesome.
If you have four people and they're all
equally intelligent.
Yeah,
that's right.
I'll get together and figure something
out rationally,
but when you get to a place where you
can't even communicate with those people
anymore because it's $300 million of you
and you're scattered across a continent,
but you're all supposed to be on the
same team,
voting over like really important issues
that you probably don't even know
anything about,
like what you're talking about earlier
about assault weapons or fracking.
You'd be bringing up anything to certain
people offshore drilling.
What?
What are we doing?
The other thing is that we're supposed
to be for or against fracking.
I have no idea.
You definitely shouldn't be for it.
I don't think it's.
I think it's proven that it's safe long
term because there's getting.
They're getting into water supplies that
causing earthquakes.
There's a lot of real,
real consequence.
There's definitely a lot of problems
with it.
There's also definitely a lot of wealth
that was created on the energy,
that energy.
Those are positive things and negative.
The problem is everybody wants to
discount the negative or the positive
note with you.
Yes.
No one agrees that it's actually a cost
benefit ratio,
but the thing that's like what you were
saying before with like with four
people,
democracy works,
but I think a lot of it is like,
okay,
so if we get into a fucking thing,
like let's say we're in a car crash and
one of the people in the car or a car
breaks down rather,
and one of the people in the cars,
the mechanic,
we don't sit here and go like,
well,
let's vote.
Who gets to do this?
You just go,
well,
you're a mechanic.
The three of us are out in the fucking
woods hunting elk.
Me and Louis don't go like,
well,
I think we should do it this way because
you've done this larger.
You don't have all day.
You're going to ruin the whole
experience.
Most of the time,
just pure voting isn't how you get to
something.
You defer to experts and when you just
have this voting thing where it's like,
well,
we'll all just cast a vote.
The dumb people the same as the smart
people,
the educated,
the same as the uneducated.
You end up with a fucking this
competition to just say bullshit.
That gets anyone up.
Well,
I'm going to make America great again.
Donald Trump and powers the worst
elements of our society and you're like,
this is all fucking retarded.
I gotTa pee again.
I can't believe this too.
Should we end it or should we keep
going?
We're at three hours.
All right.
We should end it.
If two of the three of us need a pill,
I am so excited that we did this.
We got to do this more often.
When you guys going to be in la again,
next time you invite us on this.
Again,
this is surprisingly,
it worked really well with for people to
step on each other.
It was a lot of fun.
Man,
of course is available everywhere.
Are you guys on Youtube as well or just
on?
Oh yeah,
everywhere.
We have our own platform called gas
digital network.com.
That's our network.
Fast is a July 14th and 15th.
Presale tickets,
April second.
Twitter from tickets on sale when a
April second is presale.
It's gonna be nuts.
Where do they buy the tickets?
NYC Dot com.
All right.
All right everybody.
Thank you.
Bye.