Trey my day,
Joe Rogan plot gas by night all day.
No,
your life is very different right now.
That it was a year ago.
It is.
How crazy is that?
Yeah.
I like you.
A year ago you were talking about like
not doing this anymore.
I've got to figure out what I'm doing
and now you're the fucking world champ
about a frickin one 80.
Yeah.
Mike.
Mike career in life with it couldn't
have been different a year ago than it
is now.
How strange is that?
How that can just like that in an
instant.
You just never know.
What does that feel like?
It's like when you wake up in the
morning,
you have to go,
okay,
I wake up this morning,
that's real.
P diddy
real.
I'm,
I'm happy.
It's,
um,
it's enlightening.
It's fun.
It's,
it's great to be the champ.
I love it.
Honestly.
It's a completely different thing.
And Yeah.
You know,
a year ago I was so frustrated because,
you know,
when I lost her onto the last time,
I knew I had a lot,
a long road,
you know,
and to,
to work my way back up.
But I thought I had done that and when I
beat Jessica,
I,
it was announced like,
you know,
this is going to be then the number one
contender eliminator fight.
And then afterwards they're like,
yes it is.
You're going to fight Ronda.
Then I felt like the carpet was kind of
just pulled out from under my feet
because they're like,
just kidding.
Holly's,
you know,
holly's fighting.
And they announced it without telling
me.
So that's why I was so upset because I
was like,
I don't take that shit lightly,
you know?
Yeah.
Like I was training my ass off already.
I had already reached out to um,
a girl in France.
I can't say her name right.
I think it's like [inaudible],
I don't know some French name,
but she beat Ronda and judo.
So I had already like been making plans
with her to train with her and fire over
here and she was changing things.
Then I was like,
I feel like such an ass,
like I feel like an idiot.
Right.
They look like an idiot because here the
announcement was made and I didn't even
know.
So I was kind of upset about that.
But you know,
we talked about it and we smooth things
over and,
and I took it personally at the time,
but I don't think it was meant
personally and it was a business
decision and I understand that that at
the end of the day that's what it was
and it all worked out.
So
the UFC is in a weird position because
they're both a promoter and sort of a
sanctioning body.
Yup.
And that's really rare and matter of
fact,
I can't think of any other sport where
that exists.
Yeah.
You know,
they have just this ability to decide
like they'll dealt us decide like this
person gets a show.
Like the whole conor mcgregor situation
is a perfect example of that.
Like all of a sudden if he had beaten
nate diaz or if he had beaten dos Anjos
like dos Anjos didn't get injured and he
beat beat Dos Anjos you fucking know for
sure they were going to have him fight
Robbie lawler.
Yeah.
Like for sure.
And they were just going to like figure
out a way to do something with 145 Palm
Tata.
And why wouldn't they do it if they were
business people because that's where the
money is.
I mean it would've been if he had beat
those on Joe's and then when on and
fought Robbie law or Jesus Christ when
we talk to like a 5 million paper view
by event it,
they'd have to do it.
It would be insane.
But if that was like a sanctioning body,
like you've seen it before in like
boxing,
like someone won't take a mandatory
challenger and they get stripped even
when they just won the title,
it happens all the time.
Like we're a phytol would just win the
title and then they have this mandatory
challenger who nobody knows and they'll
go,
fuck that fight.
I'm going to go fight Canelo Alvarez,
I'm going to fight this guy or that guy.
And then he gets stripped.
Like,
cause there's like five different
sanctioning bodies.
Like boxing is way more of a mess.
So there's like pros and cons to doing
it the way the UFC does it.
But from a point of view of someone like
you,
it's probably much more frustrated.
Well,
you just never know what to expect.
Like you,
you get curve balls all the time in the
UFC.
Don't know what to expect.
You know,
like a lot of people were so pissed off
at me for,
for the Holly Holm,
not having the rematch right away,
but it's like,
it's not,
it's not my choice.
You know,
they have this of you,
I don't know,
cause they think that I like turned it
down or I should have went in there like
guns a blazing for holly and like put
myself out of my shield.
Like,
no,
we have to have the holly rematch.
You guys,
you don't understand.
But um,
yeah,
they call me up.
I'm like,
Amanda,
July 9th.
I'm like,
okay.
Yeah.
How did he notice UFC 200 how the fuck
do you say no,
no you don't.
You can't say no if that's what they
come up with you like I'm in and now you
know,
it's like,
dude,
relax.
Most people don't get immediate
rematches in their career.
Like,
unless you are conor mcgregor or Rhonda
or,
or you know,
someone that's really got a presence,
you don't get an immediate rematch.
Like I did when I went back and strike
force when,
when I lost to Ronda,
I didn't get into media.
I've never gotten immediate rematch.
My career,
I would love to immediately rematch cat
when I lost to her.
But you don't get it.
Sometimes you got to work your way back
up and you know,
hope for the best,
but we will.
I'm sure it will fight each other again.
She's fighting a volunteer mission.
Shanko now just say I have to laugh when
people say like that we're scared to
fight someone.
You know,
like people were like,
oh,
you're scared to fight holly again.
Like you can't listen to those people
are scared is not a relative.
Like it's not a term that I feel like
fighters really,
we don't,
we don't have scared the way normal
people have scared,
you know?
Yeah.
Like a normal person would be scared to,
to,
to get off their couch and go to the
gym,
you know,
to,
to spar or something.
Like,
that's what we do.
Like we live like what most people would
shit their pants to do on a day
fool to not know that it's a dangerous
fight.
So it's not a matter of not being aware
of the danger.
Yeah,
but it's a matter of managing the
consequences are like,
I think he did a fantastic job with the
holly fight,
like literally you did in that fight
other than the fifth round,
which is the most amazing part of it.
But you did everything.
Like when we were talking about like
what you have to do to beat her.
I'm like,
she's gotta stay on the outside.
You get a very her rhythm and she's got
to let holly come to her.
Like she can't rush in because if you
rush into holly,
it's like Russian into Machida are
rushing to anyone who's a great counter
striker and you saw the Rhonda fight.
Ronda just came bulldog and honor and
tried to out bulldogger and you just,
you can't do that with holly.
She's too fast.
Footwork to her,
her striking is so precise.
Her,
her counters are so clean and our
movements
very hard to read,
like it's very unpredictable.
I remember what a couple times I tried
to maybe come forward and get her to get
to the fence and I couldn't tell whether
she was going to jet out to the right to
the left.
Like she,
she's like two steps back left.
And I was like,
ah,
you know,
like I couldn't even tell like she had
gave no indication of which way she was
going to go.
Yeah.
Well you just did a fantastic job of
varying,
your approach to your speed was
different.
Like you,
you,
you did a lot of fainting,
you varied things up a lot and you could
tell like,
she was like almost like waiting for
these moments to happen when you're
going to come forward and then you
wouldn't come forward.
And then it becomes like a test of
patience.
Like who's going to get outside of their
comfort zone?
Who's going to take chances?
Who's going to,
who's going to engage.
And she also has that weird stance too
when she kind of halfway stands like a
boxer and halfway stands like a karate
person.
She throws like a lot of sidekicks and
on the front leg techniques.
Yeah,
she's,
she's a tricky one but we put together a
really good game plan and I was happy
with that.
He did,
but it was the fifth round,
fifth round was crazy.
God,
when you grabbed a hold of her and then
eventually got her back and got her to
the ground,
it was so crazy because every aspect of
from your initial entrance to the take
down to getting her back,
there was nothing 100% about it.
It was all touch and go.
It was all scramble.
It wasn't like you had complete total
control over like maybe like Damien Maia
versus Rick Story.
Like he,
Damien Maia gets rick stories back.
He's got them locked up and then he
anacondas and squeeze some and then it
gets them.
It wasn't like that.
It was like you were fighting for your
fucking life and you knew there was no
time.
There was no time.
You were likely down by like at least
one round and you were headed into the
fifth and final round and maybe if you
won that round you could've got the
decision.
But fuck,
you're fighting the champ.
Who knows,
who knows what's going to happen.
You take our back and then when she
tries to shake you off the top and you
hang in there and you hang in there and
you see if you like,
and I would watch them like,
oh my God,
she's going to go out.
And when she went out and you climbed
off her and she was unconscious like
Holy Shit,
what a moment.
And I wasn't gonna ratable.
It was incredible.
It was one of the best moments in all of
women's championship fighting as far as
like,
like an extreme,
extremely dramatic moment where your,
you're trying to accomplish something.
She's fighting tooth and claw.
Neither one of you are exhausted.
So it's not like anyone's like
physically compromised.
It's just a fucking mad scramble between
two killers and you get her and you got
her back and then you get it back and
you'd sink the choking.
And she's trying to fucking shake you
off and you hung in the APP and when she
rolled and you're on top of her and you
hung onto it and you realize like,
oh my God,
she's going out.
And she just,
she didn't even tap,
she was throwing punches in the air
while you were choking her unconscious.
I think to myself,
I'm like,
when is she going to tap?
It didn't in my,
in that instinctual moment,
I'm so used to in training you get
people in a choke,
you know they tapped.
So I'm waiting for that tap and I'm
like,
good God.
Like when is this girl going to tap?
Like I know I've got,
or what does she hit tab and then,
then I felt her like I saw her,
you know,
from my peripherals kind of do,
do something.
I wasn't quite sure if she was tapping
or what she was until I watched the
video later and then I felt him pull me
off and I'm like,
that's the feeling that we fight for is
that feeling that that feeling of like I
did it,
I established my dominance.
You know,
it's a,
you know,
it's a prideful sport in some ways,
hand to hand combat with someone else.
It's like,
you know,
I,
I did it tonight.
It was better.
It has to be prideful because otherwise
there's just certain sacrifices into
certain fires that you're just not going
to walk through.
Like you have to have every fucking
motivation.
You have to be Zahn,
but you also have to have an ego.
There's to be so many things going on.
If you do achieve that highest level of
greatness,
it's like walking on a tight rope,
you know?
Oh yeah,
we'll let her just like that perfect
balance.
You know,
I'm walking between buildings that are,
you know,
hundreds of stories high or,
and then it's like,
it's,
it's Kinda like that.
I mean,
you have to have the perfect balance and
everything has to meet perfectly.
And that moment,
including the training camp,
not overtraining.
Did you ever hear of that video that um,
the video is not that good,
but the audio is,
is awesome.
It's between the fourth and fifth round
and it's my corners.
What they're telling me between the
fourth and fifth round.
It's such an emotional video for me.
When I watched it,
it makes me relive that moment.
And Brian came in there and essentially
he was like,
Misha,
you've got to get,
after you got to,
you have got to put your chin down and
Mike Tyson,
this chick.
And that basically means just get after
her like get,
get in there,
get after it,
take the risk,
risk getting knocked out,
go for broke.
And um,
it goes,
you know,
plays into the round and,
and basically it was just telling me
like fucking Mike Tyson,
her like get after her,
you know,
bulldog or do whatever you've got to do.
He's like,
cause you're running out of time.
And I remember in that fifth round still
trying to get out of that,
that mindset of like,
I have to find the perfect opportunity.
I have to be patient because the whole
training camp was,
you know,
patient but persistent,
patient but persistent.
No one run into anything cause you,
you know you get caught,
you get knocked out,
you'll get need,
you'll get kicked,
you'll get punched.
So don't do that.
But you got to look for the,
the opening when it's the right timing.
It's all about timing.
And after I took her down in that second
round and I just beat her up that round,
she was so,
I'm so cautious and the third and fourth
and so perfect.
You know,
her game plan was perfect.
Do to beat me to stay just far enough
out of the range and keep me from not
wanting to come in.
I couldn't find a perfect opening,
couldn't like get in on anything.
There wasn't mistakes that she was
making and in the fifth round I just
decided,
you know,
you're going to have to,
you're going to have to take the chance
of getting knocked out.
This is,
this is what it's boiling down to now.
You've got like three minutes left on
the clock and now it's do or die.
It's either you go in there you,
you go for it,
you do Russian,
she catches you,
you get knocked out,
you know,
you gave it everything you got or you
got to make something happen.
You finish the fight.
The question was really like whether the
second round was a 10,
eight round,
uh,
on all three judges score cards.
It was,
yeah,
I mean watching it,
that's what the judges said.
Well it should have been but,
but what I'm,
what I meant was the question watching.
It was like I want like when we were,
when you were headed into the fifth
round with my question was was I wonder
if she got a ten eight round for that
second round because if she did then
this is like a,
this is an even fight.
So what's happening right now?
Like what,
where,
how the judge is looking at it going
into the fifth round.
It was even,
yeah.
Yeah.
That's crazy.
That was such a crazy moment.
Does another time.
The,
in doing the post fight interview were
almost crying like a bitch.
I get so emotional.
It was,
it was incredible.
He meets are hard to explain to someone
when you're there and you,
you um,
you get to see someone like you who's
worked so hard for something for so
long,
you know.
So when I said to you like,
how does that sound?
Like what does it sound like?
You're the new women's bantamweight
champion of the world.
Like what does that sound?
And you were just so overwhelmed.
It was so crazy.
Like just to be right next to you while
you were saying that and you said when
you said,
I'm waiting for you to say that for so
long.
It just crazy.
It was crazy moment.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
Cause I know what was,
what's crazy a tie about the mind and
the power of it.
I've,
I had visualized that moment so many
times that it felt like I was confused
in that it was hard for me to
distinguish that that was the real
moment I would go.
I would imagine it was so intense.
It was so surreal.
I would imagine my to this day it
probably seems fake.
Hat's really what it,
yeah.
Sometimes I have to go back and be like,
man,
that really did.
It really happened.
It really happened right there.
Oh,
it was topped Jay.
Thank yeah,
that excited.
If you had like if Auras were real,
you know like fucking,
if you had ci it was coming off your
body for sure.
We did a photo
falling over and been shaking papers,
cups,
foreign to the air and carpet would rip
gracious
moments in my life for sure.
I could only imagine you could only am,
I mean and anyone that watches that
sport,
that moment when you choked her out and
in the whole exchange of the fee.
Well even like that really the whole
fight because a fight is like,
I mean in a weird way,
I mean we call this martial arts and
there's a lot of people that have a
problem with that.
But in my mind that there is an art to
what you guys did in that fight.
And even what holly did,
because up until that fifth round,
I mean,
like you said,
especially the third and fourth,
she was doing what she wanted to do.
She was,
she was,
and there was a display going on,
there was like a,
there was a performance going on,
on top of this being a competition to
watch it as someone sitting there
watching it and calling it,
I mean this is a work of art and to have
it in that way,
it was,
it's such a masterful performance.
It was such a masterpiece moment.
And that to me is like one of the best
moments in mma because it's such a
fucking hard thing to achieve to become
a champion.
And for someone like you had tried and
tried again,
he won the title in strike force and
you're trying and trying again and
trying to make this happen and you know,
you think you're getting boxed out and
the Rhonda fight didn't happen after you
beat Jessica I and then all of a sudden
you have this opportunity and they comes
to together in one of the most powerful
ways we've ever seen inside the octagon.
It was amazing.
Well thank you.
That was a,
that was quite a great narration of
everything that's had to happen to make
this come true.
You know?
And it,
it's,
uh,
it's crazy because,
um,
it was 10 the same month,
10 years,
the like the month,
um,
that I had had my first fight.
Wow.
It's been 10 years.
Yeah.
So it's crazy because you think 10 years
ago there wasn't even,
I mean,
women's MMA was a joke.
Like it was,
I mean,
no one to me it wasn't obviously,
but to,
to most people it was a spectacle at
best.
Yeah.
Something they kind of threw on the card
is kind of like,
ah,
ha ha.
You know,
watch the chicks fight.
hopefully it'll pop out.
You know,
it's so true because they didn't respect
us as athletes.
You know?
That's,
that's what we,
that's,
that's the,
that's the honest truth.
That's the uphill battle that it was
like nobody took it seriously.
We didn't make any money.
We were fighting for breadcrumbs at
best.
I saw holly,
um,
once since densify and I was really
actually kind of nervous about it
because I was like,
she was,
um,
at the Jones osp fight,
those happen.
And,
um,
we were both of the VIP party and my
friend Heather Clark used to train
heather.
Joe Clark checks you fighting this
weekend and Rotterdam.
Anyways,
she was like,
you should go and talk to her.
I was like,
yeah,
I want to,
I just,
I don't want to come off like,
how,
what do I say?
What's up bitch?
Yeah.
Like what,
what do you say to someone that you
just,
you knew took the dog,
say hi.
That's what I did.
You know,
I just went up and was like,
you know,
how are you?
And she like,
she gave me,
I was,
she's like,
you know,
I'm just really bombed it in and get
that rematch.
And like,
I know,
I was like,
don't worry.
well,
we'll see each other in the future.
She's like,
yeah.
I hope so.
I just like,
I hope you still have it.
It's like,
you know,
I wanna,
uh,
you see you again in future.
I'm like,
yeah,
I totally get it.
I'm been in her shoes before.
I know how bad that sucks.
And she wants that back.
But you know,
we were friendly,
but it's amazing how both of you are so
nice.
Like holly's one of the nicest people.
Nice.
She's such a sweetheart.
[inaudible] Nice.
If you didn't know she was a fighter,
he be like no fucking way.
And then you find out she's a 19 time
world boxing champion.
Be like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
How's that possible?
How's that Nice Lady?
A a killer.
Yeah.
Some tomfoolery doesn't make any sense.
Like,
and she doesn't fit the mold either.
Like both of you guys are really
interesting representatives of MMA and
great representatives because you break
that mold.
You know a fan of her manager though.
Oh yeah.
Who is your why?
I don't know.
I don't even know if I've ever met him
in person.
I probably haven't.
Maybe I have.
If I did,
it wasn't memorable.
But anyways,
um,
I guess he went like Dana went down.
So Tina Dana told me this,
Dana went down to albuquerque before
this fight ever came together of her and
I,
right.
And he said,
look,
you guys need to wait for Rhonda.
Trust me.
That's the big money fight.
That's a fight.
You want to wait for it.
He went down there.
He told me,
this is my face.
He went down to tell them,
don't fight me,
tate,
like they didn't want to give me the UC
did not want that fight to happen.
Right.
They wanted,
you know,
the,
the rematch to be the first fight.
And Holly's manager told him,
we want me Shantae and Dana said he
threw up his hands and was like,
are you fucking kidding me?
He's like,
she's been the baddest,
you know,
other than Ronda for years now.
And you want to take her lightly.
You think you're just gonna walk there?
He's like,
yeah,
we got this.
Like,
she's going to be a tune up fight.
Who's your manager?
I don't even know his name.
I don't know these 80 but he told Dana
that,
that they,
that they thought that I was going to be
a tune up fight.
[inaudible].