I gotta make sure my shit is off.
I don't want to be that guy.
The Joe Rogan experience podcast is
brought to you by the fleshlight,
but you already know this.
I've said this a thousand times.
I've been using my fleshlight actually
for real for the last couple of week or
so. Allila yeah, I guess some night
by yourself or yeah, by myself.
But I got that massage, that IC massage
stuff for your back. That makes it hot.
Yeah, that makes her, it feels like,
no, it makes it cool. Like, like tingly.
Anybody using that? What?
Yeah, that's the stuff.
Like that's like tiger balm or
something? Is that what you mean? Yeah,
it's the one that you just buy
it. Like the grocery store.
Is it lube? No, no, it's,
it's like massage oil for
the cold one on my dick.
And it doesn't seem like you
should do that. I've had,
I've used the hot one before while having
sex and it destroyed the girl's vagina
and it was the worst night ever. But the
cool one, you can get away. What happened?
Uh, I, I always thought for some reason
like massage oil and oil and all that,
you could just put it in the vagina.
You know,
like I just never really occurred to me
that the vagina, like it's a cabinet.
The shine is just some shit you use
area you could put things. Yeah.
So like human tissue that absorbs
like toxins and chemicals. I know,
I know that now because she's
screaming her name, route or holding.
It went from like hot, sexy time to
fucking bitch ass time. But ouch.
But the cold one you can
kind of get away with.
Like I've used the cold one on
a girl before and I, you know,
I just didn't tell her why,
why would you do this?
Cause I didn't know this
was back when I didn't know.
And I thought it was just lotion and I
used it and she never said anything bad.
It was the hot one that got me
in trouble when you used it.
Like what was the purpose of
what we Berlin for Lube for?
She wasn't enjoying in the
ass and they're like, Oh hey,
I think that's even worse. Dude. Yeah.
I think probably your pussy is a little
more durable than inside your asshole.
And we also used to always go ask the
pussy pussy to ass and never thought about
it cause I never thought
anything about poop.
Now that I've dated some porn stars,
they know everything possible.
That what they Ohio girls,
they don't know that just fucking
get infected and die. What happened?
So you could die from that dude.
You sticking point.
We know that now that's fucking wrong.
And they should train those Ohio,
Midwest people about this stuff.
Somebody should at least bring it up.
It should be something you talk about
it because I think about that the vagina
is right next to the asshole and you're
barely telling them about putting it in
the vagina. Like had this putting
in the asshole ever even come up.
But yet in real life it comes
up all the time. Exactly.
It's fucking that school for you.
That's birds in it.
That's Horse Shit and well I'm glad
you never killed anybody with your poop
vagina antics.
I feel bad that you should feel it.
That's why I don't feel bad using the
code lube on my fleshlight. So, uh,
this cold lube, would you recommend this?
I mean, is this, this is a safe and yeah,
it's going to fall off. I keep using is
probably not safe, but it feels really,
really good. When you're your Dick's, like
on ice bar, it's throbbing, strange land.
Here's changed led and it numbs the
fleshlight even more. Don't do it.
They'll listen. Don't do not.
This is nothing we endorse.
I Dunno what adverse effects
that's going to have on your Dick.
You Silly Bitch for ladies and gentlemen,
the regular folks out there only use
like actual real sexual lubricant.
Schlub flesh lube is something
that the fleshlight cells,
fantastic stuff you don't need
to do. And you know, honestly,
now that I'm thinking about it,
I think you're only supposed to use water
based lubes and her flashlight because
they bill it like destroy
them. So I probably am fucking
up my bitch pretty bad.
Oh, what are you doing then?
Man, I'm destroying my flesh
that I got an extra one.
If you do but don't do it.
It's, it's a worthwhile thing.
You can keep one for years.
I know, but this is the chin,
a haze special additional and that
is drawing in a haze is butthole.
Does it ever a little signature on it?
She would ever have her
signature on her bottle.
That doesn't even fucking make sense.
I like to think you like,
imagine if you're a piece
was like a signature like
so you know exactly who gave
it to you. She didn't came me. Did
you get fucking Joey Diaz? Herpes.
It's right here on your ass. Let
us the arteries. You fear her.
They should make death squad flashlights.
They would. I'm sure I forget guys.
Oh you mean like we should pose.
We did motor buttholes. Yeah,
but that's what I'm saying. You
have to pose for that. They have to,
they have to model your asshole.
Wow. That's to be down with that.
If we got a percentage of the flashlight,
those those girls make good money.
They do.
They make great money.
You're more than willing to let a
rubber version of your asshole would be
distributed all over the world. Why Not
Yours? Because you're silly. That's why.
Because what are some dude just gets
really into the idea of fucking you in the
ass because he's been practicing on your
flashlight and he dresses up like you
and he goes,
get your fucking tee shirt on right
now and if he had your little butthole
flashlight that would come so close to
completing the, that's all he needs. No.
All he needs is rufinol and to duck tape
and he's going to fuck you on video or
CIF.
Yeah.
I don't think you should be like sending
people the wrong message and the wrong
message clearly as you can fuck
my fake ass olive garden butthole.
Exactly.
Anyway,
go to Joe rogan.net click on the link
for the fleshlight entering the code name
Rogan and save yourself 15% off and don't
do any of the things that Brian said
to do.
Thanks to ana.com o n n I t,
makers of Alpha Brain shroom,
tech sport, shroom, tech,
immune and new mood. What are these
things? Easiest to describe it as,
just to go to [inaudible] Dot Com o.
N. N. I. T, they're all new tropics.
And what nootropics are his vitamins
and enhance your cognitive function.
They enhance your, your brain's
ability to produce neurotransmitters.
It gives you all the building blocks for
thought. It's nutrients for your mind.
Very controversial subject if
you're interested in it at all. I,
I endorse it 100%. Whole heartedly
believe in it. I know it works.
I use them and I've used them
before I was ever involved with
on it. I used them when I used
a, the bill Romanowski stuff,
who I'm going back and forth with
his publicist. So he's going to,
he wants to be on the, on the, on
the podcast. So he's gonna come on,
he's going to talk to us about his stuff,
which is called neuro one,
which is how I got introduced to
the, uh, to the world of nootropics.
It's very interesting stuff in Roman ask.
He's got a very interesting story.
He was a,
he had multiple concussions
from his football career
and that's when he got into
these uh, nootropics. Anyway,
go to [inaudible] dot com check out all
the information and if you're interested,
Alpha brain is something
I wholeheartedly endorse.
We also offer 100% money back
guarantee on the first 30 pills.
If you buy it, you try it. You don't
like it, you go, I want my money back.
You don't even have to return it. It's
a hundred percent money back guarantee.
We are more concerned with making sure
nobody feels ripped off than we are with
making money.
And that's a fact.
So you use a code name Brogan and
save yourself 10% off any in a holders
strapping bitches. World
Traveler. Shane Smith is here.
Well, good experience.
My Day Joe Rogan podcast,
my night all day,
my man,
my man got here and saw the whiskey on
the table right away, cracked it open.
We're not even looking at
2:00 PM and he was down.
I have to drink off my Vegas.
Is that what it is? Dude? How,
how bad was it for you?
What'd you guys go? What does the
fights, you've answered the fights. Uh,
it was awesome. And then, uh,
that night we went out to, uh,
we had 10 vice guys there and three of
them I got calls the next day because of
the limos had their wallets
and then three separate guys,
three separate cars and lost or won.
Wow.
Pocket pickpocket dudes
must thrive on that.
And they see those stumbling guys on
Monday morning that are barely together.
Yeah. So rack from the weekend. Well,
the, the, the car drivers were nice.
They were like, Hey, you know, I'll come
around and bring it back because why?
Right, right, right. They'd
be happy. They're going to
get a tip anyway. Yeah. The,
the vice, um, videos did you guys did
for Dan Hardee were fucking awesome, man.
That's really good stuff, man.
So it's really creatively shot.
It's intriguing.
The music was good.
The choices of when to put music
and when the puts, you know,
when to put no sound.
It was a really interesting man.
I thought I thought it was great and
I was out the whole scene where he's
driving. You know, I was
like, this is fucking cool.
I love Dan Hardee's and he's awesome.
He's a quite a personality
and I was really,
I love the other guy to
Duane Ludwig his opponent.
So it was hard to watch one guy, one
guy lose and one guy when it always is.
But it's nice to see Dan Hardee successful
yet. I love a story like that, man.
I love when a guy takes like this Jamie
Varner kid that fought this weekend.
Did you see that? Yeah, he
uh, went to small shows,
lost all his motivation,
um,
started getting beat by guys that should
never beat him and then all of a sudden,
uh, he just, for whatever reason,
and we'll have to figure it
out when he talked to him,
decided to get her shit together again
and just train like a fucking mad man.
They give him another shot in the UFC
and he just goes and knocks out Edson
Barboza. It was like one of the top 10
killers and 155 pounds in the world.
The last time Barboza was
in the ring was in Brazil.
We've fucking wheel kick Terry Edom and
the head and knocked him unconscious.
I mean, he's a dangerous, dangerous dude
and Jamie Varner fucked him up, man.
It was crazy. I'd love a story
like that. I love, I love, uh, to,
to just get it together. Now. It's
like one of my favorite things in life.
I love a guy who can keep it together,
but man,
I love a dude who loses it
and gets it back. You know?
That's fascinating to me and I'm
trying to think of a box of it.
Lost it and got it back.
It's not very many because of the
gorilla story is that, you know,
they had the boxing film recently. Uh,
both the old guy. Oh, that's pretty good.
The old time guy, like who had, he
had to fix his arm, but you know,
picking up the crates, it was that
guy. Which guy was that? Ah, fuck.
Now how long ago was this movie?
But 10 in the last 10 years. It's,
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah. Braddock,
Braddock. Yeah. Shit together.
I didn't see that. No,
I saw it like a clip of it and it
looks so hokey. Hollywood. I was like,
get the fuck out of there.
I hate when a guy who's got good,
like Russell Crowe gets stuck in a
movie like that. Like when you, you're,
you're using like one of the best actors
ever and you got them in this goofy ass
movie.
It's fucking fake ass boxing movie when
the guys throw fake ass looking punches,
you know,
there's not a whole lot of guys I've
ever pulled off like a real good fight
scene in a movie. It's hard.
It's hard to fake that shit.
That's the beauty of watching
it in real life. It's so crazy.
If you never seen it before, folks, you
owe to yourself for once in your life.
If you're a UFC fan to get tickets
and go to see a live event.
If it comes anywhere near you,
cause it's fucking crazy.
It's awesome when you're
right there too. I mean, I've,
I've been like inches away from
some of the craziest moments in,
in combat history, combat sports history
in the best seats. Believe it or not.
Or not floor.
It's about halfway up where you're almost
just a little bit over the top. Yeah,
you're right. You're right. The best
seats are not the most expensive ones.
The a above angles are great angle.
Especially like that first riser.
I think that's what it's first writer. So,
uh, what happened? You just kept going.
He just kept going all through Friday.
Author, Saturday, author Sunday. Yeah.
I came straight here.
Damn Dude. And he sleep,
um, in the limos, you know, we were,
we would pass out and then sort of keep
going. But yeah, a little bit of sleep.
Dude. I'm old now, so. Okay. You're
a fucking savage. You staring out,
they're going to wheels off,
man.
He's still going to wheels off the
tracks into the woods. You still
do it, Huh? Yeah. It's
fun, isn't it? Yeah.
I wished that alcohol
didn't have such a penalty.
So just steep penalty on your body. Yeah.
I love getting drunk. Yeah. You know,
I mean I'm cool. I'm really responsible
about it. I uh, I try not to do it,
you know, to a point of access
are though I don't ever drive,
but I do like it and fucked up.
That's why I like, like getting,
doing shots like in Vegas after a show
it's like let's just get fucked up.
You know where we were when the
last time and Eddie and Thompson,
Laura and I have got fucked up and
Australia. But like when Australia,
I got no responsibility. Let's can't
fucking blasted. Right. You know,
but damn the prices just ruthless on
your body. I'm going to be drunk still.
It was kind of drunk driving. Driving
here. What for real? For? Yeah, cause I,
I like woke up and went straight here,
so I feel like I felt like I was still
pretty fucked up from last night.
You really think that you could've got
pulled over and arrested? Probably not.
I probably would be fine, but it felt
like I was bugged still from last night.
Damn Dude, you're going wheels
off to both of you mother.
Motherfuckers putting me to shame.
Yeah.
I'm not putting you to the shame
when I anyway, can you just,
I don't know what I'm
allowed to say on there.
You can say anything about whiskey.
Don't say too much. Don't get crazy.
What are you gonna say? I was going
to say, you gave me something.
Jack Daniels. Jack Daniels.
Honey, he's my new thing.
Let's do shots of that. Is My
new thing. Delicious for poison.
As far as poison goes, it's the best top.
What's your, what's your poison man? Eh,
well I love Whiskey, but you know, I like
Shitty Irish whiskey. Like Bushmills.
Really?
That's kind of stuff you like.
The more expensive scotch is that more
tastes like Scott's, Scott's the socks.
I like to just drink it
all shitty whiskey. Really?
That's interesting. Is that,
is that common? I Dunno. I've,
cause I thought like the smooth stuff
was the stuff that was like really old,
expensive. That's really
smoky stuff. The I like Pete,
which is Irish whisky. Tastes like Pete.
They boiled over peat bog. There's a,
the only time I've ever had
really good whiskey is a,
there was a guy named Josh Lieb. He was
one of the writers on Newsradio. Right.
A very funny guy. Very nice
guy. And uh, he was, uh,
just a really interesting character and
he was into like really old whiskey and
I, and I, I was like, how much
does that cost? And he was like,
it was like something saying like a
hundred dollars a glass or something like
that. But really I'm like, what
the fuck does it tastes like?
And he let me try some of
it. Cause it was like, wow,
that is a kind of a strange thing
to have created. It's a very,
a very distinct sort of taste. But I
wouldn't say it's good. Right? Yeah. No,
none of it's good. No, just cheap
whiskeys. Yes. The feeling of it is good.
Yeah. So, uh, where are you
coming back from, man? What's
the latest world travels?
Well, we'd been shooting
a lot, so we shot, um,
January and February and Afghanistan.
Whoa.
Which was seriously heavy
because we did a story on child suicide
bombers and so we got incredible access
to kids who actually were caught, uh,
before they could ignite their vests.
And then we met the senior Taliban guy
and in Qubole who is supposedly supposed
to be in Pakistan,
but we actually interviewed them and
Qubole and everyone's freaking out about
that because they didn't know he was
in Kabul. You sat down with this guy?
Yeah. Yeah. Whoa. What was that like?
It w he is a,
you know,
they don't have a good outfit
for sort of looking benevolent.
Like they look like he
looked like the devil.
He looked really bad and evil and uh,
I asked him about a child too.
So I bombing because they're using younger
and younger kids now because they get
past the checkpoint and uh,
he said, yeah, you know, he,
they actually admitted on air that
they were using children as suicide.
That's as transportation
devices for dynamite.
Wow. You mean that's, that's
the best way to describe it.
Transportation devices for dynamite name.
They've essentially said,
you know, not only were willing to
kill our own, we'll kill innocent.
Can we kill children to further
our agenda? That's scary shit.
That's fucking scary shit, man.
What's it like talking to that guy?
Um, well, you know, so he had,
he was arrested for kidnapping,
um,
westerners and UN people,
and he had been in prison and then
somehow gotten out pat in Pakistan.
So the Pakistan, he said I'm out. And
then he had snuck back into Qubole.
So you're meeting a guy who's been
arrested many times for kidnapping and
Westerners for political means.
So that's weird too,
is you go out and he's surrounded
by his talent soldiers.
So he's got like 20 or 30 guys in
their courtyard, all sort of, you know,
checking you out and then if you say
anything wrong or do anything wrong,
then you, you know, they'll
just, they'll just take you away.
They don't give a shit. Right. So it
was a bit nerve wracking and he was,
he's a seriously bad dude.
I mean,
he was a commander and then we've had
Janine and then he became Taliban and then
was one of the senior commanders
when they were in control of,
of all of Afghanistan and then had
to flee to Pakistan, announced back.
Do they know who lend them out
and why? Well, the Pakistani
government has been sponsoring Taliban
almost,
isn't it incredible?
Then like they can get people into jail
over there and then they can just sort
of let them out. Really bad guys. And
people have tried so hard to capture
it.
Just they're resisting this whole idea.
Well it's also 100% corrupt.
I mean,
you can buy your way out of jail and
Pakistan buy your way out of jail in
Afghanistan. But if you're on the
right side of the Isi and Pakistan,
which the Taliban are, then you can
do whatever you want. Or the ISI.
We're the ones protecting been loud.
So what is, how does something like this,
I mean, whatever you can say about it,
how does something like this get arranged?
Well,
in Afghanistan we're lucky because it
was a guy named Sam Michelle who runs a
total news, which is the
sort of main news, you know,
pro western say news in,
in Afghanistan. And so he,
um, you know, had a lot of,
he ha he can get you sort of
see anybody in Afghanistan.
And so he got us in to talk to
the suicide bombers, the kids,
and he got us in to talk to
the secret police about that.
And he got us in to talk
to, um, the Taliban. Wow.
So you set up this meeting with this
guy and how long has the entire meeting?
Maybe an hour. So how long have
you were in his, in his presence,
the whole time you were in his presence
or just straight in and start get up?
How do you, how do you get out
of that kind of conversation?
That seems like a conversation that
should take a hundred years. Huh? A CG.
Do you have to tip toe when
you're discussing things?
Do you biting your tongue?
I had to ask him a lot of unpleasant
questions. Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
Like how did you do that?
Well, you know, for example, I'd say, um,
you know, you were [inaudible] in general,
you know what it's like to lead troops,
you know, these people train to
fight. How do you feel about sending,
you know, six year olds, you know, to, to
be transportation devices for football?
And, uh, so you couch it in such
a way that like, you're a general,
because generally a lot of the
Taliban fighters themselves, you know,
don't, don't condone the suicide
bombing. But he did. He said, well,
he wouldn't answer it.
He said,
there's a past June saying there's a tiger
above me in a river below me. Like he,
like I'm screwed if I'd even scream
to her if I don't. So he wouldn't,
he wouldn't talk to us about it.
Wow.
How, how often are, they haven't
suicide bombs go off over there
about 200 times a year.
So nearly every day there's a suicide
bomb and they're getting more and more
effective. And uh,
it's, they just had the,
the, the first civilian
suicide bombs. So, you know,
and not, not military targets.
And it was a complete, does that,
they actually did a,
they had seven suicide bombers.
Not a lot of people maybe
know this in America,
but there was an empty building across
the way from the American embassy and
they have these seven suicide attackers
actually dressed in burqas with their
weapons under the workers
take over the building.
And they held the American embassy hostage
with like a full on fire fight in the
middle of Kabul for over 24 hours before
they could kill these seven dudes.
It was crazy. We have footage of it
all and it's totally fucking insane.
Holy Shit. Yeah. But the,
the what the Taliban guy says
and which is pretty interesting,
is that they used suicide attackers and
suicide bombers because that's what's
going to get America out. And
you go, well, you know, fuck you.
But in reality that's true because what
happened is America went into get al
Qaeda and the Taliban out of Afghanistan
and now our government is negotiating
with the Taliban to see exactly how
much power they'll have when we leave.
So you're like, okay, well Jesus Christ,
what a cluster fuck. Yeah. This,
none of this is being reported
in the mainstream news.
It's not being certainly not
being talked about like that.
You see Karzai's sits down with
Obama and they all seem to be, uh,
playing nice, nice with
each other. You know,
this is all what's going on behind
the scenes. Just, yeah. I mean,
it's been reported.
It's been constant suicide bombing.
It's been reported that they've
started to negotiate with the Taliban.
And I was surprised that there hasn't
been sort of more outrage because people,
I guess are so sick of the war, they're
just like, well, fine. You know,
they're negotiating with them.
But so whole reason negotiating
the United States is, and, and the,
uh,
NATO and what do they then negotiating
power when the Americans leave,
how much power they'll have,
how they're going to share power,
et Cetera, et cetera. Wow. Yeah.
Um, isn't that what the whole purpose of
this was trying to stop those guys? Yes.
And then they're negotiating with them
about how much power there yet. Yes.
So what does that mean?
That means we lost the war.
Americans ever gonna say we lost a war.
We were like, we were like that dude.
You could beat a dick in the dirt for
a hundred years. And we were like,
that wasn't even a war. It was a
conflict. It was a police action.
We will never admit that. We need, we
don't even have a bit, we lost Vietnam.
We pulled out of Vietnam. It's like
whatever got tired of kicking your ass.
This is a weird country, man. Yo Africana.
They for sure 100% loss.
Afghanistan. I mean, what did you do?
You know what happened? You went
in to try and get the Taliban now,
now you're negotiating to give them
power back, 10 years, all that money,
all those lives. And for
what? What's the end result?
Because actually when
you're there you realize,
oh the minute the Americans leave,
there'll be a civil war.
So it's going to be back in the, in the
exact situation of a civil war with a,
with a, a massive Taliban presence in
Afghanistan. So 12 years down the drain,
my God,
what a mess,
how horrible must it feel to the families
and people lost children over there.
And then you just realize this
whole thing was a cluster fuck.
The thing that gets me is just how does
anybody look at Vietnam and not learn?
How do we not learn?
It's like this is the same shit.
It's exact same shit.
We get manipulated into these
wars by my special interests.
And this is exactly what it is folks.
And you've been tricked
into thinking that this was some
fucking some justice mission.
You know,
it's madness.
What do you think they're over there for?
What's the,
what's the number one resource they're
trying to grab over there? Who?
The United States? Well, I
think they got into a war.
I shouldn't say the United States.
What I should say is the corporations
that are trying to, I think,
I think that a profit from it.
Look,
I think they had to go in because they
couldn't just go into a rock or rock was
about oil. Um, they couldn't just go
into a rocket. They had to say, well,
we'll have to go get the guys who did
this for nine 11 and then they went in,
but they could have gone in with a
surgical team. Got The guys that got out.
I mean, they don't have to take
over the whole country. Right.
Why do you think that they, they had to
say, we're going to go into Iraq as well.
Excuse me, Afghanistan
as well. Like why? Well,
because Iraq was a complete construct.
They made it all up.
It was 100% of their like they try to
tie Iraq with nine 11 you're like, well,
I just had nothing to do with
it. A rag, 100% to do with
w with oil, with oil. Well,
because they had the
manufactured why we went there.
They the at nine 11 was like yes,
they already had plans to go in there
before but not in would say yes, you know,
we're going to go in
there after all kind of,
but they knew that they had to
actually go to the place where it was.
They had to do the true thing so
that they could get what they wanted,
which was a wreck.
Oh,
so you feel like Afghanistan was
almost like a secondary operation?
100% whoa.
And then it became the primary operation
because it was such a cluster fuck.
Well, what about all the resources
that they keep finding over there?
Like they just found trillions
of dollars in minerals.
Do you think that that plays a part in
the, uh, idea to, to occupy it as well?
Maybe.
I mean,
I think that now what's happening is
Chinese companies are coming in as they do
because they're sort of, um, not blame
free, but there are sort of like,
oh we haven't been conflicted by this
conflict so they can watch like they've
done in Africa, you know, wherever
America sort of, you know,
piss people off or done bad things
and trying to just comes in and says,
oh we'll trade with you.
That's gotta be a trip man.
Cause America goes and sees things and
you know, for, for better or for worse,
let's try to fix it.
Then there's problems and then they put
sanctions on people and trying to just
says, I don't give a shit what you
do. Wow, you can do whatever you want.
You could just give me your
Tridium or whatever it is.
Wild China just rocks at game of Thrones
style. They go old school empire ways.
We don't impose any,
we got our own fucking problems.
We've got a billion people living on one
patch of dirt. And exactly. Wow. Yeah,
they'll always going to beat it.
A Americans with that attitude.
As far as business goes and
getting into creepy places,
they'll just sneak right in.
So there in Afghanistan you think
trying to get these minerals? Yeah,
well for sure.
And Chinese companies are in there.
I mean there's a lot
of companies in there,
but the problem is going to be stability
because the minute the Americans pull
out, it's going to be full on
civil war. So you can't really
go and get minerals on
people shooting rockets.
Now knowing what a cluster fuck it is,
knowing how crazy it is.
Was it like being over there? You
as a person, as an and outsider,
Canadian in facts out there watching
this fucking chaos and filming it.
Wait,
what was that like for you?
You know,
I,
I got on the plane to come home and I was
on my motherfucking drink now I was on
my iPod or the iPad and you know, it
was does, there was a plane, you know,
it was like soaring through the air and
you can see space and all this stuff.
And because when you're in Afghanistan,
it sort of feels like 5,000 years ago
because everything is sort of, you know,
these sort of mud huts and
it's sun baked and it does,
it looks like it has a lot
of, it looks like it hasn't
changed, uh, in 5,000 years.
So you, you're really sort of,
wow, this is maternity, you know,
this is the modern age,
this is the 21st century because we
have all these crazy things that you can
sort of tweet from Afghanistan
or whatever technology.
But then at the same time you have this,
you sort of devolution,
you know, where we're sending
kids to to blow our shit up,
you know, because it, it's
effective, you know? And so I was,
there's been a lot of what I've seen this
past year, this past year of shooting,
which is, it feels like half of humanity
is just going completely backwards,
you know,
now seeing that and then flying
back into New York City. What, what,
what the fuck does that contrast feel
like? Do you take these mad trips?
And I wanted to come home.
And you see what's possible at the apex
of civilization right now as far as like,
you know,
cities and in a place where he can go
safely and the place that doesn't have,
you know, guns and bombs blowing up
constantly. I mean, no wonder why they,
that's where the terrorist
attacks occurred.
Now wonder why that's where the
September 11th attacks occurred. Right,
for sure. I mean, it was, you know,
incredibly successful. You know,
when you fly in, you still see
that the twin towers out there.
And actually we started our peace with
that because we say actually the most
successful suicide bombing of all time
was nine 11 suicide attack because it
started the Iran Iraq war.
It started Afghanistan.
Um, you know, both of which are
still going on and you know,
completely polarized the world. And
it actually, suicide attacks were,
and when we did the research, it was a
few months ago, and I've had a few ales,
I don't quote me on the exact percentages,
but the percentages are insane.
It was like suicide attacks where three
to 5% of all terrorism before nine 11
and now they're like 97% of all Jesus
Christ because it's so successful.
What,
what is it like as a sane,
rational person traveling around to
the most fucked up places on earth and
seeing humanity at its worst? Wait,
what the fuck does that feel like?
That's a hard question.
You're such a nice guy.
You're such a jovial guy.
Every time I see you're smiling and
hugging people, you seem like such a,
a warm and friendly person for you to
get thrust constantly into these horrific
situations where you get to see people
just handed the shitty it's fucking hand
of cards and the history of life.
Like here you are,
2012 the Internet's here. The fucking,
you know, the age of information is here,
but you're involved in some sort of
crazy religious war and people blowing
themselves up when they're six.
You were in the worst spot.
Yeah. Well, I mean you,
the reason why I'm happy is because
you're thankful for what you have.
When you see what uh, you know,
everybody else doesn't have,
well you happy before you did all this,
you, I'm a pretty happy guy. Yeah.
So it just enhanced your happiness
to see how fortunate you are and your
circumstances. Yeah. Fuck man, that's a,
that's a serious trip to be spending a
large percentage of your time on this
earth. Yeah. Seeing
the, the terrible spots.
Most evil like trying to fly into Hawaii
for the weekend and chill and you're,
you know what I mean?
You're spending your, your,
your job is to go to some of
the scariest parts on earth.
Yeah. Um, yeah.
It doesn't seem that freaky
at the time cause you just,
you want to get the story and like, yes,
we got into, you know, Somalia, you know,
we're going to hang out with
the pirates. They're like, yes,
we've been working on that for a while.
Did you guys go to the Somalia and
hanging out with the pirates? Oh my God.
And then you, but then you get in
there, you get in there and you're like,
you're nervous and you know, fucking,
you didn't think they would kidnap you.
Well we paid them to kidnap US cause
it's a, you pay the kidnapping fee.
So the kidnapping 15 grants.
So you pay them what they
would charge for a kidnapping,
but not to kidnap you. Well, yeah, which
is fine. I mean it's like the same. Well,
you know, grants seems pretty
reasonable, but that's all it is. Yeah.
But isn't it more for other people? If
they catch like some billion, we did it.
We did a bunch of shooting. We
shot a lot in Kenya with, uh,
with the, uh, sort of, you know,
refugees and we show it around Puntland
and now we're shooting in Mogadishu to
round it up. But, uh, it depends on the,
on the, I want to say it, but anyway,
so when you're there all you're
thinking about us, you know,
we've got to get the shot or we got
to get this and we've got to get that.
And it's only when you come back and
you're sort of having dinner somewhere in
there. Like, where were you? Oh, I
was with the pirates in Mogadishu,
US waste.
But you don't really think about it so
much at the time when a lot of people are
horrified about the Somali
pirates and they're like,
this is a terrible situation.
But what they don't understand is that
those people really got fucked into that
situation where they had almost no choice.
The Somali pirates started out
when these Somalia soldiers would,
uh,
go after people who were dumping
toxic waste off their shores.
It was killing all their fish and
poisoning their people. And these are,
there were a fisherman's culture.
I mean,
could you imagine you're a culture
of fishermen and the, you know,
they don't have a history of going
after people and kidnapping people.
They're just trying to fucking make a
living and all of a sudden some assholes
are, you know, driving around their boats,
floating around a couple of miles out,
just dumping horrible shit into their
ocean and it's fucking up the whole ocean
and they get to see it right
before their eyes. They're the,
the mother earth becoming,
you know,
poisoned the fish poisoning and
people getting poisoned and sick.
So they started kidnapping them.
They started kidnapping those people and
demanding ransom from these companies
that had poisoned their water. And then
they started saying, you know what?
Fuck it. Let's just kidnap anybody
drives by. That's what we do now.
And that's when it became those asshole
corporations that were dumping their
shit off the Somalia coast.
They made monsters. You know,
those people should be fucking
held responsible for a cleanup.
Just as much as they should be
responsible for a toxic cleanup.
They should be responsible for
cultural cleanup. You know,
if they could actually find out who
dumped all that shit and all the different
corporations involved,
it's probably a whole lot of them.
They could probably get a
fuck load of money out of it.
If the world had any code,
sort of a real court, you know.
Well, the problem is is a lot
of it was radioactive waste.
So it irradiated to see
in a radiated the beaches.
And before that the Chinese,
Japanese,
Portuguese and Spanish fishing companies
completely over fished it and then the
radiated it.
So they were totally fine.
It's actually a great movie
called the fishing without nets,
which is about that, about like they were
all fishermen and now there's no fish.
So they just take the same boat out and
then they, then they go, wow, we're,
we're working on a story in
there right now about, um,
the American government is financing,
sort of Islam is to extremists, you know,
to fight a Al Shabaab,
uh, who are, you know,
the bad boys over there.
And, uh, and so we're,
we're trying to figure out if that's true.
So the stories that American
government is funding,
funding Muslim extremists who are going
to fight these bad guys set up exactly
the same as what happened
in Afghanistan and Sophia.
And then they became the
talent. Jesus Christ. Yeah.
We just don't ever learn how,
but how does one fix this
mess that we're in? How does,
how does one put the world on its back,
you know,
straight on its axle or art in taxes?
Or does that ever happen? Does it,
it's just the way people roll.
We just fucking constantly involved in,
in chaos and love at the same time,
you know,
a lot of people meddle in other people's
stuff and then we would have to go in
and we have to save them and you're like,
you know,
we have to save them from whom
themselves, you know, like, oh, you know,
so Diane was such a bad guy
as opposed to who, you know,
just like drove Dale hurt. Like, you know,
so there's a lot of
geopolitics and you know,
sort of Geo political
gamesmanship has been,
you know, the, the, the cause
of a lot of these problems.
But now it's 99% always economics.
It's so if you look at, you know,
we have resource based wealth or you
know there's one in one in every three
countries and with resource based
wealth has a civil war every four years.
Whereas you know, the, the
remaining countries, you know,
don't have any civil wars or haven't had
a civil war for a hundred years. So the,
the, the, the percentages are insane. So
now like Afghanistan you were just saying,
but a lot of the African countries
now they're like, oh, you know,
rare earth metals that didn't used to
be worth money or no, and you know,
every cell phone so that,
you know,
the war in the Congo is now the 10th
bloodiest war in history and it's all
because of coal town, which is
needed to make our iPads and iPhones.
It's so ironic then at
the height of technology,
the iPad three front facing camera,
HD screen,
if you follow that all the way down,
there's an old African boy that's
picking out this mineral out of,
out of a hole in the earth. It's
really, that's that spectrum.
It's quite fascinating.
I mean, it's almost from,
I mean that spectrum goes back to just
the invention of tools and you know,
figuring out iron and shit and fake point
pulling stuff out of the earth all the
way to the height of technology. Where
are weird man, we are fucking strange.
Human beings are so bizarre.
How much do you look at life?
I mean your,
your experiences are far more extreme
than mine and most people on this planet,
I think. How, how do you, do
you look at this sometimes,
like it's a big work of fiction.
Do you look at life sometimes?
Like this is just fucking so nutty. It
doesn't seem like he can be real. I mean,
if anybody has seen
the nuttiest you might,
you might have witnessed some of the
nuttiest shit on earth and come back to
talk about, I mean you've,
you've got in one life,
think of all the fucking
places you've been.
Hmm.
Does it feel real?
But we always say,
they say about vice and what's the,
what's the political sort of stance
of I, so I said, we don't have one.
It's the modern condition is
absurd. There's the, you know,
the absurdity of fucking this mudder.
It's crazy. Like it's fucking nuts.
And then when you go out and
see exactly how nuts it is,
it keeps getting crazier
and crazier and crazier.
So these get bigger stories
are more insane. You know,
we were just shooting in Karachi,
which is a completely failed city.
They have a hundred plus
kill killings a night.
You can hire a killer there
to kill someone for 10 bucks.
Actually we rode around with one
of these contract killers and uh,
it was, it's just shocking.
The contract killer. Yeah.
What the fuck is that? Like? Well,
Saroo salary and my partner did that story
because I wouldn't have asked as long
and doing that story in the garage.
He, uh, why wouldn't you Lawson?
Well,
I'm karate is run by gangs by like Haqqani
network who are Taliban related sort
of mafia gang family. And then
they have, you know, various, uh,
Baluchistan gangs and then
they have, you know, uh, the,
the heroin trafficking gangs and they're
all fighting each other continually.
It's insanely violent and you know,
and basically you can't,
if you're Caucasian, you
can't sort of, no, there's no
tourists there, for example,
which there's no reason for you to be
there. It's just complete wild west show.
It's so hard for people
in Pasedena to believe
driving around in Pasadena that this
coexist on the earth at the same
departments. The after
picture. It's like, yeah,
escape from New York, isn't it? I mean,
Karachi is bigger than New York and
it's just where we're part of the world.
Is it against Pakistan? But it's on the,
on the, on the ocean and it's, it's uh,
it's, it's, it's a huge city and
it's just complete fucking anarchy.
Complete fucking,
Whoa, whoa. It's a war. It's a war zone.
How many millions of people live
in this area? My 18 to 20 million,
but all just going crazy. 18 the 20
million people live in wild west.
How do we not know about this? How do we
not know about this? That's incredible.
People know that crotch is bad, but
not like, like you described it,
you described it like a movie.
Steven Spielberg decided to make a
movie about that and told you that that
city's going down right now on earth.
You'd be like itch.
It is nothing I had know about that.
It isn't movie. I mean you don't,
you think that that's something
that would be like really,
really popular if no one
ever talks about that.
If they made a movie right now about
that part of the world described the way
you describe it,
like a,
like some crazy horror movie
about civilization gone wrong.
That's what it is. A Mad Max reality
that's existing coexisting right now.
Just as big as New York.
We'd go get no way.
You know what I mean?
We'd go no way.
Yeah. Yeah. Karachi is complete chaos.
It's scary as hell. Scaries Pakistanis
are like, well, no one goes there.
Well you go there. No one goes there,
but 20 million people live there.
That's crazy. Just shit burning
in the streets. People pop up up,
people getting killed.
It was like running gun
battles of the streets.
So you, you couldn't go. So you said, uh,
what is it you're your correspondent
look like? Sort of, she's Pakistani,
she's pack. It's he, he,
oh, he is Pakistani. He's
also snuck into the gun markets,
a Taliban gun markets.
When the Americans said that the war was
over and the Taliban were coming across
into the Northwest Frontier province
and getting a thousand handmade guns,
they make their own guns by hand.
That was like little kids
make the guns and a thousand.
We're going over every day. And
we're like, well, if the war's over,
why is there are a thousand girls
across the border every day.
And so when we broke that
story, that was solution, he uh,
he just went back to Pakistan and his
story of Karachi is fucking insane.
He's got unique access, but you know, does
he have, does he have footage? Oh yeah.
Yeah. When can we see this video? Uh,
I think that's going to go up
within the next month. I buy stuff.
You got to let me know that he has a video
of him with like grinding around with
this contract color obviously,
but he's just sort of going from thing
to thing with his gun and they were these
moped helmets. And then so you can't
see who they are and, and, uh, it's,
you know, that's an insane thing to
do for 10 bucks. There's, there's, uh,
there's a increase or maybe it's just an
increase of awareness for our awareness,
but there's an increase in sort of
assassination availability and sort of
there's been a price decrease or whatever,
you know, because now we go and we see,
like in Karachi,
they have contract killers everywhere.
We were shooting a lot recently. And,
um, whereas in, in northern Mexico,
and, um, they're, uh, they have,
um,
scenarios that get paid 200 bucks a month.
And their job is just to kill people.
Like there were just the
fucking muscle that's there,
the assassins, you know, and,
um,
when we were there,
Juarez is actually the most dangerous
town in the world for journalists.
It's the same as, so there's El
Paso on the Texas side, same city,
and it's one of the
safest cities in America.
And then you go right across the border
and it's one of the most dangerous
cities in the world,
but it's the most dangerous city in
the world for journalists. Number one.
Why is that?
Because it's the drug cartels that run
it and there are smugglers and so they
don't want anyone to
ever filmed their shit.
So instead of like coming up to you when
you have your camera and saying, hey,
why are you carrying that camera?
What are you shooting?
They just see a camera and go bang,
no point in asking you a question.
And they make a lot of,
if you write about something,
they make a and they cut off your head
and they write the story on your flesh
with blood and all this
stuff. And so, you know,
journalists just don't go there anymore.
Wow.
That is kind of crazy that we're right
next to a third world country involved in
like the biggest drug war
in the history of the world.
Most Americans are blissfully
unaware. Well, we shot the,
we shot a big piece on that.
And um, of course you did.
How'd you get the deed get embedded?
Well,
we got embedded with
people who are fighting.
This is a pretty freaky story though.
I don't know how much of it allow it.
I'm allowed to say. Oh
really? But, uh, well
I can say a lot more. Uh, but, uh,
but it's a very complex
story and we're going to,
we're going to cause some waves, but,
uh, basically we were down in, in, in,
in Mexico. Um, we'd done some, some stuff
with the cartels. Incredibly difficult,
most difficult stories to get right now
today are cartel story cause they just
kill everybody.
Um,
but we started hanging out with the
people who were fighting the cartels,
who are Mormon colonies
that's originated in America,
so they could keep practicing polygamy.
Went to a northern Mexico
and they formed polygamist,
um, um, Mormon colonies there.
And because of the colonies did well,
the cartels started targeting them and
started kidnapping them and killing them.
And so the Mormon colonies started arming
themselves and fighting against the,
the cartels. She's, so there's been a
war between the Mormon colonies and the,
and the, um, and the, and the narcos.
And we went down there to live in the
colonies and we were hanging out with the
Lebaron who, I don't know if you've ever
heard of, but they have a crazy story of,
they had a,
one of their brethren believed that
he had the power of blood atonement.
So he was killing all the people in the
church that we're trying to, you know,
mess with them. So he had about
30 or maybe at 50 children,
nearly years,
nearly 50 children.
And he had them work as
assassins for him in this,
in this bloody war that they had
down there. This is all happening,
not in the 1880s this isn't happening
in the 1980s this is happening in like
Blues Brothers Eighties Oh my God.
And so they have this crazy war,
but they arm themselves, right, because
they're all fighting it within the family.
And then because of that,
when the narcos attack them,
they were sort of armed and
ready to go and bad acid.
So they started fighting them.
But they're actually just one colony
over from the other people that they came
down with who are the Romney's.
So Mitt Romney's father was born
in one of these colonies of land,
and then they, they, now, this
is the father was born in Mexico.
Mitt Romney's father was born in a
polygamous colony and northern Mexico
Chihuahua.
She's lonely and colonials and blend.
And actually he ran
for president and they,
they said, uh, they, they, they brought
up the fact that he might've been illegal,
illegal immigrant and that,
uh, and that, you know, he,
he gave us more than a polygamous
calling me and site is his presidency.
Uh,
presidential candidacy didn't last long,
at least say that the piece, but like,
but his sons, his son, well, because book,
you know, but he's, he actually,
we say out of all the candidates,
Republican candidates, Mitt Romney
had the staunchest, you know, uh,
stand against immigration and, and
you know, it, it's, you know, and he,
he sort of ignores his roots and he
never talks about it. And you say, well,
I understand why it's completely
logical because you know, he, he, he,
he wanted to veto the dream act and he
said he'd publicly to veto the dream act,
although his father as the poster child
for the Dream Act. But you say he,
you know, he, he,
he would veto the dream act because he
wants to get away from these stories
because of the stories.
When you dig into them are fucking insane.
Of course he doesn't want to talk about,
because polygamy,
uh, not battles with drug
lords, you know, and,
and you know,
completing and kidnapping and insanity do
not a good presidential candidate make,
how was this not mainstream?
How was this,
is it going to come out during
the presidential campaign here?
That's going to come up? We get, we
have great footage. Mitt Romney's,
either the official nominee yet on the
republican side. I mean the, obviously
he will be, he will be, but he's
not official, right? Yeah. But yeah,
for sure it's going to come out. I
mean, the thing is, is, is you know it
all right?
I don't know why you can't knock them out,
but when people have written a little
bit about it, not very much about it.
When you see a guy is that flawed and
it has such an obvious story that that's
so beyond fucked. Hmm. Does it make
you feel like this has all been set up?
Does it make you feel like they put him
in there because they knew he couldn't
win?
Uh,
it doesn't make sense to me that that's
the best that the Republicans can do.
I've met a lot of smart Republicans.
I met a lot of bad motherfuckers.
You would just conservative and right
wing and maybe they're a little too by
Billy. Right? But you know, I've
met some pretty strong minded,
very articulate republicans.
How come they never get there?
How come we're dealing with these,
these like second rate hacks,
these guys who just fucking changed
their opinion when the wind blows.
Like how does a guy like that get to a
position to be running for president?
Because that seems like that's a
weak example of what a politician,
a leader can be.
We've seen the JFK is,
we've seen the bill
cleanse who've seen the,
the people that have the strong voices.
When you have a guy who was a wishy washy,
has Mitt Romney,
who's comes from a fucking religious cult
that it was in northern Mexico. I mean,
I'm like,
really that's the best you can do.
A multi multimillionaire who his
father was from another country,
but as against immigration.
But
I mean, look, the rumor is
that they knew that they,
the economy's going to go keep,
keep going down and you know,
drops aren't going to get
better, et Cetera, et cetera.
So they said, okay, you know,
we'll just put up and
also Ryan and you know,
then we'll get to the next two terms
after that because the economy is going to
be shit. Anyway, put Jeb Bush on tap.
There you go for 2016 but I mean,
Mitt Romney, you know, the, it's,
it's, it's funny because they
want the Anti Obama, you know,
so they just want to sort of,
they don't understand.
Uh,
Obama was the first example I've ever
seen in my life of it where it's pretty
clear it doesn't matter anymore.
Whatever it takes to get into office is,
you mean once, once the, the
politician gets there, that's
all out the window. All,
all it is about there is keeping
everything moving the exact same way.
It's moving right now,
making sure these corporations
make fucking billions of dollars,
making sure that the rights
of the civilians get shrunk
more and more every day
until it gets to this global scenario
that we have where the whole world is
controlled by money and money
is the government and that's,
that's it seems to be where we're
moving towards an actual real,
especially this idea of America,
what it was supposed to be, you know,
a a government by the people.
We were going to set it up.
We were going to govern ourselves.
We're going to have a very strict set
of laws and checks and balances in place
to make sure this doesn't get out of
hand and become what it used to be.
It doesn't work that way.
How do we fix this Shane Smith?
How do we fix this?
You're the world traveling.
It's going to get worse because
actually money does rural everything.
And I think that you'll probably always
has. But you know, if you look at,
you know, communism, the synthesis of
communism is that market regulates itself.
And you have a small thing
for infrastructure. Same
thing with capitalism. David,
Ricardo, Adam Smith, you know, the, the,
the free market sort of doesn't
need government. Um, but I,
and I believe that both were up.
Apologies for what was happening.
And then industrial evolution,
because everyone was looking around
saying this is fact. You know,
there's nothing, there was, you know,
every kids working in coal mines,
all that shit. But the reason why
I say it's going to get worse,
and I'm not actually, I'm actually
an optimist. I'm a certain,
not a doom and gloom guy, but is that
money runs everything. But the problem is,
is the money's running out,
right? So you have kids, you know,
in Spain you have a under 27 years old,
50% unemployment.
So you have all these young kids and
there's nothing scarier than a young kid
with no future. You've just taken away
his future there. You know, 17, 18,
19 year old kid.
What the fuck does he have to lose?
And you've seen the riots in Athens,
you've seen the riots in London,
you've seen the riots in Paris, you've
seen the riots and I mean Tahrir Square,
you've seen, they're all over those human
rights in Montreal. This, there you go.
And young people are getting
more and more frustrated,
I should say protests in Montreal, they
didn't really write. The problem is that,
you know, well, look to have rights here.
Now they have occupied
Wall Street here and it's,
it's not going away. It's just, you know,
sort of getting more and more subversive
and you know, doing their own, uh,
content networks and everything now.
But you know,
when you have young kids
rioting with nothing to lose,
then you're going to look for
a radical economic solutions.
And radical economic solutions
mean radical political parties.
Radical political parties hate each other.
And it's the,
it's the same sort of scenario you
have that started world war two,
incredible depression. You
know, somebody comes up with a,
what seemingly is sort of
fixing the depression. Oh,
we're all going to do that.
No,
we're going to do the antithesis of that.
So you have communists versus fascists, et
Cetera, et cetera. And both of, you know,
extreme sides of the spectrum. And
then there ended up warring, you know,
fighting. And what's
happening now is, you know,
Europe has just fucked and it's getting
going to get worse and worse and worse.
And there's going to be more
and more radical politics,
more and more kids in the streets.
And that's when I get worried and say,
hold on a second. What are we going
to do? Wait until there's, you know,
militias running down Berlin main street,
fighting other fucking police whatevers,
civil war, uh, until we step in and say,
Hey,
can we not fix this?
Because it's just getting fucking
worse and worse and worse. And sure.
You see bad shit in Afghanistan. You
see bad shit. And in South America,
we just saw in Caracas where it's insane,
higher murder rate than America,
you know, with 20 million people,
population, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
But Europe is about to fucking explode.
It's about to explode.
So this all has to do with the
adoption of the euro. Is that what,
fuck this whole sister situation out the,
the whole,
because Europe is all connected. All
the countries are connected now I think.
I think it's,
we've been in a depression because what's
the difference between a recession and
depression and depression goes on for it?
You know,
it's a cyclical economic
downturn. It lasts, you know,
a longer time than a recession. Well,
we, because of quantitative easing,
all these things I economic things,
we sort of kept it at bay.
But right now Europe's
already back in recession.
China slow down in new sod down.
America's very shortly going to
slow down behind them and it's no,
there's no way we can. And you go,
okay, well it's another five years.
So that means, okay, well it started
in 2008 it's going to be, you know,
eight years,
nine years before we get out of this.
So economically we had all these things
that we tried to fix it, it didn't work.
So now there's just no money,
no money, no jobs in the system.
So young people are the ones who
get forced out. The problem is,
is young people are the first ones who
are going to go out and get a stick and
start bashing shit up
because why wouldn't they?
Of course. Yeah. I mean, I've,
I've said that's the biggest problem
with this country is that, you know,
everybody wants to fix everything
that's happening everywhere,
but they don't want to
fix what's going on in,
in the impoverished areas of this
country. When you're there, see,
there was something that was released
today that a study I read today rather a
study on a message. It was on my message
board, but I forget what the study was,
what it said.
The 72% of black people in this country
are born to single parents and raised by
single parents. That's fucked.
That's just fucked. You know, if,
if we, if we want to like start fixing
things and we got to fix this country too,
I mean if we, we this, this, this
country could fall apart just as easily.
When you look at giant patches where
kids are growing up without any hope and
that's, that's the most fuck thing.
When a child like, as you said,
has no future. They feel they
have no future and they're angry,
they feel rob,
it's, you know, you're
saying, well how do you,
how does it feel to come back to New
York from Afghanistan? You know? Well,
it reminded me so much of, of nine
11, but it was like the stark thing.
Whereas what, what fucked me up
more was when you're in Mexico,
like five miles from the,
from the border and shit is fucked up.
Like some of them you were just saying it,
some of the craziest shit
you've seen generally, you know,
makes you feel better about
your life feel or, you know, I,
I'm happy I have all these, you know,
health and things. But I went to a, uh,
a church run outside of warriors
by a sort of born again,
pastor who was a,
an ex junkie and he takes in sort of the,
the refuse of, of, of, of
warriors into this church.
And it's like a lot of people with,
with severe psychological problems,
people with severe um,
uh,
drug addictions and a lot of,
there was two feral children, not
children. They were, and then adults now,
but they had grown up funeral
like on the streets sort of thing.
One sort of barked like a dog and,
but you go and they live in these cells
cause some of them have to be locked in.
And like there was,
you know,
people with open colostomy bags and
stuff with flies buzzing around their
innards and stuff and they say,
and you're walking around
and it was like just crazy.
She's fucking just degradation,
like fearful people were,
you know, and, and, and,
and like a nightmare. Like it was crazy,
you know, and, and they, they all,
he has the pastor gets them to paint and
all their paintings are fucking insane.
Like so heavy and depressing and a lot
of them are missing limbs because of,
you know,
gang green and,
and so when you come from shooting there
and then when I was just in Vegas for
the fights and you walk around
and we went out like to, you know,
a nightclub after the fights and it's
just Chanel and Louis Vuitton and this and
that. And like everybody, you know,
all the stores on the way to the
nightclub and then get everyone dressed up
whenever you're like,
as human beings,
we just want to forget, you know,
we just want entertain TV more,
just spectacular shit.
Just fucking lots of stuff because it's,
we like to bury our heads in the sand
because that's just right here. Like,
that shit is happening just fucking,
you don't have to go to Afghanistan.
It's five miles from our border.
And so you know that that's what,
what you think when you come back from,
from places like that. And by the
way, all the guns when we were there,
it's the largest hall of ammunition was
over 250,000 rounds of ammunition at
some point 60 ammunition and it was
coming from America. And I was like, oh,
that's, you know, strangely, like, no,
all the guns are coming from America.
All the guns,
all the ammunition coming from America,
all the drugs comes up from here and I'll,
excuse me.
And all the money comes from America.
Well, what was that
one crazy uh, DEA idea.
They're in a sell guns. The
fast and the furious. Yeah.
They sold guns with, with markers. Yeah.
So that they can find
out who's using the guns.
And those guns were directly used
to kill agent. Yeah. That, well,
they figured that was a scam.
It was a scam.
And that they just pretended it was a,
a mission or the mean,
just the fact that they could
ever justify selling fucking guns.
Lots of guns to Mexican drug dealers.
They had the, uh, how could they
possibly think that that would,
they had a killer cart with the CIA,
the old director of the
CIA ceremonial pistol. Wow.
Like, you know, it has like director
of the CIA on it. Holy Shit.
So Holy Shit.
They're just,
the fact that they can say that that
was an operation and they could say, oh,
this is what we're going to do.
The way we're going to track the network,
we have to actually sell them real guns.
Yeah. The Mexicans laugh
at it. It's hilarious.
This is what the Americans are doing.
Just giving free guns to the Narcos
in order to find out
what rapists are like,
I'm going to have to go
get my ducks sucked a lot.
I'm going to really have to find out what
did it, what it's like to rate people.
So I'm gonna have to do
some raping. What pop? Fuck.
How has no one getting,
why is no one going to jail for that?
Well, I mean, God knows
that the whole, I mean,
the majority of the police
done in Mexico are corrupt.
So every time the Americans tried to do
something with them, like it just gets,
you know,
well, how has no one in the
American DEA going to jail for that?
I Dunno.
That's just seems like the most
ridiculous idea of all time.
Yeah.
The worst guy,
the worst guy I've ever heard about
as a guy named Eldora keen and he's a,
a narco that was fighting
one of the Mormon colonies,
but he's famous for, uh, you know,
he's obviously there
were drug dealers and in,
so he went into a drug
rehab center or he didn't,
but he had his people massacre the mall.
18 different people in a,
in a drug rehab center just for being
in a drug Rehab Center. You know,
this is a very bad guy. Um, and he
kidnapped and killed some of the, uh,
the Mormon, the Lebaron family. Um,
but he is famous for getting caught
on the other side of the board,
on the American side of the border
with a Mexican military, um,
convoy filled with something
like 15 tons of pot
and they had a firefight with
the American border patrol.
And then they came back into
Mexico and they knew who it was.
They knew that they did.
They knew he had had a firefight,
but he went back to where he lives,
which is eight miles down
the road from the Mormons.
And the Mexican government
didn't do anything.
Whoa. I got a frog in
my throat. Jesus Christ.
Fuck
yeah.
Elder keen.
What a ballsy move.
Do you want a water or something man?
Yeah, maybe we reach it. There you go.
You need more rehab.
This is a fridge right behind
you. I'll grab you one. All right.
Get some cigarettes is,
that'll help.
Maybe.
What a ballsy move.
That guy gets in a fucking armored car.
Voi with weed and tries it too. I'm
asking a firefight with them. Holy Shit.
Now how are these and Mormon
is getting around in Mexico.
They all take convoys now.
I don't know.
Like heavily armed and shad
are heavily armed. Yeah.
So did they like drive around with
like tanks? Like what did they,
what do they do? Cause I know a lot of
the drug cartels, they have tanks now.
Jay have trucks with, you
know, with guns and stuff.
So the Mormons drive around
like they're in war. Yeah. Wow.
What a nutty thing. It must
be for them, Huh? Yeah.
They are at war and they
can't get out of there.
Are they trying to plan to get
out of and get out of there?
A lot of them have American passports,
but they don't want to
do it with like Mexicans.
Like these are like big super tall
cowboy hat wearing sort of Texas dudes,
but they're in Mexico,
three in Mexico,
and they're going to war
with these drug cartels.
I would think that if you're ever in
a place where you're at war with drug
cartels, it's time to get the fuck out of
dog asked them that. What they say. Um,
this is my country. This is my home.
It's hard to leave your home. Wow.
Fuck out of this. That's some
silly nonsense to me. Uh, you know,
I think people have to get over that idea.
You should live anywhere.
Get your loved ones together and move
where it's safe. Tough Fuck Outta here.
If you have money.
I mean if you have enough to do it,
and I can understand if you
have to fight for your property,
but that that's a lost cause. That
place. Yeah, they don't leave.
It's, I mean I had the same
answer and when I was in,
so the Africa where shooting and there's
like a lot of violence in South Africa
and I kept saying to people, why don't
you leave? I said, that's our home.
Those people are idiots. That's crazy.
That's just, it's so ridiculous.
If you know there's a better spot on
earth where this kind of kind of shit
doesn't happen,
he can look where my home is,
home invasions and and assassinations
and institutionalized rapes and all these
things are just part of the daily
equation. Then it's, then fuck it.
I'm not doing that. Yeah.
Yeah, I agree. Yeah.
The fuck man.
How do we get the rest of the world
anywhere near where we are here right now?
Is that possible?
Can,
the human condition evolves so much that
we could ever get everybody on a higher
level all across the world?
Or is this just a part of the program?
The spectrum always goes from the worst
case scenario to the best case scenario
and every shade in between.
Is that just how things keep moving?
Is that just the conflict, the Yin
and Yang? Is that, is that the, the,
the pull and push of life? That's the
best question I've heard a long time.
But I think it's unanswerable.
If anybody,
if anybody would have seen it,
the spectrum is broad as humanly possible,
I would think it would be you, you
are, I mean, the thing is is if you,
you see some things that that are,
that are great,
like we did a story on
these scientists who are developing,
um,
machines that can sort of harvest the
atmosphere so they can take out carbon and
all the harmful things in the atmosphere
and then sort of reduce it to CO2,
which you can make.
You can actually activate algae
for biofuels or you can, uh,
combine them with other elements and
lots of solar to make hydrogen cells.
And it might sound like we're
clinging at straws here,
but when you start to think, wow,
you know, if we had unlimited,
if we have unlimited solar power
and you have unlimited carbon, a,
it stops global warming would be,
you can make hydrogen cells or
biofuels and then you can say,
wow, that would be interesting
because you could actually,
you could put hydrogen cells
and t like every new car.
So every new car had to have that.
So that's a whole new industry that
we would run because of the patents,
the only,
um,
effluent that comes out of a
hydrogen cells as pure h or two,
which we're running out of water. So you
say, hey, it could build a new economy,
build this new world.
And so when you start talking to the
scientists who are really smart guys and
realizing, well, you can sort
of regulate, you know, the,
the amount of harmful toxins in the
atmosphere. Um, there is sanity. You know,
there are people coming up with ideas.
This could start a whole new economy. Uh,
you know, sort of set us out on this, you
know, great, right track and you're like,
wow, and you feel really good and
maybe we are going to be smart.
Maybe we aren't going to put these
machines to the next every factory.
Maybe we are going to do this great stuff.
And then the problem is,
is you go to Africa or
Southeast Asia and you know,
we did a story on, um, you know,
a lot of people are going, Europeans
and Americans are going to, uh, um,
Thailand, you know, to get a
medical vacations, they call them.
So you go there and you get a facelift
and two weeks of vacation on orchitis.
And so, you know, then you
can get transplants. He
can get this. And you know,
that's a more and more
people are going for, um, uh,
medical procedures. So it
started a war between the, uh,
ambulance gangs to take
bodies. Uh, you know,
because let's say you hurt yourself.
Well, more than often than not,
you're not going to arrive alive
because they want to harvest your,
your pieces. So Bangkok,
body snatchers. So there's,
there's what like street gangs that fight
each other over the sort of dead end.
So say if someone falls
and breaks their leg,
they're not going to take
you to the hospital. They're
going to take your organs.
Well, if you're, if you're injured,
they're going to make sure
that you don't arrive alive.
And then they harvest York so they
kill you. Yes. They let you die.
They'll let you die. Yeah, they
don't kill you. They let it,
they don't give you medical attention.
We never saw anybody sort of overtly
being killed. We've heard about it.
But you don't want to say, yeah,
okay, well they don't seem like
they're ethical.
So I wouldn't imagine that would be
outside the realm of possibility.
But I understand exactly
where you're going with that
one side. You have this
sort of hope, you know what,
we're going to get our shit together.
We're going to have new fucking energy
systems or aren't going to crazy people,
all this stuff. And then, and then you go
see that and you're like, wait a minute,
we're parasites were bad,
bad people.
Yeah. I, I did this thing before my,
a showtime special in 2005 or I talked
about human beings being a really
complicated form of
bacteria. So, hey, you know,
I've had this idea a few times while
tripping and the inside tanks and even on
planes,
and I've had this feeling like if you
looked at the earth as a life force and
you look to human beings, you would,
you would say, well, that's a growth.
You would say, look, if it's,
it's everywhere. It's, it's,
it sucks all the fish out of the ocean,
it throws waste in there and kills all
the rest of the life. It fucks everything.
It touches it everywhere it lives.
There's brown smoke,
you burned down giant chunks of it.
It grows right back and even gets bigger.
It's like this is some crazy growth.
I'm like, if you didn't understand whom,
if we, you were so alien that human beings
were an identifiable as an individual,
you would,
you would look at them as a giant,
huge swarm of life on
top of this other life.
You wouldn't see individual people.
You would see it just like mold and I
said that maybe we're here to eat the
sandwich. Maybe we are like moldy sandwich
that maybe we're just a really super
complicated thing that's
here to fuck things up.
That's why at the pinnacle of Technology,
the the best we have to do is the
shit that fucks things up the most.
Like nuclear power,
nuclear waste, you know,
and and all sorts of other
crazy experiments that are
probably going on right
now that we're not even aware of.
Anti matter type shed.
They were there working on anti-matter
weapons and aunt in area 51 what does
that mean? I don't even know. I don't,
I don't even know, but it can't be good.
It's like what? Nuclear power
doesn't kill everybody quick enough.
You fuckhead you need to develop something
that kills everyone instantaneously.
We have enough bombs to blow up the
whole world, like how many times over?
And they'll like, yeah, but it doesn't do
it quite as good as I think can be done.
So they continue to make nuttier and
nuttier weapons. Do you see that? Uh,
the jet drone, Dave, uh,
developed the go something like 18 times
faster than the speed of sound. Right?
Some insane amount just to get over
there and fuck things up as quick as
possible.
We don't need any better weapons.
That's, you know, we have,
we have weapons that we don't even
have the first clue about now.
Well, it's what I've, but we
are nature as, as animals,
as an intelligent animals is to
keep trying to make things better.
It's like if we stopped right now
with cell phones and said, we good,
we good with this. We can talk, we
can taxed. This is good enough. Right?
Can we just stop right there? It
would. No one would take that.
People would go crazy. Four years from
now they'd be fucking so math or iPhone,
this fucking clunky old hunk of shit.
Why can't they have something better
than this now? People would be angry. We,
we have a deep desire for
technological innovation.
At the end of that is destruction
at the very peak of technology.
The best we're capable
of is blowing shit up.
It makes you wonder if that's
really what we're here for.
It makes you wonder if we are not some
weird technological caterpillar becoming
a butterfly and all of our desires and
ego and the need to get pussy and drive a
fast car.
All that shit really is just pushing
the society and the society is pushing
technology and technology.
One day someone's going to press a
fucking button and the whole thing.
She said,
now I'm not going to be so smiley anymore.
Maybe that's the way it's supposed
to be though. Well, my theory is,
my theory is that that's a no,
that that's,
that's how the universe gets born and
dies with us and that the Bang Bang.
It's really just a bunch of scientists
with autism on anti anxiety medication
and they make a big bang machine and
one of them presses it and the whole
universe starts all over again.
And it starts again with planets forming
and then life forms. And then dinosaurs.
Dinosaurs get hit by an asteroid
billions of years ago by the whole deal.
And then one guy presses a
button and a big bang machine,
he rigs boom and it starts all over again.
Why not if the unit,
if it's possible for the University
of the universe, that's possible too.
It's possible that it's just a bunch
of scientists with autism and every 14
billion years they blow the whole
fucking thing sky high and it starts from
scratch. Uh, well definitely.
Uh, we're going to have to eat,
drink and be marry them
because we're all going to,
that's what I'm talking about.
What do you think when you talk to these
people that are like, I mean for you,
you are a realist. You're a dude who's
seen the dark parts of the world.
When you talk to people and they,
you know,
they start hitting you with some fucking
power of positive thinking type shit
and hit you with the secret or Eckhart
toll and you know, he's like, do,
do you want to like when that holds
the secret thing was going on,
do you want to say, listen, you, you're
fucking environment is real. Okay.
You don't create it with your mind.
It's real.
There really are parts of the world
that sock and positive thinking he's not
going to get you out of Mogadishu.
Right.
Well we are in Pasadena. I mean like, you
know, positive thinking. Got You here.
Yeah. There you go. Uh, you know,
New York tends to be a bit more
cynical and la tends to be a bit more,
so whether, whether I'm pretty
girls, that's what it does.
It for real and space space.
Um,
the fact that it's not, you don't get
rained on hardly ever and it's never cold.
Right. That's huge. That east coast
winter thing is, that's bullshit.
That's retarded. Everybody
gets angry. Yeah. Your face
hurts that she has no good.
He get stuck on the highway. Every
gets stuck on the highway. Yeah,
the whole fucking highway shutdown
black ice. That's always fun.
That shit doesn't happen here.
It doesn't have in here at all.
So people were more relaxed.
It really is that plus the people
that landed on the east coast,
we're all animals who were so fucking
fed up with Europe that they on boats to
get on boats and they got them when
across an ocean before there was TV. Okay.
And they decided to move to
this new country that they
didn't ever probably even
have good pictures of.
You know,
someone just told them is a land of plenty
and they decided to get in a boat and
give it a shot.
Those people are psycho.
I mean those are some really
adventuresome fucking people.
Well those were the, those were the
first ones. Those were all adventuresome.
But the ones who said, okay,
you're going to go up that way.
We don't know how far it is and we
don't really know if you're going to get
there.
And by the way,
there's all kinds of tribes that are
going to try to scalp you and rape your
daughters and all this shit
as you go through there.
And there's mountains that are probably
impassable and you're gonna have to eat
your kids, go, go west. And,
and, and it was, it was,
when we say frontier, it was like the
frontier was, we don't know what's,
what's next. We don't know what's beyond
there. And so for those people to say,
I'm going to leave,
I'm like a Irish fucking potato picker.
And I lived in New York for
three years and that was no good.
So I'm going to go out and I'm just
going to go out into fucking absolute
wilderness where everyone hates me in
the animals and want to eat me and I'm
just going to keep going until I
hit the other ocean. That's crazy.
And it's amazing how quick it happened.
Yeah.
It was just like being know
a couple hundred years,
a giant fucking swarm of millions of
people had completely populated this one
continent that before that,
you know,
the last time people came
across here was the ice age.
There wasn't really a lot of human beings
live in the air when most people don't
know is in North America.
Just a little over 10,000 years ago,
half of it was covered by a mile of ice.
I mean,
wrap your head around a mile of fucking
ice above your head and that covered
half this country.
This is the,
this country that we don't understand
like the history of humanity in the world.
We have a very, um, patchy,
sort of a knowledge of
everything past the Ice Age,
everything about people 10,000
plus years ago. It's a lot of,
there's some bullshit,
there's a lot of bullshitting because
there's a lot of information they're not
willing to look at.
Some new stuff's coming along,
new construction that they've found
like in Turkey, this go Becky tap lead.
It's at least 14,000 years old.
Massive excellently cut stone columns,
civilization,
clear civilization back in a time where
they're attributing all that area only
as hunter and gatherers, there is
no civilization, there's no cities.
Where's the fucking city man you're
going to, you got to explain this.
Not only that, it has drawings up or
um, statues that are carved into it.
Like these three d images of animals
that don't even exist in that area,
that part of the world. So it's a, it's,
it's real possible that shit. Like,
you know,
the ice being over half of this
country that's moved around for tens of
thousands of years and there's probably
been these pretty kind of nifty
sophisticated civilizations,
but maybe they get to a point,
not even as far as we've gotten right now,
but maybe get to some previous point and
just implode like those crazy ass holes
in Pakistan or implode
like Nazi Germany or,
or implode like a million different
examples from Gingiss Khan to,
to, you know, to the Catholic Church,
look at all the crazy shit that's
gone on in this country. This, yeah.
It easily could be like that always.
And that we've gotten to these really
amazing Atlantean type civilizations and
just fucking chaos. Boom. Somebody
comes in strapped up, but Dynamo,
who the fuck knows and just
ace is the whole thing.
There's one part of the world somewhere
in the Middle East, I forget where it is,
where there's um,
they found glass in the desert.
They found like this area
in a satellite image,
kind of wish I had more information
about this from the tip of my tip of my
tongue, but the, the, it was either
some sort of an asteroid will impact,
or like hundreds of
thousands of years ago,
somebody had a fucking gigantic
explosion there, right?
Like if it was like some sort of
civilization and they flattened that
motherfucker out,
that's not outside the realm
of possibility that someone
figured out something,
some sort of massive way to
fuck things up, you know,
that we're the only ones that have ever
figured that out throughout history.
It's very possible that somebody else
might have time when we might've done this
whole dance to the top a couple of
times before tumbling. You know,
this is just the highest
we've ever gotten.
It kept it together very good at
destroying shit, that's for sure.
I've got this guy coming on June
7th for those of you who, uh,
been asking me about this, uh,
John Anthony West and uh, he's, uh,
this egyptologist who is a famous for
his work is uncovering the fact that
there's not just one each option
civilization that they're dealing with.
You're dealing with old,
older and older civilizations to
go back to 30 plus thousand years.
There's actual hieroglyphs that show
that each option civilization goes back
that far. Like they even named
the pharaohs, but for some reason,
modern day egyptologist have looked
at all this stuff and said that, well,
that's a myth.
Like everything was real up until about
5,000 years ago and all the rest of that
stuff is just, they just made
that shit up because it doesn't,
it doesn't coincide with our own ideas
of how long civilization has been around
for,
you know,
it just seems to me that when you look
at how sophisticated we are today and how
close we are to fucking it up and how
badly it is fucking up and all the places
in the world that you described,
it seems like the odds that
we haven't done this already,
like it just seems really small and I
think we've got a lot of Amnesia when it
comes to the past of, of, of humans.
And I think you also have to factor and
physical things that we can't control
like the earth volcanoes,
earthquakes,
sh asteroidal impacts shit like that.
You know, when I'm driving here today,
I was driving on the the
one 18 and it's beautiful.
You're going through the hills,
the mountains and I'm looking up and I'm
just saying it is amazing that we are
basically in the whole world
is a convertible, right?
There's no top and we're just,
we just sort of accepted that
we're just head to the universe,
just nothing but space and fucking giant
rocks can fall from the sky and crush
your country. And we've just sort
of completely forgotten about that.
I mean there's, there's impact
holes that you can visit. I mean,
if you look at the general life
of the university, you know,
the university being billions
of years old right now,
look at all the holes on
earth and then you just think,
how long have we been around? 4.6
billion years. How many holes are there?
This is going to happen again.
You motherfucker this,
we're forgetting that this shit happens.
Like there's hundreds of
thousands of them. You know,
there is biggest states and they're flying
through the air and they're going to
land and they're gonna fuck up everything
there. You're really depressing me.
You could throw that. No, it's not
bad, man. I think, I think if that's,
if we're going to go, that's,
that's a fucking amazing way to go.
That's going to be quick. It's going
to be quick and it's going to be crazy.
And you don't have to worry about
anybody suffering. You know,
it's like we're not afraid to sleep and
everybody's afraid to die and both of
them are inevitable. It's going to
happen. You're going to die on it.
It's not like we're going to live
forever. If he asked her, it doesn't come,
we're going to die. For sure. That
might be a crazy way to do it.
I'm not saying it's not saying it's good,
but might not be bad.
It might be the way it has to happen
for the next ultra intelligent thing to
come along.
That wouldn't have existed before.
The dinosaurs wouldn't have existed
before us. I mean, that makes sense.
I'd rather go out by an asteroid then
a series of sort of dirty bombs by some
sort of cult or religious terrorism.
Did you see the latest footage from Syria?
All the murdered children?
Yeah. What the fuck is going
on over there? Well, it's
the same thing. You know,
that that happened in Libya.
It's the same thing. You know,
that might happen in Egypt.
Um, you know when people fight,
it's the years you,
you know what you said about Vietnam,
don't they remember Vietnam?
And you know when you go to these places
and you see what injuries look like,
which are colostomy bags and you know,
legs that are gone and our arms are gone.
You say, well you know, why would you
ever do this again? And then you know,
generation forgets and then they
go do something else. Like go,
just go do it again.
How do we, how do we stop the cycle?
Is it possible without mushrooms?
I don't think so. I think it's
what I'm thinking. Asked for a tap
doing asteroids. I'd rather have
the asteroids to do it though.
We know the concept of asteroids
coming from machines. No, excuse me.
Mushrooms coming from asteroids,
asteroids coming from Russia.
Maybe the world comes from mushrooms.
Maybe getting to be a really trippy,
well this is a from Mckenna.
Mckenna is theory.
Well Panspermia is a real
theory of life right now.
The theory that amino acids and certain
nutrients and things and water in fact
comes from comets and asteroids and
that life is transferred from planet to
planet by Asteroidal impacts. This
is a legit scientific theory. Well,
Mckenna's theory about
silicide been was that suicide,
but it's completely alien to any other
form of life that we have here on earth.
There's nothing like it biologically
are biochemically, it's, I think it's,
I'm not, I'm not saying exactly right,
but I believe it's like four Fox for all.
Oxi Nn dimethyltryptamine.
It mimics the human
neurotransmitter dimethyl trip team,
which is a potent psychedelic drug.
It mimics that,
but it also has like phosphorus and the
four position, which apparently no other,
no,
no other compound on earth does.
And the idea is that spores can exist
in a vacuum and that spores could easily
have traveled through the vacuum and
the radiation of space and landed from
another planet here,
created this life form that wants you
to eat it so it pops up and looks like a
dinner plate and it pops up all
over the place. Everywhere you go.
It's not hiding it all.
And karmic.
It's literally at the bottom of
the food chain. It lives on shit.
It's just a humble little thing that
wants you to come along and eat it.
And when you eat it,
you're granted spectacular visions,
spectacular visions and feelings of love
and God and unity and the thoughts of
the universe being entirely connected
in one big mathematical equation,
computations and cells and organisms and
fucking all the way down to atoms and
subatomic particles and
then branching out again.
And all this shit comes from
something that grows out of shit.
All this shit comes from
something that comes from space.
And the idea is that our,
our concept of life and our concept
of intelligent is very narrow.
And we egocentrically have assumed
that all intelligence must be contained
inside a brain in some sort
of an intelligent upright
body that we can respect,
that's going to come here from another
planet and show us how to use a laser gun.
You know?
But in fact,
intelligence can exist in plant
form and that intelligence in, in,
in spectacular visions and,
and knowledge all comes out of a dimension
that you cannot access without these
molecules that exist in these plants.
And it opens literally
chemical doorways and the mind.
It's pretty fascinating idea. The fact
that, you know, that is alien invasion,
that mushrooms are an alien invasion.
I got to read this. Who's MCKENNA?
Terence Mckenna. He's a w who
is a crazy psychedelic chemist.
Slash botanist. Slash.
Uh, I think his degrees,
we're all in ethnobotany.
And his,
I think his main study of work was
the concept of the stoned ape theory,
um, that and his idea of
TimeWave zero, which would,
the idea was that time was like a
mathematical progression of waves and that
like a novelty and terrible
times would all just,
they were all almost be
predictable that you could,
it was some sort of a mathematical
equation or getting to infinite novelty,
which was like in this year supposedly,
really, which is probably horse shit. But,
uh, his other, the fascinating
theory was the mushroom theory,
the stoned ape theory.
And that was the theory that that's how
human beings actually evolved from lower
primates was the consumption
of psychedelic mushrooms
and his theory, actually,
I don't know if it's been supported
by a lot of different scientists.
I know there's some debate on whether or
not as timelines are right, but it's a,
based on the idea that
a bunch of monkeys ate some
mushrooms and then help them evolve.
It's interesting how many theories there
are about how he got from sort of that
to this.
Yeah. Well, it's crazy. You look at
it, we go to visit them in the zoo.
I took my kids to the zoo the other day
and I'm staring at my cousin's sure.
In a cage.
Well here in the home of Scientology,
you know,
they believe that the aliens came and
went into the monkeys and that's what we
are.
We're just vessels for alien souls.
Well, that's the sexiest idea.
Sexiest idea is the auto knocky stuff.
You know the stuff that we were
created by aliens and we were a genetic
engineering program and you know,
you look at like stuff on the Sumerian
texts from like 6,000 years ago that
depicts the Annunaki coming here.
And how do you not know that
that's not science fiction?
Maybe that's like their version of a
sure outer space or the outer limits or
something like that. Well it's, it's,
it's insane how many people are like
this was, this was how it happened.
It's aliens, mushrooms,
it's this, it's that. Well,
the weird thing is the doubling
of the human brain size.
I don't know what the fuck happened,
man.
I think it's probably a lack of
information more than it is a,
I think it can't just be mushrooms that
we did. We did. That would be amazing.
If it was like, oh you have to do is eat
mushrooms, your brain would just grow.
But we just got on mushrooms within a
hundred years we'd look like those gray
aliens.
Just giant heads.
We would need any muscles because we
would use our minds to control matter.
And we'd just be moving shit
around constantly with our minds.
I feel mushroom trip coming onto you think
so. I think I'm ready to do it today.
Or you got that. Um, you've got one
over here, man. You want a cigarette?
Um, that's going to fix today. I
was thinking how much I love you.
I hate cigarettes and I'm handing him,
I'm like, I just want you to like me.
I just want you to be
happy. Shane 11 to you're,
you're, you're blowing my mind today.
A lot of people on my mind, always,
a lot of people have been passing around
this, uh, speech that you gave at Africa.
It was some conference lately where
you were talking about the future of
television. Can you explain it? Because
I haven't actually watched it yet,
but I'm interested in what you yeah.
Um, it was a speech, uh, for
Internet week about, you know,
everyone's online versus versus cable.
And you know, what I was saying
was, so I didn't know what to do.
I didn't have uh, uh, anything
plan that was very smart. So I,
I was flying back actually
from Afghanistan, no,
it's finding back from Afghanistan and I
ducked into Pakistan to see the garage.
He shoots,
it was flying back from Pakistan and I
was thinking about all the kids that I
had seen who are going insane
and who were, you know,
the guys who would kill for 10 bucks
and this is fucking crazy fucking dudes.
And I was like, look, the
youth everywhere in, in,
in Asia and Africa and Europe here,
everyone's fucking revolting.
But what, what we making like,
so when I went to do the upfront,
which is where all the TV shows get sold
and online shows get sold and you have
like, the voice was just, which is the
biggest show, which is just American idol.
It now TV is derivative of TV.
TV is just making shittier and
shittier shows based on itself.
And then the on the Internet,
which could be this,
it could be revolutionary because it's
better because you can be watching
something,
been text somebody and then
get information than Google
this and fucking what's
it going on here and here.
And instead of trying to be and
say what the fuck is going on.
And by the way,
young people are revolting all
around the world and they want the,
this is how they get their news now.
They get it through blogs and
online shit here and there.
They don't even watch TV anymore.
But instead of doing something innovative
and challenging and revolutionary,
we just do shittier versions of TV shows
with half the budgets. And so it's,
the city sort of Google says,
you know what really pisses
me off is Dah, Dah, Dah.
It's like America's funniest home videos
with a, with a sort of annoying host.
And you're like, why don't we,
why don't we use the internet?
Why don't we use, you know, the, the,
the social networks and you know,
video and all this stuff we can do now
to actually do something that's good and
revolutionary and start changing shit.
Because when he asks and says, well,
how do we fucking stop all this shit?
Well,
the first way you stop about it is
it stop. It is to find out about it.
So we have to know about it and then we
know about it. And then we can do shit.
Like we can not buy certain things,
you know, dollar advocacy. You know,
consumer advocacy is the most
powerful tools we have, et Cetera,
et cetera. But the first of
all is knowing about it. And,
and so I just sort of got really pissed
off that the Internet has become so
derivative and so shitty and just
trying to mimic TV interviews shit.
So let's try to fucking make something
that actually people understand where the
people, like whether people use
that helps people or, or, or,
or they understand of shit. Like, for
example, like Kony 2012 you're like,
what's it shows that it's viral shows
that people actually want to know this
shit and shows it. But like it was, it was
okay. Like it was this sort of half ass.
What did you think about that
whole situation? I mean that,
that is another example of one of the
reasons why I believe that life is a work
of fiction.
A fucking guy decides that he's going
to make this viral video against James
Kone
whack, whack, whack in it. Oh,
is that his name's Charles.
Connie James [inaudible].
He's going to make this viral video,
expose the world to this horrible person,
but they're getting a disproportionate
amount of the money goes to them and then
they get accused of being unscrupulous,
whatever the words would use to, they
didn't do anything illegal. They just did.
They're a little funky with the money.
Then the guy shows up naked in the
streets, beating off acting gang.
Did you see in the video?
Yeah. Uh, that's like craziness.
Like, well, they didn't,
I'm sure they didn't think they went
through these kids that go over and they
shot it Fairfox to him. You know, I've
been there. It's a bad part of the world.
And, and you know what, it's
interesting on a few points.
One because it shows that the fucking
like everyone, kids don't care.
People don't care about
anything outside of America.
Like it's a big in media that I would
say don't do anything outside of America.
People just don't give a shit about it.
Well I think it shows that people
do give a shit about it and,
and these guys weren't expecting it.
That become a huge thing and you know,
so obviously when weird shit happens to
you, you have different ways of coping.
The Sky Cope by going fucking
go see,
which actually seems appealing sometimes.
Like when life's really hard,
you're just say,
I'm going to take off my fucking clothes.
There's fucking serial killers and
assassins everywhere. I've just,
I'm going to get your flashlight.
Fucking that guy was
on the street in his underwear.
He got naked.
He was like a flailing his arms around it.
And acting like Super Gay.
Yes.
I wonder what he was on.
What makes the act gay besides being
yeah, mostly Cox balls, booty hoes,
red band flashlights. What is a well,
yeah, Cody. I mean the thing is, is it,
it became huge and I think it shows
that there's a massive audience anyway.
So it was possible. Yeah.
And the whole thing is,
is let's make shit that actually isn't
shit. Let's make stuff that, you know, uh,
is telling the stories. And so that's what
we're doing. And I said, you know, look,
if,
if it's vice who's doing it,
then we're really in fucking trouble
because I didn't come up with any sort of
save the World Cup.
Yeah. But you're not compromised
yet. And as a human being,
when you gotten to the point
where you see this information,
you're not compromised.
So you're releasing it and you're focusing
on it and you have an honest died for
what?
Well, it's also when we went around
the world and expanded the company,
you just see all this shit happening
and you're like, what the fuck?
Why isn't anybody fucking
saying this shit? And then,
but, but I always say that,
look, if we're, if we're a new source,
then it's the world's in trouble because
we were a style mag, you know, we all,
we gave a shit about what's fucking, you
know, famously say, you know, cocaine,
supermodels,
rare denim and sneakers.
And then when you go around the rest of
the world, you're like, holy fucking shit.
And you sort of, you know, come
out of the pond and go, okay,
well we gotta do something.
Well, I think that's probably, they're
here to get you. You got enough. I think,
you know, the only way journalists ever
become journalists in the first place,
they feel they have something that
they feel needs to be sad, right?
They have this desire to,
to send a message.
And that comes from seeing
things that are wrong.
Seeing things that need to be reported
on, things that you know, and,
and it turned you into a journalist.
I mean,
essentially the reality of
the world turned you into
a journalist and you're the
perfect example of what a journal is
should be because you're not compromised
because you can do these stories
and you can, you can, I mean,
if you had someone overseeing you,
someone from NBC or CBS, do you,
what do you think you could've
gotten any of this stuff done?
Well,
if you said to them,
Hey,
I'm going to go to Pakistan and I'm gonna
meet with the Taliban, I don't think,
yeah, we wouldn't be allowed to, to do
a lot of this stuff that
we do because we just,
we just go in and get permits.
You guys just go,
don't generally don't get permits.
You asked for the people,
if you could put them in
a movie on television,
the people that they sign anything,
they signed things.
But people generally want
to tell their stories.
But I mean ask government permission
or police permission or all you know,
the things you're supposed to or also,
um,
you're generally supposed
to go with security teams
and we're like what do I did
a security team wants, cause we
were doing a show with MTV and um,
they made us get one in Beirut and I'd
been to Beirut like 20 times if they were,
it's not that bad sometimes and
parts of it are bad, but, and,
and we were walking target cause you
just have all these dudes like talking.
And so I said I'm never going to have
security ever again because that's the
sure way that you're not going to get a
story or the real people aren't going to
talk to you or everyone's going to
think what, who are the fuck these guys?
So we go and you just, you just,
we call it immersion as them,
you just go immerse yourself,
you know, in, in, in the
place. And then just, you know,
press record,
don't go in with any sort of preconceived
ideas or notions or political
paradigms or I'm going to
prove this because generally
you're not going to prove
that. Like for example, if
you went to Somalia and said,
I'm going to prove that these guys
are barbarians pirates and you know,
then you're going to shut yourself off
to exactly what you said, which is,
well actually we illegally irradiated
their whole coast and illegally over
fished it so that there are
starving and they're like, well,
we're going to tax the,
the people who did this to it.
Yeah.
They're called the people's coast guard.
That with voluntary coast guard of
Somalia, they call themselves. Yeah.
What the fuck man, dude, if anybody
knows how to fix this, it's, you know,
you see it all. I think
it's the Internet. Yeah.
Well he's the only hope we have the
Internet and technology. The technology,
like what you were saying about pulling
carbon out of the atmosphere and
cleaning the air and reusing the fuel
they're using. That makes sense. I mean,
if technology can put it out
there, it seems like, you know,
we should be able to harvest it. Maybe
not now, maybe a hundred years from now,
whenever the fuck it
actually becomes viable.
Well, somebody asked me at Internet week,
the guy said, well, what if I'm not angry?
You know,
I'm whatever,
22 and I'm not angry and I want
to go get an Mba and make money.
And I said, great. You know,
I think that that there was the sort
of our grandparent's generation that,
that, you know, were, they
didn't know better. So they
were like, oh, space, age, food,
you know,
the TV dinners and produce all the food.
Let's make it all with computers
or whatever. Not Assembly lines.
And so it started to be bad for us,
you know, and started to, you know,
all these things, Agent Orange, let's,
you know, do all these terrible things.
But they didn't know any better.
The technology was sort of their savior.
But the baby boomers,
you know,
they were the first generation that
knew better but still became the largest
energy consumers, the largest
garbage producers, all this thing.
Gen X has sort of slipped by.
But guess what,
the bills here and it's going to be Gen
y like they have to pay. There is no,
there is no get out of jail free card now.
So as you're seeing economically and
socially and culturally and politically
that we're shifting and if you,
if you just want to sort of say,
I'm going to stick my head in the sand,
which we've done for a little while,
I don't think you're going
to be able to anymore.
I agree with you. And I agree that
with that things are shifting.
And I also think that that's why these,
uh,
attacks on the constitution had been
permitted in and are being pushed through.
I think they've,
uh,
they've seen the prognosis and they've
seen the future and the future is the
trends that we see on the Internet.
And it's a trend towards a more
libertarian line of thinking.
It's a trend towards a smaller government,
more accountability, less bureaucracy.
The idea of creating jobs doesn't mean
you create some new fucking laws that
you'd have to saddle everybody with and
a bunch of people to enforce those laws.
And that's what they,
a lot of these politicians like to think
of as creating jobs. You know, it's not,
gee,
you're creating problems
and you constantly keep
attacking the constitution and
pulling amendments apart and,
and really defacing the whole idea
what this country was founded on.
They're doing it just because they
sensed the future and the future is not,
it's not, it's not going to work
the way it works now. It's just not,
we're not going to deal with this whole
idea of representative government and
we're not going to deal with special
interest groups. That shit is nonsense.
That's gotta go away.
Yeah.
I think if you look at,
at what's happening too is if
you look at Syria, for example,
if you look at, at what happened
in Egypt or, or Libya, you know,
I spent a lot of time in those
countries just before the revolution.
I got arrested and in Libya. And
then when I went back, you know,
and I said it, you know, I would
have never called this, you know,
not a lot of people did.
I would've,
I would've said the opposite because
it was so restrictive and it was so
hardcore and everyone was so pro regime.
But because of the Internet,
because of Twitter,
because of Facebook
resolve these social tools,
you had all these young people
able to communicate and say,
actually I'm pissed off too. Oh you're,
oh, we're all fucking pissed off. Hey,
let's change.
And I think that you know that that change
isn't going to be pretty in a lot of
cases and it's going to be problematic.
But you do have young people who are
taking up arms and now you also have young
people who were just smashing the shit
out of cities like they did in Paris and
especially in London last summer.
But you know what happens when,
when you know,
occupy Wall Street becomes Egypt,
you know,
to try to smash the status quo.
What happens when occupy Wall Street
becomes Syria or it becomes Olivia and you
know, it's, it's not in the foreseeable
future maybe, but I couldn't,
I didn't call Libya or Egypt or Syria
either. You know, there's a lot, a lot of,
of, of unrest out there and there's a
lot of people communicating that unrest.
And in fact, if you see that in America,
it's growing and that if I was, uh,
you know, campaigning this summer,
then I would be focusing on, oh,
we have a huge fucking groundswell and
a global groundswell of dissatisfaction
with the only group that's actually going
to get off their ass and do something
about it.
You must have
at least some emotional attachment to
Julian massage and the wikileaks case.
Um, when you see this, uh, this case and
is Bradley Manning Kid this, this, uh,
who's, I believe it's still in
solitary confinement. Yeah. Um,
I don't even know if he, does he have
a court date? I mean, I dunno, but, uh,
they just lock this kid in a box,
cut him off from humans until he's got,
I'm sure he's completely
crazy at this point.
I don't think you can not go crazy in
solitary confinement for five years. Yeah.
Well it just shows that
conspiracy theorists aren't crazy.
You're not crazy at all. The
majority of, of of these are,
are, are proof that there are, you know,
very sorted and unseemly
things going on every day.
100%. And the, the information that that
guy released alone makes him a hero.
That guy release things
that are anti American.
He released things that are their
war crimes. He saw war crimes.
We're not war criminals or
Americas where American,
this is how I'm most proud Americans
feel we're American and we're not cunt.
That's it. We don't take any
bullshit, but we're not cuts that,
that's when you get a guy who feels that
and he's an American and he's a soldier
and he wants to, you know,
look, he's a voluntary soldier,
signed up to represent this government
and he sees his government doing horrible
shit that's not being reported.
It's being covered up.
Covering shit up when you do crimes
is not how crimes get resolved.
What's it not?
When did tell him the truth and and um,
keeping governments and big business
and check become anti America.
The guy's a goddamn patriot patriot
and he's locked in a box and then Julia
Sanje gets in trouble. This wiki
leaks thing is so fascinating, man.
People were accusing me of getting my
information wrong, but no, he's in jail.
He's not even accused of rape. He's
accused of having sex without a condom.
I wasn't lying. He apparently, you know,
they were sleeping together and he
stuck it in this chick. I don't know.
I don't know the fucking full story,
but the bottom line is that's why
they're trying to export this guy.
Like if that's not the craziest thing,
you were going to regulate
voluntary sexual, it'd be
two people are naked in bed.
We're going to decide what didn't,
didn't happen between a guy and a girl
and you're going to spend that much
fucking money to monitor this guy and
make sure he checks in constantly.
And this is what he's put videos
online of his, his daily routine.
He has to drive to the police station
and check in before he can do things. He,
it's under house arrest.
The whole thing is madness.
Well the thing is is the fact that they
keep going on on the story and saying,
yeah,
we don't want them for actually blowing
the whistle on every crime that's been
going on in the government. We want
them for this sort of weird, you know,
quasi thing that happened in Sweden
that wouldn't be considered anything
anywhere else.
Well yeah. What did I think someone
described it as surprise sex.
Like that's not it.
It's not even rape.
Technically it's like they had had
consensual sex with a condom and then they
were lying in bed. I don't
know. The fuck really happened,
so I shouldn't even be saying this,
but the idea that they're,
they're wasting so much resource on a
sexual issue, that's even a violent one.
Not even rape,
but it's kind of smart actually because
it's, for example, it's, you know,
it's the one thing that you,
you know, you can't say,
well they just drummed it up and it's
bullshit. And another, because yeah,
well rape is very serious. It's the
worst of the worst. So you're in,
you're in a catch 22 of saying,
well they just drummed it up to get
this guy for blowing the whistle.
But yet at the same time they drummed up
the one thing that you're sort of taboo
to go again.
It's the number one thing.
Yeah. And, but they didn't,
they couldn't even get a good version
of it. I mean, no, the story is so weak.
If it was,
you know,
he roof her and he did this and he tied
her up and took pictures and we have the
pictures. Oh well the guy's obviously a
con that released important information.
But I think the sad thing about
it is that you look at, you know,
deep throat, you know, who you know,
just announced to he was and all this
stuff and he did it just to save the
government. And all that stuff.
He's a hero. Right? Right. And, and
well, it depends on who won.
You know, Bradley Manning
could come out to be a hero.
Julian Assange's can come out to be a
hero if there was some crazy revolution in
the future.
You know,
we realize that this is where the
turning point of American society,
when they said, we're not going
to take this bullshit anymore.
When they watch that collateral
murder video and realize who do,
what are we doing to our children? We're
forcing them to even think like that.
So this is it.
This is acceptable.
This is if this one shot at life and
this is how you're going to spend some of
your time shooting missiles down and
innocent people wandering through the
street.
Well,
what my question is,
when did it change from
journalism and the fourth estate?
It's job being to make sure that
politicians weren't lying to make sure the
corporations weren't doing these bad
things and want to gate changed it. Right.
Well,
I think actually distribution I think
changes it because for companies run all
news media and they're all major
global corporations at all have huge
advertising. And so they're conflicted
and they don't go after politicians.
And I remember during the the Iraq war,
you know,
people knew that there were, you
know, that this was all a construct.
They knew that there weren't
more weapons of mass destruction.
They knew that everyone was used to joke.
I used to hang out with other
journalists and they'd say, of course,
I mean alcaide is, is the
opposite of, of the bath party.
How far do you take that?
How far do you take the
whole idea of conspiracy?
I Dunno if it's, it's, it's,
it's certainly a conspiracy
I think. Yeah, for sure.
But that's been admitted to now.
And, and I think that the, the, the,
because of nine 11 the Prescott co-opted
and it became an American to say
anything bad about the
government or the military.
And I think that that is,
that is,
was one of the sort of turning points,
a, because that's bullshit. And B,
because young people got
completely disenfranchised
by the news media because we
saw it all happens. You say, wait
a minute, this doesn't sound right.
And then afterwards they're like, yeah,
there was no weapons of mass destruction.
Yeah, there was no car of here. And
you're like, well, but we knew that,
but we kept saying it.
The news media became part of a government
propaganda program and everybody just
went along with it.
And that's fucking scary because no
matter who's in government, you know,
if they can just put together a
propaganda, how is that different than,
you know, than Nazi Germany?
How is it that different than,
than any of these totalitarian
regimes where they say,
yes, you know, uh, you know,
Camille Song is God or whatever.
Like how is that any different?
Because you can use the
fourth estate as you. Yeah.
Pr Agency. Well, there was, we,
CIA released some sort of a state and
right after the war with Iraq and started
that, they were going to start releasing
fake stories to throw off the enemy.
And once, once he admitted to doing
something like that, that's it.
Incredibly slippery ground.
Like that's the only way to defeat the
enemy as you have to put out fake stories
and lie to everyone and we're
supposed to give you that power.
Like what kind of checks and balances
are in place before that stuff gets
distributed? What do you know
what the fuck is going on here?
Well it's also, you know, Memorial Day
and you said it exactly right is that,
you know, what are we
doing sending, you know,
going in with what's our
mission to go into Afghanistan,
what's our mission and what we haven't
mentioned? Okay, that Taliban, Taliban,
Taliban, okay, now we're letting the
Taliban in because well we've lost.
We're saying, okay, well we have to have
power sharing with them. And so you say,
well everybody knows it's going to go
right back to civil war. So you're like,
well why did we come here? Why did
we do all this? Like what the fuck?
So you don't think that it's some sort
of a grand conspiracy to extract minerals
and all that stuff.
You think it's much more of a cluster
fuck shit decision by government and then
being in place because of momentum and
because of the fact there's contractors
and they all want to keep getting paid.
Resource Wealth for sure. And it was
the, it was the story that, you know,
we broke in Sudan that time,
you know,
Darra for as oil and resource wealth.
You know, we did it in the Congo,
we've done it in a lot of
stories all over the place.
I wouldn't say I would say they got
caught in the quagmire of Afghanistan,
much like the Soviets did.
They went in there,
they were trying to do something and
they just got sucked in and then it got
worse and worse and worse and
worse and worse and look it guts.
It's so bad on every level.
I mean America is in there trying to
fight this war on drugs, war on drugs,
war on drugs.
They've been in there 12 years.
There's never been more heroin for
cheaper or higher quality ever. In fact,
it's so good that they put the
golden triangle out of business.
It's all coming from Afghanistan.
And so America is the biggest drug
dealer in the world because we're just
sitting there running this country
that just ships out all the heroin
in the world. How much of a
piece does the CIA have of that?
Who knows? I would say
that, you know, look at,
it's been documented that they
were part of the original, uh,
outflux into America from Vietnam
during the Vietnam War. Um,
as a way to keep urban populations
sort of at bay. Um, that's,
that was like a real social experiment.
They would bring heroin into the
ghetto to real. That's, that's,
that's well documented. Yeah. But is
it well documented the intentions?
Yeah, because there was civil unrest
in the major urban center, so they,
they allowed heroin to go in because
it took away all sort of, well,
everything comes up. Heroin
Addiction. So I mean,
if it's been a part of
their policy in the past,
obviously they're going to be
incredibly sensitive to it.
But I don't think that you can say that
they're not involved or at least the
State Department is not
involved because the, uh,
statistics speak for themselves.
There's two times more
by a factor of two,
so 100% more heroin addiction.
Heroin addicts in America since the start
of the Afghani war and heroin's never
been cheaper.
It's never been better quality and
we've been running it so like it's,
it's just flooding out to destroy the,
you know Russia is now,
I've got 7% in Pakistan,
which is a Muslim country.
Extremist Muslim country has something
like 12% in, in Karachi anyway,
a heroin addiction and it's just,
it's flooding out of
Afghanistan and that's we,
we have gone in and taken all
the fields that we didn't,
well not only did we not take the
fields now we guarded them. Syria. Yeah,
definitely.
Most people want to come up with some
sort of crazy explanation or excuse for
why they did that.
It's because
fear that they're going to, it's the
only way they're really making money.
They're making money two ways, which is
the American government and, and heroin.
And so they're like, well if we really,
if we take away the heroin production,
then they're really going to hate us.
Do they, does any of that stuff make
its way in pharmaceutical grade? Uh,
opiates like oxycodone,
things along those lines.
Zero knows.
I don't know.
I all I know is like every time
we do a story on the heroin, uh,
situation in Afghanistan is fucking
shocking because you're just like the
Americans let them and there's actually,
you know,
pictures of American troops guarding poppy
to this is
the war on drugs sort
of except over there,
over there were a war
against the war on drugs.
Do you see the war on
drugs in Afghanistan?
And then you see the war on drugs
in Mexico. You're like, wow.
Well it's completely corrupt
from start to finish.
There is this war on drugs is completely,
what's the craziest slippery war ever
when you use the war on drugs and then you
have armed fold soldiers, gardening,
hobby fields, what side are you on?
And this war on drugs, cause it seems
like you're on the pro drug side,
you're guarding the drugs.
Like,
how could you have a war on
drugs when you're carting,
they dry and you're sending
all the weapons to Mexico
and they need and all the
money and you don't
even go to jail for it.
And 90 what was the amount? 90% plus
of the heroin comes out of Afghanistan.
And what did you say about how much would,
how much is the percentage of an increase?
Since we have occupied
just in America it's doubled, but
that's just in America. But in, in,
in Russia it's gone through the roof.
It's the doubled in UK,
but Russia and Pakistan in the
Middle East, countries like Iran,
everywhere on the path has just
heroin addictions or has soared.
In fact, heroin addiction
is so huge. And Russia,
did you see the thing we did on Crockett
fuck man
to,
to heroin,
that if they then when they can't get it
or because it got expensive now because
so many people are buying it that they
make their own synthetic heroin and uh,
and it's called Krokodil because it makes
you look like a crocodile because it
makes your skin like scales.
And then the scales fall off and
you just have like bone there.
It's insane.
If you haven't seen it,
if you haven't seen the images
online of people that are addicted,
that have that, it's incredible. It's
so frightening. It's frightening.
It's so frightening that people
would do that to themselves.
Literally shoot drugs that make
my skin rot and fall off the bone.
He's not exaggerating.
There's like people with big,
their arms have like big gaping.
See the bone,
you see the bone and they can walk
around. They're not even infected. Well,
some of it, yeah, some of them get
infected. It was weird. It looked like,
like it was burnt off,
like it was like fused kills all
the flesh and it falls off Christ.
That's insane. And what happens
then? They just die. I mean,
you can't just have your bones
just exposed like that. Right.
Does it ever fill up if you quit?
No. I don't know the answer. Does
anybody ever get off that shit? It's,
it's even more addictive than heroin.
So
that you guys had that shit about the
Colombian drug that you're blowing
people's faces. Yeah. That is
terrifying. Whether the free freaky
thing about Skubala mean is you don't
believe it's true until you see it.
Because the stories are, it's
the Zombie drug, right? And it's,
we heard stories of,
you know,
people coming into their apartments on
the security cameras and like clearing
out their whole apartments and you'd
see them on security cams doing it,
you know, and, and they don't have any
recollection. They wake up in the morning,
their bank accounts are
drained, et Cetera, et cetera.
And they couldn't figure it
out until they, the FARC,
the guys who were Colombians
who are making a cocaine,
we're using the same process to refine
born Dango flowers to makes cupola mean.
And what was happening with generally,
it started out as hookers and hookers
would put a condom inside their mouth
right there.
So we can go down and then they put a
little sick Apollo mean in their lips.
And then when they go to like kiss you
whenever they go and they would spit
because Coppola Peter the, you inhale
it and then you think you go, Holy Shit,
that's scary.
And then you go into this trance like
state and then it's auto suggestion.
So you, you say, okay, we're going
to go down to your apartment. Yes.
And we're going to go to the apartment
and then we're going to clean out all
your shit and we're going to go
to your bank and we're going to,
and they have security footage of them
going to the bank and signing shit.
And it's not like one or two people. This
is like happens all the fuck. Oh my God.
And so, uh, it's it, that's a
fucking terrifying drug. Terrifying.
Cause you're just gone,
you're in a sort of Zombie like narcotic
state and you just do what people tell
you to.
That's the real ultimate date rape
drug. Yeah. That's the real shit.
So we gotta make sure people
don't get ahold of that.
That's a life rate dating one
of those girls. Oh my God.
Someone spit something in your mouth.
Either Zombie,
those girls have to be on date ago.
There's no way you can date that guy.
What a girl that would do
that to somebody. Like,
if you knew that's what she did as a job
and then you ever got in a fight with,
I get all these tricks.
She was a hooker. I know.
Imagine dating one of those hooker girls.
That's just me.
I'm silly though. Especially ones that
take over your brains. Absolutely.
Shit like that.
Why would that exist?
Why would there be something that allows
you to be turned into a fucking Zombie
to someone else's suggestions like that?
You know,
when you see the different
things in nature,
like different parasites to
control different organisms
and make them do fucked
up things. And it really is kind of
bizarre when you stop and think about it.
I'm like,
what kind of a system?
What kind of a world that we
live in where there's like,
there's that land around a plant plant
that grows and if he gets into your body,
people just already around you don't have,
that's crazy.
You become a fucking robot. You become
an automated little slave for them.
Drugs or drugs are crazy.
We just did a story on,
you probably know a lot more about it
than I do, but uh, I have a game of yeah.
And we were doing a story
on the underground heroin
clinics where, you know,
people,
uh,
like it's actually started by a lot of
ex junkies who were like 40 year junkies.
I couldn't get off, tried, you know,
hundreds of times to get
cleaned and they would do,
I have a game and then it
interrupts your addiction, you know,
for like two weeks or whatever. So it's
long enough that you sort of get a,
you know, you don't have
to go cold Turkey. And uh,
so we went to these clinics where
they administer, I began and stuff.
It was fucking fascinating. It
was crazy. Did you do it? No,
because I saw them do
it and it's, they, they,
they were taking massive doses so
they were there taking like 48 hours.
Lots of vomiting like
crazy.
If I have a couple of friends that have
done in one that did it recently in one
that it changed his whole life.
I have a buddy of mine,
he got his back on injured, got
hooked on pain pills, right. Pain,
pain pills started, uh, taking,
you know, the Nate, you name him.
He was taking them and he couldn't get
off them. How's it was ruining his life.
Goes Down, gets an IB game,
boom. Clean hundred percent.
Now brings people down there,
started his own center down there,
brings people down there to uh,
to introduce them to Mexico.
But I'm like a fucking Mexico man.
Mexico. Scary as fuck. Well, they,
it's because it's still legal there. It's
illegal here. It's a schedule one drug.
Just like heroin. Well, everything in
Mexico is decriminalized now. Right?
They di Di. Most people don't know.
They didn't, they decriminalized acid,
mushrooms, pot coke, everything to
fight the cartels. Correct. Exactly.
But yeah, I have a game that's the, yeah,
that's the strongest drug I've ever seen.
Like, because people under it, we're like,
holy fuck. Yeah, my business partner.
Did it change his life? Well,
he's just done a couple of times.
He's done a couple of different
things, right? It changes lives. Done.
Iowasca know I began,
he's really into going to these
weird places and going on big trips.
But the Ibogaine is,
is interesting cause we follow some junky
straight through the whole process and
it was pretty remarkable because
it work. Like, yeah, it's nuts.
Yeah. Um, oh, I'll bring my friend
who's done it. He, uh, you know,
he described the process and I
didn't want to do it even slightly.
It sounded like hell yeah.
Like, you know, you can,
you can talk me into doing some DMT.
Maybe it's 15 minutes and I'll send you
the piece. There's so much vomiting.
It's fucking crazy. Days of vomiting
that cannot be good for you.
Well,
you gotta think don't matter if
someone's hooked on heroin, anything,
they'll take anything
to get them out of that.
I've watched people slip into addiction
several times in my life and it's,
it's just like being turned by a vampire.
It really is.
It's a feeling that you've lost
someone there. They're slipping away,
they're slipping away from themselves,
from their family, from everybody.
They're slipping away because of a
compound, some sort of a chemical.
It's really what a bizarre thing that we
have. This, this, this addiction quality,
you know,
always say something.
The piece we say that this mother gives
her son to these sort of New York fruit
cakes. Nice guys. But like weird guys
who do sort of west African Voodoo,
uh, you know, when they,
when they administer the Ibogaine and
we were taking your son to Mexico,
to one of these clinics because we
couldn't legally do it in America.
So he brought the whole crew down to
Mexico to shoot it. And it was like,
how bad is heroin that a mother
is going to give her son to these,
you know,
crazy west African Voodoo shonky dudes
to take off to Mexico and administer the
strongest drug in the world too.
So he's going to puke and fucking go nuts
for two days. That's how bad heroin is.
Okay.
And that's what the government
sells that, that, that uh,
America,
listen man,
let's wrap this up and let you get some
sleep. All right? You're the fucking man,
dude. Anytime you want to do this.
Anytime you're in town, you, uh, you,
you got to an open invite.
We'll,
we'll open this pitch up at four
o'clock in the morning for you.
Whatever you want, man,
you're fucking awesome. Um,
continued safety and success in your
travels and thanks for illuminating giant
parts of the world that I
personally wouldn't have not,
I wouldn't have been aware of. It wasn't
for you and what you guys are doing.
You're fucking awesome man. Thanks buddy.
Good you, you're saying? All right,
my friends.
Thank you everyone for tuning in.
This week we got tomorrow a Mike
Dolce famed MMA nutritionist.
Uh, he's going to come in
and then a Wednesday bobcat
Goldthwait is coming in. So,
uh, we've got a fun pack date
fall Shane on, on Twitter.
It's Shane Smith 30 on Twitter and a thank
you to the fleshlight for tuning into
our podcast. If you go to Joe rogan.net,
click on the link for the fleshlight.
Enter in the code name Brogan
and you'll save yourself 15% off.
Thanks to on at.com. Uh, all
the other stuff. O n n I t.com,
the Oh stuff that we've been talking about
kettlebells. It's all coming soon. Uh,
the hemp protein,
which is fucking delicious.
And that stuff's so good and it doesn't
fuck with me as much as way does hemp
protein is delicious and the
stuff we have is Maka in it. Ah,
raw cocoa and um, it's, it's
sweetened, went by Stevia.
So it's really healthy for you.
It's a,
and it's the best tasting
shit I'm telling you.
It's like my favorite all time protein
powder that's coming out soon to go to
[inaudible] dot com enter
in the code named Rogan.
Save yourself 10% off any and all orders
and any bottle of 30 pills that you
buy,
no matter what it is,
you have a 100% money back
guarantee on the first order.
You do not even have
to return the product.
You just say this stuff sucks and
you get 100% of your money back.
The reason why we're telling you that,
the reason why we give it to you that way
is because these are all good products.
They're, they're solid.
They're, they're based on,
on strong sound knowledge of nutrition.
And I believe in him 100% use a code name,
Rogan,
save yourself 10% off and we'll
see you dirty pitches tomorrow.
Thanks for everything we love you guys.