And Five,
four,
three,
two.
Yes.
How are you sir?
Good,
thanks.
Thanks for being here,
man.
Um,
I wanted to ask you this because I was
reading this today and I started to
freak out a NASA is planning on drilling
into yellowstone.
Okay.
To save the world.
I didn't know about this.
You know,
about the relieving pressure.
What are they doing?
Yes.
Yeah,
there's the practice.
We're talking about chiropractors for
the startup folks.
Uh,
I think they plan on like a,
you know how like if you have like a
giant cyst and you sort of make a slice
in it,
you can kind of squeeze everything out
of there.
Let's see a doctor do that.
I've seen doctors do that.
I've never seen this.
I do this.
I have no idea NASA wants to send
through.
NASA wants to spend $3,000,000,000
drilling into a volcano to save the
United States and a presumably a large
chunk of the world to write because
there would be some sort of a nuclear
winter type scenario where the guys
would be covered with.
This is not your area of expertise and
sorry to throw this out,
I wonder,
I wonder about the providence of this,
but you know,
uh,
these are things that,
it's some people's areas of expertise,
but no one has figured everything out,
right?
Like we don't know all the forces that
are pushing around to make volcanoes and
earthquakes,
stuff like that.
So back to that picture.
Look at this picture.
That picture freaks me out.
I think it's realistic.
Yeah.
Every six to 800,000
years,
that thing.
Blow Sky High.
Microsoft paint version of geophysics.
Yeah.
It's from like a geocities site from
1994.
Yeah.
Well,
here's the thing,
they have to think about it,
right?
If he keeps this up close to you.
Sure,
yeah,
yeah.
Pull it.
We,
uh,
there's all sorts of disasters that
could happen to us that we don't really
plan for because human lifetimes,
a hundred years.
Technology is a few hundred years,
but maybe there are disasters that
happen every thousand or 10,000
years and they could be very bad.
I think solar flares are the one to
really worry about it because that what
you you're concerned with,
it's not my pressure professional
concern,
but I was once sitting next to a hot
shot lawyer who had just been finished a
visiting Washington DC to campaign for.
We got to start hardening up the
electrical grid because one kind of
solar flare that he says happens every
thousand years could wipe out
electricity in the United States or the
world for weeks or months.
Millions of people would die,
right?
So a few billion dollars and we can
harden it and fix things,
but who's going to spend a few billion
dollars for something that happens once
every thousand years?
Isn't that the issue?
It's like even with preventing asteroids
or doing something to avoid collisions.
It's right now we don't have an issue,
so we have other things to worry about.
We have a terrible president.
We have a global warming.
We have this,
we have that.
There's always something that keeps us
from being rational about the future.
Yeah,
that's right.
And with the good news with asteroids is
that there's other good reasons to look
at this guy and map things.
Right.
So the what astronomers are doing are
piggybacking asteroid mapping strategies
off of things they can actually get
money for it.
Right?
Because yeah,
no one is going to pony up that much
money to look at the asteroid.
Why would think that that would be like
a really good use of money?
Like let's,
let's keep an eye on the rocks that
might kill everything you would think
that everyone would say for their
retirement and so forth.
Right.
This avilia planning for the future,
not what we have all four.
Well that's a big ability.
I mean that's a big plan for the future
that,
I mean literally you're talking about
like it wasn't there one that just whiz
by that was three miles wide.
Yeah.
But was by means.
It was something like eight times as far
away as the moon.
Was that what it was?
Yeah.
This is not.
There's the chances of an asteroid even
will be very bad.
The chances of a bad one or are much
smaller than some of these other thing.
You don't come from me.
Alright.
For Comfort,
I hear the truth is I take the comfort
as you will,
but isn't there like there's a lot of
areas they can come from like behind the
sun where the,
the gravity of the sun sort of distorts
the view.
Not really high.
They got to orbit,
right?
They can't stay behind the sun.
They.
Sorry.
They can.
There are,
there's what's called the garage point.
There's a place exactly the opposite
where the earth is going to have to hang
out.
If you were to be hidden from us for a
long time and you can hang out there but
you would never leave there.
So there probably are some asteroids
right opposite the earth,
just like most planets have them.
So they're just sort of orbiting.
So what you're saying,
yeah,
they're opening once a year,
a 180 degrees away from the earth and
that's what they will be doing until
they are possible.
That one can come up and hit us from the
bottom.
And we're not looking.
No,
it's not.
No Way.
How's that?
Now,
part of the danger is something from far
outside the distance holders that we
just haven't just too far away to dim
and it wouldn't come from like in where
the South Pole is very roughly speaking.
We're looking at the whole sky,
not just a,
you know,
you can see below the South Pole if
you're in Chile,
for example,
with lots and lots of telescopes.
That's where they have that.
What is the,
the giant one that they put in Chile
recently that's not totally operational.
Uh,
yeah,
there's,
there's a whole generation of
telescopes.
I forget which one it is that's there
yet,
but one of them is it the giant Magellan
telescope?
Maybe essential one.
I think they're just still working on it
now and Chili's because it's because
it's a high altitude and the environment
is very flat and dry.
Yeah.
So I'm a Hawaii,
he's not a good place to put telescopes,
but that's gotten in trouble with a
local resistance and astronomer is just
not even trying to take that into
consideration and therefore getting
themselves in trouble.
Canary Islands are okay.
But uh,
yeah,
two ladies,
one of the best places,
Chilean Antarctica.
Actually,
I've been to the Keck observatory couple
times.
I've been three times and every time I
go,
the first time I nailed it and every
time I've been since then I haven't
gotten like,
one time we went and I didn't plan for
the moon and I was like,
oh,
there's too much moon out.
And it was,
it wasn't,
it was just too bright.
This guy was too bright.
And then the next time unfortunately we
got it when it was raining,
kind of cloudy.
We didn't get a good vision,
but the first time,
first time changed my life.
I mean,
I've really felt like I was on a
spaceship looking through a window,
you know,
what they were observing,
I don't know,
but we were actually just at the visitor
center,
just looking at the visitor center to
the sky is so magnificent at night,
you know,
there's no light pollution.
They use diffused lighting on the
island,
you know,
the whole deal.
And um,
the,
the image that you got from just looking
up,
I mean,
just with the naked eye,
it's just spectacular.
It's just an amazing view of the Milky
Way,
the telescope through there,
right?
Yeah,
I think so,
but it gives you a perspective that I
think I think we're missing with our
cities and I think we've done something
amazing by creating these cities were,
wow,
you know,
you just walk down the street and get
some food delivered,
you know,
you can go get a car,
you can,
you know,
go buy a TV.
There's all this stuff and these
congested areas.
But in putting all this artificial
light,
we've removed our connection with the
view of the cosmos.
It's absolutely true.
And I'm,
I'm the biggest booster of cities.
I love cities.
I love living in them.
I think that they're good for the
planet,
et Cetera.
But uh,
yeah,
it does exactly like you said,
it sort of makes our environment so
artificial that we forget.
Uh,
I remember a great story a friend of
mine told me she worked for an
organization called project exploration,
which is based in Chicago.
They were devoted to bringing the
wonders of science to kids and
minorities and so forth,
and they do these trips from Chicago on
the train out to Montana to dig up
dinosaur bones.
Right.
And so they are out there.
They get to go on a ranch,
they get to dig up real fossils,
bring them back,
and she said the thing that got them the
most that was most effective to them was
they saw stars for the first time in
their lives.
Right?
They'd grown up in Chicago,
they'd never seen a star in the sky.
And I think that's a shame.
Yeah.
You see these faint little flickering
things you don't see like a full.
The view of the Milky Way where you
actually look up and you see that white
sort of stripe across the sky and you
realize,
oh my God,
that star.
So those are all stars.
The Milky Way is the best.
I get dizzy looking at it.
Right?
Knowing that we're at the edge of this
spinning disk whirling around,
uh,
and if you don't get vertigo,
you're not doing it right.
Yeah.
As a person who studies space,
do you ever take time to like go out
into the desert and just to stare at the
space with nothing out there?
No light pollution that much,
you know,
honestly,
the thing that I study are equations and
formulas and theories and I use space.
My friends who are observers go out
there and collect the data and figure
out what ideas we have are right and
which ones are wrong.
And I'd love it when I get the chance,
but I don't go out of my way anymore
than anybody else.
Um,
you were saying that people were asking
about general relativity.
Was that the,
uh,
the quantum and quantum mechanics people
on twitter say,
all right,
I hope to figure out quantum mechanics,
but the first time here they look up to
you for this.
Yeah.
Well the problem is not impossible.
I don't think I'm just joking,
but what?
I'm very touchy,
but it's one of those things where
everyone is hoping that someone is going
to be able to boil it down and simple.
And Neil degrasse Tyson does a very good
job of doing that with the cosmos.
He's been able to boil down quite a few
things on this show where a lot of
people went,
thanks man.
Finally I kind of get it sorta yet.
He's fantastic.
He has an amazing ability,
especially off the cuff.
He.
Well,
it seems like off the cuff I,
I had this vision that he goes home
every night and plans out answers to
every possible question because there so
slick when he delivers that does a
little.
Because I've heard him give the exact
same semi off the cuff,
but they're great.
So it sounds like it's like a stand up
comedian delivering a line.
It's new to you.
Yeah,
that's right.
Yeah.
So what is it about it that they don't
understand?
You think quantum mechanics?
Uh,
I think that's the subject of the next
book that I'm writing a book I'm working
on right now.
So just starting thinking about it,
but it's not just the people on the
street,
it's my professional colleagues with
phds in physics who don't understand
quantum mechanics.
And rather than being embarrassed by
that,
you know,
rather than thinking,
wow,
this is a terrible thing that we should
devote all our resources to
understanding,
they flip it,
they,
it's like a aesop's Fox and the grapes,
you know,
the parable where the Fox is trying to
get the grapes and you realize that he
can't reach,
reach them.
So he says,
I never wanted them anyway.
They're probably sour.
Right?
So that's a physicist.
Or like with quantum mechanics,
like now if you try to understand it at
a deep level,
they disrespect you.
You're like,
why are you wasting your time doing that
when we could be calculating some
numbers?
Right.
Ego and knowledge.
It's always a weird combination.
I would always,
always.
I've always assumed when I was younger
that well,
when you get to the highest levels of
science or any sort of intellectual
pursuit that the people that are really
involved,
there wouldn't be any ego issues.
It would all,
you know,
as an outsider,
I was like,
well there's ego and every other part of
the world.
But those super smart dudes that are
figuring everything out,
they got all that stuff locked down.
Kind of the opposite of that.
Really,
really,
I love them.
These are my people,
you know,
and uh,
but,
but it's,
it's.
Well,
I'll explain quantum mechanics
eventually,
but please.
But you are right.
I mean the,
I mean,
sorry,
the,
this ego thing.
I'm the.
One of the thing about academia being a
professor,
right?
Whether it's science or anything else,
is that you are constantly being
evaluated by every other person you
meet.
There's a hierarchy,
there's a rank,
how good you are at everything,
right?
And it's not written down necessarily.
There's not a rankings that appeared in
the sports pages,
but everyone is judging you all the time
and you know,
my students and so forth,
they say,
well,
I don't like to ask questions in a
seminar because I worry that someone's
going to be judging me.
And all I can say is that yes,
they are going to be judging you at the
very,
very tippy top.
Am I number two or number three?
Right?
And it's.
Yeah,
it's very sad and it's not,
not everyone's like that,
but a lot,
most people in the field get to be like
that and probably it helps forward the
advance of science.
Right?
The competitive nature of it.
It's competitive and egotistical and
they want to do better than everybody
else and prove that they're better and
and I'm sure Einstein and Newton where
justice driven by that is that anybody
else?
Isn't it weird?
It seems like human beings need that
comparative sort of competition thing
going on in order to afford whatever
they're doing.
They need peers.
They need some sort of.
It helps it's there.
Yeah.
And we live in a world with scarce
resources,
right?
Some of us are going to live longer than
others.
Some of us are going to get tenure and
some of us are not.
Some of us are gonna be Nobel Prize
winners and some are not.
So no matter what,
there's going to be competition.
Yeah.
And in your,
in your field is there is a big issue,
I guess with people disregarding other
people's discoveries or wanting to
rather like saying like wanting to
poopoo things and I think this a very
complicated issue that I don't really
have clear because certainly scientists
can be very,
very supportive of each other under the
right circumstances.
Uh,
but there are,
there human beings,
there's all sorts of cognitive biases
that they have prejudices,
basie and priors for what's likely to be
true,
what's not likely to be true.
And it's not just perfect reasoning,
perfect rationality,
right?
People come in with their prejudices and
if you go and tickle their a
preconceived notions,
they'll think you're great.
And if you say something that doesn't
quite fit into what they're thinking
about them,
they'll sort of look somewhere else.
Your ministry,
do you,
um,
do you teach this?
When you're teaching classes and you're,
you're addressing potential future
cosmologists and quantum mechanics,
quantum mechanics now committed.
There's no person who does quantum
physicist as good.
Yeah.
What do you,
do you tell them about the potential
pitfalls?
Maybe plant a seed in their head like,
hey,
you can avoid this.
You can still be competitive,
but avoid all these traps that are
essentially like these intellectual
rabbit hole you can go down that are
really not beneficial to anybody.
Yeah,
I mean if I'm formally teaching class
and I'm standing up there in front of a
lecture hall,
a 98 percent is teaching the material
pretty straightforwardly.
I try to dribble in little words of
wisdom here and there and especially if
I think that there is a way that we
always teach the subject that is wrong
and wrongheaded and we should be doing
it right.
I tried to highlight the differences,
but if I'm advising students like my
graduate students or my undergraduates,
then I,
you know,
lay on very hard the,
uh,
my own perspective on how it is to be a
scientist and what is the good way to do
and what's the bad way to do it.
What are the pitfalls?
And also just,
you know,
how to not make mistakes and trip up
your own career.
Yeah.
That's critically important.
Now,
what is it about quantum mechanics that
you think people don't understand?
Well,
yeah.
Everyone agrees on what we don't
understand this the thing that makes
quantum mechanics,
which is our single best theory of the
universe in some sense,
the thing that makes it difficult to
understand is that as the only theory
you've ever invented,
where there is a difference between what
the world is
and what we see.
When we look at the world,
right?
In every other theory,
if we look closely enough,
we would see the world as it is,
and quantum mechanics has this
fundamental rule that says you can't see
the world as it is you.
If you have an electron,
right,
a particle that can be spinning
clockwise or counterclockwise,
you think that's what can happen,
because every time you look at it and
you say,
is it spinning clockwise or spinning
counterclockwise?
You get one answer or the other,
but the rules of quantum mechanics,
I,
when you're not looking at it,
it's in a super position of both and you
can calculate the probability that
you're going to get one answer or the
other and this drives people crazy
because they think that what they see is
what is real and therefore they have
very,
very difficult times figuring out how to
make a sensible theory of quantum
mechanics that explains what you
actually see.
Yeah.
Even you just explaining that.
I'm circling around and signed my brain.
I'm looking for like a Cabi to put place
this.
Where does this go?
Superposition.
What was he saying?
He's saying that it's in two different
places at the same time or that it's
still an emotion at the same time.
Good.
Right,
so that's right.
So exactly what you're doing right now.
You're saying that you know,
there are things that it can be still in
motion,
this place,
that place and somehow it's in both at
once or something like that.
And with quantum mechanics says it's not
an either.
Like if you ask where's the position of
the electron,
there's no such thing as the position of
the electron.
If you look at the electron,
you will see it in a position,
but that is not the fundamental essence
of the electron.
There's something called the quantum
state where the wave function,
there's a mathematical way that we have
representing the reality of it,
but the answers that gives us two
questions are just not here.
It is.
There has how fast it's moving,
et cetera.
That's not what we calculate using the
theory.
Does this,
is this sort of.
I mean it's very bizarre.
Right?
And it's very complex.
And is this sort of lend itself to get
hijacked by Woo folks?
Oh totally.
Which is why like what the bleep,
like the what the bleep do we know?
That was when I first started really
paying attention to this stuff and then
I was reading criticisms of what the
bleep and that's when I got an
understanding like,
oh,
okay,
well this is kind of horseshit and this
lady is kind of a channeler.
Yeah,
like what?
In a kind of a cult,
sort of a deal.
What?
Wait a minute.
Like when she was saying her name was
ramp though,
it was like that's her real name.
Ten thousand year old warriors,
you know that.
How come they didn't put that in the
movie?
Like the.
There's a lady in the movie,
if you've seen what and so many people
are in my God that changed my life and
we were training because all of a sudden
they thought that like magic was real
and it is kind of right.
I mean it's something magic,
but magic.
The world is not magic,
but when you look at an atom and realize
that most of it is space,
like most of the things that we're
looking at are mostly space and that
subatomic particles really do kind of
blink in and out of existence.
You look at all the various quantum
weirdness that is real and observable by
people like you that actually studied
this stuff.
It looks crazy.
Yeah.
In fact,
so I hate to be that guy,
but both the claim that atoms are mostly
space and the claim,
the particles pumping out of existence
are both entirely bullshit.
Oh,
please educate me more.
Why do people say that all the time
then?
Because they are privileging what you
see when you look right.
Privileging like white privilege or
different.
Exactly like that.
Know they're there.
They have a view of what should be.
Okay,
and so if you have an electron in an
atom,
we have a mathematical way of describing
it and it's a cloud.
It's not located anywhere.
It's not empty space and here's the
electron and most of the rest of it's
empty.
It's not like a little miniature version
of the solar system.
The solar system is mostly empty.
There's empty space in between the
planets and if you draw a picture of the
atom or look at one from your high
school science book and Adam looks just
like the solar system,
right?
Exactly.
Is at the center and these things moving
around it.
That's not what it is.
It's A.
It's a smooth cloud that is everywhere
inside the atom and that cloud is the
answer to the question where I do look
for the electron,
where would I most likely see it?
Okay,
and so the leap that is very,
very hard to make is what the electron
truly is,
is that cloud.
It's not what you see.
You never see the cloud.
When you look at it,
you see the electron position,
but what it is is that cloud and people
just can't.
And so that's what they talk about.
Particles popping in and out of
existence.
What there is is this wave function,
this probability cloud that tells you
how likely is it,
you'll see a particle,
and if the answer is,
well,
it's very unlikely.
It's point zero,
zero,
one percent chance.
If I look here and look here again,
look here again.
Then when you do see it,
you're tempted to say,
Aha,
a particle has popped into existence.
The reality is there was the cloud that
was there all along.
It was sitting there.
It was not fluctuating,
he was not changing,
but it's not what you see.
And everyone from Einstein on down has
had a real tough time wrapping their
heads around that.
Yeah,
I still don't get it.
So,
uh,
so when people say that an atom is
mostly empty space,
it's not true.
It's mostly this wave function for the
electron.
Yeah.
So there's this sort of very difficult
to describe property to it yet.
And they were trying.
So we are we looking at things sort of
in a very material sense,
like you know,
this mug is ceramic,
this table is wood,
and we think about the composition of
it.
If we cut into the ceramic,
we know what it looks like.
So we're trying to apply those
principles to like maybe an Adam.
Yeah,
exactly.
They just don't apply because it's the
other way around.
Like we,
we think that our world that we see
every day is sort of basically how
things work and we're going to sort of
translate other extremes of existence
into that language,
whether it's far or way back in time.
We're very,
very small or whatever,
but there's no reason to think that our
everyday life experience has equipped us
with the vocabulary to talk about these
things in any sensible way and in fact
it hasn't,
so we have a very completely viable way
of talking about the atom.
We have very,
very rigorous mathematical ways of
describing what happens and then quantum
mechanics says what you see when you
look at the Adam is different and we
just sit there and insist that what we
see is the real way to talk about it.
No matter how anti quantum mechanical
that viewpoint really is.
That's got to be incredibly frustrating
to you because I've heard like
legitimate mainstream scientists on
television talking about the Adam and
describing it in that way.
Oh yeah.
I know.
Believe me,
and this is to be,
to be super fair.
People disagree.
Okay.
So I think that people disagree about
what the fundamental nature of quantum
mechanics is and I have no problem with
that.
I mean,
I have a point of view and I actually
believe in the many worlds
interpretation of quantum mechanics and
we can explain that and I think it was
perfectly sensible and coherent and fits
together.
Uh,
but if you have another point of view on
quantum mechanics that is also perfectly
sensible and coherent fits together,
that's fine.
We can disagree and we can ask about
what experiments to do.
The sad thing is that most physicists,
especially ones that go on tv and talk
about this stuff,
just don't think about it that hard and
therefore they're sloppy when they talk
about it and therefore people come away
going,
oh,
I don't really get it.
It's very gettable.
It's totally understandable.
Again,
we can disagree about what the
understanding will ultimately be,
but physicists contribute just as much,
you know,
not on purpose,
but they,
they allow,
they opened up the space for what the
bleep do we know people to insert their
woo in there because they're not doing a
very good job of measuring up to the
reality themselves.
So it's,
it seems like it's something that's
intensely complex that almost needs to
be described with mathematics,
which would require you to have a deep
understanding of mathematics to really
completely grasp.
Is that a fair assessment until my book
comes out?
Yeah,
that's what it is.
What is the book?
Oh,
well,
so the title of the book is something
deeply hidden.
This is a phrase from Einstein and the
idea is that there is something real
that we can get a handle on is just
different than what we see and I,
I don't think that we need the
mathematical details to get it right.
What we need is to have the willingness
to let go of our intuition a little bit
to,
to accept the idea that the way the
world works at a fundamental level is
very different than the typical ideas
about space and time and stuff that we
are born with.
Where were you when that,
what the bleep moving was out where you
were a professor yet?
Uh,
I think so.
I,
I lost a perspective girlfriend over
that movie,
like we met and we went on a date and
she's like,
I got the best movie for you to say I
don't think I'm gonna like it.
And she says,
well,
you got to be open minded gotta.
At least watch it.
I watched it.
I was like,
oh my goodness.
Did you try to explain to her that it's
not true?
But there was,
it was not a close call.
It was not like,
Oh,
if I explained this,
she'll get it.
Is Love this movie
important.
Right.
And I have a friend.
It was a really sad story.
Um,
I have a friend who was really into the
secret and uh,
she was actually a friend of a friend
more than a friend and um,
I ran into her at the comedy store and
we were talking and she was explaining
to me how she has sort of use the power
of the secret to map out her life.
And it was all gonna take place.
Right.
And I didn't see her again for like,
like a year or so later,
maybe more.
And then the next time I saw her,
she was like,
I don't understand,
you know,
I,
I really thought this was going to work
and my life is still a mess and my dad
is a loser and every guy date is a piece
of shit.
And it was just like,
yeah.
And she just couldn't,
she couldn't get it right.
And she was convinced that this law of
attraction,
which in my eyes is very similar and a
lot of ways,
like the,
the idea behind it is,
look,
you're taking a bunch of people that are
extremely successful and you're asking
them how'd you do it?
And they're like,
well,
I visualize it.
Holy Shit has got to be the answer.
Right.
No,
that's,
that's one part of a giant thing that
makes someone successful.
Yeah.
And luck.
Is it even bigger for a lot going on
there?
Yeah.
Like did you imagine that you were born
with two legs because some people
aren't,
right?
Yeah.
So when you deal with something like the
secret or something like that,
you know,
the,
uh,
the rabbit hole,
well,
you know what the bleep,
there's this desire that people have to
find like some secret message,
like there's,
there's a,
a magical quality to the world and all
you have to do is think about it and
look about it in a certain way and your
life will take on this incredible
quality.
Right?
Yep.
And I think that,
uh,
it's.
So my last book,
the big picture I actually devoted,
even though it was mostly about physics
and philosophy and cosmology and
biology,
I devoted a little bit to the
fundamental principles of reasoning and
especially basie and reasoning.
I don't know if you've ever heard of
basie and reasoning.
I have.
What would you describe it?
Sure.
I mean it's,
it's basically the,
the essence of it is the following idea.
Someone tells you a good idea or do you
come up with a good idea yourself?
The usual thing that people will do is
either say,
that sounds right,
it's true,
or that sounds wrong.
It's false.
And what Phase II and reasoning says no
to every possibility you say,
okay,
maybe it's true.
Maybe it's false.
I will assign a probability to it being
true or false.
It's called that the prior probability.
And then I will go collect data.
I will say,
well,
what will the world be like if this were
true?
And then we'll go look right?
Does this a woman over here like me?
And she romantically attracted to me?
Well maybe that would affect what she
says.
If I say hi to her and therefore I'm
going to do the experiment.
Right?
And this is everything from going
through your everyday life to being a
professional scientist.
So look fine.
Read the secret.
Be told that there's this law of
attraction.
If you understand how physics works,
you know that it's completely nonsense.
But if you were tempted to believe it,
say to yourself,
alright,
let me test it.
Let me figure out what,
whether it's true or false by saying if
it were true with the following,
things would happen.
If it were false,
the following things would happen.
And that I think that everyone thinks
they work that way,
but almost no one really does.
Yeah.
It's very difficult.
We have these preconceived notions that
we really like to clean code.
Yeah.
We really like to imagine that we're
right about things we hate to be wrong.
And if you.
Once you were on a path like I believe
in this,
it's super hard for people to shake that
loose and people generally think that
the probability that something is true
is either zero or 100 percent.
You don't like the idea that there's
something as 70 percent true and
therefore they can sort of improve that
or deep or,
or disprove that or whatever.
It's just a,
it's just hard going through life
thinking about probability distributions
for every possible version of reality.
But that is the best way to do it if you
can probability distributions.
Yeah.
Is that what you do when you walked on
the street?
Oh yeah,
totally.
I long list of numbers in my head.
I mean the good news is you.
There is a certain threshold,
right?
If something is 99 percent true or 99
percent,
99 point nine,
nine percent likely to be true,
get on with your life.
You just accept that as true and don't
keep trying to come up.
Come up with evidence for it against it,
unless it's forced itself on you.
Like a.
When people say that the universe is not
really expanding my,
my field,
I get this right,
like we've had evidence since the 19
twenties.
The universe is expanding well,
who says it's not everyone who emails me
every like I get emails and letters and
they have their own theories and the
light just got tired coming from these
other galaxies that gets tired.
There's literally something called the
tired light theory like fatigue.
Yes,
exactly.
And I'm not,
you know,
so there's some version of the
scientific method that says every idea
should be treated seriously and you
should sort of write down what the
evidence for and against this is.
But come on,
I've done that.
I know the universe is expanding.
I'm not going to waste my time.
That's okay.
That's why we can get through our
everyday lives perfectly well without
being very good Bayesians at all.
Have you had many flat earthers email
you?
I haven't had flat earthers email me.
I did once tweet.
I had one tweet mentioning the phrase
flat earth and I did get an invitation
to come on a podcast,
a flat earth podcast.
They have a flatter with podcast.
I'm sure there's thousands,
but uh,
yeah,
they are.
They're out there.
Where are they going to try to school?
You,
uh,
you know,
it was to their credit,
it was quite polite and you know,
we know you don't believe this,
but let's come.
Come on and have a conversation and
we'll talk to you.
And we're just about questioning things
and getting at the truth and getting an
education and actual astronomy or
astrophysicist that the crucial thing
that you notice whenever you talk to the
many,
many physics and astronomy crackpots out
is that
they're never asking questions.
They're always here.
I will tell you the truth if you want to
know it.
They're never like helped me learn.
Right?
If people,
if people email me and say,
help me learn that,
I'm usually very happy to converse with
them one way or the other.
Well,
it's super easy to start questioning
things,
but it's very difficult to get a degree
in astrophysics or to get a degree in
astronomy or to really read books about
it.
Like I getting through Lawrence Krause's
last book,
man.
There's chapters that I had to like go.
Okay,
let's go through this one more time.
Like when he came here I had to ask him
like one of the first things we did,
it was probably a mistake because it's
so complex.
I tried to get him to explain gauge
symmetry to me.
Okay.
Yeah.
And it was just like he did it like two
or three times.
I'm like,
okay,
there's certain parts about it that are
really hard.
Yeah.
Whereas we can try that again if you
want,
but it is.
There are hard things.
That's okay.
You would be surprised if there weren't.
Right.
Like if you spend 500 years learning
about the universe and everything made
perfect sense the first time,
that would be kind of remarkable.
No,
yeah,
it's super complex and I,
I guess that makes sense.
It makes sense that it would be.
Now when someone boils it down to
something that's really woo woo,
like,
you know,
what the bleep do we know,
how is that frustrating to you?
What does it mean?
That must make you communicating with
people that have seen that and have
these ideas that are false assumptions
based on it.
Sort of like I said to you that atoms
are mostly hollow.
What does that frustrating?
I mean,
what does that line gets frustrating at
different levels?
You know,
I think,
um,
I,
my first impulse is to be charmed and
happy when people care,
people are even interested on a very
positive.
Have you?
Uh,
yeah,
like I first want to give people credit
and see if there's something inside them
with that we can work with and try to
work toward the truth.
Right?
Um,
but then,
yeah,
so,
and I think most people maybe are like
that and there's some hardcore people
who have made up their minds about the
craziness.
I mean,
you see where it would come from,
right?
Because quantum mechanics says what the
world is is different than what we see
when we look at it.
So it's a small leap from that correct
statement to we bring the world into
existence by looking at it.
Right.
Then you're deepak chopra and DM me on
twitter.
So whenever I tweet something about
quantum mechanics,
he retweets it with something.
But it's all in your mind.
It's all consciousness bringing the
world into existence.
He loves word Salad.
Yeah.
That guy is the biggest like dealer of
worlds word salad.
Yeah.
The world is ever changing.
This is putting them the word salad into
a recipe that people think is nutritious
for them.
Right.
They really liked to eat even though
there's no actual nutritional value.
Well there's,
you get a lot of that from like certain
yoga classes,
like there's certain yoga classes that I
go to where like the yoga teacher will
start talking some woo woo shit and like
you're being in the middle of the pose.
And I'm like,
what the fuck is this guy going on about
the.
I do it too.
And as long as the pose is helping me,
I'm going to put up with that smile my
way through it,
debate them
right in the middle of it.
But it's weird that that stuff is all
can sign up.
That's all sort of kind of in that sort
of genre of people that are trying to
improve their life or be spiritual or
they love that deep rock show up or
shit.
Like I've had the,
I had this conversation with a friend of
mine who's like,
it gave me a Deepak Chopra book and I
started going through it.
Now was like,
I go,
you know,
this guy's crazy,
right?
Probably wants to do well,
it's probably not a terrible person
probably wants to do well.
But he's also ignoring the actual
scientists that study all this stuff and
he,
he's sort of pitching this thing that
what it is like this Deepak Chopra ism
this sort of like spiritual pseudo
spiritual view of the world that he's
pitching to like,
uh,
these,
these middle aged housewives.
They're like looking for some sort of
meaning to life,
but they don't like going to church.
Yeah.
And Daniel Dennett,
the philosopher,
came up with a great word for it.
He calls them deep at ease.
When you string some words together in a
way that sounds extremely profound,
but you look closely at it,
it doesn't actually mean anything at
all.
You know there's a website that will do
that for you.
How the Deepak Chopra quote general.
That's it.
It's not that hard.
I would like to laugh at.
There's another website that comes up
with brandon physics,
paper titles.
It's not that day.
Not that different.
Usually tell when it's a random visitor,
but the physics stuff is.
It's almost be I guess,
similar issues with the reason why deep
bra can do that is because most people
don't understand what he's talking
about.
So if you say a lot of stuff about
things that people don't understand like
I've had,
we've.
There's been a bunch of videos that we
played on this podcast about a fake
martial arts practitioners.
There's a whole business and these
people that have these fake martial arts
techniques and they use all these huge
words that are rare,
very rare about the central nervous
system and about the,
you know,
the structure of the body and they'll,
they'll use all this stuff to try to get
you to think like,
oh,
well this guy,
obviously it's an enormous vocabulary
and a deep understanding of anatomy.
He must therefore be this she master
that he's pretending to be and it's kind
of very similar.
So I kind of recognize that pattern in
the EU.
People like,
oh,
I kind of see what you're doing.
You're throwing a bunch of very
complicated word that aren't in most
people's vernacular and you're saying
them in a way that makes me feel like
you have some sort of a connection to
the CI and to the shock rose into the
inner whatever that everybody's trying
to reach to be happy.
Yeah,
and another problem is just that
whenever there is a field,
whether it's physics or medicine or
whatever,
where we know something,
but it's hard,
complicated,
counter intuitive.
When we explained that we translate it
right,
you know,
in physics we have mathematical
equations that are quite an ambiguous as
to what they say,
but then we use words,
we say,
well there's a cloud,
there's a probability,
etc.
And every translation is inaccurate in
some sense.
So if you're bAsing beliefs off the
translations,
then you can fudge them a little bit
more to get almost wherever you want to
go.
Oh,
you're confused me more.
I was good with the cloud up until now.
Why?
Why is it a cloud like why?
When you describing where the electron
in habits,
why is it a cloud?
Well,
it's if you're thinking about the
electron,
the,
what the wave function is sort of how we
use it is you asked the question,
if I were to look for the location of
the electron,
there's a machine that tells me the
answer,
the probability of seeing it here with a
certain number of probability of seeing
it,
their probability,
seeing it somewhere else.
And so at every point in space there's a
number,
the probability you will see the
electron there,
right?
So if you visualize all those
probabilities all at once,
it looks like a cloud that is filling up
all of space and then the leap is to say
there's no such thing as where the
electron is.
There'S only the cloud.
it's not like the cloud is expressing
your ignorance of where the electron
really is.
The cloud is what there really is.
And I sound exactly like deepak chopra
or there's no way.
No,
no.
You don't bore versus electron cloud.
Oh yeah.
Here we go.
Visualization of it.
It is.
That's right.
Yeah.
So on the left,
these are.
This is the picture we like to draw
electrons orbiting around as if they
were little planets in the solar system
on the right is closer to reality,
but you see even there they couldn't
quite resist the temptation to make it
point to list and little dots and it's
really should be some smooth
distribution.
This is what the,
the physicist would call the thing on
the right,
the wave function or the quantum state
of the electron and it is that cloud and
it answers the question.
What's the likelihood that we see it in
different places?
The hard part to mentally get to is the
cloud is what is real,
is it almost like,
like what,
what we're looking at here with all
these dots here and it says jamie would
go back to where it wasn't pleased,
um,
where it says the probability of the
density of electron and then you see all
those dots is the issue like making a
visual representation of it.
Almost like,
like if I asked someone to draw a visual
representation of a thought.
Yeah,
it's something like that.
Exactly.
Because we're used to stuff,
coffee cups,
bottles of water,
and like they have locations in space.
They have a shape,
a size thoughts.
Yeah,
exactly.
But it's hard to draw them.
Right?
Where's that going?
Where the hell is that?
I mean,
that's the most important thing that
we've ever had when it comes to the
creation of civilization,
inventions,
innovation,
creativity,
all those things are just thoughts and
try,
draw thought.
Right?
But when you were intuitive,
we're,
we,
we get that.
You mean when you say he's hard to draw
a song,
right?
But okay.
No,
what it is you can draw the musical
notes and then.
But uh,
yeah,
and so if you talk about an electron
that's supposed to be a thing I was
supposed to be somewhere that I can like
find it and someone comes along and
says,
no nature is totally different than that
and you will never in your life be able
to see with perfectly clear eyeglasses
what nature is really like.
They get a little annoyed,
but it's the truth.
What do you think about the very uber
bizarre theory that the universe is
incredibly fractal in the sense that
what we're looking at when we're looking
at the universe is essentially some sort
of subatomic particles for a much larger
adam and then it goes bigger and bigger
and then there's a human out there.
I think also a part of another galaxy
that's also part of another universe.
It's also part of another atom.
That's also right.
No,
I get it,
but no,
I think no,
the closest thing that is a little bit
more reasonable to that.
well,
so let's go the other way around.
Yeah.
Um,
well let me ask me or let me ask you,
why is it no.
Well,
so let's go the other way around.
Okay.
Let's,
let's,
let's ask if maybe what we think of as
adams could be alive with like little
people and substructure that we just
don't know about.
So if you're an honest,
conscientious scientists,
you always say we don't know for sure.
Right?
But what we,
everything that we think we know about
quantum mechanics says that things like
electrons and quarks are completely
featureless.
That if yOu tried to put little wrinkles
and make them different,
like the earth and venus and mars are
very different from each other.
Every electron is exactly the same as
every other electronic.
And if you tried to give it any
distinguishing features,
it would cost an enormous amount of
energy.
Energy that's just not there,
so there's fundamental principles of
physics that says that there are no
people living on adam's okay,
and so what we're like with our solar
system,
even though it kind of vaguely resembles
and adam in some sense,
we are nothing like real adams.
We could not be patched together to make
a solid object in this bigger world or
anything like that.
So the.
So our exIstence sufficiently different
from the summit atomic realm that I see
no way that we could be the same thing
as the subatomic realm to some bigger
people.
I do think we could be living in a
simulation as elon musk famously a
suggested.
We could be all living in a computer
simulation.
I don't think it's likely,
but it's completely plausible given what
we know right now.
Right?
The real issue is that one day we most
likely will have something as long as
technology continues to exponentially
advanced,
will one day have something that's
indiscernible from the reality,
there'll be able to interface more than
likely to be able to interface with your
senses,
with the way the mind perceives reality
and create something that passes that
uncanny valley and literally feels like
like real life matrix.
I think that we might be very far or we
might be pretty close.
I think it's hard to tell because
there's so much We don't know right now.
It's not like this is coming in the next
10 years,
but it could be a thousand,
but yeah,
absolutely.
It could.
You know the thought experiment that
that helps people accept this is you
know,
a single neuron in your brain,
you have something like 100 billion
neurons in your,
but every
single one is not that complicated.
It takes in some inputs,
outputs in some outputs.
It might be work to figure out exactly
what it does,
but it's not mysterious.
Right?
So We couldn't imagine replacing one
neuron in your brain with a solid state
micro,
a device that does exactly the same
thing as that neuron,
and you will be the same person roughly
speaking,
right?
So,
okay,
so if you believe that,
then do that With 202 neurons and do it
with three neurons and you're gradually
building up who you are,
but just replacing your brain with
something that is a machine made and if
you believe that can happen,
there's no reason to think that machines
can't be as human as we want them to be.
do you follow any ray kurzweil stuff?
A little bit.
I don't think that,
uh,
he's and especially deep thinker,
but he's a good one.
How are you counting on his desk?
I could be this mother fucker.
you don't think he's an deep thinker.
I mean,
he's a brilliant guys.
Invented a bunch of really fascinating
things.
Yeah.
He likes to extrapolate without,
uh,
without limit pretty fearlessly.
Well,
he must have irritated you for you to
jump right out with.
I don't think he's a particularly deep
thinker.
No,
but I do think he serves a role.
I think there are people who,
uh,
make us think more deeply.
Like I remember seeing a panel
discussion with,
uh,
murray gilman,
who was a famous physicist and isaac
asimov.
This was like 30 years ago when,
uh,
as well as still alive.
And there was some,
someone else who's on the panel,
I forget,
it was another physicist.
And the amazing thing was the science
fiction author was by far the most
conservative thinker up there in terms
of what he thought would really be
happening a thousand years from now.
Right?
The physicist had these Way out ideas
and asthma was like,
yeah,
I don't think it's going to be all that
different.
Right?
And it's just hard to predict the future
accurately.
And there's a role serve both by trying
to be as realistic as possible and,
and careful and basie and saying what
are the probabilities?
And so forth.
There's another role served by just
being the,
a provocative in saying,
well,
maybe this crazy thing is going to
happen.
Maybe we'll cure death in the next
hundred years.
And a light bulb change for everybody
dramatically.
That seems fairly likely,
right?
They'll to figure out some way to
reverse aging.
Yeah.
I think that's plausible.
There's no biological reason why not.
Kurzweil's got some weird motivations
to.
he literally wants to sort of rebuild
his father.
Yeah.
He wants to be able to piece together
some sort of an artificial intelligence
version of his father and go back and
see him.
Yep.
that's deep.
That's a word for it.
Yeah.
He,
he thinks that there's gonna come a
time,
uh,
inside his lifetime hopefully,
that you'll be able to download
consciousness,
that consciousness is going to be
something you,
you'll transfer sort of like a code.
Yeah.
I think that there's,
there's a difference between,
you know,
what is potentially
given arbitrary amounts of time and
resources and what is realistic in the
relatively near term.
By the near term we mean 50 or a hundred
years.
Right.
And I think that people like ray
kurzweil are far a exaggerating what's
going to be possible the next 50 or 100
years because they underestimate how
little we know about how the brain
works,
how important it is for the brain bring
to be in our bodies,
right?
We,
one of the,
one of the breakthroughs in artificial
intelligence over the last couple of
decades was to realize that if you try
to build an artificial intelligence
computer,
it's,
it becomes much more realistic if you
give it a body,
if you give it a face and it can
interact with people.
I mean we underestimate the extent to
which having a body is an important part
of how we think and who we are.
And these,
this is just like such baby steps and
understanding this stuff that to imagine
that in the matter of decades we'll have
it all figured out and have downloadable
consciousnesses is not realistic to me.
Do you think that we have to absolutely
understand the exact way that the human
brain works in order to replicate its
possibilities?
No.
I mean,
I think that uh,
we probably won't step,
probably won't be the way that we make
artificial consciousness or artificial
intelligence,
like we won't just be reconstructing
human beings.
Like when we made cars,
we didn't reconstruct horses.
Right.
We just did it in a very,
very different way in cars are much
better than horses and in various ways
not as good in other ways like going on
the hills,
going up hills.
But also,
you know,
in the early days of cars,
one big complaint was.
But if I'm drunk and passed out,
it won't take me home.
I'll buy.
Does that a complaint?
That was a complaint.
Hilarious.
Because the horse had just take you home
and knows how to get there.
Exactly.
Finally,
we'll get the artificial and nobody gets
mad.
Self driving cars will be able to do it.
Finally,
if you're driving a horse drunk,
nobody gives a shit.
No,
you're passed out.
That's right.
Yeah.
That'd be like a big adjustment for
people.
Yeah,
exactly.
More trunk.
And so the idea that the way that will
make artificial intelligence is just
sort of mimic a human being is just
crazy.
That's not how it's going to be.
What do you think it's gonna be like,
well,
I don't know.
There are.
There are problems that can be solved by
things that we design or just a
different set of problems than the thing
that evolution naturally made us do.
Right?
Like evolution built a very,
very general purpose machine that is
inefficient and irrational and all sorts
of ways like anyone's pocket calculator
since the 19 seventies can multiply
numbers way better than your brain can
write.
Your brain has enormously more
computational capacity than a pocket
calculator.
Why can't we multiply numbers?
That ability was not important back when
we were evolving these things.
Right?
So the set of things that it is easy to
design is just very,
very different than what the brain does.
So who knows?
I don't know exactly what it will be,
what it will look like.
I actually think that the more important
thing we'll be blurring the distinction
between human beings and machines.
You know the,
the crossovers.
This is another one of elon musk's
project is called the neuro link.
The idea of basically a neural lace,
something that is just interfacing your
brain very,
very,
very fast so that you have access to the
entire internet or whatever peripherals
you want in real time.
So wikipedia is part of your memory
essentially,
and that's just who you are and how you
walk around and you can multiply numbers
as fast as you want to.
That seems very likely that augmented,
augmented reality.
Yeah.
And some sort of a weird symbiotic
connection to the net into the
electronics,
whether it's a wearable thing or maybe
even an embedded thing.
Yeah,
that's.
I think it will be embedded.
So yeah,
this is more efficient.
We use.
We will you be one of the first
adopters?
Are you gonna wait a little while.
I'm never a first generation adopt or
even have iphones much less,
you know,
things embedded in my body.
But look,
I just adopted two kittens.
They get microchip implants.
Oh yeah.
You adopt a cat that gets a microchip
inside so you can't lose it.
Yeah.
And so to think that we're very far away
from doing that,
I don't think is right.
I think that we're going to be doing
things.
I was just looking at a a laptop bag.
It's a laptop bag that also is a.
You have a passport bag and a laptop bag
and then a carry on and then a check and
sto for airport airplane luggage and all
of it is bluetooth and all of it is
location coordinated with gps so that if
somehow or another your bag gets lost,
you literally can go on a computer and
I'll show you where your bag is.
Like,
whoa,
how long are we going?
When are we going to do that with people
and I feel,
you know,
I,
I'm a big believer in privacy rights and
so forth.
Her dilemma,
do I let my employer microchipping what
does this.
There you go.
There's a company in Wisconsin that had
microchip day on August 1st and they
implanted microchips and people first of
all,
that dude with his ears in that,
those fucking earplugs and the lower ear
lobe thing.
You ain't doing nothing buddy.
Sticking that in me.
Look what you've done in your ears.
Fellow Wisconsin company becomes first
us employee.
What,
and these are very simple,
just location tracking things.
Right?
Why would you allow the company to do
that?
I wouldn't allow my company to tattoo
me.
Why would I allow my company to
microchip?
It's for tracking and you can also like
they can buy stuff in the cafeteria and
one,
you know what else you could do use your
wallet.
You say that,
but you know,
do you turn off all cookies when you
have your laptop on and your browser.
So I do know.
No I don't because it's convenient and
these guys they like,
they get,
they can buy their snacks with their
microchip.
Well wasn't the machine and get a snack,
but here's where therefore separation
every last this laptop I can go like
that and then I could walk out the door
on that laptop stays here and all the
cookies and all my browser history stays
here.
It doesn't.
It's not an estimate.
They want you to think now you're
freaking me out.
Another thing I wanted to talk to you
about with quantum mechanics that came
out of that movie,
what the bleep.
That was very confusing to a lot of
people was the whole observer effect.
Now that is something that I've tried to
explain to people that the issue is,
well please,
if you could explaIn it like this is the
thing is that people believe that in
quantum physics it's been proven that if
you look at things that you looking at
things changes those things,
but the way it's been described to me,
it's like,
no,
it's actually because you are measuring
those things and that's what changes it.
The act of measuring in.
Yeah,
and that there's some sort of physical
interaction when you're measuring
something.
That's what's changing the effect.
Is that correct?
Yeah,
I think that's right.
The this is a legacy of the battle days
of quantum mechanics.
When people were a little bit fuzzy
about these things,
it was better at it.
The bad old days like battle rap,
battle days maybe like see einstein and
bohr going at it,
rap battle,
the bad old days when people had a more
limited understanding of what quantum
mechanics really is and spoke about it
and slightly sloppy ways,
so there is the truth that if you want
to describe what you see when you look
at an electron,
what you see is different than what it
is like you.
You do change it by looking at it and
therefore back in the battle days,
a lot of people wondered whether there
was something special about
consciousness or human perception or
something that was helping us explain
the laws of quantum mechanics.
So as you are pointing toward no,
the answer's no.
There's nothing special about quantum
mechanics and consciousness in any way.
A rock could do the same thing or a
video camera or a speck of dust.
The the quantum mechanics rules says
that things change when systems interact
with each other.
The way that you described the system is
different when it's all by itself.
Then when it interacts in some
interesting way with some other system
and that system can be a person,
but it can be anything else also.
So in that famous experiment that's in
that cartoon that gets passed around by
people every two or three years when
they're like,
wow,
the world's made the magic and they pass
this around.
It's usually a yoga teacher.
They,
um,
that,
that shows that the,
you know,
there's the particles in the waves.
Indeed.
Do you remember the saving and funding?
I know it's dr quantum when we get in
trouble playing that be maybe for
shitting on it,
we will get mad at us.
We might get pulled,
we get pulled from you had a good run.
What people,
you know,
they own these videos and so it's a real
issue is wildlife videos.
Those suckers,
they're,
they're so quick to pull the trigger and
you know,
they have a claim.
It's their video.
So if you use working together.
Yeah.
So if you use it in mock,
whatever is happening,
or even if you tell them,
hey,
go watch this video,
it's on youtube,
here's the name of it,
right?
You would think that'd be like good
advertising,
but no,
get here.
I'll bring it up and I can.
We can like talk about it a little bit.
Okay.
So give,
give me some volume so I could hear what
they say.
Yeah,
that's it.
Yeah.
The double slit experiment,
right see is similar to
the line.
The marbles make bar when we add the
second slip,
something different.
If the top of one wave meets the bottom
of another way,
they cancel each other out.
So now there is an interference pattern
on the back wall.
Places where the two tops meet are the
highest intensity.
The bright lines and where they cancel
there is nothing.
So when we throw things that is matter
through two slits,
we get this two vans and hits and with
waves we get an interference pattern of
many bands.
Good so far.
Now let's go quantum.
So now you're going to freak out.
This is where you start getting mad
quantum quantum,
I know,
tiny,
tiny bit of matter,
like a tiny marble fire street already
shaking his head folks.
It's not a tiny marbles.
You got to do a little bit of commentary
on we can't just play the whole video.
I can do the gun.
I know exactly what they're talking
about.
That's very famous experiment.
So yeah,
so if you have two slits that you let
marbles go through,
they get two slits in the receiving
screen on the other side,
right.
Whereas if you let a wave go through two
slits,
you get this interference pattern.
Right?
And so what happens when you let an
electron go through?
The answer is you get an interference
pattern.
It's more like a wave than a particle,
but the real weird thing that they're
going to get to eventually is if you
have.
If you let an electron go through two
slits,
but you put little detectors on the
so you say which detect which slit did
the electron go through.
Then it always says it goes through one
or the other.
It never goes through both.
And the interference pattern on the
other side disappears.
You only see the two lines that you
would have seen if they were marble
link.
So the point is when you're not looking,
the electron is acting like a wave and
when you're look at it,
the electron acts like a particle.
That is the lesson of the double slit
experiment.
Right?
Why?
Because when you put that detector on
the slits,
you interacted with the electron and you
localized it,
right?
There was no such thing as the position
of the electron.
There was no such thing as the answer to
the question.
Did it go through one slit or the other?
There was only a cloud.
There's only a wave going through,
but you affected it or whatever the
detector was affected it.
When it looked through the slits to see
did it go through this one or this one
and that affect changed it from being
going through both lists to being only
going through one and how does it affect
it like that?
Well,
there's this what,
what's called quantum entanglement.
The detector becomes entangled with the
electron and this is where you get into
what I my favorite version of quantum
mechanics,
which is the many worlds interpretation.
The the right wAy to think about the
electron was that cloud,
that wave going through.
That's the natural thing.
The weird thing is that when you look at
the different slits,
you only see it go through one or the
other and it acts like a particle.
So how do you explain that?
So in other words,
our natural intuitive way of thinking
about electrons is as particles.
Little marbles and quantum mechanics
says,
no,
no.
It's naturally a wave.
The weird thing is when it acts like a
particle and if you are many worlds
person,
what the answer you give is the
following.
When you look to see to the electron go
through one slit or the other you or
whatever video camera you had or
whatever becomes entangled with the
electron and what that means is that the
wave function of the whole universe,
the wave function of both the electron
but also your camera and you and the
stars and galaxies and so forth splits
into and there is now one branch of the
wave function which which acts like its
own separate world which says the
electron went through the left slit and
your cameras saw it go through the left
slit and it made a little line on the
other side and there's another branch
which says the electron went through the
right slipped and your cameras,
so it goes through the rites lit and it
makes a line on the other side and so
they're both still there,
but the world split into and now you're
only in one of them.
You don't see the whole world anymore.
You managed to make it more confusing.
Congratulations.
Screwed my head up even more.
I did that.
I understand it.
The less,
now that's even more baffling,
but the bit you understand is actually
true.
That's true.
Well,
it's a little illusion of understanding
doesn't count.
Oh,
okay.
So by not understanding,
I understand more.
There you go.
Boy,
you have a weird job.
A very,
very weird job.
Well,
it,
I,
I get it now though in talking to you,
why,
you know,
you have the deepak chopra's of the
world and why you have the,
what the bleeps because it's so
intensely confusing.
Yeah.
And especially with the limitations of
language of just counter intuitive,
it's against every little bit of our
everyday experience.
It's a set of concepts that were not
equipped with that.
We're not born with that we have to
struggle to get into our heads over
many,
many years.
And it shouldn't be surprising.
So you as an educator,
when you were talking to people about
this,
it's obviously you've probably done this
thousands of times,
right?
And tried to have theSe kind of weird
conversations with people like myself.
That's sort of lack the tools to really
truly understand what you're saying.
Um,
what,
what does that mean?
It's got to be frustrating in a sense or
no,
I love it.
Yeah,
you do.
I do.
Yeah,
that's correct.
Because what a great attitude
I was there.
That used to be me,
like it's not like my brain was born
ready to understand quantum mechanics.
Uh,
I worked at it and struggled with it and
got it wrong.
And who knows,
maybe 10 years from now will think,
oh,
you're so stupid 10 years ago.
Right?
But I think that it can be understood.
I think that people who wants to try to
understand it a number one are already
90 percent of the way to being awesome.
And number two,
the remaining 10 percent is very,
very achievable.
It is understandable.
Wasn't it fireman that said,
if you think you understand quantum
mechanics,
you don't understand quantum mechanics.
Uh,
he said something like that.
He said he can safely say that nobody
understands quantum mechanics,
which is fine,
except that you should therefore be
outraged.
You should not be proud of that.
He was kind of a funny guy.
Oh yeah.
He's being funny.
And I think that it's certainly true
that we don't understand quantum
mechanics,
if I understand,
you mean both understand and everyone
else agrees that you understand.
Maybe someone understands it,
but certainly there's no consensus on
the right way to understand it,
no consensus in the right way to
understand that.
It was a very disturbing concept.
People like me,
we want you to say,
well,
water is wet and oxygen is this.
You know,
this is what it is.
I think a thousand years from now,
historians of science will look back on
the 20th century and shake their heads
in despair.
They'll say,
look,
you guys,
quantum mechanics fell into your lap and
you didn't spend any time thinking about
it.
You didn't try very hard to understand
That's embarrassing.
Really.
Like the general public or science
professional scientists,
people with phds in theoretical physics.
Wow.
So when it comes to the people that you
were talking about,
like scientists sort of dismiss quantum
mechanics,
what are they dismissing and how are
they doing?
Well,
to be very,
very clear,
they're not dismissing quantum
mechanics.
They use quantum mechanics everyday.
They love quantum mechanics.
Quantum mechanics is a recipe for
calculating what's going to happen in
your experiment.
That is an unprecedented precision.
It's really the best way we have of
knowing what's going to happen in the
lab that we've ever invented and there's
no reason to think that it's wrong,
but then when you press them on,
okay,
what was really happening?
What is the description of reality that
corresponds to the calculation you just.
Did they get annoyed and frustrated with
you rather than give you an answer to
the question?
I'm sorry.
Like what?
Do they get annoyed and frustrated with
you?
Like when you have these conversations
with these people?
With anyone?
Yeah,
they will.
You will.
Because they don't understand this.
Well,
they don't understand which is fine,
but they act as if not understanding it
is okay and to me that is not fine.
They will say,
my job's not to understand the world is
just to make predictions and I think
that's not really the job of science or
physics at all.
Their job is not understand.
It's to make predictions.
Well,
how can you make predictions if you
don't understand what you're making?
A prediction that is exactly the
situation with quantum mechanics right
now.
Like we have a recipe,
we have an algorithm set of rules,
do this,
do this.
You get an answer,
and the answer is right.
The answer is verified and experiments
over and over again,
and you say,
well,
okay,
why is it right?
What was happening?
What is the thing that is moving around?
And they go,
oh no,
no,
don't ask me about that.
That's hilarious.
Now what do you do most of the time when
you're not teaching?
So like if you're working on this stuff,
like I,
I would imagine there's not someone
telling you what to do.
Right?
So when you're,
when you're working on this kind of
stuff,
like how do you structure it?
Yeah,
it's up to you,
you know,
there's this sort of a selection effect
that did that.
The ability to structure on your own is,
is necessary to get to a certain stage
in your career.
But uh,
yeah,
I had students graduate students who I
work with as well as other colleagues
that I collaborate with,
but it's roughly speaking,
going into the office or going to a
cafe,
sitting down with a piece of paper and a
pencil and writing.
That's what I do.
That's my job.
You go to the office or a cafe and you
sit down with like one of these yellow
legal pads and you write all that
chicken scratch that.
Nobody understands.
But you guys have recently changed.
Now I have an ipad pro with an apple
pencil and I do you do all that.
Only very,
very recently upgraded.
But maybe you can get yourself onto them
saying samsung note eight,
that it has the pen on it.
Have you seen that?
That's pretty bad ass.
You can.
Yeah.
While the screen is dark like this,
you don't have to turn the screen on.
You pull out the stylists and you can
draw notes on screen.
Okay.
Up until I got 180 pages of notes.
Like on the actual screen itself,
you don't even have to open it up.
All right,
that's pretty cool.
But now I'm invested,
now I got the ipad,
so I know that's how it works.
Right?
But the things,
the differences can carry that around in
your pocket.
Yeah,
I know that is a difference.
Yeah.
But um,
so when the idea is that there's a set
of questions in our brains as
professional physicists,
there's an infinite number of questions,
but at any one time you're focusing on a
couple and you have a couple of ideas.
And so you say to yourself,
well,
maybe if things are like this,
then this would follow and let's try to
calculate what that would lead to.
And does that lead us someplace good?
Or is that just crashed and burned?
And that's what you do over and over
again until you get a paper you can
write.
And where do you start from?
Like what is a,
like let's say you get to the cafe,
like what's your starting point?
Well,
so for example,
let's do quantum mechanics.
So we want to understand,
um,
the many worlds interpretation of
quantum mechanics.
So you say that the world really is some
quantum wave function,
but you and I observe things like space
and tables and stuff like that.
Right?
So what does that mean?
What does it mean to say that there's a,
there's a table lurking in the wave
function of the universe or there's no
stars and galaxies.
So that means that there's some way of
writing the wave function of the
universe that is sort of here's a table,
here's the rest of the universe.
So I might write down on a piece of
paper,
well here is a toy model,
like a simple representation of the wave
function of the universe that includes
one piece and another piece and they're
interacting with each other.
How would I know that that was tabled?
Like how,
how would I know in tables they're not
really what we care about,
but why is space three dimensional,
right?
This is the kind of question we would
worry about.
So what would a wave function look like
that represented three dimensional
space?
Is that natural?
Could I poke at it and kind of make a
prediction for what the early universe
was like on the basis of that?
Things like that.
So now like when you do calculations,
like say if you were doing calculus,
do you study black holes at all?
A little bit,
yeah.
A little bit reading paper right now on
black or are you?
Yeah.
And what are you writing about?
Like what specifically?
Well,
there's this famous problem in black
holes that they evaporate,
right?
They give off radiation.
Stephen hawking back in the 19 seventies
said that black holes weren't completely
black.
Right?
There's,
there's quantum mechanics as they will
gradually evaporate away.
So that's fine.
We think we understand that.
What does that mean?
What does it mean to be,
they're not completely,
but what it is,
what a black hole is essentially like
the event horizon is this tiny,
infinitely dense area and it's sucking
in the galaxy around it.
And uh,
like supermassive black holes.
that is that there is this still
believed that there in the center of
every galaxy and they represent one half
of one percent of the mass of the galaxy
itself.
Tiny fraction.
Right?
So the larger the galaxy,
the larger the supermassive black hole
basically.
Yeah,
that's right.
So what is it?
So what is the black,
what is it?
Yeah,
a black hole is a region of space.
It's a region of space where the
gravitational field is so strong that
you can never leave that region of space
to go to the outside world.
Jesus,
that's what it is.
But.
So stephen hawking,
so that's the,
there's,
there's different sort of levels of
sophistication and thinking about what
black holes are.
So a one level is to forget about
quantum mechanics entirely.
Use general relativity.
Einstein's theory of gravity that he
invented 100 years ago,
1916.
And he says,
what is gravity?
It's spacetime curving on itself.
That's what gravity is.
And he has equations to tell you how
much space,
time curves,
etc.
So we can describe black holes in,
in those terms.
and one of the things you find is that
black holes only ever increase in size,
right?
They can suck things in,
but they'd never shrink because they
just suck things in.
But then in the 19 seventies,
stephen hawking says,
well,
what if we take into account quantum
mechanics?
There are,
you know,
there's these clouds of probability all
around the black hole.
And he says,
if I look at a black hole,
does it look completely black?
And the answer is to his great surprise
and still to hours,
no,
it doesn't look completely black.
Even black holes when you look at them,
will be seen to gradually emit photons
to emit radiation very,
very,
very slowly.
And how were you looking at them?
Like what method are you using this as a
thought experiment?
We've never seen this in the real world.
The actual black holes we know about
emit radiation so slowly there's no
practical way to actually observe it.
So this is entirely theoretical right
now.
So.
But if it is entirely theoretical,
how do you measure that?
They're not entirely black.
We haven't been able to do that.
We predict that they're not entirely
black,
but we've never verified that prediction
yet.
You're freaking me out,
man.
All this a lot.
A lot of physics is making predictions
that we can't get past,
but someday we're hoping.
But why even assume that?
I mean,
I don't understand what the motivation
for assuming that they're not entirely
black.
It's not an assumption.
It is.
If you believe what we think is already
true about general relativity,
the curvature of space,
time and quantum mechanics,
then hawking says it.
It follows from those assumptions that
black holes are not completely black.
they give off radiation.
Okay?
Now what about the theory?
And then I've heard this fairly
recently,
that there is potentially another
universe inside of a black hole that as
you go into a black hole,
you may in fact be going into another
universe that's filled with hundreds of
millions of galaxies that have hundreds
of millions of black holes to the center
and perhaps hundreds of millions of
universes inside of them,
right?
Uh,
it's possible,
which again,
as I said earlier,
is what you should always say in these
circumstances.
There's no reason to think it's likely,
but it's certainly conceivable that that
happens.
By the way,
the journey would not be pain free.
When you look inside the black hole,
you would die or you'd be very,
very.
The technical term is spaghetti
[inaudible] because the gravitational
pull is much stronger at your head than
at your feet as you're diving headfirst.
So you will be pulled into a very thin
nonliving with cannon ball,
but that doesn't help.
Doesn't help.
Did you go crazy when you saw that movie
interstellar where,
you know,
it was a weird thing.
I actually know a lot about the
backstory there because kip thorne,
who was,
who invented the idea,
what is it?
My colleague at caltech.
So,
um,
If you know,
remember the movie or the book contact
carl sagan wrote that movie.
So carl sagan,
it was a brilliant guy,
but he was not a physicist.
He was a planetary scientist.
He studied life on other planets and
things.
So in his novel he had this idea,
he wanted his heroin a lie to get across
the galaxy very,
very quickly,
faster than the speed of light.
And so in the first draft he said she
falls into a black hole and then she
gets spit out somewhere else in the
galaxy and he knew that that couldn't,
that's not exactly right,
but it didn't sound right.
So he called up his friend to kip
thorne,
whose a very famous physicist at caltech
who is,
by the way will be winning the nobel
prize and a couple months in october.
Is it rigged a.
No,
but it's just such an obvious choice
for.
Because he also helped invent lego when
they discovered gravitational waves.
And that's definitely gonna be worthy of
the nobel lego lego.
Yes.
What's that?
Uh,
do you remember hearing the
gravitational waves were detected a
year,
year and a half?
Yes.
So lego is the observatory that did
that.
Oh,
okay.
So that's his law,
the observatory.
So he was one of the other,
one of the moving pieces,
moving forces behind that.
So gravitational waves were some
theoretical thing that's now been proven
to be real.
That's right.
Big announcement about the new
gravitational waves from ligo might
become.
And yet that was August 24th.
Pretty recent one hour ago.
Oh yeah,
I know what it is.
Whew.
So there's another.
I know.
What is it?
Tell us.
Can you tell us?
Um,
I can tell you because it's on the
internet because I don't want to tell
you because it's,
I should let lego tell you,
and this is a rumor,
but I,
I would just say stay tuned.
When we saw,
when we saw last year,
the announcement was black holes were
spiraling into each other and giving off
gravitational waves and that's what we
saw.
Okay.
That's,
that was the source of the gravitational
waves that we saw.
This news story is about neutron stars
spiraling into each other or spiraling
into something.
I don't even know the details.
They just a rumor,
but it's a different source for the
gravitational waves than we had before.
Here it is beyond black holes.
Could lego have detected merging neutron
stars for the first time now merging
meaning like this infinitely slow pace
that you're sort of measuring.
Nobody's very fast.
Very fast.
It takes seconds once,
once they're.
Once they're together.
Yeah.
Once they were very,
very close and emitting gravitational
waves you can observe.
Wow.
And the exciting thing is,
okay,
once black holes can merge,
why not neutron stars the differences
that black holes,
despite everything I just said them
about not being completely black,
are pretty darn black.
so you see gravitational waves,
but you don't see them in your regular
telescope.
With neutron stars,
there's a chance you can just see them
as well as detect the gravitational.
Now neutron stars,
now when they're doing this,
you know we're,
we're talking about like how far away
are we observing this?
Oh,
I don't know.
Usually millions of light years.
Wow.
So anything you're observing happened
millions of years ago.
Yep,
that's right.
Jesus.
That's the.
That's one of the bigger mindfox.
It's hard to get your head around when
you look it up in the sky and you're
seeing something that's a million light
years away.
Yeah.
When you're looking through a telescope,
you're seeing something that might not
even be there anymore.
Oh yeah.
Well,
in this case,
you know it's not because it gave off
one of the biggest explosions in the
universe.
Then that's what you're seeing.
The aftermath of those neutron stars are
no longer around.
If they're,
if they're that it might've made a black
hole,
there might be some black hole remnant.
Wow.
Yeah.
If we've observed the birth of a black
hole for um,
I don't think we've observed the birth.
We've observed one big black hole being
made out of two smaller ones.
That's a leg.
That's what lego saw,
right?
They actually observed it taking place.
It depends on the definition of
observed.
We know That it happened.
Yeah.
From the gravitational wave.
Sacred.
Sure.
That we observed.
Okay.
So you have a signature that is
undeniably the evidence of this.
Now this one,
I don't know the details here with a
neutron stars,
but they're,
they might be able to say there is no
black hole left behind.
I don't know.
I'd be surprised.
That sounds very precise.
Very unrealistic.
But that's the kind of thing we would
hope to be able to say someday.
I've seen that on drugs.
This thing.
Yeah.
You're showing if you take dmt,
you can see that.
So what is this?
Uh,
this is the animated depiction of these
two black holes spiraling into each
other.
And because this is another one of my
caltech colleagues that do need to get
outside and it looks like he's just been
buried in books,
then we wouldn't get good physics and
those people went outside.
Don't let him outside little bit.
StAy inside that a lIttle bit,
buddy.
Kid outside of some pictures don't make
themselves,
I'm sure.
No,
I'm sure they delegate.
He's got this fish on the wall,
he's losing his mind.
He's drawn fish.
Um,
when like when you try to make these
visual representations of something that
is like,
essentially you're,
you're,
you're only interpreting,
you're getting the gravitational wave,
you're getting the information that
data.
And then you try to make a visual
representation of this thing that's for
the general public,
right?
It's not basically not really for you
guys.
That's right.
So if you could also though see the
event happened using visible light or
using your regular telescopes,
that will give you enormously more
information.
So that's always a good thing to aim
for.
So as they do like this,
uh,
this array that they're putting together
in Chile and all these different,
new,
more advanced super telescope are
raised,
they're trying to get more and more
actual visual information so that people
could see this stuff or something.
Something.
I mean,
there's a lot.
It's much easier to detect light than it
is to detect gravitational waves.
So this is the sound.
This is the actual gravitational wave
from the early detection's,
the first ones we got last year.
So this is lygo hanford on top,
and lego livingston.
Is this the actual sound?
There is no actual sound.
They translate it into sound.
It's a gravitational wave that they
said,
well,
what if it were a sound wave instead of
gravitational waves?
This is how it would sound so confused.
And I was watching a documentary and
they were talking about hyper novas and
uh,
they were talking about the initial
discovery of hyper novis that they
detected this gamma radiation,
these bursts in the sky.
And they originally had one working
theory that there was some sort of an
alien war going on right now.
Always do that.
Like astronomers,
bless their hearts,
they are happy to at least contemplate.
Some of them are way out speculations
like when pulse ours,
which are just spinning neutron stars.
When they were first detected,
they were called lgm for little green
men because they were these very,
very regular pulses and people say what
could it be alien?
Right.
It's sort of not like one of those
planets that we've observed recently had
something that was orbiting it and they
were trying to figure out if it was some
enormous space station that was causing
this.
Well,
there was,
yeah,
there's a something that got labeled the
alien mega structure,
which is basically like something that
is bigger and colder than you would
expect,
but maybe if it were,
you know,
some structure surrounding a star,
that's what it would look like.
And I wouldn't bet on that.
I don't think that's the reasonable.
Whenever I read something like that,
I'm like,
oh,
they just want funding.
They just want to get people excited.
You don't get any funding for that.
No anti get funding for that.
For really.
For an alien mega star.
Yeah.
Because the people giving you funding or
your fellow scientists
taking cheap thrills rather than being
serious.
So what you Do is you get hits for your
website and you might not necessarily
like when you're going through some of
these websites that science websites for
the most part really straightforward
sort of titles to their articles.
But occasionally you get a little click
baity oh yeah.
With some stomaCh women.
Human beings,
they would like little more likes on
their juice it up a little bit.
Get people excited.
Yeah.
Um,
so when they first initially discovered
this,
these gamma ray bursts and they thought
there was some sort of an alien war
going,
going on in space.
Um,
I mean there's,
I mean,
so far,
nothing,
right?
So far there's no detectable evidence
whatsoever of anything out there other
than us.
That's right.
But wheN the thing,
if there is,
I mean when an,
if.
Right.
If the thing comes,
if one day we get some sort of
undeniable signal,
whatever it is,
or we see something or how does that get
processed?
Like do you have to go like straight to
president trump and go,
hey man,
I would not do that.
No,
that's not what I would do is like saY
if it was one of your colleagues
though.
There is a procedure.
It's not even very well publicized as
far as I know procedure or like a more
self appointed.
I think it's like,
you know,
people have said,
all right,
we are the alien detection network.
You might be able to keep your mouth
shut if you like.
People can't handle this shit.
Well I think it's,
I think that we're not very realistic
about these.
I think that it could happen.
Um,
but we're just like with quantum
mechanics or artificial intelligence or
whatever,
we tend to put everything in the frame
of what we're immediately used to.
Right?
So we can redeem out radio signals into
space.
We're really good at that.
Right?
So we tend to think that aliens will
either be discovered or actually contact
us by beaming radio signals and us.
But that's a hOrrendously wasteful way
to do interstellar communication.
Right?
For one thing,
radio waves move at the speed of light.
So imagine you're a thousand light years
away,
you have no idea what's going on on
earth,
but you say,
well,
there's a.
It's a promising location for life to
arise.
I know wHat I'll do,
I'll beam a signal at them.
Well,
how long are you going to be mad?
You're going to turn the telescope on
for a month.
Then in the whole history of humankind,
they better be listening the exact right
month.
Otherwise they're not going to hear it.
It's actually way more efficient to send
a spacecraft eVen though it's much
slower.
That's okay.
You have plenty of time.
Send a space craft and park it in the
system that you want to know about and
then wait for life to arise in that
system.
So honestly,
if we're going to detect evidence for
aliens,
it's much more likely we're gonna find a
monolith on the moon or something like
that.
Then we're going to hear them in our
telescopes.
A monolith.
The moon wasn't
that 2001,
right?
But wasn't that something that uh,
one of the astronauts said they saw
something up there.
Some of those astronauts have lost their
mind as they got older and I've always
wondered,
like edgar mitchell's the big one,
he's the one who says he's seen some
things that aliens are real and I always
wonder,
are those guys getting crazy as they get
older or they're going,
look,
I got to get some money.
I need some.
I need some attention.
What's the best way to do it?
It happened to that alien market.
That alien market's a big market.
They could be perfectly sincere,
but look the way you want when you pick
who's going to be an astronaut is
someone who can fly the spacecraft bank,
right?
They don't need to have good judgment
about whether or not they're aliens up
there.
That's not what you're goIng for.
You.
they just need to have an understanding
of what the task is and how they're
gonna perform it.
Yeah.
Edgar miTchell was a he.
I think he might've passed away
recently.
Did he pass away,
but he's one of those guys that people
always bring up when I'm not a believer
necessarily in.
Not that I'm not a believer in alien
life,
but I'm not believer in anY of the
people that say they've seen aliens.
Are you juSt.
I did a show for psi phi and one of the
episodes we did,
we spent weeks talking to people that
are ufo researchers and studying the air
quote evidence,
right,
and there's nothing there like be a good
basie and if someone sees some flashing
lights in the sky,
what is more likely alien civilization
or they're not accurately reporting what
they saw,
like eye witness testimony is terrible,
terrible,
terrible in this specialty,
in these weird cases.
Yeah.
IT's just very,
very dismissible.
So.
Right.
And you want to keep an open mind
because if there was a unique event
where an alien spacecraft did enter our
atmosphere and observe us and then take
off,
it would be quite fascinating.
If you could actually get a good read on
some more.
I think it'd be hugely important to the
history of life on earth,
right?
Like human history.
If we won,
if and when we finally discover
intelligent life out there somewhere
else,
that will be one of the most important
events in our history.
The idea that it's a,
you know,
a 20 foot long flying saucer that comes
and visits you in,
in Wyoming is not very plausible.
well also the idea of physical beings on
board.
this thing seems counterintuitive.
Like why?
Why would they do that?
Like we don't have to do that anymore.
Like we send the mars rover up there,
we get amazing footage.
It stays up there forever.
It doesn't need food.
Exactly.
So that's what they'll do.
They'll send a rover here.
Not a.
Not a either a person or a radio wave.
That's what I would imagine.
I would imagine it would be.
Obviously I don't know what the fuck I'm
parked.
So if you're getting mad right now,
I get rid of the aliens.
That's okay.
I would just assume that it would be
some super complicated drone and what
they would.
Yeah,
they would try to just take data,
observe,
maybe get some sort of a visual
understanding and obviously with the
kind of telescopes that we have,
like the [inaudible] eight when they
were 22,000
miles out,
we take these incredible high resolution
detailed video and photographs of the
earth itself.
What kind of shit to the aliens.
they probably don't need to get anywhere
near us.
Right?
Yeah.
Imagine that
weird thing is there.
You know,
the fermi paradox,
they should be here already,
right?
Like the solar system should be buzzing
with these drones and either a.
Well almost certainly it's not because
it's not clear why they would try to
hide from us really.
And if they don't try to hide,
they'd be easily noticeable.
So there's something we don't understand
about life in the universe either.
it's much more rare than we might guess
or for some reason it's not very
gregarious that doesn't go and visit the
rest of the stars in the galaxy.
My thought was,
and this is a obviously a very
controversial thought,
but no one wants to think that we're the
first.
Right.
That's like,
well,
if there's us,
then there's probably more right,
maybe right,
but maybe it has to happen once.
Some it has to happen for the first time
somewhere,
right?
Like this,
like a single celled organism had to
become a multicell organism and had to
take place through mutation and it had
to take place at one point in time.
Will that time on this planet,
at least it was the first time was one,
one point eight mil billions of years
ago.
Right?
Why do we have this?
We know that we are the only thing
that's ever done that as far as we know
here,
so why would we assume that anything
else that we might be the tip of the
spear?
It's completely possible,
I think,
and it's also possible that we're.
That life happens all the time,
but it never becomes multicellular or
intelligent.
Mm,
right.
Or becomes intelligent,
but never build spaceships.
There's many,
many ways it could happen,
but yes,
we could be in the entire observable
universe.
The only spaceship building species
right now.
Well,
we also have this weird way of defining
intelligence by the ability to change
your atmosphere,
your environment,
or your to,
to,
to build things like,
that's what we think of as intelligent,
whereas dolphins are obviously extremely
intelligent,
but they don't really impact their
environment much at all other than
biological life,
like eating things and waste and things
along those lines.
But they don't build structures.
They don't,
they don't keep records,
they don't.
And we live in a weird planet that is
roughly,
you know,
I'm a comparable proportion of land to
ocean,
right?
Be very easy to imagine planets that
were all ocean that,
that the dolphins were the apex
predators and that was right.
And so,
uh,
just got really smart,
really good at eating fish.
Yup.
Yeah.
They played games and whistled songs and
that was great.
Yeah.
Well also the idea that life only has to
exist in this goldilocks zone has always
been weird to me.
Oh yeah.
No,
very strange.
Also,
I don't know,
one that we're already finding
exceptions to that,
right?
Like even here in the solar system,
uh,
you wouldn't necessarily look to earth
first if you didn't already know,
uh,
the moons of jupiter and saturn are very
plausible places to look for the of
life,
even though
they're outside the goldilocks zone
because it's just different conditions.
So I think we should be very,
very open minded about the conditions
around other stars where life could
form.
Yeah.
I mean we find weird life at the bottom
of oceans and volcanic events insanely
hot.
And they find these,
these life forms that are able to thrive
in those conditions that would kill
almost everything else.
Yeah.
And part of that is,
you know,
it's,
I think that the response to that would
be,
well,
life started in fairly benign conditions
and then evolved to survive in these
harsher conditions.
But I just think that our ability to
understand chemistry and biology is not
that good.
Especially hypothetical speculative
chemistry and biology.
We should be very humble about saying
how life needs to be on other planets.
Right?
We always assume that it has to have
water and it has to get carbon based
and,
and maybe that's right,
but we can't say that we know.
Right.
Did you ever go through a period in life
where you were obsessed?
Are fascinated by aliens?
Yeah.
When I was a kid,
uh,
I certainly not only aliens,
but psychic powers and all this stuff.
I was very,
uh,
you know,
interested in all the cool stuff and I
became more and more scientific as I
aged and yeah,
those are weird things that are somehow
or another linked together because
they're,
I don't want to be mean in saying this,
but they're bullshit.
You know,
like the psychic powers are aliens and
when you bring up the fact that it's
very likely these things are bullshit.
People get very upset.
Like you're taking away their santa
claus.
I don't know.
There's a video I saw literally this
morning on the web of the.
These people stood outside a little mark
on the corner of a street in New York
where people were buying power ball
tickets.
Okay?
So people buy powerball tickets and it's
like 10 bucks.
And they come out and they were offered,
can I buy your power ball ticket from
you for $20 for twice what you paid for
it and 11 out of the 14 people that I
said,
no,
I'm holding onto my ticket.
Right.
Because they thought that this ticket
was the winter and they're like,
this is $700,000,000
that I'd be given you for $20.
Right.
With no rational justification.
But they,
you know,
it's,
it's in some sense innocent.
If you just.
Okay,
you're wishful thinking about your own
little ticket,
that's fine.
But it leads us to be not completely
rational and planning our futures.
Yeah.
I'm with the people that won't take the
20.
Is that a role it come on?
I mean it might go in and buy two more
tickets yet with the 20 would just be 20
and it would just be $20.
Now you can go,
but you might have in your possession
you might the ticket or it might be the
next one.
But what if you give it to them?
Give them the ticket,
you get to 20,
you go buy some users tickets.
And turns out the ticket you gave them
was 700 million bucks.
You've got to jump off a roof.
And what if the one you buy is the worst
one?
The one that when you're a glass half
full kind of guy,
aren't you?
The probabilities work out,
you know,
it doesn't really matter.
You don't know what the number is going
to be.
Right?
But that the randomness of it all,
what gets people like
panicky,
right?
Like what if,
what if it could be,
I mean,
the best way to,
you know,
calibrate your odds of winning the
powerball or saying,
you know,
just play the numbers.
One,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six.
And people were like,
well that's never going to come up.
You're like,
actually the probability of that kind of
is the same as any other one that you're
going to pick.
Huh?
Doesn't matter what it was.
Just random.
Now,
have you ever read anything compelling
at all that leads you to think that
maybe somebody might have observed
something that could potentially have
been something from another planet or
some sort of.
No,
I don't think so.
I mean,
I think that a astronomers do have a set
of things that they don't understand
very well.
The most recent example are these things
called fast radio bursts,
which are a little bit different than
the gamma burst,
gamma ray bursts,
but you know,
as always,
the more we think about it,
the more we say,
oh,
actually I can come up with a perfectly
plausible explanation for that is
nothing to do with alien.
I'm going back to this sort of uploading
consciousness thing.
There's a very real possibility that
once civilizations or intelligence pcs
become sufficiently advanced,
they upload themselves and they realize
there's not really any motivation to go
exploring the universe and maybe die
anymore.
Yeah.
That's what my thought would be,
that once civilizations get sufficiently
advanced,
they would go per virtual.
They would figure out a way to create
these artificial universes to travel
into that are probably just as complex,
if not more.
I think we have every right to imagine
that given them,
you know,
so little about what it would be about
right now.
Yeah.
But if we can create artificial
intelligence to that is the very
bizarre.
It's like if we can create artificial
intelligence and somehow or another
corral it into existing only in this
virtual world that we've created,
and then inside this virtual world
you're interacting with these
artificially intelligent creatures that
are disembodied,
right,
and then in this world you would give
them some sort of a body and you would
interact with them.
I think that again,
the thing that we under appreciate about
that is what is the motivation that
these artificially intelligent entities
would have?
Like we human beings like it or not,
we get hungry.
We wouldn't have sex,
we wouldn't have power or whatever,
but like if you're just a virtual being
in an environment without these
energetic constraints or a need to eat
and sleep and so forth,
why do you do anything at all?
I don't know.
I mean,
why would.
I have no idea what the psychology would
be like for something like that.
Did you see x mokena?
I did not.
How dare you?
That's an amazing movie.
I saw it twice actually.
I think I saw three times.
It's really good.
I mean,
it is a very balanced take on potential
artificial intelligence and someone
making it as you can see it really well
made movie,
but you see the story that was sort of,
I don't want to give away too much of
it,
but you see the struggle in these things
as this guy is interacting with these
things and you see the struggle as
they're to
interpret what they are.
Right versus what he is.
But they are in bodies,
right?
They're like,
yes,
yes.
Yeah,
yeah.
Gotta wonder like what?
I mean,
elon musk is terrified of this shit,
right?
I mean,
he said that we might be summoning the
demon.
That's his exact quote.
Yeah.
And I get a trouble.
I tend to agree with him.
Um,
and again,
to get in trouble on twitter for saying
that I agree with him,
but because people who are actually
doing artificial intelligence have this
very real appreciation for how far away
we are from something that you would
classify as intelligent in any real
sense.
And so therefore from their day to day
perspective,
the worry about superintelligent ai is
taking over the world is laughable.
But my argument,
and I think Illinois is that,
yeah,
but what is the percentage chance have
to be that this is going to happen
before you start worrying about it,
if,
if the consequences,
really the ruination of the world,
right?
There are only so many things that we do
for which the worst case scenario is
quite that bad.
That's what makes it a special
circumstance and it might be very,
very unlikely,
but are you willing to say like,
okay,
one percent chance that all human being
destroyed?
I don't think that's,
that's actually the worry,
but we should just do our due diligence,
right?
We should think about what the
possibilities are.
We should plan for them.
Probably no big deal.
When I said this on twitter,
people knowing that I was a physicist,
we're like,
well,
what did you think about people who are
worried that the large hadron collider
was gonna destroy the world?
Right?
I said,
well,
what do you mean?
Physicists did many,
many studies checking to see whether or
not it would destroy the world.
We don't want to be destroyed anymore
than anybody else and so I think that's
a very sensible thing to do for
artificial intelligence also.
yeah,
I agree.
It just when you see articles like did
you see the recent article or the google
ai that they had to shut down because
they were starting to communicate which
with each other they invented.
That language was not very convincing.
If you ever saw it printed out,
I'm sure.
But to me that's,
that's like a scene in a horror movie
where like,
and then you go to 10 know blank screen.
Ten years later we're all dressed up
like mad max.
We fucking,
you know,
bandannas over our face and we're
running from terminator bots.
So I think that's the thing,
you know again,
and again we're coming to this theme
that our imaginations are not quite up
to the task because our imaginations
about superintelligent ai or something
like that.
SomeThing frankensteined ask it just in
robots or something like out of asimov,
but the I think much more realistic
worry or things like currently existing
neural networks and deep learning
algorithms.
So basically there's all sorts of
problems like pattern recognition,
facial recognition,
right?
We are very,
very bad at sitting down and writing a
program that recognizes faces.
Human beings are not very good at
figuring out how to do that,
but we have ways of building programs
that can teach themselves to recognize
faces and they're amazingly good.
So we have programs like when you onto
google or your
itunes or whatever and you know your ifo
is recognizing your face.
There is some neural net that is doing
that and there is no human being alive
that understands what it's doing.
All we know is that it's getting the
right answer.
Okay.
And that can be.
That kind of logic can go very,
very far.
And so I'm not worried about like a
robot like ultron taking over.
I'm worried about are all of our
infrastructure being run by programs
that no human being understands.
whoa.
Oh,
that's something I hadn't even
considered,
but yeah,
that's a real issue.
The real issue,
right?
That's an actual real thing.
I've always wondered whether or not what
human beings are doing with our insane
lust to innovate and to constantly
create new and more spectacular things
and to always look for the next version
of something.
We're not satisfied with the iphone six.
We want the iphone seven.
That's not a problem,
but that wednesday the eight come out.
We always have this intense desire for
better things.
We don't.
I mean,
unless you're a classic car advocate or
add a devote,
we really what you want is like,
oh,
this new car stops faster at handles,
better,
accelerates quicker.
We always want things to constantly
improve and I've always.
And when you look at human beings,
like if you looked at us subjectively,
that's one of the main things that we
do.
We,
we produce better technology,
better objects,
better engineering.
It's like constantly improving and
accelerating and then there's this
potential artificial intelligence thing.
I've always wondered if that's really
what our focus or what our purpose is on
this planet that were like some sort of
an electronic caterpillar there going to
become a butterfly that we recognized
and some sort of a weird way or nature
recognizes the biological limitations of
flesh and tissue and that it can advance
far better with something that we create
so that we don't even realize what we're
doing by making this cocoon that we're
just building it up,
building enough and we're not even
thinking about what we're doing.
We just,
I want a new laptop,
woo,
and by buying this and buy this
materialism that we all have,
right?
We have with this,
people have this innate sort of desire
for new and shiny objects that that is
fueling this innovation and that's
pushing along this and that one day
we're going to give birth to this new
version of life.
We can call it artificial life,
but it's not artificial.
It's right there.
It's just created by human beings,
which obviously are created by this
intense and very long evolutionary
process,
but this might be a part of that
process.
Yeah,
so I would,
I would tend to want to remove from that
the sort of anthropomorphic are
teleological aspects of the language
like that it's a purpose or were meant
to be here,
but I completely agree with the idea
that there's a threshold that has been
crossed,
whether you want to say it's the last
500 years or the last 10,000
years,
uh,
they're human beings have developed the
ability to do something that has never
been done before and that has this sort
of recursive self reflective thing that
we can build things that can build
things and we can build things that can
learn and we can build things that are
like living things.
And we are just at the very,
very beginning of exploring the space of
what's going to happen because of that.
And the idea that we human beings are
going to be around 10,000
years to enjoy the fruits of that.
I have no idea whether that's true or
not.
I don't even know if that's bad.
I mean,
maybe it'll still be human beings.
Maybe 100 years from now we'll cure
death and aging and we'll stop having
kids and the people who are alive a
hundred years from now will different
other million years.
Maybe human beings will just become more
and more,
uh,
melded with artificial things and
they'll have artificial bodies and so
forth.
Or maybe,
you know,
one another under appreciated thing I
think is that at the very,
very small scale where we do like
nanotechnology and so forth,
there is a whole bunch of problems that
have already been solved at that scale.
Namely biology cells,
right?
Like cells do many,
many things really,
really well and they also repair
themselves.
They're much less brittle than things
that we build using metal.
Okay.
So synthetic biology,
just programming existing biological
organisms or designing new ones,
but we would still recognize them as
biological,
but it might be very,
very different than anything that
naturally appeared through the course of
evolution so far.
That could be the thing that takes off
and 100 years from now,
that's all the living beings or all the
beings with higher intelligence left on
earth.
I mean,
I don't know what the actual thing
that's going to happen is,
but what I know is that the pace of
change is just accelerating.
We're just at the very start.
Yeah,
we really are.
And it's,
it's.
So do you ever sit around and try to
extrapolate and trying to like look at
where we are now as opposed to where we
were at the turn of the century and a
20th century and just thinking like
where is this going?
I mean this,
it seems like any day now some new
invention can be put forth that changes
the way we interface with reality.
Right.
And it's subtle because it's not
uniform,
right?
It's not like it's a weird fact if you
wanted to make a movie and set it 50
years ago.
Right.
So in the 19 sixties it wouldn't be that
hard to film outside and in certain
areas,
certain suburbs,
it kind of looks more or less like look
in the 19 fifties.
Whereas it's actually,
it would be harder to make something
that was in the 19 sixties look like it
did the 1910.
It's right.
There's sort of more obvious visible
change just because cars were different
and so forth,
but you don't see the sort of
technological change that might be have
a far bigger impact,
uh,
in electronics and artificial
intelligence and so forth had happened
in the
last 50 years.
So jessica,
there's no visible sign of the change.
Doesn't mean that the changes cannot be
eventually a very profound.
It's always amazing to when you look
back and like science fiction movies
from the eighties where they were
predicting 2017,
you know,
they,
they thought we were going to be flying
around in space constantly.
Yeah,
like the movie alien.
What year was that supposed to be?
I think that's like the year $2,100
or something like that.
Right?
It's not that far,
but what we're really good at is taking
things that already exist and
extrapolating it to be faster and
bigger.
Right.
So if you can build an airplane,
then you can build a rocket ship and
arbitrarily fast.
That's easy to imagine.
But things that change culture,
like really curing aging,
that's hard to imagine what that would
be like.
It's also greedy because like where are
we going to put all these goddamn
people?
If they live forever,
you live forever and everybody has four
kids.
We've got a real problem on our hands.
No more.
No more kids.
No ham clearly.
Do you have kids?
No.
Well that's why you say that,
but I'm not gonna live forever either.
You know,
if I did have kids and maybe their kids
would live forever,
but you know,
that's,
that's the thing.
That's the size of the change in society
that will be required by something like
that.
Twenty one,
22.
That's When alien takes place.
That's 100 years from now.
Get out of here.
There's no way it could be.
Maybe a model.
They had some shitty monitors for 21,
22.
I mean,
god,
they were terrible.
Terribly one know.
Yeah.
But the inside of the cockpit for mother
when that dude gets in there and finds
out that there's some giant plate far
into the future.
Right?
oh yeah.
It's really,
really hard.
Yeah.
I think we're more likely looking at
some sort of a augmented a desktop sort
of scenario.
Like,
um,
have you seen these new products like,
uh,
that microsoft is working on and some of
these other companies,
but I think before very long,
it won't be a desktop,
it'll just be our thoughts really.
We'll just,
you know,
like I remember what I had for lunch.
I'll remember what the population of
Malta was in the year.
1,500.
What am I looking at here?
Jamie?
Shitty movies.
This.
Yeah,
this is the first one said.
I mean,
that's.
So I was googling,
it could of got tagged with something
else and I didn't recognize it,
but that's pretty,
that's pretty good.
looking pretty good.
No,
that can't be the original alien is it?
I Think that's like alien two or three.
No dramas.
Yeah,
this is bill.
Is that the first one?
The second one you clicked on?
Yeah,
that's,
yeah,
they look pretty bad ass.
So that's trauma.
What I meant was there's a white room
that,
uh,
I forget the actor's name in the
original alien,
the original alien.
People don't even realize it was in the
seventies.
It seemed crazy.
Yeah,
it's corny weaver ages very well,
by the way.
Just,
sorry,
what was the.
Oh,
the defenders here's done yet.
Um,
because she was in that movie up.
she's probably in her twenties back
then,
but that movie in 1979,
like their idea of what?
Twenty one,
22 is going be like they had
like weird lights flashing and the cabin
that didn't really seem to make a lot of
sense,
but they looked electronics.
These might've been pictures from the
new alien.
Yeah,
that's what it looks like.
Yeah.
Because they could do to kind of look
like a tesla is yours.
Yeah,
it was weird because they're kind of
saying this is like from actual
production set.
Oh yeah,
that's the new one.
See?
Because they're kind of saddled down by
the problem that they're replicating a
film,
you know,
that was from the 19 seventies and there
might be settled down by the deavers
that look like you're in an airplane.
Yeah.
Would not be like that.
You don't think so?
No.
It could still be here in your head.
He thinks I need buttons.
Yeah.
So even navigation while being here.
Well,
I think we live in the only generation
that's going to get repetitive stress
injury from poking it or devices all the
time.
Really?
Yeah.
That's what,
that's the most useless thing that.
well,
it's a very slow,
inefficient interface type.
Being on your cell phone.
It takes best.
I hardly do it anymore.
A lot of times I'm talking to my phone
now.
That's very old fashioned wri.
Very retro.
No,
no.
Using voice recognition software.
Yeah.
Okay.
Right.
That's retro mean when to make phone
calls.
oh,
I do that too.
I'm a crazy phone call person.
Um,
but the uh,
text function ready for his recognition
function,
that's really amazing.
I don't use it as much,
but yeah,
look how good it works.
I'll show you right now.
It's really pretty interesting.
We can click on this,
right?
There's like the notes thing.
This is how I do a lot of this stuff.
Like if in my car and I have an idea
that comes to me,
I'll either record it like with the
voice recording function or sometimes
it's better to do this and when you're
doing this it essentially can pick up
everything you're saying in real time
and print it out.
Yep.
They cut it right.
That's amazing.
Right?
Bad is.
I mean everything perfectly spelled.
What I Just said folks is now on my
phone.
Amazing.
What does this scene,
these are the new.
I don't know how well they work.
I've only seen him out and commercially
whatnot,
but real time in ir translations and
french spanish,
english.
I've seen chinese,
japanese.
oh,
I've seen that.
Size of an ear bud.
Yeah,
I've seen that.
So again,
once you have the link inside and he
just interface with your brain,
then essentially you will speak every
language.
One hundred 29 bucks.
That's amazing.
So you can go.
Is it called babel fish?
That's what it's called.
Like it like it.
Like oh,
that's not the name,
but I know,
but that's not the name of it.
What is it?
What's the name of it?
This one I have now from waverly labs,
it's called the pilot.
I think the pilot.
This is pretty awesome though.
You just go this way.
He's japanese.
One of them.
On this particular one?
I don't believe so,
but I'm 90 percent sure.
I've seen videos like on facebook
showing a japanese one.
I'm finding my first trip to Japan and
that'd be very bad.
Just has amazing.
Yeah,
I've never been there.
What you going to go to tokyo?
Where are you going to go?
We were flying.
There's a conference in food cola and
then we'll visit a hiroshima and osaka
after that.
Oh wow.
Kyoto.
Hopefully.
I went to Japan a few years back and it
feels
like you're in a super polite alien
world.
Happy.
That sounds good to me.
It's beautiful.
They're very polite and the food's
amazing.
Even more one to one.
And then using watson.
Watson to do more languages and I just
said before portuguese scroll up so I
can see what it looks.
So watson is an example of one of these
programs which learns things that we
don't know how.
Right.
Okay.
That's a problem.
And that speaks japanese and french.
So yeah.
So this one is,
um,
how does it,
where jamie,
what do you see the bluetooth and wifi
out of the range of bluetooth and wifi
translate one to one can still work just
as well as the first device on the
market for language translation using ai
that does not rely on connectivity to
operate.
It offers significant potential for its
unique application across airlines,
foreign government relations and even
not for profits working in remote areas.
Whoa,
that's crazy.
So,
uh,
so it's different than the pilot
earpiece.
How's it,
how do you wear that?
Soccer was like get over your head.
It sounds just like a hearing aid would
probably just look like that.
And I'll probably be big now just like
they use probably big gets smaller and
smaller.
This would not be sexy while you were
wearing it,
but yeah,
unless you're into that stuff.
Um,
it was saying that you download language
packs so it'll be off the internet.
Yeah.
So essentially it'd be like,
um,
there's these map applications like onyx
maps and stuff like that.
you can download like a,
like sort of a google earth type to
topographical map of areas and you could
look at it,
say if you're hiking,
you could look at these on your phone.
Even if you don't have cell service,
you can just pull them up and get a
google image of like,
oh,
hey,
here's the creek that we have to go down
to get water.
yeah.
Yeah.
We're getting.
It's getting super slippery.
Two hundred 79 bucks and you can use
that sucker.
That's right.
Now that's amazing part.
Don't do it.
Take three to five seconds to translate.
Woo.
Most languages there's a thing called
google lens,
which is pretty amazing too.
I use this when I was in Italy and you
take your phone and you look at
something through your phone and it
translates it on the screen,
which is amazing.
Like you're looking at a sign and you
hold it up and it'll tell you what the
site like.
We were at a train station.
I was like,
what the fuck does that sign?
Say you put your phone up there with the
google lens and it'll translate it.
I know I use that.
The only problem was like for menus,
it's like,
what is this out with roses chicken.
I have no idea what that is.
But yes,
right.
Yeah.
Well fortunately,
or unfortunately when you go abroad,
uh,
americans travel so much and so to a
english people from england shore.
Yeah.
But it's such a common language.
Most of the world can speak english.
That's right.
Yeah.
We would definitely have an advantage.
That was huge in Italy.
I mean it's like you barely need to
understand anything other than saying
thank you and saying,
you know,
hello and good evening.
Things along those lines.
One to sarah,
you,
um,
you can get by.
But yeah,
the first time I went abroad to farm
speaking country was France and I was
just too shy to talk to anybody because
I was not in paris.
I was like out in the middle of nowhere
where people did not speak english and
you know,
by now I'm an I.
And I even had like read the phrase
books and things like that.
But by now I've just done it so many
times.
I don't really care.
I'll try to speak my two words of the
local language and then try to switch to
english and if it doesn't work,
it doesn't work.
CAn we just do hand gestures?
When you traveled a place like France,
France,
excuse me,
people have this french people in
particular.
There's always the stereotype that you
hear that french people think that
americans are rude.
Like I would like try to go like way out
of my way to make sure that no one
thought I was like a rude american.
Yeah.
Because there's always this reaction
that they have.
Like the worst case scenario is the
american goes over there and it's pissed
off that they don't speak english and
they started don't know.
My first trip I was treated very,
very well in France.
Very,
very politely.
I even like I bought something in a
store and I didn't understand what the
price was,
so I just sort of kept gIving money
until they nodded and by mistake I had
given too much and the guy like ran out
after me to catch me leaving to give me
my money back.
That was uniform.
except in transportation industry.
It's like whenever I wanted to buy a
plane ticket or whatever,
that was very,
very hard.
The ironic enough with a rude or were
they just definitely tired of dealing
with tourists,
you know,
I would,
I would say in french I would say,
you know,
do you speak english?
And they would say,
of course I do in french.
I'm like,
okay,
well then can we do that?
Yeah,
they're probably just exhausted.
That just exists.
But that's how it is in America.
I mean,
you deal with people at the airline
counter.
They always had this look in their face.
Like,
what time is it?
When do I don't,
I don't have to doing something you're
not passionate about unlike you with
your legal notepad,
right.
In the alien languages and uh,
you know,
I can find somewhere it's a,
it's a great privilege what I do for
living,
right?
Like,
I can't believe that I get paid to do
this and it's hard.
I have to tell my incoming graduate
students,
if you get a phd in theoretical physics
from caltech and you probably want to be
a physics professor because that's the
only thing you can do with that degree
and your chances are maybe 25 percent of
that's pretty damn good.
It's good.
But after You,
you're like 26 years old and putting a
lot of work to still only knows the 25
percent chance of succeeding,
if that's still pretty amazing.
I mean,
if you're trying to be a standup
comedian,
your odds are like one percent if you're
lucky.
No,
the very,
very good thing about academia is it's
very clearly upper out and you know,
you,
there's time limits.
Like if you haven't succeeded by now,
you're gone.
You can to be discovered tomorrow.
Uh,
you usually go to wall street and make a
lot more money.
Oh,
so hE's to be in physics from caltech.
You're not going to start praying.
People will hire you to do something
interesting.
So what would you do on wall to wall
street with a phd from caltech these
days?
All the money's being made by algorithms
that study of the stock market
and destroy human beings picking stocks,
right?
Renaissance technologies and places like
that.
Um,
I mean,
like we were just talking about,
but soon the entire stock market will
just be dueling algorithms trying to
sell something a microsecond before
something else does.
Now you are involved in a hard science,
right?
I mean,
you're,
you're involved in this trying to
understand the world and the universe
itself.
Do you get,
do you see any of the identity politics
issues that are going on on campuses
today?
I mean,
it's such a hot subject,
whereas
a little bit,
you know,
I don't,
my job at caltech is research professor,
so I don't even teach a lot of courses
to be honest.
And caltech is not the typical campus in
many,
many ways.
Uh,
but you know,
we just had a professor who was
basically fired,
uh,
for harassing students.
It,
it does happen.
Sexual harassment.
Yeah.
That's trying to get laid.
It wasn't quite,
it was more complicated than that.
He fell in love with a student and fired
her.
And um,
and yeah,
there's just no question that,
you know,
I'm in an area of theoretical physics
where there's a very tiny fraction of
women,
um,
and even tinier fraction of african
americans and so forth,
but that's kind of less surprising
because they just don't come up usually
in economic circumstances that put
theoretical physics is one of the
plausible future research careers.
Uh,
But you know,
I see an enormous amount of
discrimination against women in my field
and it's there and women leave and some
of the complaints against it or are
overblown,
but many of them are very,
very real.
so that's a real problem for us.
I think it's changing.
I think it's fixing,
but it's slow.
What kind of discrimination do you see?
It's these days it's usually very
subtle.
It's usually a,
you're taking a little bit less
seriously if you're a woman.
I mean there's all sorts of tests that
have been done,
right?
Like people handed out a mathematics
papers and with,
and then all they did was change the
name of the author James Smith versus
Jennifer Smith.
And they were always ranked much worse
when it was Jennifer Smith who was the
author even.
It's exactly the same paper grilling
and,
uh,
and know there's a certain style of
aggressive in your face,
egotism that serves you well in academia
generally.
And in physics in particular,
uh,
putting yourself forward,
asking questions,
being loud and noisy and a women are
less good at that for whatever reason.
They're not trained to do that or it's
an eight.
I have no idea.
But,
uh,
they can sort of get bullied into
silence or just say like,
this is not worth it.
I'm going to go do something.
We go to wall street to make money.
Also a woman who does that is not likely
to be received as well as a man who does
that,
held against them.
Yeah.
They're deemed to be like a bitch.
So my guy was aggressive at caltech.
I'm on the fourth floor of a building,
which is the theoretical physics,
theoretical high energy physics group.
Uh,
so there's maybe 30 people,
total professors,
post docs,
graduate students.
Uh,
and until this year,
there were zero women out of 30,
which is just embarrassing.
It's just bad.
Right.
And who would want to be the one woman?
Right,
right.
Yeah.
But you know,
especially there's two like men either
who thinks they can have sex with you or
amanda can never have sex with you.
Right.
That was,
we both annoying and like,
if you're lucky you get a guy who
doesn't want to have sex with you,
he just wants to be your friend and
that,
that's all right.
Yeah.
But I think that,
you know,
honestly,
if I were giving advice to young women
whose primary goal was to become a
successful theoretical physicist,
you know,
if that was your only goal,
then don't raise a fuss about sexism or
discrimination because just like
worrying about the interpretation of
quantum mechanics counts,
it's points against you when you're
being judged as a theoretical physicist
worrying about discrimination against
you.
Key accounTs as points against you.
People think like,
oh,
you're,
you're not really interested in physics.
You just want to make a political fuss.
Wow,
that's unfortunate.
Keep quiet.
Yeah.
I mean,
I know that what you're saying is
pragmatic,
but a lot of people don't want to hear
that,
like keep quiet.
They don't want to hear,
keep quiet.
When you tell women too,
when you're talking about
discrimination,
so maybe your only goal in life is not
to personally become a successful
theoretical physicists.
I mean,
just as a.
I don't,
my advice is not keep quiet.
My advice is if that's your goal,
the way to achieve that goal is to keep
quiet.
That's gross though,
right?
It is.
and so I think that it's the job of the
guys to raise a little bit of a fuss
about this and you know,
I saw that at caltech where this guy
recently got fired.
How many people were willing to make
excuses for his really,
really,
really bad behavior.
Uh,
you know,
it's,
it's unseemly to talk about these
things.
We hope it's not true like these,
this is our friend.
This is someone we worked with.
We don't want to believe this about
them.
We want to protect him.
So physics,
philosophy,
astronomy,
all these areas are now having these
examples of famous big name professors
that it's finally being revealed for
last 20 years had been regularly
harassing graduate students and pushing
them out of the field.
I think maybe finally that's coming to
light enough that it's hopefully will go
away a little bit.
Human folly,
you know,
it's interesting.
It's a lot of what we were talking about
earlier with the people that don't
necessarily understand quantum physics.
And so they sort of dismiss what's
important about it or people that,
you know,
just use their,
they,
they rely too much on ego or they,
it's too much of a part of their life.
I mean,
they human folly,
that sort of make excuses and gets
involved in everything.
And you know,
I'm uh,
I'm not,
uh,
the broader question of identity
politics,
etc.
I mean,
I'm,
I'm pretty lefty justice warrior about
this stuff.
To be honest,
I think that,
uh,
the number of women,
for example,
women are just the most obvious example
in my field who have been
pushed out of my field because of bias
and discrimination in very,
very obviously,
you know,
um,
verifiable ways is just,
that's the big embarrassment,
you know,
but at the same time I'm kind of a free
speech absolutist if some crazy person
who has very retro grade views wants to
say those retrograde views.
And I think that if someone else wants
to invite them on campus to do it,
I think they should be allowed to say
all the craziness that they want.
I don't think that's the right solution
to these problems.
Yeah.
I think the solution in those cases,
for someone who's got a legitimate
viewpoint to debate them,
yeah.
The marketplace of free ideas.
Actually the chancellor at berkeley just
put out a very good statement saying
exactly that and I gave her credit for
that.
Well,
that's great.
You know,
Because I know that they have an issue
there with ben shapiro coming who is a
very reasonable guy and sometimes gets
lumped into the alt right and gets
lumped into these fees.
Not that at all.
It just happens to be conservative and
young and very articulate,
but for awhile they were trying to limit
his participation there and putting them
in the same category that they would put
milo yiannopoulos or of these other guys
here,
which it's we're,
we're very weird with free speech and
that we love free speech as long as it's
in line with how we defend free speech
for people we agree with.
Yeah.
I mean,
I don't know ben shapiro,
but Larry Summers is another example.
He gave this famous speech at harvard.
He was the president of harvard and a
world famous economist and he gave this
speech saying,
well,
maybe the reason why we don't have as
many women physicists as male physicist
is because of a,
a different distribution of innate
abilities.
Now I think that you could make a veRy,
very good case that his substantive
claims were entirely bullshit.
Like he misread the data and he was
making excuses and that's one thing.
That's the guy on the street.
It's another thing if it's the president
of harvard.
Okay.
But then after that,
like people were saying,
well he shouldn't be invited to give
talks about economics at other
universities because he said this bad
thing.
I think that's ridiculous.
He said,
we're world class economist.
Like he was wrong and you should
criticize him,
but I want to hear what he has to say
about economics.
That's something that
entirely different because it also.
There's never an issue with someone
who's a professor who's constantly used
to really not being questioned and been
giving lectures and being able to talk
in front of students and you develop
sort of a general hubris about your own
opinion.
Well,
I would hope that,
I dunno,
in my areas of academia,
you can't get through lunchtime without
having all of your opinions at the time.
Like that's just what we do.
Right?
Like it's,
you don't,
you never sit around and say something
and everyone agrees.
That seems like a very healthy
profession.
Then that's hoW to get things,
get,
make progress,
but of course usually we're talking
about the wave function of the universe,
dark matter.
Right,
and you know,
to be very,
very fair.
There's,
like we said before,
there's still prejudices about purely
physics topics like you talk about
quantum
mechanics or the nature of the dark
matter and in discussions get very,
very heated and emotional and people's
jobs depend on it and the whole bit.
But the idea that things go unchallenged
is not a.
That's just doesn't fly very far in this
field.
Well,
that's beautiful.
I would love to talk to you about what
you just said,
dark matter because that's something
that I would imagine if you went out and
just randomly polled a thousand people,
all 1000 would have no idea what dark
matter is.
Yep.
There may be gay.
Oh yeah.
It's like part of the universe.
It's really.
We can't find it,
but it's.
I think it was rick and morty recently
that had a silly episode about dark
matter.
It's a,
it's a cartoon,
a cartoon network.
Show a.
It's a hilarious,
silly thing that uses science fiction to
to,
to actually do that.
Yeah.
I think I know what you're talking
about.
Dark matter is real.
It exists.
Yes.
Okay.
How do we measure it?
We measure its gravitational force.
It pushes things around in the universe.
So what do we think it is that we don't
know?
That's the.
That's the thing.
We know certain things about it.
We know that it's dark.
We know how much of it there is.
It's about five times as much mass in
dark matter.
Then there is an ordinary matter.
Ordinary matter is every particle we've
ever seen ever,
right?
So all of the atoms,
all the stores,
all the galaxies that we see in our
telescopes,
that's five percent of the mass,
and then dark matter is 25 percent and
dark energy,
which is something completely different
is the other 70 percent of the universe
and these,
those are facts.
Those that's basically,
you know,
99 percent likely to be true.
What it is,
the dark matter,
the dark energy that is much more up in
the air that we have lots of candidates
and we're not sure which one is right.
Boy,
that doesn't help,
does it?
Well,
you know,
so I went on science friday,
science friday with a ira playdough npr
show.
Okay.
Um,
and he says,
he says like you,
cosmologist,
like,
shouldn't you be embarrassed?
You only understand five percent of
what's in the universe.
It's amazing.
They know that much.
We know five percent of us,
the universe,
like 100 years ago we didn't know
anything about the universe.
We didn't know the universe was
expanding.
We didn't really ever other galaxies,
you know,
come on.
This stuff takes more than a few months
to figure out five percent I think is
pretty healthy.
Yeah,
I think we're getting there.
What is the current theory as to like
where it resides and how it's formed and
what its properties are and what impact
it has on the galaxies?
I think this is a really,
really good question because we might be
in flux right now for a long time.
Like basically from the 19 eighties to
today,
there was a leading candidate for what
the dark matter was,
something called the wimp,
weakly interacting massive particle.
So if you indulge me for just a second,
we have the particles we know and love.
Uh,
there are four forces that push these
particles around.
There's gravity,
electromagnetism,
and then there's the strong and weak
nuclear forces to nuclear forces.
And the nuclear forces are distinguished
by being short range,
like you don't notice it in your
everyday life.
You gotta be down there at the atomic
scale.
So it turns out that if you imagine a
new particle that obviously interacts
through gravity because everything
interacts through gravity but doesn't
interact through the strong nuclear
force like a proton does,
or through electromagnetism that will be
charged,
but it interacts through the weak
nuclear force.
Okay?
So you imagine a particle interacts with
the weak nuclear force relatively heavy,
and you calculate how much of those
should be leftover from the big bang.
You get the right amount to be the dark
matter.
So this is called the wimp miracle.
The idea that if you just hypothesize
out of the blue,
a new particle that is invisible and
stable and interacts through the known
force of nature that we call the weak
nuclear force,
that could easily be the dark matter.
So that was seemed so natural and
simple,
and there were many more complicated
theories that predicted that such
particles would exist.
I would say that many people,
10 years ago or so,
I would have said there's a 90 percent
chance that wimps,
weakly interacting massive particles are
the dark manner.
Here's the problem.
If the wimps,
if the dark matter is wimps,
we can build detectors and look for
them.
And we have done that.
We've built these giant detectors,
deep underground.
You're shielded from all the cosmic rays
that are just noise and contaminating
your experiment,
uh,
and you wait for a little weakly
interacting,
massive particle to pass through your
detector and bump into an atom
underground underground.
Uh,
usually these are in minds,
right?
So they're an old gold mines,
a mile underground,
counterintuitive.
So you're going a mile underground to
search for something that's in space.
I made up the mile.
You might want to,
if you can get even 100 feet underground
in a deep mine,
it seems so counterintuitive.
You'd think you'd have to throw
something into the sky,
live in a noisy environment that the
trouble is not detecting them.
The trouble is seeing them peek out over
the noise.
That's what we're trying to do.
It's like going into a quiet room to
listen to something very,
very well.
Was the initial discovery that led to
the conclusion that dark matter is the
preeminent mass of the universe.
Like what?
What percentage of the masses?
It will.
Sorry,
let me just finish this up very quickly
because this point is that we have built
these detectors and we haven't seen the
wimps.
Oh,
okay.
So for the first time people are
beginning to shake their belief that
maybe wimps are the most likely
candidate.
There are other candidates,
other kinds of particles.
That could be the dark matter.
Maybe it's still winds.
We just haven't found them yet.
That's still possible,
but I would say if five years from now
we haven't found the wimps,
then people are gonna start saying it's
something else.
Okay,
so the first evidence,
uh,
well,
you know,
it comes in drips and drabs.
My,
my caltech predecessor,
fritz zwicky famous astrophysicist back
in the 19 thirties,
pointed out that galaxies were orbiting
each other too fast in what are called
clusters of galaxies.
You look out there in the sky,
you see like these bunches of galaxies
that are orbiting each other and you
calculate how heavy the galaxies should
be from what you see.
You can calculate using newtonian laws
of physics,
how fast they should be orbiting.
They're actually orbiting much faster.
And he said the only way for that to
happen is if they're much more massive
than youth on.
if there's much more mass in there,
there's some missing mass.
Okay.
But at the time we didn't know it could
just be stars that we didn't see or gas
or dust or whatever.
it wasn't really until the 19 seventies
that vera rubin famous astrophysicist
looked at how individual galaxies are
rotating and she found that it's a
similar kind of thing.
The edges of the galaxies are moving way
faster than they should be given the
amount of matter that is inside.
And she concluded that a lot of dark
matter causing a gravitational pull that
we didn't see but is causing this,
the edges of the galaxies to spend a lot
faster than they should be.
Wow.
so that is the reason why.
Is there a possibility that some new
discovery could happen or could come
forth where you would re examine this
idea that there's some missing mass is
always a possibility.
Um,
I,
so there's certainly this idea that is
on the market that because all of our
evidence for dark matter is indirect
because it's through it's gravitational
influence,
not by directly touching it or seeing
it.
Maybe we just don't understand gravity.
Maybe gravity is a little bit different
now.
I would argue,
and I think I'm right,
not everyone agrees with me sadly.
But,
uh,
that idea has basically been killed off
by our observations of the microwave
background radiation.
You know,
we are 14 billion years after the big
bang there was,
you know,
the big bang was very,
very hot and dense.
And is glowing to beat the band
everywhere,
but it was also opaque.
The light didn't get very far and about
400,000
years after the big bang it cooled down
enough,
it became transparent.
And then these,
this,
these photons of light just stretched
travel through the universe unimpeded.
And we can see that the leftoveR
radiation,
we can see these faint patterns,
these oscillations in the microwave
background,
which look exactly like they would look
if dark matter we're causing them and
they don't look what they would look
like if gravity were modified.
So there's a much longer version of that
story.
But the basic thing is if you,
if I can just pull authority and say,
trust me on this,
uh,
I was,
I was totally on board with the idea
that there was something wrong about
gravity.
That'd be very cool thing.
If it were true,
there'll be a big mind bending
discovery.
But we've tested that and the microwave
background,
there were predictions.
It would look this way if you modified
gravity that way,
if there were dark matter and the answer
is spot on to the dark matter of
predictions.
Very different from the modified gravity
So dark matter exists.
And what percentage of the universe is
currently believed to be matter?
Twenty five percent.
And I read once that they had discovered
in entire galaxy that was made out of
dark matter.
Yeah,
pretty close.
MayBe not entirely because then you
wouldn't see it,
right?
It's hard to discover it.
That was what I was going to ask.
How do you see this stuff?
Like how does,
like how if you can't detect it,
if you will,
you know it exists,
right?
But you know,
because of its effects,
that's a,
you don't,
you can't like point to it.
Like you can point to the sun,
right?
So you need some tracers,
you need something that tells you that
dark matter is influencing the motion of
stuff in this,
this mdm space.
So in a galaxy,
it's just like the stars at the edges of
the galaxy and most of the mass in our
galaxy is dark matter.
Like we see the pictures of galaxies
that you see that look very beautiful.
The actual size of the galaxy is much
bigger than that,
but it's all dark matter.
The galaxy you see is a tiny little
puddle,
you know,
one fifth of the total mass,
let it sort of settled down to the
center of this big puffy cloud of dark
matter.
Whoa.
And the.
When people say,
well,
there's a galaxy that is only dark
matter.
What they really mean is it's almost
only dark matter.
It's a puffy coat or dark matter where
most of the stars have been pushed out
by something.
But some of the stars or the gas you can
still see orbiting around and that tells
you there's a some concentration of dark
matter there.
Do we know what dark matter is or does?
There is.
There are.
There's lots of theories.
Chimps were the biggest theory,
but there's alternatives.
There's one alternative.
It could be small black holes that were
made in the very early universe that
seems unlikely.
There's another kind of subatomic
particle called the axion,
which is nice because people invented it
for totally different reasons and they
also worked out that could give you
exactly the right abundance to be the
dark matter.
And there's a whole,
there's the,
You know,
dozens of different theories out there
for what it could be.
So we're looking,
we're trying to figure out which one is
right.
What a weird thing to have something
that's invisible.
That's a giant percentage of the entire
universe in a large percentage of
galaxies,
right?
Yeah.
Percentage of galaxies as dark matter
most nineties in the nineties.
Yeah.
well,
uh,
let's say 75 percent,
80 percent,
something like that depends on the
galaxy,
but uh,
on the other hand,
what right to be think that we have to
think that most of the universe should
be readily visible to us.
Now,
does dark matter exists on earth or is
it only in deep space?
It depends on what the right theory of
dark matter is.
But in most theories,
there are dark matter particles passing
through your body right now.
So with this wimps detection theory of
where they've developed these detectors
deep in the ground,
would that would be able to detect
something that's actually prevalent here
on earth?
Yes.
And it's not that they're stuck to here
on earth,
there were,
the earth is just moving through space,
so there's a wind of dark matter
particles that were passing through and
occasionally bumping into and we're
moving in some sort of a spiral through
the moving and we're orbiting
around the sun,
right?
Yeah.
Now the,
the,
the Big bang one is another weird one.
um,
because I was watching this thing on
television that was proposing
alternative theories to the big bang and
one of them was that the universe is
next to another universe and that
somehow or another it collided with this
universe.
And that this is a probably a process
that repeats itself.
I know we get paid to come up with these
ideas and that's what we're doing.
you know,
they're in starbucks with the pencil and
paper.
Yes.
What do you buy iNto that?
Like which one do you
by handling it works?
No,
I don't personally think that that's
very likely.
It's on the table.
It's a reasonable.
Is it still on?
Is it a recent.
Yeah.
Um,
uh,
when was it first suggested?
Maybe around the $2,000
or so.
And did it,
did a bunch of people jump on board or
wouldn't say save something like that
comes up.
One of your colleagues has this idea,
so then you go to the cafe with your
legal pad and gore and how do we do
this?
exactly.
That's right.
And so what you would do in that case,
so someone proposed an idea and you say,
well,
okay,
how would we test it?
How would we know?
Well,
maybe,
uh,
like we said before,
maybe it predicts some pattern in the
leftover microwave background radiation
from the big bang.
If you're a different theory for what
happened at the big bang,
then maybe your imprint post big bang is
a little bit different.
And that's exactly the kind of thing
we're looking for now.
So
the imprint,
the microwave imprint of the Big bang,
this 14 billion year old event.
Yeah,
what is the,
like terence mckenna had a fucking
hilarious way of describing it.
I do a terrible job of butchering it,
but,
um,
that people like,
it's funny how he was talking about how
many scientists are atheists that they
don't want to believe in god they don't
want to in.
He was an atheist as well.
He was an atheist rather as well.
But,
uh,
he said,
but they are,
they do want you to believe that
everything came out of nothing for no
reason that anybody knows of 14 billion
years ago there was this infinitely
small area that was smaller than the
head of a pin.
And that's everything you see in the sky
and it exploded 14 billion years ago and
no one knows why.
That's right,
yes.
Good.
but isn't that a mean?
That is so crazy.
And you know,
it's one of those things that theorists,
you know,
uh,
people that are really into a god's
religion,
they point to like,
well,
this is the scientists.
God,
this is this,
this event,
this is a miracle.
I mean,
this is the way bigger miracle than
walking on water or turning wine into
water,
into wine.
I mean,
that's
baby stuff.
Exactly.
That this scenario would be 100 percent
compatible with the laws of physics in a
way that turning water into wine.
He's kind of not.
Yeah,
I think that the.
So here's the thing,
and I think this is actually not always
communicated very well.
The big bang is the phrase,
the big bang Is used in two different
senses.
One is what we call the big bang model,
which is the whole history of the
universe for the last 14 billion years
from an original hot,
dense state expanding cooling galaxies
form.
Here we are.
That's true.
That's settled.
Not art.
We know that.
That's right.
Okay.
The big bang model,
but then there's also the big bang
event.
The beginning of that story time equals
zero.
The initial singularity,
it's a prediction.
If you,
again,
if you remember we talked about in black
holes,
you have general relativity,
einstein's theory of gravity.
It makes predictions and one of those
predictions,
if you trace the universe backward in
time,
you hit a singularity,
you hit a moment when everything was
infinitely dense,
infinitely fast expanding,
et cetera,
et cetera.
That's the bIg bang moment and it is
certainly not true.
it's the opposite of true.
It's,
it's.
It has no right to believe that that
actually happened because it's a
prediction of general relativity,
but general tiffany's not right in that
regime because you're ignoring quantum
mechanics once again.
So if you don't think that you
understand the fundamental quantum
mechanical rules of the universe,
you have no right to say what happened
at the big bang and what physicists
should say if they're being honest,
is that could be that there was a first
moment in the history of the universe,
the first moment of time,
a day without a yesterday,
and once we understand quantum mechanics
and gravity and how they play well
together,
that will all be very clear.
Or there could have been something
before.
You know.
There could be the,
what we call the big bang,
may have been just a phase.
The universe goes through occasionally
and this bouncing universe idea that you
were talking about with the two
different universities hitting each
other,
that would be an example of a scenario
in which the universe was eternal,
that it lasted forever and right now we
have no way of knowing.
We're very openminded.
It's 14 billion years ago.
Maybe it was the beginning,
maybe it wasn't.
We just don't know.
What do you take?
Um,
of the idea that the big bang is process
a continual expansion and contraction
process and that it starts with the big
bang,
the universe expands and then somehow in
other polls back into itself until it
becomes this incredibly dense small
point again.
And then the whole process starts from
scratch,
right?
Yeah.
That's one of the scenarios on the
table.
Um,
in fact,
this,
this idea that you referred to,
which was what was originally called the
egg pie erotic universe.
Don't ask why it was some ancient
greeks.
Cool name.
Yeah.
It's a cool word name.
So that was the idea.
There's this extra dimension in two
universes of smacking into each other.
They later realized the same people,
very well known,
respectable physicists realized they
could just play the game over and over
again so you could have this smacking
together call that the big bang,
it expands and cools,
but then it recontract and there's
another bounce and just goes on an
infinite number of times.
I am personally not that fond of this
idea.
Number one,
there's no evidence whatsoever or reason
to believe that our universe will ever
contract,
if not only expanding,
but it's expanding and faster as doing
the opposite of what you would expect
for we're going to contract,
so I don't think that's very likely.
And number two,
the single most impressive empirical
fact about the universe is the
difference between the past and the
future,
what we call the arrow of time,
right?
A,
you remember the past,
but not the future.
You make choices now that affect the
future,
but not the past.
So this difference between the past and
future is nowhere built into the laws of
physics as we know them.
All the laws of physics that we know
treat the past and future the same.
The reason why there's a difference is
because of the big bang,
because the big bang was a very,
very special organized state that the
universe could be in and ever since then
we have been expanding and cooling and
sort of winding down and that's the fact
you have to explain if you want to
explain the origin of the universe in my
view and the idea that there's an
infinite number of cycles.
Doesn't explain that fact at all.
There you go.
Lawrence krauss was trying to explain to
me the size of the universe and the age
of the universe and he was saying that
14 billion years,
like when we look back into the known
universe,
like the,
what we can say is like 14 billion
years,
but he was saying that that essentially
doesn't mean that that's as far back as
it exists.
It just means that space is moving
faster than light.
when you get back to that distance,
there might be something even further
back than that,
but we're not going to ever be able to
see it.
I hope he didn't say exactly that.
I'm sure he did.
Right,
so fuck that up,
I'm sure.
But again,
sometimes even my favorite people in
cosmology used this language of space
expanding faster than light.
Entirely bullshit because space doesn't
have the speed.
The expansion of space is the answer to
the question.
You know,
spaces this big.
By whaT amount has it expanded in
one year?
One second later,
right?
I have heard that expression before,
that space is moving faster than light.
So why now?
Why did they say they shouldn't say
that?
Saying that.
I know because they're lazy and bad.
Saying that these are like high level
guys.
Yeah,
I know.
Okay.
So what is the never going to be invited
back to cosmology conference after this
podcast?
Well,
you always have the infinite monkey
cage.
That'll,
that'll be my new career.
Right.
So what is happening then?
Well,
space is expanding and light is moving
through it.
Right?
And what is certainly true is that the
speed of light is a finite number,
right?
Right.
It's one light year per year.
The way to remember it.
Right?
So if the universe had a beginning,
a finite number of years ago,
then there's only so far out that light
can get between now and then.
That's all there is.
So there are things far aWay that are so
far away we can never possibly see them
at this current age of the universe
because it would take longer than 14
billion years for light to get from
there to here.
And that's just because the universe has
a beginning.
It has nothing to do with the fact
that space is expanding at the speed or
that speed.
Okay.
Um,
if there is a,
a point where the big bang begins,
right?
There is a single origin point and it
explodes outward and we are seeing it
from some position.
So we're seeing this explosion 14
billion years ago.
Does it move in the opposite direction
as well as their $28,
billion years and you know from point to
point.
Right.
So it's not like that.
The big thing is not a point.
Okay.
The big bang,
and this is,
this is hard to wrap your mind around.
The big bang is not a location in space,
it's a moment in time,
the time in the history of the universe
when everything was on top of everything
else,
uh,
it's easier to talk about one
microsecond after the big bang,
then the big bang one microsecond after
the big bang.
The universe could very well have been
infinitely large.
We don't know.
It's not like the universe started some
micro second,
so any other time?
Infinitely small.
Well,
let's just forget about the infinitely
small.
Okay.
Insanely small things were closer
together.
There's no such thing as the size.
If the universe is infinitely big,
it's always infinitely big.
Okay.
But you can still the big bang.
Oh,
okay.
So if all matter is condensed into a
very small spot,
it doesn't mean that all things around
it are not infinitely large.
Well,
you don't want to say around it because
we're talking about the entire universe.
So it visualize an infinitely big
universe full of stuff.
Stuff,
stars,
galaxies.
Okay.
Like right now,
like right now,
and let's wind the clock backwards.
So suck it all in.
Yeah.
So the thing is that as far out as you
look,
even if you look at,
you know,
with your god's eye view faster than the
speed of light,
there's still stuff out there.
It's uniformly spread,
let's say.
Okay.
So.
But it's closer together.
It's the relative size.
The relative distance between galaxies
and stars is smaller in the past than it
is today.
But the whole size of the universe is
still infinity and that's still true all
the way back.
Fourteen billion years,
right up to the big bang.
The universe could have been infinitely
big,
but the density,
the amount of stuff in a cubic
centimeter goes to infinity.
Whoa.
Yeah.
How big is the estimation that it was at
the moment of the big bang,
but before,
like before it expanded,
right?
It's thought to be fairly small but
infinitely dense.
Right?
well,
I don't even think you can say it was
thought to be in fairly small.
No,
the observable universe.
So I think this is,
this is maybe what gets lost because the
universe is finite in age.
We only see a part of it.
Okay.
When you see a part of it,
a few tens of billions of light years
across called that the observable
universe.
That's fine.
I didn't size.
Okay,
so that definitely was smaller and there
was an actual number you can attach to
the question.
How big was it at the big bang and we
don't know the answer.
We can sort of.
It depends on theoretical predictions.
It was the biggest possible size.
It could have been.
Was about a centimeter across the
biggest possible.
Yeah.
As big as it could be.
So you're talking about essentially like
a pinky nail.
That's right.
That's as big as the whole universe
could have been that.
That's right.
In fact in this,
so everything you see,
everything around you right now that you
can reach out and touch every galaxy out
there with billions of stars in them.
They were all condensed into this one
centimeter cubic region of space.
What is the large,
and it couldn't be much smaller.
That's the largest.
It could.
Oh,
that's as big as it could have been.
It could have been much smaller.
It could have.
What is the smallest?
It could have been,
um,
will be called the plank size,
a 10th of minus 35 or 10 to minus 40
centimeters or something like that.
So incredibly tiny invisible.
Oh yeah.
Very,
very invisible.
Yeah.
Whoa.
Why do we think it happened?
Well,
what is the reason why the evidence we
have?
Yeah.
What,
what,
what is the current theory as to what,
what the big bang.
Like why did the big bang take place?
Well,
that's.
So,
that's a good question.
So there's no preferred conventional
answer.
We just don't know that that's not,
that's not a,
we don't know because we're not sure
that's a,
we have no idea is to answer.
Um,
obviously if there was a bounce or if
there was some universe before ours,
out of which ours came,
there would be a sensible answer to
that.
We just don't yet know what it is.
It's a more challenging question.
If you think that the big bang was truly
the beginning of the universe,
which is perfectly plausible,
it's perfectly compatible with the laws
of physics and then you're in one of
these situations,
you have to reorient the kinds of
questions you will allow yourself to ask
because if the big bang was the
beginning,
there's this intuitive feeling that
there was time before the big bang when
there wasn't anything and there was
nothingness.
Nothing just sat around for a long time
and then it decided to bang.
Okay.
Could've sat around for an infinite
number of years,
right?
Yes,
but,
but don't think of it that way is what
I'm trying to say.
Don't think about nothingness
transforming into the big bank.
Think about our universe thing of it
from the other side,
from the side that that we already
exist,
but visualize into the past and imagined
that as you visualize into the past,
you hit a beginning.
You hit a first moment of time,
a time when time itself came into
existence,
but there's no time out of which it
came.
That's the beginning of time.
It's like walking north.
You hit the north pole once you're at
the north pole,
you can't keep going north.
There's nothing weird.
It's just thAt everywhere,
every direction you go in,
we'd now be south at the big bang.
Time is only toward the future,
not toward the past.
That's all my mind blowing is that the
era of time,
the arrow of time is the particular fact
that not only does time flow it,
the universe changes.
There are differences between the past
and future.
God.
This time,
this is tough.
It's tough to.
How do you guys sleep?
Very well actually,
when I was a kid,
like it was 10 years older,
so when I first got interested in this
stuff and uh,
so yeah,
when I was 11 or 12,
the thing that would stop me from
sleeping was I be dreaming about,
you know,
the big bang in the universe.
Then I would come to the beginning and
we go like,
but what if the universe had just chosen
not to exist?
I was no sleep for me.
That
oh,
choice,
right?
I know better now.
I moved on to other more worldly
concerns keeping me awake at night.
So is there anybody working on any sort
of theory to try to understand what
forces might have caused it to burst
forth?
Yes.
So I mean there's two answers to that.
One is yes,
I'm one of them.
There's plenty of people thinking about
this kind of question,
but really,
I hate to say it,
but you shouldn't ask that question
because again,
we're embedded in this world.
So the question you asked was what are
the forces that caused it to burst
forth?
Right?
So that presumes that there was a cause
and that,
I mean causes and effects work
themselves out over time.
So there was a time when there wasn't a
big bang and then there was something
that caused the big bang to occur.
So what I want to suggest is that that's
just not the metaphysical framework in
which to think about the origin of the
universe.
Don't ask what caused it,
asked what were the laws of physics that
can be compatible with both the universe
we see today and with the universe
having a beginning 14 billion years ago.
We don't know the answer to that,
but that's the question we should ask.
It's,
it's,
it's such a complex discussion.
It's,
it's so complex that it's almost like
infinite and its possibilities that you,
you,
you go over all these variables,
these possibilities and what we know and
what we're learning and it's just,
well,
it's very,
it's complex,
but more importantly,
it's a realm that is just so far outside
our experience and our toolkit for
dealing with the world that we have no
guidance,
right?
We're kind of at sea,
like what are the kinds of things we
should be asking about?
What are the answers that would satisfy
us?
Right?
Um,
I would argue that there are brute
facts.
There are things we just need to accept
if we come up with a picture of the
universe,
a set of laws of physics and a story for
the history of the universe that says,
well,
the universe started this way and then
that happened,
et cetera,
and someone says,
well,
why did it happen that way?
And I would say there is no answer to
that question.
ThIs is just what it is.
I might change my mind if you convince
me,
but there's no right to demand that
there is a reason why things are one way
rather than another.
Do you have difficulty like thinking of
a potential reason that one day we will
wrap our heads around?
Did he think that it's within the realm
of our possibilities,
our understanding?
It's always possible that there is a
deeper explanation,
right?
But then you want to say,
well,
okay,
why is that deeper explanation true?
And I think that this chain of
explanations bottoms out,
I think that there will be one
foundational appointed,
which is not sort of self explanatory,
but it's just.
And That's the way it is.
Are there any legitimate scientists that
are contemplating the possibility of a
big bang not being the origin of the
universe?
Oh yeah,
absolutely.
The big baNg could be just one of these
moments.
One of these things that happens,
a one possIbility is that there's
another universe that it sort of big and
quiet and empty,
but through a quantum mechanical
fluctuation,
a little part of the universe could
pinch off and become a separate baby
universe and then grow by itself and
that could be the origin of our
universe.
So like a stellar nursery for universes.
Yeah,
and It could go on,
say the great thing to really.
So I haven't blown your mind yet,
but now I'm about to do it.
Oh,
you already did put it back together
again real quick.
When you look at the universe,
the universe is finite in size.
You know,
we were talking about it could be
infinitely big,
it could be finite insights,
but if it is finite in size,
we think that a finite universe has zero
total energy,
zero total charge,
zero total velocity,
etc.
so making a universe costs nothing.
Alan guth,
who's a famous cosmologist and mit says
the universe is the ultimate free lunch.
Universes are not an expendable
resource.
You can make.
if,
if you could make one universe,
you can make an infinite number of
universes just as easily.
I don't understand that.
How,
how it.
Well,
so you understand there is.
Yeah.
Well there's bath,
right?
So look,
you look at the sun and you say,
look,
the sun,
that would.
That seems to be like it would be hard
to make a lot of stuff there.
It can just appear,
but the son also has a gravitational
field,
right?
There's gravity around the sun,
and what the math suggests is that there
is energy in the gravitational field of
the sun which is negative and which is
exactly equal to the energy of the sun
and cancels it out so that if you've got
a universe with nothing in it,
but the sun,
that universe would have zero total
energy if it were closed in on itself.
Wow.
Yeah.
It cancels itself out.
Yes.
So negative energy in gravity cancels
the positive energy and stuff.
Therefore,
universes can have zero total energy.
And this is all obviously very
hypothetical speculative mathematical
stuff.
It's nothing we've done in the lab.
So take it with a grain of salt.
We could change our minds,
but that's the current state of the art.
wow.
So the entire universe you believe
revolves around that principle.
Free lunch.
yeah,
you could easily.
So again,
if you could make a universe at all,
then you can probably make an infinite
number of universes just as easily.
It's not like you have a 100 pounds of
universe stuff and that gives you a
finite number to me.
EverY universe costs you nothing to make
people have a hard time even thinking of
there being more than one universe.
And yoU start thinking about the fact
that there's 100 million galaxies in
this 100 million,
at least $100,
million solar systems.
Right?
And this galaxies is one of hundreds of
billions of galaxies,
the known universe.
And that there might be more than one
universe.
Right?
And the idea that this was all for our
benefit seems a little ridiculous to
very tiny compared to the size of the
universe.
Yeah.
Well,
that does get to be a bit of an issue at
a certain point in time.
Just the massive at all is a defies.
It defies not just our understanding or
our,
like for the average person like myself,
it defies your ability to put the what,
what you're describing in the words,
right?
That's part of what the problem is.
Training.
Yeah.
As we keep pumping into.
But here I can restore your,
uh,
your,
your thought that we matter for the
universe.
Bring it back pretty bad because we're
wrapping this up in some sense.
Uh,
we are in the middle of the smallest
scales in the important part of the
universe versus the largest scales.
If you look at the universe on very,
very small scales or very,
very early times near the big bang,
the universe looks very simple.
Not a lot of complications.
Like We said,
you can't build a civilization on an
electron.
It's just no possible intricacies there.
It's a very simple thing.
The universe is also very,
very simple and large scale and it will
get only simpler in the future.
The university sort of dissolving into
emptiness as the universe keeps
expanding,
it's only in between on scales,
like the size of a human being or the
earth and ecosphere that things are
complex.
right?
So even though we're much smaller than
the size of the universe,
we're very big compared to adam's.
The number of neurons in the human brain
is roughly the same as the number of
stars in the galaxy,
so we are kind of a peak of
structuredness of the universe of
complexity.
I mean until we build even bigger
artificial intelligences and sO forth,
but there's something that we are
maximizing.
Something that is a is sort of
concentrated on us which is not size or
scale or time.
It is complication and complexity.
Wow.
Now in the same sense that the energy
and the gravity of the stars sort of
managed to cancel each other out.
Is that the case with people as well?
Well,
if this is all again math,
the whole universe
is a free lunch.
The claim would consider a universe
with nothing in it,
but you pick your favorite thing,
a person,
a star or a galaxy,
whatever.
Then the totaL energy in that thing,
minus the total energy in the
gravitational field,
because that's negative would be exactly
zero.
Wow.
That is super hard to wrap your head
around.
Yeah.
And then there's the big question,
right?
You wouldn't get paid the big bucks if
it were using with the big question is
why,
like why do you think this is all
happening or do you ever use that word?
Why is,
why is a weird word,
right?
Yeah.
Why is it weird is happening?
It is.
So what's causing it to happen?
What are the forces that caused it to
happen?
You ever.
Why do you ever look at all and go,
is there a purpose to all this?
So.
Sure.
Um,
and I think the answer is no.
I think that the,
I think that yeah,
there's no reason why.
And again,
just looking up into the sky,
uh,
you know,
unless the purpose was to make a pretty
sky boy,
anything that we're seeing here on earth
could have been done much with much less
effort than making 100 billion galaxies.
Right?
Um,
there's no evidence in anything that
we've learned about science or the
universe that gives us a reason to
believe that there's a purpose behind it
all.
If anything,
as time goes on,
the entropy of the universe is
increasing and the universe is becoming
more random and disorderly.
Um,
I think that we're riding a wave of a
universe that is growing and expanding
and cooling and becoming more and more
disorderly,
and that's a finite amount of time.
So 14 billion years from the big bang to
today.
Sounds like a lot.
That's one point.
four times 10 to the 10 years,
but the future of the universe is
enormously longer thAn that.
According to our best current theories.
It's,
it's way.
It's potentially infinitely long anyway.
The last star is not going to burn out
until a quadrillion years from now.
We are very close to the beginning of
the history of the universe and,
but it's not forever.
It doesn't last and infinite amount of
time.
So the universe is a femoral.
We human beings and living creatures are
temporary structures within it.
And the idea that it's all for some big
cosmic purpose,
it seems to hold very little water.
Do you ever contemplate what,
what function human beings have in the,
in the university,
the way we interface with reality,
the way we interface with our,
the nature around us?
Yeah.
I think that,
uh,
we don't have the function.
I don't think it's the right way to
think about what human beings are.
We should be glad to be alive,
enjoy it while we're here,
uh,
be nice to each other and try to learn
more about the universe.
But it's not if we choose not to do
that,
that's not going against any preordained
function that we have.
Your,
you're a remarkably calm when you
discuss these things.
like,
do you have any existential angst?
Do you have any,
like I think the other way around,
and honestly this is very,
very small amounts of data.
But,
uh,
from what I can tell when personal
tragedies strike people who are
atheistic cosmologists and scientists
deal with it way better than people who
think that we're embedded in a matrix
with a bigger purpose or a spiritual
reality.
Really.
Yeah,
because you get that this,
this happened and you have an infinite
perspective,
like when someone dies,
it's sad.
You can be sad,
but you,
you can't say,
well,
it shouldn't have happened.
right?
This is.
These are the kinds of things that
happen.
Damn dude,
it's gonna.
Take a while to process.
This is a long one.
Go out and look at the milky way.
I'm gonna.
Have to listen to this about 30 times
and take notes,
but thank you very much and it was
awesome.
I really appreciate it.
Thanks so much.
If people want to get a hold of you or
read some of your stuff,
what is the best way?
I have a website called preposterous
universe.
What a great name and you know my last
book,
the big picture,
talked about all these questions about
purpose,
why we're here,
what we should do about it.
Is there an audio book available as it
is?
I recorded it not far from here.
Excellent.
Beautiful.
Thank you so much,
man.
That was awesome.
Thanks everybody.