The Joe Rogan experience,
that's an interesting way of doing it.
Are you completely opposed to
legalization?
No,
no,
no.
I mean I am not completely opposed to
legalization.
Mind concern here is that the country
are too ignorant right now for
legalization.
Not that people will go out and do some
dangerous things related to drugs,
but if you legalize drugs now,
what will happen is that you will have
the detractors say things like,
any ills in our society is going to be
blamed on a drug.
We are so ignorant.
We're susceptible to believing that.
So before legalization I'm arguing that
we have this increase in education about
what drugs do and don't do,
do so people cannot be susceptible to
being hoodwinked like that.
I'm arguing that the education provides
an inoculation,
if you will.
So you're saying we can handle the truth
essentially.
What are you saying is that we need this
decriminalization step before we get to
a legalization,
that it's the.
We couldn't just jump right into
legalization.
It will be too much change.
Pandemonium.
People go crazy.
Fear.
People would use propaganda to set
people against the,
you know,
to go against it.
Yeah,
so I'm thinking about,
well,
I'm not saying it'll be pandemonium.
We have Washington and Colorado right
now.
Mark my words.
There will be studies coming out of
Washington and Colorado showing that
young people in those states do more
poorly on whatever measure you want to
have as a result of marijuana.
The studies,
the data won't support that conclusion,
but that's what people are going to be
drawing from those data.
And so I'm.
This is my prediction right now as a
result of people's ignorance about
marijuana and that's that's marijuana.
A drug that we have a lot more
experienced in with heroin and,
but mark my words,
you'll see those steps come up
and they religions have a way of
prosecuting psychedelic losers are
losers say users throughout history,
but they would call it the work of the
devil and that's what I ran into with
the Mazda text who I was working with up
in Wahaca,
is that they had to.
When the Spaniards came,
they had to flee into the hills to
continue the mushroom tradition.
And now you'll actually see,
um,
I went to San Jose,
Delpha Civica,
one town where the mushrooms are readily
accessible in this other town,
what La de Jimenez and you'll see on the
churches they have Jesus and Mary and
then on the other side they have a
mushroom,
so they actually worship the mushrooms.
They've kind of mixed,
I guess to survive.
They mixed Catholicism in with their
worship of these mushrooms and um,
it's,
it's pretty trippy per se to see it
painted on these churches.
That's actually
a big part of really ancient religious
artwork,
period.
You know,
a lot of,
if you look in,
look up,
do some research on the connection
between mushrooms and even the Catholic
Church.
There's mushroom iconography all over
the place and really ancient
descriptions like one of the earliest
depictions of Adam and Eve on some
ancient fresco is Adam and eve with a
mushroom tree in between them.
Have you ever seen that image?
See if you can pull that up.
Jamie,
Adam and eve mushroom picture and we'll
find the description of it.
Uh,
and eve mushroom.
Yeah.
We just lost track of all this stuff.
It's also one of the reasons,
yeah,
this is.
It's right away.
You could pull up that image.
It's pretty intense.
That's a.
that's an image of Adam and eve.
I mean,
look at that.
That's crazy.
The mushroom.
That's fucking crazy.
It was really strange for me when I was
in Mexico to see them blessing the
mushrooms on the altar a instead of the
communion holy water,
they give you mushrooms and that's your
sacrament.
That's what you eat.
There's another one,
Jamie,
pull up.
There's the other,
another one that's a different image,
but a very,
very similar image.
See that one on the far left.
Far Left.
Yeah,
right there.
Click up that one.
Look at that.
Isn't that trippy?
That's from 1147.
They call it ce now.
They don't call it a d anymore for
whatever reason,
but that's from 1147.
So they knew even back then about
psychedelic plants having some sort of a
connection to Christianity and these
were,
you know,
these are from churches.
So it's,
um,
it's really fascinating.
That's just something that went away
even before I ever went incident Jujitsu
philosophy.
I fought a tough man contest when I was
18 years old.
Mr t was the referee.
I swear to God it was a video that I
have.
Video was on entertainment tonight.
Show a clip of me with a Mohawk.
So you had three guys.
I fought all heavyweight day,
day one 75 minutes.
I will have my clothes on.
And I was,
I was,
I was like,
I was brown that weight by one 75 at
all.
So,
uh,
I fought three guys.
I knocked out two guys,
man,
the second guy took.
Dude,
how about that?
Tough man experience was the worst head
trauma than all my fights combined.
How about that?
Oh yeah,
yeah,
for sure.
Wow.
I had a concussion like you wouldn't
believe I've never get through to this
day.
You want to get grossed out
in case you didn't hear it at home.
Kids.
Oh my God,
that's nothing.
That's my joy.
That goes from the tough was my.
I fought one guy and he was a day.
It's funny because they put it,
the two small guys together.
So they put me verse this guy,
he's fucking scarred for life now.
It was me versus this.
Ah,
they,
they announced me as a weight lift in
pizza boy from long island because I
delivered pizzas and my buddy at the
time,
Jim mccluskey,
he was a professional boxer.
Me and him,
we got into a ton of street fights
together.
But uh,
he used the items for the day,
my life.
But I used to fight a lot.
He got it looks stand like this,
you less of a target as it.
That's why he,
that was my lesson.
So,
uh,
so I,
I went in there,
I didn't know what the fuck do you
expect?
No head gear,
just these big gloves on that guy who
runs it,
whatever his name was.
Beard.
Yeah,
I believe,
I don't know.
I guess so.
But uh,
they put me in verse,
this platoon leader from Desert Storm
and this guy,
he's from long island to.
I didn't know.
And uh,
I ended up fucking drilled him so I,
I fucking hammered them and they stopped
it right away.
That clip.
I can get it.
It was on it.
I got it on tape.
I get,
I can get it to you.
I think you'd be.
Want to see it.
It's funny because they showed it on it,
that statement tonight and I'm like,
ah,
that's great.
Mary or whoever it is making a face.
But Mr t was the referee.
I thought it was amazing.
You're a smart dude because I was just
at this tech conference,
uh,
and we as ceos and this thing and we
were talking about it and I,
we got into a fight with one of these
big dudes or an old dude,
big powerful guy.
And he said,
you know who,
who,
who wouldn't,
jails.
Snowden.
I said,
me,
I wouldn't tell them what's the
difference between snowden and Woodward
and Bernstein,
Woodward and Bernstein and the
presidential papers,
like they were the punks of their
generation like,
but now they're heroes because it's the
baby boomers and Snowden's fuck you.
It's what's good for the goose is good
for the Gander.
Anyway,
we got into this fight.
What's he,
what's his argument?
You know,
he was just,
he's bad and has the same argument.
No,
he's not,
he's weakened country,
a trader,
I'd kill myself in front of them.
And so and so,
so we got into this fight,
but,
but uh,
you know,
the interesting thing about that is a,
the fact that a lot of people,
you know,
whistleblowing is seen as eye.
I see it as,
as that's what's going to keep democracy
safe,
but this sort of overreaching and I
said,
look,
you know,
I didn't come to America for it to be
able to live in a police state and this
is the definition of a police state is
that they could watch everything that we
do and that it was all these tech guys
in the tech guys just sort of rolled
their eyes and said it's already
happened.
The tech is already there.
The,
the government has already made the
deals.
It's a de facto thing.
You can't change it.
And then,
then I got kind of worried because
you're exactly right.
You're 100 percent right.
The tech is so pervasive that you can't
fuck with it.