Low Freak bitches.
Was he found guilty before it was
revealed that there was these dirty?
Yes.
Yeah,
they and they didn't and they knew that
this case existed and they didn't allow
like the lawyer Ross,
his defense was trying to postpone the
trial a couple of months so that the
grand jury investigation,
the criminal charges they knew were
going to drop the complaint.
Uh,
but they were not allowed to postpone
the trial.
Well,
that seems like a slam dunk if you can
prove that these cops are using other
people's user names and they were
hacking into people's accounts and that,
that seems like right there,
like you can't.
You can't prove anybody that's a trial.
I would certainly.
I'd like to see that trial.
Like my perspective on it is,
is I'm fine with whatever the truth
turns out to be.
I would just love to see both sides have
their day and I was at that trial and
the defense did not have a day.
That's always how it is though,
man.
Mean the idea that you get a fair trial
is such a fucking joke because there's
so much railroad and going on.
Yeah,
because especially when there's an
agenda like this to prosecute someone in
a,
in a,
an important case,
a landmark case they think is going to
establish a precedent.
They will fuck you.
Yeah.
That's Kinda how it is.
They will fuck you.
And that's what they did to this guy.
Now this dread pirate Roberts character.
What's his name?
Dread.
Pirate Roberts.
Oh,
I mean,
the guy was accused of being a God they
think Russell brick just.
And he's denying that he was dread.
Pirate Roberts.
He's saying,
here's what we know about him.
We know that he had these like hardcore
libertarian values.
He wasn't a hacker.
He wasn't a computer guy.
I didn't know anything about coding at
all.
Um,
he was a physics major,
you know,
he was a,
he'd put himself through to universities
on full scholarship.
He had a master's degree in mechanical
engineering from Penn State.
Very Bright.
Um,
we know that he had hardcore libertarian
politics.
We know that much.
He admitted to creating the Silk Road.
He said he did it to create it like an
economic stimulation where he would
combine tour and Bitcoin to allow a
marketplace to exist that would be free
for everybody to use.
However they wanted to use it.
He claims he said he built it with the
help of a lot of other people was he
doesn't really know how to code and he
just let it run.
And he took off and he was done and he
moved on and that's what his family,
his mom and dad back him on that.
And that's what his family claims given
being around him because they're a very
tight knit family.
All this time they were like,
this was not someone who was on his
laptop all the time.
I don't know how he could have been
running a mill,
a almost a billion dollar drug empire.
Um,
he wasn't that guy.
It wasn't,
the guy just sat on his mama's keyboard
all the time.
Um,
so he claimed he's not dread pirate
Roberts prosecution claimed that he was
in and uh,
and that was what that first trial was
about.
What is there proof that he was a,
they did find a journal on his laptop
and the journal on his laptop is like,
you know,
today I'm setting up a dread pirate
Roberts account today.
I'm going to do this today.
Fuck.
Does that fuck writes a journal on their
laptop of all the shit they're going to
do that today I will take over the
world.
It's kind of how it was.
That seems so silly.
Yeah,
I mean it's,
it's,
you know,
it again would love to see like
I went to the trial thinking,
okay,
now we're going to see what happened.
Right.
And I would love to see the defense
really have time to sort of talk through
their end and have expert witnesses and
get into the nitty gritty of it because
I mean I would say we were the wherever
the truth lies,
but,
but to be in the courtroom and to hear
all that and just think,
okay,
if this is true,
this is like the most naive,
you know,
criminal mastermind and the history of.
Could you imagine breaking would have
lasted like wouldn't have lasted half a
season if they had Walter White light,
you know.
So today I will plant a bomb in the
courthouse today.
I'm going to blow up that bomb.
This don't tell anyone for law
enforcement,
you know?
Yeah.
It's not like he knows a lot about
computers and computer could be hacked
into or anything.
Yeah.
That's so stupid.
So our t just really liked the videos
that I was doing and asked me to come
there for an interview and um,
I just said there's no way I want to
move to DC.
That sounds horrible,
but I just couldn't.
I couldn't pass up the opportunity and
they said that they wanted me to have a
show and just do exactly what I was
doing and just rant and,
and have an international platform to
do.
So the,
the only hesitation that I had,
I mean I talked to someone who initially
interviewed me for our tea and I asked
her,
why do you work here?
Like why is Russia today covering things
that activists care about?
Like what is,
what is going on here?
And she was like,
look,
if I have to work for the Russian
government to tell the truth about
what's happening in my country,
that's what I'm going to do because we
have to get the information out there.
At that time,
the Cold War,
Russia was not in the news like
militarily or like this crazy Cold War,
renaissance and resurrection in terms of
like propaganda wars.
So at that time I was like,
that's great.
And I mean,
the editorial freedom that it gives is
completely unmatched.
And of course people are gonna love you.
That,
that gross generalization that
everything on the networks propaganda.
The problem is everything's propaganda.
Every fucking thing is propaganda.
Tell me one media source that is not
used in some way to push a viewpoint or
a bias.
Everyone has bias.
There is no such thing as neutrality.
You know,
everyone comes with an opinion.
Everyone that comes with a bias,
and I'd rather know the bias,
which is Russia today.
You may not get the truth about Russia
from going to Russia and watching Russia
today,
but you will get the fucking truth about
the U.
s government and you will get the truth
about corporations because it's state
funded so you can talk about those
things without worrying about
advertisers and sponsorship.
So I always tell people navigate around
the bias.
No,
I'm not going to tell people that there
is no bias.
That's fucking stupid.
Of course there is.
It's Russia today.
It's fun about the Russian government,
so there's a lot of factors that go into
that,
but I'd much rather know that bias
blatantly in front of my face then not
know the tens of thousands of special
interest and conflicts of interest going
into the entire corporate media
apparatus and all these other agencies.
I mean,
and that's even scarier because you have
people on those channels that had been
fired for criticizing the U.
s government and it's not even state
funded media.
It just corporate media.
How long his uncle Paul been around for?
Well,
he started.
Uncle Paul started is I've
been doing character for years and
relationships long before I did.
I'm on the radio.
I didn't coin my girlfriends and maybe
he was uncle Larry many years ago.
There was Roger Davis or Roger d and
this is long before chip,
there was Roger and Roger had a brother
Lester who was burned in a fire and it
was,
you got a whole time,
like all storyline.
Lester was burned everywhere,
but his knees and his,
he would always wear knickers to show
off.
His legs was a whole thing and uncle
Roger and uncle,
uh,
uncle Larry and then it merged into chip
who my girlfriend hated so much.
Chip became the fucking because they
would chip would embarrass people.
I did had literally before I ever
thought I'd do on the radio,
I would be out with girlfriends and
embarrass them by doing that.
Like I'll just be making bad jokes in
the cab and my girlfriend jen and even
grow up and go home and just go,
just shut the fuck up.
It's not funny and it made me so happy.
And what?
This is what Dr Jen crazy.
He'd be like a really nice steakhouse
and the waiter would come over and she
would order like the salmon and then
chip just goes.
How much is that?
And would ask the way there.
And she was like,
do you know how humiliating it is that
people think I fucked that guy?
People think I'm fucking this guy.
And that's where they come from.
That visceral reaction.
It was real,
like I was who doing one night that she
all I would do,
I would do it,
you know,
I,
Edgar's one,
I don't do as much because it's bigger.
Edgar's the one with the tiny mouth he
drew
and that's his thing.
But he had a brother Eugene and Eugene
was always telling her that like,
you know,
you need to get right with the Lord.
And he would always tell her she was
garbage and a whore.
You tell my girlfriend she was all for
and she was not worthy crying.
I'm crying.
But I,
I.
What happened was my girlfriend at the
time,
who's now my best friend,
she might extra offer from years ago.
She hated Eugene so much.
And I mean,
it wasn't even funny anymore.
Could we would do it and she would dig
her fingernails into my face.
She dug her nails into my face because I
think eugene hit a spot.
It's real.
And um,
it was,
it was such a visceral reaction from her
that I stopped doing eugene because she
caught me dirty texting with another
girl.
She fucking,
I told you I wasn't even to go.
I have a fuck.
It was just a girl.
I told you my dirty intriguing.
It was a girl.
I was like,
I'll pay you 500 baby.
So I fucking,
I'm such an addict.
I would save my conversations to jerk
off to,
and I hit the wrong button by button and
I fucking printed it.
Dude,
So she wakes me up one morning she goes,
Jim,
wake up.
And I knew I was in trouble.
So she found these things and she knew I
hadn't fucked the girl,
but it was a real strain on the
relationship.
So as I swear to you as,
as one of the ways of making amends to
her,
I stopped doing eugene.
I killed off Eugene Mellencamp because
she,
because I do a baby boy character in
jelly who she liked,
who's jelly.
I don't do jelly publish to embarrass
these.
Just a little boy.
But she thought he was really cute and
uncle Paul would always molest jelly and
fucking and chip was so stupid.
Chipotle is dropped jelly off and uncle
Paul's house and he didn't know it was a
whole fucking inner world.
So yeah,
chip would be like,
well Ivanka,
Paul's a good guy.
He's helping out and she is.
So she would drive her crazy.