This is real,
this is live is really happening.
This is what the Joe Rogan experience
podcast is brought to you by the
fleshlight.
I was going to get that.
Go ahead.
If you go to Joe Rogan.net
and click on the link for the flashlight
and enter in the code name Rogan,
you will get 15 percent off.
Number one,
sex toy for a man.
That's it.
That's the end.
Is there a number two?
Number two flashlight.
Number two,
what?
Sex Toy?
That's a good question.
What is number two?
Your hand going to shut off the music,
right?
Number two is probably one of those
standard blowup dolls I bought.
That still gets action.
I will never use one of the.
I don't think.
No,
I don't know anybody who does that.
Maybe stanhouse.
You have one?
Have you used them to Joanna?
Angel wine and it's a.
It feels like it.
You're one of those racks like at the
pool.
You know,
it smells like a raffle.
I fucked a lot of RAF.
Yeah.
Does that.
So maybe I shouldn't have.
Yeah.
Feels like it.
So.
Oh God.
So it's just kind of a whole.
Yeah.
And what's cool though is the one I have
a,
I have you take out the fleshlight out
of it,
the,
the case like fish in the bucket thing
and he put it through the whole of the
blowup doll.
Then it's okay,
but then you're still feeling like
you're fucking,
you're saying take the
insides of a flashlight,
the good feeling part and stuff it into
that hole.
Yeah.
I said that you could do it in a gas
tank as well.
Just stick a fucking put clothing on the
doll and it kind of is on the car.
Oh yeah.
Well I think you're even more fucked up
to pretending that things a purse.
Well that makes me,
I swear to God,
it makes me a little sick to my stomach.
Thinking about how is it when you're
especially horny or lonely or what?
Neal Brennan is talking like Neal
Brennan?
Yeah.
Hey guys.
Indian slash producer,
character slash director slash just all
around Hollywood bed.
I'm starting to realize something about
myself,
which is a standard.
Like I like,
I like talking.
You like talking?
Yeah.
Meaning like I like Chapelle one time,
said he'd made a fortune,
he talked his way into a fortune and
which always,
and now I realize what he means just
because I've been doing a lot of road
shows and gigs and shit and you just
have to talk,
right?
But you got to go do radio and talk and
talk and talk and you just.
And I go,
Oh yeah,
I like talking.
It doesn't feel like work to me to go
when people are like,
do you hate doing ready?
I'm like,
I don't know.
You go and tell jokes and be funny.
Maybe you think of something new.
It seems all right to me.
It doesn't bother me.
Well,
you're a,
you're a writer as well.
And writing is so much more difficult to
just talk and shit.
Ah,
well that's what made me realize that
this guy,
Alan Stevens or seven comedian,
uh,
he wrote for and he said,
he goes,
I'm actually not even a writer.
I'm just a bullshitter.
Which is like,
I know what he means now.
Like I,
I really want.
The minute he said it,
I was like,
I'm a bullshitter too.
Like I write better jokes,
just talk and I can write good jokes
writing,
but I'll.
They can,
they'll get a little bit better if
there's a social center.
Yeah,
there's some that just only come out
when you talk to.
Yeah.
Is there some about like the pressure of
having that human thing that you need to
please,
particularly if they're comedians that
you like and respect.
That's why I like writing with a guys.
I'm friends with you because it's like,
Eh,
I don't want to,
first of all,
don't want to have to pitch to a guy
that I secretly don't think is funny.
Yeah.
And there's something about bouncing
some of off likeminded people's heads
that also allows you to come up with
some shit.
You know,
when you know a guy's already got
several steps of the puzzle figured out
along with you and that Nigga.
What the fuck?
Yes.
The other thing is the,
there's that Chappelle used to say that
he and I were like thrilled killers
where he'd like stabbed the person and
I'd be like,
good her fucking head off Dave because
you're just so like,
you're like,
you want to one up that person.
Then he went up to you and then and then
you got like a vineyard,
you're talking and then you really don't
know.
Well,
that's always offends me when people put
comedians on the line for really,
really outrageous shit.
They said onstage as if they really mean
that drives me nuts sometimes because
half of what we do is try to say the
most fucked up thing.
Like you didn't just fucking go there.
Like when you're talking to a bunch of
comics and you're hanging out with
comics,
we,
you know,
we're going to go,
we're going to go to the most fucked up
place possible because that's the only
way to make the person laugh,
to get us to.
That gets us off anymore.
I mean,
we endorsed the idea of whenever it is
beastiality anything,
you know what I mean?
Like I'm not,
like,
there's nothing in my,
and I'm like,
this is a fact,
this is written in stone and this.
It's like,
here's,
here's an idea,
here's another idea.
Doesn't mean that if your brain goes
there,
yeah.
It goes back to that tracy argument of
like what Morgan tracey Morgan the other
night at the comedy store,
I do a joke about a mark twain and how
they're taking all the words out of
Huckleberry Finn and I ended up saying
nigger like seven times.
No one's ever had a problem with that at
all black rooms because I never say it
as myself.
Of course I say it as in yes.
Finally a girl in the audience goes,
no,
and I'm like,
what?
She goes,
you can't say it.
And I was like,
why?
Why can't a black girl?
I go,
why can't I?
And she's like,
well,
I don't in here and call you cracker.
And I was like,
well,
you just did.
That's a.
and I didn't,
didn't bother me at all.
Got The show back.
Got It.
Righted the ship.
We ended up talking for about an hour
after the show.
Me and the girl and she was like,
I go,
you know,
before I did that joke,
I specifically did jokes about Mexicans
and Asians and you didn't have any
problem with that.
She was like,
no,
I didn't have.
And I go,
so you,
your problem is with racism against
black people,
but not all racism.
You're fine with racism at large,
but you're cool with it,
but you're against it when it's against
black people.
Which she's like,
yeah,
I'm a hypocrite.
So we ended up having like a half hour
discussion.
She walks away.
She one of these people who like,
she's never lost an argument in her
life,
like,
just didn't even when I wasn't.
So like she doesn't know why I won the
argument.
She walks away.
You and I know.
Uh,
she knows.
Yeah,
she walks,
she walks away and uh,
and her husband goes,
here's the problem.
And he goes,
I know that you don't have any hate in
your heart.
Problem is she does.
She does have.
So she had,
she had said during the conversation
that's been dropped on you,
that dude's a week away from telling
that bit.
Well,
no,
he just say that to random people at the
comedy store.
She's got her heart.
You.
Well,
he wasn't saying it like that.
He was just saying it like she's got
like she is up the mind that white
people are constantly saying the n word
and it's like,
no,
we're not.
I've,
I told her,
you know how many times I've heard it
without a speak for yourself saying that
he's saying that she said she recognizes
the argument that she thinks that white
people are constantly using the emerald
wise will run around.
It's like if a guy uses the n word in
that way,
if he's not,
if he's not being funny because there's
no humor to it.
I did get disgusted.
That's how many times I haven't even
heard it without a sense of humor or I
go,
maybe I've heard it five times and I
have,
I have,
I have definitely were mostly.
Did you hear it in Jersey?
Yeah,
I heard it in Boston a lot.
Oh,
right.
I heard that.
I've heard a guy at times,
you know,
I've been around people that were
looking to jump racists.
It's creepy.
It's creepy to here,
you know,
and these fucking Niggas and they go,
Whoa,
whoa,
whoa.
Yeah,
Yeah.
Just because some black people did some
fucked up shit,
you know.
Have you ever seen gone with the wind?
Yeah,
I think I have,
but it was a long time ago.
That is the most racist movie in the
whole entire world.
I just watched it from my first time
recently.
I think it was 1930.
I don't think I've ever watched watches
39 because the guy,
one guy a directed a gone with the wind
and wizard of Oz in the same year,
but he did wizard of Oz.
Well that makes completely sense because
I,
because I thought it feels like the
wizard of Oz but racist and,
and there was the same like production
design in the same feeling of it.
The,
there was one scene where it was late at
night and there was like tons of little
white children in their beds.
And then there's this black child
cranking this fan to fan all the white
children when they slept.
Yes.
Oh my God.
There was the part where the main
actors,
the one that Clark Gable says,
you know,
frankly my dear,
I don't give a damn that girl,
like she has like a slave and she's like
slapping the slave in the face because
she wouldn't shut up or something like
that.
It is so uncomfortable to watch and then
you realize the Clark Gable guy like I
don't know what ethnicity he is.
He,
he was like from Glendale or something
like that.
Like I never thought this was supposed
to be like this,
like,
like handsome,
striking young man.
But he looked like somebody.
This guy.
Like he,
he,
it was weird.
What do you mean?
Like he didn't look like a leading man.
So like you're used to like the rock say
like a big manly hands had this guy
looked like a little rocket.
The rocket will know you're talking
about he racially,
he looked,
he looked.
He just like for back then it seemed
like such a racist movie then.
Then they had like,
they would have gone after him now.
Yeah.
It would have felt like a little Mexican
looking dude.
Yeah.
Like one of those standard Mexicans like
Oscar de la Hoya,
Mexicans,
maybe it was stolen,
but gone with the wind I thought was a
creepy ass movie.
So that's the,
the woman who won the,
uh,
the academy award for it yet for playing
a maid.
And by the way,
she was the best person in the movie.
That chick I could fucking watch all
day.
She was hilarious.
But,
uh,
the,
the whole thing though is so creepy
because now they have the intermissions
and the opening sound.
What used to play in the movie theater,
sitting there for 15 minutes in the
middle of the making about listening to
piano music,
thinking about racism winds like what is
the plot of them who wins?
You know what?
I was just so fascinated with the racism
that I don't even remember what the plot
was.
Shit,
man.
It was freaking me out.
The video,
the image of the black boy fanning.
Oh,
it's creeped and there's so many little
things like that in the movie put to
wizard of Oz feeling to it.
Now,
do you think that this movie is supposed
to reflect the genuine racism of the era
that it was depicting or 39.
So it wasn't even.
There were still people alive from that
time.
Like when was 39?
Yeah.
Wow.
It was the first color movie,
I believe that.
Or one of the first color movies.
Yeah.
Wow.
I think it might've been the,
the first.
Uh,
but,
but the.
Yeah,
I don't,
I think that it was so it's not like it
was made in [inaudible] 78 and they were
taking like,
there were still black people still
couldn't vote when the movie came out.
They didn't have to fan you anymore to
drink it,
but they couldn't afford for vote.
Wow.
Yeah.
Old Movies,
man,
old movies will trip you out or other.
There's a,
there's a,
the in the godfather,
someone goes let's sell drugs in their
neighborhood,
their animals.
Anyway.
And I remember seeing that and going
like,
that's a little rough like as an adult
probably 20 going like maybe cut that
out.
Like Mooney always makes the joke that
like the fact that they aired on
television pretty irresponsible or is
this sort of like fucked up Dave and
introduced that idea that there's
anybody that would listen to that guy
and think he was making sense.
It's dangerous.
It's.
Are you talking about Mooney or the guy?
The Guy Saying that and the Godfather?
Yeah,
it's messy.
If you're a little black child and you
have to fucking listen to that now,
do you think they should cgi,
they should eat that gun out of all
these movies.
Do you think they should.
CGI that did was create a work
for.
And then work of art reflects a honest
behavior,
but when you put it on television,
it's a very tricky thing and if you're
going to hear that on tbs,
I wonder if they.
I wonder if they,
uh,
if they,
if it went in there is on television.
Well,
I don't endorse them censoring it,
but I don't get to see where people
would not want their kids to be exposed
to certain things that are in certain
movies more than Jackson.
If you could just flip through the
channels,
you know,
it's easy to get to something.
What was the first moment you saw that
you were like,
oh,
this isn't.
This is an adult.
My parents took me to a drive in and
there was some Kung Fu movie.
I was a real little kid,
but I remember my mom being pissed off.
I got to say,
it doesn't surprise me.
It doesn't frighten me.
Like you little Joe Rogan and to come
from like your parents get murdered.
My parents were crazy,
so and in the background your parents
get murdered in your wife and the images
of Kung Fu or fucking streaming and on
your possible tyrants are going,
Joe,
you have to avenge us.
And there was a girl who had a
in the movie,
she had marks on her chest,
like she got scratched and the guy said,
let me see what it looks like.
And so of course she pulls her whole top
off and I just remember my mom saying
this because I was like fucking four
years old or something.
But I remember her going.
She didn't have to take her.
Sure.
Dot that way,
like she was mad at how preposterous it
was.
She didn't have to take her shirt off
that there was another,
there was another route.
This is ridiculous.
That was.
Yeah,
that was exploitative.
She could've just,
her being upset by that.
And what did your dad go like?
Well,
let her finish.
Jennifer,
what was your mother?
I think her real name is a Santa.
Wasn't real.
Yeah,
but she didn't like it.
So she went by the name of Susan.
She and I have something in common
because I don't like it either.
A,
what does that mean?
I don't know.
I don't know if.
No idea.
Some Italian name.
It does sound like an Italian.
A slang for blind people does it there,
but I don't,
I don't appreciate.
There's got to be a lot of them.
Uh,
how many days a week do you guys do the
show to?
Most of the time.
And you're doing a podcast now yourself?
Yes,
I am.
I'm doing a podcast called,
uh,
the champs,
with me and Neal Brennan,
Moshe Kasher,
and I can't even dj doug pound who's
from Tim and Eric.
And uh,
our angle is we have a,
we only have black guests because black
people are so underrepresented and
podcasts each crazy.
Yeah,
it's crazy,
you know.
But like,
are you sure tyler was the only blind
person?
Women and black people just don't.
It really is like,
they're behind on,
on podcasts in terms of popularity.
It's a lot of white men like Joe Rogan.
Um,
and so this week we've had a comics,
we had a jerrod Carmichael on who's
really funny,
young guy and you know,
in words.
And then this week we have Blake
Griffin,
the basketball player who is about as
cool and funny a guy as you'll ever
meet.
Like you can't believe it.
How cool and end.
He's legitimately funny.
Like we were texting one night I go,
uh,
he,
he was going to vegas and I go,
Hey,
if you need,
um,
if you need a carrot top tickets,
kill yourself.
And he wrote back,
actually I just found out that carrot
top killed himself.
And I,
and I wrote back,
oh,
that's a shame.
Kind of put on one hell of a show.
And Blake wrote back,
flake wrote back,
I give them props,
but the fucking guy used them all,
which is like,
that's a pretty good joke for a 22 year
old dunk champion.
But that's maybe not even the best exit.
He's just a really funny dude and
incredibly nice.
Like we had,
um,
we did a podcast in my house and he was
drinking.
He brought up,
he had a bottle of water and then he,
he finished that and then he refilled it
in the,
in the tap,
in my kitchen sink was used to the
locker room on it I guess.
But it was just very like impressed by
like,
how are you not a Dick?
I kept asking him,
how are you known a Dick?
And he never told me no,
but he's like,
he,
yeah,
he's,
he's got one car,
he rents his house.
Like he's just a smart.
It's kind of an interesting situation
with a lot of athletes is a lot of
athletes that just did not nice people.
It's like part of getting good at the
sport means kind of.
Well that's what we were talking about
is being.
And you could talk,
we get,
this would actually be an interesting
thing because I would like to make a
legit documentary about this competition
in America,
uh,
in that.
Because like coby Brian is too
competitive.
Michael Jordan is too competitive to the
point where it's like,
dude,
I don't look like I'm all for winning.
I'm all for.
But you clearly are something is there's
like a switch.
And I was talking to another NBA player
who's,
who's a big star and I won't say his
name [inaudible].
I go,
I go man.
And Colby is a,
he's too competitive.
And he's like,
well,
you know,
man,
it's this,
you know,
you get in the game.
I go,
he's too competitive.
He is,
I know.
And tell them that all the time because
like he,
it's like sort of weird to people when
you're,
that how they get so good though.
Absolutely.
Mike,
Mike Koby Bryant,
Michael Jordan,
guys like that are Michael Jordan is an
incredible athlete.
And you pair that with this crazy spirit
and you get Michael Jordan.
But what I'm saying is at what point is
it too much?
Where it's like you deal with mma,
I think about it in comedy,
guys knocking each other out of the way.
It's like,
what are we getting at?
Because all every study of human
happiness,
and particularly there's a lot of
sociological studies coming out in the
last five to 10 years say that people
don't get any happier beyond a certain,
a financial point.
They don't get any happier,
uh,
with possessions.
They don't,
you know what I mean?
So it's like,
what are we,
what's the point?
It's also now it's like cap.
This is the first time in my life where
I've ever thought like,
capitalism isn't so great.
You know what I mean?
Where it's finally falling apart,
where you kind of go,
well,
all right,
let's see what happens.
I think it's not perfect,
but I think the idea of,
you know,
you're working your merit and your
ability to maneuver your way through the
system counts up to something.
The more effort you put in,
the more reward you get back.
I agree with the idea of capitalism and
that went.
But when you,
when you get involved in the system that
we have now with,
with some just the stock market alone,
like,
and trading.
And what did you short on this article
the other day?
It was brilliant and he said,
because I've had to tell people that,
haven't read it.
It was in the Sunday,
New York Times.
He basically more above it.
The third wealthiest man in the world or
America says,
Richard said,
fuck
he,
whatever.
He owns the company,
a five products in your house.
Um,
he basically said,
look,
we,
I weed people rich people like me have
super rich,
don't get taxed enough.
We used to get tax way more.
And I've had this argument,
but you know,
how Republicans thought,
we say a tax cuts lead to an improvement
in the economy.
And I,
in the back of my head,
I've had this argument that a sacrament
with Vince Vaughn one time about that
people don't get into business if taxes
on doing standup comedy.
We're a 70 percent and not 40 percent.
I would still do standup comedy.
Do you know what I mean?
I'm not doing it for a bit.
I think people start their own business
because they don't like working for
other people and they,
um,
and they have an idea that they want to
create by themselves and I don't think
it comes down to I'm not going to do it
because taxes are too high.
And Warren Buffett made that point that
capital gains tax,
meaning gay,
uh,
taxes on money you make in profit on the
stock market.
Like if you make,
if you invest 100 grand and then you
make 15 grand off of it,
uh,
they will tax the 15 grand at.
Now it's really low.
It's like 11 percent if that.
And Warren Buffet said it used to be 29
and he said,
and everyone invested just as much.
So I,
I reject the idea that,
that we all liked this,
that taxes,
that even socialism,
I think you would do the exact same shit
in a socialist country.
I think you would,
if they paid you to host fear factor and
a podcast and news radio and all this
shit.
If you did the same,
if you,
if we all got paid relatively the same
amount of money,
I believe that I believe that I do what
I do because I'm compelled to do it,
not because of the money.
Now I'm not saying everyone's an artist
or everyone's a writer,
a comedian or whatever,
but I'm,
I'm of the mind that,
that people.
So you,
uh,
you're almost advocating everyone
getting paid the same amount.
Uh,
I don't.
Here's what I'm advocating.
I'm advocating that the,
we live in a country where people,
art,
people die because they're poor and I
think a lot of Republicans or right wing
people think that,
that the reason they're poor is because
they didn't work hard enough.
And that's simply not the case.
A lot of times I think people,
I think a lot of people on the right are
born on third base and think they hit a
triple.
You're born into this career.
You know what?
That's an old phrase,
but yet it's,
it's,
you're born into this life and then you
go because you don't.
It's like when Barbara Bush said during
Katrina,
Hurricane Katrina,
she goes about the people in the
superdome.
She goes,
some of those people have never lived so
well.
It's like you fucking cunt for you to
say yes.
She actually said that.
Um,
so,
so the idea that people will,
they,
they just believe that people in rich
white people couldn't believe that there
were people in America that didn't have
cars when they said they would go,
well,
the mayor told them to get out of town
and drive out into town and they're
like,
they didn't have cars and there were no
buses.
The buses stopped at a certain point.
Um,
so just the idea that people are dying.
Uh,
and then we get into this thing of like
American's best isn't,
uh,
a lot.
Most of the people that say America's
best system in the world don't know what
the other systems and also the idea of
like socialized medicine.
Why wouldn't you want to help save
people's lives like I,
you know,
I think the idea behind it is that it
doesn't encourage competition amongst
doctors,
doctors.
So doctors,
if they're only going to get paid a
certain amount of money,
no matter what,
they have no incentive to be excellent.
But that goes back to my point.
I think most people that are doctors are
compelled to be Dr,
but I don't think it's either or.
You don't think that a doctor is
compelled to be a doctor.
He enjoys it,
but works even harder because he gets
financial compensation for his work.
I think personally,
I personally
don't because I think that people that
are driven are not driven by a financial
renew.
Right?
But you don't think it enhances things
is even if they're not driven by it,
even if they would be doing it happily
for a peasant's wage because they love
the art,
whatever the fuck they're doing,
you don't think that it makes them
really push it and have it sometimes and
not slack off when there's money on
online?
Uh,
yes,
I think,
yeah,
to give people money makes me have
productive.
Uh,
yes.
But I guess the point is why are we so
compelled to be productive?
It's like where they go,
they go,
man,
France fucking only works 35 hour work
week and we get an image in our head of
like,
that's faggy a 35 hour work week.
What are you affect it?
No,
they're having a good life like we
don't,
but we've these systems and the images
and the and the,
the cultural norms are such an America
that we just go with fucking.
I wouldn't be caught dead only working
30 about why,
why,
why do you?
Why?
Why do we all have this need to like,
I'm going to fucking work and I got to
generate and I got to make fucking.
I got to trick people into wanting to
buy shit that I'm doing so that I can
get money and then buy shit that I had
been tricked into that I don't need.
I don't need any of this.
This is a song that I've been bouncing
around forever and my conclusion and I
don't have a real conclusion,
but what I always believe is that it
seems that everything in nature operates
in some sort of a natural system that we
accept.
Whether it's salmon going up river,
there's bizarre things,
you know,
they're going up river and throwing
themselves on the rocks and it happens
every year.
It's just a cycle and it's put in place
for a reason.
It's put in place to make sure that only
bad motherfucker,
salmon get to breed.
You've got to be the baddest
motherfucker to make it up that river.
And I think that that is the same thing
with human beings.
I think we are a part of a natural
system too,
but we're the apex of the natural
systems and we're so super complex that
we don't even understand our motivations
for things.
We don't understand that this drive and
this,
you know,
all our ideas of personal gain really
aren't about personal gain.
It's about enhancing the amount of money
that goes into this system that makes
things and innovate.
It's.
That's what it really is all about.
It has nothing to do with you or I all
of our wants and needs and loves for
material possessions and all the things
that comes with it.
Those that all that is doing is somehow
or another pushing innovation,
pushing you.
Keeping up with the Jones' is pushing
some sort of a technological singularity
that we're pushing towards said
that,
do we not attended?
We just let it is I guess on
productivity as this,
as this,
as this high high.
That's the ultimate goal.
Just seems like no,
it is ridiculous for the fucking people
who own the company,
but it's not.
It's middle.
Like the middle class is gone now
because it's because we've all been
tricked into thinking like,
like these people that provide jobs are
these fucking messiahs the particularly
in the last year and a half of like,
what about the jobs?
What about the jobs so that they go,
well,
we don't want to hurt.
We don't want to tax people like Warren
Buffet because they provide jobs.
Actually most jobs in America,
I think 60 percent of America are from
small businesses,
um,
now having.
So I guess it's just the idea of in
they're starting to study like a gross
national happiness.
Um,
and I,
and,
and a lot of it is not contingent upon
capitalism and productivity and I.
because now I feel like people are so
drunk on productivity and getting these
possessions that they are,
have less time for the kids.
They get to work two jobs,
they got an.
It just seems like it,
it just seems like we're at a breaking
point in terms of like,
uh,
I don't,
I don't know if it'll happen,
but I,
I wish there was some amount of
consideration from people.
Uh,
I,
and having said that I enjoy a hard
day's work.
I enjoy like him.
But what I like about it is I like the
personal interaction.
That's what I've always loved about work
is the personal connection you have with
people and like feeling like we're doing
this thing together that I'm completely
for,
but it's,
you know,
it's like the money part I just find not
negligible because I think it's
important to make a living all that
stuff.
But,
but I just feel like there's too much of
a premium put on productivity and
getting pregnant.
There are.
But you know what?
I love having an.
I love having a laptop.
I think it's awesome.
I really liked being able to go buy a
cellphone.
I love it.
I love being able to get a car.
I'm not making any of these things and
neither are you,
right?
You don't know to live this life this
way.
We need somebody to make shit and you
know,
no one's saying that should be,
you know,
I understand that,
but
that doesn't necessarily preclude that.
It couldn't have happened in another,
in another financial system or arc or
like as,
as the guy on the Internet the other day
said,
a felonious monk is the guy's name,
but he put up,
posted a youtube video that got a lot of
love.
He said a black dude.
He goes,
how can you,
how am I going to say that capitalism is
the best system in the world when we owe
billions of dollars to a communist
country.
You know what I mean?
We just like [inaudible].
America is like,
this is best.
Okay,
well,
why don't we eat.
Their system is clearly beating as a
communist.
Uh,
they're there.
It's like a communist with a soft
capitalism.
I don't even know how you described the
Chinese Chinese a financial.
I don't know enough about our financial
system to even comment on it and when I
say things I'm usually wrong as far as
like numbers and.
No,
I'm,
I'm.
That's the thing about all this shit is
no one under all the fucking.
They don't know.
They know that.
That fucking.
What's his name guy?
The ponzi scheme guy.
What's his name?
Bernie madoff already made off.
It would never been able to get away
with that if they all knew that that is
the best proof of this is some crazy
fucking get.
So when people go,
when people go,
well,
I don't think that we should have done
the bailout and why don't think it's
like,
yeah.
In a perfect world,
Matt Taibbi wrote a book called Grip
Toby,
which is fucking excellent book.
I love that dude.
A.
The book is really,
really good.
I love the rolling stone articles.
He was the guy who.
He broke the Goldman Sachs article
because he was on.
How is he still alive?
I know.
Well,
that's proof that there is no
illuminati.
If you needed any more for,
but that's the only shred of proof,
that mentality.
There's a lot.
Um,
the,
uh,
the he was on,
he was in the press pool on I believe
Obama's or Mccain's campaign for
president and they were all talking
about the,
you know,
the bailout and the all that,
this,
the tarp and all that shit.
And he was with all the correspondence
and he goes,
does any,
do any of us know what top is?
And none of them did.
And he was like,
I have to study,
I have to write about this shit because
we're the ones who are supposed to know
and we don't fucking know.
And he said,
and he said,
the amount of work it takes to even
understand it.
He's like,
it was,
it was pitifully boring,
uh,
how much shit he had to do to even begin
to understand it.
And his point about tea party people
was,
they,
what they long for is simplicity.
And that shit is over some financials.
It's not just financial simplicity,
but I think the whole idea of calling
themselves the tea party,
I mean they,
they,
they are actually,
they're reinvigorating memories of the
original Boston Tea Party.
No,
absolutely.
But,
but having said that,
it wasn't.
The Boston tea party was about taxation
without representation and this is about
complex financial instruments and the
interconnectivity of the global
financial system.
It's like you can't,
they don't know what a fucking uh,
uh,
reverse mortgage,
all that shit
that you just go.
I don't know what the fuck.
I don't know.
I'm a relatively intelligent guy.
I have and my dad was a tax attorney.
I don't understand any of this shit.
And you try to look at like leveraged
mortgage and shorting.
Yeah.
You look at talent.
Try to figure that out.
I,
yeah.
Shorting.
I could explain relatively [inaudible]
like,
but,
but the,
uh,
what about that dude that shorted the
economy that there was some,
some gigantic wage have made that the
economy that are American economy's
going to lose its AAA standard or
whatever it be making millions of
dollars.
Yeah.
Some guy made a fuckload of money when
our credit rating dropped.
Yeah,
that is correct.
But again,
you wouldn't even try to explain that to
somebody in the tea party.
Try to explain that to a fucking
intelligent person.
Try.
Explain.
So anyway,
so yeah,
so,
so they're trying to.
So
they're trying to,
uh,
they long for this simplicity of like,
I don't,
I believe that there should you believe
in,
in corporate socialism,
but you're like,
fuck you if you're dying.
But if a corporation is even as like a,
a graze,
like a flesh wound here comes everyone
to like,
we got to help the corporations because
they provide jobs like you motherfuckers
are buying into this thing of it's the
deification of corporations.
Well,
if you ever watched that documentary,
the corporation.
No.
Yeah,
that's an amazing piece of work.
It really gets you thinking of how the.
It's actually set up and the way it's
set up.
No one feels like they're doing anything
badly even though bad things are getting
done
it.
You can't be a corporation without being
fucking dastardly.
You eat.
You have to,
the way the system instead of,
and this goes back to my,
my,
uh,
my capitalism argument,
the way the system is set up,
if these corporations profits don't
increase every 12 weeks,
their stock price goes down.
So how do you make profits increase?
Either fucking expand your market or cut
workers,
so.
So they cut orders is a fucked up thing
to do and expanding markets is a pretty
dastardly business to uh,
so.
So they're not the only way you survive
in these.
I remember when me and a Chappelle,
we're having stuff with,
with comedy central,
a lot of stuff and I go get that.
That's not their viacom for a reason.
Like they're just,
that's what they fucking,
they who,
how can we get there?
They're hungry machines that are built
to hoard money and fuck people over.
Well,
when you get into negotiations with
anyone about anything and you start
really realizing,
oh yeah,
this is where it is.
How was your a fear factor?
Negotiation was.
It wasn't gross.
It was easy.
There were nice,
great.
Well luckily I did it for 148 episodes,
so they knew I could do it.
I didn't know I was going to have to
audition for it and I was like,
you better not make me audition for our
jobs.
Stupid.
They were always kind of weird with that
show because it did so good.
Like I think it stayed on NBC website
the whole time.
It was off the air.
Like you could still go to the show page
for fear factor and it was kind of odd.
That was the only show that you could do
that with?
Well,
I don't think it was ever officially
cancel and I think we just stopped
production.
Who was weird because it never liked.
Got horrible ratings.
They all die off a little bit,
but it never had.
It never was horrible.
It was just.
We had done a syndicated version.
Are you guys 148 was enough to
syndicate.
Oh,
it was 100 more than enough syndicates.
They syndicates most shows at 100.
No,
absolutely.
But I'm saying did you.
But it's like a who wants to be a
millionaire?
Like they,
they,
they stripped it,
stopped doing it prime time and then
they did they ever.
No,
no,
I didn't do that.
Well that would be the budget of fear
factor is really high when you factor in
some of the crazy fucking stents these
people have to do and they're big this
year,
man.
There's some nutty shit.
These fucking people have to do like
some real real like were you like,
whoa.
Like this is fucking scary.
Let's.
This one's nuts.
I can't describe any of them.
It would be a,
it'd be a breach contract,
but it's
bigger.
Like the stents are bigger and crazier
than we've ever done it before.
You were ahead of your time jail by the
way.
I wanted to say that you never wear
makeup on any time you go on TV shows or
if you're on shows and stuff like that.
He's always been the person where they
have to make a person come and just
like,
no,
I don't want any.
And they're like,
well we're just going to give it up.
No,
I don't want any.
You never get.
I was watching a show the other day
though,
where you can now with the hd,
you could see the makeup,
the bad makeup jobs on all these people,
and now I'm just imagining you with rosy
cheeks.
Yeah.
You had a skin thing though,
didn't you have the little Lego?
You can see it on my knuckles.
You had it on your face that would
periods correct.
Yeah,
but it goes away.
There's a stuff called protopic ointment
as long as you catch it,
like right as it's coming out,
you can get it to go away,
but you've got to be real diligent about
your vitamins and stuff like that and
wouldn't really shows.
It was like when I'm out in the sun,
you know,
got it.
Really shows them a speaking of vitamins
that wanted to talk about last time we
were here,
we were talking about a hgh,
all that stuff.
Um,
and a buddy of mine texted me and said,
[inaudible],
you were saying that there's basically
no side effects,
etc.
Not say there's no sound.
It's relatively safe if you're doiNg it
under a doctor's supervision.
Right.
You're smart about it.
Uh,
and my buddy texted me and said,
uh,
what about,
what about like cancerous cells?
It will accelerate the growth of any
kind of self.
There's no evidence,
there's no evidence that it supports
cancer growth,
but there is evidence that if your
body's immune system's down and you're
not healthy than cancer can grow in your
bodies easier,
right?
If you have your overall system is
operating more efficiently because of
hormones that you've introduced to it or
because of vitamins and supplements,
if your system is working better,
you're going to be able to fight things
off better.
It's really that simple.
If you take a holistic approach to the
human body,
you know,
cancer is a very,
very,
uh,
tricky mystery of the human body as to
why it exists in the first place.
But a lot of people believe that
anything,
any ailment that at least part of it has
to do with how you feel,
what kind of energy you have,
how much work you have to put in every
day.
How happy are you?
And the idea is how much does the whole
system are you?
How much money did you make last
quarter?
That doesn't protect you from cancer
fella.
Wait,
what?
But that's what they would have.
You believe that if you're.
Who are these day,
I believe the exist in that world needed
to be an artist.
This is crazy.
It's like rejecting yourself in the
proletariat to know.
But I see people.
nobody's more proletariat.
Then the kid,
the kid proletarian and he calls himself
the kid.
I liked to hang out with that guy.
The,
uh,
the,
I just think it's fucking disgusting.
I think when people are,
again,
it goes back to that you can be anything
in this country.
You can be anything in this country.
And they,
it's never.
You never hear it from when people go,
yeah,
you can be in this country.
Having said that,
if you're white,
if you're born into a,
into a upper middle class white people
or above,
it's way easier to be anything which
they never said.
What's an unknown saying?
It's a level playing field and it's
impossible to make it level.
They'Re is.
I agree,
but they're implying that it's level.
I think that the people on the upper
crust believed that it's level goes bY,
did anybody believes it's level,
but I do think that they think it's a
better setup than India.
That's what I think.
I think they believe that people here
have more of a shot at living a real
life than France.
You know,
there's people that have these ideals,
but you know what America is ranked in
terms of class a jumping in the world.
14th.
Yeah.
Who's the number one who just fucking
around eight might be India.
Really?
Yeah.
It's,
it's,
it's definitely not.
Um,
it's,
I don't think it's the uk.
I don't think.
I think or it might be Germany,
Germany has got a really good economy
but,
but uh,
in terms of like the german,
he was in the shitter right now to now
they're the only ones that's not really
not.
Yeah,
they've done better than anybody.
Some reason when we were over in Germany
doing a show,
that's what our driver was saying.
Maybe he was just a whiner.
Uh,
yeah.
No.
So,
so the idea that America is the best you
can jump.
It's like,
yeah,
first of all,
it's 14th in the world out of $200,
which again is we made good,
but in terms of if you ask people,
they'd all go,
we're number one.
Yeah.
You know why we're number one?
Because we had leonard's cantered.
We make muscle cars.
We have some of the fucking best shit.
We designed some of the best shit.
We invent some of the best shit.
Fucking van halen.
There's a reason why we have the best
comedians.
There's a reason why that's a fact.
Even though there's some good ones from
other countries,
that's a fact.
Give us number one on shit that we
deserve,
that we're actually number one on,
but we're not number when people are.
You can be anything.
There's of.
We don't have all the best bands,
but we got most of them.
Let's be realistic.
Uh,
yeah.
Joe,
you make a really good point.
We do have most of them.
America.
I'm ted nugent concert.
The other night on tv who was there had
it on hd net.
I have this crazy thing with ted nugent,
man to new [inaudible],
one of my favorite people to watch.
You know,
how come?
Well,
because he's.
first of all,
he's super right wing rah rah guns kill
american bison.
He dodged the draft in Vietnam and if
you listen to some of the stories that
he told,
I don't know if it's true,
but by shitting himself and by doing
crystal meth and getting his heart rate
up and then showing up,
I don't know which of those stories are
true and you know,
but this guy dodged the draft and yet
he's this crazy like super pro military.
God bless our war.
Yes,
god bless you warriors.
And he's got a camo vest on and he's
playing guitar and looking to god made
some bad ass tunes mean no matter what
you say about his politics,
stranglehold is a fucking jam.
You know that,
that song,
man,
that's a bad ass.
That's one of my favorite all time
songs.
He played the fucking shit out of a
guitar,
right?
Yeah,
fine with ted nugent can play the
fucking shit out of a guitar.
But god damn,
he's so crazy with this pro warrior
stuff and salute the warriors.
It's,
it's,
it's
first of all,
it's a pretty easy,
you know what I mean?
It's like pretty low hanging fruit to be
like,
I'm support the troops.
It's so silly and it's,
it's almost like he's positioning
himself to be a cheerleader.
You know,
I'm your guy and you're going to
cheerlead a guarantee.
You're not going to get another.
But pro-america enemy.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Even controversial doled ted's
controversial,
but you know exactly what it's
marketing.
Yeah,
it's fucking fascinating is what it is.
Uh,
somebody,
um,
when,
when they swift voted for john kerry,
bill clinton had the best point,
which is the minute they swift boated
them when they said he didn't,
he wasn't a hero,
isn't all that stuff.
he should have challenged dick cheney
and George Bush to a debate about
Vietnam and he would've won the election
like that.
Um,
I think the way he laid down after that
was all over.
It was almost like he's not really
wanting to be president in the first
place.
Uh,
he,
he's,
he's a,
he's soft.
Yeah.
Again,
that's one of those things.
It's like,
I feel like democrats,
if they have a shitty candidate will
kind of admit it.
I'd be like,
eh,
no.
I feel like republicans kind of did with
mccain where they were like,
yeah,
when,
so far as to get sarah pailin to join
them.
That's how little they believed in him.
Yeah,
exactly.
Wanted to do a little bit the trick.
They wanted to go to the party favor.
Yeah.
Then now this,
this michelle barre.
When things fucking.
What are you,
I understand you want to be in charge.
I know you want to win.
That's where this winning thing comes
again.
You want to win,
but at what cost do you really think
she's good at being charged or
something?
Here's the real question.
Why did this country become like this?
Why are other countries more relaxed
wise like Italy the way it is,
why
Italy is really disorganized?
There are,
I mean in terms of what are you talking
about?
I mean about the people,
about people,
their behavior,
what they accept and what they don't
accept,
why they're driven and whether or not
driven
well that that's an I,
I,
people come here.
I mean,
I think that originally people came to
America to escape.
I always call us like not england,
whatever angle is like they don't have
guns.
Well we fucking have nothing but guns
like,
uh,
they,
the,
the character of America is a,
it is this kind of outlaw thing.
It's certainly become this outlaw thing
and it has become.
We make best fucking cars and we got the
data.
It's just constant.
Nobody believes we make the best car.
Whatever you were saying where you're
like,
we need to make muscle cars.
Vented muslim,
but queers.
Yeah.
If you asked a bunch of people in the
south and the north west,
if they will go,
yeah,
fucking America does.
It's all that stuff of we're the best.
You don't really hear it in other
countries.
You hear like,
this is a nice
country,
but you don't go.
We're the best in the world.
Are so polite about it.
They're like,
canadians are doing good down.
There are apps.
Yeah.
They caught a lot of canadian comedians
in the american character.
I don't think it has
to do with the old west.
It's like the last,
uh,
it's kind of the last land that was
settled in the world was the west.
So it's just wild douche bags,
dia that we are,
it's a great question.
It's one of those guns,
germs and steel steel things where you
just go,
I don't really know why we are where we
are.
I always think australian dudes are a
little rough because of the prison
thing.
That's why there's so many,
uh,
australian like leading men because
they're like,
fucking still dudes over there.
Um,
whereas,
uh,
he had the american character.
I,
I don't,
I don't know.
But,
but I know that were a little soft.
Right?
I know I put,
I don't think we're soft,
I think,
well in terms of that,
but I'm saying the american character in
terms of like we're the best,
uh,
we're,
we never fucking lose nothing.
We withdraw.
We don't have a hero right now.
Do we have an action hero semester
stallone to 70 fucking years old?
He's still beating people up.
Oh yeah.
No,
like the rocks.
Not really much of an action hero
because he is.
He's legit,
but he's not.
He's not legit.
Like stallone was.
No,
not yet.
but it's not going to happen.
Well,
the thing about stallone,
stallone was legit as an actor first.
Like with rocky,
he was legitimate and an actor.
He was respected.
Then he went on commercial as commercial
as you can get like many,
many times that he started out as that
legit guy.
But in terms of action stars,
I mean I feel like you had said like the
new guy's going to be like a hardy
christian bale.
Christian bale I guess is kind of
different action star,
but it's the same way.
Yeah.
No.
If there's none of that 80,
it's morning in America.
That shit,
like all that that's over.
And now it's just this like it's America
to me is defined at this point by
dislike.
Vicious infighTing between left and
right and everyone's got their own
little own little bunker and fuck them
and everyone's got in the audience.
Everyone's got their own little feedback
loop of like people.
I go on the huffington post and the
daily beast.
I would never go on fox news.
I would never.
I actually tweeted a couple of weeks
ago,
uh,
which news do you guys root for fox or
cnn?
Because that's what it's come to.
It's come down to these teams of like,
I like that news.
Yeah,
it is a while.
Meanwhile it's,
it ought to be facts.
You know what I mean?
Now it's come down to this like,
tell me the facts that favor my ego
telling me that,
spin this,
so that.
So that my worldview is confirmed.
It is amazing and we've allowed
entertainment to enter into the news
because that is exactly what it is.
Editorial and entertainment.
Yeah.
No,
when you,
whenever you see some fucking guy and he
gets busted doing something creepy
sexually and he's like a senator.
Fox news will always put democrat and
second,
doesn't matter if that guy's a
republican,
they'll put democrat and then they
correct it,
but the thing is,
the most important thing is that the
first inclination,
the first image was another pervert
democrat.
Right.
That's illegal,
man.
You guys are criminals.
But if the fucking sending the news,
you're a propaganda machine.
They are very probably supposed to be
protected from that.
Well,
but they,
they,
that's all.
That's all gone.
This is the protection from that dude,
the internet.
I agree.
Dude.
Since doing this,
doing your pockets.
The first one,
I don't know,
it was six weeks ago or something.
I really see the value of the.
It's just so democratic.
It's fucking fair.
Because I went on the road and I had
people showing up from twitter and I was
getting like the.
I was getting a bunch of money at the
door,
like I was getting a percentage of the
door instead of this thing of like,
yeah,
we'll give you 1500 for the weekend and
then you maybe if you make the bonus,
which you never going to make,
and then I can do one show,
tweet it out and get a grant,
you know what I mean?
Get like a fair wage for,
for the skill and the,
a popularity instead of them going like,
you know,
you're not popular,
you're going,
but I have 80,000
people on twitter who sam popular come
to the show and yet you're telling me.
So.
So that's what's great about the
internet is,
is it,
is really fair.
And,
and uh,
and I didn't even realize the sort of
power of it.
you were quick to.
It wasn't because of your worldview or
was it because,
uh,
because you just happened to,
you lucked into it.
Well,
I've been pretty deeply embedded into
the internet since 1998.
I had a message board on my website and
so from 1998 I would write blogs and
interact with people on my message board
and I think in 2001 we switched it over
to a vbulletin and now it's kinda like
$5 million posts on it.
yeah,
it's got.
I mean I don't know how many thousands
of members,
but it's super active and people are
constantly posting on a regular basis
and there's a.
There's great value in connecting with
people online.
The biggest resource in human history
for gathering information,
for being introduced to new information
is this.
Nothing is like twitter has ever existed
before.
Every fucking day someone's sending
someone.
I don't know who's sending me some cool
link yesterday.
It was some fucking
crazy video where these dudes took a
hornet and they threw it into a spider's
nest to see who would win the horn of
the spider.
It was fucking bad ass man.
That marvel,
but the right.
That spider just fucks that hornet up.
Spoiler alert,
spoiler alert.
It's worth seeing again though,
even if I have spider,
spider,
jack's the hornet and so no,
no comparison long was the fight.
That was very quick.
Hugh sackett,
did you give it a van?
A mma announcing?
No,
I didn't.
No commentary.
I did a.
I did a lot of this fuck by myself.
You know when you by yourself going,
fuck,
we just lucky spiders are little man.
could you imagine if a spider the size
of your house?
Man,
you have translators out here.
I didn't even know there was translated
in California.
Huge dead translate on.
It's killed once,
one accidentally.
I didn't realize I'd killed until I
stepped on it.
It was in front of my house.
It was like my fucking hand was my hand.
I'm not joking.
It was my guy,
harry harry fucking crab.
It was a crab walking around.
I really didn't realize how big it was.
I stepped on it and it crunched and then
I went back inside the house and got a
flashlight and came outside and looked
at.
Giant was so big.
It almost seemed like a pet that got
loose.
Doesn't that freak you out that when you
lay in your bed that some spiders that
could crawl from the host of fear
factor.
Okay.
Everything can be probably somewhere.
I've seen everything creepy crawly on
this planet.
On your few.
Can't throw me.
Yeah,
the dude,
eddie bravo went to Costa Rica once and
he told me how horrifying it was laying
in this place because it was like an
open air cabana and that's how they kind
of kept at cooley were above the ocean
and above the wall there was like a gap
between the ceiling and the wall.
Whereas just air comes in and fucking
bugs and he said did well like birds.
These birds size bugs flying around the
fucking room.
Yeah.
That,
that kind of shit freaks me out,
but this isn't that bad.
Every now and then you got to kill a
snake.
Based on that.
You were talking about a snake the other
day.
He killed a rattlesnake the other day
and then there was transistor.
You're time I fuck rattle snakes and
people say you shouldn't do that.
And because I've got kids and
rattlesnakes can go fuck themselves.
Yeah.
If I can,
and I have dogs,
my I've had when I had pit bulls,
both my dogs had to bring them to the
hospital on two separate occasions for
rattlesnake bites.
Oh my god.
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
no joke.
Dude.
You're a fucking vigilante.
I went running ones with the dogs.
I ran over this rattlesnake and I didn't
realize I had run over it until I was in
the air,
in between paces.
I thought it was a log.
I thought it was a big ass fucking
branch.
I mean it was big,
you know,
because I'm running with the pitbulls
and I have to keep up with them and I'm
taking the turn and as I take the term,
we'd go over.
They didn't notice it either.
Thank god,
because it was totally outstretched.
They go over it.
I go over and then I stop and turn.
I pulled him over,
I get 'em on the leashes and I start
pulling up to the thing and it's like my
forearm dude.
It's enormous.
Big fucking
rad norm.
It's like your forearm.
My form for a snake is huge for a guy.
It's not too small.
It's not that bad,
it's not embarrassing,
but these fucking snake was huge dude.
It was like it had to be eight feet
long.
You didn't kill it and you just.
I try to kill it,
but yeah,
I try to tie the dogs up your website
very quickly.
My website I've been doing since
[inaudible] 98.
And what,
who do you think
is who is like if you had one,
if you.
If there was like the joe rogan fan,
can you describe him or her?
To me?
No,
there's what do they all have?
What's the commonalIty?
Is there anything?
No,
I don't think so.
No.
There's a lot of right wing guys on my
message board and a lot of like really
hippie guys and you know,
I can say there's,
there's no,
you know,
there's people that appreciate someone
who's going to tell you the truth is
going to be people that know that I've
been involved in controversial shit from
the beginning of my career.
I don't.
I think that if you can express yourself
as long as you can,
let people know how you feel about
things you should,
you should do.
What the fuck are you like?
You should do what you want and not
worry about others.
That's what I love about twitter is you
just say something like,
fuck you,
and you just go,
yeah,
no,
I'm not taking it down.
This is what I.
like I said,
it's the George Bush thing and just go
like he,
George Bush never made a mistake
because.
yeah,
well that's what I mean.
Like some people go when,
when,
when we killed in london,
it's like,
or gets killed or whatever you want to
say it in people's heads.
I think they get that credit.
Bush somehow.
If there's one constant in all the
people that I do meet,
is that there?
Surprisingly nice and I get this from
comedy club waitresses.
They're always saying that when we do
theaters,
people always say that like,
your fans are so nice.
They're you guys.
That's what,
if there's anything I try to put out,
are they put up like underdogs?
I guess everyone's maybe in this world
if you're not a fucking ceo,
you're an underdog.
Yeah,
I mean,
yeah.
If what you said about corporations is
true and it is the,
yeah,
we're all underdogs and we're all in
this together and I think if there's
anything they share is that there's a
lot of fucking nice people that come to
my shows and people that are just trying
to have some fun man and people that
respect someone who's going to say what
they really think.
Yeah.
That's the other thing politically,
that they've been learning.
Studies have elections.
They people vote for people with the
courage of their convictions.
That's why they go.
He's a flip flopper.
Everyone's like,
fuck this guy.
Wait.
He takes into consideration facts and
changes his opinion.
That fucking fuck this guy because he
just needs you to be like this pillar.
That's George Bush was a pillar of,
I believe stupidity,
but he wasn't.
He didn't move.
Yeah.
They also have everybody convinced that
if you do flip flop and get caught,
you're done.
Instead of someone coming up and saying,
yeah,
in
some ways you done because
they go,
this guy's soft.
This guy's a flip flopper.
People respond to the courage of your
convictions.
I told a story the other night,
uh,
at our,
I did a show with ari.
I'm in montreal.
It was,
we were telling stories and I told a sex
story that,
that,
uh,
I was dating two girls at the same time,
which I didn't like.
I don't like doing that because I told
them was variety.
Well,
no,
not my problem is when you date more
than one girl,
you get the stories mixed up.
Oh yeah.
He
died in nine slash 11.
My mistake.
Um,
so,
uh,
so I was dating two girls.
One came over thursday night.
She had very short hair then and she
gave me oral sex.
friday night,
a long haired girl come over.
She,
she don't come over and we had regular
sex.
A saturday night,
the short haired girl comes back,
we have oral sex again.
I go to the bathroom,
she comes out and goes,
hey neil,
if you're going to sleep with other
girls,
uh,
be a little more clever about it.
And I was like,
what are you talking about?
She goes,
I just found a hairband and economy
behind your bed.
Now I'm basically cold,
busted and uh,
and I took a pause,
like a really.
And she goes,
yeah,
and I go,
man,
what has been going on in here?
And just walked out of the room and she
was fine with it.
What's because I just sold you just go.
That's crazy.
And just
eddie murray used to do a joke about it
where it's like just denied.
Denied.
Yeah.
But that's better than denying instead
of denying you're incredulous.
You can't believe this is going down.
That's better than denying who you
reacted perfectly.
If you denied it,
you'd have probably been busted.
Yeah.
But instead of denying it,
you like,
you didn't even consider it as a
possibility that you could have been.
He's been doing.
Yeah.
You were like,
what the fuck is this?
I got to talk to them
manager or something?
Yeah.
You must have a clean underneath bed
though.
I never clean underneath my bed.
So even if a girl came underneath my
bed,
she'd be like,
oh my god,
there's $500 bucks.
Somebody taught me a long time ago.
If you're dating more than one girl,
you gotta,
you gotta have a lint brush.
That's the key.
when pro,
because they girls shared a lot of hair
and earrings.
You gotta scoop earrings out.
You got to have a lint brush.
You really gotta be on top of it.
You're getting variety.
Jail.
Yeah,
but you're also.
There's a lotta,
there's a lot of.
There's.
Look,
people don't think about it from the
guy's point of view.
Who's,
who has to date three different women.
They don't.
They only see it if you're a dog.
Yes.
but do you have any idea of the stress?
I'm under that.
I'm constantly having a lint brush
things and fucking collect the earrings
and,
and um,
socks.
People.
Don't.
People feel bad for you,
dude.
You should be able to cheat and not get
fucked with you.
Fucking these broads.
Got to get off my back.
What
do you think about people that want to
live a,
a polyamorous life and just continue
that forever?
Like the idea that we should never be
committed to one person and we all
should stop being so jealous about what,
what our loved ones do with their bodies
and just go and have a wild.
It seems crazy.
It's a great idea.
In theory,
I think it's good cause I like I have a.
I had a girlfriend and then we broke up
and now it seems as if we're going to.
We're headed back to togetherness.
Oh shit.
I'm.
Hi.
I'm and I'm and,
and we were talking about it yesterday
actually.
That is my problem with relationships is
you have to make an emotional promise in
the future.
So I have to go.
I'm going to love you 10 years from now.
Meanwhile,
I've changed so much in three years.
the fact that I'm making fucking
emotional promises.
It's crazy.
I hope I love you.
I hope I love you,
but the idea of going like,
I guarantee you I love you and if I
can't then you get half of my shit.
I bet you that I'm going to love you.
I'll bet you half my shit that I'm going
to
relationships make sense to me.
Of course marrIage doesn't make sense to
me.
Less kids are involved and even then I
only got married because of my wife.
I wanted her to be happy and I wasn't
going anywhere.
I'm committed to the whole thing and
raising children all requires this level
of commitment and that and I'm more than
willing to embrace it.
The only reason why I was willing to do
it legally and sign all that stuff,
I was like,
this is like,
this is some crazy stupid tradition.
It's completely ridiculous.
Then sayIng you should have to break up
and you have to bring in the legal
system.
So to do it without children to me seems
preposterous.
To do it with children is ridiculous,
but I submitted to it but to do it just
because you're in love like my god,
you're crazy.
You're connecting yourself with someone
legally and
well.
Do you really fucking know them?
You don't.
I mean it's fucking.
You don't specify things are going
great.
Yeah.
When your life is going great and
everything's going great,
you you barely know people.
You know them.
When some shit hits the fan,
it's easy to.
It's easy to know somebody when you're
in fucking.
You're both in love with each.
Exactly what's the.
Especially in the beginning because
every little annoyances like,
no,
that's a little thing,
and then it metastasizes and it's three
and a half years later and you're like,
ooh,
and also you might be evolving and them
not advice averse.
You know
how you've evolved as a person.
You almost are saying when you're in,
if you're going into this relationship
like I'm done revolving when I know the
way I feel about this and you is never
going to change.
It's like it just.
It seems like a state basis
when you could.
You could get involved with the chicken.
Then she can turn vegan on you and then
you're in the middle of the relationship
and all of a sudden they're giving you
shit about eating cheeseburgers.
definitely.
Oh fuck that woman.
Have you well know I'm people think
I am vegan.
I didn't do.
I was single when I never do it in.
Why not the that?
Because the meat industry is fucking
disgusting.
Like the amount of greenhouse gases,
cows and mitch shit like that.
Like they're worse than cars and I'm not
that big of mika.
I just wasn't,
you know.
Here's the problem with that statement.
Go.
Cows are awesome and so are cars.
So we've got a problem.
Cool.
We've got a problem because I enjoy.
You testified before congress.
Uh,
I will call me.
That'd be.
I will have that testimony and if I do
testify before congress,
you can guarantee 100 percent.
I will be high on marijuana are usually.
Well,
whatever testifying.
Did the fear factor people get get on
you about being,
talking about being high end.
One of the producers sent me a text
message when we had signed the deal
saying breakout the pot lollipops
because it was a,
was an inside joke.
I would take the pot lollipop every day
at work.
Right.
That's how I enjoyed the show.
I enjoyed doing it.
When I was stoned.
I would come in,
if I wasn't stone,
I would think about all the shit that I
could be doing at home.
I could be playing pool with one of my
friends.
I could go to jujitsu class,
I,
I'll do all these things that I,
that I would like to do today and write
some jokes instead of being out here in
some fucking rock quarry with six
different knuckleheads that want to be
famous on tv,
but then out of that pot lollipop and
now it's soaking the full experience and
then all of a sudden I'm like a fucking
scientist.
Then all of a sudden I'm studying human
behavior and taking it all in house and
cars and thinking about new orleans
between the sun and the earth and how
this is fear keeps the heat in and it is
that.
If it just shifts a little bit,
we freeze to death.
That's the.
Did you.
Did you tell your back on a lot of cops?
Oh yeah.
Yeah,
right away.
Great.
There's no way to do it.
Other than that,
I wouldn't disrespect people that enjoy
the original show by trying to do it
sober.
One hundred 48 episodes.
Don't out of my fucking mind the
integrity of that,
but listen,
it's medical marijuana.
What I'm doing is legal in the state of
California.
I'm a.
I'm a voter
I that had told me to ask you about
something that's like,
it's,
it's the chemical that gets released
when you die,
but you can eat it or smoke it or
something around the dmt not.
Yeah.
Oh,
sorry.
Sorry.
I've talked to about it so many times or
something like google it.
They'll give you a documentary to watch.
Can you get me any?
No,
I can't because it's illegal.
You fucking retard.
You mean like lollipops,
you know?
I mean like dimethyl tree.
Domestic trip to me is like really,
really illegal.
Like it's not like a slap on the wrist
sort of thing.
Having a nuclear weapon in your house or
something.
Is that true?
It's scheduled one,
but so is weed,
but weed is elise has admitted it may.
Even the government has admitted has
certain medical properties to it.
There's,
you know,
it's very hard,
very hard pressed to come up with
medical properties for
dmt.
The problem is dmt exists in many
different plants,
not just one and all the plants that it
exists in our legal right,
so you can actually have a plant that
contains dmt in it and it's not like
having a marijuana plant which contains
thc.
The dmt plant would not be illegal.
It would only be illegal if you
extracted it,
went into the plant and took this stuff
out.
But the problem is also exists in your,
your,
your own body.
It's like terence mckenna joke.
Everybody's holding when it comes to the
you,
you're all,
you're all legal.
You know,
you're all.
Y'all have it.
Isn't hgh illegal?
You'll have different synthesize with
bacteria.
I mean they make it something that they
make in a laboratory.
It's different,
but I'm saying it's not mobile dentical
I don't know.
No,
no.
You can get it prescribed.
It's prescribed it for a bunch of
different things.
For recurring.
It's healthy.
It's healthy for your body,
you know?
I mean,
I'm not saying all levels of it are
healthy,
but for people that have injuries per
month because I want really want to
know.
Well,
we'll sit down.
I'll talk to,
you know.
I know,
But I want to.
I don't want to wait.
I want to know the information.
Okay,
well I'll do that some other time.
Maybe you didn't fuck in the army knew
you should've gotten high with us before
the show.
Neil.
Neil brennan is not high on marijuana
and brian and our need some in your
life.
Brown settled.
Yeah,
I do drink.
Not really.
It'll put you in a good place.
How can we take the weed?
Because it just makes me sleepy.
But you get in the wrong lead.
My does not make you sleepy.
It makes you think about space.
Yeah.
No,
I do want to do the uh,
the,
the chamber.
You should do it then the fuck you want
to do it?
Well,
who's holding you back?
If you want to do it,
why haven't you done it yet?
You're one of those guys.
You have fox something.
There's a force.
A lot of people are scared,
man,
scared of themselves.
Uh,
I,
yeah.
I feel like I know my foot pretty well.
That tank is you buddy.
If you know yourself,
you've got to get to know yourself much
better.
Tank is,
especially if you're high.
The scariest most self soul searching
moments I've ever had is alone in that
tank.
On a pot.
Brownie.
yeah.
Because the marijuana,
when you,
when you eat it,
especially anything that's fucking with
you,
anything that's in your head that you're
not happy with,
just gets exposed.
You know,
that's the beauty of that tank.
It's just like a,
it's just the,
like the best show for you to see.
That is your life.
That is like,
here.
Here is you.
This is you.
We're going to put on a show and we're
going to show you.
We're going to do a documentary on your
life.
What changes did you make every result
of?
I'm not talking about outlook.
I'm talking about talking about behavior
from the tank.
Yeah.
I think it slow.
Slowly but surely made me a nicer
person.
For sure.
Yeah.
Made me more humble.
I think all the psychedelic experiences
make you humble.
They're all very humbling because
they're very ego dissolving and there
you know,
you,
you feel like you're connected with
everything and when you come back you're
like,
wow,
just knowing that that experience
exists,
you've heard that you've sought study
where people that did shrooms,
like adult
did it,
like conservative adults and I think
seven of them,
seven out of 10 said it was one of the
best spiritual experiences of their life
and they do it again.
It's beautiful.
Yeah,
no,
I agree.
I would encourage them.
I've always said I would encourage my
kids to do sharp.
You know,
it's all about set and setting.
People have taken them in party ideas,
you know,
in a party saying and you know,
had a bad time.
Maybe they got too high.
It had a bad trip.
It's all what it's going to take you on
a journey and you have to submit to the
journey and you also have to be willing
to go for a ride.
Man,
you can't try to resist it if you try to
resist it and hold it back or deny the
things that it's exposing.
That's what a bad trip was all about,
you know,
that's the epitome of a bad trip.
I also think there's people that just
shouldn't ever do it ever though.
Absolutely.
Like duncan saying yesterday that he
wanted to not dose whatever large
amounts of people,
you know,
he was talking about.
It's a really brilliant idea in
injecting it into the common cold,
injecting lsd into the common cold.
So somehow when you got the common cold,
you also want in his vast lsd trip.
Wow.
That is brilliant.
Yeah.
Until you get some kid that has,
you know,
a whatever,
some kind of alzheimer's or not
alzheimer's,
but uh,
autism.
And then he fucks him.
Yeah.
And then he goes out and shoots up
a genius idea though.
The idea of spreading something
psychoactive through a cold.
Like I wonder if that's possible,
like just the idea of a cold.
To me it's so bizarre,
the idea that there's some invading
organism that tries to shut your body
down and consuming.
You have to battle it with your immune
system,
but the fact that maybe this invading
army,
my kerrick psychedelic chemicals,
why not?
It's where the capital thing comes in
again because capitalism,
cause they,
they,
it's,
they spend more money on boner pills and
then they do on solving the common cold
because there's just more money and
vulnerable probably aids research than,
than boner pills.
And it's like because there's just more
money and it's like,
yeah,
but you're going to do more good.
What do you inherent good.
What do you think about the people that
don't believe that hiv causes aids?
Have you ever heard of this argument?
Does,
what the fuck is the guys?
And there's one doctor that's like a
very well respected doctor.
UH,
and he's got this,
he's a teacher at the university of
California in berkeley and he,
for whatever reason,
doesn't believe that hiv causes aids.
Yeah,
I mean,
again,
I think a lot all conspiracy theorists
and all that shit is just about people
going like they're lying.
It's like calling bullshit all the time
so that you feel like you have the upper
hand
peter duesberg.
yeah.
This is the only thing,
the only reason why I listened to this
guy at all.
I mean I don't,
but the only reason why I would is that
he's a phd professor of molecular
biology at the university of California,
berkeley.
That sounds like a guy who knows things.
Yeah.
But there's hundreds of guys that I
know.
It's just so funny when a guy like this,
like this is my point of view.
I'm in no way saying that hiv does not
cause aids and nor would I ever.
What the fuck do I know?
I'm not A doctor.
So what freaks me out is when I read.
So you got a real nice dot.
You've got forums like a rattle snake.
This when a guy like this peter duesberg
guy who is way more educated than me in
the subject,
you know,
and way smarter than me to when this guy
has some fucking,
you know,
all these,
uh,
website articles and all these published
papers on this shit.
And he believes that act was what was
killing all these people back in the
day.
God bless.
Sounds it sounds completely nutty.
Uh,
yeah.
Got bluffing.
I mean,
he might be just as crazy as the person
that's saying that the end of the world
was going to happen two months ago,
you know?
No,
it's funny how much worse alcohol is for
you than aids says,
look,
magic johnson is alive and kicking with
hiv,
but amy winehouse is dead as fuck
alcohol.
yeah,
that's pretty interesting.
Uh,
hiv aids is way more treatable.
Yeah.
Alcohol then like the alcoholism.
Alcoholism or even drug it certain like
nobody wants to get aids.
Again,
alcoholics,
you have to keep them from going back to
getting it.
Could you imagine if someone got aids
and you cured them and they're like,
oh,
I just like to get some aids again.
Shit.
I got the itch for aids every day.
What are you going this weekend?
Hey,
try not to get aids guys and try not to
get aids,
but that's alcohol.
You a,
you gotta keep those people from
crawling back into that fucking
alcoholics depression?
No,
I mean I do occasionally,
but I don't need it.
If I,
if I go out to dinner,
I might have a glass of wine or
something like that.
If I go out with some friends and
somebody wants to do a shot,
I usually don't say no,
but I could go the rest of my life
without drinking the night be I feel the
exact same way.
But the marijuana,
because the idea of,
of being
like,
I need a alcoholic,
you know,
get rid of my inhibitions.
I don't really have any inhibitions.
Can shoot with your arms up in the air
like that.
Exposing your armpits.
You don't give a fuck.
I really like doesn't even have any
inhibitions.
Look guys,
this is like some shit that you would
say to a check right before you booked
your car.
Oh,
a buddy of mine used to say the greatest
pickup line.
You know this buddy.
I want to think about it.
Okay.
I'll know it as immediately.
He used to say,
um,
you,
he would go up to girls and go,
uh,
they say that spontaneity is a sign of
intelligence and you strike me as a very
spontaneous person would say we go back
to my place and fuck or something and it
would work.
Is that your ideas?
How often would listen?
We both intelligent here.
Let's cut the bullshit in a muffler
hanging out there.
It was in the eighties,
the eighties.
This is pre a pre aids.
Nice.
Which is raw dog.
Yeah.
Rhonda,
a.
That's ted nugent
song.
Raw dog war hog.
One of his war.
So,
you know,
I watched a show,
jay.
Well this is one of the reasons why
because I look,
I even from people that I disagree with
them on some things I may agree with
very much so and other things.
And one of the things I agree with him
is he's a hunter and he gets all of his
food from his own ranch.
He has this huge high fence set up with
this,
like,
you know,
several thousand acres he owns and taxes
and he goes around on his ranch and
shoots animals and eat.
That's what he eats.
He doesn't eat subsistence.
Yeah.
I like the idea of that.
I love the,
you know,
the fact that this guy stands up for
people that think that there's something
wrong with hunting,
you know,
and I think that's completely
ridiculous.
I think if you're eating meat and then
you're telling people that they
shouldn't be hunting,
that's just fucking nonsense,
man.
It's ridiculous.
You know,
hunting is the.
If you want protein from animals,
that's probably the best way to get it
for you.
And it's probably the best way to get it
for your head.
So you understand what the fuck meat is.
You know,
I mean,
the reason why american indians were,
were so vigilant when it came to using
every single part of that animal because
they knew how god damn hard it was to
get a deer.
You know,
you used every part of that animal.
Nothing went to waste.
Right.
You know,
and we,
we have this incredibly wasteful
society,
incredibly wasteful attitude and I think
hunting and gathering up your own food
just to,
you could put that in your hand.
That's really what you're eating.
This is where it comes from.
Well the other day about if they thought
the recession would change people's
character somewhat,
like if,
if,
if because of now that because it seemed
like everyone was rich for 10 years and
now now it seems like everyone's poor
and you hope,
I mean at least because I would drive
around la and go like make a good living
and I don't have a bmw or I don't have a
poor whatever these cars are and I would
always think why do people.
So I'm hoping that it'll go back to.
I hope people's values will be less
materialistic.
I kind,
I mean I,
I could go either way.
I can make an argument either for either
for either being likely to happen
because they're not going to stop
promoting consumerism like
bore.
We're locked into a certain pattern of
behavior and it would take something
monumental shift that it would take some
19 sixties type shit.
Where's everybody got on acid?
It would really take something like
that.
It would just something
that's ever going to happen again
because I haven't.
I've just had a theory that those
computers are two good shit's too sweet,
man.
Too fucking easy.
Sit in my house or go out and riot,
go out and pick it and go out and you
have the reason those kids in london
we're riding is because they fucking are
poor and they have nothing to do.
Listen,
there's a.
There's a thing going on in Florida
right now where they have a real problem
with these pain management centers and
what it is.
Legal drugs,
right?
See cotton's.
Yeah.
You can get them at a pain management
center where you go in and you literally
go to a doctor and then right next store
from the doctor after he writes you a
prescription.
There's a pharmacy.
It's all inside the same building and
what it is is they figured out a way to
make heroin in a pill form.
It's really that simple.
They figured out a way to make heroin in
a pill form and then it got released.
Well,
if someone ever does release,
whether it's sill assignment or whether
whatever the fuck it is,
when they start releasing it as a
medicine and they are working on that,
yeah,
they.
There was a thing a couple of weeks ago,
but yeah,
they are.
I have the perfect dosage.
They have the dosage exactly.
Not too much and that will get everyone
nice and high.
What's going to happen is that shit's
going to get out just like it gets out
in Florida and I don't know what state
it's going to be that it's going to be
one state where the pharmaceutical
companies make some fucking creepy deal
with congressmen and senators and
somehow or another they allow,
like in Florida,
doesn't have a database with the way
Florida setup is.
You can be a doctor.
You could prescribe brian's and
oxycontin's and then brian goes next
door to me.
I'm a doctor.
I prescribed him oxycontin and he goes
down the street and he just keeps going.
There's no database.
You just go to as many places you want
as long as you know,
come in,
scratching your fucking skin off with
blood coming out of your eyeballs.
They just move you onto the next.
Yeah,
but I don't think.
But even the cyber selling thing,
I think it's,
if,
if you feel like your.
I just feel like we're locked into this
thing of like possession.
Well that's what would cure that.
Big groups of mushroom uses.
Mushrooms,
users getting together and forming
communities of.
You can have a lot of people that have
had these,
like changing these transforming love
experiences where when you do mushrooms,
man,
you really do love everybody.
Man.
You really have this joy for all things
living around you in this,
this sense of this sense of a symbiosis,
a sense of uh,
uh,
connection with everything.
Whether it's the molecules of the air,
the grass,
the trees,
and this,
this,
this connection that you can't feel when
you're on it,
and it could be completely an illusion
or whatever,
but alcohol is completely illusion to.
And the culture of alcohol.
Absolutely.
Shapes in area and the culture of
it makes you hate everyone around you.
Culture of silicide been with a graph
and would be the best thing for,
for a society because that what alcohol
does to you,
it makes you angry.
No,
it actually,
again,
it just makes me sleepy.
It just may.
I need energy and like I don't have a,
uh,
an excess of energy so I can't be like,
if I were going to do drugs,
I do cocaine or speed or something.
I've never done any of them,
but not do any drugs at all.
Nothing takes all.
Often I would do shrimps.
Well you shouldn't do shrooms if you
take zoloft.
I believe that that's not good for you.
I believe that you're not supposed to
combine those two.
Uh,
I haven't in a long time.
So how long have you been on zoloft?
Twelve year.
Wow.
Yeah.
What does that do for you?
Uh,
it makes me not want to cry.
It makes me not like,
it makes me just put paper over the
mirrors.
Yeah,
that's true.
Nice one.
Oh,
what do you hate?
Have you always been a sad person
growing up or did you just get a little
off after?
No,
I was always a sad person.
Did you ever try anything?
Like a regular exercise like running?
Yeah.
Did that help?
No.
I mean it helps.
Like in,
in the cocktail,
I think I'm better off exercising than
not.
So it adds to it.
Yeah.
But it,
but I don't,
but if I took nothing and just exercise,
I just get real,
like low energy,
zoloft,
particular look,
you guys couldn't be money.
Zoloft in particular has a supposed to
have a psychotic effect when you
introduced it to cocaine,
cocaine and zoloft together as supposed
to be very bad.
People have psychotic episodes.
Got it.
Yeah.
I mean,
I.
There's no risk of me doing cocaine.
No.
Um,
but there's,
there's a real risk of me doing last.
Yeah,
you should.
You should find out about that from
someone who also has it in.
Does it
now,
have you tried to take a break from it?
Like have you ever felt like I took a
couple of years ago I took a break and I
remember I'd be out with my girlfriend
at the time and just at dinner with her
and her friends and I literally will be
falling asleep.
Not because like the regular reasons guy
one guys want to fall asleep just
because I,
I couldn't,
I was.
So we're vegan at the time?
Uh,
no,
it's back when I was eating meat guys.
Fucking interesting.
Um,
so,
uh,
but I even,
but I,
I just realized before I started taking
that five htp stuff that I started
taking reasonable and up my dosage of
zoloft,
my neck and back and shoulders were
fucking tight and knotted up all the
time for like years.
How often do you exercise?
A couple times a week now I've been
trying to extend.
It's like everyday.
But um,
because I want to,
I feel like,
you know,
like I said,
I think it helps.
Did get a punching bag.
Oh,
greatest thing you can ever have.
He blog so much stress.
Get someone to teach you how to punch
correctly,
get a punching bag and just beat the
shit out of it.
You feel so good when you're done.
It's like ugh.
Like you know,
I mean when you get angry and what do
people want to do?
They want to hit things.
You know,
there's nothing better than just beating
the fuck out of this inanimate object.
It just blows all that monkey dna out of
your system.
And then I feel like I'd break my wrist
or something,
wrapped them up.
You wrap your wrists up.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
You take your hands.
It's not that hard.
They sell these a gel wraps that are
pretty easy to,
to learn how to wrap your hands up and
then if you're smart,
you put a little athletic tape over that
so it takes five minutes.
Okay,
well I go to the gold's gym in venice
that did they have a bag?
The mecca body?
Do you do squats there?
I do the I do.
And I take an exercise class with a
bunch of 40 year old women
that would actually be funny watching a
guy just lifting very little weight,
screaming through it.
Uh,
yeah.
No,
I,
yeah,
I take it with a bunch of 40 year old
gets called body.
Yeah.
And it's actually a great class.
It's,
it's,
it's on your,
but to be more attractive.
Shut your fucking mouth.
I got it.
All right.
So you'll enjoy this joe barbell right?
AdjusTable weights.
Put as much as you want.
My little little as much as you want.
And then we do every muscle group in
unison to music.
Okay.
So the weight is varied via the from
person to person.
Uh,
but the exercise is the same.
So you and you get every single group.
Now are there women in the class at lift
more than me.
Yeah,
there are.
Joe,
is that tough for me?
Yeah.
Joe is tough.
But uh,
I liked the class and,
and those bitches better watch their
backs because I'm going up to the 40
pound level when it comes to curls.
Gateway class
says a lot for one arm.
It's doing it for two homes.
A lot of reps I would say.
Yeah.
No,
I'm doing all right.
But that's the uh,
that's no good.
Hey joe,
I want to apologize.
But it's music.
It's like a whole thing because I don't
know.
I know I basically figured out what to
do,
but I like the hour and doing it.
They make you do it,
you do it to them,
you follow up,
there's a teacher.
Whereas when you're by yourself it's
hard to motivate yourself.
Yeah.
And,
and it's also,
I would like take a break and go get
some water and like this is like go,
go,
go.
It's a good class.
Those fucking classes are hard man.
You can poopoo them all you want.
But a lot of those.
Yeah,
that's what they pulled out the steps
and you start stepping up and down and
throwing punches.
That shit's fucking difficult.
Yeah,
that's,
it's.
Well I think girls just like,
it's that group thing,
like they like going to the bathroom to
get a name,
like doing shit together.
Yes.
A worth guys.
They yell at each other though.
What do you mean?
Just in general,
mrs rogan goes to the gym,
there's a Bunch of caddy cons,
a bunch of these uh,
mostly name is the name of the chair and
the day hunt.
Yeah it is.
Look it up on yellow pages and they
fucking yell over who gets what spot and
you know,
they try to steal the right spots,
the room and they yell at each other
when they throw kicks.
I have a theory that women would be
better off if they could punch each
other in the face.
All that like snapping and cattiness.
We'd go out the window.
That's why guys aren't,
is cause we,
cause I know if I do it more than twice,
you're going to punch me and,
and there is nothing legislating women's
behavior that way.
There is with guys.
I've had guys on the set of,
of tv shows that I was in charge of.
There was a sound guy named charles who
I sort of snapped at one time and he
looked at me like,
you know,
I will fuck you up.
And I never snapped at him again.
It was one of,
I just think it's like,
it's a good thing to checked.
Yeah.
It's just as long as you know it's a
possibility.
It's true.
like it helps regulate behavior.
I'm not saying that they ever should.
I think it's always wrong to hit a
woman,
but uh,
you know,
what regulates black chicks,
black chicks regulated video that I made
a video that I made in the.
Where the fuck was in milwaukee.
There was a,
I did a show me walking afterwards.
I just went out and took pictures of
people for an hour and a half and these
black chicks guarded me.
They put their back to the crowd and
like student a semicircle and created
this system where the people had to go
through them this way.
And when you entered in,
you entered in only from here and then
you left only that way.
It was really funny.
They were hilarious.
So I made a video with them afterwards
to my youtube.
They will,
they will fight my youtube channel's joe
rogan.net.net.
There's a video,
I don't knoW.
It says something about joe rogan shows
love to the milwaukee something,
some stupid fucking some stupid title.
There's nothing you can do.
You just have to be stupid.
Did I tell you I'm going to be in
baltimore next week.
Are you going to be more comedy factory
guys?
What is the baltimore common factor?
It's a new club,
I believe.
Nice.
Because for awhile they only had the um,
they only had a in baltimore.
They had the improv in the improv went
under and I had never heard about
anything else.
I think it replaced the improv really.
Is the improv the one that you went to
like maybe nine years ago?
We went a long time ago and it was like
a whole outdoor courtyard area with a
bunch of bars and stuff.
Yeah,
that's exactly what.
that place was dope at the same place.
it's where the improv used to be.
Oh,
what a great spot.
That's that.
That's a great spot.
Apparently.
It's nice.
Okay.
So what is it called again?
The comedy factory in baltimore.
The baltimore county factor.
And what days are you there?
Eight.
Twenty five through eight slash 27,
which is next thursday,
friday,
saturday.
Folks don't miss this tremendous
opportunity to see neil brennan.
I personally talk about capitalism.
I don't talk about my dick.
You can talk about the ladies.
I will talk about politics.
Obama,
you can argue with his socialist.
Ask in person.
I'm noT sure that I spoke to him for all
his social ideals,
but it just seems like people don't like
it without thinking about it.
You know what I think,
man,
I think you need to concentrate on
yourself.
That's what I think.
I think it's a very complex system.
It's very fucked up.
There's lot of things wrong with it.
The big,
the big question.
The big key is how do you make yourself
happy?
Because nobody else has to figure it out
on their own as well.
And how you make yourself happy and
that's,
you know,
everyone has their own unique answer to
that question,
but how do you make all these other
people happy?
Man,
I'm not so sure it's socialism.
I don't think that would work at all.
I'm not so sure it's making everybody
get paid the same amount of money for
everything.
I don't think that would work either.
I think the reason why we have so much
cool shit because there's a god damn
race going on as competition going on.
Some people rise to the occasion,
absolutely,
but I feel like it's we punish those
that don't know.
We have to figure out individually how
to be happy.
That's what it is,
and we also have to figure out how to
keep corporations from being so fucking
corrupt and crooked that they are
able to get away with shit to get there.
Nothing's gonna stop because they're.
The corporations themselves are buying
messages saying,
don't touch us.
We provide jobs and that's all you care
about and jobs will give you more.
Not only that,
they're paying masses,
masses of money,
giant sums of money to help politicians
tend to office lobbyists,
lobbyists,
campaign contributions.
The all of the above,
I believe that is a massive key is
campaign finance reform.
Gary,
it's so scary that companies can just
buy presidents.
You.
They could just have us convinced that
bump we got to get into Pakistan.
There's a lot of shit going on.
Yeah.
By the way,
while we're there,
we just found trillions of dollars in
minerals.
Oh wow.
We're coming from.
This is crazy.
Oh,
we found a natural gas pIpeline.
the biggest source of natural gas in the
world in Afghanistan.
We never even knew it was there folks.
I,
we never knew it was their next stop.
The Congo.
There's a lot of shit going on the Congo
and we got to get a lot of unrest.
We got to shut it down,
shut down,
find a shitload of minds.
The condo who fucked up the Congo so
fucked up.
Even the United States government is
like,
you know what?
I know you guys are making billions over
there,
but you can have that crazy part.
Is China going to war in the Congo?
A lot of.
In fact,
at one point I looked at my financial
investments tonight.
I was invested in a company called petro
China,
and I was like,
what is that?
And I went and they,
they uh,
god I want when I was investing in
petrochina and uh,
like lockheed martin and that was a
petrochina is,
it's a chinese gas company,
but they'd get it all from africa.
They get it all from either the Congo or
uh,
or,
or Nigeria.
just one of those dislikes.
The gas,
you mean petrol?
Yeah.
Wow.
So they're,
they're,
they're pumping it out of africa.
Yeah.
And they're,
they're buying,
you know,
it's like they'll pay both sides.
They,
they,
they bought the government there.
They've,
it's,
yeah.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
And that's the thing is no one's gonna
do anything because it's way easier to
sit on your computer.
I have,
I have a theory that that crime went
down when cable cable increased.
I believe that they are directly
correlated.
I can't prove it in any way.
Giving people something to watch on tv
makes less crime.
Just people have shitty.
They go,
I want to get in and
involve.
I want to.
If you can get a laid with a lot of,
by inviting a girl over and all that
shit and having shit to do with her,
I feel like that's,
you will get a regular job just so if
you can,
if I can afford verizon,
time warner and whatever else,
I got to get them straight.
If I can get posey than I'm.
That's.
I have that budget.
That's my budget.
There's also the thing.
Did you see,
did you read,
um,
a focus on New York times book?
It was where they said the reason crime
went down is because the crime started
going down in 91 and abortion was made
legal in a 73 basically saying all the
guys that would have been 18 and
criminals were boarded up a.
Yeah.
Which is,
it's.
And it's in that book a freakonomics
that's interested in the first edition
of freakonomics.
And you just go and they did it.
Cool.
You know what's crazy?
They did it by state because certain
states legalize it sooner and those
states crime started dropping center to
the month holy.
Which is like one of those things where
you go,
wow,
that's fucking awesome.
If that's true,
right?
It's awesome.
I mean,
and people go,
that's human,
that's human engineering,
whatever,
But It's like social engineering,
social engineering,
but it's like,
I don't.
If you don't want a baby,
go ahead and I'm going to take your word
for it.
You're going to say,
I'm going to be a bad parent.
I'm going to go ahead and take your work
for real problem with abortion becomes.
WheN do you say it's not legal?
At what point?
You know when?
When it's a baby inside.
Is it still legal?
No,
no,
no.
Not when it's a baby.
When you can see it.
It's a baby and it can exist outside the
womb.
Okay.
What a month before that.
Is it a baby then?
What about a month before that?
It looks like a baby.
It looks a little immature baby.
When can you kill that?
Know that gets crazy.
Well,
yeah.
That's one of those arguments.
It's like,
well,
once you start having it,
there's no good.
You can't tell me like it's just a
protozoa.
It's like once this pharmacy a,
it's a,
it's a.
As much as I don'T connect to it.
When it's a bunch of seeds,
drop it out.
It doesn't seem to me.
There are people that do believe that
you can connect to it.
Yes.
I've heard that.
The sperm and the egg and the just the
thing splitting and splitting and
splitting it.
Like you'd go that that's a person.
Some folks believe it's like the 49.
No.
Well that's the thing is once you.
You can keep going back,
you can keep going back to it anytime
you jerk off.
It's important.
Yeah.
I think they whole abortion rate.
That's why I call my bathroom the
abortion clinic because I go in there.
I jerk of joe's typing,
but he would have given me a big laugh
on that.
I believe.
No abortion clinic.
Nothing we can say.
I don't know.
I was going to say I wish there was a
camera that you can like in like check
to see if it's like retarded.
Like,
like,
like I just have a space there.
Tests and yeah,
you can test,
so it's not 100 percent now like you'll,
you'll know it's retarded.
It's,
they put it euphemistically,
but it is basically your child's going
to be a to say brain damage,
disabled,
whatever,
and people,
people,
a lot of people get abortions because
of.
Yeah,
I'm the sole is supposed to enter the
body and 120th day of pregnancy,
that's the yogis believe that the pineal
gland comes from the hundred and 20th
day 919.
So you can get rid of the baby before
that and it's just a like how it made
answers that the soul enters what
happens to the soul.
I feel like it's got like a bus ticket
and it goes and it's on its way to the
baby's house.
One hundred 20 days there.
It's got a suitcase.
I'm,
hello?
I'm here.
Where's the fucking baby?
Yeah,
where's the soul?
Good.
Is it just go out and fart gun in the
air?
It goes away.
It goes back.
It goes back to the river souls.
Hopefully that's the,
that the uh,
yeah.
it's like either you're for or against,
but all that stuff,
like not necessarily think either you're
for it or against it.
I think there's a rational argument that
could be said that after a certain
amount of time you shouldn't be able to
do it.
You know,
these late term,
pre at any fucking.
Linda's got fingers,
man.
Did you use eyeball documentary?
The lake of fire.
That's one of the best documentaries
I've ever seen.
This guy,
tony kaye directed it who directed
american history x and it's a bit of a
lunatic,
but he made a two and a half hour
documentary about abortion over that
took place.
He shouted over like 10 years.
So uh,
any he focused on both sides.
And when you come away with is it's
fucking brutal weather whether you're
for it or against it,
you know,
when they do an abortion,
they and they,
they have to find all of the parts in a,
they have,
they put it on like a medical thing and
the nurse has defined two legs,
two arms,
like just read this go.
That is so awful.
I can't believe,
but it's such a joy to watch the
documentary.
Hopefully it's unknown.
What's it called again?
Lake of fire and why they call it lake
of fire.
Uh,
it based on the song and the biblical,
uh,
based on the bIblical thing that people
that,
that some don't.
Some,
some biblical phrase.
Yeah.
This looks funny subject because when
you bring it up,
the ultra liberal amongst us will,
will never let you say that.
It might be bad.
No.
Well that's good.
The thing is I am liberal button.
What I'm,
I'm,
it's one of those things where I just
go,
wow,
I'm,
I'm for it.
But I'm not like for it.
I believe it should be allowed,
but I'm not like,
I'm not on some like you fucking,
you know,
you had,
you stand up as the best joke about it
where the people are for it in case of
incest or rape.
And he's like,
so you're for it.
If the dad is an asshole,
that's what he's saying.
Like if the dad's an asshole then you're
for it.
But if the dads nice guy than your,
than your foot.
But because it's just as much a life,
if the guy raped or insensitive,
the baby shouldn't be responsible for
its data.
And for the dad being a dick,
that is an interesting way of looking at
it.
You allow It under some circumstances
where you shouldn't.
A man can't be forced to make a woman
carry the life.
Right?
Yeah.
That's a weird thing.
Like saying that,
that's like some tribal shit that's not
very spiritual thinking that that's okay
to kill people.
Then,
you know,
we met.
Sorry baby.
Yeah,
sorry.
I know you're just a baby.
But if you believe it's.
I'm sorry,
fetus will go fetus.
But yeah,
that's the thing is I was having watched
that documentary.
I'm still for it,
but it's a bit.
Uh,
it's my,
my point of view is way more shaded and
nuanced than,
than it would be than it was before I
saw the dog.
I don't think I have a right to tell you
what you can do with your body,
but I think it should be discussed when
it gets crazy.
You know,
I,
I have a buddy who is a,
he was dating a girl and she had a late
term abortion where she had to go to
some illegal place and do it.
I don't know why they chose to,
but she was fucking pregnant and they
killed that baby.
You know that.
That freaked me out.
Man.
Did.
What did your buddy think?
I don't remember because you know,
I haven't talked to him in forever and I
don't.
I tried not to really question it than
if it was happening now.
There's no way I would not be able to,
but you know,
back then it was 23 years old and I was
just like freaked out the front and this
lady was fucking pregnant and they're
going to suck that baby out of her and
some illegal place.
Yeah,
no,
that shit is that.
I mean,
no matter what,
that's evil.
There's,
there's an you don't want to accept
reality at that point is what's going
on.
You've decided to try to change reality.
Is there an out
that's one of those blind spots though
that we live with all the time.
Like,
but yeah,
there's tons of things we do that are
just like,
that's pretty fucked up that you just
walk past homeless people.
You walk past poor people,
you walk and you just go,
ah,
fuck.
The numbers are too great.
If there was only a few of us,
we wouldn't do that.
You know?
I've always said that people lived,
they should be in tribes have like 500
monkey people.
that's what we're supposed to be.
500 tribes have a few hundred people
where we all know each other very well.
That's normal
and I believe that women would stay in,
raise the babies.
I honestly believe that the way
guerrilla style where it's like the
women,
all the women gorillas stay.
They want the babies in the guys just do
the parameter standup perimeter and
fight and fight and protect.
That's what it's always been,
man.
Yeah.
It's always been like that.
It's just we have that same genetics,
but now we're in these giant groups of
300 million people pushed together onto
this one continent and we're confused.
We're confused as to how to behave.
We have all these weird instincts to
fuck everything and kill your enemies
and everything,
but yeah.
Yeah,
but you can't.
That's what I've been doing a joke
about.
Like they that it used to be.
now we have to be romantic to get women,
but it used to be all we had to do
before it was just chased them down and
send to them.
There's a reason why men are stronger
than.
Well,
no,
I know.
That's what the are superior.
That was it.
Like that was a date.
Yeah.
Was just a chase was just.
That's why chase scenes work in movies.
Well,
that's why dirty girls like to get
fucking choked ad where the guy I got,
I gotta be honest.
We talked.
I don't know if we don't as last time.
It's,
it's,
it's not just dirty girls anymore.
It's not.
You haven't been out in,
out,
out since that real internet.
Since you porn.
Girls want to choked.
I don't
know if all of them do,
but a lot of girls want to want to get.
I could trust me really,
like I don't know what
your experience has been,
but it's been a,
maybe it's my,
my credits or something,
but it doesn't take long for them to
bring it up.
I don't,
I've never,
I wAsn't doing it.
And then I.
And then I slowly but surely like when
you're saying choke you mean grabbed
them physically by the neck and choke
them while I'm talking about in to
linkedin,
but it's not real choke unless you're
doing real quick.
Like,
like I,
I do choke but it's more like I'm just
zach just like,
hey,
I'm choking you make a face.
You know,
girls slapped,
choke a fuck that shit.
It's all gone.
So now it's all gone.
So at the beginning,
because it might be your crowd though,
dude might be attracting a crowd is like
literate and fucking they liked hip hop.
I don't know who my credits,
but I do imagine that I'm cool with
black label.
Most of them are white now.
You know what's funny is he ever look at
your crowd and go like,
wow.
ReallY?
Like it's just,
you just,
it's people that if you
by them on the street,
you wouldn't think that I bet that
person would like me
really.
And then,
yeah,
I mean,
I don't know.
I don't assume,
I assume that no one likes me.
So when people are there and eventually
I'm going to be right.
And when people are at the show,
I just go.
If I saw them in public,
I wouldn't think,
oh,
that guy's,
that guy's coming to the new and
children.
How many tour,
how many shows have you perform now?
How many months you've been doing the
like the hour?
Uh,
I just did a,
I did it for a couple of weeks and now
I'm back.
And then I'm now I'm doing like club
dates fairly regularly.
So are you enjoying this?
I love it.
It's great.
I'm
saying it's like I just liked the idea
of,
of uh,
uh,
you know,
what's funny is,
and you'll,
you may relate to,
I would assume that I'm way behind you
in terms of development standup wise,
where your feeling about the audience
changes.
The more you do stand up.
I feel like the first thing you have to
do is just to overcome nerves,
which takes.
It took me years.
I mean,
I think it takes everyone using just
reps,
right?
yeah.
Just get onstage gonna just get you as
kevin wants to.
My brother once said,
you know,
you're doing a lot of standup when
you're comfortable onstage and
uncomfortable at the grocery store,
which is fucking true.
Where you just do.
The thing about the road is you do so
much standup that you dislike when
you're not doing it.
You're a little bit like,
oh,
what am I?
Oh yeah,
no,
it should be doing standup.
So I finally got like not nervous and
from tHat your audience,
I'm no longer defensive against the
audience.
I know no longer see the audiences is
thing I'm keeping at bay,
you know what I mean?
I no longer seat is like elian that I've
got a whip and a chair and I'm like
keeping them back.
Now I see it more like I'm immersed like
a diane fossey pit.
Like I'm,
I'm,
I'm like in the middle of the crowd and
I feel like they won't overwhelm
that feeling,
that you need to overwhelm them and
control them and whipped them as
basically the same feeling that
unattractive men have towards women when
they're unsuccessful.
Yeah.
You know,
that anger that may have towards women,
a lot of comedians have that angle
audience.
Absolutely.
Because of the constant rejection.
Yes.
Or just say almost like fuck fucking
people fucking just fucking people and
you know,
and it's.
And the audience can smell it on you.
Yeah.
Immediately,
of course.
And so can women,
you know,
a guy coming to buy a drink.
No fucking lesbian.
You know,
tony Montana,
when a guys just ready to snap over to
the other side,
it's always the same thing.
Well that's.
And that's the difference.
It's like some girl said like,
you're so smooth or something with like
just nice talking to a guy who knows how
to talk to a girl and it's like you.
because you have to stop looking at it
as a buyer,
as a seller and you have to look at it
as a buyer.
That's in some ways I've stopped being
like that.
Ah,
right.
Am I.
What do you think,
babe?
Huh?
I used to do,
yeah,
a lot of dance and those guys
dot that they eat and eat and now it's
more like,
what do you.
I,
it's the chris rock thing of 90 percent
of girls want to fuck 10 percent of the
guys.
Once you get into that 10 percent,
you are officially a buyer.
Like your 10 percent.
You're in the top 10.
What leaped you into that top 10
chappelle show?
Next question.
Show.
And also just the fact that you have a
credit credit and an age soon.
Unexperienced meaning a hot girl.
How soon do you pull out the.
He was the cocreative chappelle show.
First hour.
You have a couple of january between 10
seconds and 40 seconds.
So really if you're,
if you're at a bar with someone.
So neil,
what do you do?
Well,
what I do when I was directing the,
the pivot movie,
I would,
I would go,
uh,
you're,
you're going to think I'm a douche bag,
but I,
I,
uh,
I'm a movie director and they've got
like what,
what do you.
And then you just get like it is one of
those weird ass jobs where it's like,
so,
so use by saying it,
it just sounds so cliche.
Yeah.
It in la,
especially if you're like,
what do I do?
I'm a director,
but when you're actually working,
when you actually have a job.
So I don't,
but so right now,
so right now I say I'm a comedian,
I'm in comedy.
And then just leave it like that.
Yeah.
But you
got this ace in your sleeve that you
want to pull out and want to pull out
that chappelle show.
How it,
how long do you wait?
It really all depends.
Like if it's going well,
you don't even pull it out for a while.
It's going well.
Yeah.
No,
I sit on it.
Yeah,
I get it.
The old fashion way back again with the,
with my own hands.
I don't get enough credits,
you get it just by being a community,
but if she gets a little slippery was on
a buddy of mine.
Oh,
don't do it that way.
Dia
a tropic casually at the olive garden or
so.
No,
you can't say I created the bullshit.
You just lose.
You mentioned garden every episode,
right?
Because it's the most generic restaurant
I can think of that.
But you always mentioned.
I'll start saying chili's.
You can't just say,
you have to say a buddy of mine.
You can't say like,
you know,
when I was directing,
you can't,
you can't name it,
you have to go up.
but buddy mine,
I was,
I worked on the show and did a chappelle
show.
My favorite is when I go to open mics
that people don't know me and they go,
what do you want me to say?
And I go,
uh,
particularly,
it used to happen a lot.
I go and cook inch belsher and they go,
what?
That would be good to go.
Okay.
And then they would go because they,
it's like a,
I used to call it the atomic credit
because it is one of the things like,
whoa,
take put that thing away.
Like,
how about a fucking.
You were on fallon or something new.
Did you feel like that that was a lot of
responsibility to live up to when you
first started doing stem?
Well,
yeah,
that's what [inaudible] my brother was.
My brother kevin was slamming me that
saying that like,
you know,
you're getting opportunities you don't
deserve and all that stuff.
And he said,
oh yeah,
I'm not a real comedian.
And sloW your own brother said that to
you.
What the fuck is that about?
It's about a growing up one of 10 and
elbowing each other and wow.
Petition of 10.
Why do you think I'm focused on
compensation?
I got brothers that don't talk to me,
you know,
it's like wow.
And if I blamed capitalist,
uh,
kind,
yeah,
it's amazing that you have all these
hippie ideals,
dad on smoking with us.
Uh,
yeah.
So.
And then we all competed with six guys.
There were five brothers,
so,
uh,
but yeah,
it wasn't bombing as the creator
chappelle show was worse than bombing as
an anonymous guy.
I've got to think a pressure on you.
That's what I'm asking.
No.
Yeah,
there was absolutely pressure.
I mean,
I wasn't like conscious of it,
but looking back it was,
it was definitely pressure,
but that's.
So that's what's nice to be in a place
where it's just more like,
I just,
the is like,
they just have,
it's like the robin landing on your
shoulder and fucking I'm now I'm a
chimney sweep from mary poppins.
That's who you are.
That's who I am to the audience.
So,
um,
you've done,
you've started doing your own podcast.
Have you noticed immediately and impact
and like they podcast fans are coming to
you?
Not Immediately because we've only done
two.
Our third one will go up this up now I
think called the champs.
Uh,
and they,
the,
yeah,
it hasn't happened yet,
but,
but I believe it will like it because I
see just look if if 10,000
people listen to it then that's 10,000
people that I either sort of knew me or
didn't know me or,
or,
or knew me and will now feel more
connected because I think that's the new
paradigm is the just feeding people,
just constant feeding.
Like here you go baby,
are you still hungry baby babies,
the audience in this metaphor,
like you're just.
And particularly you give them free
stuff and that eventually go,
hey,
just so you know,
I got to charge every once in a while.
So you know,
listen to this ad or it's like the
little wayne paradigm.
Little wayne put out four records that
he just mixed tapes and the and they're
good and they're really good songs.
And he just released him on the.
And then when he came up with his
record,
the carter it people bought it.
He was,
he's the last guy to sell a million
records in a week because I think people
were like,
I don't think if people implicitly knew
that that's what they're explicitly
knew,
that that's what they were doing,
but I believe that people were like,
you know what,
I've gotten so many of these guys songs
for free.
LeT me pay for a couple of them.
I mean,
I don't know.
I mean I definitely felt like that was
my point of view on it and I think that
that's the new with this democratization
is like,
yeah,
it's free like it is.
The startup cost for thIs aren't
massive,
but there there's something and then you
give it to people and you're,
you're exchanging ideas and,
and,
and human energy for their time and then
hopefully they develop a connection with
you.
You know what I noticed?
It's very sterile way of looking at it,
but it's not,
but it's a human.
Here's what I've noticed.
I've noticed when I was on your podcast,
a lot of people came and were like,
hey man,
I heard you and I didn't know who you
were.
I didn't know what you were about and
then because of this,
so I,
I,
so yes,
to answer your question,
people have come up,
but not because of my podcast,
because of your podcast.
I think what you're saying makes a lot
of sense,
but it makes it seem like you're
analyzing it like the stock market,
that connection.
I'm only analyzing it in retrospect
cause I didn't because I was,
I,
I do twitter because I've always liked
talking and little aphorisms like that
and then I was like,
oh.
Then I realized like,
oh,
I get what this is.
I get this model and I've only gotten
him really since.
DoIng your podcast is like where you
said you've never had a connection like
this with the audience.
It's a connection and to get rid of a
gatekeeper to get rid of a studio,
to get rid of a television network.
Yeah.
Is excellent.
It's amazing to be able to do something
like this.
Look,
this podcast has changed everything as
far as me doing comedy clubs.
Now I do very little publicity outside
of just talking about it on the comedy
club or just talking about it rather on
the podcast and you know,
everything has changed.
The numbers of people that come out to
see me has changed.
The ease of doing it.
I no longer have to fly in a day early
and do running radio things.
It's way easier now.
Yeah,
and that's.
And that's just from basically giving
something for free,
but you,
you're,
you're friends with these people,
you don't even know them and you're
friends with them and they start
thinking like you guys think and going
over the thing,
the ideas that get discussed on the
podcast and talk about amongst their
friends and all these good ideas.
Blossom and grow.
Yeah,
that's the,
that's the thing of it.
You do give it for free and it's.
But it's not.
It is.
It's about the connection.
It's just like I,
like I said,
I like talking.
I like,
I like people.
I think I've got interesting,
well thought out ideas that I can in a
relatively
funny way.
So it's like,
yeah,
I think people could benefit from
hearing me speak.
People will enjoy it for sure.
Yeah.
No,
they've been,
like I said,
people really enjoyed the last one.
I was here last time.
You need some marijuana in your life,
kid brand,
definitely.
Abby did the thing about you being
really tired and stuff?
I,
I really,
uh,
I,
I have that too where I'm just a zero
energy.
I'm super tired most of the time I'm
either depressed or sad or like,
you know,
and uh,
but,
but lately I've been like,
you know,
having a good time in my personal life
that,
that all magically just disappeared.
Like went away.
I've never done any kind of zoned off.
I've never done kind of any prescription
management.
I've always been the type of person that
needs it.
But if there's anything that I would say
would help me get through everything,
marijuana definitely has just helped me
tremendously.
It has a built in self promotion
mechanism.
There is not a drug in the world that
when you do it,
people that you talk about more drug in
the world is more beneficial in the
daily business.
Exactly what people have tylenol and
they talk about topics like a mild
psychedelic.
It's like a psychedelic digging use all
the time.
You can't do mushrooms every day.
I mean you can,
but you're going to fucking lose your
connection to humanity.
You could smoke pot everyday and it just
makes you more empathetic.
It makes you more,
more real,
makes you connect,
connect to your real emotions better.
The way you interact wIth people
takes away headaches.
If I'd like to be as sharp as possible,
I like my brain to function well.
It doesn't fuck with your function.
The brain it has in the past and getting
the wrong leads on.
There's two different rap weed.
I know you had chocolate fever.
So you smoke weed,
you're smoking the.
I go into a coma.
[inaudible] just gonna sit here and
chill.
I would,
uh,
you got scared.
We try to offer it to you before the
show.
I thought about a scam.
You got nervous?
I ruined my pants.
I could see it,
man.
Uh,
no.
I just don't.
You mock it.
It's like when a fighter gets hit and
they shake their head like that was
nothing.
Usually it was usually it will show he
got rocked.
How about when someone gets to the point
they didn't do guilty or not guilty?
Don't be plead.
Not guilty.
Don't be doing.
Not around here.
I'm not saying marijuana is for
everybody,
but it is for you and help you
tremendously.
You can,
if you can get me some,
a vaporizer or something.
Yeah.
That could be.
Can be smokIng because then it'll start
smoking cigarettes and really thinks no.
How long has it been?
Ten years.
IT's been like 13 years ago.
Already.
Dirty,
stinky fucking disease.
Isn't it weird?
He still went.
Oh yeah.
I had dreams where I smoke and I wake up
like at lIke in my dream I'm like,
the fuck are you doing smoking meth?
And then I wake up and I'm like,
thank god I had a friend,
the friend the other day at work,
some bad news happen,
and all sudden he goes,
I haven't smoked a cigarette and six
years and he lights up a cigarette.
I go put that fucking thing down.
I go throw that thing on the ground,
step on him.
And he goes,
yeah,
I go,
fuck that.
You're not going to do.
you're going to give in now for this.
Don't
do it.
Don't do it.
So he stomped on it and he was already
like,
thank you very much.
I to a fucking started smoking again.
Three hours later he did.
Yeah.
If I smelled smoke $10,000,
what is that?
It's the most addictive product on the
market.
Apparently though I know a dude who did
heroin who says that you can go fuck
yourself.
And everybody that says that it's tough
to quit cigarettes.
He goes,
heroin is way harder to quit than
cigarettes.
And people always say quitting
cigarettes is,
were harder than quitting heroin.
Absolutely untrue.
He said,
heroin is way harder.
It is harder.
But.
But I,
but I believe from person person.
I'm sure it's.
Well,
I didn't,
I didn't find quitting that hard.
I just decided.
But you still it still scratching?
Yeah,
but I still worry about,
about just getting into doing it again.
Is there any greater evidence that this,
the,
the politicians are bought and paid for
then tobacco?
Oh no.
Well that's what I mean.
It's like with the fact that they knew
it was unhealthy and fifties and sixties
and it took 40 more years.
My doctor recommends chesterfield.
absolutely took them 40 years to get it.
Only to the point where it's like,
alright,
you can sell them,
but we're going to tack them at such a
high rate.
It's going to.
We're gonna tax them at a cartoonishly
irate.
It's amazing too that some people have
actually sued for damage.
You know,
they've sued the tobacco companies in
one.
You know,
there's been some big handouts,
man,
so people have to figure out who gets
paid,
who doesn't,
how can they,
how many suits can they allow?
How many lawsuits really can be
processed against tobacco companies.
There's a fucking half a million people
every year dying.
5 million worldwide,
died prematurely directly as it was,
you know,
well,
I'm less interested in that and more
interested in obesity in terms of in
terms of the next terms of draining
society,
because that's where you go,
hey,
you can't legislate people's diets.
It's like,
okay,
but it's a.
It's basically a seatbelt laws iF,
if,
if you're going to eat yourself into
obesity and then you're going to drain
the healthcare system,
you're gonna drive up.
MY,
my,
the cost of my healthcare,
the cost of the government.
I mean that was a lot of the stuff with
the tobacco industry.
They had to pay states because states
were fucking paying so much money to
treat people with lung cancer that you
kind of go,
okay,
well then what?
That's got to be next.
That's got to be.
You've got an outlaw or tax cocacola or
tax frito lay in it.
Why is that?
Because it's the only people that abuse
it.
I would say that's way more ridiculous
than taxing tobacco because look,
the other day I was in a supermarket and
for a goof I picked up a box of lucky
charms and I took them home and I had a
bowl of lucky charms.
Yeah,
it was yummy,
but you know what?
I eat healthy.
I eat healthy,
but I.
I reserve my own personal right to eat
something shitty every now and then.
It doesn't mean that shitty food should
be illegal because you're too stupid.
Incorrect because physical,
the physical addiction of cigarettes is
far more pulling.
Then the addiction to sugar.
Sugar is like,
that's a psychological addiction more
than anything.
Right,
but you do admit that conviction.
Do you notice in your personal alignment
when she'll turn your email?
It can be an addiction.
You know,
I believe that's an addiction.
I believe I am an addict.
I believe on the computer addict.
Yeah,
and I want someone to tax seen people
that cAn't stop texting.
The kids stop texting him out of where
they are.
There.
There was,
I heard a story the other day that a
couple in Korea they met online in some,
you know,
world war craft kind of thing.
They met in person,
had a baby and then just kept going to
these,
these cafes and uh,
they had,
uh,
in their online world,
they had a child together and they came
home one night and the baby had died
from their real baby had died from
starvation because they were so hooked
on the internet that they're idiots.
That doesn't mean the internet,
you know,
I don't think it should be illegal,
but I'm saying there's no,
you're not saying the difference between
shoe.
You can just go,
well,
sugar is a way more.
People are obese that are,
that are nice,
but I like snickers bars.
I liked sneakers.
So you're bright,
you're just going to get taxed for it.
I'm willing to pay the tax,
then you're going to pay a much larger
tax.
But that doesn't cure anybody.
Let's resolve any of the problems.
People have quit smoking by 40 percent.
Smoking.
Smoking is fucking way down from when,
from 20 years ago.
really 40 percent.
That's pretty high.
Yeah,
and particularly among teenagers.
Really.
Yeah,
as well.
That's a good start.
Yeah,
that's what I mean like it is when they
go.
You can't legislate.
Yeah,
you can.
IF you're smart about it.
And,
and it is,
you know,
it.
This shit is a drain on society.
What they should also do the opposite
too,
which is a making vegetables and
healthy.
TheY would subsidize vegetables with,
uh,
with,
by taxing snickers.
You.
So you're in favor of the government
getting all lee Willie and people's
business and taxing things.
But again,
it's people's business.
But where's that money go,
man.
That's when the real problem was
everybody thinks that taxing things is a
solution,
but you're going to give that money to
an inept government.
This is going to create more fucking
jobs and it's not going to go towards
what you want it to go tour.
It's going to go towards many,
many jobs being set up for the
decimation of the,
the spreading of this money that you've,
you know,
you brought in taxes.
Most of the time you raise taxes,
you're gonna raise government.
The government gets bigger.
There's more jobs,
more people working in the government,
very few things actually get fixed,
but there'll be more people.
Okay,
well,
or you can everyone can,
uh,
the,
the alternative in these indicates of
cigarettes and it should be illegal to
kill people.
Illegal.
I agree with you.
I mean if you're going to keep anything
illegal,
number one should be cigarettes and I
don't think they should be illegal.
I think you should be able to smoke
cigarettes every fucking day.
Don't get me wrong,
but if you're going to go by the law
that the government has the pattern of
behavior that the government has been
pushing since forever,
that they're looking out for the best
interests of their citizens.
But tobacco stats are pretty
encouraging.
I mean,
if you say that's a good start,
450 million people or 450,000
people rather in this country alone,
450,000
just in this country,
but in 5 million worldwide,
hundred thousand,
but still an insane number of people.
That pile of bodies is fucking
alcoholic.
Way more than that.
No,
no,
no.
Alcoholism related deaths.
No,
no,
it's not as many as cigarettes,
so it's like 150,000,
but I'm saying you could drink yourself
to death slow.
I'm talking about the amount of people
that stopped as a partially as a result
of the higher taxation and just making
them prohibitively expensive.
Well,
that's saying about maxine snickeRs.
even if you.
It may not be addictive to you,
but clearly it's addictive to a lot of
people.
I would say if you want to tax the
fucking holy shit out of cigarettes and
keep selling them,
I would say good.
That sounds like a good idea,
but is it possible that the money that
you take from the taxes would directly
go towards something that seems
worthwhile?
Will some.
How about the lotterY?
A lottery goes fucking builds roads.
I mean there's the lottery build roads.
Yes,
that's what It is.
I mean there are tons of things.
The lottery in england pays for fucking
the bbc.
He's amazing.
Yeah,
I mean it's such a.
It's and you want to talk about that
shit.
The lottery should be illegal.
Well,
and sorta.
Yeah,
but not really.
You can do it.
We're stupid people.
It should be illegal is shorting things.
How has that nuttiness of gambling
illegal in,
in the stock market,
the nuttiness of gambling,
like the guy who shorted america's
credit rating,
that somehow or another I actually have
no beef with that guy because if you bet
on contraction,
yeah,
but you're betting that's.
Then yoU're betting you're not investing
in the snob,
but in an investment is gambling.
You're gambling that this company is
going to become more sort of,
but you're supposed to be educated as to
the benefits of this company.
I mean,
when you write in fucking lockheed
martin.
I didn't even know her,
but I'm saying you,
you,
you don't thInk of it as gambling.
You think of it as investing.
I am I absolutely family.
I think the stock people don't have any
sense of the term is not that people no
longer buy things because they believe
in the company.
They just look at the metrics and go,
no,
that's true.
That's not true.
I know a gUy who,
uh,
has apple stocK,
he's a huge apple fan and one of the
reasons why he's all excited about the
apple stock doing so good and she's a
fucking apple fan.
He loves It.
I think there's a company mall,
small percentage.
I don't know,
I think it might be a small percentage,
but I think some people that invest,
they do invest with their people that
invested in,
for that are all excited at ford's doing
well because it's an american company,
you know,
they invest with their head and their
heart,
but think that that's not
the average person.
Yeah,
I think the average per.
I don't.
I'm a relatively smart guy.
Like I keep saying,
uh,
and,
and I,
uh,
I invested,
I don't know what I got into like a
green investment thing because I'd like
them to do well,
but I'm probably losing money.
RiGht.
You know what I mean?
Like,
I,
I like it.
It's a stupid way to my,
my financial guy was like,
this is stupid.
Just let me put it in petrochina,
lockheed martin,
koch g,
you know,
all that,
all these monoliths.
And so you manaGed it,
you it,
then you did.
But I was discouraged by a,
by a relatively.
You know,
I see what I just.
It seems to me that the idea of shorting
seems crazy.
The idea that you can gamble,
that's when it's really gambling.
Anything else to me seems that it's
investing.
You invest your money,
you buy shares of a stock that you
believe in,
whether you believe in them because you
like them or whether you believe in them
because you think it's a good.
It's a good investment that they're
growing and they're going to continue to
grow.
You like the way they're set up.
I think that's one of the few naive
point of view.
You hold your singing that like a singer
or holding their thing.
Why is that name?
Because people just are in the stock
market to get to make a profit.
They're in it to make a profit,
but they look at this as this is gonna
make a profit.
This is a good sound investment.
If I've done my bit,
I do with.
I liked the company.
I like.
It's just they haven't.
It doesn't have to do with that.
I can see that.
That doesn't have to have anything to do
with.
It could be that you just look at the,
they appear to be continuing to be
profitable.
That makes sense to me though,
that you can invest in something that it
could be profitable.
I'm going to invest in.
It doesn't make the opposite where you
go.
It's like because you're gambling,
that's what I don't understand you are.
You are literally saying I'm willing to
bet a billion dollars that this fucking
country,
if it goes up,
that's the thing.
It's not like it's the same
inverse of benny of investinG.
You're going,
you just basically you borrow money,
you borrow a million dollars.
Uh,
and,
and with that you have to start paying
back.
You have to.
I understand that.
I understand the concept.
I just,
I see it as just the inverse.
It seems fucking crazy.
Luckily I'm not in finance,
nor you.
Brian,
what are you doing with your sleeves,
todd?
Doing it is how you are trying to play
this.
Neil's rolling up and for a long time I
think.
I think this is it.
Let's bring this back to the barn to
bring it home.
Bring it to the bar.
Thank you everybody for tuning in.
Thank you neal brennan.
And you guys can see neal brennan and
one of the dates again.
Twenty five,
26,
27 in baltimore at the competent.
The baltimore comedy factory.
And listen to the podcast called
champs.
Yeah,
that's a dope comedy club.
If it's the same place with the improv.
That place was great.
And the champs is on itunes,
correct?
yep.
And stitcher and,
and yeah.
And you can find it just online.
Go search it,
search there,
brennan and follow him on twitter.
Um,
and um,
that's it.
So many ways.
We will feed you baby.
Be back.
Uh,
September 23rd.
I'm at the paramount theater in denver,
Colorado.
And what is it?
September 16th,
16th,
16th at the house of blues and new
orleans.
I'm very excited about that.
That should be a lot of fun.
Yeah.
And um,
that's it.
Thank you everybody for tuning in and
we'll see you next week.
Kevin smith is August 30th.
He's going to be doing it.
And anthony bordain,
september 11.
Holla at your boy.
Talk to you guys soon.
love you bitch.
Oh,
in the flashlight.
Yeah.
Go to joe rogan.net.
Thank You for sponsoring us and keeping
the lights on and thank you for prior
providing a good place to shoot loads.
If you go to joe rogan.net
and click on the link for the flashlight
and enter in the code name rogan,
you will get 15 percent off the number
one sex toy for men.
All right,
that's it.
We'll see you guys soon.
Thank you very much.
Bye bye.