The Joe Rogan experience lie.
Apparently you don't need an ID to fly.
You just need to go.
They were like,
we need to put you through like 20
security tests,
so come to the airport two hours early.
I was like,
God dammit.
They're going to molest year.
Yeah.
Have you ever had that happen before
where you get like roughly frisked?
No,
but I have gotten yelled at by a TSA
agent because I didn't want to go
through the body scanner and he was
like,
what are you a celebrity?
He's like,
only celebrities don't want to go
through the body scanner.
And I was like,
why?
I was like,
this is crazy that you're talking to me
like this.
Like what the fuck?
This is nuts.
It's an option,
isn't it?
Yeah.
He was just like totally demeaning me.
Like in front of everyone was nuts.
Why would celebrities not want to go
through it?
But it's like,
yeah,
why would you want to get molested?
I mean,
well it's.
I've never had it happen to me.
Everyone has been pleasant with me,
but Graham Hancock,
who's been on the podcast several times,
she's a good friend.
He went through one and he said this
dude like just was aggressively sexual
with him,
like grabbing his,
his body,
like it felt like he was being molested,
like I shouldn't say aggressively
sexual,
but he grabbed his cock and the whole
thing mean like he said,
it felt like he was getting raped,
like obviously not as extreme,
but you know,
it's like a form of a violation and he
was really shocked by it and he wrote
about it.
He was shocked enough that he didn't
just let it go.
We sat down and wrote some stuff.
Well,
there was this report that came out that
said that there's so many more cases of
malfeasance and misconduct and the Tsa
than any other government.
I mean this is like 20 times more.
And so there was this investigation done
to find out,
well why is there so much fucking crimes
happening?
Like robbery,
sexual abuse and stuff.
And it was.
And basically this representative
figured out that they don't really do
background checks.
Oh my God.
And they're just kind of skipping
through this huge,
uh,
you know,
you think that you would.
So basically they're hiring a pedophiles
and child and lessors what they found
out.
Yeah.
No,
wait.
Yes.
Well not nice people too.
We should,
we should say that I've,
I've met a lot of really nice people to
Tsa.
You fucking government chill.
Relax.
Well,
how do you think that you should do
security?
We did before nine slash 11 was totally
created in the wake of nine slash 11 is
a total thing.
New Government Agency.
Just like the department,
Homeland Security and just,
I mean think about it,
the hijackers brought on what knives,
like you can still bring those in.
This Guy Jonathan corbet basically
expose the fact that you can just create
an insole in pocket and bring in
whatever the fuck you want through these
body scanners.
So they really have like a huge security
breach.
So.
But when you go back to why the body
scanners were implemented,
like an inside pocket that's like silver
or something.
Oh.
So it has to be like,
yeah,
you can carry anything through.
Oh Wow.
Yeah.
But I mean,
the reason that the body scanners were
implemented in the first place,
this is Michael.
Michael Chertoff was tied up with rape,
rape,
a scan,
which is also the name of the body
scanner,
right?
Rapiscan,
rapid,
rapid scan.
But I call
the government was really
like,
Yep,
losing.
I've got a patent rapiscan.
I got a patent,
I'm not changing the fucking name.
And then you understand it 100 percent.
Like you ever the worst feeling in the
world.
Strong words you ever go to a concert
like pipe.
My wife me go to fucking.
Oh God son.
That's the ugly one.
And my wife made me go to.
Is always bad.
But then when you say,
I shouldn't say the only thing worse
than Dave Matthews is John Meyer,
your wife made you go to a John Mayer,
John Mayer Meyer.
And she was just like,
just enthralled by him.
I could do.
John Mayer will know I can do to.
No,
I think he's great.
I think he's very talented.
But if your wife is really into going
know what I'm saying,
like she dragged you there and just
stares at him.
And you're like,
I paid for this.
Paid to have your wife close her eyes
later and think about him.
You notice she's not clapping because
when her hand slipped down.
Okay James,
she's deep.
She's clapping with one hand.
It sounds like something stabbing of
seal.
It sounds like one of those martial arts
movies where they ripped a guy's heart
out after.
She's just fiserv herself.
She's all the way to her elbow.
Just gritting their teeth and pounded it
in there.
Get the wedding ring off.
She's just fucking strafing the.
You can see her rib cage expand.
That's a fist.
Goes up there.
Okay,
let's go.
Then you realize it's in her asshole.
You thought it was bad?
Fucking shit.
Up to.
What?
Is this the fuck are you doing?
I thought we were going to see a
concert.
Just says licking her arm.
Oh John.
Oh John,
make me eat my shit.
Meanwhile,
that's not the craziest person that ever
lived.
Nope.
That's not even close.
Oh Shit.
Itunes or recording to server to get the
fuck outta here.
Server.