The joe rogan experience.
Now this shit ain't working.
I don't have my headphones on
blasted. You ever look for your head,
your sunglasses, and you realize
they're on your fucking face? Yeah. Yes.
My sunglasses. And they're right there
in your fucking head. Yeah, that's,
that's when you know you should quit
weed, right? Is that the moment?
And he didn't take it.
Take some time off.
Shit. I've been doing that
since I was a kid, man.
The Joe Rogan experience podcast is
brought to you by several things,
several things. And we believe
in number one is the fleshlight.
I believe it. You know
why? Because I've used it.
I believe in it because you're Gunna
masturbates stop fucking playing games.
Listen,
you know you're going to masturbate.
You'll know you're going to masturbate.
Just get that over with.
You don't want to be counting on one
person to take care of your biological
needs. Okay? Because then you
become a slave to that one person.
That's very dangerous.
You have to be able to take care of it
yourself because life would be chaos if
we couldn't reach our decks.
If our Dick Scher and some weird spot
in our back and we had to get a chick to
touch it. There was no way he could
do it yourself. You'd be doomed, man.
Just so you,
you would have the balance of power
would shift terribly against you.
It's the perfect cotton.
That sense in that sense,
the fleshlight is an empowerment tool.
It allows you to extract biological
matter and remove some confusion in your
consciousness and some distractions in
your everyday life because all you're
thinking about is I got a park,
some of this fucking sperm somewhere.
You know it's building up inside your
balls like a bunch of wild steroid eat and
troops ready to fucking fly out and go
to war. That's what they're like, man,
that's what your loads are like. They're
like a little savages amped up refugees.
It's committing suicide,
jumping off trees face first to the rocks
and a thick load today, like really thick,
like uncomfortable. That's not good.
Yeah. What's that mean is that
you've got a clock, you got a clog,
a little thing down there. You got to
stick with Qtip in there and clean it out.
It was like a goober. Goober. Anyway,
click on the link it Joe rogan.net and
enter in the code name Rogan and you will
get 15% often number one sex toy for men
and then you could shoot your loads in
it.
That's right at a discount.
I've said this before and they
need to Mrs. Clause one bad. Yeah.
They should have totally come up with
a woman like snow on it and shit. Yeah,
little little white white hair.
Oh,
why not?
I think she was a virgin and
that's my mom's name. Right?
You shouldn't be the one person
to fuck marry, kill badge.
If they could go back in time and
eventually they'll get to that point.
If you find like someone's like,
you know right now found like two ton
Commons body and then they put like,
we should talk about this
one not doing a commercial.
That's why the commercials are so
good. Dude. They're totally organic.
Let's just get him out of the way.
We are also brought to you by on it.com
makers of Alpha Breen and new mood,
which I'd take both of them on a
regular basis and the fucking awesome.
I support this not just because I'm
making money from it and because I,
if I wasn't making money from it, I would
still tell you to look into nootropics.
It's there. It's a fascinating
field of science really.
And it's all about
chemicals and, and, and um,
vitamins that enhance cognitive function.
And I think they work
differently on different people.
But for me, I get a nice,
like good,
clear feeling out of taking these things
and I don't believe it's a placebo. Um,
you know, there's, there's,
there's evidence that it helps Alzheimer's
patients when you give them like
certain nootropics that I can actually
can slow the onset of Alzheimer's.
Most importantly though,
if you don't like this stuff,
you get a hundred percent money
back guarantee. Just say it sucked.
If you don't have to return it, she'd say
it sucked and you get your money back.
It's really that simple. And if you like
it but you think it's too expensive. My,
what I say to you is please
go buy the shit in bulk.
Go and save yourself some money,
steal the ingredient list off the website
and just duplicate it. I really do.
I hope you do that and I hope you enjoy
it and I hope you look into the just the
subject of nootropics.
I'm neither educated enough nor do I
have enough time to go into depth enough
and have it actually be
interesting in a podcast. You know,
I would maybe like to have some like
scientist on explain brain chemistry to,
you know I,
but I couldn't do it obviously.
So the best I can say is go Google it and
look up nootropics and there's a bunch
of different kinds and there's a bunch
of different formulations that other
people offer as well. And a lot of them
are really good. I've tried power drive,
I think that stuff's really good.
There's a bunch of different companies
out there that sell similar stuff and not
saying buy my stuff, but if you
want to buy my stuff you can buy it.
And go to [inaudible] dot com
if you've got to Joe rogan.net,
click on the link for Alpha brain and
during the code name rogue and you get 10%
off that. Okay. Or not
whatever, Bro. Okay, Jesus.
Merry Christmas. Take me hit that shit.
Bitch. Duncan trussell's in the house.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Joe Rogan podcast all day.
I think
that was one of the best
commercials. Whoever did. Duncan
flowed seamlessly how it has to be,
man.
I can't just always say the
exact same thing. Fucks.
It's too uncomfortable.
I feel like a big phony.
I was talking to Stan
hope about that once, man.
He said the worst thing is when like he
like he goes to the UK and went to the
UK and he saw the same people were in
the same seat both nights that are like
really loud and they sat in the same seat
and then the second night they sat in
the same seat, but he's going to do like
most of the same material, you know?
I mean you only have so
much fucking material. And
the art of stand up comedy is to relay
each piece of material as if it's really
happening in your head right now.
But when someone just saw you the night
before say the exact same shit, you know,
and he's like, oh, it makes you feel
like such a fucking phony. Hate it.
When someone knows your shit.
It's flattering. It's flattering.
They're just trying to flatter you.
They're trying to make you feel like
we're super fans are coming to see you two
nights in a row. I do like, I mean, if
they are super fans though, I would like,
you know, if Bill Hicks was in town in
Boston, I saw him two nights in a row,
I saw the same set twice in a row.
I wanted to,
I like watching that because you get to
see the nuances and the way they do it
differently. It's cool. But for a lot
of people they don't want to see that,
you know? But I was, uh, you know,
you're an open like comic, you know,
an amateur and you know,
a total comedy nerd.
And know the opportunity
to see like a craftsman.
I saw Richard Jenny a couple
of nights in a row too.
I saw a couple of different guys a few
nights in a row. Like I went to see them.
I saw don my rare a couple of nights
in a row. You I wanted to see their,
their act over and over again.
I wanted to see how they did
it and it's interesting man,
when you see people's different reactions
in different crowds are like, wow,
why didn't that one work? Man,
this is crazy. Like this is weird.
Told you one of my favorite moments
in comedy is watching Bill Hicks bomb.
He bombed with the confidence and
flare of a man who was crushing.
Like it never bothered him.
Like there's a lot of people
who say it never bothered them,
but you can see this like fear or
detachment in their eyes is panic.
Look, he never got it. He
never got to the panic look.
He would bomb and as he was bombing he
would talk through the bombing and he was
doing this bit where he went on
after this other guy. And this,
the other guy that went
up is a very nice guy,
but he's really hacky and he had like
a bunch of like, you know, cartoons,
smoking pot jokes, where do
I get daffy duck smoking. Oh,
you know, another guy who was one of those
guys, but he was a nice guy. You know.
My point is he was killing
this audience was monkeys,
they were apes.
It was one of those dumb audiences and
every now and then to get them, you know,
in Boston you have some really educated
people and then you have a lot of troll
people to fucking cool. Yeah,
yeah. You've got a lot of those.
Well they did not like Hicks.
It all,
he came on like super
confident and like real,
like slow and deliberate with his,
uh,
the way he was putting his set out there,
you know, and like real, like you just,
you know, like you own the room, you know,
and just would start doing as
material and they didn't like it, man.
And they were leaving in droves and
he had this bit where Satan fucks John
Davidson in the ass and he would like
rotate people. It'd be John Davidson,
it would be Oprah.
And then he shits out Geraldo Rivera,
he's on the, on the toilet shitting, and
he's making this shit noise for like,
man, like two minutes, which is
a long time to just sit there
and he's making this and he looks up and
people are just leaving in giant groups.
It's fucking great. It's fucking terrible.
Fucking terrible. Not Funny at all.
After that last guy,
and then they're leaving and Hicks looks
up and I swear to God he wasn't even
phase. He goes, yeah,
it's generally clears the room
and just to me and my friends,
I think Fitzsimmons might've
been there for that one, um,
to being my friends and 50 people.
It was fucking hilarious.
The bits were hilarious. It was a, it was
like so interesting. It was, it wasn't,
I'll be honest, it was not the funniest
material than I'd ever seen in my life.
It wasn't the funniest delivery,
but it was certainly the most thoughtful,
without a doubt. It was a
totally different kind of
laughter I was experiencing.
I was experiencing experiencing
a laughter and the Lego fuck,
he just nailed it too. It wasn't
just the laughter, it was like, wow,
that's an awesome point to just shove into
a joke, you know? You know what I mean?
So it wasn't like he was the
funniest guy. Like he, you know,
if you compare it to him to like
the guys that I knew growing up,
like Steve Sweeney,
Steve Sweeney used to fucking Corolla.
I mean crushed the point where you
would be terrified to go on after him to
follow a guy like Steve Sweeney
in Boston when he's on full tilt,
when he goes up there just rabid and full
of energy, you're fucking doomed, man.
He's just too good.
And it was a hex wasn't like that.
It was a totally different kind
of funny, you know, it was,
it was it's own little thing,
man.
And it influenced a lot of people
to sort of branch often in,
into a more thoughtful
direction, you know? Yeah,
it's really cool when you see somebody
who's got the balls to just say exactly
what they're thinking on stage with
zero pandering. Yeah, that's not,
that's not going to be that. That
can't be that kind of crushing comedy.
It's a different thing all together.
It's still super funny. But you know,
my thing is, dude, I
like the sandwich at it.
I like to shove it in between shit
that just has no points at all.
Just ridiculous. And just the stuff
that I think is funny and it's usually,
she's like gay jokes.
It's usually for whatever reason,
it's usually someone inadvertently sucking
your dick or be someone is sucking a
dick for a reward.
My sense of humor is so fucking juvenile,
man. I'm so childish. And I actually
thought like, man, maybe I got a problem.
Like why am I such a child with like
stuff that I think is silly and funny?
You know? Like maybe there's
something wrong with that.
And then I went to see Jim Norton and uh,
Jim Norton was in Austin and
he had more Dick Jokes than me.
And I said to him afterwards, I go, dude,
I was starting to think maybe I have too
many jokes about Dixon my ass until him
what to see you.
I saw an hour's worth of Dick Jokes
and I fucking thoroughly enjoyed it.
I'm like, thank you.
That made me feel good.
Cause as a a person who
was an audience member,
I saw it from an audience
member's perspective like, oh,
it's just a big crazy silly ride.
And you go like, it's not like,
you know you can't have so many
jokes about dicks. And also
if you think it's funny, then you kind
of have a, an obligation to do it.
As a comic. Can you think something's
funny? You should talk about it on stage,
but because if you think
something's funny or like, oh no,
that's not high brow enough,
I'm not going to do that.
And that's another form of pandering.
That's not it at all.
It's exactly, if you have a
joke about shitting your pants,
you're supposed to tell that joke.
Yeah. It's not supposed to be out to,
oh you're doing straddle logical material.
If you think it's funny.
That's the thing.
If you're just doing it to get it shock
out of people and you're doing at a lazy,
that's a whole different story.
Ari Shapiro has been doing some
bit that's been killing about,
he was in Australia and he got diarrhea.
It's a totally true story and it's
fucking killing for him. You know?
For someone to say that you're not
supposed to do that. It's funny.
It's really funny and it happened.
It's a real story, you know,
to for you to say that there's
something wrong with this.
For you to say that
there's any kind of rule.
It's like telling an artist where you
know you can't paint. That's light green.
Yeah.
If you come over someone's house,
like you have to really know that person
before you talk about shitting herself.
Yeah. It's a weird thing. Unless
they're a dog. When you're on stage,
it's one thing,
right?
You're supposed to be exposing everything
to anybody anyway, but if you were,
you know,
you don't know someone and they start
talking to you about shitting all of
themselves. You come over here, I need to
talk to you about it. I'm cool with it.
You know,
if like you're a good dude,
like you seem like just an
open dude and you're like,
how's the cheeseburgers
there? I was like, well,
they're pretty good but lives in the last
time I had, I'm to be honest with you,
I shut all over myself.
I couldn't even make it to the bathroom.
I would start laughing like, oh shit.
And you think that's what it is.
I would have a normal conversation with
you. I wouldn't be like, excuse me,
to Judith Segall,
shit on yourself.
How dare you sir.
Speak to me like such a scoundrel.
Who all you,
how dare you?
Where do you get this confidence
to come to me? Isn't that funny?
When you realize that you're
actually offending someone,
you realize that like this
really is in some way.
Something I'm saying is having an effect
on you that's like causing you to shut
down.
Listen folks,
I know you've been programmed to think
that you're the asshole when you're
swearing and someone reacts like that, but
no, no, they're the asshole. That's dumb.
It's 2000 and fucking 11
if you're really offended.
If someone talks to you about shitting
their pants, then you're the dummy.
You're the problem.
It's not the guy who shit his pants.
That guy's telling you a funny story.
Okay?
You're just some weird stuck up person.
It doesn't want to hear that.
Like if I don't think something's
funny and it's got a logical,
I'm not going to get offended.
I'm just going to, it's not funny.
It's not going to bother me.
It's like whatever you're talking about
shitting herself, fine. I don't really,
it's not, it's, it doesn't
bother me. It, some people,
they've never heard that
stuff before. Comedians, we,
we've been horrifying each other for eons.
You've horrified me in so
many different ways. You
feel you're really, really good at, um,
taking a story that already kind
of know, for example, grizzly man,
the guy getting eaten by the bear.
So like you'll give me really high and
then start talking about like, yeah,
like what, what was the Gwas grizzly
man, his name was Timothy Treadwell.
Timothy Treadwell.
And you start describing him getting
eaten by a bear in this like precise,
microscopic way where you're like every
moment you're describing the bones
crunching and his femur snapping and like
you're just really good at taking it.
Like to the next level to yeah,
wait to become a werewolf.
Cause at first you start talking about it,
you know when you're high, you're high,
you're like, well fuck, you're
seeing it's so clear. I'm like,
I'm not going to let I know
what he's doing. He's a,
he's going to take this into
the deep water in a second.
I'm not going to let it freak me out.
And I still remember the Treadwell story
and sure enough, I'm like, Jesus God,
this is horrible.
Poured Timothy Treadwell.
I could just see his bones turning into
jelly and his eyeballs bulging out.
Is he screaming for the bear to stop
attacking him? But it won't. Anyway,
you're very good at that.
So after you've been hanging out with
people who can professionally tell stories
in the most detailed way,
then it's really hard to get around
anyone who's going to say anything that
offends you. And also the Internet by
the way, is also like what's going to,
I've seen every,
I've seen everything.
My favorite picture in the Internet.
This is a strong same statement. Yeah,
and it's true.
My favorite picture is there as a kid
and he's standing in front of the goats,
see butthole and the guy's spreading his
ass hole open and it just says welcome
to the Internet. Yeah. The kid
is looking at that and I'm like,
yeah, that's it. Exactly.
Yeah. You can't get, you can't
get upset by things anymore.
It's kind of retro and
quaint when you are,
when you come upon someone who actually
can get offended, when you realize,
oh my God, you can still get offended.
How have you maintained that?
That's amazing.
This I,
you mean I really have the power
to disturb you in a real way. Yeah.
Like you don't realize though, you're
not under the glove all day at work.
A lot of people are under the
iron glove all day at work.
They're just stuck in an
office where they're there.
All their behavior was restricted.
Most of them even have to dress funny.
They have to wear like weird things around
their neck to signify that they mean
business. Yeah. Right. And you're,
you're walking around in some office
where everybody's stifled and you're all
forced together today all day to do
shit you don't want to do all day long.
You know, it's, it's, that's not good.
So people are like buttoned
down because of that.
Whereas you can do your smoking pot and
playing world of Warcraft, you know,
trying to write some jokes, you know, and,
and then we're going to go on
the road and we'll go to Chicago.
We'll do the Chicago Theater
January 27th with Joey Diaz. Yeah.
But you know what I'm saying? Like that's
your, your world, right? You're not,
you don't have like a shit job that you,
you know, get up to every morning. Right.
That's true. That that's, yeah. So yeah,
I understand people are buttoned down
and they've got conditioned and some,
it's too hard to just go away plus free
you all the time and you're at work all
and you're just like,
why
can't, why can we fucking talk?
Yeah. This is crazy. This job sucks.
This is ridiculous. We've got to
find another way to make money.
Or like those fucking email forwards
it. Those people saying, do you know,
hit those email forwards and it's
like the worst joke of all time.
What are the chicken side of the rabbit?
And he shut the fuck up.
You know? My mom was brutal. My mom was
brutal with those. I had to stop her.
I said I was really nice about
it. I was like, does this,
there was this not that funny to me.
And by the way,
I don't want your friends sending
me any crazy emails, so don't,
let's not link it all together.
Doesn't even know how blind carbon copy.
She just copies it copies here. She
hasn't sent me one in a long time though.
But the ones she did, I would still just
look back and I'm like, oh Jesus Christ.
But what about those also when you
get on those patriotic mailers, oh,
those are brutal.
I've had a bunch of those country.
I once knew that this is a
story about a country. Yeah.
And then just make things up. Yeah.
The, the thousands of terrorist acts.
So we prevented, how about
total was, could have wiped
out humanity 17 times over.
But we're out there doing the dirty
work. They were stopped. Yeah.
There's a jog living in Georgia.
It always tries to find
like so cinnamon oh party.
There's a dog living in
whose master didn't come. Oh,
stories are great. Well, you know what,
it would be beautiful if
that really was the case.
Could you imagine if you really had 100%
faith in the u s military and you knew
that there was a bad guys and we're the
good guy and it's clean, black and white.
There's no doubt about it. We
only do the right thing. Always.
We avoid war whenever possible and we
would never engage in warfare profit like,
but that's what people
like to think that like,
they like to think that
that's what we are.
Well, it would like if,
if every 50 years, uh,
Scorpions climbed out of the volcanoes
of the earth and they were like poisonous
and deadly and they shot lasers out of
their eyes and they could like burn you
alive and you met someone who's like,
I've made the decision to go
down and fight the scorpions.
I'm going to fight him, I'm going to
give my life to fight these scorpions.
You would be like, you are
fucking hero hero. That's a real,
here are amazing. You're going to go
fight the laser shooting scorpions.
It's incredible. Now it's so
muddied. It's like wow. You know,
they don't even know a lot of them. They
don't even know what they're doing now.
Like, well, we're going to
Afghanistan because um, oh,
you know,
we're going down there cause uh, you know,
Obama's not going to veto this fucking,
this new bill,
the one that passed through the house
pass through the Senate and the Congress,
apparently they, they, oh, okay.
Didn't know Obama was not going to be
totally turns the United States into a
battle. Indefinite detention. Yeah.
Indefinite detention for United States
civilians. Yeah. It doesn't have to,
you don't have to. Yeah. You don't have
to go to trial. Did you see the thing,
I was on Reddit with Mccain,
I ran Paul as Mccain point blank.
Does this mean that you can arrest a
United States citizen and detain them?
And definitely, I just tweeted it,
but, and Mccain is like, you know,
pretty straight forward.
It's like if someone is a threat to
the security of the United States,
we should be able to arrest them and
detain them because apparently like a lot
of the people that they didn't detain
indefinitely and they let out according to
Mccain ended up killing some troops.
Yeah. So I like what they're saying.
What they're saying is, listen,
this is some fucking dirty warfare
and we need some extra power,
but we're not going to abuse it.
But the problem is you can't get that
extra power because everybody abuses power
once they get it.
There was just the,
otherwise they would already
be an accounting for all
the fucking money that's
missing. That would already be
there would already be someone,
some repercussions for all the lies that
were told that led us to believe there
was weapons of mass destruction.
Just straight up lies.
We think about what you can get in
trouble for. You know what, what you,
what you know what you were thinking
about like how crazy insider trading is.
You can get arrested if you
have information that will,
you know a stock's going to go bad.
Think about that.
But then think about the fact that someone
somewhere lied about weapons of mass
destructions. They, they made up some
sort of a story or they fabricated some,
some evidence and it became the real
reason why people supported the idea going
there and yet it didn't exist. So if we
know that and that's not chased down.
Yeah, you don't chase that
down. There's, there's no,
there's no like big news followup
and documentaries about it.
How they chase that down and
found out how it happened.
Locked everybody up and cleaned out all
the people that they were in business
with. No, it's just somehow or another,
it kind of gets swept under the
rug that a war was started on.
Bullshit.
Yeah.
They've allowed somehow another hypnotize
people to the point where people have
allowed a war to be created on bullshit.
A country that had
absolutely no connection.
Then we could see like a
straight connection to Iraq.
What the fuck is that? Yeah,
it makes no sense. Oh, we gotta
go over there and get him.
He's got weapons of mass
destruction. Okay. Listen,
we were going to go to war
with the people that killed us,
but we can't figure out who the fuck
they are. Cause apparently don't matter.
They're nomadic terrorists that have
actually been living in America training.
Let a flow. Okay. Okay. Since we get the,
they're all dead. Since we can't get them,
let's go get some people
that look like them. Right.
Let's go get some people in another
country. Not even from a small country.
It's like, it's like Canada does something
fucked up and people go attack Mexico.
It's that fucked up. It's that silly.
Oh, then that's what it's like.
It's like if Canada attack somebody and
then they decided to attack Mexico and
retaliation. No, that's
what I want.
I walk my dog and I walk my dog past
this House with these two ferocious dogs
behind a fence. I've got little
Chihuahua. And so that you,
Allah loves coming in,
standing in front of this
fence and barking because
what happens is the two dogs
come charging down towards my
Chihuahua and barking at my dog.
And one of them is so mad at my Chihuahua
that it starts biting the other one on
it's ass. And it's the funniest
thing you've ever seen.
It's just taking it out on the closest
thing that it can bite, you know, so,
so it's like also,
isn't this known as, um,
isn't it kind of like what
happened in Afghanistan?
Isn't that called Bull Baiting? Isn't that
what it is? It's like a sun sometimes.
This is what really creeps me
out is I think that, uh, the, um,
the people that were fighting
in Afghanistan and the
war that we picked with
people, uh, I think they're really
good at fucking war. You know,
Afghanistan is called
the graveyard of empires.
And I think that the people that were up
against aren't just as stupid as a lot
of people would like to paint
them. You know, they can't fucking,
they can't even read. They're just hungry,
starving. People who can't even read,
they don't know what they're doing.
I think they kind of do know what
they're doing. I think that they, I mean,
a bin Ladin said,
all we have to do is like make it seem
like we're going to attack and look at
how much money the United States spends.
They were just like, oh, we have to work.
They turned on a fucking money faucet.
They basically like,
well look at what they did.
Look at if look at what al Qaeda did.
We now have a,
a country where our military can arrest
us if we're considered a threat to the
security of the United
States. So that, you know,
cause I mean a journalism mean anything
journalists could that mean like a Wiki
leaks guy?
Couldn't Malcolm X if we can.
Malcolm X had gotten arrested
and detained indefinitely.
Just don't you think that he would
get arrested that lower? Sure.
If he was in America fucking ever than
being assassinated though he hasn't been
assassinated yet.
But if,
if they could arrest him or assassinated
what they've done with that guy,
you know,
he's in a sort of a similar situation
where he has to report to a police station
like every year is to check in and
he's not allowed to go anywhere.
And as his trial is like still, he hasn't
been, they want to send them off to,
where was it? Norway, Norwegian who
was charged with now Sweden, Sweden,
sexual misconduct.
Whatever he did is just some weird moment
where is in bed with a girl apparently
she's saying, yeah, stuck his dick
in her without a condom and yeah.
Well it seems like we are,
sometimes it feels like we're on the
precipice where they're going to stop even
putting up this act that they're debating
and deciding and using courtrooms. The,
see that's the problem with indefinite
detention because it's like,
let's imagine that I think [inaudible]
I don't know. Let's imagine,
I think the Alex Jones is a threat to
the security of the United States because
of the things that he's been saying
or weakening the government. Right?
So let's imagine that the government,
the federal government decides to Alex
Jones is a real threat. And so they, uh,
they decided to arrest them.
They've got to put them on trial.
They've got to prove
that he's a real threat.
Was he like manufacturing
fucking explosives?
Was he planning on doing
something to a federal building?
There will be a trial and in the trial
they could use evidence to show if he was
really a real threat, play his
tapes, show what he was up to.
Now the military can just arrest him.
It's not even arrest cause they're,
they're not putting them on trial.
They get to tell anybody
they were arrested and they
just come and get you and
they put you away indefinitely because
somebody thought you were a threat to
this curity of United
States that chills me, dude,
that is so fucked up.
And if you think that's just going to be
used for, I don't know, whoever it is,
these invisible people that I'm not even
sure who they are that are lurking in
New York or wherever they're at.
You're crazy.
If you think that's going to
happen, fucking turn on. Uh, um, uh,
some Waco footage,
you know,
watch those fucking ATF agents
torching that Koresh compound.
If you think that they're just going to
fucking use this law for the worst and
most extreme cases, no fucking
way, man, they are going to use it.
They're going to use it any way that
they want to use it for drug dealers.
They're going to use it, use it for
whatever they want to use it for.
They're going to use it for
anybody, man. I mean we're,
we could be doing this fucking podcast.
It's not a female.
Can't think of what you saw that cop at
Uc Davis due to those kids that were on
their knees because he thought he could,
cause the law was on his side.
They weren't moving. He told
them to comply. They did not.
So he thought it was okay to spray
chemicals in children's faces. Yup.
And that guy is representative
of human nature.
He's representative of abusive
power. It's very simple. It's,
it's no logic. Abuse of power. Yeah.
I get someone has made your
life a little more difficult.
They made your job a little harder
because now you have to look out for,
you know, all these kids and
they're all this place where they,
you don't want him to be,
but guess what? Fuck face.
You're not allowed to spray him in
the face with fucking chemicals.
That's assault.
You're assaulting kids and you're think
you're allowed to do that because of
something written on a piece of
paper. Fuck you. Stupid. That's dumb.
You think that that's,
that's morally reprehensible.
Just innately it's in your mind.
You know,
that's a negative thing in your mind.
Do you know that a peaceful
protest with students,
with children who have this idealistic
view of the world and you're going to
squash it while you're
wearing a bulletproof vest
and spray them in the face
with fucking chemicals.
They want a peaceful protest,
which is supposedly guaranteed us.
We're supposed to have
the right to assemble.
We're supposed to be able to get together,
even if it is private property,
you know, would that is where
the issue takes place. Well,
where the fuck out should they be?
Well, no. Yeah, you,
you're supposed to be able to do that and
you're supposed to be able to do a lot
of them
and the community should embrace it
and the fucking school should have a
dialogue with them. They're supposed
to be ironing everything out.
You're not supposed to just,
you know,
new spray people in the face with fucking
chemicals. But because that guy could,
because he wasn't just some guy who
didn't like what the kids were saying,
you know,
like if you and I went down there,
you don't like these fucking kids
are spoiled. I'm going to fuck it.
Spray him in the face with tear gas,
Yo Dude, they would lock me in jail.
They would tackle me,
throw me to the ground because I don't
have the authority to assault them.
But this guy has the authority to
solve that to somehow or another,
it's become his job. That is exactly
what's going to happen with this bill.
That is exactly what's going to happen
with this. This amount of power.
You can't just give it to be people
and hope they're going to be good.
This should be the fucking
law. You can't do it.
You can't ever do it.
You want a way to stop terrorist threats?
Let's get the fuck out of their
countries. How about that? How about that?
That's a good start,
but you stop occupying these fucking
countries that don't really need us.
We they don't.
No one needs us in Afghanistan.
I want all everybody's relatives
come back fucking home.
Those people that are sending you over,
they're not looking out for your best
interest. That's ridiculous. That's right.
This is a time old story. It's a timeless
tale. It's been told back and forth.
The last edition was Vietnam, but
apparently nobody fucking learned from it.
Apparently.
Everybody just still thinks that
someone's looking out for you at the top,
despite all the evidence to the contrary,
someone's looking out for you, man.
Yeah. Well, and also
there's the, you know,
it's set up in a way that for many people
they feel like it's one of their only
options is to join the military.
They feel like they, it's like a,
they feel like it's going to pay for
their college and it's, um, the, a lot of,
you know, I get to it the
fucking, uh, or the UFC,
there'll be a marines there.
You've seen those, right. And,
and we do them for the troops. We do,
we do shows for the troops. Yeah. But,
and we have troops that are flown in
and we get them tickets. No, no, no.
That's cool. I'm talking about outside.
The recruiters were there like recording.
Yeah, they're recruiting
people. I don't mean that.
It's awesome that fucking at the fights,
the fights where they're recruiting
people and you're all juiced up with
testosterone up to seeing a Florida
fucking be tricked into that.
That's not fair.
That's like a whorehouse that's open
right in front of Australia. Yeah. We,
you're like, Whoa, what are you doing
here man? The one, I signed it fruit,
they were doing a pull up
contest is what it was.
So they having pullup contest and so
they're getting guys there. It's like,
go do a fuck at the hundred pullups look
and they're doing a hundred bullets.
And I'm like, man, you could be
a marine. You're really tough.
You could be a marine.
And so they use,
recruiters will come on college
campuses and you know, it's uh, the,
the United States military
uses, um, many, uh,
of the same things that cults do
to indoctrinate the people into it.
Uh, you know, cult, uh, change your
identity. They changed your name cults.
We'll shave your head.
They'll make you wear certain clothes.
They make you refer to people
in a very specific way.
They make you use a very
specific language in cults.
People will tend to say the
same thing over and over again.
That's just based on whatever the
leaders said. So a lot of the, uh,
the indoctrination is very similar to when
Colt's come out to campuses and stuff.
It's a very similar thing.
And what they do is they, um,
they get people to join up who haven't
actually considered the reality of what
they're going to be doing.
Some of them really do want to like
fucking blast goddamn machine guns in the
desert cause it's fucking fun.
There's a great book by
Sebastian younger called war. Uh,
and it's fucking awesome if you read that
book. No. Oh my God. It's so good though.
Refresh my memory. He decided to write
a book about, it's this deadly valley,
Afghanistan and it,
and so he decided to write his name.
Sebastian Junger. I don't know
if it's younger, a younger,
he's written other things before
the renewal. Yes. Yup. That's right.
I don't know what else though, but I, this
is, I just kept hearing about this book,
so I was just trying to remember what I
remembered about it. I can, he's like,
he lived with these fucking
troops out there. He's bad ass.
He's like a really tough dude who like,
goes deep into the shit and like, um,
and uh, he's a journal. He's
a war turn on the CNN guy. He,
is he the guy that has like the accent?
I don't know. Look at Australian accent.
Is that the guy? I don't think he has an
Australian accent, but I could be wrong.
I only saw one interview with them.
I don't remember.
I'm going to want to
keep interrupting you.
I'm trying to remember this summer camp.
Sorry. So his, what he did with his book,
which is remarkable and beautiful,
is he managed to write the book with
no moral or ethical slant to it.
You know, he's not saying like war
is bad or you shouldn't go to war.
You should go to war.
War is good.
It's just describing the experience
of war is purely as he can.
Exactly what it's like to get hit by a
roadside bomb or exactly what it's like
to like be in the middle of a firefight
and how they've studied adrenaline
levels when you get into firefights.
Okay. No, I'm, I'm remembering.
I'm going looking at the
pictures of them online. Yeah.
I saw him on a CNN interview,
CNN or c span.
They also did a documentary about it too,
about this group of people.
He's bad ass fucking marines
out in the middle of it.
Like in the deadliest fucking valley.
It's called the Korengal valley
is what it's called. Those guys,
those embedded reporter guys are
fucking crazy. Fucking crazy man.
But what a nutty job. Huh? They
want to go where the action is.
Yeah man. But the, the, the,
the experience of war for a young guy
who he says there's no drug like it.
He says that there's
nothing that you will,
that will get you as high is being in
a city life or death situation where
you're defending your, the people around
you, who you are like connected to.
There really are your brothers.
You're like surrounded or you're with
these people. See for for the troops,
that's what their war is there.
War is protecting their dear
friends from getting killed and,
and that's how they're taught. They're
taught, these are your brothers.
You will give up your life for your
brothers. That's what they're taught. And,
and so you develop these intense bonds
for the people around you that are formed
from massive burst of adrenaline.
You know, cause like when adrenaline,
when your body is experiencing
super dangerous situations,
all the senses turn on.
It's,
I think it's an evolutionary
trait designed to like
teach you so that you learn
how to survive. Like
you know, way back when,
if you're getting attacked by a tiger,
you would re you,
you know how you remember
everything in a dangerous situation.
Everything becomes crystal clear.
You see everything,
everything's kind of in slow motion and
then afterwards you totally remember it
with this vividness that you
don't remember other things.
This is where a post traumatic
stress disorder, shock disorder,
post traumatic stress disorder comes
from is that people are getting really
intense situations in war.
They get these fucking memories
burnt into their brains like tattoos.
They can't forget it.
Then their mind keeps going back to it.
Like when your memory wanders
and you think back to a moment,
it's kind of dulled and the colors are
dim and you don't remember their memories
go back to it 100% so
it's like they're their,
their heart start racing and it fucks
up your life because this thing has been
burned into your mind.
So in these situations you're experiencing
life at its super high voltage and
you're experiencing with a group of people
and you form bonds with these people
that you don't have with normal,
with normal people in life.
You inform these intense bonds.
Maybe it's like the kind of bonds you
form when you're with your wife and she's
giving birth or something. When you're
in sharing those moments with people,
it's like that. So I
think the there, you know,
these affects are studied by the people
whose job it is to make the troops
efficient and they use these really
intense conditioning techniques and stuff
that a lot of these people
aren't prepared for it.
They don't know what they're getting into.
They don't know that they're getting into
more than just defending their country.
They're getting into a well studied system
of brainwashing and conditioning that
transforms them from,
you know,
normal American citizens and the people
who are willing to die for whatever
their commander says, you can't
question what your commander says.
You can't question whoever the superior
officer is about doing this or that you
have to do it or couldn't
work if that wasn't the case.
If like each individual person got to
decide, oh, I don't think I'm going to,
I don't think I'm going to
shoot that fucking grenade, man,
I don't want to do that. I don't think
I, you know what the place down there,
all the people are with the
guns that want to kill me.
I'm probably not going to go there today.
It's amazing how easy it is to sell the
idea that you're supposed to go kill
someone because some
people that are in office,
even though you know that everyone in
office is essentially corrupted the,
but because those people were in off of,
they tell you,
you're allowed to kill these people. Not
only, uh, are you allowed to kill people,
but when you come back they'll
be happy to see you. Yeah, sure.
It's like in any other time, if you find
out that other guy killed somebody, like,
look, you know, this fucking
guy, man, he's a good dude.
But he went to jail for manslaughter.
He beat some guy to death in front of
a nightclub and he's kind of fucked up
with Jill for 10 years. You, you like,
I don't want to be around that guy.
They're going to kill somebody.
But if you are around a war hero,
so different feelings, different
feelings for them too. You know, I mean,
some guys have have issues over it,
but I've met guys that don't,
I know some really smart guys that went
overseas and they're happy that they did
what they did. 58 confirmed kills
dude. I know some snipers. Yeah,
I know one dude very well. There
was a slight bro. Well, I mean,
you gotta be a weird thing,
man.
To be looked at someone from a distance
and make them disappear from Earth.
Blend from a distance. You know,
it's, that's what it is. I mean,
that's what being a sniper is.
You're not there to fucking good when
the target content playing pinball,
you're there to pack
people off if they want
to kill, operate people's heads. Yeah,
you're, you explode their brain. Yeah.
You, you're a widow maker. You're out
there fucking making kids grow up,
grow up without their debt. You're out
there fucking making it so that like, uh,
for the rest of their lives,
there's going to be sentimental moments
where a guy looks at a grainy picture of
the person whose face you just turned
to jelly and bone fragments for the rest
of their life. They're going to be looking
at this picture of being like, man,
I wonder what my dad was like. I bet he
was pretty fucking cool. Oh, guess what?
You're not going to know his fucking
head looks like a goddamn blast.
A tomato that fell off a car, his
head splattered everywhere. That's it.
And a professional did that.
Who got trained in a fucking camp designed
to teach people to do that and the
most precise way
possible. It's crazy, man.
It's amazing when you
break it down like that.
When you look at it for what the
actual physical act of it is,
instead of looking at it as a patriotic
American supports everything that we do
overseas and you know, put a fucking
flag on your window. It says,
God bless our troops. You know, instead
of just looking at it analytically,
not even like casting a blame
just described as describing it.
You just just describe it.
It becomes insanity.
It becomes a point where people
were angry at you and they will say,
you're talking shit about the American
soldiers and the U s army. Well,
you actually not even,
you don't even have to.
All you have to do is just
describe what's happening.
You don't have to talk any shit
when you describe what's happening.
The reality of the details is so horrific
that people will interrupt you with
excuses. Sure. Interrupt you. All you
have to do is say what's happened,
not even cast blame.
Just describe it accurately.
What you're doing there.
See as you're walking through the laser
in the museum that makes the fucking
doors shut in front of the diamond.
You know,
it's like people have these trip wires
in their brains where the moment you
start talking about just the stuff
we've been talking about now it's,
you're hitting a fucking icon.
You're hitting some conditioning that's
been intentionally put there. Um,
that's been intentionally
put there because if it's
not there, then you know, uh,
the country can't function as an empire.
I mean, it's got, you've got to have,
if you're going to run an empire,
the population has got to have deep
and intense admiration for the military
force because if they don't,
then the military force isn't going to
function because the military forces made
up of the population. But it becomes, at
a certain point, Tom, you have to wonder,
when does the military force realize
these guys that are paying you absolute
shit money and the guys that we
have to do foundations for it,
we have to do a benefits for, you know,
to, for a traumatic brain injuries.
You know, like people have to have help
and contribute. That should, to me,
when I found out that they need money for
traumatic brain injuries for hospitals
to deal with these guys,
when they come back overseas
with these horrible injuries,
the first thing I thought is,
man, how is that possible?
They let that become an issue.
How much would that cost in comparison
to how much fucking money they're making
over there? How much would it
cost and who's making money?
How about the fucking
people that are making the,
all the equipment he'll sell on the
caliber and the people that make the air
conditioning machines,
there's,
they're spending billions of dollars on
air conditioning over there. You know,
giant tents that they're fucking air
conditioning. There's a lot of my,
you're telling me they don't have any
money to spend on traumatic brain injury.
We shouldn't.
They like invest in the best medicine
possible with a smart scientists.
How much would that cost?
Would that be cost prohibitive?
If that's cost prohibitive,
then that the means of fucking
war should be cost prohibitive.
You shouldn't be investing in a war
that you can't take care of your fucking
soldiers after it's over. What
the fuck is that? That's like,
that's like driving across the country
with just enough money for gas and no
money for fights.
The most fucked up thing ever man. It's
like, and, and that's the, that is the,
the real sickening thing about it is
whenever you run into people who are
soldiers, like, like that guy, there
was a coolest fucking guy at the,
her Moses show he did man.
He like said he listened to your podcast
and like he was like in a special
forces guy and he was fucking cool man.
And every time I run into those people,
they're cool and an
authentic way or you know,
you could be good friends with these
people. You could trust these people
there. You have to have a
tremendous character to get
through the special forces,
the green berets. You don't say what you
will about someone, you know, being a,
you know, a soldier who's a, you know, a
puppet of a giant corporation, whatever,
to be like a special forces soldier, you
need to be a bad motherfucker. Period.
Yeah.
Do you man,
and those people are like some of our,
there's some of our best people.
Yeah. You're really, really are.
There's some of our best fucking people.
So to send them off to bullshit wars
where they're getting fucking liquified
instead of using them for real purpose,
for something,
for like really building the country up
and really do like for in the inevitable
event where some shit is going to happen
and we're going to need them for real
thing, you know, to send
them to waste them for these
fucking politicians who are,
who are the real pop of the corporations
to fucking send these heroes off to get
their faces blown off in some country
that they don't need to be. Man,
that is beyond evil.
That's some Rep Tilian
vampiric weird shit man.
It is. It is. Yeah, it is.
It's, it's if, you know,
if they were eating people
instead of just killing them,
if every person that died, they
ate, we would be horrified. Right,
because everybody just dies.
Yeah. Somehow or another,
it doesn't seem like the kitten
killed by monsters. No, they are.
They're being killed by
psychological monsters.
They've been killed by people who are
willing to kill people in order to profit.
And it's really that simple and it
doesn't seem like it should be possible in
2011 but that's the
business that they're in.
The guy who works at the
fucking butcher shop,
the guy who works at the slaughterhouse.
Okay.
Do you think that guy at
a certain point in time,
don't you think he gets used
to killing cows? The fuck,
yeah, he does. It's his job.
But if you had to go
there today and the like,
you just were alone with the cow and all
this machinery and then there was like
a fucking manual,
the told you exactly how you pull the cow
into this and lead them into this spot
and then send the piston through his
fucking brain and then hook them up and
then got him.
You'd be so freaked out at the whole
process because you're not used to it
because it's not,
it's not a normal yeah.
Part of your life. Yeah. Meanwhile, yeah,
so these people are just used to it there.
They just make sense to them and yeah,
it's a normal part of their
lives and normal part of
their life, man. It's in it.
It's like when you hear about the friends
of Bush that got all those deals and
Afghanistan,
all the contractors and Shitty I to
like the and how much they charge for a
workout there that they charge,
like saying money,
money for this stuff and you realize, oh,
this is just a, you know, the act of war.
It's just a way to test out some
new technology and to, uh, get,
get a lot of people, some work and
make a lot of people really writ,
yeah, incredibly rich. And the
idea that everybody, you know,
people say there's no way that people
would go to war just for money.
And I'm like,
there's no way they wouldn't,
there's no way they wouldn't if they had
to sacrifice a few thousand people here
or there to make untold
trillions amount of dollars.
That is what it is too. Yeah. Yeah.
That's funny. Cause if it was like,
let's say there was just a group of like
robed a demonic magicians that lived in
some giant black tower and they're like,
okay,
we need 5,000 of your
strongest and brave as men.
We're going to sacrifice them at the
top of the tower and from their blood,
we will reap great energy. You'd be like,
fuck here. That's the evilest thing ever.
But if they're like,
we got to send our troops over there
to defend and fight for our country,
suddenly you're like, oh yeah, totally.
Makes Sense. Go ahead and do that.
They're going to fight for your freedom.
We're pigs, man. Listen to fucking,
I was the Ozzy Osborne. He sums it
up perfectly in that sock. Yeah.
Why the war machine keeps turning.
Yeah.
It is a war machine. And that's
something that, you know,
people have warned us about from the
beginning of time. You know, there's,
you know, people that are in
charge, they're like everything.
They're going to eventually get drunk
with power and they're going to lead you
in some terrible direction
at all. Corruption evolves.
And if it's not checked,
it gets stronger and stronger and all
you have to do is just go back to the
Kennedy assassination.
Go back to Lyndon Johnson,
go back to Richard Nixon and
Watergate and they're, oh,
crux.
Yeah.
They've always been crooks and no one
got caught a few along the way. Nixon,
a few guys got popped for a little
bit of this and a little bit of that,
but for the most part,
everybody got away with everything.
The people who drafted up the Northwoods
document, they didn't go to jail.
Whoever the fuck shot Kennedy.
Ooh,
it was Lee Harvey Oswald acted alone.
Yeah, sure he did. Sure he did.
Yeah. All those people that heard
bullets coming from behind them,
they're just crazy. Yeah.
They're just silly people.
That was fucking probably like
five or six dudes with guns.
They think they've got to rely on one guy.
And do you think that one guy really,
really was on his own?
Just a lone nut?
Yeah,
we shut the fuck up.
Which is why when you see John Mccain
or pretty much directly telling Paul the
yes with this bill,
if someone is a threat to the
security of the United States,
you know John Mccain,
this is from the person who fucking
chose Sarah Pailin as his vice president.
So that's how fucked up this man
is. When you hear him saying, yeah,
we can indefinitely arrest United
States citizens who are a threat to the
security of this country.
You have to ask, well,
what is John Mccain's definition
of security? I know what mine is.
What's John Mccain's definition
of the security of this country?
Because I think it's wildly different
from my idea and your idea and for most
people's idea of the security of the
country. I think for John Mccain,
the security of the country means that
the corporations are able to function
without getting disturbed by people who
have the gall or audacity to say that,
uh,
the way that wealth is distributed right
now is unfair and is fucking up. Uh,
uh,
is,
is basically eating away in eroding
the foundations of what this country is
supposed to be about.
I think fucking McCain would very much
like to take those people and put them in
some indefinite detainment.
Um, if he could,
and eventually, maybe it won't be
Mccain. Maybe it won't be this year.
Maybe when this bill passes,
it'll be 15 years before it happens.
But eventually people
just start disappearing.
People will vanish in
the middle of the night.
Did you hear about this fucking
ridiculous thing that Newt Gingrich said?
Gary Johnson outed a Newt
Gingrich about, uh, being a,
a pot smoker and the fact that he,
uh,
was pushing for some thing that would
make marijuana distribution after a
certain amount,
like a,
with a certain volume would make it a law.
You would be able to be put to death,
essentially,
you'd be eligible for the death penalty.
This newt Gingrich,
the guy who had missed it,
he had smoked pot.
He's talking about like pot dealers at
wow. Gary Johnson outdid them on this.
Right. So yeah, so new. So
right. And those are made.
There are many people right now we're
in control of this country. Who, okay.
Oh, how crazy is that? It's evil.
Or imagine that someone's saying that
you are a guy who sells pot because he
sells a lot of it. What? He
sells one joint. Wow. One
joint. No death penalty. Okay.
I've saw a million joints. Death penalty
off with is, hey, you know why? Why?
Because you're giving
more people the same shit.
That doesn't even make any sense.
I've never understood that.
The idea of like a volume
issue makes the crime worse.
Like give your cell on a couple
of joints to your friends.
It's like a little slap on the wrist.
But if you're selling a hundred thousand
pounds in the back of a semi, yeah,
you're going to, you're going to get
locked up for the rest of your life.
Take it a little further back.
Yeah.
You're talking about a fucking farmer.
You're going to execute a farmer.
It's agriculture. Malaria, shit grows
out of the ground. You, you want to,
you're going to execute a fucking
guy who like, who is a horticulture?
Is there a botanist? You're just
gonna. You're going to kill somebody.
You grew a plant. It's not like he was
whipping up poison. You know what, that's,
that's the weird thing.
You could probably whip up 500 gallons
of cyanide and distribute that around and
you couldn't get the death
penalty for that is deadly.
Is that as pure deadly cyanide. But if
you're growing enough fucking marijuana,
uh, Newt Gingrich thinks that
he can. He wants to execute you.
He wants to kill you.
Speaker of the house.
Newt Gingrich introduced in 1997 the
drug importer death penalty act of 1996 a
builder of acquired a sentence of death
for certain importations of significant
quantities of controlled substances.
It would have applied to
anyone convicted more than one,
so carrying a hundred doses or about two
ounces of marijuana across the board,
or two ounces of marijuana
across the border. 100 doses.
That would be the death penalty.
You'd be eligible for death. Yeah.
What a monkey.
What an old limp Dick Monkey.
Just you old dumb fuck you.
You ancient thinking shithead.
You fucking rule maker.
You write it down and everyone knocks
the hammer and then it makes it right.
Your fucking system is obviously bullshit.
All of it's bullshit.
So your laws are bullshit. All your rules
are bullshit. All this posse comitatus,
comitatus, whatever it is. That's
bullshit too. It's just we just decide,
people write things down on paper and we
decide what is right and what wrong and
then we know we're not agreeing to this.
We didn't even get to vote any of this.
There's the idea that they can just
impose this on you is nothing short of
imperialism.
It's nothing short of people telling
other people what they can't do.
Telling other people that
they're not, they don't.
They're not as special as them,
that they're not worth
as much as them did.
They don't have any rights that they
don't have any authority and that these
people who write the things down on people
on paper rather all of a sudden have
the authority over the mass of other
humans that don't. They're special.
They override and now they're
telling us that the override,
because they have weapons because
they're going to allow the military to
actually enter into civilian
areas and stop uprisings,
so you're going to have tanks
can stop Operation Wall Street.
Literally what happened in Tiananmen
Square that horrified every American when
we saw those kids get run
over by tanks and killed,
it was terrifying that their government
is so fucking ugh against them,
that their government is so
cool and so evil that he,
they been willing to
run over their citizens,
run over the people whose hard
work literally funded the empire,
funded these tanks.
Every person chipped in a certain amount,
but because he's people defy,
because these people protest,
they're going to run over him with tanks
and crushed him on television in front
of everybody.
That's right. And, and, and that's, that's
the type of person that Newt Gingrich's
and that can come, that can come
from this, from this action.
And that's why people don't understand
like why you getting so outraged about
this? Why is this like this is crazy.
This is like a movie. This is like Batman.
Okay, we're, we're in Batman
right now and you know, the,
the evil people are slowly getting
their grips on our, on our government.
There's some guy with a fucking mask on
and he's working for all the bad guys
and he's pretending to be a senator and
Batman has to figure this guy out and he
has to get to him. And right now
that guy looks like Barack Obama.
Barack Obama was like,
he's got a mask on,
he's like some fucking lizard guy
underneath all this and he's just a really
good actor and he's got everybody
convinced that everything's Cool and David
Eick is right, man. They're
all fucking reptilians.
He's kind of like him,
man. It's so ridiculous.
It almost like that would fit right into
the plot if you found out Obama really
was a reptilian.
Yeah.
Would it like fit right in the plot of
you found out that new Gingrich really
was some evil reptilian that wanted to
take over the reptile farm. You know,
he doesn't like to leave this
young reptiles runs things.
I would run these humans correctly,
you know? Well you can, you know,
before you get to there, fuck.
Before you get to the reptilian part,
you can just kind of look at what they
really are and what they really are.
Here's one thing you know about Newt
Gingrich. Newt Gingrich is a murderer.
He wants to kill people. Newt Gingrich
feels comfortable killing people.
You know that. And you also
know that Newt Gingrich, uh,
makes would make money off of that.
Newt Gingrich makes money off of,
would make money off of killing people.
The people who support war make
money off of killing people.
They literally transform
human beings into money.
They kill human beings. And that
turns into money and money's energy.
So what that means is they're vampires.
That's what they really are.
They're vampires.
They or they convert human energy
through destruction into cash,
and then they use that cash
to make their lives better.
Just like vampires sync their things in
the people suck the blood to stay alive.
It's the same thing. It's vampiric gets
a vampiric form of existence. And um,
it's really fucking terrifying
when you realize that it's 100%
true. They're not only, is it 100% true?
It doesn't seem to be any way to get
them out other than them dying and young
people taking their place, young people
who grew up with the Internet. Yeah.
Well it seems like a certain
amount of the way the system is.
It's like they've sort of
just accepted it, you know,
and everyone's accepted
that it's just fuck
wash, but you, and you have to think,
I don't think that they're unaware
of the fact of where they're,
where they're fallible.
I think they know where they're fallible.
They can't correct it.
I think that they may be,
they know what they're doing in a
really intense way because they've had
infinite amounts of money to study human
psychology and to understand how to
control populations.
And they got it down to a science man.
There's a great fucking documentary on
the BBC called the century of the self.
Have you seen that?
No.
Edward Bernays is this Guy Bernays
who was like Freud's cousin. And,
um, it's all about the ways
that they started studying,
how to manipulate,
uh,
the perception of populations for the
sake of corporations. So for example,
cigarette companies approached
Bernays and they're like, listen,
women don't want to smoke right now
cause they think it's too masculine.
What do you, what do you think we can do
to make it so that women want to smoke?
And so Bernays said,
well,
you need to make women feel
like it's a form of activism.
Are there like pushing against uh,
a male dominated culture?
It's like make it part of the
woman women's rights movement.
So what they did is they got a bunch
of these girls to march during the Macy
date,
Macy's Day parade.
And at one point they told all the
press that they're going to do this.
At one point the women lifted up their
dresses and like pulled cigarettes out of
their gardens or whatever and started
smoking in front of all these reporters
who were snapping pictures.
And so their reporters put
that in all these newspapers,
women's women want the right to smoke.
Now all of a sudden what Bernays did or
what the cigarette companies did is they
tied into the DNA of the
women's rights movement smoking.
So now smoking becomes a empowerment
and empowerment and a sign of feminism.
And all of a sudden women started smoking
and it totally fucking worked. So yeah,
totally work. So, so it's like, so stuff
like Cree now's a long time ago, man.
So he has a long time ago. So
they started studying, you know,
they started studying.
It's just like,
imagine like somebody who herd sheep or
imagine somebody who is in charge of any
kind of animal,
a beekeeper for example,
or anyone who's in charge of
controlling animals. They're experts.
They know how to like, they know how to
do, like Turkey hunters are the same way.
They're not in Turkey cause,
and just the perfect way to make
a Turkey appear and to blast it.
So I think that people put a lot of
money into studying human perception.
The way people work. And I
think maybe they, the what,
what we think the amount of control
that we think we wheeled his ma,
it's an illusion. I don't know when I
see those fucking black Friday videos,
you know when you see the black Friday
videos of thousands of people stampeding
through a Walmart banging down the
door of a fucking Walmart like zombies.
If you ever seen that video,
when you see that,
it's really,
to me it's like man,
I mean maybe you and me and a few
other people have these ideas,
but in general as a herd it seems like
they've gotten people so doped up and
dumbed down that uh,
I don't know that they're
making too many mistakes.
I think they make mistakes here and there.
I think they fuck up.
I think there's a lot of shit that's
going on that is just coincidental and is
more of a,
a symptom of the,
the way we've sort of developed
as a society than a grand plan.
And it's more of them filling
in the gaps that were available,
taking, taking advantage of a lot
of situations that are available.
I don't think that it's one gigantic
group with a fucking finger on all the
marionette handles autonomy.
I think it's worse than that. I think
it's, you know, the term gets stalled.
You ever heard that term? Yes.
So I think it's the good stock.
I think it's like the,
somehow the,
the super consciousness that has emerged
from this group of people collaborating
his car, there's like a, it's,
it's become its own thing.
It's become an organizing force that's
organizing towards the negative and
towards the vampiric and not
organizing towards the positive.
Did you listen to the, you, you didn't
listen to Bruce Lipton? I didn't.
It was really interesting.
He was on the podcast yesterday and one
of the things he was talking about was
the importance of creating a community,
like a good community of,
of people.
You feed off their energy and those
people that you're around and you feed off
their energy, you know, if
they're positive, you'll,
you'll actually feel better.
You'll have a more positive light. And
it totally makes sense. Totally. Oh yeah.
That's, it's, it's the most important.
That's one of the reasons that people, um,
advise, uh, spending time
and Ostrom's they're spending
time around people who are
meditating because you, um, from being
around people who are working on,
and also it's the same with martial arts.
Do you want it,
if you're around people who are fighters
and you see the different forms and
styles that they're using,
that's going to,
you're going to evolve just from being
around them and seeing what they're doing.
So techniques. Yeah. I said, yeah,
it w you know, it's like you,
when you learn techniques of thinking too.
Yeah.
That's one things that people always
comment on this podcast. People, oh,
I get emails and tweets and Facebook
to zone where people are always talking
about how, you know, they don't know
anybody that thinks the way they think.
They don't have anybody that
has the interest they or
who looks at things in the
just the raw, honest, black
and white view that you see.
And here's my perceptions and it's not
flavored by what's politically correct
and it's not flavored
by, you know, what's, uh,
what's thought to be
a acceptable behavior.
It's what I really think and I want to
know if you think the same thing and when
when you do that people,
it resonates with people.
They don't know anybody else who's doing
that. All right. Well, um, so yeah,
so, so right. So in that same
way that like this podcast has,
because of the incredible connection it's
given me with like Shitload to fucking
people,
uh,
my evolution sped up because I'm
constantly getting like amazing videos,
book recommendations, basic things
from Blake's, Twitter lists,
all the crazy stories.
So it's certainly altered me
and I and it for the positive.
Now imagine 100% of many of me as well,
you know, as I've been a part of it,
you know, as like doing the
podcast, being a part of it,
it's completely enhanced my,
my perception of things and
people have cleared up, uh,
things that I didn't understand before.
People have sent me alternative points
of view that also should be considered.
Like there's so many interesting bits
of information they keep coming at you
from all these different forums. Right.
It's great. It's creating a feedback loop.
What I was getting at is that this what
these people have put together with the
people involved in the military industrial
complex and put together is a very
high level evil version of that.
That's it man.
But they have a high level evil version
of thinking where everyone is thinking
along the same way.
And you have to make sacrifices and
you got to crack some eggs to make an
Omelette. And all of this
thinking is put into like a,
a mindset. And that mindset
is enforced into the troops,
beaten into their head, supported through
the ranks, applied to corporations
and,
and many of them.
And it's really like when you consider
that many of the people at the top of the,
uh, power structures are fundamental
is Christians. It's hilarious.
Now imagine this, imagine that they
weren't fundamentalist Christians.
Imagine they were just, you know,
cultists and they believed in a dark God.
They worshiped at dark art and this dark
God was a child sacrifice or, and, uh,
sacrificed its own son at one point,
spelled the blood of its own son, um,
out of some sense of obligation or power.
And that they were praying and worshiping
daily to a dark God who was planning
revenge on the majority of the human race
and was right now at this very moment,
planning and getting ready to destroy
the planet with plagues and different and
horsemen and trumpets and
weird like crazy fucking, uh,
angels that were going to fly down and
kill and poison the largest of the earth.
And they're worshiping this guy daily.
They go to church and worship a god
that wants to destroy the planet every
fucking day. They pray
to this God, oh Lord,
give me the courage to lead today so that
I may be prepared for when you were a
turn and destroy the planet. That's
who they fucking pray to, man.
That's God. They pray to God. They pray
to a God that wants to wipe us out.
Throw us in hell,
kill the fucking homosexuals,
destroy the majority of the planet.
So all that's left is a few John Mccain's
style honkies where their feet a river
of blood waving up at
Gabriel are worshiping God.
Like I'm walking down the streets
of gold waving American flags.
That's the freaks. Who are, a lot of them
are running this fucking country, man,
that ain't good. That's
not good. That's bad.
I don't want anyone having access to a
nuclear arsenal that worships at God.
That's planning on,
it's some random time blasting the
planet I'm living on and wiping out the
majority of the people because he's
pissed about what they did do is fucking
Hippie kid 22,000 years
ago. Like, come on man,
forget about it. I'm, I wasn't
alive back then. I can't help it.
They fucking threw your kid up on a cross.
I had nothing to do with it.
Why are you coming back to kill
their descendants? You weirdo.
You us the fucking break.
You're God traveled back in time and
pluck them off the fucking cross, man.
Yeah, and this need controlling
this whole game, doesn't he?
How can you just give it come down
and give us better directions?
He just gives you this game and you just
fuck this game up and you're supposed
to read some old manual and how to play
the game and it's interpreted through
three different languages
and it was just a,
a spoken word thing for a
thousand years before that.
So who knows how much of it's fucking
valid and this is how you playing game and
you're fucking up along
the way and everybody is telling you,
you keep fucking up and he's going to
come and he's going to take you away.
He's going to take you away and
I'm going to put you in a dark,
dark place forever. But this is thoughts
and they have these ideas, these urges,
and they seem to be natural.
You better stop Presto's fuck.
I want to fuck all the time.
Don't do it. Go to house.
This guy's an asshole. I want to kill
him. You can't do it. You can't kill him.
And that's the most amazing
thing that these same people,
all of a sudden you're allowed to
kill him if some sanction group says,
absolutely you can do.
You can even say you're doing it for God.
May God bless you all. Wow. God,
God is blessing us to go Jackson.
People we don't know
their God, their God. I
called their God loon, loon,
and it's this weird fucking creature.
It reminds me of an HP
Lovecraft demon spirit.
If you change the name of their guy
or their guy doesn't have a name,
that's the name, it's a name was
God. It's like out of fucking cone.
And it's a nameless. It's an
invisible, nameless God. Yeah.
And they worshiped the invisible,
nameless God, and, and,
and part of worshiping the invisible
nameless God is a sending kids off to war
and fucking letting the kids kill people.
And another part of worshiping the
invisible nameless God is making it to gay
people can't get married. The invisible
nameless one. You know what he hates Joe?
What he fucking hates but sex. Damn.
Why did you make it feel so good?
One with no name. He curses
the gays. The one with no name.
He doesn't like bud sex.
He's like really upsetting the
end of the little Richard Song.
Tutti frutti used to be Tutti.
Frutti good booty.
No, it didn't to the fruit it, that's
why I, that's why little Richard is his,
his booties. He's eternally
damned by this fucking Luma.
Tutti Frutti good booty evil man.
He's an evil man.
Did you see that damn cartoon I made
by the way? No. Jesus heals a gay, no,
I like read did like a,
I took an old Christian cartoon of Jesus
healing a leper and just replace the
words with him. Healing a homicide.
She'll hold it up. Hold it up. Who isn't?
I didn't like four hours.
So it ain't looking at
professional fucking going
to be known enough to give me
a thank you to be now.
Sorry. Don't you know I have to
qualify it first. You're so humble. No,
I will when I have to
be. This is not a, hey,
we should talk about that sketch that
you did. That's like the I got you.
I'm going to get you
sucker. Oh yeah, please.
Let's clear that's clear that because uh,
I know for a fact that Dunkin did not
remember that thing when he made that
sketch. And I also know because I
didn't remember that sketch and that,
what are you talking about? Dunkin made
a video with Natasha, a hilarious video.
What's it called? Uh, it's
called falling apart. Falling.
You're Padam teeth and the
idea of the video, there's,
there's a scene where the girl starts
taking off fake parts and there's a scene
in, I'm going to get
you sucka. Where is it?
The same thing happened where
he's alone with this girl Keenan.
Ivory Wayans is alone with his check and
she starts taking off all those parts.
I completely forgot about that.
Even though I'm a big fan of Keenan
Ivory Wayans and know I saw that movie,
I completely forgot about it and I know
the Dunkin did not know about it because
when he, first of all, I know Dunkin,
he would never do something like that.
You're one of the most,
you have some of them.
The most clear artistic integrity out
of almost anybody that I've ever met.
It's you're,
you're 100% legit and what you do to
the point where you wouldn't even do the
Pauly shore reality show.
That's true.
He walked away from a money
job on a television show
where he was going to be on
a reality show cause he [inaudible] thing.
I would like to say there was no money.
It was a,
it wasn't like I was walking away from.
It would have benefited the pop,
but have benefited you. I thought,
Oh, I thought you get paid for it.
You wouldn't get oh no money at all.
I don't think that's legal.
I don't even think that's
legal to put you on television.
I think they have to give you, they have
to give you like some after a minimum.
That's what I thought.
Because there was a documentary,
technically they weren't going to pay.
It's a documentary,
but it was all scripted. Everything
he did with script, how is my feeling?
They was all scripted. That
was my feeling. But they all,
they do that with all these
reality shows when they create it,
things for them to do well I think,
I think in the dilemmas in the long run,
maybe someone could have contested it
or something, but really if it, if it,
if there had been money I
would've still walked away,
could have been a good show and he could
have been a good show if it wasn't what
it was was a Pauly shore
showcase if could have been,
was like a real realistic viewpoint of
all these dudes who are doing standup are
out there scratching that real
intense creative environment.
That was that comedy store
man. There was, there was some,
you know when we were around back then,
the comedy store with you and me
and Dheas and Ari and you know,
there's a lot of good guys. They're, it's
fucking great right now. I mean like,
and believe you, it's fucking really
good there right now. The crowds are,
it's packed. It's got a really
cool vibe. But like, but that,
that fucking poly thing, man, it was like,
there was a lot of reasons that I
walked away from that and at one of the
biggest ones, um, aside from
the fact that I did not want,
I desperately didn't want to be in it
was that I had gotten trapped at that job
as the talent coordinator.
I've been doing that job for a long time
and I needed a way out and it was just
a perfect exit mechanism for me.
And it was,
that show is like,
I'm so happy that that show happened
because it got me the fuck out of there,
man. You can get stuck at a desk, man.
Yeah, you can get stuck at a job. But the,
as far as the way his brother movie stuff
goes, so let me, let me just explain it.
Um, the, the scenes are very similar,
but Dunkin sort of has a completely
different point to it. But look,
the idea of someone having something fake,
I mean,
how many movies have been when a guy
grabs a girl's hair and it's a wig and
she's bald with like four or five straggly
hairs has been like a bunch of those
sex naked gun. Yeah. It means it's just
one of those, it's like a comedy device.
It's almost like a spit take that
someone's got a fake leg or fake arm.
But both videos,
the in every way in ones and yours
took it to the end most degree,
which is by the way, what you naturally
do when you make something funny you,
you always
in, the more you beat on
it, the funnier it gets.
And it's essentially the
same joke. What, what? Um,
so where that idea came from
that I did and I have seen,
I'm going to get you Sucka and
I did not remember that scene.
And if I had I never would have done
it. That's a scary thing, right?
When a an ideas in your head and it
comes down, you're like, God damn it.
That was too easy. Well,
no. See, here's the thing,
what that idea came from was from watching
Natasha take her earrings off and I
was watching her take her earrings off
and then I started thinking about like
how like when you're dating someone
you're like try like when you're in a
relationship with someone and used or
you start dating somebody and you know,
part of it is you begin to like
disassemble their personality. You know,
the more you get to know someone,
when you've been with
someone for a very long time,
you're in a relationship
or you're married,
you get to know the deepest part of them,
you end up getting to know very,
very deep parts of them that
are hidden by the hidden,
by their personalities and things that
they don't ever display in public or
maybe they don't even know about. You
get to know the deepest levels, man,
when you're,
when you've been having sex with
someone for a long time and you know,
like the deepest level of a person
and you've been living with someone.
So anyway, I was thinking like, man, it's
so weird how that's what it's all about.
It's basically just like plucking away
the different pieces of someone until all
they are is, is this primal spark that
you're fucking, so that was the idea.
That's where it came from. And you
know, you think of when you look at it,
Natasha taking over earrings.
Yeah. That was pretty high.
But, but so, so, um, so, uh,
anyway, that's it. That's
where the idea came from.
We had to pitch it. We pitched
it to Adam TV. They never,
we've pitched it to Adam TV.
They didn't know about the, uh,
they didn't mention the weigh ins thing.
Uh,
we made the fucking thing
and then immediately a few
people posted links to the
Wayans brothers and it's like God fucking
damn it as it really, really similar.
Cause I, I saw the movie but
I barely remember it. I think
that it's, uh, it's the,
it's the exact same, it's the
exact same device, which is, uh,
disassembling a woman,
but the endings totally different.
And the point of the
things totally different.
But to me what was really surprising and
intense about it was that some people
like really use that against me.
And like kind of like a really angry
fucking way on Twitter and youtube.
Have you been at like,
I didn't even know this APP.
I got some like shitty
messages from people,
but it's like if I'm going to
steal, right? If I'm going to steal,
I'm going to steal something.
I'm going to steal a sketch.
I'm going to steal fucking something.
You know what?
I'm not going to steal it from,
I'm not going to steal it from a
fucking Wayne's movie. You know,
like it's so obscure. It's probably
easier to hide. I'm going to get you.
Sucka is one of the most popular.
You have to, you have to consider it.
It is possible that your might have it in
your head and that you forgot. Oh well,
sure, of course. But that shit
happens to me, all that man.
But here's the thing. A lot of a
lot of jokes are a form of math.
It's like an equation. If you take
up some mess, it's an equation.
And if you break that equation down,
it has natural logical
connections in that equation.
And a lot of comedic minds are going to,
if you give them a premise,
they're going to come up with a
parallel thing. Unfortunately though,
you saw that other one
first. Yes. Factors.
It could have been juiced in my brain,
but I still though there it is like a,
Wayne's has got a transvestite,
I think it's a transvestite.
She appears hot at first and he takes
her apart and she's not hot as I recall
from it. He flees and that's
it. You know what I mean?
It's like it is the same court.
It's not the same thing.
It's like I'm fucking making,
I'm making,
you can't really defend it though
because it is exactly the same joke.
You know what I'm saying?
Like if someone was,
someone stole the joke from you but then
just twisted it into that and I know he
didn't steal it. That would be no,
there'd be no, you know there's like,
there's like no excuse. You can't
say, well I did it differently.
Of course you thought of it
under me and I fucking do it.
It's there on the Internet.
There's nothing I do about it.
And like you're not even Mexican.
My name is nay know man. I did some,
you know what I'm saying though?
It's like it's like it
parallel thinking is just,
it's unavoidable what it is.
You got to go, Oh shit, I
didn't, whoops. Listen to me.
I'm going to steal your
fucking sketches from now on.
I've made the decision and said
that someone will cut that.
Edit that part.
I don't unleash the hackers Joe.
They're going to cut out that part. You
just fucked up. Really fucked up. Yeah.
You said something you should never say.
Why?
Say Rude mean things and pretend that's a,
that's a tired form of common.
It can be fucking funny dude. The soup.
I did the soup this morning. That
show's funny, dude. I did not know.
They had a bunch of really funny sketches
where they were making fun of the
chicks are high. We're real
housewives. I was stone cold sober.
They were making fun of real
housewives of Beverly Hills.
Like one of the crazy chicks is kind of
cracked out and the show this one of the
writers as how hilarious version
of this check. Like I had to,
I just guessed by seeing it.
It was hard to hear because
it was really loud in there,
but I asked her like right away,
I was like,
that's like girlfriend real house while
she's like, yeah, and I high fived her.
It was like really funny shit man. That
Joel Mchale Dude, he's fucking funny.
He's got a great delivery and the
writers are really funny, man.
They had some funny shit on
Kim Kardashians and dude,
I watched this one show,
this access morning show where this guy,
they were goofing on it.
It's on tonight's episode.
You have to watch this because
you can't believe this is real.
This guy is reading from his blackberry
and he's talking about his help,
his Mexican help. We gave them a chance
to serve the other day, you know,
we've never served before and here you
go, here's your shot. Oh my God, dude,
it's so gross.
And then he reads the guys text in broken
English. Oh me leg shaking all day.
Ah, reads it in like a
Mexican accent. Ah Dude.
It's like you watch it and go my God,
someone pull that guy aside and
give him a mushroom trip. Yeah.
Someone give that dude a mushroom trip
and a mirror and sit them in a room and
tell him to think about as the life of
fuck man. Yeah. It's pretty disturbing.
This as it's so clueless.
Again here I'm doing it.
It's just so clueless.
It's like so weird that you don't,
you don't think that people are
gonna find that really gross. Yeah.
It really makes me believe in the idea
that like there's like two species
happening right now.
Like humans are differentiating and like
some humans are jumping away from the
uh, what, what most humans are.
I think some people are splitting away
cause like for me to be in a mind state
where I thought like that or I acted like
that or I read someone's texting and,
and, and like some stereotypical
Mexican accent to humiliate them.
If I was for me to be new one,
thank you. Assuming I would have to,
I think I'd have to have a head injury
and it imagine if I started doing that,
you'd be authentically worried about,
you'd think I'd had a breakdown or this
is how this person lives every day of
their fucking life. So it's like,
what is that? Who, what kind?
What kind of being is that? Is that,
that's a human, I know it's a human,
but it's not the same kind of human I am.
That's a different kind of human
that's a full of shit human.
That's a full of shit human. That's a,
I don't know what it is. How old is it?
How old is that thing?
How old is that guy?
He's in his thirties so this is a guy in
his thirties he's managed to get to his
thirties and he still like that nothing's
knocked him off the path. He's never,
you know, when you see someone
like that, you know a few things.
You know that he's never
smoked pot probably.
It's probably definitely never taken acid.
Never eaten mushrooms,
probably has never
heard really good music.
And he's like,
he's like one of those salamanders.
It never really goes to the transformation
because the water never reaches a
certain alkaline level. Yeah. That's what
he is, man. You know, you ever hear those?
There's certain, there's certain animals
that never met a morphosis. Yeah,
the word metamorphosize.
There are certain animals that if the
conditions are incorrect or if there's
pollution in the environment,
all kinds of different factors
have to be taken into account.
Otherwise they won't make the connection.
He's like a puppy that's eyes didn't open,
her ears didn't open. You know, it's,
it's eyes stayed fucking shut.
It's a fucking,
it's just silly hippie argument that
everybody needs psychedelics better.
You know, it's not everybody. I'm not
saying everybody needs them, but God damn,
a lot of people could use them. A lot
of this if they would just study, um,
and they would just distribute
them through experts.
Imagine what this world would be like if
we had centers where you could go as a
young man to have a psychedelic
experience and get a broader view of the
universe.
And someone takes you in and they do
blood work on you and make sure you're
healthy.
And then they sit you down and you watch
documentaries and you take a class and
when you graduate from the class and the
class is all about pharmacology and the
way that different things interact
with your body and when the,
when you're done with this class,
you feel educated and you feel like you
can make your own decision whether or
not you want to try this and if you do
want to try it then they have a ceremony
and every kid goes in there and you
all with proper meditation techniques,
proper education as to what the,
the history of the use of these substances
is and the history and the anecdotal
evidence that it may have been responsible
for the actual birth of religion.
That this might be what
religion is all about.
It might be psychedelic experience.
If we could have that,
we can have communities
where we did that well.
You'd have a big giant football field
fill of people that are doing mushrooms
and are putting out positive energy
and are there and are balanced healthy
people that want to unite together as a
species and want to embrace each other.
And help each other and
no one ever get greedy,
but let's all work together
and do this together.
And you could have a football field
filled with people doing this.
A stadium filled with people doing
this. Yeah. That would fix the world.
And it sounds ridiculous.
It sounds like you're saying
mushrooms would fix the world.
What would do it better? What? What
could possibly have that effect?
Education education doesn't
necessarily get through.
Your subconscious education doesn't
necessarily get through your programming
side. Education doesn't necessarily get
through anything in your life. That's,
that's really ingrained as a
behavior pattern. It doesn't always,
you can tell people all day like Brian
that cigarettes caused cancer and this
silly, goofy [inaudible] cigarettes
probably more than mushrooms. No, no,
it wouldn't. Mushrooms would
do it better than anything.
Sex is just in is no enlightenment
involved in that, Brian. It's silly.
The psychedelic experience itself is
important. You need to be humbled.
It's not just everybody fuck everybody
and feel good about it. Yeah.
We've talked about this before when
Duncan was design in like, you know,
that might be good for like five
out of 10 people and the other five,
they're so terrified they're not
going to ever leave the house again.
This is not necessarily the case because
if it was done correctly through some
sort of a shamanically center where they
actually evaluated people and, and, and,
you know,
and taught them and educated them,
he'd probably be able to weed out
the people were fucked up and the Pr,
I'd be like, dude, reality itself is
a little fucking slippery for you.
Maybe you should not be doing this.
Maybe we should look into like
Ritalin for you. Maybe we should,
you know what I'm saying? I mean,
sure, I'm a lot of people or 100% anti,
uh, antidepressants. They're
like, fuck that dude.
You're ruining your brain chemistry.
Fuck that dude.
Don't let them change your brain.
I know several people where it's literally
changed their life for the better and
save their life. Maybe even, I know
several people, so I would never say that.
I would never say that.
Well, man, no know. No
fucking, I mean the thing is
there's no rules. It's like you.
This is the main rule is it's this is
your incarnation and you get to do what
you want with it.
The idea is to like as much
as you can expand and your,
your levels of happiness in your awareness
so that you can feel connected and,
and good in this existence and
there are a lot of tools to do that.
Some of the tools take a long fucking
time do and I think like when Mckenna was
talking about mushrooms being the
most obvious tool to transform the,
to create like a huge wide scale
transformation on the planet,
he recognized that there's not a lot
of time. That's what he was thinking.
It's not like we've got a ton of fucking
time to create like meditation temples
or to spread good information
or to spread some new religion.
There's no time for that shit.
You would if you really wanted to
transform these weird people who worship
invisible,
homophobic child sacrificing God's.
If you wanted to transform people who
feel comfortable dropping bombs on other
people,
then the quickest way to do it would be
to give them a substance that allowed
them to connect to each other end of the
earth and to develop an instantaneous
form of empathy unlike anything else.
And then when they came back to,
it'd be much more difficult to think
about, to perceive what they're,
they're weird,
invisible God in the same way.
It's almost like we're
moving in a direction in a
terrible direction because we
don't have the proper ingredients.
So because we don't have
the proper ingredients, we
can't feel what we're doing.
And it's almost like we have a numb arm
probing into the darkness that that numb
arm is scratching the fuck out of reality.
And we don't know because we just can't
feel it. But if we could just feel it,
if we could add this other ingredient
into the mixture that his life, well then,
okay,
now all your pieces are in order and now
you can see and feel what you're doing.
Because the big problem with human
beings when it comes to pollution,
when it comes to destroying the
atmosphere, when it comes to the idea of,
you know what, what these nuclear
disasters, we're not feeling it.
We don't feel it.
We don't feel the damage that we're doing.
We don't feel the garbage
patch in the ocean.
You don't feel anything when you throw,
when you,
when you take a water bottle and
then you toss it in the garbage can,
you did your job. I'm done. I'm done.
I have no connection with this anymore.
And then we don't feel when it goes into
the ocean and becomes a fucking patch
that's floating, that's as big as
Texas. We don't feel that. And that,
that is a lack of a connection.
That's a missing thing.
That's an animal that doesn't
have all of its ingredients.
Well, it's fucking blind.
Yeah. That's what it is.
It's blind and everyone's stumbling
around blind and there their focus is, uh,
on material gain and their
focuses on shit that can,
if it does make you happy, it's a form.
Very transient, temporary happiness.
That's you for a lot of people.
It's usually followed by like depression
and stress. Like people who buy shit,
they can't afford getting the debt to
the banks and become slaves. And so yeah,
man, people are, um,
people have lost the initial original
connection with the spirit of the earth.
You know, if you think about like
Iowasca and the people and um,
drinking it in the jungle and community
with the mind of nature and then getting
direction from the tribe,
from the mind,
and for people to think
this is hippie bullshit.
When scientists first came to the
Amazon and discovered Iowasca,
they tried to call it telepathy dean.
That's what they were going to try to
talk to do. They were going to name it as,
because the fact that they were
able to have these telepathic
experiences with each other and they
all communicated about having shared
visions and shared hallucinations. So
they were going to call it telepathy in,
but it was already the chemical and it
was already named harming or the, the,
you know, whatever the, the
substance was. And so they had to,
they had a stick with the name harming
but we'll, we'll see this substance.
I think uh, for these people has
been a form of spiritual compass.
It points in the right direction. It
reminded sets you straight. It's a,
it's a like a tuning fork for your soul.
But it's amazing that talking about
this, how did this happen? Talking about,
this is ridiculous.
Talking about this as absolutely silly.
I feel nervous when we start talking
about mushrooms can change the world.
Cause I'm like who the fuck you know, w
what does this idiot saying? You know,
what can I bounce this? Is he
saying he, while you're compelled,
meanwhile you're compelled to say,
listen, I know it sounds stupid.
I know I'm a goofy look. Fuck I
know him. The fear factor guy,
I know who the hell am I am
barely got through high school.
I went to three years of college
where I halfway paid attention.
But I'm saying that we might
be overlooking one of the
biggest tools that human
beings have ever had for
evolving and developing,
and that might be why the fucking train
is off the tracks and into the woods.
It might be that the animal isn't
balanced and it might be that the animal
literally developed eating all this stuff.
The animal might have become consciousness
and aware from being a savage eating
all this stuff. It might be, you know,
we might have a symbiotic relationship
on this earth with certain plants that
we've made illegal.
We might need them in order
to be aware of our potential,
the potential harm that we can do,
the potential good that we can do.
You have positivity.
There's no mind about it.
The value of positivity is so important
when you're on a substance that is where
all bad trips come from.
All bad trips come from some negativity.
Whether it's a paranoia,
whether it's a fear,
whether it's a bad memory that you
have that you're trying to avoid,
shitty behavior that haunts you,
that you can't correct whatever the
fuck it is that triggers the bad trip.
It's always a negative
thing. Well, what what it is,
is it's what's happening is that when
you're, when you're taking a psychedelic,
you're being given a glimpse at yourself
from a distance that maybe you can't
have an obtained and you, like
meditation will give you that distance.
It gives you a form of
intense mindfulness.
And so all of a sudden
you're able to see, um, the,
I think the root of whatever
pattern your life is becoming.
The root as a feeling.
And that feeling for a lot of
people can be a negative feeling.
And so that's when people say, you know,
I don't like smoking pot, man, cause I,
it makes me get introspective.
I get paranoid and nervous.
It's like no pot is not
making you paranoid.
Pot is showing you the paranoia that
exists deep within you that's causing you
to act fucking weird and causing your,
our relationships to be a little
more adult than they need to be.
And causing your actions to be a little
muted because you're afraid of the
reaction that people are going
to have. Do you? Cause you're a,
you're still stuck in survival.
You want to survive so bad that you're
scared and you've covered that up with
all the different,
whatever clothes you've decided you're
going to wear in this incarnation and
your tattoos or whatever you've learned.
But deep within that,
behind all that for a lot of people is uh,
something that you could easily turn
negative energy. But I think it's, uh,
it's fear, it's fear and that
and psychedelic show you that.
And so the way to trip and he centers
that you're talking about and if they're
really, the centers were there, then
when someone started experiencing, uh,
a difficult trip, then these people would,
instead of getting them away from that,
they in the best way possible, try to turn
the person to like, what is that fear?
Is that fear real?
Cause the joy of a psychedelic is
when you have the balls to go into the
darkness and all of a sudden you realize
that darkness was a complete illusion.
All the darkness and negativity and
Spooky Shit and guilt and fear and crappy
thought was inside you and all the bad
things you thought you've done and all
the things that you feel terrible about.
Secretly you realize that's nothing.
It's an illusion.
The universe loves you.
You're completely embraced
by the entire universe.
You're an incremental part of the
functioning of the cosmos and you're an
incredible, wonderful, perfect fucking
thing. And when you get a glimpse of that,
it's the greatest feeling
ever because you're healed.
Cause that's what true healing is,
man.
True healing is realizing you were never
sick in the first place. True healings.
Realizing you were just, you
just had some fucking, uh, yeah,
a little bit of dust on the windshield,
man. I think you brush it off, you know,
that's, uh, and that's, and that's what
psychedelics do for you. And you know,
what else does that for you?
Really good therapy,
but really good therapy costs a lot of
money and it takes a long fucking time.
You have to be open to it,
open to change and smart.
And you have to have the ability
to recognize your own faults.
Some people just have this weird shield
between them and reality where they've
become successful because they never admit
guilt and they just press forward and
they rationalize every single thing
they do when just press forward.
And that becomes a mindset just as much
as you know what we're talking about.
Yeah. That becomes just
how work is done, you know?
And that's how military his work,
that's the only way they work.
You have to fall into a mindset.
Yeah. Well, yeah, that's how, I mean,
that's the thing. We've, we're all,
we've all fallen into a mindset and a
lot of the fundamentalist Christians,
they've fallen into these
rituals and patterns,
but they don't have a
real connection anymore.
So they're faking it or they're actually
just like taking cues from like really
charismatic lunatics.
Wouldn't it be awesome if the military
really was our bravest and boldest who
wanted to protect us
and who are led by the,
the most moral and intelligent
people on the planet.
These really, truly were heroes.
And in case some shit goes down,
they're never puppets.
They're only heroes.
There's no doubt whatsoever that they're
only doing the right thing when that'd
be beautiful. Yeah. They'd
be like celebrities when
that'd be beautiful. You know,
they should be, they re most of them
really want to be heroes. You know,
most of the really want to protect.
It's the people that are putting
them there was, are the problems.
The people that are pointing you in
that goes, those are the bad guys.
Go get them. I'll be over here with a
pencil to write down how many a kill.
And if you do a good job,
I give you a shiny piece of metal and I
stick it to your fucking chest. Ah, yeah.
It's so fucking sad, man. It's so
sad and disturbing and it's like,
it's, it's so easy to get
caught up in, in that, you know,
it's so easy to get caught up
in the macro, uh, of, of the,
of the darkness that's in the world.
But man,
I think that the trick is to like only
spend a little time on that and spend
more time fucking working on a real
basic things in your life that you can do
right now to like, um, to make
things a little better. Like tickets.
A lot of people will focus on Kim
trails when they need to be focusing on
stopping smoking.
Like I had a person
describe Kim trails to me,
smoking a fucking Marlboro
light talking about, man,
they're fucking drop in this shit on us.
That's sickening. US making us stupid.
It's like, dude, you know, you're
inhaling, you're inhaling cancerous smoke,
uh, created by fucking
corporation that's making money.
It's making money off of healing. Healing
cares about some fucking Kim trails,
brother, you got to
stop smoking. You like,
that's probably way worse it many more
people are dying from cigarette smoke.
They're dying from chem trails. Yeah,
that's so silly. So those are the steps.
But people,
it's a really simple thing to do.
You get caught up in the macro
instead of being like, you know what?
Here's the thing you can try instead
of worrying about Kim trails,
why don't you fucking get a good recipe
book of like raw recipe book trading raw
for a few days and see if that makes you
feel better. Cut Out some fucking, uh,
cut out eating processed food for a few
days, not forever, just for a few days.
And the issue is
a lot of them are really misinformed
and they really do believe that there's
this constant aerial bombardment.
But one of the reasons why they believe
it is because they have done some
chemical spraying on people and
they've done it against people's will.
It's a fact. Sure. You
know, it's not, it's,
I don't believe it's happening every day.
I think a lot of what people
are seeing is called con trails.
It's a natural thing that happens when
jet engines encounter moisture in the
atmosphere.
It was explained to me by a pilot.
Yeah.
But let's go fight the chem trail pilots
when we've got a clear head because we
haven't been eating shitty food and,
uh,
and when we feel like fit
because we've been exercising,
that's when we can start waging the real,
yeah.
Oh wait,
my point is,
my Pi is the reason why they believe
that there's chem trails is because there
have been chem trails. They're really
happened. The government has experimented.
I have no doubt. I don't
think they're doing it all
the time, but it has happened.
Sure. There's not only hasn't had,
hasn't happened, but in certain states,
I'm like, God was at Georgia.
I forget what state it is.
Um, anyway, the point is that it's,
it's literally like written into
insurance laws. Like there's,
there's things about, you
know, like chemicals spraying
that like a, you know, you,
you insure against, I believe I'm, I'm,
you know, I'm, I'm speaking out of, uh,
out of hand right here because I
don't know the exact details of it.
It seems a little blurry in my mind
right now while I'm trying to pull it up.
But I remember whatever it was,
this little piece of legislation,
whether it was a all you know, something
about insurance or not, whatever it was,
it was written down.
It was essentially saying that there
will be weather controlled experiments
there. They will do something
to alter the weather.
And we know that in Abu Dhabi they
made it rain 50 times last year.
Wow.
So they essentially made it rain
once a week with a plane flying over.
I think it's aluminum oxide
and bury him or something.
I forget what it is that they,
they spray into the air,
but they spray it and somehow or another,
it makes these clouds form and it makes,
it makes rainfall in the desert in
Abu Dhabi. Man, it's amazing. I mean,
it's incredible.
So if we know that they're doing that
well they gave people so he didn't lose
learn how to do it over there is my point.
They probably practiced some shit
here and they, they, you know,
and they probably been doing it here in,
in small doses for a long time, you know.
Well.
Yeah,
I mean like I eat pretty much anything
that I've found out about the government
doing. I wouldn't be that surprised,
like know no matter you say syphilis,
you're talking about the Tuskegee.
Yeah, they fucking blasted Vicki.
What is the exact details of that? They
expected. A bunch of books asked me.
I think what I was was they told some
that they're being treated and they
weren't being treated with any medication.
They lied to them to see the
degenerative effects of the disease.
Dude, on this century of the
self thing there, there's uh,
there were interviewing the fucking main
psychologists for the CIA during the
60s and the 70s and he's just talking
about all the shit they did with LSD
experiments where they like
white people's paths away.
They would blast you on as it and give
you a lecture shock therapy to try to
fucking or raise your personality.
Like they've done all kinds of crazy shit
and they probably are continuing to do
crazy shit.
And there was a really good chance that
when you're driving through any public
space,
you're being bombarded with subliminal
messages and all the billboards that
you're seeing that are turning
you into a mat, into a,
into a fucking rabid consumer that
only wants to eat and drink and a,
it doesn't ever want to think about
anything more than getting a raise and
getting drunk at night. And it may
be that this is all intentional,
but what I'm saying is if you
worry about that too much,
then you're not going to do your dishes
and you're going to have roaches in your
fucking apartment and then you're going
to start feeling depressed and then you
get really caught deep in the trap to,
to the first thing you have to
do is like come to your senses.
That's the first thing.
And the easiest way to come to your
senses is to like stop taking the fucking
stop putting the pills in your mouth. You
know, like movies about mental asylums.
Inevitably the hero will always start
putting the pillows under his bed and have
that little line of pills under his bed.
And all of a sudden he's come to his
senses again and he can plan his escape.
But until you fucking stop taking the
pills, you can't plan your escape.
So it's like, okay, yeah,
maybe there's some fucked up
shit happening in the world,
but you got to stop smoking.
Maybe there's some fucked up
shit happening in the world,
but you should run a few times
a week. Maybe there's fucked
up shit happening in the world,
but you need to take a shower,
brush your teeth,
floss good so that you're
get clean and healthy.
And then when you have
more of a clear head,
then you can start making real moves and
really analyzing what may be happening.
But until then you're all foggy and
fucked up. When you see Michael Moore,
don't you want to go, dude? Yeah,
forget about the government. Yes,
take care of yourself.
So you got to deal with a fucking
tear at tyranny and yourself.
You've got to deal with the fucking
demonic senators and congressmen inside of
you that keeps telling you to eat a
fucking cheeseburger and a bag of Doritos
before you go to bed.
Stop those fucking people first veto
there bills that are coming from inside
your heart. Is that a self
hate thing? Is that an,
I don't care about my own safety thing.
It's just like I'm obsessed with my goals.
I'm obsessed with my interest.
I don't care about my own personal safety
to the point where I'm just going to
over feed myself. Yeah,
well rational thinking, just
completely given to impulse.
It's a fuck. What did, I mean? I think
what it is is it's like a, a row.
It's a literal Rut.
It's like you've been going in this
circle for so long that you can't get out.
You're like a truck.
His wheels are stuck in the mud.
So you just stuck in this endless pattern.
That's what we do.
Humans get stuck in patterns, you know?
And so the idea is to get knocked.
You gotta knock yourself
out of that pattern somehow.
And the quickest way to do
that is with a psychedelic.
If you don't want to take a
psychedelic than just seriously start.
I know that sounds super hippy.
Start fucking juicing. Drink healthy,
eat healthy, just eat healthy. I don't
care why you eat, eat fucking healthy,
fighting mixed juice. Three days.
Vitamix. Vitamix is way better.
Yeah. I just, I got this fucking a,
it's the best way to force yourself
to eat a ton of vegetables.
Do you just drink it? You know, you
think about like how much I eat.
I have a one big cucumber,
like six stalks of celery,
five big giant leaps of Kale and a big
chunk of ginger and a pair and I just
blast all that shit. There's no way I'm
going to sit and eat all that ginger.
I love Ginger and as you can
throw in there, that's good man.
Fucking Jalapeno.
It's so fucking good.
I've had marked drop and Jalapenos in the
blender with almost everything I made.
I made a fucking chocolate Mousse the
other day and my calendar and I threw a
Jalapeno in there. Delicious.
Kind of like spicy chocolate. Why?
You can put in fucking anything. You can
put it in like you can put anyway dude,
you need to show in the food. You can
do anything with the Jalapeno Jalapeno,
my asshole today. Chop. What does
a slap chop. You could be as flat
and the slap chop. I gladly do it.
You'd be like Dunkin, the Jalapeno guy.
You could have a book.
I'm dunking Jalapeno guy
showing you [inaudible] please.
Crazy.
I put it in my baby out the Jalapenos
inside toothpaste kills bacteria that he's
enlisted marine can't get to and this
is like an ancient way that the Mayans
used to clean their teeth. They cheat
on Habanero peppers. I love it. I love
imagine if that's true. If it's like
you'd kills all the poison. Why Jalapeno?
Well that's isn't that one of the things
that Japanese people like to use Wasabi
with Sushi because was Sabi
apparently has an effect on any,
any sort of bacteria that you might,
yeah, I mean it's fucking blowtorch.
Hardcore snort Wasabi. Good luck. I
always fuck that up to you man. I always
like a giant bite it to love it.
I love Wasabi.
I ate up a whole fucking jar
of Habanero salsa last night.
I had chips in this big jar of like
from the moment I ate the first bite,
I was like, God damn, that shit is
hot. I couldn't stop. I was sweating.
You never get fire shits or
anything. Oh yeah, go. All right.
I know I'm going to kill myself.
Take it to, I'd do a fucking,
I get in a horse stance.
Why don't you just think of that as a
member of the movie come through when the
flaming pots in front of them and one
sign as a dragon and the other side is a
tiger and he picks up
the pot with his form.
I don't think it's a coincidence that
I have a tiger on one arm and a fucking
dragon on the other and I was a
fan of the Kung Fu show. Okay,
well, well how about that?
I'm going to get you sucker.
I stole that. I stole that
without even thinking about it.
I'm just saying, man, I'm admitted. I
stole my toe like my tattoos from Kung Fu,
but I think that's what the
motivation was. Oh Hey, confidence.
Motivation.
You hit Kong theory.
There's some Kung Fu guys mad at me.
He said that the guard is actually called
baby monkey. It's called baby monkey.
It's hilarious. It's really fun. When do
you find that? Because I that Eddie Eddie,
we'll send it to me. Eddie Bravo sent
it to me. It's a fucking hilarious.
You want to play it all right play.
I'll tell you what, what part it,
cause I tweeted it. What part? The guy
starts talking shit about me but it's,
he's one of those dudes and
this is, this is truth. Listen,
there's a lot of people that got upset
at me because I said things about Kung Fu
and there's a lot of people,
cause I said come food is kind of bullshit
and a lot of it is just like a bunch
of people practicing things. Like if I
come at you like this, what would happen?
I would move to the side and it would
attack this way. It is, it's, it's,
it's like a one step,
you know,
in taekwondo we still have the things
called one steps. And what it is is,
you know,
you would throw a kick and the other
guy would counter and when it was his to
him imprint into your mind what to
do once you start sparring and then
eventually you start sparring.
But when you start sparring,
that's when techniques
really get weeded out.
And that's when you understand what is
the most effective use of energy and
force, what techniques work the best, what
techniques are really truly applicable,
and what techniques are really kind
of frivolous and a waste of time.
There's better alternatives will come.
Food never did that.
They didn't have all the sparring,
they didn't,
he didn't know how Kung Fu didn't like
go and enter into an ultimate fighting
championship where it was public and
everybody figured it out and it was spread
out through the Internet.
So there's the debate amongst all the
minds of different martial artists,
whether they're kickboxers are wrestlers.
There is a genuine consensus when
it comes to mixed martial arts.
And that genuine consensus is,
here's the school there,
here's the group of effective techniques.
This is what actually works. Yes,
you can. We'll kick someone in the face.
Absolutely. It's difficult to pull off,
but you can, we'll kick some of the face.
Can you monkey fist them on the nose?
You can,
but that's not the best way to do it.
The best way to do is the Jab and
then one two jab, right? Monkey fist.
Apparently there isn't a monkey first.
Apparently I made it up.
He apparently it's leopard fist.
The guy told me liquid fish is
no monkeyfy sure right days,
no monkey face lab fs. But that's his
style of Kung Fu. Because this dude,
this dudes were also, we're
angry at me. We're talking, man,
I hit you in the face with a monkey
paw. You're going to be upset. You know,
so I'm like, you know, so there's a monkey
park then it must be, it must be real.
So he in his and his style
of martial arts, it's real.
But in this one Kung Fu guy,
it's a leopard Paul.
And that's the only technique that works.
I'm not saying that you,
you shit won't work and it's definitely
better than knowing nothing at all.
But as far as he is the
best thing to practice, no,
there might be some good benefit to it,
but if you want to look at the real
true evolution of martial arts, what it,
what is martial arts with
a martial art is, is uh,
an art where you figure out what is the
best way to attack and disable a trained
killer.
That's what you want to be good at.
You want to be good at
beating trained killers.
You don't want to be good at beating
people don't know what they're doing
because that's what a lot of people are
doing. A lot of martial arts are, it's,
it's your drug developing techniques.
They really will never work.
If you're fighting against Anderson Silva,
you're going to get them off.
There is no best one.
The best one is all the effective
techniques of all the martial arts.
It's tech take downs from wrestling and
judo kicking from karate and Moy Tai Jiu
Jitsu, submissions from
judo and Jujitsu. You know,
there's all these different things.
Leg locks from Samba, all of these,
and you don't have to have, there's
no correct combination of what to use.
Some guys only use a
few of the components,
but they have a very unusual physicality
or they're very good at one of these
aspects of the point where,
especially like a stand up fighter,
like a guy like Anderson Silva,
that's his number one specialty
stand up and he's so good at it.
Every fight start standing up.
So he has an advantage at
the beginning of every fight.
He has an advantage and if
you can get to that spot,
you don't have to be
like the best wrestler.
Like Anderson's not taking people down.
I mean,
I'm sure he could if you wanted to,
but you very rarely see him taking
people down. He just blasts everybody,
you know? So if you can get really good
at certain aspects of it, you know,
there is no exact formula what to do.
But as far as techniques,
there's a general consensus of techniques
that work. You know the basic kicks,
front kicks and round kicks. There's
the crazy ones. Act Kicks, wheel kicks,
there's all this stuff works,
but you know what doesn't work?
What doesn't work is like crane
techniques. When you're standing.
I mean it will work,
but it's better to box.
It's better to curl your knuckles
up and blast them in the face.
It's better to kick them, you know,
and the kick them correctly the best.
You got to go to a certain,
I'll tell you when to go.
I think it's two minutes and four seconds.
Joe Rogan. Yeah, well MMA countable you.
Monkey non-fan, Marco Locke,
nonsense martial arts.
There's no monkey
monkey,
but I understand Joel type is saying,
oh come cool. If not,
then you're fucked man.
The funny thing is Joe used the word
monkey to lamb and marketing come home.
He's really don't know.
No one used the monkey
technique more than the MMA.
This lake where epic,
this would call baby monkey
showing the garden done.
You will feed baby monkey whack,
whack,
whack a leg while my nine month
waistline and up back be 5% of the time.
And that is exactly what MMA,
you think the baby monkeys,
65% of the time inside that cage.
Now who is the monkey here?
I have no problem of the work monkey.
You as low as eight is
a good cat like mine.
Monkeys painting Ahmad monthly spending on
MMA fighter are strong and tough,
but don't be confused just because they
do full contact then they might be real
martial artist.
Do you think gangster do full contact
fighting and they must be all wheel
martial artist? Absolutely
not. Okay. Hold on. I simply,
teenage street fighter.
I think we might be getting trolled.
That feels like a troll as I'm watching
this under the influence of the sacred
plant might disguise obviously
reading off of something. Yeah,
he's reading off to the side. I'm
listening to it. I'm like this guy.
It doesn't sound like it makes sense. And
then when he hits that Armbar God dude,
he does that so slow.
That's a guy who's not a grappler at all.
He was on a grappler.
That guy doesn't know what he's doing.
One of the things was called monkey
baby monkey. Big Monkey. Awesome.
Well that might be a technique
we very well might be,
but it also might be a troll
was totally like a trail.
That's why he mentioned my name cause
he knows I'm stupid and I bite. Yeah,
I just went right after it and he wanted,
he got me the fuck you and Sam trip,
baby monkey.
Good work man.
I could get that for a licensed
play. Baby Monkey, big monkey.
A lap at Winco with a wound with
this technique is called baby monkey.
It's brilliant.
Whoever
did that. Congratulations. You did a good
job. Well done. If it is real, Sarah,
please come to 10th planet,
10th Planet Jiu Jitsu in Los Angeles
and I love to try out your baby monkey.
See if I could pass your baby monkey.
I went to kiss your baby monkeys.
I Bet I can pass your baby monkey. I'm
just saying right now. I mean I'm no,
I'm no killer.
I'm know Marcella Garcia,
but I watched your role and I'm pretty
sure I could pass your baby monkey.
That's all I'm saying.
Challenge your baby monkey on me and
then I'm going to get side control.
I Bet I'm going to get side
control. Yeah. And this is hot.
I don't give a fuck bro.
I don't give a fuck dude.
I'm going to want to try that
wack ass baby monkey. I mean,
I'll show him what's up.
10 plants, Jujitsu Bitch.
And you know the other thing that
music, like if there in that video, Joe,
here's my thing, it's funny, but if he's,
if he's serious. Yeah. If he's serious,
it's offensive to me because you know,
if he's serious, I don't think yes,
but if he is serious,
it's offensive to all martial arts because
that guy doesn't know what he's doing.
The way he's hitting that arm
bar. I'm like, Jesus Christ.
Or now he's hitting an armbar though.
The one thing though is he's hitting it
like our Kung Fu guy because that's what
the Kung Fu guys, that's what I have a
problem with. The Kung Fu guys react.
They do techniques,
they practice techniques as if the other
person isn't going to react like the
grab you and pull you like this and
attack the liver from this position.
You know, and they have all
this nonsense like, well,
how do you know the guys still gonna
be there? I know you have a game plan,
but it seems to me like you're,
this is like you're getting way ahead
of yourself. You're stupid dude.
Can I ask you a martial arts question?
Sure. This happened a very long time ago.
I used to work at a summer camp and um,
they would have like a martial
artists come every, uh,
every term till like demonstrate
martial arts to the kids.
And he was just some guy from
like some local Dojo or something.
And so he would get a kid and he, his
fucking head man, he didn't like had it,
he'd been shot like five times in the
head. He'd been, he'd been in Vietnam,
he was really intense fucking guy and
shot in the head, really heat something.
He took something to that, his head at
it like shrapnel, my head strap. So yeah,
shot and had, probably not. So he, um,
he bring a kid down and he do this thing
where he held the kid's wrist and he'd
slap him in the neck,
knocked the kid out,
and then like they'd get the
kid to stand back up again.
And it was something I've always
liked from time to time. Wonder, like,
what the fuck was that? Is that real?
Well, how hard did he hit the kid?
I just like a slap, you know? It was
like, it didn't sound really hard. No.
Then it's bullshit. So the kid was
just like, what is that hypnosis? Why?
It's a lot of, is the power of suggestion.
A lot of people, a lot of people do,
and this is a very uncomfortable subject.
I think a lot of people
have very weak brains.
Just like some dudes have little dicks.
You know,
you ever seen a guy in a movie and
like it has a little duck. You laugh.
It's so small. You laugh. There's,
there's people, little brains to their,
they have a little Dick. That's what it
is. Their brain just sucks. That sucks.
Yeah. And that's why when you go to
see, didn't you go with me to the,
the Boston comedy connection?
Didn't you see the r rated hypnotists
with me now already went on stage.
Now I didn't see that and see that.
Damn, I wish I thought it was you.
Brian was at you. Were you there when the
r rated hypnotist? No, Muslim and Joey,
but the book.
But you know when you watch an r
rated hitmen to show rest in peace.
Mr. Frank Santos, who was the guy that
I'm discussing in a longtime friend, um,
very hilarious already hypnotists,
but he would go onstage and
he bring people and they
would sit down and with the,
the smallest amount of work, I mean close
rise. Concentrate on what I'm saying.
I'm not a concert and my breath, I'm
going to three, two, one. When I hit one,
you're going to think you're with Madonna,
Madonna,
like his backward McDonald's hot McDonna's
underneath you and she's naked and
you're going to have you, we, we inside a
Madonna on account of one on three, two,
one. Where are you John? Oh,
you see this guy who is just a normal
person? It was just 1520 seconds ago.
He was just sitting there with
his eyes closed and now this,
this guy really thinks he's
fucking Madonna. Like wash
the guy, come in his pants.
I watched a guy come in his pants.
Frank Santos told him to come
and his pants and he's like, oh,
you're not going to be able to hold her.
You gonna come. Oh, and the guy goes, ugh.
The guy came in his fucking
pants. He was embarrassed. He was,
it wasn't an act. He
wasn't an actor. He wasn't,
there's no way an actor could
be that good. I mean, it
was this, it was the, the,
the look of confusion on his face when
frank cleared him up and sent him out of
it and went back to his friends,
have to be at scratch act or to come to
make friends with him and do you came
your fucking pants. Everybody was going
nuts. He went back to sit with his group.
He didn't believe what had happened. He
was like, no, I knew what I was doing.
I wouldn't do it. He was the
fuck you did dude. Like the,
they go into this trance. I don't know
how it works. It doesn't work on me.
This work I do.
It's like an old magic trick where like
that dude was a really a paid actor.
That's part of what that
kind of hypnotism is. I mean,
there's different kinds of hypnotism is
there's hypnotism where you can sit down
and someone can put you in a very
relaxed state where you are, uh,
cleared of all your distractions and
cleared of all your connections to the
world.
And they talk you through this.
They talk you into a mindset where you're
open to suggestion and where you're
open to objectivity.
There's a, that's a type of,
of hypnotism and it's a legitimate type
of hypnotism and it does get you to a
certain state, but you're conscious
of what's going on the whole time.
He's not getting you to suck his dick.
He's not telling you there's
an elephant in the room.
It's going to cut your head off.
You know,
he's not freaking you out with
bullshit and nonsense and trickery.
He's just kind of guiding
your thought pattern.
But there's also a type of hypnosis
that doesn't work on everybody,
but it does work on dummies
and that dummy hypnosis. You,
if you're a guy like Frank Santos,
you can get people to think they're
having sex with Madonna in a stage on a
stage in front of 300 strangers.
You really can do it. I've seen it.
I don't understand it,
but I don't understand people that are
allergic to peanuts either. I don't,
I don't think the human body
is, it's not uniform. There's,
there's some people that have a weird
glitch. It's like, you know, some,
some cell phones you can fucking
hack into them, you know,
so when somebody else's cell
phone, but see, here's the thing.
So if Frank Santos can make a man and
Boston blast in his pants from four
seconds of mild hypnosis,
think what the fucking CIA can do to you
if they've been studying this shit for
like 15 or 20 years.
No. Let's see. The sacrifices they've
made to in the, in the, you know,
the name of progress when it comes to Lsd,
they dosed a whole fucking village in
France, including women and children.
They dose their bread. You
know about that story? Nope.
The freedom of Information Act, it was,
it was revealed like, I don't know shit,
I want to say 2009 but I don't remember
when the exact date it was revealed,
but the CIA did a fucking LSD experiment
in a small French town and dose the
entire town. Here, I'll look it up.
CIA dosed French town acid.
Yeah.
Dude,
they didn't give a fuck here at the
CIA dosed entire village with LSD.
Yup.
Incredible story.
Back in the 50s and entire
French village suddenly went mad.
It was not as prevalent.
The previously thought due to an Erg
got fungus contamination of the village
bake his bread, says
investigative journalists, HP
Aberly, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah. Instead, it was part of a CIA
secret mind control experiment with LSD.
In other words, the CIA put a French
village on acid to study them.
Wow. Wow. And by the way, they're
responsible for the fucking unit monomer.
Do you ever watch that
documentary that yeah. Yeah.
He was a part of the fucking LSD
experiments and Harvard. Yeah.
G W W what a shocker.
You think there's a coincidence in
that the one guy gets so crazy that he
decides to make enough money
as a mathematics professor
to fund his attack on
all the technology of the world
and the way he's going to do this,
to send bombs through the mail at
people that are creating things.
Well, see, that's the thing.
That's why you have to begin to ask
yourself which components of my belief
system or if things that I've arrived to
naturally from my observation of nature
and which parts of them are placed in to
me by a system designed to turn people
into consumers. And I think
that more often or not, uh,
a greater percentage of your personality
then you would like his is not you at
all.
It's a tapestry that's been cleverly
woven by a system designed to make people
feel totally normal,
spending the majority of their lives
driving in a commute and working in a shit
job and being tired all the time.
First of all,
let me just say that apparently this is a,
this theory of the French
town as a also questioned.
Some people don't agree with it.
Some people don't think it's true.
Well they were dosing fucking ah,
they, they, they deal some soldiers,
soldiers and they were dosing horrors
were dropping it into their John's drinks.
That was a rolling stone
article, but yeah, yeah, yeah.
[inaudible] what the fuck was it called?
How's operation? Midnight Climax.
That's what it's called.
The CIA ran a brothel. Oh.
In San Francisco. In
New York. And they, uh,
they dose the Johns because they find
any willing participants and their LSD
studies.
Cause unfortunately the gay people like
Pepsi bottles full of Shit and blew
their fucking brains out. You know,
they weren't sure the dosage. You know,
when I first started
fucking around with us,
she wanted to know what would happen.
Yeah. The shots, the whiskey Sun.
God do a shot of whiskey and you
actually do want a shot of acid.
You know what Mckenna
described molecularly? He said,
LSD has the power of an aunt that could
disassemble the entire statue of Liberty
in 30 minutes. He was, that's
molecularly, that's what it's like.
That's how strong acid is the past.
But imagine you like getting in in a
town and you don't know you're having it.
So a lot of people that don't know,
that's the number one theory
of the Salem witch trials.
The Salem witch trials has to do with
the first thing that they were saying
about as previously thought it was a,
an Erg got fungus contamination
of the village, Baker's bread.
Apparently what happens is
when you have a crop of, um,
like wheat or whatever the fuck it is,
any, any kind of grain and um, you,
it freezes if they have
a frost and then it,
when it thaws out apparently is
susceptible to certain funguses.
Like it fucks up the plant and the plant
gets contaminated sometimes by certain
funguses and forgot when it contaminated
the, you know, when they, they've,
they've like done core samples of this,
this point in time, you know, whenever,
you know,
the 1600 whenever the Salem witch trials
were and they found like these late
frosts that they think could have
attributed to ergo infection and then they
found evidence of Ergo.
So they're pretty sure that when all
these people went mad and crazy and they
started burning women, you know, it's
just like they just, they just went,
they were whacked out on,
on their bread and they thought
that someone was poisoning them.
It really did think it was which class,
which makes much more sense than,
you know, like it was just a religious
thing. It was just, which is possible.
I mean, we, we've seen horrible things
done in the name of religion, but when,
as a whole group of them and it's all in
one area and all those other pieces are
in place,
there's a fucking psychedelic compound
that makes you lose your marbles and it's
in your bread. Of course. That's what
happened. I mean, it only makes sense.
Why is this? Why is this one
area think it's bewitched? Yeah,
because they were right. There was, there
was this fucking chemical bewitching.
You know,
they just blamed it on the wrong people.
They didn't blame it on the bread. Well,
how would they know? How will they know?
Yeah, so these crazy ass, I'll start that.
These, these women were witches. You know,
they'd look at, I'm all paranoid
just talking about just the one.
She's doing this to me.
You know, really mean.
He's seeing giant mice attacking him with,
you know, invisible swords. You know,
you've seen all kinds of
crazy shit everywhere he goes.
It's really, yeah. Strange
to think that books have been
written about how to torture witches.
There's a book. Have you ever heard of
the Malleus Melissa Kerem? Jesus? No.
Look that up. The Hammer, what is it
called? It's called, it's called them,
I believe the Malleus. [inaudible]. It's
called the hammer of the witches. Look.
That shit appetite, Karen. Yeah,
I think it's Melissa. Karen.
I'm probably butchering the name, but
if you put that in, you should find it.
And if that hasn't worked,
put in Dude fucking in and it's amazing.
I knew spelled the shit out of
it and it's still the found,
it's the way to spell correctly folks
is the Malleus, m a l l E. U. S.
Is that an l? L l. L. E. U. S. Uh,
and Melika carried them Mel if a carrier
Kerem Melvin Kerem [inaudible] is m,
a, l e, F, I, C, a, r, u, m.
And just get an approximation and
then Google and just finds it for you.
[inaudible] of the
witches. That's incredible.
It's a book that was written
during the inquisition. Oh my God.
It's available on Amazon. God love
the Internet. I'm going to order that.
Watch this. Watch this while
we're doing the podcast. Boom.
Bitches ordered that shit son.
1996.
I'm on dope was up. I just
bought an awesome book after
the witch trials though.
It, it, they,
they still were eating
the same bread though.
Wouldn't they still be crazy? You
know, like if that was true, no,
because it didn't last for very long.
It's only for one season. So you know,
for one season or whatever season that
this happens where they get this green
and this grant is infected with the Ergo.
That's the season where
everyone's jacked and fucked up.
But Mckinnon's theory was,
was I think more that it wasn't
that these people are freaking out.
This isn't mcallister was a mainstream,
uh,
like I guess it was archeologists is that
call archaeology when you only go back
a couple hundred years. History
that can be archived. I don't know.
I think there's a difference between
historians and archaeologists.
I'd love to know, but I, there,
I've read Mckenna talking about how,
um, the getting rid of the
witches, it was part of the, uh,
transformation from the into male
dominated culture and that that was the
burning of the witches was
a representation of this
shift from what does he has
a great name for it. Dominator culture
or something. What does he call it?
The shift from the, uh,
the, uh, he was, uh,
from maternal society to Terminal
Matriarchal Mushroom Society Mushrooms.
She's a patriarchy that where the way
that you taught people is through like,
like the God of that society teaches
people by beating the shit out of them and
punishing them forever. It's not the
way that I'm a mother is supposed to be.
And so the witch trials where the shift
from a one form of nature based religion
into a new form of,
of religion where people
started worshiping the
invisible like free chromophobe
make that possible.
But the other finding I
think was after it was like,
I think it was even after
Mckenna was dead, Mckenna,
I believe.in 2001 I think this was,
I think they discovered this little later.
So it's kind of clear evidence.
I think it's just combinations because
there were, it could be that too.
Then back then who were practicing.
It could be that would have never
killed the witches if it was like a,
a balanced society, they will
just go, oh, you're fucking,
which I'll know you're not. Oh my God.
I was on acid or something, you know,
they wouldn't like get together with
pitchforks and fucking torches. Maybe
it could be they were already pissed off
at checks and then when they got on the
acid or the Irgun rather they'd be like,
well this is a fucking,
this is a perfect time to kill
all these bitches. You know,
it could be that this is the last straw
when you know, it's a weird thing man,
when you know,
the whole idea of happiness and pleasure
is a lot of it revolves around people
wanting to be around you.
And a lot of it revolves around the
opposite sex wanting to be around you.
And for most of us, you know, look,
the reality is most of us are
not that attractive. You know,
there's not that many people that
are really, really attracted to you.
And for a lot of people,
their life is a constant series of
rejections and especially from women guys,
they're dumpy.
They have no self esteem and they'd
get a couple of drinks in them.
And who you think maybe
I'll get a flow could good.
Some of the nurse he like say
something awful and knowing, you know,
like really it's just
like a lack of confidence.
Like people would say
that they're a Dickhead,
but really a lot of it is
like a preemptive attack
because you think eventually
this person is going to destroy your
soul because that's your experience with
relationships. That's your experience
with interacting with women.
Every time you've attempted
to interact with women,
they've let you know
that your pulsive Ooh,
no thank you.
It'll get away.
And that programming just enters into
this guy's definition of what a woman is,
of what you know who you want. You're
the person who brings the bad feelings.
You're the person who brings,
it's horrible, horrible. Sure.
So you get a few drinks and have low
spots where you're pissed and you're
fucking,
all of a sudden you're like using tricks
from the game to try to say shitty
things to girls, to like dis Dell
that discombobulate them in somehow,
like trick them into fucking you instead
of just getting them to have sex with
you because they like you because you're
a good person. You're fucking cool. Well,
I don't think people can realize that
in part of the reason why people can't
realize that as because
people are selfish. You know,
I have a friend and I
who will remain nameless,
but we had a conversation where he was,
uh,
he was getting dumped and he was super
upset about it and he didn't know how to
deal with it. And he was asking me for
advice and I said, do you love this girl?
And he said, yes. And I said, well, if you
love her, you should want her to be happy.
And if her being happy means her being
with another man or another person,
you should respect that and you
should love her still. I go,
this is just a human being and people
break up and I don't hate everyone.
I used to date, in fact with
time, I love all of them.
Even the ones that I
didn't get along with men,
when I look back on every single girl
that I ever dated, I swear to God,
I only will allow the positive thing.
I have some negative stories that
are really funny and I tell them,
but in my mind when I'm
thinking about that person,
I only think about them when I loved
them. I only think about them. What are,
no matter what went wrong, you
know, no matter what, you know what,
what horrible thing was said, you know,
that made the whole thing fall apart.
I re I refuse to define them by that
and I instead define them by their
potential, by what, what they meant
to me when they're at their best.
But it's really fucking hard
to teach people that, man,
it's really hard to over and over again
realize when you fall face first into
the face,
first into the fucking dirt that you
thinking is incorrect and that it's not
empowering and you're not helping
yourself or anyone else. And in fact,
you're devaluing yourself into this
person's eyes because you become desperate
and you have no personal sovereign,
Ted's right.
A man that can't be with
a woman without a woman,
when a woman doesn't want to be with
a man is a repulsive thing. You know,
we've all seen it, man. It
was an episode of fear factor.
We had this week where this,
there was this poor guy
and his wife didn't want to
have nothing to do with them
anymore. They divorced and she was
fucking, you know, just live in her life.
And they were still connected because
they had a kid together and she would just
mock him openly and publicly and she had
no desire to fuck him again and she was
kind of just ready to ready to
make fun of them. And it hurts.
It hurts washing it, man. It
hurts your fucking soul. It
cuts into you, you see it,
and you'd go to this poor fuck.
He doesn't even know.
He's just trapped in
this horrible pattern.
And this person has become
a drug dispenser, a negative
Downer drug is person,
gives them a depressing drug every time
they see them. It's crazy. It's amazing.
It's called, yeah, the bonds of Maya.
That's it. That's my name for it.
Or you get entangled in the illusory
aspect of the universe and you don't even
realize it and then you're
just fucking in pain.
But you're the reason you're in pain.
It's so sad,
but it's real and it's like it's,
it's a plague and,
and, but it's, it's also kind of cool man.
That was kinds of prisons thought prisons
are the best presidents to get into
because you have the key. You
say it out, get out of it though.
But one of the things is you can't be
selfish because if you are a selfish,
always want that person to be with you.
You know,
and this is what I was saying
to my friend. I was like, dude,
she does not want to be with you.
You'll have to accept that.
You have to accept that this is a human
being. And if you love this human being,
you should want this
human being to be happy.
And your definition of love is his only.
He only loved this human being.
If the human being provides you with
the sex drug provides you with the sex
chemical, you can't just accept the fact
that she wants to sex drug from someone
different. Her jeans are compelled
to fuck someone different than you.
And whether it's become because you have
personality shortcomings or physical
shortcomings.
It's not her responsibility.
Her responsibility is to go towards what
she enjoys and what she's attracted to,
but we are so selfish that no one
ever thinks that way, but also, man,
aside from like letting someone have a
happy life and not trying to manipulate
or control them into being stuck with you.
The other thing is it's so much better
for you to be with someone who really
likes you. Kia. My God, the guys who
want to like change a chick, you know,
you grow to love me, my God, dude,
some savage is going to come along
and fuck her in a laundromat. Okay,
that's going to happen.
You can't. You can't.
Everyone needs to be extremely
attracted to each other.
Everyone needs to be extremely well.
There's just in track attracted to each
other's minds, which is personality,
whether it's physical, whatever it is,
they're there. There has to be a real,
because if there's not, if you don't
have one of two things is happening,
either you're not putting that out enough.
You're not a dynamic enough human.
Both with your consciousness or with your
objectivity or with your love or with
your affection or with
your, your, your generosity.
You're not putting out enough working.
And if you're not putting down out enough
people don't want to give it back to
you. So this, this beautiful,
attractive, healthy, vibrant,
generous,
loving person won't be attracted to you
because you don't want to enhance them.
You want to draw and take away from them.
And so you rely on wounded animals and
it's just one more wounded animal after
another wounded animal.
And that's all you ever get because
that's all you're attracting.
You're attracting wounded animals.
Cause those are the only ones that are
stupid enough to fucking fall into your
web. That's true, man.
And also a lot of those
systems that pickup systems
are designed to trap wounded
animals. She's like, exactly. Yeah.
So it's like really just praying the
vulnerable and it's only because the, the,
the value of sexuality, it's such a,
it's a value. It's very important.
Like you need it. Like it will make
you feel better, you know, it will,
it's your medicine. You
got to go, you know?
Yeah, but you know there, there's
get it on like Marvin Gaye Song.
I'm your medicine.
Open up and let me in.
It is a fucking drug man
dough and you're so great.
I can't wait for you to
operate. Boom, boom. Get up.
Let's make love tonight.
Wake up cause you do it right. The
guy was a bad mother fucker. Dude,
he's such a bad motherfucker.
His Dad shot him.
His Dad couldn't deal with the sun.
Just massively eclipsing him in every
possible way as a human, as Dow.
Just a regular guy who is Marvin Gaye,
Marvin Gaye's, a motherfucking Dick,
sling and superstar with a voice that came
from angels. Okay, and who are you? Oh,
you're the guy who fucked his mom. Get in
line, bitch, you're just a normal dude.
You Ain't nothing special compared
to Marvin motherfucking Gaye.
You're a regular guy and you may
have son that's a mother fucker.
You made a psalm that his songs,
they play them without them words in
elevators and people sing along to the
music.
His fucking songs are so good that
when you're in an elevator and a Muzak
version of let's get it on, comes
on, you can hear him saying,
let's get it all. You can
hear it. You can hear it.
He's a bad motherfucker,
dude.
He and printed the consciousness
and this guy couldn't deal with it.
So he shot his own son,
didn't want to play the game.
So he picked up the board and he threw it
away. Yeah. Goodwin couldn't win a game,
unplugged it and plugged the fucking
x bucks, shooting your own kid.
God, I don't care what he did.
You, you fuck someone fucked
up. It has to be you to,
unless your kid is a murderer and unless
your kids coming at you with a fucking
sword and trying to, he's, you know
he's on PCP. Yeah. Okay, I get it.
You got to do what you gotta do.
He and he shouldn't. You know,
he's a threat to the playground.
Kid makes you,
you're automatically a fucking
idiot, right? Oh my God.
Yeah. Something happened,
which is why it's fucking weird.
The story of Jesus.
It's like you're going to send your
fucking kid down to a planet is savage
fucking you don't understand.
He died for our sins. Oh, that,
oh no.
Somehow or another we could still sin,
but we get forgiven if we tell him,
if we embrace him, you get forgiven.
You're allowed to still sin.
You could totally fuck up, but at the
end you have to like really realize and,
and really embrace Jesus as your God show.
What are you saying to do that?
Once you do it, it's not a crazy leg
escape clause. It's like, you know,
some corporations don't have to pay
any taxes at all and they can just fuck
everybody over and make trillions
and trillions of dollars. Anyone?
What kind of loophole was
that? That's ridiculous. Well,
they just have to pay the right
politicians and this loophole,
the death loophole is you can just
fucking rape and pillage your whole life.
But if you find Christianity at the end,
like general butt naked from Liberia,
you know that story?
There's Shane Smith. Yeah,
us on the podcast guys
directly responsible for the
death of thousands of people,
thousands of people. And he killed
babies and ate their hearts. Yeah.
Eight they're still beating hearts.
Okay.
And he's a Christian and because he's a
Christian, they didn't even prosecuted.
Praise God. How amazing these
guys, God, God, so beautiful.
God is going to put him in heaven,
but not like a regular person who's born
in the jungle of Brazil and is good his
whole life and only does good for his
tribe and his family and you know,
and has great respect for the earth.
That guys go straight to hell on earth.
That confer a Spec for the earth. I don't
want expect the origination Douche bag.
It's going right to the fucking oven,
dude. Dude, do you know about
dispensations? Do you know what dispenser?
I believe they're called dispensations.
Do you know about this?
I may be saying that word wrong,
but it used to be able to buy from the
Catholic church for whom the ships used
to be able to do that. Yeah, you could
buy, say like, you could save your salary,
you could buy like no matter what,
you're going to have it.
Like I gave you this much money. Yeah.
So I'm set like, here's like, you know,
whatever, to 200,000
bucks, I'm cool. Right?
No matter what I do for the rest of my
life, I'm still going to have, and like,
yeah, you're fine. You, you gave enough
money. Now you're fine. That's hilarious.
It's amazing. That's the cat. That's
brilliant. Like the Catholic Church.
You know how funny that is to like come
up with a trick like that when you start
realizing like, wait a minute,
I can just write down on paper.
The people are going on an imaginary place
forever and they'll give me thousands
and thousands of dollars in
gold and diamonds. That's
incredible. It's incredible.
Like talking seriously
about like the tooth fairy,
like if we were having a conversation
about the tooth fairy people were willing
to die for the tooth fairy.
Yeah.
They're willing to kill you
for degrading that tooth.
Fairies are real and it ruined their
lives. They're, they're willing to,
they're willing to, um,
not use birth control.
They're willing to not wear condoms and
fucking bring kids into the world that
they didn't even want to
have for that tooth fairy.
They're willing to do a lot of
crazy shit for that tooth fairy.
And then there's a wide spectrum of
crazy and it varies from town to town.
Church called the church call it. And I
think that there's like a re, you know,
there's something that's an actual, you
know, I think there, there really is a,
I don't know what you call it, but I do
think there's like a super consciousness.
You can tune into that.
We'll give you some direction and the
directions usually don't be an asshole.
Well, why? I was saying that
the morality of the universe would tell
you that you're not allowed to spray
pepper spray in the face
of kneeling children.
The morality of the university
say these are peaceful people.
You have no right to do
anything to harm them.
They have a legitimate gripe and concern.
Whether they're handling,
they have the correct way is
debatable, but you, you know the,
the morality of the universe, the true
knowledge of what is right and wrong.
It's like instinctively,
instantly you realize that's an evil task.
And if that was your little girl,
that's your 18 year old girl.
Idealistic first day and you know,
first year in college and this asshole
is spraying her in the face with pepper
spray, you'd want to beat his brain
flat. You'd want to beat him to death.
If that was, if I saw that
guy spray my baby in the face,
I would not be able to help myself. It
wouldn't, if there was cars in the way,
if there was a cops in the way,
I would have tried physically
to get my hands on it.
I would have to really stop
myself. It would be like, uh,
like a murderous animal like
rampage. You would, you would,
you would feel it from the bottom of
your DNA that you would have to stop this
person from doing that.
We want this guy's doing
it because somebody wrote
some shit down on a piece of
paper that's a detachment man.
That's a detachment from the f the
things that you do and the impact those
things have. And you could say followed
by the word of the law and you could say,
well, those full can hoop is weren't
them. We would never have a problem.
And while all these things are correct,
that's not the real issue.
The real issue is there's a detachment
from the things we do and the effect
those things have and that attachment,
that detachment is due
to a lack of sensitivity,
which I think can be attributed to several
things and a lot of it is contributed
to awareness and our focus on awareness,
whether it's through yoga,
whether it's through meditation,
whether it's to isolation tanks,
whether it's through psychedelics,
what is through long walks,
where you sit by yourself in the alone
in the park and you do an audit of your
day and an audit of your true honest
thoughts and try to be a fucking real with
yourself man.
And don't bullshit yourself so you can
sleep better at night and think that
you're doing the right thing every time.
And all you would have
to do is imply though,
apply those ideas to life
and everyone would be fine.
Everyone would be fun,
could no one would ever start unjust wars.
They would realize you can profit anyway.
There's always going to
be assholes out there.
You can profit on fucking tanks and you
can profit on jets. We need those. Yeah,
we do need those. But we don't need that
many and we don't need them everywhere.
We don't need a a military presence
in over a hundred different fucking
countries.
We've gotten completely out of hand those
people making jets and making bombs,
making guns. I'm a, I'm a
hundred percent pro gun.
I have guns and I think that you should
be allowed to have gone pro hunting.
And I'm, I'm pro trapping. Um,
I'm, I'm pro all that Shit, man. I,
I believe in the Second Amendment
fully, strongly support. You're right.
But I think,
I just think we're at a stage right now
where people are starting to realize
that the stuff that's written down on
paper is not necessarily serving the human
beings that it's supposed to represent.
And we just,
because it's written down on paper and
because of bunch of people say it's
written down on paper,
we are supposed to abide by it.
We're supposed to deal with it.
We're supposed to allow that cop to
spray the chemical and the kid's face and
not get beaten up and immediately
thrown in jail. Like he should be.
Like your instincts would
be if any civilian did it.
And that's our real issue.
Our real issue is we're,
we're,
we are operating under an archaic
society using the wrong map. Yes.
We're using an old shitty map that
worked at different kinds of terrain.
The terrain has changed now we need,
we need to new maps.
People have got to come up with new maps.
You don't just get the fucking luxury
of using an ancient, whether it all map,
whatever the fuck the map is,
whether the map is your Bible
or whether the map is, um,
the current version of the constitution
with all the amendments or whether the
map,
whatever it is,
it's time to start making new maps
based on the fact that we're now all
connected. When you see things
like this new bill that's passed,
it turns American into a battleground
and empowers the military to come in and,
and,
and arrest civilians who
are being disorderly and
arrest anyone who is a threat
and detain them. Anyone who
they deem a thread. That is the,
all the evidence that you
need to know that it's over.
That is the monsters clawing at the
fucking, at the head. The, the, the,
the gravestone is it pulls
them underground as the
earth sucks them into its
core. The monsters are clawing
as they're dragged down.
They are trying as hard as
possible to gain ground.
And one way they're going to do it is
completely violate the bill of rights.
Where they're going to do it is to
make the constitution and valid.
And that's what they're doing.
And they're doing it under the
guise of patriotism and protection.
And you're like protection from
what you fucks. But see, that's why.
That's why they're there. What, what has
to happen is people need to start, um,
continuing to take like the action
they're taking with occupy Wall Street.
But we need a fucking super genius or a
group of super geniuses are a collective
of people to come up with a new map
for how this shit should be working.
You know what? I'm
starting to think, well,
this is what I'm starting
to think is going to happen.
I used to think that there's going
to be some sort of violent upheaval.
There's going to be real problems.
I think that there's going to be people
on the occupied side that are far too
intelligent to be ignored
and that eventually they're
going to figure out some
vulnerabilities to the system and
then they're going to have some power,
and once they have some power,
then people are going to talk and then
they're going to have to work something
out and change some laws and changed some
rules because until there's some sort
of a threat from the other side, you know,
it doesn't have to be a violent threat.
It could simply be some fucking
computer geniuses who know how to rework
everything,
not a shutting down the fucking Internet
who knew how to make things and valid
in, in an own functional.
It could be people who know
how to manipulate, you know,
money through through the Internet.
Who the fuck knows,
I mean it's going to be deemed a terrorist
act, whatever it is, you know, anything.
I mean that's really what by by
the, by the Patriot Act, you know,
anything you're doing to
attack the government now is
like a terrorist act. Yeah,
right. I bet me even suggesting that
someone may try to do this makes you under
suspicion.
You extrapolating and looking
at history and you look into
human behavior and you're
looking at this situation
and knowing that it's going to
escalate. What, what could happen.
I think someone's gonna figure out a
way to have some power, the occupiers,
but saying that by saying that
it's almost like I'm cheerleading,
I could become an enemy by saying
that. Which is amazing. You've,
I'd say you're a little, this was Orwell
Orwellian. It really is. I mean it's,
it's amazing that life is now more fucked
up than fix fucking people come at,
you know like the people who like are
looking under their car because they are
tight. They got a flat tire and like,
Hey, what's that fucking box there?
And they pull the box out from under
their car and it's still kind of magnetic
bug. Some people stuck on their car
in the middle of the night tracking,
then they come and collect it. You know,
like that guy who popped it at school.
And how about this carrier Iq?
Should Brian,
you just send me an update on this
carrier Iq. What was the update again?
When they say that the FBI
will not release any records
on this carrier? Iq Shit.
Yeah, they won't comment on
it. I mean like the, the, the,
the guys that from the company or there,
you know,
talking saying that they've never
given it their information to the FBI,
but the FBI will not comment whatsoever.
And the refuse a freedom of
information act requests. Yeah. Right.
Because it's an ongoing investigation.
That's what they're saying.
Don't have to have fucking power.
There's so much power, so much power.
And you know,
the best way to abuse power is to say
that we're doing it for your own good.
We're doing it for your own
good. You trust us. Listen,
we need this power in order to,
to get the bad people.
We know you're a good person. Trust
us. We just need this little provision.
What's a terrorist? Exactly. Oh,
some guy who sells 20 joints.
Newt Gingrich is a 200 joints.
Oh 200 doses.
He's a terrorist and he
should be put to death.
Someone who grows plants or the
fuck's that want to run our world.
Man. Really? That's what
we need. That Ron Paul Guy,
even though he doesn't
believe in evolution, I've
heard some, the problem with,
I mean I don't,
I talked about this in the lavender hour
about Ron Paul and we got some people
riding in there like shit that I didn't
investigate fully. I, like I said,
I like what didn't you invest it as
issues? Something about a Hollywood,
get rid of the highway
systems or something.
Like he doesn't want to support like,
um, he wants to go back to buggies. No,
it's not bad.
In fact of Huggies horse running.
He wants to go back to know
it's some kind of thing.
There was a few things that
were um, a little, uh, the,
I didn't know that because I really
love the guy and doesn't need to be more
specific. I meant to go and
invest. And it's something
that you don't remember. No,
I remember they said Ron Paul, we get
somehow get rid of the interstate system.
Ron Paul interstate system. I couldn't
find it. You couldn't? I don't,
I don't think so.
Just,
and then also the evolution thing came
from the commerce clause. Is that it?
I don't, I don't know. That's
something different I think,
but I love him right now. I
still like him, so I don't know.
I'm sure there's some
weird shit about him.
I guess if he doesn't believe in
evolution, that is fucked up, man.
That's maybe you've had a
religious experience. Maybe
ate some bad bread one day.
Trip the fuck out.
It's got an insight to people who believe
the earth is 5,000 years old or that
some of the funniest fucking people ask.
There's a,
there's a big move for Ron Paul right now.
Man.
He's moving with this occupy Wall Street
thing. Ron Paul is fucking exploding.
Ron Paul is neck and neck with Newt
Gingrich right now in the Iowa poll.
That is unprecedented people,
people, they're not expecting this.
Did you hear all these other
guys are falling apart?
That's the crazy thing about
these dummy republicans.
All of them slowly but surely
are showing that they're morons.
First it was Herman.
Cain is fucked. Everyone.
And then it's Rick Perry who can't
remember anything and then it's, you know,
it's fucking Mitt Romney. He's got
way too much money. Rick Perry, Shit,
fucking Internet video about
celebrate craisins but,
but you know, we know the
gays want to get buried. Yeah,
we can put gays in the military. K's in
the military. We celebrate Christmas.
Meanwhile, he's wearing the same
jacket from Brokeback mountain.
He's wearing the same jacket that
heath ledger war in Brokeback mountain.
You almost wonder if his stylist has
a sense of humor, you know? I mean,
how brilliant would that
be if they're like, well,
we got to make you look
like a good old boy. I mean,
you're just like George Bush again.
You're reincarnate.
Lot of people love George Bush. He
was a good man. It's good president.
We want to get you dressing like a
rancher. Which a ranch. Okay, we'll,
we'll dress him like a rancher. Rancher.
Rancher. Gas Line. Well, you know,
we know ranchers like, Oh,
you know American strong.
Okay. Yeah. Like Heath Ledger.
Yeah. Give him the fucking same jacket,
but come on man. What are the odds?
Who the fuck has a tan jacket
with a brown, a dark brown color?
Get the fuck Outta here. He's winking
at you and somebody who's waking
someone.
Someone behind the scenes.
That's a one on 99% are and then
don't like it. Don't like it.
It's a whistle blower.
Yeah, man, there's that.
There's definitely like
little clues out there.
He's Desperado and what it is now,
it's like one of those shows
where it's about to get canceled.
So they bring in a black character. We
need a nutty neighbor and he's a rapper,
you know, or you know, whatever.
They're just panicking right now.
This is a death spiral,
but they're all like,
all of them seem like they
should be on Jerry Springer.
They don't seem like they
should be running for president.
I seem like just freaks and,
well Newt Gingrich's clown,
guilty of ethics violations and you
know he was accused of over 40 different
ethics violations and serves divorce
papers to his wife dying of cancer.
There's just so much that I don't
like about him and one time, this is,
by the way, this is the one thing
that really sticks in my mind.
Think about this nude because this really
sticks in my mind as to who you really
are.
There was a kid the in one of those
MTV shows that came up to him and said
boxers or briefs and instead of
having any sort of a sense of humor,
he's like,
dad is a stupid question and I'm not
going to answer your stupid quite like the
way set it like demeaning to the kid,
like an authority to fix.
The kid should have said bitch and
just cracked him right in the face.
Like you wouldn't have
jungle you old rotten Bruna,
old rotten tomato sitting on a fucking
window sill. Yeah, rotting in the sun.
Getting fresh with stupid.
It's a stupid question. Yeah.
We're joking around as a TV show.
This is MTV
dummy. You know what does the way you an
asshole, you know guy comes up to you,
he's asking you questions about all kinds
of legitimate shit and he said, sir,
one question,
boxers or briefs and you get angry at him.
You get angry at him because
he threw that in there.
What kind of a nice caring you.
You're agreeing to do an interview,
but you don't like the underwear question.
That's frivolous.
Soon as time of if seriousness,
fuck you. Fuck you.
You creepy withered Turd. You'll creepy
dude. It's your last chance to be king.
It ain't going to work, dude. Often you're
getting exposed and you're exposed now,
but they're going to hack away at you
slowly but surely hack away at all the
different times that you
use your influence to make
money hacking away at all
the different times you force things
through that other people weren't
comfortable. Yeah, they've got,
this is the thing about Obama, man,
that I think about Obama,
whether or not you like him or not,
I think that guy's a pretty,
a pretty dangerous,
vicious guy and I think he uses like a
lot of tricks that the fact that he's not
vetoing this act, this act would
put him at odds with Congress,
put him at odds with the Senate and he's
not going to be to not fucking vetoing
it. It's amazing. And he said
he would veto to veto it.
He's not going to be taught. It's amazing
where we, this is, it's going to go down.
Yes, I did a piss. Yeah, they've
said he's going to sign it.
Let's just wrap this pitch up and I'll
send this thing. It's fucking him.
Three hours long. Thanks
everybody. Thanks for tuning in.
Thank you to the fleshlight for.
Thank you for that.
Thank you flashlight for
so many wonderful memory.
Thank you for being so awesome.
Thank you for every time I've gone
like this inside of your body. Ah.
Can I talk about a show? I'm
doing? Sure. Yeah, please do.
I'm going to be at Caroline's
and New York City tomorrow,
Friday and Saturday.
I'm featuring for Natasha Leggiero as
they come out to Caroline's is the shit.
That's a great point. That's a fun place
to be, man. Caroline's in New York City.
You can't get any better than that. Come
that's on Broadway. Yeah, come, come.
It's a hilarious show.
Um, but we were also,
Dunkin and I will be performing together
on New Year's Eve at the Melrose Improv.
Holla at your boy. Me, Dunkin
and Joey motherfucking Diaz.
P S suck it. Okay. We don't know
a thing. There's only one show.
That's the right way to do it.
We might have two shows,
in which case the eight o'clock people
don't get to celebrate the mystical
changing of the guard. That's right.
She was a flux. We'll fake it.
We'll do a count down that way you'll
celebrate it twice, right word. Um,
also we were at the Chicago Theater
January 27th and it is almost sold out.
If it sells out.
Apparently they're going to open up
some other sections like this upper high
balcony, but the tickets you want
to probably the ones that are,
well actually it's fucking old badass
theater when it was tiered theory man,
that'd be awesome if you have
the top balcony. Um, but uh,
it's me and Dunkin and Joey Diaz as well.
Or should I say donkey, Joey Diaz and I,
because that's the correct way
Curtis and letting people know,
that's why you say that
the toy structured, because
I'm thinking of you first.
That's what people like. Okay, so learn
from that all you dirty bitches. Oh,
you fucked up evil selfish fucks. Who
are not looking out for your fellow man.
Look out for your fellow man and only
hang around people who are 100% looking
out for you too. This is possible. This
can be done. Okay. I have proven it.
You can do the same thing.
You can manifest your own reality
and make it so Dogen. God is love.
Gets him Jizan Jesus and holes.
Guys,
let's end this with a chance.
Can you give us a chance to,
and this will say real
quick, that were, oh yeah,
we got the Ice House this weekend,
Friday and Saturday and Saturday
we're doing the ice out.
The annex in the Ice House.
It's a small room.
It's only 85 seats and it our
star studded shows. And uh,
it's given us a full line of Friday.
We have Nick Thune, Doug Benson,
John Reap and Pablo Francisco.
Saturday we have Joey, Dia, I,
Eliza Slessinger, Sam triply,
Darrell. Uh Right, right.
And Skyler stone. Boom, boom, boom.
These are crazy huge shows. And it's only
like, what is it, 15 bucks, 10 bucks.
So was house comedy done? The Ice
House is the shit. It's a great club.
It's got a great vibe. It's where
we do most of the podcasts from. Uh,
we were doing a lot of them from there
lately. This one we're doing for my,
my office,
but most of them we do at the ice house
cause it's such a cool group of people
that work there and it's a good vibe.
And the club has been around for like
over 50 years. Right. And isn't it like,
yeah, 50 year anniversary this
year. Crazy. I mean it's, it's all,
it's got like real history like in
the walls man. It's like a real spot.
And the,
the podcast there have been phenomenal
and well we also do a podcast there this
weekend. Um, every show that we do there,
we also do a show called
the ice house chronicles.
And if you subscribe to the
Death Squad, uh, on Itunes,
you can get the ice house chronicles
for free. It's always for free.
And it's another good reason to subscribe
to desk walk cause he's got a lot of
other good stuff on there.
Like Sam triple, he's on there,
he's got the naughty show on there. Tom
Securian and Christina Palicki. They have,
uh, your mom's house. Yeah.
TB and TB in the Hebrew is a,
who is it?
It's his TV and his girlfriend do it and
you'll store it. And then you know this,
they're constantly doing new ones
on there and there's, you know,
it's just awesome. Free Entertainment.
Okay. Um, so check that out.
Thank you to the fleshlight for
sponsoring. Our podcasts already said yes.
Thank you to onnit.com oh
and it makers of Alpha brain,
a new mood and shroom tech sport
and now shroom tech immune.
There's a new shroom
tech, um, which is um, uh,
based on mushrooms that
enhance your immune system.
We're trying to keep you healthy.
We're trying to keep you smart.
Is that trying to keep you not
for working out just for immunity?
There's one that's for working
out. That's uh, that's the um,
the shroom tech sport.
And then the other one shrimp to commune
is like supposed to help your Chaga,
mushrooms and a bunch of
different mushrooms that
enhance your vitality and help
your mood. Yeah. Yeah. I got something. I
just, just that's a new product bitches.
Again, with all the audit, a dotcom
things, I tell you this very simply,
these are all things that I am
supporting because I believe in him,
although I have a financial stake in it,
I can guarantee with 100% certainty I
would never ever participated in anything
that I didn't think was legit. I've been
using nootropics for a long time now.
I absolutely 100% have had positive
effects from them and there's science to
back it.
There's,
you can look online and find all sorts
of information on nootropics and I
encourage you to do so if
you're interested in them.
If you feel like the
products are too expensive,
please go buy the ingredients in bulk.
Make it yourself. Save some money.
I will be happy. I swear to you,
if you want to buy ours though,
you can get them from onnit.com o n n
I t and if you go to Joe rogan.net and
click on the link for Alpha brain,
it'll take you right there entering
the code name. Rogan get 10% off.
And as always,
there is a 100% money back guarantee.
If it doesn't work for you, if your body
doesn't feel it for whatever reason,
you can't, it's not worth it to you
hundred percent money back guarantee.
We want you happy, we want you healthy,
we want you to in and then we love you.
We don't even know you.
We do love you as long as you are
the way that we want you to be.
We want you to be loving back.
Don't be a cunt.
We love the truth inside and we say
we love you, but if you're a con,
then we're not going to love that aspect
of you. All right? So get it together,
bitches. We're all connected.
We're all connected.
We're all connected and we'll see
you soon. Bye. We love you. Bye.