Hey everybody,
this is a very special podcast,
very special Saturday afternoon
podcasts.
We'll watch an old fight from 1954.
That's supposed to be a pro wrestling
match with Gary Tonin,
one of the best Jujitsu artists in
America today,
one of the hot young fucking killers of
grappling.
And of course my brother Eddie Bravo.
Yo Yo Holler.
And we're watching this video that we
found.
All of us found this on the underground.
Someone posted it.
I'll have to give the dude props.
I forget his name,
but it's a Kamora the guy who the
shoulder lock,
the Camorra was named after because you
use it on Leo Gracie back in.
What was that like the forties or
something like that man from adult?
No,
well this is only 1962.
I would would know it was a long ass
time with black and white point point
being,
um,
he,
he was uh,
he did some pro wrestling and he did a
pro wrestling match with this guy.
I think I'm selling this saying this
right.
Riquito were Ketos on where?
Ketos on.
I hope I'm saying that right.
I'm just reading.
I never heard anybody say it.
That's a big Japanese.
He's huge.
And this match starts out like this
starts out of pro wrestling match where
they're like,
you know,
they're like doing a bunch of stuff.
They're kind of allowing each other to
push each other around in there.
Somewhere in the match.
It becomes like a war.
And the big dude,
that right there kicked the ball.
So the righthand and this,
this just turns into a fight.
This is a 100 percent of fight now.
Oh yeah.
He's looking around panicking.
He's panicking.
He tries to clench and this is real.
Now this is a real single,
like he's fucked up.
Look,
the referee says don't do that.
And boom,
he punched him in the face.
He's poking him in.
The eyes kicks out.
Oh Shit,
someone get.
Wait for this though.
Gets even crazier.
Look at this hand slaps you soccer.
Kicks Him,
man.
He had the headlock.
Some.
This is totally real now.
Holy Shit.
I mean he's fucked up right now and this
dude is still beating his ass.
My referee doesn't know if it's fake or
not.
I guess,
I don't know,
I mean,
what's.
Check this out.
Here's the finishing Combo.
The referee looks at his eyes.
You'll find back in.
Oh yeah,
he's great.
I think the refs afraid of kicking his
ass to the park and look at that.
Left the left hand that he dropped him
with a hundred percent.
Legit.
One hundred percent.
Legit back that up just a little bit.
Jamie,
to that last combination.
Right about there.
I mean this.
You don't fake shit like this.
Like when when he stood up,
when he saw was a little bit before
this.
Jim Did he soccer?
Kicked him go a little bit before this.
Yeah,
but he was against the hips right there,
Jimmy.
That's good.
See,
this is when the dude is desperately
scrambling trying to take him to the
ground.
And Ricky on again.
I hope I'm saying that right.
He's beating that ass.
He was mostly doing open hands but he's
kicking him too and then he kicks him
again.
Boom.
The bitch slap right to the IR.
Did he come?
We'll walk to the rather and look at him
and said,
dude,
what the fuck is going on here?
Look at the boom.
I mean that is.
You cannot fake head kicks like that.
That's 100 percent legit.
This guy is getting the fuck beat out of
him.
It's crazy,
man.
I mean he gets up.
He's already really,
really badly fucked up.
Like the referee checks is.
Dude,
don't worry about your.
I think there's a good chance that that
knockout was just him.
Like,
I don't know how to end this.
Let me just drop to the fucking floor
and pretend like I can't breathe.
May Be Right.
That last left hand holding onto the
road.
He got fucked up.
Man.
That's so crazy.
I've never seen anything like that
before.
A down dude.
Stay.
Stay down where it starts out just to
pro wrestling.
Match and turns into full on Valley
Tuto.
See,
this is so cool.
We were talking about this before the
podcast started that it's so cool that
shit like this exists and we can watch
some like historical moments in martial
arts.
This is a historical moment.
Wow.
I wonder what the aftermath was.
Did the guy match or something?
No,
he got murdered.
Who got murdered?
The big guy because of this problem.
That's the story that you know,
that's the legend is true.
Who knows what I would glean to believe
that that guy got his ass thoroughly
kicked.
He got.
He got a double.
Crossed him on TV and he couldn't abide.
Yeah.
He could have died.
He was getting soccer.
Kicked hard.
I can definitely see Komora having some
deep connections with the Yakuza and
they said we got to kill this
motherfucker.
That said,
no rematch,
no grappling match.
No submission.
Only.
No metamorris kill this motherfucker.
Just self killing them.
Killing them.
Quit.
They get ugly.
The dude who put the video up is Ian
Paisley is my hero.
That's his name on the underground.
So thanks to that dude.
That was one of the most brutal ass
kickings every time caught on video.
And there's another dude who posted
something.
His name is a p o l o n I s t a polo.
Nice dot.
I guess you'd say it.
Um,
and he wrote a whole breakdown of what
happened and apparently this Nikita's on
guy,
you know,
Kimora was saying that recruiters on
that he got taken for greed and the
money and the fame,
he lost his mind and just started
beating the fuck out of the dude.
And so apparently they stabbed him with
a urine soaked knife.
That's what the story is.
This is so crazy.
Who's died?
Like days later we ran out of the poison
to maybe only your own kits in Saudi.
You're fucked.
Well,
you know,
they do those poop things where they
take poop and they transfer,
they transmit fecal matter,
transplant it to someone's,
a intestinal tract and apparently it's
supposed to be like good for your body.
Like to get that bacteria,
like somebody else's bacteria in your
body through a fecal transplant.
Makes Sense.
Kind of,
but not really.
Right.
You wouldn't want to.
That helps.
That helped you think I'm joking.
There's no waiting list for that shit.
Yeah.
You wait two years for kidney liver.
Shit,
dude.
You better be white.
Fresh shit should be at the operating
table.
No,
they got fresh shit.
Yeah.
The doctors just shit,
right.
Dr.
Deacon Hormones.
No added hormones.
Tired all the time.
You need.
You guys gave me some bullshit.
It just doesn't happen.
The right amino acid chains.
So this guy ricky cheetos on like if
you,
if you watch that,
that might be like one of the first ever
double crosses that's on,
like,
like video.
I don't think there's anything like
that.
Our worldstar hip hop,
right?
So clear.
Even though it's black and white 100
years ago,
you see the strikes clearly and there's
lights and that's one of the thug life
video.
Someone's definitely going sunglasses
with drop down when he got his hands up
for real man,
that's,
that's a ruthless.
Ruth was beat down.
Not Quite as ruthless as that night.
Fucking horrible,
horrible man telling me about it.
But I just didn't.
I wasn't,
uh,
I just didn't get to it.
And then finally someone said,
dude,
sit down.
Watch this shit.
I've.
Oh,
okay.
Well it's brutal too.
We watched it on the air.
Yeah,
we watched it live.
Not Live,
but the first time I saw it and it was
unbelievable.
It was hard.
It's hard to imagine that someone could
do that.
Just ran those dudes over.
He's saying that now that the video is
out and now he's gonna.
People are gonna.
See the truth that it was self defense
gun.
He's crazy.
That's what he said.
I said one guys coming after him.
I said gun.
That's why we had to run them over
because of the gun,
but there was a.
It seems like there was a gun in that
video.
I mean,
or something that the guy took out and
put in the gun spot behind your lower
back.
Let me just.
Someone ever do that with a chrome like,
man,
let me get his comb.
Kick it in the crack of your butt.
You only put guns back there.
When a guy does that and he sticks
something behind their back.
It's owning a gun.
It's never a cell phone.
It's never anything else.
It's a fucking gun.
That's it.
It's a gun.
Nobody puts anything back there but a
gun.
W what?
What the fuck else you hold behind belts
between
your ass cheeks and your pants belts.
When I get promotions,
I hide it behind my,
but that's the only thing that's going
to promote him.
Your honor,
you've been training for a straight
three times a week.
You're on three times.
I have the documents here three times a
week for two years.
She was due for his brown belt.
Yeah.
Well he ran over the brown belt too.
Then he wrote over that dude.
That dude apparently lived.
The second guy died.
The second guy ran over his head.
Yes.
The Guy who went flying off screen.
Frog,
man.
Yeah.
That's the stories about that.
They're gonna.
Those are gonna.
Go on for eternity.
The rap world.
Holy Shit.
If you're,
if you're in that rap music world,
the more famous you get.
It's like in China,
the more famous you get in China,
the triads takeover.
You know what I mean?
They're like,
you got to pay us on.
We're responsible for this shit.
You know,
we own the movie houses or whatever,
and in the rap world,
the Tei is always walking around with
the gun.
He went to jail.
It's like it's people are killing each
other and get to big man.
It's crazy how much the world is
attached to like organized crime or
crime or violence,
so it's okay because we accepted Nwa.
Nwa was not real.
It was.
It was like a like slayer pretending
they were satanic.
Nwa The dudes pretending to be ruthless
gangsters in that album.
You can even do an album like that.
Now they rape a 14 year old,
a preacher's daughter in the drive in
and one of the songs,
a fortune,
they're pulling a train on her and the
singing about it.
It's a song about that.
And then a song about killing hookers.
One less bitch I got to worry about.
They have like little acting scenes in
between every song.
There's a scene where they pull up next
to a hooker and she goes,
hey,
when you want,
what'd you do?
What'd you want to come in?
And Oh look,
you let me go shoot that bitch.
Shoot that bitch.
That bitch.
That's part.
That's before one less bitch.
You know what I mean?
That's okay.
So we accepted all that shit.
So not just accepted it,
they sold it.
Yeah,
and it was huge.
Huge.
I mean it wasn't.
None of it was true.
It was just,
it was like the extra and it's like a.
The director and the writer,
they're not satanic.
Do you think that doing that though,
just open the door to real thugs.
Like how many real thoughts you've seen
who Trinidad James,
you know,
that is no.
To put a pull up.
Trinidad James,
all gold.
Everything you tell me if this character
is real or not,
but this is.
It's the craziest thing ever.
Trinidad James Mileage.
It's incredible.
It's going to be your new favorite
rapper.
The name of the album,
the name of the song is all gold.
Everything.
He's going to take over nods for me.
No,
it's just got
my sweet spot.
Anyways.
What's that?
Cleverly play this for you.
You got a cleverly play this lie.
So we don't get a yanked over here.
Okay,
well just don't show the video at all.
Just show all of our faces like because
it just go back and forth from that
basis.
Just let us see the video.
Watch the video,
we'll watch the video,
all gold,
everything.
Oh,
this is the explicit version.
Let can check this out.
Barbecuing.
They have guns right away.
Oh my goodness.
That's.
Try it and I love this guy.
I love his nails.
Look got long as nails are like,
I am picking up shit.
Gold.
All in my nails.
He's getting.
He's getting French tips and his nails.
He does.
Wow.
Look at all that cash.
You need to start making videos like
this.
Get more street credit.
Did jujitsu world.
Is this the real dude you think?
That's my question.
Is this guy for real?
Nick,
nick,
that Bobby Carter and his crew,
they all got arrested for this stuff.
He's got a pump crew.
Was Bobby me swagged out.
Hold on.
Jamie,
what are you saying?
Federal gun charges on him for what
they're talking about in their songs.
They went and looked at,
looked at it and oh,
these guys,
not these guys,
but there are people like this.
Not In the same car or anything like
that.
Famous rap,
but not these guys.
Oh yeah.
I had heard that recently.
Some guy is in jail,
some guy from San Diego for like a
rapper and he's flashing gang signs.
He's had no criminal history at all as
different thing too.
It's a different thing to.
Well,
that's a.
that's a wonderful video.
I liked his style.
I like his office and he's got the
puppy.
That's the best day.
All that shit.
But he's got the cutest little puppy
though.
Balance out all the gold.
Have you seen the white kid with tattoos
on his face?
He calls himself stitches.
No.
Oh,
I'm going to find you your new favorite
song.
Song Song.
This is brick and your face is.
My favorite trick is.
Look,
it's got $5.
Million hits.
America is in trouble.
He's an 18 year old rapper from Miami.
Stitches.
Well,
he's got a tattoo on his face of
stitches across his mouth.
Like the joke because he white or black.
White as fuck.
He's a white guy.
Okay.
White people representing 15.
Got a dope car.
I'll put the brick in your face.
I love this dude.
Oh my God.
Holy Shit.
Ak Forty seven tattooed on his face.
I'll put that brick in your face.
Now what you're going to do with it.
This is Florida.
That's what this is.
This is my new favorite rapper.
I tell it to you is better than
Trinidad.
Jazz tells you like it's got to be
sweet,
and then this one,
he's got all platinum teeth or gold
cartel.
The videos.
Some rifles.
Assault,
right?
Exactly.
He needs a tank.
Got To take your tank and wolverine.
Is that Hell hellraiser?
I love smelling.
Selling.
Oh,
I love selling blow.
He's running around with guns.
Cocaine all over that.
Say I love selling blow,
but it's.
It's flashing the word.
Yeah,
I love it.
That was important.
We have to make sure that the audience
understands that.
I don't think it's clear enough.
You know what he said was arguments
about it.
Yeah.
You know what he's doing,
man.
He's like,
okay,
everybody thinks they're crazy.
Watch this.
When you think you fucking top the crazy
Olympics,
motherfucker.
I'm going to tattoo guns on my face and
stitches.
I'm only 18 and I'm just going to say
it.
I love selling.
Blow doesn't want to say it.
I'm going to print it across the screen.
I didn't have a gun in ever seen.
Wow.
Does he?
He doesn't even have any white friends.
What's up with that?
It's racist.
No,
you're better off.
This is the.
This is the way you guys video.
He's the only white guy.
White guys are laying there getting
away.
Except for him.
He probably hates white people.
Now what you're gonna do with it.
That's what you get.
What I'm saying?
It's going to be all day.
It's going to be in your head now.
What going to do with it now?
What you're gonna do.
It's gonna be my new tagline after I
submit people.
Yeah.
Now what's she going to do with it?
That's rude.
Gary Coleman.
Gary.
You first win and then stick.
The White Guy was a hell raiser guy.
You know what I mean?
I think that was him.
I think that was him with a mask on that
was supposed to be him.
I've just.
My interpretation of it,
I think he should have.
He should have stayed 100 percent black
shit.
Hell raiser kind of brought it back to
white people because black people don't
like hell raiser and should've been
spawn or stockton,
you know,
that's very good point because hell
raiser was a white guy in the movie and
black people hate scary movies generally
speaking.
I'm sure.
Scary movies generally all
stereotypical,
stereotypical generalizations of how to
raise up people.
You got to be able to generalize,
generalize,
you know what I mean?
Cause if you can generalize and you
can't make any fucking points,
that's so true.
You know what I mean?
You can't make any points.
I know.
I know one guy that doesn't do that.
My yes,
I know a guy too,
but generally Jesus Christ,
that's one of the things are.
Before you say what you just said,
you go,
yeah,
I know this might sound a little bit
racist,
but I'm not racist.
But you ever see that twitter feed?
I'm not racist.
It's all people saying racist shit.
But then they say some racist shit that
was the most racist.
How can you read some racist shit and
not be accused of being racist?
We'll find out.
I don't think so,
definitely not because if someone said,
if someone was telling a story about
some racist white guy who said the n
word to a black guy,
the black guy hit him or something.
Oh,
can you tell that story and use and use
that word or do you have to say it again
when describing the story?
It's a tough one,
right?
Because Howard stern just says the word
because when he talks about someone
else,
so you get this one right here.
Jamie.
Stop right there.
I'm not racist,
but will not stand to see my country
attacked by black whiners that feel
sorry for themselves.
Quit.
Quit breaking the law ass.
Oh,
this is.
These are real well put.
Well put what?
He's got a fucking moron.
There's a difference between high levels
of African American and a n word.
Yeah.
You don't even say the word until I'm
Mexican,
so I.
I could actually get away with it if I
say an Igg Iga,
but am I.
I can't do the other one,
but you can't even say it.
You can't not.
Not even calling something it not
calling a person a nigger,
but saying the word like me saying it
right now and you're like,
oh,
you can't say it.
How come you didn't say it?
He just did it.
You know,
it's,
I think it's awesome.
Like,
you know what I mean?
They have a word.
It's no big deal.
But like what if you got one until you
can say wetback and stuff too.
What if you're like reading to like a
group of small children.
You know,
if the guy had called me a wetback,
that would be very offensive.
That doesn't seem that.
It's not quite as strong as the n word,
but it's,
it's up there.
It's like bronze metal.
You know what I mean?
An end is like the gold metal year after
year.
Not even being racist,
but walking behind black people in the
hallways is the last place I ever want
to be.
No,
no.
That's exactly what you're.
What the.
Not even being racist.
Oh my God.
I'm literally,
I literally am not racist at all,
but like I don't get why a lot of black
people feel the need to be ignorant
literally all the time.
Wow.
He's talking about Trinidad James.
There's a double double literally and no
period.
I'm not feeling that sense.
I'm not racist,
but.
But what is it?
Caucasians,
Caucasians are evil as hell.
Smh,
I've got a real issue with Smh,
which,
what does that mean again?
Shaking my head.
I am just stop,
stop,
cut the shit.
Especially white people.
Oh my God.
Look at this one.
I'm not racist,
but Justin,
please stop hanging with black people.
They are making you too ghetto people
think you're trying to be black.
Seth Rogan said about Justin Bieber,
Howard Stern.
He said,
uh,
that uh,
he thought he was going to meet Justin.
He thought,
okay,
he's going to actually be a cool guy.
Watch.
He expected me to be a cool guy,
but seth throw him under the bus and he
said he was a uh,
I don't know the exact words.
I don't.
Just the opposite of cool.
Not,
not a nice guy,
a Douche bag.
But you know what,
I thought about that.
He got so famous,
so young and he's really fucking good
looking.
He's.
He's a guest model now.
He's on sunset and he's got his leg with
the CIC for gas or something like that.
The guy's a really good looking guy.
If he.
If he didn't have a.
He wasn't a musician,
he would still get mad chick.
So how is a guy like that not going to
be a Douche bag and possibly it is
tough.
He's up against them.
Impossible.
Everybody's kissing his ass all fucking
day.
He's really good looking.
We can sing.
He can.
He's very talented.
I mean his songs.
I would never buy a cds,
but the dude can sing really good.
He could play guitar.
He shreds on drums.
He's been a musician his whole life.
He's actually very talented,
but there's no way that guy's going to
make it through the teens.
And I was 21,
22,
21 night just.
But how you going to get there through
all that and not be a Douche bag.
It's impossible.
Is a recent scientific study done that
proves that assholes get more chicks.
John Danner just cued us into this one.
I believe that they did a study.
I'm not 100 percent sure where or when,
but they had a women analyze photos of
different pictures of men doing
different facial expressions and the men
with scowls and like their chest puffed
out.
Essentially what you would look at
somebody and be like,
oh yeah,
that dude's an asshole.
Like right off your perception.
Right?
Those got higher ratings in terms of
good looks than the guys that were
smiling and looked happy signs,
typically chicks,
but those studies are all who's.
Who were the people that were in those
studies.
That would make a huge difference.
If it was young people,
older people,
I could make a huge difference.
I haven't done a full analysis of this
study yet.
I would want to know.
Right?
Like whether it's college kids that are
young and don't know any better or
whether it's women in their thirties.
I would like to know like where the drop
off point is with chicks,
get tired of dudes with their chest
sticking out,
you know that for whatever reason might
be appealing for an 18 year old.
I think girls like that in the beginning
and then they end up fucking hating.
It kills zone.
You know what
I mean?
They were attracted to the barbarian and
the fucking wild savage.
But then now they got them that damn,
I wish he wasn't such a fucking savage
because other bitches like that too.
So then they ended up hating that shit.
Right?
Wouldn't,
couldn't be.
Yeah.
But it's okay because that acid is just
going to move onto another chick.
That's totally okay with that.
So while,
until it wears off,
that asshole is not looking to settle
down with like one chick,
you know?
Depends which asshole.
Well you know what I think it is.
I think we're still stuck with the
echoes of some ancient Dna.
I think we still have,
for whatever reason,
we still have all the instincts that
people had back when you had to worry
about like marauding hordes coming over
the top of the hill with swords and
knives,
like you had to be kind of an asshole
back then,
you know,
and you had a fuck more than one chick
because your kids are all going to get
killed by arrows and fucking flying
body.
So that's a good point.
It's a very good point.
If you're living back then,
man,
you had tons of DNA spreading mean.
They used to have fertility rituals.
Whether you would hope that people got
pregnant.
The exact opposite of what we do today
today.
Everybody's like,
please get her fucking period please.
And back then they were.
They had rituals and by the time we were
in our twenties,
in a way before we had kids,
those people back in the day like we're
all our DNA came from.
They were on their way out the door.
They not only had kids,
they were getting old and they were
going to be dead by the time they're in
their thirties.
It'd probably be killed or disease or
something so that crazy.
The reason why we're here is because the
same reason why women would like a guy
that's aggressive or an asshole because
she thinks that guy could protect her.
It's this bizarre fucking trick that
nature is played on this,
this thousands of years of evolution
technologically and historically and how
much information we have in the way we
could communicate with each other.
Still doesn't work.
Still doesn't stills in totally stopped
at monkey.
Fuck gene.
That's still deep down in the back
because chicks want some guy who could
defend the castle.
Is that true,
Garrett?
Thanks.
So study.
Study proved that man,
your personal study.
What's not my case study.
Now I wish.
I wish.
I wish I.
I'm working on becoming more and more of
an asshole.
I'm trying to get better at it and not
people that have fucking acl
reconstruction.
Then I'll do my best.
You know,
man,
I'm chasing that dream because I.
it's clear that they are more successful
with women.
For sure.
Donna has a wizard that Kai,
he is such an interesting dude.
Such an interesting guy to talk to.
Such a smart guy.
I actually don't train there for the
technique at all.
It's just for the stories that he tells
us.
And so you were saying before the
podcast that data her,
you went to Danaher's to get a private
or something like that at first or train
with them.
And then he,
uh,
introduced you to his leg lock system?
Oh,
um,
yeah.
I mean just when we started,
when I started training with John,
um,
you know,
first it was just an inconsistent basis,
like once a once a week or so,
you know,
a lot of MMA fighters come to like a
Monday afternoon class.
So I was going in there and that was
when I was in college.
I didn't have time to go over all the
time,
but once I started going there
consistently I got a chance to see like
kind of the strategies that he teaches
and leg locks aren't like his main
focus.
But I think he's made huge innovations
in the leg lock game to the point where
like,
you know,
when he teaches it,
it seems like that's like his main
thing,
you know.
But uh,
yeah,
no,
it's definitely went over like our whole
leg lock game.
Me and uh,
you know,
Eddie,
Eddie Cummings.
Yeah.
Um,
both of our games just stemmed from that
for sure.
You know what I mean?
He's such a smart dude.
Yeah.
So,
so on the ball about so many things
about,
you know,
all sorts of different aspects of life.
He's a very interesting perspective.
Somebody recently asked me what was the
best advice I'd ever been given and I,
I continually preach it.
This is it.
And uh,
that,
uh,
John always tells us never to get
married,
but he lists for four reasons why you
could possibly get married.
Um,
these are four circumstances,
all of which have to exist.
All right.
Otherwise,
marriage just isn't an option.
Okay.
The first all at the same time,
it was for all four.
Otherwise it's.
Yeah.
And then the offers on the table,
it's not like you definitely have to get
married.
It's like,
alright,
we understand why,
so the first is that the woman has to be
between the ages of 18 and 25.
Okay.
Second is that you have to be over the
age of 55.
The third is that you have to have no
money and the fourth is that she has to
have tons of money.
Otherwise it's just not even a question.
Don't get that even in the wheel house.
Oh my God.
That's funny.
That is hilarious.
And I think he recently added some
innovations to that theory with like the
woman has to be an info maniac or
something like that.
He keeps making it harder and harder to
get married as we as we go along.
I would love to see her debate like an
angry woman.
It would be.
I'm sure he's done that many,
many times,
but on those points.
So he's not married.
I don't see that happening anytime soon.
What's that?
Does he have a girlfriend?
We don't know anything about his
personal life.
He's a superstar you?
No,
no.
Honestly,
even if I.
I don't,
we,
we'd never.
We're not the player.
What's that?
Would you consider him a player?
I can't answer any questions like that.
I don't know.
I just,
I'll tell you,
this is my car guy.
You guys think like we're like best
friends with them because he trained
with him all the time.
We know nothing about this guy as a
human being,
you know,
like,
just like the little bits of pieces of
the stories.
We never hang out with them.
None of that stuff.
Like it's a,
he's an enigma for sure.
Like what he does once he steps off the
mat,
if he disappears into the ether,
as far as I'm concerned,
I have no clue.
Let's give a.
He was a philosophy student right when
he started training in Jujitsu.
Yeah.
GotTa.
Get him on the podcast.
I was super smart guy.
Yeah,
that would be an insane podcast.
he'd be great.
I would definitely
love to have that.
Meanwhile,
Gary,
you're competing tomorrow at the Eddie
Bravo invitational here in La and it's
at the orpheum,
the orpheum theater,
downtown La,
the orpheum.
Amazing,
amazing place to have startup four doors
and the paper view starts at four.
It's going to be on bluedot
videos.com/Ebi,
1499,
and if you,
even if you don't train,
if you're thinking about training,
you've sound like,
ma'am,
I'm neither.
Should do something.
You would watch how fun it is.
Watch how exciting it is.
I think that the only reason why Jujitsu
and submission grappling,
the way you're doing it on your show was
the only reason why that's not on
television.
It's just people aren't,
they're not accustomed to it.
Like you're accustomed to having golf on
TV.
So you sit there and watch golf or
you're accustomed to having cricket and
some parts of the world like try
watching cricket.
You ever been in England?
If the channel and crickets on your.
Like what?
The couple of times just to see if I
could figure it out by watching it and
I'm like Nope,
I don't know why they keep running.
John told us that way.
Cool.
History about cricket.
They used to be a a guy that was known,
so at first they were only throwing like
70 mile an hour pitches and they started
to increase it up to like,
you know,
in the nineties and the 100 mile an hour
pitch range and a cricket.
You're allowed to purposefully throw the
ball at the person that's bagging.
So these guys would just wail people
like in the face and they were just
known for that became famous for just
smashing people in the face.
How does that benefit you if you're
hitting the.
What's that?
How does that.
How is that good?
I guess?
I guess if you hit the guy and like,
you know,
fuck them up enough,
it's going to be hard for him to hit the
ball and hitting the knock them out.
I don't know how that works,
man.
The guy hitting the ball have all the
gear on who has the gear.
Yeah.
They see this is back when they didn't
even really have that much gear to where
they weren't even allowed to wear
helmets or anything like that.
No,
no.
Here's the question.
Why would you not try to hit the guy
every fucking time?
I think that.
I think that's.
I was trying to do.
I think that's why you have a giant wide
paddle for a defensive tool that it
affects a tool that's in that
circumstance aim for the head every time
you think it was like that paddle work
better back when people were only
throwing like 60,
70 miles an hour.
But now they're like majorly pitch.
You ever seen the guy throw a fast ball
like a major league fastball?
It's Kinda terrifying me.
It's insane.
I've seen it live.
It's Kinda terrifying.
This speed at God can throw a ball.
It's Kinda like,
like Eagle.
Whoa.
Look at that swing.
It's,
it's,
you're guessing.
It's like in that area.
Yeah.
Well you're hoping that he's aiming for,
you know what I mean?
Specifically your area.
So who was the guy that died and then
they started instituting those helmets.
He's a,
it was a famous baseball player.
He got hit and the owe me might not have
died.
He might've gotten like really fucked
up.
It was never the same again.
But I believe he played for the Red Sox,
but it was when I was a kid,
it's kind of got hit with a ball and it
really fucked up and his career was
done.
It was never the same again.
I remember thinking,
man,
like one ball can do that.
You can get hit with one ball and you're
done with the fuck.
Was that your last name?
Hayward.
I don't know.
It was,
uh,
it was,
it was a famous case.
Wade.
Bob died late nights.
Different guy.
He died later.
Fuck,
you know,
this is probably some sports fans right
now.
Screen when you got the whole fucking
story wrong.
Faggot.
You've got the whole June.
Even the white grease ball.
My point being,
if Jujitsu is on TV,
if they got to see some wild matches,
especially one of the things I
appreciate about watching your match,
I got exposed to you by Eddie.
The first one I saw was you and chrome.
Yes.
We talked about.
We talked about it.
That was an exciting match.
Whoa.
That was two dudes to do like,
just razor sharp assassins trying to
chop each other down.
Man,
what a match.
Just what a match.
That was incredible.
You know,
the first time I met you was at that
seminar,
right.
And in Florida for you at that seminar
in Florida,
Florida.
No.
It thing.
So we,
you know.
Well,
what ended up happening was the reason
why he did Ebi one was originally I was
going to do the sub only worlds that,
that was going to sw.
Oh,
that's what it was going to be.
And Scotty from on the Mat,
he,
he knew he was on board.
He goes,
dude,
that's a great idea.
Let's do it.
Me maybe a sponsor.
And he goes,
but can I get my boy Gary Tonin in there
for sure because we were going to do a
one slash 70,
the first one.
Sub only world one 70,
60 man bragging.
And I didn't even,
I hadn't even heard of you.
How do you keep.
I don't keep track of,
of the top Jiu Jitsu guys.
I really don't.
I don't know about it either.
So,
um,
I can barely keep track of the guys in
the UFC.
And he said,
I got to get Gary Toner and I go,
well,
what I'm trying to do is get the best
submission guys.
I'm not,
I don't care about the best ib jj of
points guys.
I don't want points guys.
I want submission guys because he's
good.
I go,
okay.
You sure?
Okay.
Like I was going to put him in as a
favor.
I never even,
I didn't know this guy.
So sub only worlds.
We had investors interested and then it
fell through and then by the time I was
ready to start pushing it again,
I decided a victor got involved.
Victor Dobby loud from the UFC.
He's a Spanish commentators,
systematic Joe Rogan.
He got them all said,
let me be the unvested let me produce
it.
And it's called Eddie Bravo.
Invitational.
So.
And I thought,
hmm.
And he gets,
he wanted to her to call it that for a
recognition he doesn't do.
People would know right away.
And it was his idea.
Ebi was his idea.
I was like calling up my name,
are you sure?
But then as you think with a business
mind,
you think,
okay,
that is a good idea.
Let me put myself out there.
And,
and I was uh,
you know,
uh,
we were gonna do,
Metamorris was already in the works and
it'll be perfect.
My name would be back.
We can boom,
we could piggyback off that,
you know,
so I thought it was a good strategy.
It's a great strategy.
I have a well established name already
to try and build up something else.
So much harder.
So the very first one we did one 70 and
we did the featherweights too.
We're doing UFC weights and Gary,
of course,
you know,
he was going to be in sub only Scotty
from under.
Matt was involved in.
He said,
my boy,
Gary,
you've got to put them in.
And by that time I,
I,
I bjj,
Kuma Tay was out and I remembered who he
was.
That was the guy that was Scotty
Nelson's boy.
So then went to Abu Dhabi 2013.
And um,
I remember the first time we met there,
we were at the hotel lobby and I still
didn't know you were just like,
hey guys,
I didn't even know it was like,
Oh shit.
And then he goes on.
It was one of the greatest Abu Dhabi,
even though you didn't get the gold
medal,
it was one of the greatest performances
because that fight with chrome was
absolutely incredible.
And then after that,
after you almost pulled it off,
but he ended up finishing it.
That's what made it crazy to,
that's tricks and Sun and Hickson's
coaching.
But after that you did the absolute 175
pounds you want against Blue Shesha in
Cyborg.
And those guys couldn't tap you.
You were going after them.
I mean,
Jesus Christ,
this is the guy that just almost look at
them in the absolute,
the smallest dude in the absolute.
He gets the biggest.
He gets the two champions,
Cyborg one,
a,
the absolute ambush.
Esha won the heavyweight class.
So they fought twice in the finals.
One time.
Boucher,
one,
one time cyborg wearing.
So that's crazy in itself.
But he went against both of them.
God Damn sideboards.
Giant man.
Like it has to be like 2:30
plus at least.
Yeah.
When he was doing the metamorris match
with sharp,
I was like,
this guy's sick.
He's really strong.
Super technical,
really good off his back,
and then boom,
after that we're like,
Holy Shit.
He's got some ridiculous guard.
What do you call it?
Tornado.
Tornado,
garden.
I've seen them in videos.
It's a tornado guard.
Is that what it's called?
Especially with the gies.
Amazing.
He's.
He's one of the bigger guys that started
to.
Started to be moved like a lighter guy
when it comes to Jujitsu,
used to just be like two big fat is
falling all over each other in the head.
Guy For dude over to 30.
There's nobody that has.
I haven't seen.
I mean,
as far as I'm sure there's guys and in
Sao Paolo somewhere that are,
they're just as good.
I don't,
I don't have my finger on all that.
But what I've seen out of the famous
guys,
Cyborg is a big dude.
Nobody move.
I don't see anybody moving my camera,
his half guard.
It's insane.
I can't even play as hell.
I'm like,
that's a whole different kind of half
guard.
I'm trying.
I've got a couple of students that are
on the case.
I'm like,
go study him.
We're going to eventually bring that
shit and that's on the table because
it's working at a high level.
He gets under dudes and with his
hamstrings fucking launches.
It's crazy.
We should call him by his name because
everybody thinks cyborgs.
The chicken fights for our brand
Jujitsu,
Cyborg,
Jujitsu.
Cyborg is super yoga and there's a lot
of great videos of him doing strength
and conditioning work online to that
motherfucker is stupid strong,
and there's another Cyborg that does
Jujitsu and MMA to what?
Yes.
This is smiling cyber.
That's the guy that Nick Diaz aren't
to remember that that guy.
Sideboard tips,
right?
Well,
that cyborgs husband.
Yeah,
that's right.
Yeah.
Ex husband.
There's a bunch.
Of course.
And bottom line is gary went to.
I got to watch that fight again because
I mean they could.
They were so frustrated.
These giant superstar legends are
already living legend.
Both of them already.
Just he's a fucking animal and he
couldn't tap them is crazy.
Did you know about cyborgs guard?
Like,
did you understand it?
My,
my,
uh,
teacher Tom the blast and my original
teacher,
um,
uh,
he fought him in Abu Dhabi in 2009,
2011,
something like that.
I guess where was,
which one was in Barcelona a doesn't
matter,
but anyway,
he thought of it.
Um,
so,
you know,
I did a little studying on him just
because,
uh,
you know,
my,
my teacher,
we fought them and that it was a very
controversial match,
like kind of,
uh,
when you look back at it,
it looks like they kind of screwed Tom.
So,
um,
you know,
that for me,
like I definitely was familiar with
them.
I watched videos of him and stuff like
that after that.
But I'd say he'd made leaps and bounds
from that point.
Uh,
you know,
I really,
I didn't,
I took his Jujitsu a little bit for
granted before that fight.
He in that Abu Dhabi,
uh,
you did.
So I felt like it was like the biggest,
uh,
like a climax of his career for sure.
In terms of his technique.
It was,
it was on that if that event for sure.
Two trains hard.
Yeah man,
definitely trends heart.
That's interesting.
Um,
when you,
when you see a guy like that and you see
like those,
those leaps and bounds,
what,
what do you attribute that do?
Do you attribute that to like the high
level Jujitsu that's available today?
Everybody has to kind of keep up.
What do you attribute it to?
Just I'm just like people.
I think overall people getting better,
right?
We all admit that,
Yeah.
I mean you guys have today are about,
there's guys that stand out in my mind,
you know,
it's always going to be more so Garcia
in Hickson in his prime and so he's
going be these guys that stand out,
but the guys that today it seems like if
you're,
if you wanted to get into Jujitsu and
watched submission grappling like the
Ebi tomorrow,
it's just.
No,
no better time.
Like if people are finishing people now
and every day I got a bunch of Jujitsu
nerds and my association and my
homeschool,
they're just,
every time I see a cool clip,
every time I see a cool clip of a new
transition that Jeff Glover put on it,
you know,
on instagram or whatever,
I'll tell my little Jujitsu,
Gina says,
you see that one new,
a half guard sweep seen it.
Like everyone just seem to come up with
new shit shit that I saw in a video and
I thought I might going to teach us
tonight and uh Oh,
you're doing it wrong.
And I've seen that video a thousand
times and that was the only one that was
going to give us steel and move.
Well,
that's a beautiful thing about Jujitsu.
That's misunderstood.
A lot of people think that it's a,
it has to do with strength and
aggression and think of it as being like
this thing.
But so many of the guys that do it,
they are like,
if they weren't doing this would be
building computers or something.
We talk about it all the time.
It's crazy how we could actually
dedicate this time to something that
people actually care about and we could
actually make money or something,
you know,
so,
um,
but yeah,
that's definitely more of the mindset
for most of them.
There are those,
you know,
muscle head kept guys.
There's a few of those for sure.
But guys like you,
the thoughtful,
intelligent guys seem to always rise to
the top.
They figure out how to always have the
best answer to whatever problems in
front of them.
Yeah,
that's what we're really looking for.
I mean,
that's the theory that I try to pass on
to my students and stuff.
Um,
you know,
as opposed to like I tell it at seminars
all the time.
I'm like,
guys,
if you're ever doing a move and you're
just like,
this isn't working,
the reasons probably not because you're
not pushing harder or you need to go
faster,
you know what I mean?
Like that's not the reason something's
not working.
It's because your techniques flawed,
you know,
you're doing it for his defense is good.
Yeah.
Either or.
Yeah,
there's a lot.
That's one of those things that,
oh,
I always used to like laugh when people
would talk about it.
When it comes to a complicated
techniques,
like some of you are rubber guard
that takes a long time to get flexible
and you have to do the reps to pull them
off and people would say,
oh,
that's.
That doesn't work,
and we would always laugh like,
okay,
dad kicks work,
learn how to do a head kick right away.
Like this is a perfect example,
right?
Like head kicks,
like a wheel kick to the head.
How long is that going to take someone
out?
You can't say it doesn't work.
Watch the two or rockhold 5 million
fights.
Now there's a lot of them.
So in a lot of ways Jujitsu is is like
everything else,
right?
There's going to be these levels that
you see of it that are super high and
then you realize what's possible and you
go,
oh,
and then along the way you got a lot of
people are second guessing a lot of
doubters.
A lot of people that don't think this is
going to work or that's going to work,
there's just so many moves in Jiu Jitsu.
It's unlike any other sport.
It's endless.
Ever.
All the top guys have their own style.
There's so much to learn in.
The only way to get good at certain
transition or move is to spend a lot of
time with that certain move or that
transition.
You don't have that much time,
so the smart thing to do,
it's because sometimes you're working on
a transition that might not pan out and
you hit it a dead end.
So you're like,
dude,
you don't know what moves to spend this
precious time with.
So you look at the pop guys and what are
they doing?
They already done the research and
development at works,
so now you know what safe to put reps
into one.
That's a safe one and the safe ones are
the best ones.
Right.
I think the compliment to that though is
like,
so you look at that and I seen,
I've seen people do it.
People that used to be on our team,
it would look at these guys,
what are the top guys do and focus on
that,
but you focus too much on it.
Those top guys like let's take like the
Menendez brothers for instance.
All right.
With like Baron Bolo,
right?
Yeah.
Okay.
These guys are doing a move that they've
perfected,
right?
Yes.
So sure I could study what they're doing
and learn what they're doing,
but am I going to be able to make.
Am I going to be able to make the same
headway that they have with that move?
Probably not.
So I probably need to pick up a
different facet of my game and headway
with that move.
You know what I mean?
Then that's what I try to do.
You know,
that that's what I tell people that,
oh,
you know,
what's the best way to get,
a step forward in competition,
a step ahead of the game and I think
it's being somewhere being in a position
more than other people are in that
position and developing that not so much
what you see other people doing.
If you're constantly just trying to do
what other people are doing,
you're going to get caught up in that
game and they'll always find a way to
submit you because they've been doing it
longer.
You know what I mean?
I think that's the like the opposing
strategy to what you were just talking
about because I totally agree with you.
I.
I have.
I use both strategies.
I always promote and push to keep your
goto moves polished and not forget about
your goat tools.
Those are your special moves.
Anytime a new student comes,
a a new student comes to me and they see
them developing a move.
Even if it's a move that I suck and I'm
like,
that's your move right there.
I remind them,
I go,
that's yours.
Get really good at that.
That's your secret weapon.
You got to have secret weapons,
but at the same time I have new students
starting every day,
so I like to expose them to everything
that's working out there and create
their own style.
Even though personally I teach the baron
bullets part of our warmup system.
I'm not ever going to be a bar polo
player.
I messed with it every now and then when
I'm rolling with a 12 year olds and
women,
all the shit out of a white belt girl.
I'll do that.
I know,
but I know eventually eventually I'm
going to get really good at that in like
10 years and then they'll be able to
attack with it,
but right now you stick to your Goto,
keep those strong and take your go tos
to the highest level but also also have
a constant introduction of new stuff in
your game.
It'll pay back later,
maybe 10 years down the road,
15 years down the road where maybe it's
not your game now,
but it will be after the light,
like I'm killing it.
You definitely need to take all those
elements from the good guys for what
they do for sure.
And it's really no other martial art
like that.
Right.
That has so many different moves too.
There's just.
It's incredible.
It's like a five dimensional martial
art.
It's.
Yeah.
I mean it just keeps getting better and
better at over the years.
Like Joe was saying before,
you know,
the progression of Jujitsu in general
and the level of it is just going up and
up and I think the biggest innovations
that are happening now are probably in
the leg lock game frontier for you and
Eddie and Eddie come into a big part of
that big part of that.
Since they want a 10 plan,
they want.
We have never outlawed a heel hooks or
reaping.
I just never wanted to get heavy on heel
hooks because I want her to train my
fighters for MMA.
I don't want them to the first habit to
go to heal hooks because it's a little
dangerous when the highest nine guys are
telling me when my leg lock school guys
are telling me,
manny,
Carl,
caren.
Oh Bro,
bro.
MMA leg logs,
last resort.
You don't want to give a position when
they're saying that.
I'm like,
okay.
But I never discouraged it,
but I had leg lock,
like [inaudible],
one of my black belts.
Very good at leg locks.
Denny got really good at.
Like I told denegall five years ago,
submerse yourself in leg locks.
I want.
He's not going to do mma.
I go,
so
leg locks are very important for you.
Uh,
but then when we saw what you did in
Ebi,
one leg lock the shit out of everybody.
And then in the grapplers quest,
ultimate absolute in the Obi wan and the
finals,
you beat Richie Martinez,
one of my guys,
you heal,
hook them inside hook.
And then at the grapplers quest,
ultimate,
absolute,
or ultimate whatever submission only I
get those mixed up.
It was you and Nathan Orchard at the end
of that 16 man,
another one of my black belts.
And you've got them with the inside.
He'll hook again.
From that point,
Nathan decided,
you know what?
He started studying everything you were
doing and we to me,
I never got deep into my.
I got a good crippler or a game over
whatever people call both legs reaped.
I got when I escaped the mountain,
I go to that.
I'm good at that.
He'll hook,
but generally I'm not good at heel
hooks.
Never really looked into it.
I didn't know the system.
I didn't know the system until Nathan
studied your personal game and then
showed it to me and I'm like,
wow,
it's like rubber guard because people
don't.
People think like rubber guard is just
reaching up and grabbing your legs and
hold on and throwing up an arm bar.
They don't realize there's our system.
There's all these positions as a path.
I didn't realize it was this exact same
thing for when I first started training
leg locks.
I like,
I walked in like Eddie had already done
a lot of,
you know,
made a lot of headway in the leg lock
game and obviously,
you know,
John had been teaching him so,
when I first came in,
my intentions were always preparing for
ADCC.
It's,
my intentions were like,
all right,
I want to know a little bit about this
leg lock game.
I'm going to be competing in a
tournament where he looks her legal,
which I don't usually do.
You know,
I want to be ready for this.
we're ready for whatever people are
gonna throw me.
I'm just going to learn how to do it
well enough that I can defend it and
then I learned that it's like a whole
different martial art just like walks in
and I'm like,
what the fuck?
I'm like,
I wanted to ask John because I'm so
frustrated I'm not passing Eddie's guard
because just keeps blocking me.
And I'm like,
so you know,
when a guy's good at lego logs,
how do you pass the guard?
He's like,
fucking learning logs dude.
See you got to learn how to,
how to do what he's doing so that you
know,
the counters and everything.
So I realized I had to spend time on it,
you know,
as opposed to just dismissing it as like
a small part.
When you see someone,
when you see someone dismiss them in
mma,
like the highest armed guy saying don't
do it because it's last resort,
but then you see a guy like I was gonna
say that one you guys about.
What do you think?
Like blocks today,
leg locks in mma.
What do you think?
I just think there needs to be.
There's a few guys that are using them
well and I just,
I think that,
uh,
you know,
there's just not enough people out there
that are confident enough in them have
I've done enough technical research to
make them useful,
you know what I mean?
If you teach one dude is shitty healed.
Yeah,
absolutely.
But what do you think about as far as
specifically?
So it's terrifying.
The guy knows that he has a confidence
in his heel,
hooking nosy can break a limb with it
and he finds in every different
situation.
Most of our transitions we get from,
you know,
oh,
Pahara got a leg there.
He got to like here,
you know,
he learns how to get there from many
different positions and that's what I
was talking about and kind of what Eddie
was
talking about with finding that thing
that's like yours,
you know,
he's there all the time.
So if he can get you there,
boom,
you're done.
You know,
you don't know what you're doing.
Exactly.
You're thinking he's already moved on
instance.
This is what I'm thinking about.
Leg locks is a,
I hear this stuff from highest on,
you know,
10 years ago.
Yeah.
I hear my,
one of my purse,
my first MMA fighter was,
he was rubber guard twister.
He lives like,
uh,
like I,
I created this guy,
but he also had a leg lock out any did
MMA and every time he tried to go for
leg locks he got knocked out.
Yeah.
So that came.
There was a,
there was a point where uh,
he had to.
It was too dangerous.
Yeah,
after like 12,
five.
But then,
um,
you have uh,
uh,
Hussam [inaudible] coming out coming out
of nowhere and people I think are still
giving them more like,
well he's making the leg locks work
because he shows strong and he's so
scary.
And so because people do feel like we
need to see it a few more times from
different people.
Hey,
I hope leg lock works.
The more submissions on the ground,
the better.
I love the way with smart pull in
garden,
the leg locks.
He's not even trying to take dudes down.
Well,
you know what I think is when Alan
belcher figured it out,
yes,
Alan belcher figured it out.
I mean he willingly went into his half
guard.
He willingly went to the ground with.
That's the biggest mistake.
People make up poems.
He defended every single step of the way
and then beat them down and stop them.
I think at the high level,
that's what it looks like.
I think if the guys is kind of shaky
about leg locks and he's not like,
he doesn't have leg lock defense in his
DNA,
he's going to get caught.
But Alan spent two months solid with a
dean lister floorman a Davi Ramos who's
a mini pet horse leg and he said the
first two weeks he just got leg locked
all day and after a while you learn how
to slow it down and then you get tapped
and you slow it down and then you get
tapped and you slow it down and then you
start attacking because that's what he
said.
So I think maybe with the leg game,
if everybody got really good at the
defense that yes,
you can get,
you can get in these positions and avoid
getting hit because I think the saddle
and the honeywell,
I think it's pretty safe right where you
ain't going to get hit there,
they can't reach you.
But if the guy defends it and is
comfortable defending it and then can
sit up in a certain spot and sprawl out
on you,
then it could be a trouble.
I'm not a,
I'm rooting for leg locks and mma.
Trust me,
I'm just not 100 percent I need is once
the punches coming,
once they start flying.
I hear Ryan Hall is making leg lock
works in an MMA training.
So uh,
maybe maybe like maybe leg locks,
um,
will be the future of or part of the
future of grappling.
And well,
you know,
we always have this conception but this
idea of it because of Frank Mir versus
Ian Freeman.
I mean,
that's like cemented in people's heads.
Remember Frank Mir is going for the heel
hook look like he's got it locked up.
And he's like,
Ian Friedman's teeing off on his face
while he's holding onto his leg that
was,
gets he stomped on me.
He got fucked up that.
And that was when frank was a monster.
I mean,
frank was real young,
wild and aggressive.
Romeo Santo and walking
Hanson.
Assad was very good at leg locks,
had a toehold,
what can enhance and caught him once and
hit them two or three times.
And he was just how it started.
So,
okay,
who's caring?
Who's got better leg locked technique
imagery or Paul Harris because
[inaudible] has worked some dudes needs
to.
I think in an Aria is probably more
technical.
What do you think?
Um,
no I,
no I didn't come and says no.
Yeah,
I think that you're,
you're seeing kind of,
first of all,
you're seeing two people,
um,
do leg locks to people that are,
that don't have any clue what they're
doing when it comes to like locking,
right?
So it's in the MMA world,
not to discredit anybody that uses them
effectively and under nay pars is using
them effectively in both.
Um,
but then when you're watching people use
like locks and fights,
you can't just credit,
you can just be like,
oh my God,
that dude's leg locks are amazing
because they're going,
again,
in terms of grappling,
they're going on somebody that doesn't
have any clue what they're doing most of
the time anyway.
Um,
but uh,
in terms of,
you know,
who's,
who's better,
I mean it's clear that the headway that
[inaudible] is made with an outside,
he'll hook is just way above anyone
else.
[inaudible] has some other,
I'd say men are better at some of these
technical transitions that he does.
Some very unique,
you know,
counters and unique,
uh,
you know,
attacks entries as well.
Yeah,
I mean we definitely study them and try
and use some of that stuff.
So I think he's just a little bit more
creative,
a little bit more unique,
but I don't think necessarily.
I think Paul Harris has a better system.
Okay.
Paul Harris has a better system for
breaking a limb as opposed to a lot of
creative transitions and can eventually
submit somebody.
But you know,
if you ever think about getting a
private with Paul Harris,
uh,
no,
because I,
you know,
I favor my knees and I don't want to
get.
Oh,
you definitely just break my legs for
sure.
I mean,
he'd try anyway.
We'd say,
oh for sure.
For sure.
Dude.
The guy's a crazy person.
They brought in a sports psychologist to
try and like,
hey,
why are you breaking your training
partners legs and everybody's legs and
competition and not letting go.
And the sports psychologist after week
was like,
fuck this.
I don't know what the day brought him in
because he was breaking his,
his training partners to camps and
stuff.
Dude.
Yeah.
Whoa.
God Damn Eddie,
you're nodding as well.
Yeah.
Just wondered.
Confirmation across the board.
So he had a tow childhood man.
You hear about his childhood that,
that big scar across his chest.
They tried to Krazy glue.
That shit's shut when he was like a kid.
Wow.
Yeah.
He grew up on a farm,
a pig slop,
and he was like 13.
It's a really heartbreaking story.
Not surprised at all.
Been working since he was like a little
kid.
It's one of the reasons why he's so
fucking strong.
Pig slop has something to do with it.
You got to start getting pixel up.
I'm sure you added some other things.
Says Diet once you got some of them wake
up in the morning.
It's just super dense in protein.
Tastes like shit,
but it's good for your plus.
It's like an instant fecal transplant as
well because reading a little bit of
picture in there.
Perfect.
Me.
See his fight with Fitch.
Uh,
no I haven't.
I've been watching a lot of highlights
specifically actually explained it.
Alan belcher actually went over like
what he did wrong.
Like it's pretty interesting man.
He had a video outlining the technique,
how to defend and how par has went to
straight leg lock.
Nobody did and what he should or the way
you have done it.
And the way you did do it.
So really interesting.
Alan Belcher is a wizard when it comes.
That's the way Paul Harris got the fight
to the ground.
He's fighting John Fitch,
Ncaa Division One wrestler.
How did he take them down?
He didn't even try,
he just shot for a week,
single and just sat down and went for a
leg lock.
Once he gets a hold of you,
it's like you have a whole new level of
Oh fuck.
Like everybody has in their head like a
level of Oh fuck.
Like,
okay,
I'm okay here.
I can defend here.
But I think he's so God damn strong.
And on top of that it's technique.
So sharp.
Then went to grabs a whole,
you see this look on dudes faces.
They're like,
Oh shit,
I'm not getting out of this.
Guys are letting him get where he wants
to be though,
you know,
like most of them anyway.
Um,
you know,
the better strategy is to put him where
you want them as opposed to,
Oh yeah,
I'm just going to keep this on the feet.
No you're not,
you're not going to keep this on the
feet.
He's going to find a way to get to the
leg lock,
lock guard,
put them,
put them down,
put them down.
Shows you what a Demon Hector Lombard
is.
Because Hector Lumbar was like getting a
hold of my legs.
He beat the shit out of him.
How did the fight go?
Stoppage.
Lombard stopped him.
He just couldn't take them down.
Couldn't take them down,
couldn't get him into leg lock,
couldn't do anything with them.
Never got him to the ground.
Did he try to pull dark to Lombard?
Is Stupid.
Strong,
stupid,
strong.
He's the only guy I've ever seen lockup
with Tim Bush and just face plant him
just by,
by polar like Tim Bush was trying to
shoot and take them down and he sprawled
and just slammed him into the ground
like he's so God damn strong.
And on top of that he's got ridiculous
technique.
You know his judo is off the charts and
then he's got submissions to men.
There's a video of him in a submission.
Grappling match.
We snapped to dude's leg and you can
hear it.
You could hear the snap.
Nothing grip.
Which one?
Lombard.
Hector Lombard gets a dude in a leg lock
and snaps his leg.
I think I've seen it.
Sounds like you've got them in like a
straight ankle lock.
And you hear a crack number,
John Lobur got his foot broken off with
a toehold in Japan.
The whole foot just broke off and he's
just looking at it.
They flipped hanging and the ref stops
it.
And he's like,
oh shit,
the pancreas.
But the whole,
it was like a,
like,
um,
Anderson Silva's leg tonight,
Jesus Christ.
When you really stop and think about the
progression over the years and all the
crazy fights you put like you gotta wake
your brain up to that fight.
Have you guys looked into the CSW leg
lock system with Eric Paulson?
You guys look at him and I trained at a
school once,
um,
but you know,
in terms of like looking at their system
of like Luxe,
I'm not as attuned to it.
Eddie.
Eddie does a lot more research than me,
you know,
as you called people,
Bjj nerds,
that's for sure.
Um,
so
you're just like,
Eddie,
what?
What's next?
What does it mean?
Shit?
Yeah.
You don't want to go.
I do a little bit of research,
but it's not.
I don't do extensive stuff.
You know what I mean?
I've just trained it all the time and
you know,
I,
luckily I live in an age where have all
these people around me that,
you know,
study and,
the martial art,
you know,
like,
I always think about that,
think back to like,
what was it like when nobody knew what
the fuck they were doing and you just
had to make everything up and you had
nothing to go off of,
you know what I mean?
Now we're in this era where it's like,
you know,
I could go to John with pretty much
anything.
I'm going to get 95 percent accurate
answer to whatever question is that I
have because he's seen it 100 times
before on tape,
you know what I mean?
Um,
we don't have to innovate as much.
Are you planning on finding an mma?
Yeah.
One or two years,
you know,
I gotta I don't know old people in the
face yet.
So how old I am?
Twenty three.
And um,
so you're just concentrating on striking
before you do it.
Yeah.
I just want to learn.
I want to know what I'm doing before.
I do know,
wrestled your whole life,
right?
Uh,
I wrestled from fifth to ninth grade and
I started doing Jujitsu so it gave me a
little bit of a grappling based,
but it wasn't a,
you know,
I mean,
it wasn't,
you know,
I knew how to do a single and a double
leg,
like things in the ground.
Nothing serious.
Nothing that I really remember.
Now I do wrestling privates with a d,
One guy Matt Fletcher.
I'm on a biweekly to two a week.
And what kind of striking training
you're doing?
Striking training has started working
with Frank Savannah,
a boxing coach.
She's,
I'm just doing it like once a week.
Right.
You don't have time to.
I am in Manhattan,
but I haven't checked anybody out in the
area.
I've just been doing stuff in Jersey,
bringing people to me because I run a
school.
So it's hard for me now because Enzo is
who's connected with a lot.
Right.
Like Phil nurse doesn't want you guys
all somewhat somewhat connected.
You have some guys teaching,
but um,
you know,
I haven't gotten in touch with those
guys.
Um,
it's just,
I'm just a real basic level right now,
so I just want to get to a point where I
can start going to some professionals,
but it's almost like with Jujitsu,
without knowing anything,
like what uses it to go to the best guy
in the world,
you know what I mean?
Well,
you know what dude with a guy,
as good as you are,
I think the most important thing is you
go to like whoever you go to,
if you decided to embark on your mma
career,
go to someone,
but it's got a full knowledge like a for
Rasa hobby type.
Dude,
look,
someone's got a full knowledge of MMA.
Guys are so gigantic.
I don't think they get the credit that
they deserve.
Yeah man,
the Duke Roufus is of the world and you
know,
those,
those guys that just look,
look at the whole package of what you do
as a fighter and piece together the
right strategy for you.
We have good connections with a,
you know,
for us,
for us and that camp,
you know,
their guys come to us for Jujitsu and
our guys go down to them from me.
So I'm definitely hoping once I,
once I get some striking and shoot
boxing to a certain level,
I'd love to go down there,
you know,
like I said,
it's just so I feel like,
you know,
almost they wouldn't know what to do
with me at this point just because I'm
just so,
you know,
base level right now.
Useless to go down.
I don't want to waste their time.
So you just turned the box from your
train more time.
I'm just boxing right now.
My boxing coach told me that he thinks,
you know,
I used to spend about six months purely
unboxing before I jump into Moitai.
Um,
you could probably do it either way,
but that's a good idea man.
He kind of contrast the two things that
they're trying to teach you.
So focused on one thing first and then
I'll jump into that for sure.
Yeah.
I get those mechanics down and then uh,
the trans transition is very important
though some people don't make it,
don't make it,
and the guy has leg kicks are just,
they come into play,
the elbows and knees come into play.
There's too many things that come into
play.
Guys make the mistake of focusing
primarily on boxing just because it
feels good to punch somebody in the
face.
Pretty good at it.
It's not an awkward movement for your
body.
Seems pretty self explanatory.
Everybody understands it.
But then kicking is this whole thing
where you're moving your body in a way
that seemed awkward and you're,
you have to think about where you're and
foot placement goes to some guys,
they just become that boxer,
a wrestler,
Jujitsu type guy,
but can't do that anymore,
man.
It's just Vittori Belfort's we'll
kicking you in the head.
You know what I mean?
It's like now it's on such a weird level
that guys can do things.
Guys that are like super high level and
everything.
They'll always have that advantage over
you in this one thing.
Like when your,
as you're planning out your future,
super important to look at all the
spots.
Some guys never do that,
you know,
like no one ever expects shale son and
throw a head kick.
You know what I mean?
Like he's a good example of it.
No one ever expected him to just never
put that as a threat.
It was never.
But like a guy like a GSP or fill in the
blank,
they can kind of do anything.
Perfect example.
Mean you can do anything.
Yeah,
definitely makes you more dangerous for
sure.
If Jujitsu,
like professional Jujitsu was a big
thing.
It was on television,
it was a major league sport tour we're
trying to go.
But would you go into mma or would you
stay with you?
It's an interesting question.
I haven't really considered it yet
because we just haven't gotten it to
that level.
Um,
I think,
I think I would still try it at some
point to transition into May.
Maybe I would hold it off for a little
bit longer.
Like if I really,
if I really saw that the sport was
taking off and I,
you know,
I felt like that's where I could make my
headway and that's where I could make my
mark.
I definitely spend a lot more time
there.
I still think I would like to make a
transition and a purely for so purely
for,
for a few reasons.
One,
just to test myself,
I'm at a new thing to,
um,
to make sure that I have the knowledge
for when,
you know,
somebody comes up to me and goes,
oh yeah,
I want to make a transition to mma from
Jujitsu.
What's your advice?
Well,
I can't really give them advice if I've
never done it before.
I don't feel like,
you know,
so I want to really know what I'm
talking about.
If I'm talking to these guys,
these young guys that want to come up
and do something with an a instead of
just Jujitsu.
So I,
I definitely,
from a teaching perspective,
I need to get into Nma and experience
that and know what it's like.
That's,
that's how I feel anyway,
regardless of whether or not Jujitsu
takes off and it's on tv and all that
stuff.
Are you planning on ever doing any
amateur boxing matches or anything along
those wild?
I got to talk to some of my coaches and
stuff and see what they think is best in
terms of,
you know,
my development and things like that.
I would imagine that that probably,
you know,
would be good for sure.
Um,
I,
I want to avoid a as much as possible.
I'm going the route of just getting
knocked out all the time and training
and stuff like that and just having that
just gritty type of training where
you're just,
it's just getting you tough,
you know,
in quotation marks.
And then I'll get to a point where I'm
in a fight and I'm just getting touched
on the Chin and knocked out.
I want to make sure I'm focusing mostly
on technical details and then putting it
all together.
So smart and so happy to hear you say
that.
So one of the most important things,
you know Jamie Varner just did this
interview recently,
Jim Varner,
who was a former WEC lightweight
champion,
really tough guy,
did this interview recently.
We said I shortened my career because I
spar too hard as far too often our
bigger guys,
you started talking about I was sparring
Ryan Bader and all these dudes are way
bigger than him and that over those
years of doing all that sparring with
these larger guys and sporing really
hard three days a week.
He's like,
don't try to prove you're tough,
you're tough,
you're in the UFC.
You really tough,
like don't just try to do it right.
And he said sometimes you don't even
have to do with once a week,
once every other week maybe even.
Yeah,
that's what I'm thinking in terms of
like when I get to the sparring and
stuff like that.
For sure.
I used to spar back in the day like
probably like three,
four years ago.
Uh,
when,
uh,
you know,
some of my teammates is starting to do
it some mma.
I just did it for fun and for some
experience and things like that,
but it was,
it was stupid and dangerous for me to be
doing that without really knowing what I
was doing in terms of striking.
I think,
you know,
because all I was really doing,
I mean all I was really doing was,
you know,
hitting until I could get to a take
anyway.
But I mean just taking unnecessary
damage for no reason from people that
wanted to take my head off,
you know,
it's not smart and people think it's
cute.
They think it's fun.
Like this guy doesn't even know how to
box.
Once we touch them up,
get in there and throw hard hooks on
your fucking head.
You don't even see them coming and that,
those,
those shots that you take in those
sparring sessions,
they could really fuck you up now for a
long time.
The lad that had never really,
you know,
I didn't have to pay the price for that
at all.
If you could find guys that sparked
technically really fast and have good
control of man,
you can progress so far.
Yeah,
because it takes away all the fear of
getting hit.
If you just find like it's just hard to
find the ties apparently have a down.
I was talking with John Wayne par when
he was on the podcast and he said they,
they spar like they play,
like when they're kicking each other
though like slapping each other and
because there's fighting every week so
they don't want to get hurt.
So when they're sparring they're like
playing with each other.
No one's trying to hurt anybody.
It should always be like that and that's
like the biggest problem for people
starting out in training Jiu Jitsu to
get that guy that's just squeezes
everything and you need to be able to
relax,
get submitted and move around.
Like you have to be comfortable and all
that stuff.
You know?
It's like a hard thing for me to teach
new people coming in and it's like the
hardest transition.
Get them to a point where they're
comfortable enough to relax and then
just let their mind open up to like what
they should be doing now.
Yeah.
It seems like it's just time.
It's the only thing that fixes that time
and everything and striking to and you
see guys that trained for a long time
and maintain that mentality and still
are just like you did just rough and
tough guys that are trying as hard as
they can,
every single role and they're not making
a lot of progress.
I see plenty of people like that so time
but with good direction from like
coaches and teammates and things like
that because there's still plenty of
guys that you could be training for 10
years and you're just still trained like
a jerk off.
So there's a lot of those guys that
never really developed much,
much offense either.
They have like a couple of good moves
that they look glad to.
That's a weird thing.
And then some people just figured out
how to get like,
how many years were you doing Jiu Jitsu
will you started hitting like a real
high level?
Um,
I mean I think,
you know,
I,
I mean it was a,
it was a progression.
I was focused on like points Jujitsu for
a long time.
I was still trying to submit people,
my strategy was I'm going to get to the
back because there's a high score for
points there and I could do a rear naked
choke,
said you highly effective submission and
it's low risk,
you know,
so that was my strategy for everything.
So the first five years of my training
was all dedicated to that from every
position.
Let's get to this guy's back,
choke him from behind,
keep this simple,
I'm going to have more points and I'm
going to be able to submit.
The guy passed that.
Those,
these last three years I think I've made
the biggest developments in terms of
like broadening my submission base and
learning how to submit people from
different places and things like that.
But I think it was kind of good for my
progression,
you know,
because I got positionally sound in a
bunch of different and had like a
strategy and things like that.
But it,
it took till I was a black belt to
really make advances.
And in Jujitsu,
I feel like,
you know,
high level,
what do you,
how do you feel about what submission
only versus the points game?
Um,
I mean,
I think it,
it takes a couple of different things,
you know,
like,
so I mean you could see people that are
possibly successful in both are
successful in one or the other.
Um,
but I think what it comes down to is
kind of the mentality of the person
that's training or competing in either
one of those things,
you know,
it's like you take somebody and whether
they're appoints fighter,
if there are points,
spider competing in a submission only
tournament,
they're going to pretty much see them
take the same strategy and the
submission only toilet.
Um,
you know,
it's,
it takes,
it takes guys that are constantly
hunting for submissions in training.
Um,
and that's,
that's when you're gonna see the best
matches,
you know,
guys that are constantly hunting after
submissions all the time.
It's not just like a situational thing.
There's like this,
there's just this overarching thing that
some of the bigger Jujitsu guys say.
I think I saw like an article from Kyle
Taylor and I love dietary,
you know,
a great guy,
but he posted this thing that said like,
you know,
Oh,
uh,
you know,
I,
I hate when people talk about submission
fighters and points fighters and,
and you know,
the difference between the two.
And I think it's like the points fetters
was,
it's all the same,
you know,
and these guys talk about,
Oh,
I'm going to use my Jujitsu and if a
submission opens up,
I'm going to,
I'll finish the guy if the submission
opens up.
No,
you make the fucking submission open up.
It's not,
it's not like,
oh,
I'm waiting for this guy to like
accidentally stick his arm out there.
No,
I make them,
I take his arm away from him.
That's the point,
you know,
uh,
there's two complete.
Those are two different mentalities,
you know,
I mean,
oh,
I'm going to wait for this guy to make a
mistake and I'm going to make this guy
in danger.
That's a newer mentality,
right?
Because the original mentality was like
one of the reasons why I would favor a
longer matches,
you wanted to cook his opponent and want
to slow them down,
wanting to make them make mistakes,
didn't have the physicality to impose
himself on people.
So he waited until they got tired and
then they would give something up and it
can work.
Sure.
And I don't think it's not a winning
strategy.
You can see clearly you see guys grind
people out them.
But I think that,
I think that not just using strength,
you can find ways to,
you know,
open up submissions on people.
It's,
it's,
there's definitely a deeper level of
technique there.
Yeah.
That's why the difference between the
way Josh Barnett describes it,
you know,
describe submissions in the way,
like some more technical jujitsu based
guys would describe submissions.
Yeah.
Like Barnett always calls like catch
wrestling,
like a violent art that elect your,
your,
your attack.
It's not the gentle art to just use a
general art catch wrestling,
the violent art.
So these,
a lot of the young guys like yourself,
super aggressive gods.
There's like,
there's like a change in philosophy then
more adherent to that philosophy,
like the aggressive go after it.
Philosophy.
Yeah,
and I think when we're talking about
taking grappling to a point where it's a
spectator sport,
which is what Eddie's trying to do in
many of these other organizations,
that's what needs to happen.
Whether it's,
whether it's going to help you win
fights or not.
Like you know,
you take a look at the UFC and Dana
White's always telling people like you
have to have exciting fights,
you have to have exciting fights and
it's true because you won't have as many
fans if you don't heal eventually kick
you out of the UFC if you don't.
You know what I mean?
But that's what makes it a Spec it.
That's why people get paid to do it
because people are excited to watch it
and whether you win or lose,
it can't be the only thing in your head.
I'm at that point.
If when we're talking about bringing
people in,
if you're making money,
you're putting on a performance,
you know,
so it has to be about the attacks.
It has to be about what's exciting about
Jujitsu,
the submission,
you know what I mean?
So people constantly getting attacked.
That's what people want to see.
And that's going to make this like a big
thing that people are interested in.
Are you still interested in competing in
the GE or you're just doing.
I'm also competing against.
I just don't focus on it because nobody
pays anybody to compete in the G.
number one,
let them.
Morris does.
Yeah.
Most and most of the matches don't ended
the submission and they're considered
boring matches the most of them.
I'm not saying all dot matter.
Metamora should go all Nogi what's,
uh,
yeah,
I,
I do.
Um,
I don't necessarily think that you can't
have excited matches in the gate.
I just think you have to find the right
people.
You have to find two people that are
willing to put it all on the line and
just try to submit each other and not
give a shit whether or not they get
submitted.
It's hard.
Even when you find people like that,
when one,
when they both have a grip of the color
and the stuck there,
they're really good at just holding each
other.
It's a,
it's a tough one.
Yeah.
No,
I agree.
I think it just,
it just makes it more exciting,
more smashing the game.
Uh,
I,
I'd consider it,
but it would take out a bigger camp,
you know?
Uh,
I definitely,
uh,
I'm definitely just focused on Nogi
right now for everything in my future.
It's just like you,
if I'm going to do MNA,
it only makes sense.
Um,
every match,
every super fight that I'm being asked
to do is without the gate.
It just literally at this point makes no
sense for me to spend a lot of time on
it.
Now,
once again,
like I said before,
from an instructional standpoint,
your students that might be interested
in training and the gate at some point.
Once I break away from,
you know,
my athletic career,
I'll definitely study the geo.
Definitely studied judo,
definitely study all the things that,
those little intricacies that people use
in Jujitsu,
the lapel guards and things like that.
So that I can better help my students,
but not so much for me as a professional
athlete.
I don't think.
I think at this point we're hitting a
point in Jujitsu where you have to make
a decision.
What am I going to specialize in?
And uh,
I think I'm going to specialize in Nogi
submission,
grappling with Marcello.
I've never rolled with Marcello
recently.
He's been,
uh,
you know,
he's been injured.
I think he's coming back now pretty
strong from what happened to him.
He got his knee hurt doing something.
I'm not a hundred percent sure what,
maybe snowboarding.
Yeah,
exactly.
Perfect.
He loves really.
It's awesome dude.
Once you will,
eventually you'll,
you'll,
you'll do it.
I've been skiing.
It's,
it's different when you're going
sideways.
Was it different?
It's first of all to better.
It's,
it's,
uh,
it's better really.
Once you go snowboarding for years,
you don't go back.
For years I was snowboarding like when I
was like back to guy was like,
I was skiing for losers on the
snowboard.
Snowboard is so much cooler.
So I do it for like four or five years,
just like,
you know,
once a year,
twice a year,
you know,
family would go on trips or whatever.
And then one year my friends like,
dude,
you gotta try out scheme,
you know,
see how you see how you.
Like now at snowboarding I was at a
level,
this is my strategy snowboarding as fast
as I possibly fucking could in a
straight line going down the hill and
then fall to stop myself.
Alright.
Sounds like getting almost knocked out,
you know,
falling into the snow.
How fast are you going?
I have no idea.
Who knows?
And I'm only going like,
you know,
bunny slopes or like,
blue,
whatever,
the blue squares,
intermediate,
whatever I could never do.
I was fearful of a black black diamonds
straight down I saw put on skis.
I put on skis the first time I try it.
Black diamond,
no problem.
You know what I mean?
It's like it,
it's,
I mean clearly you're not doing it
technically,
but like it's safe.
You know what I mean?
I could,
I felt like comfortable,
like at slow myself down snowboarding.
I just feel like you're looking in one
direction.
It's just tunnel vision.
You're going as fast as you can.
It's so.
It's so much more.
Uncontrolled is difficult.
So what you're saying is snowboarding is
more exciting.
I think there for a thrill seeking point
of view.
Hell yeah.
It feels more dangerous to me.
You're locked into this board.
You don't have your two legs to be able
to separate and balance there.
So often the snowboarders collide with
each other if you're going that fast.
When I'm on the slopes is the high much
higher percentage than everybody else,
but you just got to learn to turn inside
because really snowboarding and skiing
is just the art of slowing down,
brake,
brake and slowing down and slowing down.
Slowing down because as soon as you
don't slow down,
boom,
you go down like a Ronnie Bono.
Oh,
back to Marcello.
He.
What would he be?
Someone that I think personally has a
Jujitsu fan you against Marsala would be
the most interesting.
Like if that was metamorris yeah,
Jesus.
I would never superfight Ebi.
Yeah,
we'd never call them out or anything.
You just don't have any right to,
but I'm not going to be an amazing
match.
I love that matchup.
I'm rematch with chrome.
Absolutely.
I asked for it all the time,
but again,
I can't really call crone out.
He beat me so I,
you know,
I called them out in a sense like,
hey,
I want to fight you,
but I would never talk shit about chrome
to try and get them to fight me because
it's just not.
That's not fair.
Like what do you mean
made that match was the finish that made
that match and it made the match for
both of you.
It's,
it's like it made the match so much more
exciting than if you guys just went to a
draw.
If you went to a stalemate at the end
and maybe you know,
you were both clenched up with each
other and it ended,
that would've not been as good with.
That was a perfect example of what's
possible at high level Jujitsu.
So exciting.
The fact that he did submit,
you blew up.
Yeah.
You put him in some terrible positions,
man.
I mean you,
you had him in some bad spots.
We were like,
Holy Shit.
And you know,
Eddie and I went off about it.
We watched the video.
We was there alive.
Yeah,
that's right.
I was like,
we were all crying.
Oh,
is he gonna beat crone.
and then one minute left,
it was chrome.
They broke you guys up.
He looked at Hixson.
Does a video of you explaining
Gary and then we play the video of the
fight on the Internet.
It's on youtube.
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
So it's,
it's cool that like,
something like that exists and I just
think that we need to have more of those
out there.
And then eventually Hollywood people are
going to go,
hey,
whoa,
whoa.
What is.
This is wild shit.
Hold on.
Nobody.
Nobody has this locked down.
This isn't on television for the UFC has
established a very firm like huge
property in the UFC.
Like that's what everybody connects with
mma.
MMA equals UFC and if you're fighting
for Bella tour,
they go,
oh wow.
So you're going to be fight for the UFC
someday.
Like it just what it is.
There's none of that with grappling.
It doesn't exist.
Right?
How many times have you heard a guy
trying to?
2,000,
2000.
One,
Two guys that were already deeply into
the UFC was we saw a 93.
It's 2000,
2001.
Even to this day.
You run into guys that aren't into it
and they've seen it a couple times.
Just a couple dudes rolling around.
I was like,
uneventful for them.
For them it was uneventful,
but when we saw it,
what did we see?
What was the difference?
The difference was the fucking
tournament.
The first one I saw was UFC two and that
was $60 tournament because it ends up
being.
When you see one match at a time,
it's like a documentary.
You see maybe that first round you
don't,
you don't know one looks familiar,
but that second round you're like,
oh shit,
that dude with the long hair against.
That's the Ninja Dude.
And then the semifinals,
or you're like,
Holy Shit,
how's that?
Gonna work out.
You just saw their career that night and
then the finals,
holy Saint,
Patrick Smith.
You're like,
Holy Shit.
I went from hating hoists in the opening
round because he beat my karate guys,
rooting for him and just being as
follower right there at that final,
because I.
Pat Smith was kind of a,
you know,
he was like a heel even within that.
So it was a movie.
That's why we got to work with the
people that watch it back then got
obsessed with it instantly.
It was the greatest thing ever.
If they would have been single matches
and you didn't know those dudes,
it would probably would.
We wouldn't have that drama unfold.
There's just be a bunch of single
matches so you can't.
Exactly.
And you can't do that with mma,
but you can totally do that.
Would you did too.
And that's why Abu Dhabi is so special
because it's a bunch of 16 man brackets
supervised,
but the only thing that I think Abu
Dhabi should have a $60 bracket habit,
like four days,
like a whole week.
What?
Every day is a different one because the
way they do it now it's like it's like
watching three movies at the same time.
You're not watching it unfold and then
on the Internet you just watch a link of
the finals and then you go back and
watch a semifinal.
You don't.
It's like watching a movie in pieces and
you already know the ending,
but what what metamorris does is have a
single fight.
Every fight is his main stage.
There's three matches or 12 matches,
like the moon deals.
It's one match at a time showcase,
but it's not a tournament style.
So.
So what I'm trying to do is I took the
best from Abu Dhabi and the best from
metamorris and try to combine it
metamorris submission only one match out
of time.
And Abu Dhabi,
the super 16 man brackets that are in
themselves,
if you watch it one by one,
one at a time center stage,
it's mindblowing.
When you watch it like that,
we need to watch it like that.
In my opinion.
That's what made Ebi Ebi too,
which I mean Gary went and submitted
everybody in that 16 man bracket.
Every dude he ran through and in the
final,
by the time we got to the final with him
and Richie,
Richie blew through everybody on his end
of the bracket,
so it was Richie and Gary.
The.
Everyone was going nuts because they saw
it unfold one at a time.
That's the secret,
right?
That's a very good point.
You know,
they're trying to do that with glory and
I am actually.
I've been advising people against it.
I think it's a terrible idea for
kickboxing and too much data,
too much damage.
People going to get hurt for cut.
It's not going to want to get Kayo.
That's the problem you get sometimes you
get killed and you still fighting when
you know you get,
you get knocked out and you're still
fighting on autopilot and then it's over
like what happened?
You want,
you want a decision like what I've seen
that happen with guys,
it's not say Gloria,
they fought three times.
They had the last man standing
tournament in La.
We went to that right.
You can do that,
that should.
They fought three fucking times,
man box and the first fight Joe
Schilling had to fight for rounds
because the third after the third round
was a draw.
That's how powerful tournament's on when
you watch it,
it's so powerful that you might not be
able to do on kickboxing is all this
shit could go wrong.
It's root,
it's risky,
but the tournament is so exciting that
if we could pull this off and no one
gets hurt and we get lucky,
it's a grand show that people are going
to watch over and and when you watch it
from the beginning to end,
you feel it.
It's a documentary.
That's a very good point though.
That's a very good point and I think if
someone got ahold of that,
someone who produces sports television
and realize that this is like an unsung
property like this is out there.
The sport is at a very high level right
now.
Guys are very,
very exciting and no one has capitalized
on it.
No one's put it on television and no
one's making money with it,
but they just don't know.
They just don't know how to do it for.
First of all,
you got to get rid of the points.
Know I put together Ebi,
like if some old Jewish guy who owned
some network said,
I don't know about this martial art
stuff,
but I like your kid.
I'm going to give you one season.
I don't know about no Jujitsu or
anything.
I'm going to give you one season.
As soon as the ratings drop,
it's out.
We got a deal.
Then you would go,
oh shit,
okay.
We got to get rid of the fucking game we
got.
We got to get rid of the points and we
got to have a tournament.
You've got to see it unfold because
that's what makes the ultimate fighter
so awesome.
It's at the tournament,
although it doesn't happen in one day,
but it's still a tournament.
You see the brackets unfolding just like
the march madness.
I hate basketball,
but I understand why there's
tournaments.
You see it all unfolding.
You see the drama,
you know,
and,
and that is what's missing from
grappling.
That's why,
in my opinion,
that's why you can't get it on tv
because in all the other formats,
it's just too much stalling,
too much holding.
We need right now to dispute your claims
because right now you're talking crazy.
Disrespectful,
so about biggie.
There is no live.
Let no let go.
Let go.
I think that's one of his quotes.
There's nothing funnier than Brazilian
misinterpretations of English.
I said Eddie,
a picture of a tee shirt that I've found
in my closet way back in the day of
Waleed Ish.
My leg t shirt.
Yeah.
What the fuck did it say on it?
It said on the back there's a cartoon
picture.
Him being always on me and he's like,
he's actually the nicest,
sweetest guy in the sky.
All those mean looks.
It's all him doing pro wrestling.
He's actually super sweet,
Super Nice.
He'll take a picture and then he'll be
like a little kid.
He'll look at his picture.
A classic one back in late,
2004,
2003.
I love that dude.
He has a shirt where it's him standing
there like in a cartoon character and it
says on the top,
don't be coward.
Don't run from them.
Don't run off the fight.
Yes,
don't be coward.
Don't run off the fight.
Can you imagine?
Imagine what a.
When he turned in,
like when he went to the t shirt shop
place,
there's an American guy.
It was like,
this is bullshit.
Put it now.
Now I can.
Okay,
we're going to need some initials on
this right now.
Initial right there and right there.
It was crazy.
Let's just use the damn shirt.
I'm trying to find a printing it.
We're like,
boss,
come here.
I just want to make sure it says don't
run off
the fine.
We'll call it that.
I'm trying to be coward and he's just
like,
I just want your approval here and
initial here and I see he didn't tattoo
it on himself.
I want to get this out of the way.
Now you Mr.
Smile,
you realize what you have written here
and this is exactly how you would like
print it.
It goes to court.
You know what I mean?
To do a selfie video that I'm trying to
find the picture I know and claims that
they fucked up.
Yeah.
This is not the true Jujitsu.
I never say run off.
Run off the stupid.
Doesn't even make sense.
Yeah.
He was a.
That was a crazy match with him and
hoists.
Remember that shit on the beach in Rio.
They fought like with Matt,
so were laid out in the sand.
Everybody got sand in their eyes and
their face.
There's fucking sand everywhere.
They slapped him some mats down on the
bed.
She always had big balls to take that
because while lead was fucking everyone
up back then and while lead he got him
in a clock choke,
put them to sleep.
That's right.
That's a weird thing to watch too.
I can't believe they let him take that
bike.
Is Jen the general consensus in like
late like after the UFC around like how
good is hoist Jujitsu for real and he
was never like a world champion or a
national champion or anything like that.
Everybody knew that.
Everyone knew his.
He had decent Jujitsu.
He wasn't lighting the world on fire.
So for him to take a vow that volleyball
match man that showed he had gigantic
balls because volleyed was a destroyer.
Yeah.
That's a hugely ballsy move.
And you know,
he got choked asleep,
which I think was very important for
Jujitsu just to show like you.
Everyone looked at hoists.
Gracie,
rightly so as this massive innovator,
this,
this pioneer of Jujitsu and mma I heroes
was after the UFC gets choked out.
Yeah.
He's a hero of Jujitsu and then you go,
okay,
well listen,
there's guys out there that are another
level,
another level above him,
you know,
and this is one of them.
Well that's what he said about Hicks.
And he said,
well,
I'm not actually that good Hickson's 10
times better than me.
And then the Japanese went,
oh,
okay.
You sure?
Okay.
Do you have his number?
I found that it's not a cartoon cartoon.
I found it.
It's actually a picture of him.
I thought it was a cartoon,
but we had more than one eddie.
There was more than one.
No,
no,
no.
This is the front.
The back.
You need the back of the bag of it as a
card.
Okay.
Let me see.
No mercy,
no rules,
no pain.
This is a different one then man.
This is the one that things don't go
together.
I have the same shirt on the back.
One hundred percent.
I haven't him.
He's in.
He's in cartoon form two and the bad.
All yoked and shit.
There was definitely more than one of
those ridiculous shirts though,
but that's why a those is so funny
because you know,
if you think that he's actually being
conservative and not those kind of
conservative with his language.
He's a.
he's not a stick man.
He's a real motherfucker schick shtick
as the stick.
I say no,
no,
no.
Stick.
It's like his act out a lot.
He's actually that cocky in real life.
People think amazing.
It's super confident guy.
No,
he really is like that.
Would you be willing to match him with
the game?
Because the game is his strong suit.
I wouldn't.
I never said anything bad about him and
he's always been nice to me.
Fuck it.
No comment.
He's scared the videos when Nate Diaz is
taking it serious?
Yeah.
Oh my God.
Fuck man.
The first time I met him it was a joke
either.
Not a joke.
He's,
he's really that arrogant.
It everyone thinks he's just pretending
to be arrogant.
He was doing,
she was doing.
I'm showing my respect because his
passport has specked.
So you said,
you said that someone was thinking about
trying to turn submission grappling into
a television show,
like who's trying to do it?
Oh No,
no,
no.
I was just saying that people were
trying to be trying to be like the UFC
and the way that you were talking about
how somebody be fighting in Beltour.
It's like,
Oh yeah,
when are you going to be in UFC?
People are trying to do that.
Um,
I've had multiple organizations now
asked me to be exclusive to their
organization for competing.
Yup.
So much.
No,
sounds terrible.
If they pay enough cash or enough money.
I don't know about all that.
Man.
I,
I'm,
I'm in favor of.
Look,
the big issue with with the MMA is in
the big issue with boxing has always
been that trying to get the best guys to
be able to fight the best guys when
you're exclusive for one promoter,
exclusive for another promoter and it
makes things super problematic.
Independent contracts for independent
matches and no longterm commitment to
things is the smart way to go for
grapplers because if that gets
established as the Goto,
then it favors the grappa and then
there's no advantage that the promoter
has over the grappa.
The grappa could always find another
promoter,
so if the,
if the.
If the promoters get along with the
grapplers and everybody agrees with how
much money everybody's making and it
seems cool and fair,
then that would be a good way to do it.
You know,
so no one has a lockdown on the market.
I think that's very important.
They're trying to adjust me to turn down
the offer.
Yeah,
yeah.
I did.
Good for you,
man.
Good for you.
That takes balls and that's a smart
thing to do because I think if,
if everybody's just set that precedent
and we created this market where the
grapplers where the star,
like this is what's important.
If people want to see,
you know,
fill in the blank,
Marcella Garcia versus Gary tone of
people want to see that match.
The real benefit is of that match.
The benefactors of that mass should be
Marcella Garcia and Gary Tonin.
And then of course some money should go
to the promoter.
You know,
some money should,
but it's what's the only thing that's
exciting about submission grappling is
the submission grapplers.
That's it.
Yep.
Because if you're not selling that,
you're selling air.
Yep.
That's it.
That's all you got.
So if you're locked up to one
organization,
it's also limits.
Matches,
matches.
You can't make it can only do a certain
number of matches per year.
Right?
So what,
what organization puts on 12 matches a
year right now is the same guy every,
every match.
What do you say?
I'm sure that the promoter,
whoever's doing this,
I have no idea.
I'm sure he's probably saying to
themselves,
Hey,
if we want to be as big as the UFC,
UFC type stuff.
Exactly,
and it's just such a flawed mentality.
I feel like for the sport doesn't have
to be so young and it's so tiny and
there's very little money.
Every single one of these organizations,
these professional organizations,
Ebi,
Metamorris,
Polaris,
all these things that are popping up
here and there.
They're all doing amazing things for the
sport.
They're broadening the audience for
submission grappling.
It's so silly to think that you need to
be just the guy.
Everybody is cross promoting each other.
I like when my guys fight Metamorris,
right?
They're going to fight.
It helped me personally.
My guys,
Gio Boogie,
Nathan Orchard,
my guys,
I try to get them on metamorris carts,
texted hallock go,
dude,
how could you not want ge or is on your
fucking show?
He just blew through everybody in the
Abu Dhabi trials all within two minutes
to get everybody.
One Eva one as a featherweight one is a
bad way.
Finished everybody.
How do you not want that guy to go
there?
You're dealing with a rational
individual.
That's the problem.
Well,
the people that are doing Jujitsu,
the people that are involved in Jujitsu,
if you're involved in these matches,
if you're involved in competition,
most likely 99 percent of the time
you're making your money off of
teaching.
Right?
Most of the people that are running
these schools,
that's where they're making their money,
so it's not like a situation where
there's this giant piece of pie that
everybody's battling over,
so everybody wants dominance.
It's like it's beneficial for you to get
your students into metamorris because
then they could highlight how good of a
teacher you are.
Good for everybody.
That's good.
It's good for Metamorris.
It's good for Ebi when he comes back,
because will never be exclusive.
He's always going to be an Abi.
Oh wait.
Yep.
And so why would I want to keep them
from metamorris and back and forth?
I'd tell her,
look,
let's let's work together and use.
Let's let me blow up the guys and then
ship them off to you.
I love Metamora,
but he makes the most money that way.
And then we come back,
we,
we bring them back over to Ebi.
I think this is the new way of thinking.
I think this,
this kind of exists in everything exists
in martial arts were martial arts today.
Like here's a perfect example of
Jujitsu.
Guys are constantly trading techniques
to each other,
constantly showing each other things.
The whole thing about martial arts in
the old days,
like in the sixties,
in the seventies,
was how secret it was.
They had secret techniques and they
would hide from you the seeing.
You couldn't teach white people member
brutally got in trouble for teaching
white people.
Same thing with Mexicans.
Either you couldn't teach western,
couldn't teach Americans you,
you know,
they wanted to keep it within the
Chinese culture.
Now it's the total opposite.
Now everybody's exchanging and
everybody's just trying to find out
what's the best shit.
Who's the best at this?
And you get guys together and you match
them up with each other.
I mean,
that's essentially the new thinking and
new thinking for everything.
And the fact that this is how it is
right now so far with Jujitsu,
with professional submission grappling
is awesome.
That means it has a shot.
But as soon as someone comes along and
buys the whole thing and then wants to
put on only,
like you said,
12 matches a year,
like you compete,
how often do you compete in as once or
twice.
Once to.
Twice a month.
Yeah.
That's insane.
And that's one of the reasons why you're
so good.
You're not just training all the time,
you're throwing yourself into battle all
the time.
You know,
I've seen quite a few of your,
your matches online and I saw the recent
one where you,
uh,
what's the guy's name?
The leg locks specialists.
The MMA guy I've seen held.
He's really good,
man.
Yeah.
That was a really,
really interesting fight.
It was really cool to watch.
He was probably one of the most game
people that showed up to that show.
Like he was prepared.
I felt it.
I could see it,
you know,
like man,
that was a,
that was,
he was there.
He showed up for that Mesh for MMA.
His jujitsu technique is stellar.
Yeah.
You talk about leg locks at work,
at mma and leg lockers that are having
success.
Your number one guy a man back in the
day when he used to go for leg locks a
lot.
Now he really doesn't.
He's still awesome.
Uh,
and then you say,
oh,
that's right Marci Mel,
because he'll pull guard just like some
art right into.
He'll hook up your,
the performance that,
that,
uh,
really impressed me.
There's a,
there are two performances and
metamorris man,
when you went against kit bail and you
just,
you didn't even leg lock.
And he guillotine.
That setup was so beautiful.
That's a crazy setup.
Your arm was in a such a weird position
when you were,
when you guys were trying to scramble.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And in Metamorris,
the whole metamorris is in a constant
struggle with how do we put together
exciting fights.
That's what it's all about it.
So there's a show comes out,
everyone on the internet goes boring,
boring.
Oh,
this one was great.
Are born.
It's always like.
So if you have a boring match,
people on the Internet are gonna fucking
flame.
You.
That's when everybody was mad at Brendan
Shot.
Yeah,
exactly.
And,
and,
uh,
maybe the last I like them whether
they're boring or not.
I liked the whole atmosphere.
I liked going to metamorris and hanging
out.
I fucking love it.
It's a high level.
There's a lot of money behind it.
Um,
I wish I had that kind of money behind
Abi then it would be on like donkey
Kong,
but it's beautiful.
It's beautiful.
I love metal.
I love even when some matches are
boring,
I love it because then I talked to the
guy next to me,
you know what?
I'm just trying to watch a match.
Nachos.
They're outstanding.
You know,
the boring matches when the key matches.
Come on dude,
look around.
Everybody is on facebook and on
Instagram,
on boring young.
Everybody is like communicating right
during the match.
It's,
it's incredible.
But,
but,
but I'm in the middle of all that.
No one can say he just saving shell
after Shell because his matches.
He goes out and just finishes.
I'm boring show except for Gary.
Gary tone and with two RS and a Kit
Dale,
so you could find that.
And then that does.
He does maxwell match.
You know dude,
man,
you just,
you without you right now man.
Without you metamorris would be Ooh,
you're keeping a metamorris afloat
because they're just boring.
Match after boring match.
Again.
I love Jujitsu.
I understand boring matches.
I think you've got to get.
I told her like don't.
He doesn't want to go pure and Augie
because he feels like it's disrespectful
to assist the spirit of Jujitsu and
shit.
I told him,
I told him I go do what Abu Dhabi does
util will make the decision.
Let the fighters make the decision.
And so you could wear anything you want.
And you know what?
When they have that decision,
knowing where shit.
All the guys that love the GE,
they take it the fuck off.
That's how I.
But the hobby is I would be.
You could worry can you can at Quito
pants.
You can wear anything.
You want the shit dude,
come on.
Come in with some.
At the top would be the one that you
were at.
There was this Japanese fighter in a
blue superman outfit.
Remember that guy?
People loved him,
but he showed up like several costumes.
It's like Spiderman.
Superman is if you do that,
if you do that,
the promoter,
he is off the hook.
Say,
I want it to be.
I want them to wear whatever they want.
You know what?
Nobody would work.
I think it comes down to what Joe said,
a huge events for the guy.
They have all these handles and weapons.
You'd be wearing the weapon around your
neck and dude,
go straight.
Marco,
who was straight fucking those bikini
briefs.
They were in Paris in pride,
in pride.
You could have all Jitsu guys go to
pride.
The only one who's wearing a [inaudible]
Yoshida noise and he wasn't even
Jujitsu,
but all the other Brazilians,
they're wearing those bikini's that they
were on the beach.
They're shaving their legs.
The greasy,
the greener.
Mccoys took the g off.
Remember?
Boy started wearing the g pants when he
fought Aki Bono.
G Pants top.
Yup.
And here it is in Metamorris.
Hallock.
Please don't sue us for this.
We're trying to pop up metamorris no
need to get crazy and this.
This is the match that made kid dale
lift weights.
I follow instagram.
Oh Dude,
he was.
He was jacked during that.
Everybody kept telling me how much I
rather than it going to be wrong.
No were wrong.
He was very big,
but now he's giant and you've seen the
pictures of him on his instagram.
Holy Shit.
That guy's swole.
The fuck up now.
You made them lift weights.
If you look at his instagram,
you look at it is why are you looking?
You're looking at funding.
Someone said something stupid.
What's APP when they're introducing you?
Because they can call me a five time
Nogi world champion,
which is not true.
So views that.
Chris,
whose idea was that together?
I don't know man.
Chris Howard is old school,
black belt man,
old school Machado.
Linear.
She's been around a long time.
That's cool to see that.
He's refereeing this.
Yeah.
Our.
Our video sucks.
If Fat Dick Today.
Dude,
I love that role.
And unguided do the cut to a photo.
Little skyline.
Fuck.
Is that WHO's running?
Who's running the operating board?
So you pull half guard here immediately.
Tisdale's on top of you.
And what do you,
uh,
you try and establish here when you're
doing this,
what's your go to shit.
It's Camorra's from here or I'm probably
trying to come underneath them for a leg
lock.
Um,
so.
So you play in it light here.
We'll relaxed.
No one's gone crazy yet.
You guys got a long match,
right?
It's like a 20 minute match.
So when you have a match like this,
are you a,
are you really consciously like
budgeting your time and your energy a
little bit?
I use you,
you use your energy efficiently.
When I,
I'll feel I'll use my energy when I feel
like it's a,
it's going to help me attack,
you know what I mean?
I'm not going to use energy just to push
and pull,
you know,
if I'm going to,
I'm going to use it to make sure I'm not
in danger to make sure my opponents.
So now you're going after his leg.
Damn beautiful.
Jamie.
And then you'd have to look at this
point wasn't very good.
Um,
you know,
my form there is a little off to nasty
transition.
There's definitely some things that I
could've done a hell of a man that
looks,
that looks terrifying.
And he's rolling here?
Yes.
Okay.
Dale gets out.
How dare he,
you could tell it looked like you were
at everything.
Go right back to this as your go to
shit.
Huh?
Outside he'll hook.
You need to be perfect for them to work,
man.
It's just so much detail.
But uh,
yeah man and back in half.
And then some camera work.
Metamorris save on lights.
They go back to kids with every good
passer.
Very good.
He actually showed up to my job right
before this.
Yeah,
I heard he was training with you guys
and coincidentally did we were working
on your site.
So then coincidentally it wasn't trying
to,
that's what he was saying.
He was saying,
Oh yeah,
they're trying to get.
That's all we were doing for a while and
he showed up and he's fighting gary
toning and I'm like,
I'm not going to change my,
my,
I gotta show this to my students.
So I apologize for that.
No,
it's all good,
man.
It was not on purpose.
I've never met him.
He just showed up to my gym.
Really Nice Guy.
Cool Dude.
I ended up falling on instagram and all
that stuff,
but yeah,
he's a funny dude.
I'm sure.
Kindergarten stuff compared to what you
guys know what I'm agenda so that the
computer fucking up.
Yeah.
So we get back out to the feet and then
me,
I drilled this with my wrestling coach
for,
you know,
we do this all the time.
He's still drilling.
I'm just establishing the under hook
from collar ties and hitting a good snap
down from here to get a good snap down
and get control of the head now and then
I just follow it and now my hands aren't
connected yet.
Right.
And then I'm trying to connect my hands
finally get it.
And once the hands get connected he
tries to struggle out a couple more
times and finally sinks in deep.
I can't believe we can't see this j
we've got to deal with that today.
Okay.
This is annoying.
Is the one time where it'd be really
nice to have video.
I can get Zach to help you,
Jamie,
and yeah,
we can do whatever you got to take care
of that.
Can you play it at all?
Or.
We done stuff on mad right at the sweet
spot.
Yeah.
No,
what's happening Jamie?
There it is.
There it goes and he already tapped.
Perfect.
Okay.
Back it up a little bit then.
So this is the part where you don't have
your hands connected.
Yeah,
because it does have your arm.
He ducked hard so that my hands were
separated and then I connect him.
Finally get that crunching on the neck.
Then you got it from half guard here.
Huh?
Are Men or Marcella team?
Uh,
it's uh,
you know,
it's high elbow Gulati and you catch
this from half guard all the time.
Um,
yeah.
Yeah.
Well I don't set it up from half guard
but I ended up in half guard for the
finish for sure.
And then we come up a little bit.
We reset it.
Boom.
Wow.
You got a full mouth Marcella,
or you guys call it high elbow.
High Elbow.
But yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I mean,
Marcella uses it.
Yeah.
No,
finished in full garb with his arm
trapped.
His arm was trapped.
His was his left arm trapped.
Uh,
I didn't see.
I didn't see that.
I'd have to watch it again.
I don't know if I intentionally trapped
it,
but damn,
that guillotine right there,
man.
That was huge one seeing Marcello hit it
all the time.
The only reason I called it Marcella
teen,
I didn't know it was called high high
elbow Gilot time.
Sure.
That was a name.
But I just stuck with Marcella teen so
that in,
in the 10th planet system,
every time that comes up and it's so
crucial,
it's a part of our warm ups that I want
Marcello to make sure he gets credit
because sure,
no one's had more success with it than
anybody I would say because of that
success.
He's probably the best at it.
No,
I've seen him run through black belts.
Uh,
I've seen her run through a high level
black belt 10 times in 10 minutes.
What's the same?
The same guillotine technique,
man.
John was preaching to me to get good at
that technique for so long and like I
sucked at it for forever.
It takes a long time.
How will you connecting your hands?
Uh,
I just grab.
So when I grabbed like mid,
mid.
Should I go down past the pinky
inbetween the risks and the,
and the pinky bone and then grabbed my
left hand over the right hand,
grab my hand.
I know I've hit some on the left side
and competition.
I've gone the opposite direction.
But um,
in terms of like if I'm finishing on the
right side.
Yeah.
Left hand over.
Right.
So I've seen people hit it,
hit it like this.
I've seen people do it with 10 finger
grips.
Yup.
The difference between those,
what Marcella told me is this feels so
much easier for me,
but what Marcella says,
and uh,
Danny does it this way too,
but marcel,
we went over it.
He said he doesn't like this as opposed
to this because the guard underneath is
going to come up and reach and grab.
And if he gets in between these two
hands here,
his fingers are going to come up,
he can wreck the grip.
You got to be the grip.
But if he comes up here and I come this
way,
it doesn't matter if he grabs the
inside.
That's how most people think they're
doing right thing.
They're gone
and I still get choked.
They're gonna still get choked because
he's coming around it instead of here.
So that makes sense.
It makes a lot of sense.
There's a bunch of different.
We're talking about people don't know if
you're listening to,
especially.
There's a bunch of different ways to
hold your hands with different
submissions.
And that's one of the interesting things
about Jujitsu is that there's little
tweaks that you'll learn a little turns
and twists.
Like Einstein always likes to call it
freedom rock.
You know that one team where like,
you know,
you ever seen that commercial for
freedom rock.
It's like ridiculous.
A commercial for one of those
compilation records that you would buy
when you turn it up,
man.
So like the turning it up,
freedom rock,
like the turning your,
your,
your hand to the side and forcing the
blade of your wrist.
And this one's named,
he named me basically named the squeeze
of the dark.
There wasn't a name for what you're
technically doing,
you know?
Uh,
so he named it and it's a good name.
It's a great name.
It's freedom rock.
Just to remind you that it's just,
it's not just figure four on your arms,
you got to turn it in and squeeze.
So it's a smart thing.
It is a smart thing and it's cool that
there's those little technical things
about Jujitsu and for,
for people that get involved in it and
start realizing like from the outside,
you look at one way and then you get
involved in it and you start seeing all
the depth to it.
That's where all the Jujitsu nerds come
into place because that's what it does.
It seem.
It doesn't seem to jive like people
like,
well how come these really computer
oriented,
nerdy kind of dudes are so in love with
Jujitsu?
Well,
you know,
like Donna,
her always talks about there's a video
that we were talking about earlier that
they playing on the underground with him
talking about it being high level
problem,
problem solving under stress,
and that's what's exciting about people
who are,
maybe they would be into video games or
maybe they'd be into chats or maybe
they'd be into all sorts of problem
solving type things,
but you get doing it in real time.
The rush of success is so much better.
Like the rush of winning a chess match,
I'm sure is great,
but do you think it is good as you
choking kit dale out of here,
get the fuck out of here.
There's no way.
It's not even possible.
You know,
that rush is the ultimate rush.
That's the,
you're dead rush.
This is not a like a Bang Bang.
You're dead in a virtual sense when
you're wake character.
This is like you're playing death.
Somebody overlaid some of your podcasts,
uh,
over some like Jujitsu video,
some real about you talking about
submissions and like what submissions
really are,
what a tap really is.
And you're like,
oh yeah,
that's I just possibly killed you right
there.
Yeah.
You're killing dudes.
You killed.
Killed Kennedy mean perfect.
Perfect.
It's also beautiful for people that are
practicing it that you could kill a guy
like that and look,
he's fine afterwards.
You're holding his hand up.
He's fine.
Means neck was sore the next day,
but other than that he's fine.
He didn't get knocked out.
He didn't get beat up.
So it's almost like a more ethical form
of combat entertainment.
If somebody was going to put it on,
somebody decided to put the Ebi on spike
tv or something like that.
It's like,
you know,
everybody has a problem with,
with head trauma.
Like that fucking kid that just died.
A boxer just died the other day of
trauma.
It's going to happen no matter what if
you have combat sports.
But in Jujitsu it's way,
way,
way safer.
Yeah,
absolutely safe for longterm for the
participants.
And you could still like you watched
that match,
man,
that's exciting.
Shit.
I dare anybody who knows nothing about
Jujitsu,
just watch Gary Thompson versus Kit Dale
and watch it with an open mind and watch
those transitions that you're going
through and you realize like,
Whoa,
this is a.
they're doing a crazy thing here.
They're like,
they're like Helson Gracie.
I had Steve Maxwell and the podcast the
other day and Helson Gracie.
Somebody asked him to describe Jujitsu
and I guess his English is not the best
in the world and he's got a little bit
of an accent.
He goes,
this is Jujutsu.
You do this.
Then I do that.
Then you do this.
Then I do that forever.
Isn't that the dopest fucking answer me?
That is kind of what it is in a way
until one of us almost dies or keep it
until you can't keep it up anymore,
and then that guy beats you.
The super hyper way of killing someone
and breaking their limbs.
John dammit her.
Remember we hung out with them that one
night he said,
if you,
if you look at it,
a striking is the least intelligent way
of taking someone out,
grappling that's the most intelligent
way.
Striking is the most caveman way of
fighting,
just keep hitting each other's heads
over and over until someone goes down
when grappling is like,
let me take this guy down and
scientifically put them,
put them to sleep and get the hell out
of that is true,
but in a situation where you can't
grapple with someone,
like if you're in a street fight,
would you want to be in a street fight
with Marcella Garcia in a bar or would
you want to be in the street fight with
John Wayne.
John Wayne Park is going to be head kick
and motherfuckers and putting people in
the hospital with elbows to the face
like you tried to get close to that
dude.
You're going to get your head smashed
in.
John always talks about striking eyes,
like inability to do crazy amounts of
damage in such a short period of time.
So there's clearly pluses and minuses to
both in real life situations.
Absolutely.
You don't want to just go to the ground
striking skills.
I wish I was a kickboxer.
It would be nice to be able to have the
confidence to throw,
you know,
you could take three dudes out if you're
striking move.
If you time it perfectly,
you can take three dudes out for those
who don't know and they fuck with Melvin
manhoef in a bar.
First guys asleep dead.
There's two guys left.
One guy runs says fuck that,
and then it's one on one and that guy's
dead.
He's dead.
Badr,
Hari Badr,
Hari.
Apparently they,
one of the reasons why he was from jail
more than once,
I think beating the fuck out of people.
One of the reasons why he's in jail.
They took this guy's leg and they
stomped it and snapped his Shin in half
and this guy is fucked the wrong dude to
fuck with,
you know,
in a,
in a street confrontation.
So I see both sides.
You know,
it's,
it's good to.
You can get like super
high level and striking.
It is intelligent.
It's more intelligent than wrestling
with somebody.
You know,
if you're in a bar and a bunch of other
people around and you're in a melee type
situation,
if you can be a John Donner,
her,
you know,
look,
you could,
you could protect yourself for sure.
You know,
John is an excellent blackbelt.
Anybody that goes one on one with them
is just going to get mangled.
Some untrained person doesn't know any
better,
but I'll,
I'll be willing to bet that even
multiple people that have tried to
attack John had some trouble as a
bouncer.
Absolutely many years of his life.
He's had to deal with a lot of that.
So he would use you as a shield.
Oh,
start using your arms to beat other
people senseless with.
But the point being is not unintelligent
to have a John Wayne par skillset and
there's,
there's definitely an intelligent way to
use striking obviously Badr Hari or hey,
I didn't say that.
I was just throwing her under the bus.
Why do you feel like we're doing all the
time and just completely misconstruing
everything he's ever said to us.
Just ruining all of it.
There's no either or.
Because.
Because there's a lot of intelligence
and there's a lot of technique to high
level striking if you watch like those
Lawrence Kenshin breakdowns or the Jack
Slack breakdowns on the under
underground.
He goes over like the real technical
process of why like bluecat or you know,
a yachtsman Cli on the really high level
Thai guys.
Why they're so good.
There's a lot of shit going on.
It just looks like they're smashing each
other with their bones.
But nope.
How one guy keeps getting smashed and
the other guy does all the smashing like
this.
And I know,
I know guys that are dummies,
shit and amazing Jujitsu.
So,
you know,
I know some really super strong and the
same either currently.
Um,
I'm,
I'm excited about Jujitsu right now.
I think there's like one of the best
times for whatever because of all the,
the,
like people talking about it on the
Internet and all these online
communities that have formed,
it seems to me electric Jitsu has a lot
of enthusiasm behind it right now.
The gracie nationals and gracie world,
they proved rose gracie prove that you
can do submission only because before
that it was submission only.
What a submission only matched with like
a a dream,
like a fantasy.
What if,
what if gracie nationals,
gracie world's made it work and then
metamorris did the whole prestigious
single match,
you know,
UFC type event.
And what do you think Abu Dhabi should
do?
Because that's where all the money,
right?
That guy has more money than anybody on
the planet should do.
Submission only Ebi rules.
Not because I made it up as I personally
think I'm constantly changed like the
overtime I'm tweaking it.
I'm trying to make it so that someone
says,
well what about if a dude does this?
And overtime like,
Oh shit,
we got to change.
I was having.
I had a long conversation with John
Banner about a month ago about the
overtime.
What do we do right here?
I'm old.
I'm not going to be one of those guys.
It's going to see a glaring problem.
I'm going to do what the Japanese do.
Someone presents a problem.
They go,
Oh shit,
let's make it better.
I'm going to switch it.
So,
um,
anyways,
the shake of Abu Dhabi has the most
influence,
the most enthusiasm.
He is a black belt.
That's the guy.
Yeah.
If anybody's to take shape,
top nunes,
the guy who's going to take this and
make it mainstream,
I think he should do each tournament on
a separate day.
Make it like a week thing everyday at
different and just one movie that you
see or maybe two a day,
you see it one at a time,
you stream it,
you know,
you do it one at a time.
To me,
I,
I knew I had a feeling it was going to,
it's going to be that powerful when you
watch it unfold.
But when we actually did Ebi wanting to
man,
it was,
it was incredible to the people that
were there were coming up to me and
saying constantly.
And I mean they were saying that was the
best tournament I've ever seen.
It's only because they saw that way one
match at a time.
By the time they got the GL Martinez and
Jeff Glover in the final triple
overtime,
the place went nuts.
Do you think it's possible to do
something like this and stream it like a
Netflix service?
We're a bunch of people already have the
service and all they have to do is just
click on it,
you know,
or an apple TV type deal where a lot of
people already have that.
Like if you get access to Netflix,
you get access to $70,
million homes.
There's still people that for whatever
reason,
they don't have the ability to get the
Internet on their TV so you don't get
them.
But the people that do.
The people that have Internet connected
TV,
a lot of fucking people have Netflix,
man.
Yeah.
So much.
So they're sponsoring television shows.
They're making their own shows.
They got this Marco Polo show that's
pretty fucking dope dude.
And it's like a really expensive show.
Like you could tell they spent a lot of
money making this thing.
I'm down to take Abi to the ultimate
heights.
I just want.
I want you Jitsu on TV.
There's no reason why we can't have a
Jujitsu TV on TV.
We have dog Frisbee,
we have all this crazy Frisbee dudes
pulling tractor trailers with teeth.
Come on,
you can't.
You can't put metamorris on TV.
You can't put Abudabi on TV.
I think it just.
It's really simple.
It's got to be some mission only.
It's got to be Nogi.
If it's going to be on tv,
you ain't going to see on TV.
Have better chance putting chess on TV.
Yeah,
I agree with you with that.
There's just a lot of matches that wind
up being stalemates where they're
holding onto the collar and it's also.
It's,
it's as much as it's an interesting
learning tool and it's a great.
It's great to learn that if you get in a
fight with someone who's got a winter
coat on.
The reality is when we're looking at
sport like combat sport,
we're looking at Jujitsu,
we're looking at Jujitsu and MMA.
They should be interchangeable and
they're not.
They're not interchangeable.
When you have a gate,
they are when you have no gate,
so it seems pretty cut and dry straight
forward.
I mean,
I think if someone just wants to do
Jujitsu and ag,
it's fun to do.
It's great.
It's a great way to do it.
It's a good way to slow the game down.
You know,
a lot of older guys like it,
especially because of that reason.
It's like chess.
Chess is a great game to play.
You have to be really smart.
It's,
it's,
uh,
it's fun to play,
but you're not going to put it on Fox
anytime soon.
Nothing wrong with Jujitsu with the gay.
But I agree that for the,
for Nogi,
like the difference between Nogi is it
just smoothly transitions into mma
except for a few variables like the
getting punched when you go in for leg
locks and stuff,
the UFC is the hottest rising sport on
the planet.
There's millions and millions and
millions of fans all over the world that
are rabid fans of the UFC.
There's no reason why there can't be 1
million of those fans that are into Nogi
Jujitsu because really it's the same
thing just without the striking.
It's on the ground.
It's the same objective during the same
positions standing.
There's no striking,
but it's if you love mma,
you should be able to appreciate some
good grappling his office as exciting.
The formats,
right.
There's no points and look,
you know,
it's a single matches.
There's no reason why you can get a
fraction of all those UFC fans.
Realistically,
I'm low balling.
I don't know if it's done right.
If it's done right and marketed right,
I believe you can get 25 percent,
40 percent see there being some sort of
a cable television show where they do
it,
you know,
like a spike TV,
like spike TV has Friday night,
they have all combat sports now they
have boxing,
they're having glory and then they have
this TV.
That's why I got as many people have
that.
That's a big drop.
Is it a big drop in access over spike of
giant drop?
Really big drop.
Spike is in way more households than
access TV is millions and millions more.
Way More.
Yeah.
I mean,
I dunno,
maybe Jamie could find out the actual
numbers,
but uh,
if I had to guess I'd have differences.
Probably like $50 million plus it'd be
perfect on spike.
Yeah.
Well that kind of a place where you
would get where people were already
watching it,
you know they've already got it tuned
in.
Not that there's anything wrong with
access TV,
access TV.
He's got some awesome fights.
That's where you get lion fights like
it's the only place where you could
watch.
Not Lions.
Moitai.
You ever watch it live and what's that?
No,
no,
no.
Lion fight is probably the number one
more tie organization in America as far
as exposure because of television.
Like Kevin Ross was legit and boy guys
with more rules bigger than glory.
No,
because it's.
Gloria is not Moitai.
Gloria's kickboxing.
The difference being you can't clench.
You can't throw a nice.
The body can throw elbows in the clench.
You can't do a lot of things that you do
in white tie,
like Moitai real more tied oftentimes
winds up being a grapple fest where they
grab a hold of each other in a blast
each other with knees to the body along
the ropes.
Like that's a big part of [inaudible] if
you watch it in Thailand,
we watched some high level matches.
These guys clench up with each other and
they blast each other with the body.
They dump each other,
they sweep each other all the time and
it's just a different thing when you're
adding in knees and elbows and Gloria
doesn't have that,
just like k one didn't have that k one.
You can only for a while you could throw
elbows with two knees,
but then a lot of dudes came over there
and it just blasted guy or two,
uh,
two hands behind the head.
And then it became illegal to even throw
knees with two hands behind the head.
You can only use one hand behind that.
The owner of glory came to you and said,
Joe,
I respect your opinion.
What do you think we should do with the
rules of surely go full moly.
Tie with 100 percent
abso-fucking-lutely.
How long can they cleanse a better
sport?
It's a sport.
It's more exciting.
It's the true art of standup.
The true art of standup involves
throwing stand up,
throwing strikes in the clench,
throwing stuff like Moitai involves a
lot of elbows in tight Moitai evolves
manipulating bodies and leading people
into knees leading like Allen Joe Ban,
perfect example and his last UFC bout
the way turn that dude into that elbow
that is more Thai applied to mma.
I mean it's a combination of grappling
your opponent and striking and that's a
big part of Moitai and you don't see
that as much in glory because I think it
was along the lines of what they were
trying to do with k one,
two.
They thought it would be make it more
exciting if you had less clinching,
more exciting and the guys wouldn't get
cut up,
which is what they're worried about for
tournament's.
But I think tournament's was striking is
super fucking dangerous anyway.
I think they're asking for trouble by
having a guy like Joe Schilling,
five three.
He's fighting Simon motherfucking
Marcus,
you know,
and then after Simon mark is fucking
fighting Wayne motherfucking Barrett.
And then after that he's fighting art
and motherfucking 11 to three,
the baddest motherfuckers on earth.
And you're throwing head kicks and
punches and elbow.
You can't have elbows in there because
you get cut up.
So the the idea of tournament's,
you're preserving,
making sure the fights happen more
often,
but you can do it.
You would've killed the kicking each
other in the head.
Shin kicks the head cut.
You open like a fucking cerated knife.
I mean that can happen all the time
because you're always going to wind the
risk of the guy not being able to get
into the finals if he gets head kicked.
No towards events into dangerous.
Bring back full time.
Full Moitai.
No tournament's use tournament's for
grappling tournaments are awesome for
Jujitsu,
for Ebi,
for Metamorris tournament to the way to
go for,
for kickboxing,
100 percent Moitai.
It's a more effective art.
Is it too late for them to tweak?
Committed to these.
There's like,
like no,
it's never too late.
They own the company.
Switch it up.
Yeah,
they have bell tour.
Then they have a way more dangerous
sport anyway.
As far as like with the public's
perception would be because you're
adding in takedowns and submissions,
you're just adding,
you're just adding elbows and knees.
They should totally be able to do that
and then more time in the clench allow
guys to clench because those guys like a
guy like Simon Marcus,
you take away his clinch,
you take away a big part of his game.
A lot of his game is.
He's a really strong guy who's
excellent.
The plum.
He manipulates dudes and he's blasting
you in the by boom,
boom.
That's a big part of his fucking game.
A huge part.
Elbows in the clench.
Those are.
That's a huge part.
You take that away and you're forcing
them to just kick box and I just think
it's not as good.
Still Fun.
Glories.
Awesome to watch.
Still exciting.
Just not as good as if it was like full
more tyrell.
Damn.
I wonder if he's going to take that
advice.
I hope so man,
because full Mike more tight rules is
also way more technical.
You Watch and way more like you.
You never know what the fuck.
Like a guy like Kevin Ross,
he's a.
it's a perfect example.
He's a guy who fights total Thai style
or like bull a cow.
When you see that guy,
use everything knees to the body,
elbows in the clench,
upward coming in,
step off to the side,
leg kicks across the front of the thigh
to use in all these different
techniques.
There's so many of the clench needs.
The body needs,
the body,
elbows,
all that stuff is a part of the sport
and you,
you,
you try to make it more exciting.
That's when elite ECC were saying that
you'd go to the ground but only for 15
seconds and then you have to stay on
your backup.
We're like,
this isn't fucking mma.
When big country had our Laski down and
he was working at Kamora and they stood
him up from side control.
He's inside control.
He's got the risk pin down.
He's feeding his arm through and he's
about to try to attempt to comorbidity.
They're standing up and we're like,
what the fuck is this?
How many times where it was there a bad
stand up during a UFC fight?
When I was in your ear and I'm like,
Oh my God,
what the fuck?
And then all of a sudden you start,
you start,
you let it.
I love anytime there's a quick setup.
Anytime there's any standup,
I love it when you say something I
shouldn't be at all exists.
It's only five minutes.
You have five minutes to get a guy to
the ground and submit them and the guys
trying to kick your fucking head off the
idea that you should be stood back up
because it's boring.
Look,
if it's boring,
then you know what's going to happen.
Less people going to buy your paper view
less.
People are going to pay to see you
fight.
You're going to make less money.
If you want to finish guys,
you're going to make more money.
The market should dictate your style.
The rules should be the rules of
fighting and fighting.
Sometimes a guy like ben asked when can
hold you down and do whatever the fuck
he wants and the idea that you get to be
stood up.
You get a second shot at kicking his
fucking teeth in.
No,
he took,
he took you down,
he held you down.
Especially when every.
Especially when every Ralph start
standing up for the striker.
Exactly.
If you wanted a to lead that fight
company,
that was totally fair.
When the fight ends up there on the
ground in the amount,
the next round should start just like
that.
And the amount,
right?
Yes.
Now you starting standing up again and
you know what I think.
I think it would be more exciting.
I think if they just let the market
dictate,
just let it decide.
Just the rules.
Make it more primitive,
make less rules,
get the f out of the mix,
get them out mixed with block subjective
tires and they're like,
whatever subjective ideas he has,
what's what's good or what's not?
Come on guys.
You gotta fight.
I go crazy.
I'm like,
they're fighting with the fuck.
Do you think they're doing?
You see that guy,
me and that guy in the leg that's called
fighting or is telling the rough,
make them fight.
That was the Gary Shaw thing in the
taxi.
He told them to stand people up.
So you've got guys like Orlowski wind up
knocking big country out,
which is kind of fucked up because big
country was dominating that fight and if
they stayed on the ground,
he probably would have stayed on top of
him.
I don't see our last people reversing
big country,
big countries.
Jujitsu is legit.
He's a big fucking strong dude.
He's working for a position that he
earned.
He got you to the ground.
It's fucking hard to do that.
We'll grow lawsky.
You get them to the ground,
you get them inside control and some
fucking sole job of a promoter decides
that you have to stand these guys up
because they want war.
The crowd wants war.
We're fighting.
We're not spit and fucking Salami
sandwiches flying out of his mouth is.
He's talking.
That guy gets to dictate what happens in
a professional martial arts event.
That's insane.
How crazy would it be if there was a
lead that took out standups and you
started the next round?
Exactly.
In the same spot.
How hard would that be?
Hard.
Is that hard?
No.
No,
no.
Not only that,
that's how it should be.
That's how it should be.
If people want to have a break,
if you want to get back up,
you shouldn't have to work to get back
up.
If a guy takes you down and he's got
your fucking you mounted,
he's just punching your face and the
buzzer rings.
She didn't solve that.
You didn't solve that issue.
Got An issue,
man.
You've got a guy on top.
You punched in the face.
If this is on the school yard,
if this isn't a fucking field somewhere,
that guy would still be on top of you.
Yup.
So look,
we're going to give you a minute to get
your cardio back to make it more
exciting,
but that's it.
And even that,
guess what?
That's a little suspect.
You'd be the fight should be 10 minutes.
Maybe the presenter,
many fight should be 10 minutes and the
main events should be 15 or 20.
No fucking breaks.
Hey,
I'm down with that hell breaks.
That would be.
That's real.
MMA.
MMA is not rounds.
You know?
I know the girls would get upset.
They don't get to walk around every five
minutes.
Their jobs.
They would still be there at the
beginning and the end.
It would just be a few less of these,
a few less.
I don't think it's.
They still are an integral part of the
organization.
They're beautiful.
They're fun to be around.
Nothing wrong with octagon girls.
Nothing wrong.
It's not an anti octagon grow rant.
I love those girls.
It's importance of freight.
Where's listed?
Where's the cage answers in a ring card
girl is at your event.
Then we're going to use dudes.
You know,
we're trying to make it more friendly
for gays,
transgenders,
straight people that like watching dudes
in their underwear.
There's not a good representation of the
male form.
There's a small market.
You know there's,
there's a huge gay Brazilian Jujitsu to
community in West Hollywood.
You know that right?
They go to all the local tournament.
They show up.
They got the rainbow geese.
I haven't.
I haven't spoken with you.
I could smile that he can't hold.
Sometimes you gotta look the corners of
his mouth,
they start shaking.
It's just keep it together.
Mr Brown,
you believe for a second that I believe.
Sure.
So it works.
We'll get,
you know,
there will be some day it keeps going.
There will be gay guys are notoriously
fit.
Hey,
why would,
why wouldn't a gay guy won a Jujitsu?
Right?
You got to roll with other dudes.
Come on and get into the missionary you
to take their bags,
balls in their face to.
A lot of times they should be obsessed
with.
It should be there probably on their
national sport.
Maybe this is going to inspire them to
come clean with it.
Maybe there's a lot of dudes out there.
You're going to just take the regular
day off and they got a Rambo underneath.
I have nothing against gay guys.
I'm sure I have like five or six gay
guys in high school.
Hey,
I'm not racist,
but it's just don't get boners while you
roll and everything will be fine.
The Gay version of,
I'm not racist but racing,
but why not homophobic?
But if you roll with me,
don't get a hard on because I am fucking
beautiful.
It's like what you're saying.
You're saying,
how could you not get a little bit?
A little guy gets hard.
You're still gonna roll with it.
No,
no.
You can say your.
Your contact or contact only homophobic.
If you expect the guy to get hard and
you're upset before the match even
starts,
you gotta let the guy have the
opportunity to get hard and they say,
hey man,
can you can't like start off going,
don't get hard.
If we wrestle like,
fuck dude,
that's like hanging out with the black
dude.
Go here,
move.
Don't rub me like.
And he's like out.
I think only gay white belts get hard
ons.
I think my blue belt,
he learned to control it.
I think there's a lot of gay white
belts.
Don't get hard at all.
I think you're at a lot.
I'm just saying generally dennis will.
Have you ever gotten a hard rolling with
the girl?
Never.
There you go.
That's what I'm saying.
And you wanted the horniest people
that's ever walked the face of the
planet.
But I'm rolling with girls like every.
There's hardly no girls frequency.
You'd get more talking about zero
percent going to go up.
To say that Hugh Jitsu was the opposite.
If we lived in the twilight zone and 98
percent of the people doing Jujitsu for
women,
and I was one of them rare dudes,
I'd be like,
hell yeah,
I'm going to do Jujitsu forever.
That's how probably girls feel,
right?
Just get mauled all the time by giant
dudes.
Hey,
who said that?
Jesus Christ.
Why she entering the heavyweight class
girls,
girls that dishes here too.
They're like,
Oh,
these guys are geniuses.
We get choked.
Her attention is incredible,
but she finds herself in north south all
the time.
It's so weird.
It's ridiculous.
Makes Sense.
Like she's so good at retaining garbage.
It almost seems like she turns into
north south from the bottom.
I don't understand what's happening.
Oh,
that's a crazy sport.
It's a craziest pillow boy.
First girl,
first girl.
When I was a purple belt,
I brought.
Did you get to to.
She wanted to watch.
She couldn't believe that she got.
She was sweating.
She couldn't believe to her.
She just saw sexual positions.
That's all she saw was.
How do you guys do this?
She was turned on by guys wrestling with
guys.
Guys.
Some girls like that,
some girls do.
Girls want to find out who wins.
Take a sperm.
That's what they want to do.
You know some guys,
some guys,
some guys like two dudes getting gay
together,
some girls like that,
right?
Dude,
no comment on that one.
No clue.
Yes.
Well we have a woman in the room,
I'll tell you.
Ordain will tell us she's nodding.
So I think girls do you know girls that
uh,
are not gay,
but somehow two gay guys getting
together turns them on.
Same in France.
In Italy.
Yeah.
Bitches.
Crazy.
Those are crazy.
Say Twenty percent of women that you
know,
maybe higher and it turns you on.
You don't want to laugh.
You're not watching to laugh.
Gay Girl Porn or gay men porn.
Why?
We got to end this conversation.
I throw us about the throat microphone I
mailed.
It was through watching some dude balls
deep in another guy's ass and a girl
playing with herself.
That's the last two month.
Egos are so strong.
It's so important for us to not get
dominated by another man.
You're like,
his balls are right here.
I don't give a fuck.
I'm going almost stop the choke right
here and his balls are right here.
You're like,
that doesn't mean shit.
It's going to hurt more.
If he taps me,
then have his balls hit my cheek.
Just like blocking the chuck.
Right?
It's more important.
You're not thinking about any sexuality
at all.
In Jujitsu,
you're thinking about not getting
tapped.
You Band,
Tie Cups,
those steel cups.
Don't bet anything.
You don't.
You allow guys to wear those steel
companies,
what they wear,
whatever they want.
I'm not going to stop them from
protecting their balls,
you know,
but it's not that.
The idea is there's leverage.
Yeah.
Do you believe that Gary,
that it's increased leverage anywhere?
A Steel Cup?
Certainly more efficiently.
Break arms,
legs.
Do you wear one?
No,
I don't want one.
When I compete,
I just never have.
So it would.
It would be awkward to start doing it
right before.
It seems like there'll be a massive
benefit.
If it's illegal,
would be some.
Some organizations been cups in it.
Totally.
Yay.
Because it'll leverage.
God Damn it.
I got another Einstein Story.
Einstein was passing my guard and he hit
my Dick with his knee.
I didn't think anything of it until I
went to the bathroom.
After I was done rolling in.
My jock strap was filled with blood.
Mr.
couple years now and so I started.
I,
I peed and blood came out of my Dick.
I'm like fuck.
And I was trying to think,
should I go to the doctor because I knew
if I went to the doctor,
like I'll go,
okay,
what would I do?
If it was my nose,
I go,
why wouldn't go to the doctor?
I would see what's going on.
So I went home and a little bit more
important than your nose though.
It is,
but I went on when I jerked off,
I just want to make sure my dick works
in my sperm was like the cover of the
metallica album load.
It's blood and sperm.
It was like one of them chicken eggs
where something went wrong,
you know,
you get one of those chicken eggs,
it's got a little fetus in it or
something.
That's what it was like.
It was clumps,
but it worked out.
It did work out and then I peed.
The next day was I had blood for a few
days though.
It was blood that was coming out for a
few days,
but it never got infected.
I was like,
if it feels infected,
I'm going to the doctor because
otherwise they're gonna be staring at my
Dick.
It's going to be awkward.
They going to put q tips up there and
then probably say nothing.
You're probably not going to do anything
for you.
So I was like,
you made the right call and is cops are
the way to go because that shit wouldn't
have happened.
Yeah.
Especially like a steel cup.
Constantly squeezing my knees and every
part of my game,
the needs are generally squeezing,
so I'm in constant protect ball mode
anyway.
So you don't wear makeup?
Never.
Do you ever wear one of those diamonds?
You ever try those diamond and try it
and never.
Would you be interested in trying?
I got them here.
You want one?
I'm afraid balls are going to hang out
and then someone's gonna Smash.
My mom like vandelay Silva.
It's like compression shorts.
I met Gilbert Ivo vandelay Silva us,
right.
The ball got caught after that guy was
laying on the floor longer than that
pain.
You know that pain you get where you
feel like you're going to get sick.
He had other kind of pain,
like a ball smashed.
I remember that.
Well there.
I think he had a regular cup,
those regular cups,
so this is way before they had these
compression short cups.
There's a couple of companies,
Jocko does them to a couple of
companies,
but diamond mma,
I think they started it.
They have a cop that's contoured.
Jamie,
go grab one of those things.
They need to take a bunch of them.
They sent them to me.
They don't have any affiliation with
this company.
I just want to say they need to take a
mold of your Dick and then make a mold.
Rubber Jelly thing.
No,
no,
no.
Where it's soft.
I thought about what if you.
Dick gets hard.
It gets trapped and it's like you're
choking your dick out.
You're to question.
That's we haven't.
He wants to make like mouthpieces.
Yeah,
like a mouthpiece,
like an earpiece mouthpiece or one of
those ear.
You just can't ever get turned on.
Yeah.
So this is why would you.
It's Jujitsu.
It's other sweaty dudes.
See they have a cup that's kind of
contoured.
And Scott,
so this is.
No,
I don't think that's the way to go.
The whole idea that the point is if your
Dick is hanging out,
I'm telling you,
dude,
you were with these compression shorts.
These shorts are crazy.
They have all these straps in them and
it's all the suck that thing right up
against your junk.
I need to protect your hawks on.
You don't need to do it.
Not Outside your pants.
It's just too.
I'm not saying I got a big.
I'm just saying it's thick.
It's bigger than this.
It's not that big.
It's this thick.
It's bigger than that.
That's all you're saying,
but you should try it.
It's a good idea.
You don't need a commentator to match a
Louis Fernando Vasconcellos and king of
the cage,
and I forgot about Fernando against
Shonie.
Carter and Carter showed up at the cup,
like it looked like actually sit on the
telecast.
I go,
you know,
uh,
Bob Sapp called,
he wanted his cut back,
his cup of so tremendous.
That was a weapon.
It was like something that you'd wear
the like Mad Max and Shit.
You know what I mean?
Like anybody tried to kick him in the
balls and there's like blades and shit
or something.
It was huge.
But when you wrote with a guy who's got
one on a steel cup and they get on top
of you,
you could feel that thing.
It's like a weapon.
Like they're fucking.
You heard somebody ribs or combat like,
yeah,
you hurt your sternum,
your solar plexus,
your like,
you,
you want to get out of that position and
an arm bars.
It's got to make a giant difference.
It's a big chunk of metal knee bars.
It's almost like an angle.
There's an angle like you have a
leverage point where your Dick and how
about you put a dude in a triangle and
you owe angle on their face is right in
that anytime you put a dude in a
triangle and you're like,
his head's just in the wrong angle.
Like if you pull this head,
you're just like stuffing his head one.
Is it worth it?
I'm going to try to tap them with like
an arm or something here.
That was one of the match.
Didn't want to talk to you about.
Is Your Hobby Vasquez mad?
Yeah.
Dude,
that was such a slick submission man
because you,
you,
you're known for your leg locks and it's
kind of like hobby was defending.
Well
an obvious really good defense anyway,
and then you switched it up and went for
that triangle and cut the triangle on
the side.
As I move forward with my matches and
things like there's certain situations
where I'm just at all costs trying to
submit somebody and beat them in
whatever way that I possibly can.
I specifically in that match,
I had every intention because I had just
beaten like a really good leg locker.
Marcin held.
I had every intention of trying to not
submit them with a leg lock real.
Uh,
I didn't.
Yeah,
I didn't want to because I don't want to
be known as,
I don't want to be known as just the guy
that does leg locks,
you know what I mean?
I want to be known as a fucking killer
on the map getting.
But still,
you were still attempting them though.
But I caught them with Ronnie in,
but I had no intention of finishing it.
Rarely thought about finishing it and
said,
no,
that's not what I want to do.
I tried,
I tried six different times.
I didn't let it go.
He,
he like,
pushed out of it really hard.
Um,
I,
um,
what was I gonna say?
Uh,
uh,
multiple times I tried to set up an arm
triangle from,
we'd call it,
like a scoop Scorpion,
but it's a,
what's it called?
Lockdown.
Right.
So from the lockdown position,
trying to pass his arm across and set up
arm triangle triangles.
Because I had been wondering the bottom,
bottom and top.
Yeah,
that's what I'd been practicing and
training.
That's how I wanted to submit them,
but it wasn't working out,
but I'd also been practicing some
triangle setups.
Uh,
so,
you know,
that's those two ways work.
I was kind of going back and forth
between that,
trying to submit them.
When you set up the iron arm triangle
from the bottom,
do you try to finish it from the bottom
or do you sweet?
Uh,
I think,
I think I,
my preferred finish,
the absolute best for me is to be
slightly to be on bottom,
but to be on my hip as opposed to be
facing up towards the sky,
so side onto the person perpendicular.
Uh,
that's my favorite finish.
But I,
uh,
saw aside from that,
finishing it just directly flat facing
up I think is worse than finishing it on
top.
On top is better because you can move
your hips,
you can move on and I'll top.
It's always better to get your weight,
but on the bottom,
the only way it's going to work on the
bottom generally if you've got to have
that locked down in without the
lockdown,
because if I have the lockdown and I
have the arm trying on the bottom,
I'm just going to stay there and try to
finish it from there,
don't you?
You sometimes go sideways on a guy and
you have the lock down as well,
which puts your knee a really funky
angle talking about the arm chair and
going from the bottom,
from stoner control.
When the lead comes all the way till you
still hold the locked down.
It's like you go into the vaporizer,
but instead you go for the arm triangle.
Yeah,
yeah,
Yep.
No,
that's a.
that's a precarious position and you get
a lot of letters from there.
It's hard to set that one up because
once you go through the leg,
you still have the lockdown and it's
hard to reach.
You got really screwed up there and he's
got to kind of give it to you.
It's hard to set that one up because you
set it up if you let go the lockdown to
pass the guard because you're basically
in a lead drag position with the
lockdown.
It's the same thing.
You can pass and commit to that arm
triangle.
You could keep the lockdown role to a
vaporizer or you could get a vaporizer
by just simply turning and they're just
sitting back nice and slow where there's
no role and you go to it.
You are.
Um,
your match was interesting because when
you guys were commentating on that match
to when you saw he got to that position,
the side trying to set up that triangle,
you got fired up.
You're like,
wow.
Yeah.
You're like,
this is a,
this is a bad situation.
This is a bad spot.
I'm,
I know that Gary's,
he's,
uh,
his guillotines or death as far as I'm
sure you have way more than I know.
But I know I've seen you.
I know you got all around Jujitsu game
and I understand you and you don't want
to be known as the lead guy because you
do have really good,
like your guillotine is right up there
with the top guys and your,
the way you get to the back elite level,
um,
you got a lot of stuff going on.
Do you have a very active game from the
bottom a?
Was it a shock to me?
I mean,
you've been training essentially Jujitsu
for about nine years.
It'll be,
it'll be eight years,
uh,
the day of his tournament,
March 20 seconds.
My jujitsu manner.
That's amazing.
You've been able to have so much
progress in such a short time.
That's incredible.
You must really love it.
You must be just fucking obsessed with
since day one.
For sure.
I was just on the mat as much as
possible.
I never really took any breaks.
I'm just constantly training and
competing as much as I possibly could.
Do you remember what dragged you into
it?
Like what got you so excited about it?
So,
uh,
at first the,
just like the sport,
I didn't know it existed until I was 14
and my buddy was like,
hey,
yeah,
I do this thing,
it's kind of like wrestling where you
get to strangle people.
And I was like,
data here,
that's bullshit.
Nobody lets that happen.
And I was like,
you're a kid.
Like nobody likes to kids try and
strangle each other.
That's,
you didn't know me that UFC.
Uh,
no,
not at that time.
Wow,
that's great.
No idea.
So this is like four or five.
I was living with a,
I was living with my mom.
She was a single parent that,
you know,
I mean not that she would have
disapproved of that or anything like
that,
but it's not like it would have been
something I would've been,
you know,
brought interest to,
they didn't talk about it at school or
anything.
Maybe you heard about it,
but then look into it.
Yeah.
No,
it wasn't,
it wasn't a big part of the culture that
I was in.
You know what I mean?
So I did,
yeah.
It just never.
Nobody ever really brought it up and
tell my one friend that happened to be
training Jujitsu.
Once I learned about that,
that's when I started learning about UFC
and stuff like that,
you know,
I hadn't really experienced any of that.
So that's what got me into the sport,
but not like obsessed with it.
I was like,
wow,
that sounds really cool.
Went to a competition.
I was like,
that's the coolest fucking thing ever.
My mom was not about it.
She was like,
yeah,
that's not okay.
You can't do that.
But eventually I convinced her and then,
uh,
what really kept pushing me forward was
the one turning point moment where,
uh,
I was training with Tom to blast my
instructor and I actually,
I was training with somebody else first
and I,
they,
I was trying to escape a triangle and
Tom comes over to help me,
like to try and help me get out of the
triangle.
I wasn't doing it properly and I was
like he,
he gave me advice and then I go oh yeah,
but I usually do this like,
like in a very standoffish,
like talking back sort of a way like a,
like a child would,
you know what I mean?
So I talked back to him and it was
really bad,
like disrespectful,
you know,
in whatever way I said it.
So Tom Goes,
oh okay let's train you now let's see
how well you get out of the triangle
then lets,
lets go.
So he's trained with me for a grand
total of about 35 minutes.
I would say every two to five minutes
after he would submit me multiple times
he would say,
do you want to stop?
And every time I was like no because I
didn't think my beating was done.
Like I thought I deserved to get the
shit kicked out of me.
So I didn't stop.
You had said something?
Yeah I knew,
I knew right from the get go I fucked
up.
Right.
So he starts training to me.
I get at the end of the match leads to a
start,
like a sternum bruise the size of
Ironmans fucking circle on his chest,
like d burn,
blood bloody cuts all over my face from
fucking Eastbourne.
And like,
literally it was,
it was definitely child abuse,
like should could have been arrested if
I like complained,
you know,
but I would never,
because I deserved it and it made me
stronger person.
But after that it was like that,
uh,
that,
that pie may experience where,
you know,
in kill bill volume two,
she's like a,
you know,
beatrice is getting the shit kicked out
of her by May and she was like being
held down by the arm,
like,
do you want this power,
you know,
that sort of thing.
And uh,
you know,
I wanted that power to be able to
fucking,
you know,
have control over my feet and have
control over,
you know,
being able to defend myself against
another person,
be able to,
um,
you know,
act in that way.
And then from that point on when I was
in love with Jujitsu or eventually,
you know,
in love with competing and wanting to
teach and all that stuff.
So is that what you're white belts?
No,
no,
I don't.
I do a,
I probably should though,
if I wanted more.
Actually I do do that to my,
to my student that I'm trying to bring
up,
Gordon Ryan.
I'd beat the crap out of them as much as
possible and try to demean him and make
him whoa.
Just feel horrible to them on the DL.
You know what big brother?
Um,
takeaway one day,
like Henzel says that,
you know,
even his brothers,
they were younger than him that are
better than him.
And it's like I'm always there.
Big Brother.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I try,
I try my best.
I think that's how you make people good
man.
There's something to that for sure.
But there's also something to just like
being really lucky and having a great
instructor.
Yeah.
You know,
when a kid hasn't instructed like you
that's so passionate about the game,
like one of the hardest parts about
Jujitsu and the day was finding real
good instructor.
You know,
Eddie and I got super lucky.
We found John Jacques Machado.
No,
but if you didn't find him,
if you were in like,
you know,
the middle of nowhere,
South Dakota and there's no good
instruction.
It's hard.
It's hard to find like a really good
instructor at such a big deal to have
like a good camp when you have like a
10th planet,
Jiu Jitsu or Benzos Academy or art of
Jujitsu,
like these big Jujitsu places where all
these killers come from such a giant
advantage.
So it's so huge.
We're so lucky here in southern
California.
I mean,
what,
what's better as far as locations on
earth than the Brazilians,
like the beach and Miami.
But Miami.
Yeah.
When you find like the ones that are
like,
fuck man,
I'm going to go to Toronto.
There's a lot of trying.
Sallow went to Ohio for a little bit and
I remember thinking,
man,
have Brazilian in Ohio.
How long was that going
to jail?
They wrote,
this project has been up there for a,
an American Brazilian.
He's uh,
he's,
he's white.
Well,
how about a fucking Gabriel Gonzaga.
He's in western Massachusetts.
Man.
He's in the middle of nowhere.
It's in Ludlow,
I think with the name of the place.
He see these places make people
stronger.
You guys in California don't know.
Pain and suffering.
You guys get to live in this nice
weather all the time.
To go from Rio to that part of western
Massachusetts where Gonzaga lives.
Fuck you went from like one of the most
beautiful spots on earth to a place for,
for six months.
It's sucks.
A fat plated digs.
What else do you have to do besides
train?
Man,
there's so much other things to do here.
What's that?
Have you been in Brazil?
Uh,
no.
Not yet.
I'm looking forward to it for this next
day.
80 eight.
Oh Shit.
I mean they haven't put out official
official invites that Saul.
Paulo,
right.
Hopefully you're in 100 percent.
We'll see cios and he qualified.
So I'll be there for sure.
It's going to be in Sao Paolo,
August 28th and August 29th.
Um,
there bunch of Tenth Planet Gadget Gone,
man.
It's going to be awesome.
You should go reserve that weekend one
if I can.
Gel is gonna.
Come out with that.
Let me see if I can.
I don't know what my,
my shit.
Swole,
my friend Michael gets half a Mendez.
It might be held against Alpha.
You never know what's going to happen
that stands out.
I just,
there's so many good guys these days.
It's really seriously is on another
level,
man is on another level.
You were saying that a lot.
He is breakdancing.
Strength from the percent.
Yesterday I did an inside Bjj podcasts
and they asked me what is the single
most important attribute to Jiu Jitsu if
you only have one attribute.
And uh,
my answer was initially was a,
I would like to say openmindedness true
open mindedness,
but there's a lot of close minded guys
out there that are the best in the
world.
So it can't be that.
That's a good point.
It can't be that.
I thought about it for two seconds and
it has to be athleticism,
athleticism.
You get a guy coming in who's been doing
gymnastics his whole life and he's high
level.
That guy's going to get really good at
Jujitsu in one month,
in one month,
and that's Geo and his brother Boogie.
Both of them just really quick.
Got their black belts.
They're just,
their athleticism is just off the
charts.
They could do the craziest shit with
their hands standing on the hand,
spinning around,
landing their balance.
Their,
their,
their core strength is off the charts
and,
and the crazy thing is geo got so good
so quick.
He got his,
you know,
he's got his black belt.
Like Sabrina did.
Got His black belt in three and a half
years.
He did.
Gopal went on his whole life.
That's athleticism,
breakdancing,
the kind of break dancing geo does.
That's athleticism.
That's like super hyper,
super evolve.
Breakdancing.
It's crazy.
So it doesn't.
He got so his black belt so quick,
but it is his rises and stopping.
It's not like okay.
He caught up and that's it.
That athleticism that got him,
that black belt so quick is going to
take them to the next level quicker and
those higher levels quicker.
He is getting better.
All the isn't enough to beat someone
that can have Amanda's cassava.
Mendez is unreal.
Unreal.
Half Amanda's defense.
No one ever does anything to them.
Anytime he loses it's on some advantage
or something.
If he loses.
Other than that,
you can do anything to him.
You know,
there's a matches of him or roles within
what?
Enrico was way bigger than him and he's
tapping into a Cuban cornelius.
There's a match online is way bigger
than half a half a gallon and I know
there's other matches where maybe keen
and taps him,
but apparently no one's tapping on that.
Is the top guy in the world at 1:45
in ADCC.
We'll see if is ready for that.
Maybe.
Maybe half a smashes.
You don't know.
Maybe it's too soon.
Right now.
Maybe it's going to take another three
or four years to catch them catch up,
but we're gonna find out and I really
believe geo is on another level.
I roll with them all the time,
man,
and I can't do shit to him no more.
I'm like,
fuck this guy,
and he's lighter than me.
I got 20 pounds on.
Yeah,
it's amazing.
It's amazing.
What we learned too,
that that break dancing is a doorway to
yes and mastics.
Everybody always knew wrestling.
Of course,
his first month he was all overdues like
Holy Shit.
Shawn [inaudible] brought them over to
me and said,
dude,
this guy is on another level and he has
a break dancing crew called the freak
show and all of those guys were doing
and they all got good.
All of them really quick,
but Geo and buggy or the only ones that
stuck with it,
the other break dancers just went back
to breakdancing.
They dabbled in it for like a year and a
half and got really good.
All of them really good right away.
Professional Jujitsu in six months we're
like,
holy fuck.
There's moves that you do in break
dancing that require like insane balance
and coordination and strength like Steve
Maxwell Hmi.
Do these crazy workouts the other day
where you're doing like this push up and
then you pick one hand up and then you
pick one leg up and then you lift the
other knee off the ground by two inches
and you're holding it there,
so one legs forward using like a
superman position,
right?
You're in what you're holding yourself
up with,
one hand and one foot on the other side
and your knee is off the ground and the
leg is up and the hand is up and you're
just holding it.
It's insanely difficult.
Now you gotta show me after I'll show
you afterwards.
It's insanely difficult,
but then you think about what these guys
are doing.
They're standing on one hand,
they're spinning around with their legs
up in the air.
It's not that old school standard basic
breakdancing that you saw and it's got
their style is they do crazy weird
things.
They're always evolving and new moves
and new and that translates to Jujitsu
to me.
Better than wrestling,
better than gymnastics.
I've never seen it from day one.
I seen them come up and his.
What he's doing is he's just getting
started.
This is just the beginning of Geo Gary.
Tone and break dancing moves your
cardboard with you.
You laid that shit out.
You started planning system is off the
charts too.
He's doing back flips like it's nothing,
right?
You can do a lot of crazy.
He's doing fly
enroll in Camorra's.
He's doing that fly and uh,
what do you call it?
Sisera take.
He's doing all.
So he's very arrogant.
So his athleticism is off the charts as
well.
What's your ultimate goal?
What do you,
if you,
do you have goals that you've set for
yourself as far as your competition
career which you want to achieve?
Yeah,
I think the main goal right now is to
bring submission,
grappling to that level we're talking
about to where it's,
you know,
it's an exciting spectator sport that,
people can get paid to do and it's like
a career,
you know?
Um,
that's,
you know,
obviously,
personally that's kind of my goal,
but it's kind of a goal for the sport at
the same,
same.
It's just perfect timing.
Ladies.
He sees obviously a big goal,
you know,
it's coming up,
you're hotter than ever.
You're the shining star of Metamorris
Ebi welterweight champion and we're
doing the welterweight championship.
It's like everything just aligned
perfectly,
man.
I'm like,
fuck,
I'm,
I'm lucky that I listened to Scotty
Nelson and brought Gary Toner and I'm
lucky man.
I really want to be a part of it,
man.
I did.
I appreciate this tremendously,
man.
I have to ask you about this because
people keep bringing it up.
I hear you have a terrible diet.
Oh yeah.
Is that true?
Yeah.
A vegans everywhere hate me.
Um,
I don't know what it is,
but we'll see.
I took so metamorris the guys that video
tape,
like the pre fight whatever bs,
right?
So they're like,
okay,
watch a couple of videos that we did in
the past and it's like Braulio and
Adolfo and both of them are talking
about their diet.
Like,
oh yeah,
I just eat like a little bit of grass
and like some leaves become big and
strong and it's like,
come on man,
are you serious?
Adolfo just eats like Chia seeds all
day.
Come on man,
I saw you,
you know what I mean,
like,
so anyway,
I was just like,
all right,
these guys really have this cleaned up,
let's,
I'll give them the real look at what my
diet is really like,
you know,
and for me because I'm in between
trainings all the time and stuff like
that.
It's just like I eat whatever I can and
I need a high dense amount of calories
all the time.
So it's like cheeseburgers and pizza and
stuff like that.
I just,
you know,
that's my main bulk of my diet now when
I wake cut I know how to eat healthy,
you know,
like when I weight cut I do the right
things,
you know,
eat a lot of fiber.
And do you make sure you get a lot of
nutrients though?
Do you take that?
Definitely take vitamins and things and
then you know,
occasionally I'll,
I'll,
I'll pump in a few vegetables here and
there.
But you really don't.
She don't eat many vegetables for real.
Yeah.
No,
no,
like real daily basis.
That's we need a man.
I'm the same one.
I eat a little salad everyday,
but a little bullshit El Pollo loco
salad or something,
you know to.
I swear to God,
if you just give it a shot,
just try drinking Kale shakes in the
morning.
Have a Kale shake instead of what you
normally have for breakfast.
It tastes like dog shit.
Tastes like it.
Tastes like and that's all you pre-cum
will that.
Will that cover my vegetables for the
day?
Yeah,
I would imagine it would cover your
vegetables.
Really.
That seems to be on it.
You,
you,
you mix up some garlic.
You mix up some ginger,
like a hunk of ginger,
like a half a page.
You remember what a pager was like?
Cut a pager in half that in the blue and
sounds
too hard.
Kale.
Celery.
Exactly.
That.
There's so much effort that just went
into his garden.
The chocolate flavor.
Is that good enough?
I mean you look,
all those things are good.
Like either there's earth grown
nutrients at on and has garden of life.
Has a bunch of drinks.
They bridget.
Very legit.
Okay.
Good stuff.
It's definitely better than not having
it,
but the best shit you can get is fresh
vegetables.
That's the best shit.
Fresh vegetables with garlic.
Some fruit,
like a maybe like a pineapple or apple,
some coconut oil,
mixed.
All that shit up together in a blend.
Things kicking everyone's ass,
kicking everyone's ass going to be fine.
You're.
I'm not saying,
I'm not saying that like,
you know that you know,
me eating shitty is leading to me
winning or vice versa.
I definitely think that for longterm
health,
like you know,
I,
I mean I studied,
I studied exercise science,
I have a degree in exercise science,
you know,
we had nutrition classes and everything
like that and it's clearly you know,
for,
for your longterm health,
like eating well is like the right thing
to do just as much as exercising is the
right thing to do.
But in terms of just my ability to do so
on a day to day basis with my training
schedule and with everything else is
just very,
very difficult.
Don't make sense,
but I don't take as much stock into it
as some people believe like,
oh,
this is going to be that deciding
factor,
that point one percent that's going to
make you beat So-and-so.
I don't truly believe that,
you know?
Um,
because uh,
I mean ultimately if I lose because my
diet wasn't good that day or whatever
the case may be,
I really just don't feel like I was that
good at Jujitsu to begin with.
Like,
I should be making improvements in
Jujitsu.
Not,
you know,
not that I know.
Like I said,
it's important,
but not for.
Not for.
It's not going to be the deciding factor
between me beating somebody.
You're not beating.
That makes sense.
That's just silly.
That makes sense in some ways,
but in some ways it doesn't because if
you think about like you don't have the
ultimate optimal conditioning,
right?
You don't have the ultimate.
There's always room for improvement,
right?
There's always room for improvement in
your coordination.
your technique.
All those things.
There was room for improvement.
How could it not be room for improvement
in your new tissue?
Nutritional technique?
I what?
What technique?
Like how do you fuel your body?
Certainly is what do you use rooms or
improvement in mind,
but don't you think there's like a
technique to giving yourself the right
amount of carbohydrates,
certain amount of protein,
a certain time.
It's a couple of things.
He's young and his body is crazy
metabolism and he's not being put in
positions where he's.
He's getting dragged out into deep,
deep waters and he's getting tired and
now it's the end.
It's like a 20 minute match minute 17
and he's going against Marcello Garcia.
Then maybe that's where the Diet is
going to come into play,
but right now he's blowing through
everybody so it doesn't matter if he'd
dig downs,
but that's what I'm saying.
Like it doesn't kind of make sense.
Saying that a guy beats you wouldn't
have beaten you because you
nutritionally.
I think for the most part.
Sorry,
go ahead.
No,
I was going to say,
look,
the chrome gracie fight like the end of
the fight.
Was it just his superior technique or
was it a combination of being exhausted
and meet massive expenditure energy from
both parties and I was just in a really,
really bad spot.
I mean,
the guy had my back with like a body
triangle.
I stood up trying to last ditch efforts
to trying to defend the choke.
It had nothing to do with.
It had nothing to do with my
conditioning or anything like that.
Was I tired at that point?
I can't even remember,
but I don't think I was tired.
I think I was just in a really shitty
spot and that's why I ended up tapping
out because I thought I was about to go
unconscious.
I'm not because I was tired or
exhausted.
I don't think I would have.
I think if you put me in the same
situation at a complete 100 percent
right before the match,
I wouldn't have gotten out any better
than I did.
They're really.
Um,
but uh,
yeah man,
I,
I mean,
I agree it makes a difference,
but not.
I don't think that enough for you to
stop it from pizza and not,
not too good.
Fired,
I'm like,
I felt better about myself if I had my
tons of money and like the ability to do
that,
you know,
like Oh,
I've got to hire somebody to follow me
around and feed me good shit all the
time.
One hundred percent.
I would.
You wouldn't want that anyway.
That guy would be annoying to have to
fly.
Right.
Telling me to get the fuck away from the
pizza.
Know for sure.
Hey Man,
get away from that pizza bro.
You good bro.
We're going to keep our old poem.
I think the human body is an amazing
thing to be honest.
And I think that it takes pretty much
whatever the fuck you put inside of it
and turns it into what it needs.
So you know,
who was notorious for eating a
cheeseburger before every fucking games.
Michael Jordan.
That was like his ritual.
He would go to burger king or Mcdonald's
rather.
And you get a big Mac maybe to anybody
eat them before every Michael Jordan.
Michael motherfucking.
What'd you say?
You're talking about people we're
talking to bang,
boom,
potatoes,
steak and potatoes.
What?
That's what he eat everyday.
Yeah.
But he ate cheeseburgers before for dsps
like that.
To.
Hold on a second.
I'm going to agree with this shit.
I was a Jordan Fan.
Says,
okay,
I'm pregame meal in 2001.
I've compensated for pride.
Terrible.
Mark Kerr,
I met him at the airport at Mcdonald's
and he was killing McDonald's.
I video taped and everything just to
prove that.
Look at this.
Look at this athlete eating this crap
because I have to keep proving to people
that it's Mcdonald's.
Isn't that bad for you?
Oh,
it's definitely horrible.
I know it is,
but it tastes so good.
Is it going to drastically affect my
athletic performance?
I was heated 10 seconds beforehand.
Now every Friday my mom would take us to
Mcdonald's when she got paid on Friday.
So it was like a treat.
Oh yeah.
Raised as going to Mcdonald's.
This is what we've been waiting for all
week.
So this is so exciting.
Okay.
I'm incorrect.
Or he ate the same meal before every
game of 23 on steak.
A baked potato and a ginger ale.
That's not bad.
Big Difference.
That's a big difference.
That's healthy.
Well,
why did I hear that?
It was a fucking cheeseburger,
man.
God Damn it.
Who the hell was that?
Was that somebody else wants Mcdonald's.
Oh,
so it was a lie.
Just those things they spread out.
Oh,
okay.
So this is.
Is this like things that are just like,
okay,
he wants punch Steve,
someone,
Steve,
Kurt,
and the phase during practice.
We don't need to see all
that shit,
but okay.
So forget what I said.
I'm trying to say is fucking dying.
Was gonna take that one back already.
Good.
Some people would take that and say that
is that.
It's not that good with the grass was a
grasp.
It probably not.
Probably not,
but it's just a slightly higher grade of
beef.
What do you think Carl's junior burger
now that the natural burger.
It's a no steroids,
no added hormones.
Yeah,
it's supposed to be grass free,
right?
Grass fed or grass fed.
You know what man?
Look what a,
what a piece of meat is.
We have all these attachments to what it
is,
but it's protein and water.
There's not,
not a lot of like.
There's good aspects to some of the like
you get healthier fats from grass fed
meat because you get a healthier animal.
It's definitely better for you.
It's probably more nutritionally dense
for you,
but you could get by on like regular
Burgers,
you can get by on regular steak.
It's still human.
Body's an amazing thing.
Yeah,
you school good for your body.
Your body's taken that animal protein
and it's breaking it down and it's
making muscle with it.
It just does.
And the idea that it doesn't because
it's a steak and the stakes bad for you.
That's stupid.
It's a potato.
Potatoes are good for you.
Okay.
You say a baked potato,
Yay,
that's really good for you.
Baked potatoes,
the best way this vitamin C and
Potassium and baked potato.
As a matter of fact,
I think there's more potassium in a big
potato than a banana.
Yep.
So yeah,
so you've got.
That's all healthy shit.
The people don't think that's healthy or
people that are have an agenda.
They're like either vegans or they.
They want to promote some really radical
idea of nutrition knife.
My favorite comment on the Metamorph,
the premed Morris video was a gary.
Tony needs to stop eating cheeseburgers
and buy some proactive,
proactive like for visits or whatever.
Oh,
this.
Oh.
How dare they ruin.
That's awesome.
Do you use anything like defense soap?
Do you fuck with that stuff for awhile?
I,
you know,
a gooey soap was giving me some stuff I
haven't had.
I haven't had anybody.
Hope is the best,
best,
best.
They just sent me a box of it.
I get,
I panic when I get low.
I used.
I'm just such good soap too.
Just like that stuff that.
It's like a surgical scrub that you use.
That shit ain't good for you dude.
No,
no.
That antibiotic soaps now good for you
because it kills your natural skin
flora.
The stuff that they use for hospitals,
man,
that's intense.
Antibiotics.
What they try to deal with and use it
for my face.
Just because the and everything.
It might be causing the proactive work
though.
I use it for a little bit.
It worked out right?
Sometimes nothing works use.
You can only use something for so long
and it just gets fucking whatever.
Just wash my face every once in a while.
I used to have a friend at work as a
friar later cook.
This motherfucker had the worst I've
ever seen in my life.
A lot of tax environmental.
When you're.
When you're famous for choking people
out and breaking legs,
it don't matter.
What if you have zits.
Eddy brothers says it doesn't matter,
so don't worry about just telling him
that.
Next,
just keep winning.
That's the plan.
Anyway,
that's what I was gonna focus on and set
them up,
but I don't know how it goes with Zits,
but I know with your skin it's actually
important to not
use the antibacterial soap and they also
say you shouldn't shower like any closer
than a half an hour before your match
because orbit before you train rather
because it takes your body time to
reestablish the skin for the antibodies.
Wrote a whole thing about that is the
guy who owns different soap.
He wrote a whole thing about that on the
think it was on the undergraduate.
Not supposed to take a shower before you
roll.
No,
don't put that out there.
Now people are going to show up.
Snow.
Just stick at it.
It's got to be more than a half an hour.
More than a half an hour for your skin
health and probiotics you fuck with
probiotics?
Only to like settle my stomach
occasionally.
Not like for the,
not for the,
uh,
for the prevention of like a steady
bravo preaches that ringworm ever.
Um,
I've gotten into a few times.
It's not like a consistent problem like
some people have with it.
Uh,
you know,
got staff once.
So it wasn't,
you know,
I caught it before it was serious.
I don't,
I don't know how some people like let
staff go to the point where a spider
bite,
a fucking spider bite on your skin.
Like this big like,
dude,
as soon as I felt like,
like,
you know,
a big swollen fucking pimp while I was
like,
yeah,
it's probably staff.
I should go get that look at.
And I started to get sick.
I was like,
yeah,
seems about right.
I don't know how people don't get that
shit.
Some people are not tuned into their
body,
man.
I told you the red should fear story,
right?
We were playing pool and he was limping.
I'm like,
why are you limping man?
He's just got a spider bite my knee.
I go,
what are the.
Let me see your leg,
and I go,
dude,
that staff,
you've got to go to a doctor right now.
His knee was all swollen and there was
like a Zit and I was like,
Holy Shit Dude,
this is ugly.
Eddie has a good story about this.
He's training with a dude that had like
a giant hole in his,
but he didn't actually train with them
because as soon as he saw the fucking
hole,
it was like,
let me stay the fuck away from that guy.
He's like,
dude,
what's wrong with you?
You're,
you definitely have staff,
man.
He's like,
he's like,
you should go to the doctor.
He's like,
yeah,
I've been rubbing some like honey on it
and stuff.
I'm really not into like,
you know,
the doctor and like into like natural
remedies and stuff,
you know,
just going to keep putting honey on it.
It's going to be fine.
Those anti banners,
those anti-vaccine dudes,
he's dead right now,
but it's better for the human race
because you know,
do we really want that to keep living
on.
Brian Cowen,
his friend's wife died from staph
infection and she tried to teach,
treat it naturally and holistically.
They were like doing like all these
different weird things and he said he
came up with the house and he said she
looked like death and her gums were pale
and he was like,
Jesus fucking Christ.
Get her to the doctor,
man.
Get her to a hospital.
They take her to a hospital.
It's too late.
They get her on the ivy drip.
They're trying to give her an
antibiotic.
Died at like 25 years old,
30 years old because they didn't do this
exactly.
And especially Murcia like the
medication resistant.
There's a bunch of different strains of
staff that are really difficult to deal
with.
I'm just going to keep rubbing honey on
it.
It'll be fine.
Yeah.
Just take some parsley and you hit it
with the pores can.
Yeah.
Perfect.
Fine.
Those homeopathic motherfuckers are
scary.
You got to be real careful with that
shit.
There's sometimes you need medicine
bench.
Yep.
Madison fucking like if you could
syphilis.
Don't try to pray that shit away.
You need penicillin.
Motherfucker.
Cillin don't go out like Al Capone.
Alright.
They figured that out.
This.
They figured it out.
Right?
To use the smart dudes knowledge.
It's like you don't just jump into
Jujitsu as fucking raw white belt.
Try to reinvent the game.
Right?
You shouldn't do that with medicine
either.
Non Medicine having motherfucker fucking
try to rub honey on your staff,
bitch.
That doesn't work.
Yeah.
Okay.
If it did,
we would fucking use that.
Yeah.
If that was the number one moves,
the rub honey.
All right man.
Yeah.
You know,
um,
our friend bud,
uh,
his mom has cancer and she's been taking
cannabis therapy for it and they
attributed to a bunch of different
things.
But one of them being that she,
she's stopped doing chemotherapy and
it's at the same time she started doing
this cannabis and her tumor shrunk by
like 30 percent over a period of just a
few weeks.
They don't know if it was the
combination of the chemotherapy and the
cannabis oil,
but they know that the cannabis oil has
a big,
big effect on it and I've been talking
to so many people that know people with
cancer that have also gone that route
and have started taking cannabis oil
that Rick Simpson oil and a bunch of
different cbd oils.
It's amazing.
I'm hearing about that.
You see that vice documentary on the
measles virus and the HIV virus is
incredible.
They're using the measles virus,
an HIV virus to kill cancer and it's so
far it's working.
Ninety percent is amazing.
We live in good times.
Man decided to put that episode on
Youtube for free so that their gift to
the world that's showing the progress
they've made.
It seems like they've cured cancer.
So it seems like.
Well,
if not,
I mean there are certainly making giant
leaps and bounds from where they were
just a decade ago.
Virus kills cancer.
Not Crazy.
It's nuts.
Yeah.
But you get really sick because they
take you through it and when they gave
him this,
uh,
this measles virus,
they get really go into comas and it
almost seems like they're going to die
but never are going to die anyways with
the cancer.
And then they wake up from the coma and
then they're cancer free.
That's my man as we live in crazy times.
Man.
What do you think that.
This is the last question because we're
almost out of time,
right?
Yeah.
Five of us,
five minutes left.
Um,
what do you think about performance
enhancing drugs?
Because that is a big issue with
Jujitsu.
You know,
Steve Maxwell was just raving about it
the other day.
He's like,
they need to do that in Jujitsu.
There's too many guys that are on the
news.
What do you think?
Yeah,
because it's not in any sense.
I mean,
they have some light testing that they
do for ib ggf,
but it's like one of those situations
again where like people know what to do,
like they have enough,
they have advanced notice of the event
coming up.
They know if they could be tested,
whatever they pay after the event.
Is that what it is after the event?
Is it urine?
Yeah,
they test the randomly,
like 10 dudes or something like that.
Oh,
that's it.
Yeah.
It's something stupid.
I mean it's a step in a direction.
But um,
yeah,
I mean it's clearly a rampant um,
you know,
as to what to do about it.
Like you either need to you,
there's only two routes.
There's one you just don't do anything.
Okay.
And then everybody has their option to
use it or not use it,
which,
you know,
whatever.
I mean,
you're obviously the people that choose
not to,
are going to suffer in terms of the
disadvantage of not the strength.
And then the other way to go about is
you have to do it fucking right and just
have random testing all the time and in
a way where people can't fucking cheat
it,
you know what I mean?
Because if,
because if some camps get really,
which is what happens in Oma,
some camps get really,
really good at figuring out what the
ways are to cheat the tests or this,
that,
and the other thing.
And then other guys aren't gonna fucking
go through that.
I mean he gives those guys an advantage
over the other guys that aren't,
you know what I'm saying?
Of course.
So it's A.
I mean,
dude,
I mean in a perfect world that's like,
yeah,
let's get rid of it.
But it just seems like there's always,
there's always a way to fucking hide it
or always a way to do whatever.
So I'm just gonna keep trying to get
better at Jujitsu and you know,
hopefully that saves me instead of
bolting biceps,
we'll see.
Well,
we've also seen a bunch of guys who were
just two guys that got into mma and then
got caught when they got into mma
because then they get tested a little
bit more thoroughly and assurance out.
They were probably using it the entire
time.
Yeah,
there's tons.
There's tons of that for sure.
Jujitsu,
man,
whatever the case may be,
you know,
you think about this situation that MMA
finds itself in.
Right now I'm looking at an MMA,
you know,
as a future prospect,
getting involved in and you see all
this,
you know,
all these guys are testing positive.
It's kind of sneaky.
Something that Ronda Rousey said was
kind of interesting about the idea that
like,
oh,
this isn't like baseball wherever,
using steroids to hit a ball harder,
we're using steroids and people are
fucking getting knocked the fuck out.
You know what I mean?
And that's,
that's scary,
you know,
and in a sense that people are getting
stronger and stronger and have the
ability to do serious damage to people,
you know?
So in that sense,
yeah,
it's,
I mean,
in a martial art,
I think that's super dangerous,
you know,
um,
I,
you know,
I don't know what the answer is,
you know what I mean in terms of what
they should do or whatever the case may
be with a pds,
but just because there's,
and it's not even just steroids.
There's tons of other stuff people can
be taken dpos and all different kinds of
things,
you know.
Well,
there was an article recently online
where there were saying that these
businessmen is middle aged businessmen
have taken epo and winning cycling races
just entering into amateur cycling races
on Epo and winning them.
And yeah,
it just gives just such a giant
advantage when you're dealing with
someone who has some cycling,
you are cycling,
so you have the muscle strength and then
all of a sudden you have this superhuman
endurance.
Yeah.
So this is fucked.
It's fucked.
It's weird.
It's weird that it's so many mma
fighters are testing positive for it.
Now.
The epl world of Ali Baba routine off
who fought for the title again.
So my name,
mouse Johnson,
he tested positive for EPO.
Shane Mosley tested positive for evo
back in the day.
If you think that's really,
you know,
you'd say,
I mean people always say a large
percentage of professional athletes are
on steroids that Duh Duh.
Do you think a large percentage of our
on epl as well because cardio so huge.
I know of many that have been on epo.
I know of many that were on epo back in
the day at least I know from the
anecdotal stories that I've heard from
people that trained with them that there
was guys will take a wild west shoot epo
or eat it.
Good question.
I think
they have a pill form now though.
Yeah,
I think so.
I couldn't be wrong about that,
but I think yeah,
they've made major advances so they used
to have to do like blood transfusions in
order to do it properly.
Yeah.
Well there's still guys.
I'm sure that blood dope.
I'm sure they do that because there's no
test for that.
When you take your own blood out of your
body,
you make weight,
your body has that blood regenerated in
your body and then you add more blood to
your body.
You have more oxygen carrying
capability.
Take two weeks though for your body to
make that blood.
That's a good question.
I don't know how long it takes,
but guys could easily get a blood
transfusion two weeks out.
Matter of fact,
that would give you plenty of time to
recover if you want it to do that.
If you say,
if you take Saturday and Sunday off,
you know you train all week,
you just say,
okay,
I'm going to get a blood transfusion
Friday or a blood,
a withdrawal,
they're going to take my blood out
Friday,
you know you have the weekend to
recover.
You go back on Monday,
you start training again and then they
hold onto that blood for two weeks and
then Jack that shit back in your system.
You would most certainly have some sort
of a performance advantage from that and
I don't think they can detect that.
I really don't.
Yeah.
That was what the bikers used to do.
That was with all the cyclists used to
do it.
Yeah.
It's,
it's just,
it's a fascinating time where people are
learning more and more about how to
cheat and then how to stop cheating.
You know,
like the shit that had hector lumbar got
caught for.
I've never even heard of it before.
She designer steroid.
That was like really expensive exotic
shit that it was that clear stuff that
I'm very bonds and the victor connotate
stuff where they thought that nobody
knew how to detect it.
Yeah.
I don't know ma'am.
Strictly.
It's a very tricky,
but Rhonda is point is as valid as fuck.
It's a different thing.
They're landing punches that you
probably wouldn't be able to land.
You're doing damage,
especially when you're dealing with some
sort of a war where one person surges
and comes on at the end and stops that
person.
You know?
That's probably a big part of it.
Yep.
Eddie Bravo.
His feet are on the table.
My time to end this fucking podcast chip
as to eat your fucking heels.
I just showered.
Excuse me.
This is where people eat and they drink
coffee.
This is not for you to put your feet,
you sorry.
Stuck energy.
Etsy people were.
Especially Eddie.
Eddie's always guys,
feet out the window,
his feet on mirrors and shit and against
the walls.
When there's chairs in it.
Just a surprise.
I'm not sitting against the fucking wall
right now.
Double noticed.
Yeah,
I'm paranoid tomorrow.
Eddie Bravo,
invitational.
Only live on paper view.
Butoh videos.com/Ebi
Slash Tbi.
Four PM Pacific Standard Time because
none of the pme.
Googly Mowgli and Gary Tone and we'll be
there.
Throw in the FEC tournament.
Returning champion has got a lot of
killers.
Darragh O'connell.
He beat you in a pizza and the guy,
he seemed to me,
billy,
back in the day when we were brown
belts.
If you live in Los Angeles tomorrow,
it's at the orpheum theater in downtown
La.
You can get tickets there.
You can.
You get tickets off your website.
Eddie Bravo,
invitational.com.
You can get tickets.
Get this.
God Damn it.
This is fucking chaos.
The $10,000
grand prize.
I dare anyone to watch this and tell me
this is not exciting.
This is some crazy shit.
This one,
this is all about all about encouraging
urgency.
So what I did was,
is winner take all.
It's like a game show.
No one else gets paid,
just a winner to ensure urgency and
each.
So the winner has to win four matches
and he only gets paid on the matches.
He winds and regulation.
So there's $2,500
per match,
so it's a possible 10 grand that he
could win.
And this is only gonna get bigger and
bigger.
We're going to go 50 grand.
We're going to go under grant eventually
a million.
Boom,
that's it.
Eddie Bravo.
Invitational.
It's going down tomorrow at the orpheum
theater.
The orpheum fit,
or I'll say it again in downtown La
again.
Butoh videos.com.
Forward Slash Ebi.
You can follow Eddie on twitter.
It's Eddie Bravo.
All one word.
You can follow Gary Tone and on twitter
it's Gary to ours.
Underscore t o n o n Gary.
Thank you very much man.
Fight tomorrow.
It's going be.
Yeah,
I should say compete tomorrow.
A lot of guys don't like the word fight,
it's gonna.
Be nuts going to be awesome and it's.
If you're a,
this is your first event that you're
going to go to,
we're going to see live on paper view.
You will not be disappointed.
There are some mother fucking savages of
this,
so thanks to everybody tuning in.
Thanks to defense soap,
you guys are the shit defense soap.com
and we'll see you next week.
Much love,
big kiss dude.
I've been.