The joe rogan experience last
night set was particularly,
uh,
rich and ideas and some of the new
things that I've been working on are,
um,
there's a lot of stuff in,
I'm worth on about this sort of a
weirdness of progressive thought later,
like this really aggressive
progressiveness that's
going on where people are
denying reality and they're doing it so
because they feel like people have been
marginalized in the past,
which is true,
but it doesn't mean you
spring it back the other way.
You say bunch of stupid shit.
It doesn't make any sense.
Oh,
you judge people too harshly
for judging people harshly.
It's like,
yeah.
How does that work,
right.
Getting people for hitting.
Exactly.
Some of the most aggressive
people I know are liberals,
so it's really strange.
I mean,
there's an amazing video of,
of University of Toronto,
of this guy who was speaking
about men's rights waterfowl.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
These feminists are protesting these
students screaming in their face.
The students that want to go see
this man talk about women's of,
about men's rights and about that you
hate women and all this and they're
incredibly aggressive.
The only hate IC is in the protesters,
the only not going be,
and by the way,
incredibly ignorant to what this guy,
his actual words are.
And they weren't even aware.
They didn't even bother
doing the research.
They didn't even bother formulating a
true opinion on these this guy's ideas.
They just decided that
this guy hates women.
And that's a weird thing.
Like I've had made some posts about
feminism on online before and one of the
things that I've found it incredibly
strange is that I got called an Mra
asshole.
And so I go,
what does that,
what does that mean?
What's the Mra?
So that I had a very simplified English.
I didn't know what it meant at all.
It's men's rights advocate or activist.
Yeah,
we're activity.
And I was like,
wait a minute,
I'll feminist.
A person who wants equal rights for women
is saying that being a man who wants
equal rights for men is an idiot.
Or I could call the Dodo
and Mra Dodo and like,
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
Well,
Yoga,
well,
they had a compressive Socratic arguments.
I could call it MRI asshole.
[inaudible].
I didn't even know what an MRI,
I mean,
I'm not immense rights advocate and
by any stretch of the imagination,
I don't visit any blogs.
I don't visit any forums,
but I'm a believer in equality.
Is,
is as far as like the laws and
regulations as they apply to human beings.
And I do not believe that the laws and
regulations as they apply to human beings
in this country aren't even
for men as the art and women.
I don't think they're even for women
and I don't think they're even for men.
Yeah.
If an area,
forcible laws are fucking horrendous
for men and some of them are atrocious,
some of them are Canada,
are God awful.
Dave Foley for the longest time,
I don't know if he's resolved.
Horrible,
horrible.
Anybody who's listening to this,
just Google Day Foley,
Joe Experience divorce.
And there's a,
there's a youtube video that someone
compiled of just him talks about his
divorce.
He will make your head spin and,
and I know they'll probably be honest
TV because what he lost $10 million fund
his last divorce.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Cause he said it's not alimony.
It's all your money.
That's a,
it is.
It is.
It's insane.
And that's not fair.
It's not fair.
I don't care what anybody says.
I think that absolutely.
If a man and woman get
divorced and manage,
get child support.
Absolutely.
And if the woman was not working
during the time of the marriage,
I think there should be
some sort of compensation.
Something Fair.
It's something recent.
Yeah.
Some of the assets that he
developed by focusing on whatever.
Yeah,
sure.
Absolutely.
But that's a terrible payments.
That's just not right.
No,
it's not.
It's not right.
And I have a friend who
has to pay his ex wife.
Um,
they were,
they were married for 12 years.
He has to pay her for the rest of
her life until she gets married.
So she plays this game.
She has a boyfriend and the
boyfriend of her and he sends a,
the investigators over to figure it out
and the boyfriend's not there and then
he leaves and the,
the rescuers leaving in the
boyfriend moves back in.
And so he has to continue paying her.
Like she's cohabitating with a man and
he still has to continue to send her
money.
And it's just a manipulation
of the legal system.
And this guy has paid her millions
and millions and millions of dollars.
She's in his $4 million
Pacific Palisades home.
It crippled him financially.
And on top of that he had to pay
for her lawyer whether they want to,
it's gone through divorce and
here's where it gets really crazy.
She went to every lawyer in
town and consulted with them,
every good lawyer in town that she knew
of so that he could never use them as
counsel.
Oh.
Because they'd be conflict of interest.
But some madness.
I mean she planned it out.
She plans to divorce out for a long time.
It was incredibly calculating and the
idea that men don't deserve rights and
because of the fact that
women have been marginalized,
which is true,
they have been,
but that doesn't mean that
men haven't been either.
I mean,
human beings deserve to be treated fairly.
That's just true to you.
You deserve,
everyone deserves to be treated humanely.
I don't believe men are,
I don't believe women are,
I don't believe humans are.
But the idea that you could
separate and be a feminist,
but the anti men's rights,
well,
you're a fucking crazy person then.
You know,
you're not a humanist.
You're not a person who's looking at
all human beings as your brothers and
sisters.
You're a person with that agenda.
You're a a person with an ideology.
And that ideology is
that you're on a team,
you're on team vagina and
everything that's on TV.
Penis can go fuck itself.
And that was the,
that was the,
the feedback.
The blow back that I got for
a joke about male feminists.
Yeah.
No,
I mean I've stepped on that landmine a
couple of times and I keep going back to
it cause it is,
it is an important one.
A young man in the legal system.
I mean not just with divorce but I mean
the sentencing disparities between men
and women,
what they call the Pussy Bass,
you know,
I mean it's,
it's horrendous.
I mean you call Feminism
Marxists with Penny's socialism,
socialism,
the original prop,
the socialism with tests.
But that was a bad character
and one of my novels,
but I just call it the feminism.
Socialism is Panisse and it's
very true because I mean,
and then people call,
oh my God,
that's so terrible.
Design.
I just went through all the founding
matriarchs of the feminist system that all
Marxists,
all leftist and so on.
And also if feminism is so pro woman,
then where are they
with Margaret Thatcher?
Margaret Thatcher was like the
first leader of a Western country.
She struggled that from nothing.
I made an incredibly powerful woman,
but she was on the right,
you see,
so they hate her.
What about Iran?
I ran,
wrote,
wrote the most influential book
outside the Bible and the second most
influential book in according to The
New York Times review of books after the
Bible,
uh,
you know,
reshaped a western philosophy in many
ways and western politics and the feminist
hater.
Why?
Cause she was on the right cause he's,
that's what they think.
She was not actually on the right but so
I mean I have these sort of suspicions
when they're sort of the,
is it the leftist
ideology or the pro woman?
Now if it's the pro woman then
they should be incredibly positive.
Where are the feminists when people
insult people like and culture.
Where are the feminists when
people insult Sarah Palin,
you know,
like Bill Maher,
her called her a cunt.
I mean that's really pretty vicious.
Like publicly,
openly,
right?
I mean where are the fee because they're
on the right and culture are considered
to be on the right.
So they get a pass when people go,
you know,
but you then say something
bad about a woman on the left.
And so I think that it is more left
than it is pro women because when they
choose between their
politics and the agenda,
they always seem to choose
the politics over the agenda.
And that's why I say it's leftist
rather than than pro woman.
I agree.
And I think there's a lot of really
emotional and non objective thinking
attached to feminism and there's a lot of,
there's a lot of really strange.
The,
the,
one of the more recent ones that
I find incredibly strange is this,
uh,
there's this new trend of accusing men
of rape if they have sex with a woman
who's had something to drink.
This is a,
uh,
like a,
a broad sweeping thing that's
going through the Internet.
And a lot of these,
uh,
it's really weird because it seems to be,
there's a lot of it in this,
what they call a skeptical community.
And I,
the skeptical community seems to be
of like integrated with a lot of male
feminists and feminist
and this is something that
they've adopted this idea that
somehow or another
skepticism and this idea,
uh,
that they,
that they combine.
And it's,
I don't know if you're
aware of of the case,
the Michael Shermer thing,
you know about all that accused,
uh,
some significant sexual impropriety,
right?
Yeah.
No evidence other than a person who
doesn't want to reveal their name.
Yeah.
Who,
he,
the guy who wrote the piece
heard about second hand.
Yeah.
He didn't even hear about
it directly from the person.
And this is the person
who's supposed to spell it.
They not see,
I don't understand is,
and he is getting sued now,
but it's the idea of that
being the skeptic community.
I mean,
one of the things you learn as a skeptic
when you're breaking down any idea,
whether it's a religious idea
or whether it's an idea about,
uh,
an event that took place is that a
person's eye witness account of any
individual event is suspect.
And that it's one of the worst forms of,
of evidence.
And it doesn't mean that a terrible
thing didn't happen with this person,
but it does mean that if you look at the,
in the context of the way it was explained
in this guy's blog is that she was
put in a position where
she couldn't consent.
Like what?
What kind of Weirdo language is that?
And then the,
the corroborating evidence that he uses
in this blog is that a woman went to a
party with this guy and he kept giving
her drinks and he was flirting and that
she got drunker than she usually does.
And that's it.
That's the corroborating piece of evidence
that the man and a woman who are both
adults were drinking
together and she got drunk.
I mean,
I,
you talk about removing yourself
a personal responsibility that he,
this guy was responsible
for you getting drunker.
Like that's insane.
Like that's insane for a person
to say this and we'll be drinks.
What choice did I am feminist?
Like,
why would you,
how is it possible that a
person who believes in the,
in the power of being a woman could think
that a woman is so much weaker than a
man,
that she can't control how much liquor
she consumes when she's around a man?
If the man somehow or another like being
with her and drinking with her forces
her to consume more
than she normally would,
that's madness and there's
no excuse called I was drunk.
I mean try that with drunk driving,
right?
It's all points that,
okay,
yes,
you had diminished capacity
while you were driving,
but you were responsible for
drinking and getting in the car.
It's the one time when we're willing to
alleviate someone of their own personal
responsibility and only women.
A man is more a man who if a man and man
is more responsible if a man of women
or drunk together,
but the woman feels bad about
the encounter in the morning,
the man raped,
maybe all the man was drunk as well,
but the men are always the aggressors
and always therefore guilty.
I mean that's not humanism,
but that has taken,
and this is a long dock road,
uh,
that as a man and you know,
I'm sorry that if you're a woman,
it's really hard to get this.
We have had so much negativity
over the past 40 or so years,
pearls and masculinity that,
I mean,
we were like half criminals
just for breathing.
I mean,
if you look at the,
the role models on TV,
how,
how men to portray,
you know,
the homeless Simpsons
and the American Dads,
they deck would all just idiots and sex
trace and irresponsible and stupid at
the amazing thing is that it's true that
if you look at the belcove intelligence
for women,
it's kind of spikes in the middle of so
many more women are average intelligence
than men.
Now you still have your brilliant women,
you still have your done with it.
But if you look at the bell curve of
male intelligence is much flatter,
which means that we have a lot more
geniuses and allot my complete idiots,
right?
And what's happening is everybody's
focused on the idiots among them.
And if completely began to ignore all
the brilliance that men bring to the
world,
all of the amazing,
incredible inventions that
men bring to the world.
And it's just with focusing
on this low cluster,
which is incredibly biased.
It's like saying,
okay,
well blacks in America,
they commit more crimes and we're just
gonna focus on that and say that's
all the blacks are.
That's all we're going
to portray as blacks,
as criminals and blah,
blah,
blah.
That would be incredibly racist.
But the sexism of portraying men as
idiots because we happen to have more
cluster as a gender on that side and
completely ignoring all of the incredible
stuff that brilliant
men bring to the world.
It's incredibly sexist
and it's really hard for,
for for people to see.
I mean like the idea that the,
we were talking earlier,
the idea that a woman can competently
raise children without a man around.
It's just taken for granted.
Now,
it's absolutely not true
matter of essential to the
healthy raising of children,
but the idea that we would
recognize that as a society,
it's just we were just the disposable,
very unfortunate situation.
We're in in regards to feminism that uh,
a lot of people are dealing with their
own personal experiences that they've had
with a few asshole men in their lives
in regards to them not being sexually
attractive or not fitting into
a certain social group or not.
And then they have somehow or another
extrapolated that that all men are pieces
of shit and rapists or a massive amount
of need to be curved and laws need to be
changed.
And if you get drunk with a
girl and you have sex with her,
you're a rapist.
Right?
And a lot of this is based on their
own negative interactions with men.
And this stereotype of
feminism unfortunately is like,
there's a meme online,
this is feminism and it's a woman who,
uh,
has a,
um,
the,
uh,
of,
of holding up a sign saying I'm a
feminist and she's fucking 300 pounds.
And you know,
and everyone's like,
yeah,
that's feminism.
You know,
like this is,
yeah,
you're right,
it's a big fat are going
to go that no one's a fuck.
That's really unfortunate.
But the person,
the type of person that is a large,
unattractive woman is
going to deal with and uh,
in measurably,
it's going to be so much harder for,
for her to find people who
are sexually attracted to her,
for her to find a healthy
relationships for her too.
If you,
it's an unfortunate reality in this
world is that if you are not sexually
attractive,
you are not going to have,
is easier to ride when it
comes to the opposite sex.
It's just a fact.
Well,
I mean,
but sexually attractive and 300 pounds,
somebody who's 300 pounds,
he is for most people got
gotta be sexually unattractive.
But if they chose to
lose weight and exercise,
that's sort of a different matter.
And that's just kind of have
a basic human competence.
But one of the things that
I hadn't thought of it,
like I grew up with a,
a single mom and we lived because
single moms are used to be broke,
right?
I mean,
because it's a tough life.
And so when I grew up with a single mom,
everyone around me has
single moms as well.
You know,
what's interesting is that the kind of
man who float through single mom world,
they're not always the best kind of men,
right?
They kind of trashy,
Because like the really competent and
successful and intelligent men aren't
trawling the girlfriend
farms at the single mom.
You know,
they'll rent housing getups.
Right?
And so I think what happens is a lot of
these women have grown up in single mom
households or,
or in this sort of environment and see
who the men who floating through that,
they tend to kind of be losers.
They tend to be pretty unstable.
They tend to be kind of parasitical.
They,
you know,
they don't tend to be very,
the very best specimens of,
of masculinity.
And so I think the
breakdown of the family,
he has created an environment where a
lot of girls growing up don't have a
positive male role model in their life.
And the kind of men that they
see floating through their moms,
dads tend to be kind of trashy.
So they're like,
well,
this is masculinity.
It's also very unfortunate that
in their criticism of masculinity,
you've removed a lot of allies,
you know,
but by blanket generalizations of men,
you removed a lot of people like myself
who I can't support you on that even
though I'm an entirely
approach human being and,
and pro equality.
But when you make these
mass generalizations and
call someone a men's rights
advocate asshole like that,
these,
these are nonsense statements.
And it's unfortunate that
I guarantee you these,
and it's not saying that all feminists,
feminists or unattractive
or all feminists or uh,
you know,
uh,
not,
not sexually viable,
but I guarantee you almost all of them,
I've had a lot of negative
experiences with men.
And it doesn't mean that
all men are negative.
And it doesn't mean that there's not
people out there that you would assume
would be assholes,
are actually very nice people.
But you've got this,
this idea that's,
it's easier to define the world by these
rigid dimensions that you've sort of
set up for yourself.
And when,
when I,
when I read things that are from
this feminist point of view,
there's so often aggressive
and it's so often,
and I get that there's a blowback.
I do get that.
I get that they've
experienced marginalization.
They believed that,
you know,
society is set up to support rape culture
and all these strange ideas and that
there's a blow back to it.
But I don't think that the
way it's being handled is,
I think it's,
I don't think it's objective.
I don't think it's irrational
and I don't think it's balanced.
And,
uh,
I,
I find it really weird when
really intelligent people
attach themselves to these
feminist ideas.
Yeah.
And,
and,
but the problem is,
you know,
in Canada here I had a guy on my show,
Greg can't bill Gehringer who wrote,
um,
uh,
at the end of the family.
And it was,
and he pointed out that there's
a revolution that occurs.
I think that initially it's necessary.
And I think this is also
with blacks in America too.
There's a revolution that occurs
then is initially necessary,
but the whole point of a revolution
is to defend itself to end,
right?
So yeah,
I mean there was stuff
that needed to be done.
Obviously we've talked about the,
certainly the blacks and the 60s and some
stuff with women's kind of different,
right?
So cause women,
there's always been this
women and children first,
right?
Like the vast majority of the
people who died on the titanic,
we're men offering up
their lifeboats to women,
right?
Because there has been a sort
of women and children first,
and women have been kind of elevated.
There was no black people for
us in the south right there.
So it's a little bit different.
But there was,
I think,
some push for quality
that needed to happen.
But then what happens is you get a lot
of people who get heavily invested in
this course and they'd be,
becomes their ego,
their identity,
right?
Like I fight for black lives,
I fight for women's rights and so on.
But then what happens is society will
often listen and respond in a positive
way,
and then what is that
course begins to diminish?
And people are like,
you know,
supporting,
like,
I'm not going to support
you the abolitionists course
because slavery is ended.
Like I'm just not going to do with it.
It's over.
Right?
I mean,
there may be other problems,
but that's not the problem.
Right?
Like I know to support a lot of,
uh,
you know,
let's,
let's deal with polio victims because
we've got this vaccine and we don't really
have polio victims anymore.
Right?
So the whole point of
revolution is to defund itself,
to end for people to
move on with their lives.
But what happens is when
you haven't government,
you get these voting blocks and you get,
like in Canada,
over the last 10 or 15 years,
Katie government's given $300
million to feminist groups.
That's not coming from Canadian women
or Canadian men for that matter,
because,
you know,
a lot of it's kind of been dealt with.
But these groups continue by by poking
these scams and by continuing these
grievances and by finding the Trayvon
Martin situation and blowing it up into a
race war and all this kind of stuff.
A lot of the stuff has been dealt with,
but because the government's
still getting the money,
they still need to whip up these kinds
of hysteria there just to justify their
own existence.
I mean,
the whole point of a revolution is to end
the whole point of I want to deal with
measles.
It's get a vaccine and end measles.
You don't keep taking the same
amount of money that year after year,
but if you have a government funding it,
then you have to manufacture
these grievances,
which just keeps things
going and getting worse.
The point of revolution has a resolution
and resolution never seems to come
play.
It's never going to take place if you're
approaches imbalanced and there's just
some things that are being some proponents
of feminism or endorsing one of them
being the ability to
withdraw consent equals rape.
The ability that you mean after the fact?
Yeah,
after the fact.
Yeah.
That's sending you can send it to you.
That's like me giving you my coffee and
then judging you with theft when you
walk out the room.
Yeah,
take my coffee.
Oh,
officer that he stole my coffee because
I changed my mind after the fact when he
left.
Well,
the idea is that a man can lie to a
woman in order to get in bed with her and
then if she can prove that he did that,
but that he's a rapist because
he tricked her with his words.
Yeah,
because of course women never lie.
I mean,
they don't use makeup.
They don't puff up their tits.
They don't ever
falsify any therapy.
You don't do anything like a man because
he's wealthy and hope to get pregnant
with him either.
I mean,
I don't see any feminists that
are decrying that and that's a,
that's a horrible front to womanhood.
I think that the only way that you could
make a live in is to lie to a man and
make him get you pregnant so
that you can get money from them.
From then on.
I mean,
we're feminist.
True feminists should
be horrified by that,
which I'll focus on.
The false rape accusations,
false rape accusations,
which in some studies or 2030 or
40% of the study in the air force,
but they actually do,
even women who have
withdrawn their accusations,
2030 or 40% of Rick Rick
accusations in some studies,
who knows what it is
universally are our fast.
I mean how horrendous that and
women should be coming down so hard.
I'm wondering who make
false rape accusations cause
they make it so much harder
for the women who actually happened,
right?
Because then there's that
problem or a false paternity.
And the problem with fall three
prepositions are very few women fees face
repercussions for them.
No.
Am I in my book?
If you can,
if you accuse someone
of a crime and you lied,
you get the punishment,
they would have gotten,
you should
player football
player who has recently been released,
uh,
that he got on tape,
this girl a admitting that she lied
about him being him raping her and her
family received $1 million
or $850,000 and now they,
you know,
they have to pay the money back.
But that's the extent of her punishment.
This guy went to jail
for five fucking years,
you know,
and now he's just trying to re pursue
recording and he'd still be there.
Well,
not only that,
he's just one of many.
I have three friends that
were falsely accused of rape.
I also have friends that were raped.
I know that there's,
I know rape is real.
You know,
I have friends that have
been roofing and you know,
got out of danger because
someone recognized in been drug.
It's not,
it's very common.
You know,
rape is a disgusting,
horrible anti human crime.
And I,
I think rape is,
should be treated the
same way as murderers.
You're,
you're denying someone their humanity.
You're doing,
you're taking away something,
some part of them,
you're removing a part of the
w the who they are as a person.
It's kind of permanent.
Yeah.
Somebody you can get a new car,
but there's something about sexual
violations that it's kind of a permanent
thing.
It's horrible,
but so is lying about it.
That's horrible to lying about.
A rape is just as hard a lot of it,
but often we get them in,
right?
Yes,
yes.
And this idea of this idea
of withdrawing consent,
you know,
and it's somehow or another you could
do that and turn a guy into a rapist
that's like hating thing that's uh,
you don't,
you,
what you're doing is you're,
you're,
you're hating someone who's manipulative.
You're hating someone
who can con you into bed.
But that's been what men have been
trying to do since the beginning of time.
Like you're eating of the
game of courting a woman.
And there have been men that wear shoes
that they would never wear watches me,
would never buy.
And cars.
They don't give a shit about an apartment
that they decorate just to get the
woman to believe that they're like this.
It's all a alive.
My friend Brian,
we saw earlier tonight,
last night for sure.
Um,
Brian Callan,
so hilarious guy the first time,
if you over his house
back when he was single,
he had Jack Kerouac on the road,
uh,
sitting on his night table open.
Anthony,
I'm a predator.
So I come over his house and like,
then she may have written that,
you know,
I,
I find weaknesses and people very quickly.
So I saw that.
I go,
you're not fucking reading that.
you're,
you're hoping a chick comes over.
And she sees that and she's like,
Oh,
you read so much at polling
are amazed that he's there.
He started laughing.
He goes,
it's true.
It's true.
I decorate my house to
pretend I'm smarter than I am.
I did that.
There was a Stephen Hawking's book,
a brief history of time
or by the upper right.
And I had that on my end.
This woman,
I loved her to death.
We went out for a while.
This woman came over and she's like,
I call bullshit.
I call bullshit on stuff later,
and I'm like,
no,
no.
I've read it and she,
what she did is she went over and she
opened it and it creates like an old boat
did it never made it open before us that
didn't go with his spine was completely
unvetted that like,
you know what?
You got me.
That's embarrassing.
That's
[inaudible]
you're a fucking human being.