Yes,
and we're live.
Hello,
Danica Patrick,
welcome to the show.
Thank you.
Thanks for doing this.
I appreciate it.
I'm excited to be here.
You're in a tense lady.
You've got a lot of intensity when I met
you,
like right away.
I'm like,
whoa.
GotTa.
Go take this one in.
Well,
you know,
it's the handshake and then it's the uh,
when someone actually looks you in the
eye.
Well you have to be intense.
I mean what you do for living is
probably one of the craziest things a
human being can do.
Do you think?
So it's up there for a job.
How fast do you go?
Uh,
200.
That's,
I mean like,
you know,
Nascar's top speed is probably 2:15 indy
cars,
maybe more like 2:40 and I'm going to do
the Daytona 500 next month and then the
indy 500 in May.
So,
um,
those are going to be my last few races.
So I'm the last one's ever.
Yeah,
really?
it's a,
this is my Danica double goodbye to her.
Why are you doing that?
How can we do an a Danica double
goodbye?
Is it enough?
Is Enough?
I'm ready.
Um,
I mean I love racing but I love other
things too.
So,
um,
you know,
I'm okay with transitioning out and
there was a lot of things that were kind
of just pointing me in this direction in
2017 stuff that has never happened to me
before.
Um,
to kind of,
yeah,
head towards the exit a little bit,
but I'm good with that.
I'm a very decisive person so this is
probably one of them that I thought
about it a little bit,
um,
as far as like how to be done or,
or if to be done I guess.
But um,
the,
how was the hardest part.
My agent kept calling and saying,
what about this and what if you did
that?
And I'm like,
no,
you all need to get ready for me to be
done please.
Wow.
And uh,
so then he came up with the,
he's like,
what if you finish up at the,
at Daytona for the 500?
And I was like,
what about the indy 500?
He goes and I was really only referring
to the indy 500 and he was like,
well I'd,
I'd love you to do both.
And I was like,
oh,
well that's a good idea.
So um,
there's this thing in racing called the
double,
which is doing the indy 500 on Memorial
Day weekend on Sunday and then flying
straight to charlotte to do the coke 600
afterwards and that's kind of known as
the double,
um,
but this is what we're calling the
Danica double and it has to do with just
having spent a chunk of my career in
Indycar and a chunk of my career in
Nascar and it just kinda feels like the
right way to go out.
I don't know,
it didn't,
it wasn't clear.
It was a bit of a murky end as far as
like what's going to happen,
am I going to race next year full time
or not?
And it just kind of went suit too long
for me to have like a proper.
I'm done sort of moment in my head.
So this was just a great way to do it.
So when you say that things happened in
2017,
that didn't happen before,
like what do you mean?
I got a sponsor leave me.
My primary sponsor left at the beginning
of the year.
I mean I,
I signed a contract and when Mercury's
in retrograde so,
you know,
I screwed myself there,
but.
No,
no,
I don't know if it was true.
So,
um,
I,
I guess maybe the universe is a little
bit more straightforward
than we think it is.
A lot of good things probably happened
during that time.
Just in 2017 or during retrograde
mercury in retrograde.
I don't believe in any of that shit.
Oh yeah.
I think people look for some sort of
like hidden meaning to things when it
comes to like astrology.
Yeah.
I do try and understand it.
It's quite,
I'm trying to understand how it really
matters,
but I don't know.
There's definitely some things,
at least with the moon that goes on.
I mean the water changes with the moon,
so doesn't that mean that other things
should to whether it be energetically or
something like that?
I think the the water and the moon thing
kind of makes sense a little bit,
a little bit,
but I think it's probably just like
barely one way or the other.
Maybe it's a whisper on the wind kind of
stuff.
I think it's more in your head,
so stop putting my crystals outside to
charge under the full moon.
Maybe not so important.
I would say it's not that important to
do some something.
Someone sent me about the army using
crystals and I was like,
this has got to be like an onion article
that the army,
the army was using crystals for like
medic seat.
Think if you could see it.
Find that.
Yeah.
It's just the wounded people.
Look at this stupid shit I don't even
know.
I don't know.
I'm sure if it's real,
US Army's new holistic medics treating
gunshot wounds with crystals and
essential oils is satire.
Thank you.
I knew essential oils,
don't you think there's a plant that
cures everything out there?
There probably is something like that in
the Amazon.
Maybe not cures everything,
but there's probably a lot of stuff that
we come from.
Right.
So pair that up with some high
vibrational stones,
high vibrational stones.
Woo tense.
So I'm back to back to my sponsor
leaving your sponsor,
leaving you.
You were like,
that's it.
It's just a never happened to me before.
I've always been someone that's been
really well funded and always had a
sponsor,
always had a sponsor and never a
problem.
And so,
um,
yeah,
it was just things like that were
happening.
I got into a few big wrecks in a row,
like probably three and six weeks that
were,
you know,
like I was bawling in the medical center
after the third one going well,
I mean I was running like a top 10 and a
car blew a rotor and clipped me and put
me in the wall.
I was on fire.
Another driver broke his back.
I mean it was a huge accident and I'm
like,
what is,
what is the message?
What is someone trying to tell me right
now?
And so,
you know,
after I collected my shit and got my
face looking like halfway decent to go
talk to the media out there,
I finally got out.
But yeah,
just stuff like that was happening and I
was,
I was in a very go with the flow mood in
2017.
I wasn't pushing for anything because I
wasn't really sure what I wanted.
So I just let the universe take care of
it.
You've got a very interesting way of
looking at things.
You when things go wrong and you're
like,
what is the universe trying to tell me?
You're not like,
well I drive really fucking fast for a
living at.
Sometimes shit goes wrong.
Happens to it seems like
car racing is just inherently crazy.
I mean that's what I was saying when I
was saying you do one of the craziest
things you can for a living going 240
miles an hour is no joke and metal and
rubber and things just.
Yeah,
trust in something when you're out there
because you're doing,
like you said,
200 plus miles an hour with,
you know,
people that aren't your friends around
you with walls around you as well.
So you know,
you kind of got to put your trust in
something else.
Yeah.
That's why I was getting at that because
I think the way you think is the a lot.
It's very similar to the way fighter
pilots think.
Fighter pilots have a lot of weird
superstitions and a lot of,
a lot of pilots do,
a lot of people that are involved in
intense things.
It's almost like in order to get through
the task at hand,
you almost have to delegate certain
aspects of reality to,
to fate or to chance or to.
Right?
Yeah.
I believe that.
I mean they uh,
have a tattoo on my back,
one of his,
it's an American flag.
I got that when I was 19,
it's like an American flag that fades to
a checkered flag.
And then there's a.
and then I got that when I was 19 when I
was about 27,
I went and got the rest,
which was angel wings and some stars.
And um,
you know,
it's not the most beautiful piece of
art,
but it means something to me.
It won't be really beautiful in 30
years.
I'm sure 40.
Um,
but it's,
uh,
but yeah,
I mean,
my point is,
is that I would definitely pray that,
you know,
I was taken care of and you've got to
hand that off and just go do your damn
job and not be afraid and just trust in
the fate of everything.
And Yeah.
So that's kind of where the angel wings.
Well,
I think that people that do inherently
risky things oftentimes look for signs
or look for some sort of,
you know,
some direction,
some message from the universe.
And that's why I was.
Well,
I mean,
I feel like as a race car driver,
I've thought about this a lot lately and
I wonder how much of our job is a little
less even just feeling what's happening
and how much is actually maybe more
intuitive.
Like maybe we're,
maybe we're having more intuitive
understanding of what's going on and
what's coming.
Then we realized we just are so um,
everything's happening so fast and that
you,
you just think,
oh,
I'm,
I have really good feel.
You know,
I mean,
I'm sure there's some of that too.
But um,
so I think that maybe maybe you're maybe
maybe athletes or people at an elite
level are more in touch with that
intuitive side,
that finite,
like last thread of feel.
Maybe it's beyond feel.
It's a knowing
that makes sense.
I mean,
if you think about the amount of time
that you've spent involved in that
intense activity in this,
you know,
they say that people get road rage for
one of the reasons why people get road
rage is because when you're driving you
are reacting to things that could happen
instantaneously very quickly.
So your at a very heightened state and
people know someone cuts you off,
you start freaking out,
like instantly they go from one to 10
right away and the reason is because
they're always at seven and they don't
even realize they're at seven.
When you were in the car,
when your probably at like 13,
this one goes to 11.
Yeah.
You mean your cranked up?
Right.
And so you're probably seeing things and
feeling things that the average person
they don't experience in their life.
Yeah.
You just working at that top little top
level of
feeling of,
of,
of focus.
Was that a dictate where you call in the
zone where it kind of almost become
slightly out of body?
You don't even know how it's happening.
It's just happening.
Well,
I would imagine like you kind of melt
away and you're just.
Yeah,
totally involved task.
When I think about what I have to do,
like let's say as an example,
coming in for a pit stop and you got
your throttle brake,
clutch gears,
all the different things that you have
to do to think about it logically.
What you have to do is so much more
confusing than just going on instinct of
like just do it
because you have to use,
you only have two feet,
but you have three pedals and you have
to use all three pedals at some point in
time,
but you want to be ready for everything
and you,
you're coming in like with the clutch in
on the break,
but then you have to get back to the get
to the,
get to the throttle just in time,
but you have to have the clutch in and
you have to hold the brake so you make
sure you don't roll.
There's all kinds of things you have to
do using all three pedals,
which you have two feet and so when you
kind of,
when you have to think about what you
have to do,
it's a little more overwhelming than
just doing it to drive a manual in real
life.
I would.
I love it.
Easy.
Yeah,
I do too.
but I mean a lot of people,
it seems like it's kind of a dying
thing.
Yeah,
it is.
I mean even indy cars went to paddle,
shifting before I was done,
it was h pattern and then it was
sequential gearbox and then it was
paddle shifting and then.
But Nascar,
Nascar still still got the old h
pattern.
That left leg is important for the whole
feel of the thing.
Right?
Well especially in an indy car,
in any car you actually have a full on
dead pedal,
so you have all three pedals and then
you have a dead pedal,
which is important because you spend a
lot of time with your foot there,
but it is part of the field.
It is absolutely part of the feel of the
car,
especially with all the g loads.
How did you get involved in racing?
I raced go karts when I was a kid.
My sister and my sister wanted to race,
go carts and I just didn't want to get
left out so it turned out I was all
right.
It and I kept going,
but it's,
it's a very unusual path.
Well,
I mean I did everything though.
I was a played like coach pitch.
Then tee ball,
I was in the band,
the choir.
I took voice lessons.
I was,
I played basketball,
volleyball,
cheerleading.
Um,
I played in every sport.
I took tumbling classes and then I also
tried racing.
So you've always been intense?
Yeah,
yeah,
for sure.
Did you know at a certain age that you
wanted to be a race car driver?
Well,
when I was 10 I decided that I wanted to
go to college for engineering so I could
learn how to work on my race car and I
realized I did not have to do that.
I did not have it.
Yeah,
that's what I thought I did.
I didn't have to do that.
Be An engineer so that you could work on
your race card,
you know?
Do you understand how crazy that is?
When I was 10 years old to three
thinking that,
well,
I dunno.
Do you think you're born that way or am
I an old,
like what do you think about that?
Like to be thinking that way when I'm 10
years old,
like you know,
some people are just so much different
or more mature further along.
Is it?
Why do you think that is?
That's a very good question.
I don't think it's entirely possible
that memory gets transferred through DNA
and that there are certain people that
have a long line of adventurous people
and their family and that gets
transferred to the DNA of the children.
I think it's entirely possible.
I have.
I have three children.
Not a spiritual reincarnation.
No.
Maybe.
I mean,
look,
that's entirely possible too.
I would never.
I would never say no to that because if
you're living this life,
I mean nobody asked to live this life.
You just here.
Right?
Who knows if you get to do it again,
I mean we're.
We're assuming that you don't get to do
it again because we're assuming that
time goes on this sort of linear way,
but maybe it just does.
For you in this life,
it's entirely possible that there's
infinite number of lives being lived out
in infinite timelines all
simultaneously.
We're just experiencing this one.
We don't even know what happens when we
sleep.
You go to sleep,
close your eyes if some crazy dream
about godzilla chase.
Anyone you're on a skateboard,
you wake up in the morning and you just
assume that you're on the same timeline
that you were on before,
you know,
because you have to astral.
Who knows?
I don't know.
I have children and in one of the things
that's really fascinating about watching
a child develop from a baby to a,
you know,
a kid and see their personalities.
Like you realize,
like there's a lot of stuff that's just,
that's what they come with.
Yeah.
They're just different.
Why?
You know,
why,
why was I thinking about being an
engineer when I was 10 years old?
Why was I brave enough to go live in
England by myself when I was 16 and all
good with it.
And you know,
why?
Why,
why,
why am I intent?
Why did,
why was I intense when you met me?
You know what I mean?
Well,
I think part of your intensity is
probably.
If I had to guess,
if I could be presumptuous,
you're a woman involved in a very manly
activity and I'm sure men probably test
you in some sort of a weird way and so I
bet along the way you've developed this
sort of way of addressing them right
away.
Like a listen motherfucker
sometimes just like.
Yeah,
I mean I think you probably have to,
you know,
I would imagine.
Yeah,
to be strong you have to.
I remember when I was younger and going
to meetings with companies or team
bosses,
people like that and was the advice
given was don't say,
Oh I the sun maybe like,
you'd be sure about what you want.
And I remember that.
So yeah,
a nature versus nurture.
Some of it's learned,
but some of it's just there.
Yeah.
You can't turn a timid person into you.
Maybe you could,
but I mean it's not,
not likely you would.
You seem to be like this person.
This is just who you are and if you're
telling me that at 10 years old you were
thinking about being an engineer so he
could work on race cars.
That's not normal.
What's normal though?
What'd you want to do when you were 10
years old?
I had no idea.
I probably wanted to be an artist.
I think I want it to be an artist.
I mean that,
that follows this vein sort of.
Yeah.
But I used to want to draw comic books.
I did a lot of that.
Yeah.
So that was probably what I wanted,
but I was never like,
what I need to do is like,
I need to figure out a way to make my
hand stronger so that faster you see
Steven mind.
I did not go to college.
In fact I didn't even finish high
school.
You didn't at all?
Nope.
I left when I was 16 and I got my ged.
Wow.
I failed the first time.
You want to know why?
Okay,
good.
Because that's like a horrible,
like I failed my ged.
Oh Geez.
Um,
I,
uh,
the constitution test is something,
at least in Illinois,
I don't know if you have to pass it in
every state,
but in Illinois you do.
And so in eighth grade to go to high
school you have to get a 70 percent or
above to go to high school.
I got a 70,
so I went to high school.
Now I'm like a three point five and
above student,
like I was a's and b's not a problem for
some reason.
The constitution and government and all
of those sectors and names and holy
moly,
it's so confusing to me.
So,
um,
so then when it came time to do my take
my ged,
I didn't study at all.
I just took the test and I failed the
constitution test.
So prepare for it.
That's all right.
Yeah,
I mean,
I,
I've never studied in my life so I just
think no,
really?
Yeah.
The only thing I study up,
well study,
uh,
if I'm doing a speech or if I'm doing
something for a,
for a company,
for a sponsor and I need to make sure
that I have my talking points ready.
I mean,
I spent 15 minutes or 30 minutes or five
minutes making sure that I'm organized
in my head about what it is that I need
to get out there so that I can do my job
and deliver.
But other than that,
I've never studied in school.
Keep in mind,
I didn't have to go to a school that
long.
I never.
I mean I only went to school until I was
16,
so it's been a really,
really,
really long time since I went to school.
But you're very smart.
Oh,
I don't know.
See,
I know you're smart.
Thank you.
Well,
what do you do you read?
Um,
I actually,
I want to start reading more.
I've got a lot of books that I want to
read.
I started reading a book called the
Holographic universe.
Okay.
Michael Talbot,
right?
Yeah.
It's a good book.
Is that weird?
There's a lot of stuff in there and
you're like,
wait a minute.
It's this kind of drugs.
There's a lot of woo in there.
I think
a little woo.
So good.
I even simple books like the alchemist
and stuff.
I just really want to read these books.
I mean,
and um,
yeah,
she does more woo woo woo shit.
Yeah,
I am.
Why do you think that that is the race
car thing?
Do you think that has nothing to do
with,
it's just who you are.
That's just who I am.
I remember getting a psychic reading
when I was 18 years old.
Living in England.
Yeah.
[inaudible].
I,
I bought like Linda Goodman's love
signs,
like astrology book when I was a kid.
So when you were 16 and you got a
psychic reading,
totally had a mood ring.
Mood rings are great.
Sorry,
go ahead.
Do what did,
what did they tell you?
They tell you anything you can remember.
I can't remember,
but when I was talking about signing my
contract and when Mercury's in
retrograde,
that was,
I talked to an astrologer and she said,
just don't sign any contracts.
And I was like,
well,
what a bizarre.
I mean I was kind of learning about some
of this stuff because it was quite a few
years ago now.
But I,
I,
um,
I remember the next,
a year and a half later or so,
and you know,
shit hit the fan and I was like,
that damn astrologer was right now,
okay,
mercury in retrograde,
it's pretty standard information if
you're in astrology at all.
But um,
but yeah,
she said,
I saw a psychic in Sedona a few years
ago and she said that professionally
over the next four years,
your life's going to go boom,
boom,
boom.
And I thought,
man,
I'm going to win a bunch of races,
there's going to be awesome.
And instead I,
um,
uh,
have a clothing line now I have a book
that just came out at the beginning of
the year,
my wines finally been for sale for a
year now.
And there's other projects I'm working
on too,
but,
uh,
and,
you know,
finishing off my career in a pretty big
way.
So I guess she was right.
I think that lady's full of Shit,
I guess.
I think she looked at you and like,
this chick's gonna kick ass.
I'll.
Somebody thinks she recognized me.
Then she's like,
okay.
So when I sat down she was like,
all right,
the way it works here is like I just see
words or symbols or things around you.
So if I just look around like don't
think I'm not paying attention to him,
that's just how I see things.
And so I'm like,
all right,
I'm sitting there and she's telling me
all this stuff and she says whatever my
job is,
I travel a lot and things like that.
And then she all of a sudden kind of was
looking at me.
She'll go over,
she goes,
celebrity are you a celebrity?
And I was like,
I only am if you think I am just usually
how I answer people.
Um,
so I don't know.
Did she know who I was up in Sedona?
They don't watch a lot of TV.
I don't think.
You don't think so?
They sneak
it in when no one's looking their lunch
break areas.
Just the arrest their crystals on the
TV.
I just think he's sending positive vibes
almost all bullshit.
I think almost all psychic stuff is
bullshit.
I think you don't believe in the.
Being intuitive into intuition is a
different thing.
I think when people sit down,
they go,
I see you in a past life and you are
handmade and you,
you,
you worked by the river,
like,
get the fuck outta here.
I think that's all bullshit.
I think those people are nuts and
there's a lot
of people that want to think they're
special and they want to think they have
special gifts in there and people get
really good at reading people.
I know people who are professional
magicians and they are expert cold
readers.
They could sit down with you and breed
and tell you remarkable amounts of
things with your about your life,
just with your answers to questions,
but they'll tell you right away.
They're not psychic.
Like there's a guy named bandit check
who's excellent at it.
He's fantastic.
He does a show in Vegas and he freaks
people out because they'll tell you
right away,
I am not a psychic.
He's like,
this is A.
There's techniques to this and it's
something I've been doing my whole life
and you just get really good at it and
he knows how to do it and these people
are con artists.
They're they're con artists.
They trick you into thinking that they
have,
but they might even believe it
themselves.
That's part of the problem.
A lot of those people can themselves,
but I think there is something like when
you're thinking about someone and they
call you like out of nowhere and you
haven't told me
the prevalence of synchronicities that
pop up in your life and you're like,
oh my God,
I was thinking about that movie and
there it is on TV.
Yeah.
It's entirely possible that there is
some bizarre connection that we don't
totally understand to events into people
and into things
well like attracts like or where
attention goes.
Energy flows.
Yeah.
There's probably a lot to that.
Certain magnetism to those two things
that bring it together.
Yes,
maybe,
but I think it's very,
very poorly understood and there's a lot
of woo that's clouding it up in that
wound gets in the way of rational,
logical,
educated people.
Even considering it,
they dismiss it instantaneously because
it's connected to so many assholes with
neon signs.
It's a card reader,
palm reader,
and these people that just.
They're just ripping you off.
That's all they're doing.
They don't have a real job.
They sit down,
they talk to people for a job and you
know you could say it's entertainment.
He could say that what they're doing is
they're providing you with a service and
that service.
They sit down with you and and maybe by
telling you that everything's going to
be amazing,
you'll walk out of there with a lot of
enthusiasm and then life will be
amazing.
Who knows?
Do you believe that?
If you think your life's going to be
amazing,
it will be.
No,
no.
You get hit by a meteor kind of the
house.
You could fall into a crack in the
ground from an earthquake.
I mean those people that died in the
tsunami in Thailand,
were they bad people?
No.
Is there any level of woo that's worth
following through on?
I think
it's all things.
I think some.
Some of the connections and the
intuition and some superstitions and
ideas that we have are probably based in
this limited understanding that we have
in the connection that we have two
events and humans in life,
but I think there's also bullshit
involved too and all these things get
very cloudy.
I don't think there's an absolute,
but I think it's entirely possible that
intuition is a developing sense that we
don't totally have yet.
I think if you think about all the
things that people can do,
hearing and seeing and touching and
smelling all the different senses that
we have,
we assume that that covers the full
gamut of possibilities,
but I don't think that's true.
No,
I think you're right.
Visually,
you know,
we don't see the full spectrum of that.
We see a very,
very small amount of things that are out
there.
Yeah.
And our audio is wall.
You know,
we can hear all the sounds.
Yeah.
I mean it's entirely possible that
there's more going,
like there's certain people that just
have a weird feel to them immediately.
Like scale you got get a from this guy.
Yeah.
There's definitely people that they're
giving off weird feelings and it could
be that your reading their intent and
some sort of a way that you don't see
visually,
but you recognized by their body
language or it could be a bunch of
things.
Yeah.
Well he didn't run when you met me,
so I appreciate that.
Now we're probably scheduled to do this
interview,
so yeah,
couldn't,
but I was looking forward to this.
Why would I run?
I mean I was,
I was impressed by your intensity,
but I expected that in a way.
I mean I just,
I don't see how you could be a race car
driver and not being,
especially being a woman in a race car
driver and not be in touch.
So that's nothing I even thought about
until I was like 14.
Um,
for the first few days,
abrasive,
way late in life,
I think about being a girl out there.
It wasn't until I had cameras following
me around my schools and stuff that I
was like,
all right,
maybe this is.
And then they start asking you about it.
They're like,
what's it like to be a girl?
You're like,
Shit.
And originally I don't know really,
I haven't really thought about that.
Um,
how many other girls do it?
I mean there are various girls here and
there,
but
you know,
all of Nascar.
How many women are right or racing?
Oh,
I'm at my level,
not zero man.
That's crazy.
Wow.
That's pretty crazy.
I know.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
Well,
take it from me.
I'm going to ask you what's it like to
be a girl in racing?
I'm like,
AH,
well I don't really know what it's like
to be a guy.
So,
you know,
I only have my perspective.
That's true,
you know,
I mean,
I don't like being a girl versus a guy.
What's the difference?
I don't know.
What's it like to be a guy?
Yeah,
it probably be different,
but I think that like,
what's it like to be a woman that's the
only woman who's in Nascar at your
level?
That's,
that's a valid question.
I mean,
that's crazy.
How does everybody else treat you?
Yeah.
That,
that,
that really is the main question I can't
answer because I'm not them.
And I,
I know that,
um,
from,
from it enough experience now because I
used to not really look into it much in,
in,
in the indycar days,
you couldn't hit each other,
you know,
you really,
I mean it was,
you know,
you could block and things like that.
So there were some guys out there that
were assholes and I didn't like them,
but,
you know,
sometimes every driver has some drive,
some other drivers that they don't
really get along with.
And so,
but in Nascar you can hit each other and
it's bumpers and um,
which is really cool,
but it also isn't cool because if
somebody wants to do what they can.
So what would I say?
I would say that they don't want to get
passed by a girl.
And you know what,
I don't either.
Is that weird?
No,
I really don't.
I mean I've driven,
I've raced with girls and I don't,
I don't like it.
So do you,
do you,
do you feel differently when a
guy passes you then when a girl passes
you?
Probably,
yeah.
In what way?
Just go internally that bitch.
I'm like,
can't believe my car isn't faster,
right?
This
what happens?
The guy that passed,
good or not good that I'm like,
you know,
come on the radio and I'd be like,
uh,
yeah,
I just want you to see that what car
passed me and how bad my car is out now.
Right now I'm.
So it happens with guys too,
but you know,
I don't know.
It's just a cultural norm that girls
aren't good and allow,
you know,
aren't very good and that they,
they somewhat don't belong and I get
like the little bit of animosity at
first,
but I would have thought that people
would have got,
got used to it a little bit more than
they did.
So.
But you have that cultural animosity.
You were saying a little bit.
Yeah.
Comes from.
But when you say that it's a,
it's a cultural norm that girls aren't
good.
You don't think about that about
yourself?
No.
Yeah.
See,
I knew that you don't have any doubts.
No,
I like it.
Everyone out there,
I'm like,
you suck because of this and I'm going
to beat you because of that.
And Oh God,
I hate you.
I don't think because I'm a girl,
I'm not as good as.
No,
no,
not at all.
So why would you think that about the
other grades?
Just I'm not used to it.
Right.
You just something you're not used to.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
Yeah.
Well also it's like you're unique.
I mean,
what if you were out there in the gym
and some girl comes and picks up more
weight than you and you're like,
oh,
that's weird that on roids she probably
wouldn't be,
but Amazon freak,
some genetic freak.
I try to sign her,
bring her to,
you know,
do,
throw a punch.
I don't know.
I think um,
I think we all have cultural prejudices
to a certain extent.
Whether we admit it or not.
And you know,
maybe you're not a big it,
maybe you're just maybe just have
reservations and you're pleasantly
surprised when people surpass those
expectations,
you know?
But I would think that you would
experience probably more discrimination
as a woman then.
I mean,
if you think about a woman doing almost
any other job,
like if you're telling me you're the
only woman that does that and you're at
this intense macho job,
this is a fucking intense job.
I mean,
you'd go on to 100 miles an hour.
Everybody's nuts.
That's a crazy job.
And you're out there at the top of the
food chain with all these men.
Yeah,
I would.
I would imagine there's two things that
happened.
There's a bunch of guys that treat you
with respect there.
They're like,
wow,
really compressed.
They're cool with you.
They're like,
she's one of us,
and then there's a few that are just
dicks and the those decks are just
encourageable
man.
The amount of times I wish I was good at
taking people out.
I wish people knew how hard it was to
actually take someone out on track.
It's not that easy.
You would because you can risk taking
yourself.
Yeah,
exactly.
and if your car doesn't handle very
well,
you can't get close enough to him.
If you could,
you would just move the air,
which is almost like hitting him and get
him out of the way,
but sometimes the car doesn't handle
well enough so like you'd have to just
bomb in there and God willing,
you hit them to get you to slow down and
then they go sailing and you keep going.
But it's risk.
That's a rare moment,
right?
Yeah.
Have you done it before?
Where I've tried to take people.
I suck at it.
I absolutely suck at it.
I've taken myself out like three times
trying to do it.
I mean,
look,
I'll be the lamb.
I don't mind it to make a point.
I'm trying to make a point if someone's
driving like a dick.
Yeah.
So what was the one that was the most
sad was,
um,
uh,
it was a couple of years ago.
It was a Martinsville and this was when
something was going down with,
it was Matt Kenseth and Joey Logano and
it was during the chase,
which is the last 10 races of the
season.
And they were in the chase.
Matt and Joey and Joey had made it so
that Matt couldn't get in because he
took them out a week earlier,
a week or two earlier and then they got
to Martinsville and it's a very,
very small short track.
It's just a half a mile.
And so it,
it's easy to kind of be able to attack
if you want to.
And so he just straight took them out
and um,
there was a whole big hoopla about it.
People up in arms thought it was totally
unfair and um,
anyway,
during the same race,
some asshole hits me,
takes,
spins me out and so I come back and I'm
a lap down or something because he spins
me out and I go to take him out and I
just say off into the corner,
he manages to kind of keep going.
I spin again because I'm horrible at it.
And uh,
turns out that,
you know,
I get a $50,000 fine because I am,
I'm,
I'm not racing for position because I
was a lap down and they applied that
because that was also the same race that
Matt and Joey had their big thing and I
think maybe joey was leading or
something like that.
I think he was leading and it was on a
restart.
So they weren't racing for position
either.
So that was kind of like their rule that
they put forth to make for.
I mean,
Joe,
Matt probably got 100 or $200,000,
fine.
But I'm there,
I am not the,
I'm definitely screwed in the scenario.
So I got fined 50 grand for it and I'm
the one that's out.
So if you're another guy,
if you're racing for position,
then it's okay to bump into each other
apparently.
Yeah.
So really
you're the one that screwed.
Because if you're racing,
if someone takes you out and then you're
still racing for position now you're
going to have to be potentially,
you know,
putting yourself in another position to
get taken out when they started it.
It's a no win for the person that's
being aggressed that the aggressive.
Yeah.
Was it always legal to bump into each
other?
Uh,
it's gone kind of through waves of
different rules,
but yeah,
I mean it is legal,
but when,
whenever a big accident happens and
there's a tragedy,
I would assume that that's when they
tightened down the rules sometimes.
Sometimes not.
Sometimes.
Sometimes just accept
that it's happened.
Sometimes it's just usually if there's
something like that that happens,
it's not from one person's action that
it's maybe a chain of events that leads
to something like that.
It's one of the rare jobs that you do
that's a sport.
One of the rare sports where the
potential for death is always there.
Yeah,
that's true.
It is true.
Is that one of the reasons why you
decided
not a daredevil?
Like I am not a daredevil.
I went bungee jumping and that is the
bravest thing I've ever done otherwise.
And I only did it because I'm afraid of
heights,
so I just needed to know that if I had
to conquer a fear,
I could.
Well,
what's your definition of a daredevil?
Your brake controller?
You could potentially get hurt.
I'm not though.
That's true.
Yeah,
but you're a race car driver,
but I'm a methodical driver,
a methodical.
I don't go out there and just,
you know,
hold it wide open until the car does
something and then I'm like up better
lift now I'm like,
I'm methodical driver so I build up what
I think what you're saying is you're not
stupid.
I think that's very nice of you.
That's like a really,
really nice way to say that.
Yeah.
You're not dumb,
but you're definitely a daredevil.
Thank you.
Well,
I'm have to be.
There's no way you could not be.
I'm just not.
I'm serious.
Really knows me knows that I'm not
brave.
Oh Wow.
That's so crazy.
I know.
I think you're talking crazy.
Talk over here.
Well,
you know,
it's true.
I,
I just had been grooming this talent
since I was 10 and 26 years later I'm.
I'm okay with it.
I think it's both of those things,
but I think there's no doubt that you're
a brave person.
Actually my first time in a go kart was
horrible.
What you your three?
Ten,
10.
And my sister was eight.
My Dad built the go carts.
There's a big parking lot out back.
So we got like spray cans,
wd for whatever,
pop cans,
I don't know,
whatever.
Yeah.
I grew up in the Midwest,
so pop and set them up in a big circle
for my sister and I to go out and drive
around,
drive our go carts for the first time.
And my dad made there was the little
mistake with the brake pedal and so it
stopped working and since I'm 10 and I'm
really young and dumb and I don't know
what I'm doing.
Young,
dumb and broke.
I guess I was.
Yeah,
like the song goes.
Um,
but I um,
I went to hit the break,
it wasn't there,
so instead of just spinning out or
continuing to turn,
I just went straight and I was headed
for a trailer,
like kind of a higher elevated trailer
which would have resulted in
decapitation.
And I swerved at the last second and hit
a concrete wall and I like go flying and
my arm lays back on the,
on the muffler and my cool puffy jacket,
Burns and bruises all up my legs and on
my arms.
And um,
that was my first time in a go kart
within,
you know,
five or 10 minutes of being out there.
And so my dad just got a new one and
built it and we went racing.
So maybe I am really brave.
I don't know.
You're right.
Maybe it's,
I always felt like an indy car to some
degree.
I wasn't brave because people were
willing to do things that were
perceivably more brave.
But I also,
I did describe them as dumb.
You're right.
So you're probably a little right.
And I'm maybe a little right too,
but you're right.
I think you definitely brave,
but I think there's definitely a line
where bravery become stupid because the
risk outweighs the reward 100 percent,
100 percent.
It's a masculine thing in a lot of ways
because it's testosterone makes you do
really stupid shit.
Like why?
Well,
they're all competing against each other
and the trend out macho each other.
I mean you could go,
there's a bunch of twitter accounts so
you can go and see what's that one?
Hold this beer
is a twitter account called hold my beer
while was exactly why I do everything.
It's like people jumping off roofs and
stupid shit and it's almost all men.
There's occasionally a drunk girl doing
something stupid,
but it's almost entirely men,
so I would think that men trying to out
macho each other
somewhat inferior then because they do a
lot of dumb stuff.
Maybe their hormones are not in balance
like ours.
They definitely,
when competing against each other,
we'll do dumb shit and they trust around
drones to blame.
Will they try that out?
Macho each other?
Yeah.
I mean some don't.
Some are smart and they don't,
but you know,
there's just a part of being a man.
It's like trying to prove that you're
not scared as part of being a man.
Tell me about men.
What you want to know
now.
What else is.
What else is a very manly that women
don't understand?
What,
what,
what don't women understand about men?
That's a good question.
I have no idea what you understand about
us.
Maybe just speak from experience.
Yeah,
but I don't.
I don't know what.
Like if we ask a guy like what's wrong,
see that's nonsense.
Talk.
Many girls out there like,
honey,
what's wrong?
What's wrong?
And you're like nothing.
Sometimes it's not really.
Is it really nothing?
No.
Sometimes you just want me to like,
decompress.
Yeah.
Sometimes it just wound up that annoying
when a girl does.
That depends on the girl,
you know?
What do you mean?
It depends on the girl.
If she's annoying,
yeah,
it's annoying.
But if you're in love with her and she's
awesome,
she can know nothing.
We're good.
Yeah.
It depends on the right one.
Oh,
100 percent.
That's 100 percent.
Yeah.
If someone's asking you questions and
you're getting really fucking annoyed,
it's probably not the question.
It's probably more the person.
If you think someone's amazing and they
ask you something stupid,
you'll just laugh.
You won't get annoyed.
And you guys could both joke around
about how stupid it was.
How the question was dumb.
That's good.
If you get angry,
it's most likely you're just like
annoyed anyway.
Yeah.
So you're just like ready to ready to
ready to sort of fall over that annoying
and to get out,
get out of my space.
Kind of a attitude because you're
already annoyed with them anyway.
You're already don't really like them.
Yeah.
There's probably something that's
already rubbing you the wrong way and
you're tolerating each other instead of
enjoying each other.
Yeah,
I mean I would imagine a person like
you,
a very intense person,
you probably have a difficult time
finding,
you know,
like if you got a square peg in a square
hole and everything slides in together.
Perfect.
And everything's amazing.
Personality wise.
Behavior wise,
I would imagine with something like you
look,
it's a very particular.
You have to find someone who appreciates
your intensity,
right?
Like a lot of times guys are,
they want a demure,
you know,
sort of docile little creature like
me home.
Well the suburbs on the table here when
you get back,
right?
And meanwhile,
you're out there with a fucking gold car
going 150 miles an hour in the driveway
that's running five businesses.
Yeah.
You're going 200.
So if you're saying what's wrong,
the guys are fucking nothing.
Probably a bunch of other shit that's
really wrong.
It's very insightful.
All right.
So what,
what don't men understand about women?
Um,
she's tapping her fingers,
going through everything.
I mean,
I just think that we'd like to be,
you know,
we like to be told what you're thinking.
I do.
I like to know what someone's thinking,
you know,
the whole,
like we're just,
you know,
just keeping to myself like,
tell me about it.
Now I want to know what your self is
thinking about.
I want to know about you,
what's going through your head,
like communication
now,
this universal amongst all your
girlfriends when you get together and
talk about.
I would think so.
Yeah.
So the problem is like,
you look at a guy and say,
you know,
really liked this guy and you're like,
this fucking dude.
Some crazy mystery like what's going on
in your head,
man?
Yeah,
that's not good,
but it out.
Everyone wants to know where they stand
and what someone's thinking.
Oh,
where they stand and where they stand on
what they're thinking.
Because you know what if the thing about
someone else.
Oh,
so you need to know.
Yeah.
You just didn't know if you're all in.
Yeah,
100 percent.
I'm just all in person.
So for me it's not a mystery like you
wanna know what's going on in my head.
I'll tell you right now.
That's intense.
Yeah.
So yeah,
for guys like off drifting,
you automatically assume this one,
the fockers thinking about somebody else
now,
what are you up to?
Exactly.
That's what you're thinking.
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly.
You want to be able to ask.
I guess guys probably do that too,
to hear nice things to girls like to
hear,
you know,
girls like to be,
girls like course to.
He would be appreciated just like a guy
does.
I mean,
I think that's my advice most of the
time in relationships.
I'm like,
sympathy goes a really long way because
I know it goes a long way with me no
matter what facet of my life it is,
but you know,
sympathy goes a long way.
So you know,
if your husband's in a bad mood,
then why don't you just actually start
off with instead of feeling like you're
under appreciated going,
hey baby,
look like you've had a really long day
and I'm sure been working your butt off.
Like what can I,
can I make you dinner?
Like what do you want?
What's your favorite?
You know?
And they'll probably go,
oh,
you know what is not that not that big
of a deal.
You know,
Babe,
I'm fine.
Hey,
let me take you out to dinner.
I get to eat.
The sympathy gets sympathy back and you
don't,
it's not,
it's not good to do it to get it
necessarily,
but you should really feel like you are
sympathetic.
Like if they're in a bad place,
try and help him.
That's sound advice.
Yeah,
just sympathy.
Just be nice because most people go
under appreciate,
especially in a relationship.
I think the longer it goes,
there's a lot of under appreciation and
assumptions that get made about who does
what and checks that box off and
probably especially with kids right
amounts out here with kids it gets way
worse.
It's just there's a lot of time that's
involved with taking care of those
little suckers.
You gotta pay attention to them and talk
to them and they.
And if you have more than one,
like once you start talking to one,
the other one wants to just chime in and
show you what they're doing.
Sure.
You don't die now.
I gotta deal with this.
Yeah.
I think people get used to things,
you know,
and that's part of the problem.
So they get used to each other for
granted.
They do.
And then.
And then you know,
it's like I always tell people,
aspire to be the person you pretend to
be when you're trying to get laid.
If you could be that person all the
time,
you will have a much better life.
I also love the expression for every hot
chick,
there's the dude's sickest groner
yeah.
I don't say it that way,
but yes,
I use more flavorful language,
but yeah.
Is that,
was that too much or too little?
Too Little?
How would you say it?
Uh,
for every hot chick,
there's a guy somewhere that's tired of
fucking honor.
Sorry you'd say it,
but yeah,
I mean I guess,
but that's not entirely true either.
I mean it's for the most part,
a lot of the times it's true,
but a lot of the times people don't
appreciate or circumstance.
Exactly.
And then it's with various aspects of
your life.
Like I always feel like that,
like I just got over the flu a week and
a half ago.
I had the flu and I was sick for like
two days and then when I was sick I was
thinking,
man,
I don't appreciate how good I feel when
I'm healthy because here I am line here,
akin watching Netflix,
feeling like shit going,
wow.
When I'm healthy and I'm working out and
I'm running and doing Jujitsu and all
the activities and I got all this energy
and I feel great.
Like I just can't do anything right now.
I just take it for granted.
You forget,
like you don't feel the joy of just
being healthy.
It just escapes us.
We just so think it's normal
taken for granted.
Yup.
Now,
do you think that you're stepping away
from race car driving when you deciding
it's just like enough is enough.
Do you think that in some ways that this
is you appreciating other aspects of
life too,
that you're,
you're,
you're
looking at your racing thing and you're
like,
you know what,
I did a lot,
I did enough and then why don't I just
appreciate all the other stuff?
Well,
I think that's a good question that will
lead me into a good thought.
Like,
um,
I think it's actually more me being
honest.
Like I think everyone would expect since
I do what I do at the level that I do it
at the racing is my only thing I care
about.
I love it so much.
I'll do anything I drive every day.
And the truth is no.
I like racing,
but I don't.
There's a lot of things I don't really
like about it too and I'm grateful for
everything.
It's given me,
but if you were to ask me what I do
outside of racing and my personal life,
I don't go to the racetrack.
I don't really watch races.
I don't,
don't do that.
So those aren't my hobbies.
Like your hobbies or your real loves.
What do you not like about it?
Um,
well I would say that in the last year.
So the,
just the,
as far as an energetic space,
it's just so sad and negative at times.
A lot of the time.
And even in just racing in general,
most of the time it's miserable.
Like you have some days that are good,
but most of the time it's not happy and
you wish there was,
you're,
um,
you're not satisfied.
You wish somebody would have treated you
better out there.
You,
there's so many things to be negative
about and just the grind of it.
Um,
it's the people like everybody's worn
out and you know,
you have to be really careful about the
people that are around you because they
got to be in a good mood because it's
easy to spiral out of control because
you see each other for three,
four days a week,
every week for 40 weeks a year.
So,
you know,
you got to be in a good space with
people,
but it still doesn't alienate you
completely even if you're in a good
space that people,
the ones next to you because you got a
car next to you on both sides and the
garage and hollers next to each other
and buses right next to each other and
you see a bunch of other people.
So,
you know,
it was just,
I don't know,
there's a lot of negativity to some
degree.
I'm a lot of grind.
It just kind of feels like the grind a
little bit.
And so I just kind of felt like it
wasn't a space that I wanted to be in as
much anymore.
Like I,
I want to be in a happy space where I'm
just doing things that bring me joy and
um,
yeah,
it just wasn't doing that as much or I
was noticing it,
I was noticing I was missing that or
wanting it more.
I think that's really what it comes from
is growing as a person and realizing
I think everybody's afraid to take
chances and do something new in their
life because they're identified a
certain way or there'll be judged if
they don't do it or judged if they do
something different and who are they now
and are they crazy and what are they
thinking and you know,
it's just life.
Just do things that make you happy.
It's interesting because you're talking
about this and the negative aspects of
it is all interpersonal relationships
and so talking to people,
you're not talking about that the grind
of racing itself,
like the heat of being in the car and
the strain and the intensity and the
nerves.
You're not talking.
Yeah,
I didn't,
not the first thing.
I mean that is,
that exists on some level,
but I mean that's,
that's fine.
I work out,
I work out twice a day,
a lot of time,
a lot of times,
so I'm okay with the whole physical
grind of things.
Yeah.
What do you do?
Crossfit and like interval running,
training,
sprinting,
um,
stuff like that.
Circuits twice.
Volt stuff.
Yeah,
a couple of days a week.
I do twice a day.
Maybe more intensity.
Yeah,
very intense for sure.
that's,
that's the name of the game and get it,
get in,
get out.
Um,
so,
uh,
so yeah,
so I mean that,
that is part of it.
The physical part of racing exists and
it is exhausting,
but I mean,
you recover from that every weekend.
Um,
but yeah,
it's,
yeah,
it's just.
And I just love so many other things.
What are you going to do now?
Um,
well,
the longest project I have is my wine.
I bought the property in 2009,
planted a vineyard and it's finally for
sale.
Um,
so,
um,
so it's called,
started in 2009.
So nine years bought the property,
planted.
It started from nothing.
So it came from in 2006.
I went to Napa Valley on a,
on a trip and was on this beautiful
property and it's like looking at the
fog and the valley and it was wonderful
Keesha's and fruits for breakfast and
this amazing white wine.
And I was like,
man,
it'd be so cool if I could have
something like this some day,
but I don't have $50,000,000,
at least not right now anyway.
And um,
because I never abandoned the thought
that I would be able to afford that
someday.
I just didn't,
I couldn't then.
Um,
so anyway,
I just started the process a different
way.
I didn't buy a wine that was built and
established with the vineyard.
I bought dirt,
planted the vineyard.
You go about doing that.
Do you do hire someone?
Uh,
well that,
that day I met a winemaker who ended up
going into consulting instead of just
being at one winery and um,
so he actually helped me pick the
property.
Um,
he's still my winemaker today.
So you bought this piece of land and
then like,
who does the day to day stuff?
You're so busy.
Yeah,
I have a GM.
No.
Um,
who handles all of it and does the
promotion and gets it in restaurants and
you know,
help sell it.
What's it called?
Somnia them,
which is a Latin world,
Latin word means dream.
I was looking at some language
translations trying to come up with that
was probably trying to come up with some
sort of an llc or something like that to
cover the property up.
And I was like,
oh no,
this is way too cool.
This is,
what should the wine should be called?
Um,
so Somnio,
I'm,
it's a Latin word.
And Are you doing red and white or just
so ready to start?
Um,
the only the vineyard is Cabernet,
cab franc,
petite for doe and um,
so from the cab franc and petite or doe
bleed off,
we're going to make a rose a this year.
Um,
and then we also then source some grapes
from Knight's Valley to make a 70 old
blank.
Um,
so we,
um,
we just decided it was going to come out
in the spring along with the,
with the cab or early release and the
um,
and the,
and the rosy.
But it needed some time in barrel,
so we're gonna wait a little longer and
put it in barrel.
That's fascinating.
So that much take a shitload of your
time and thinking as well.
Honestly,
it's probably the least amount of my
time that company.
But I would imagine if you have this
giant investment,
you got the scholarship and investment.
Yeah.
Do you have someone working for you?
They're growing grapes,
two employees and um,
um,
farmers that farm it not full.
I mean they farm many other properties
but um,
but yeah.
Were you affected at all by the crazy
fires?
No,
actually I was really lucky that the
Napa valley fires were.
I'm on Silverado trail side up.
It's actually very,
very close to Howell Mountain
Appalachian,
but it's um,
like,
like 60 feet off of being home out in
the Appalachians.
So anyway,
way down south on Silverado trail there
was fire and then straight across the
valley.
Not too far laterally across,
but it was all the way across the valley
was the fires on the other side.
So I was about as far away from it all
is I could get.
And so I just talked to my winemaker,
um,
a few days ago and he said that there's
really nothing,
no residual from any of the fires or
anything.
So that's amazing.
Like with my wine anyway.
So,
so that whole area,
it's such a bummer that far was in the
same.
Oh my gosh,
you said it was going,
I forget the exact number,
but it was something insane.
Like it was going a football field
distance in three seconds,
like at its peak.
I know that the big,
I think the big reason was the wind came
in that night,
like 40 plus mile an hour winds came
through that night.
Very,
very,
very devastating for some.
Um,
but that's one company.
The clothing line is called warrior.
Um,
so that came out a year ago,
January of last year of [inaudible] 17
warrior.
Uh,
when
is it like affliction,
like skulls and swords and shit?
No,
doesn't worry.
Your jacket I have on.
It's very nice.
Lovely.
No,
it's more athleisure.
Um,
so leisure,
have you never heard of that?
No.
Oh yeah,
that's a whole.
Yeah,
there you go.
Thanks.
I'm a 17 year old.
Um,
it's,
yeah,
it's like leggings and sports bras and
tee shirts and jackets and sweatshirts
and athletes.
[inaudible].
So,
uh,
I want to go back to this wine thing.
Oh,
so you have this thought in your head
about some.
Dang it.
Yeah.
Well I'll go by.
So I'm telling me where I can get it.
Can you get it anywhere else?
Omnium wine.com.
It's not sold in very many places and
mostly online.
It's not,
there's not very much made so.
Okay.
So you can order it online and you guys
will ship it.
Okay.
So now you get this piece of property
and you start talking to this guy who
was a consultant and you started talking
about making wine.
Like what is the process like how does
it you have to buy the property and then
how do you get the seeds?
How do you get the right grapes?
How do you know?
Well,
you have to go through a bunch of
permitting.
Um,
so permitting for a plans for it.
Uh,
there's a certain grades that are not.
So if it's over 20 degrees grade,
then you have to have special approvals,
but under you can plant.
So I literally planted six acres ish of
Max,
that's the Max that I could plant on my
24 acres that I have that was below 20
degree grade.
And so,
um,
so,
uh,
you have to go through erosion control
permitting because it's the slopes and
if you're going to dig up the ground,
you don't want it to slide down the
mountain if it rains.
So we had to kind of get creative with
some of the infrastructure to dissipate
the water and so it didn't create just
rivers and rushing of new dirt sliding
down the hill.
So,
um,
because it's al at that elevation a
little bit,
um,
so,
and then you hire farmers and then the
winemaker helps pick out the root stock
and the clones and then they plan it and
you wait a couple of years for it to be
ready and then the start making wine.
So it starts with clones which stops.
Oh,
rootstock and what does he graft on the
clone that they want?
What's a rootstock?
So the actual route,
yeah,
that would be.
I,
I wish I knew every single thing that
you're asking to the nth degree,
but I mean that would be like cabernet
petite rideau white wine,
right?
Whatever.
I'm sure that there,
when they did all this,
I know I would want to see what that is.
That sounds fascinating.
Tiny little tiny little roots,
but just send it
trellising up and then you know,
then you get into,
you know,
depending on your winemaker,
they decide then how much fruit to drop.
I'm so sort of the vine comes up and
splits off and makes like a tea.
Um,
and so they decide how many clusters
they keep on each side to determine,
you know,
what kind of wine you're making.
So you know,
we drop a lot of fruit to make really
good
wind.
What does that mean by drop fruit?
Like you'd lose literally cut the cut
the cluster off of the vine.
So you.
Yeah,
that's why like if you're buying bulk
wine,
it's,
they're not dropping a damn thing right?
If you're buying grapes,
they're also not dropping a damn thing
or.
Well,
not as much,
probably because they're,
because they're there,
they're there,
you're paying by the ton.
So this is a long process.
It's a really long process to go nine
years from the time you start to making
your first bottles.
Probably why most people,
you know,
I mean if you have enough money to build
a winery,
you're probably a bit older and like you
run out of time.
Yeah,
yeah.
I mean especially
you're going to get any return on your
investment,
you know,
I'm a lot of millions in the hole,
but,
you know,
whatever,
it's a passion project.
Are you doing it as an investment?
Are you doing it because just you
love it.
Um,
and uh,
yeah,
I can
[inaudible] you can.
Yeah.
Why not do what you can,
just money.
Yeah.
And I love the lifestyle.
So I want to share that with people that
are styled napa
wine,
you know,
the connection that you create,
sitting down together and sharing it.
Um,
the stories of the vineyard,
the story of how it came along.
I mean,
I have,
the good thing is,
is people were like,
well,
you got up there.
I'm like,
well,
I have a story.
Um,
but that's what people connect to.
So,
um,
that's,
you know,
so then it's a matter of getting that
story to the psalms in different
restaurants so that they can tell you
the story of Somnio them and then you're
like,
oh,
that sounds amazing.
Oh,
that's hers.
That's so cool.
Like,
I would love it if my wine was a good
story that someone told,
and then they were like,
oh,
and this is actually Danica Patrick's
wine.
And you're like,
oh,
no way.
Yeah,
I gotta try that.
You know what I mean?
I'd rather have that be the backstory
than the front story.
Do you know maynard teen and from tool
to know?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
I've drank his wine before.
Could he?
Could he see us?
Could you see us?
I just.
Yes.
I have some in my fridge right now.
Got It.
A long time ago.
Got it up in Jerome,
Jerome,
Arizona.
He has a little cellar door in jerome.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
I've never met him.
I tried to meet him,
but it didn't.
He's actually in town I think.
Oh really?
Yeah.
I think he's still here.
He was just.
He was here yesterday for sure.
Yeah.
He sorts of.
Some of his grapes from California I
think for SOM is whining.
Yeah.
He did a similar thing,
but he did it in Arizona.
He just bought this land and then
develop it in Arizona,
but the red,
I think the better read came from
California.
Is that what?
He's a freak.
He's a real crazy person.
In what way?
Super Intelligent too.
Super,
super smart.
Too Smart.
Too Smart to talk to.
Most people is just so out there and
it's an intense as well and maybe it's
something to do with the choices.
So He.
I mean he's a lead singer,
three fucking bands and then says,
then let me,
let me just start making my own wine.
Opened up a restaurant.
Like he's just,
he can't do enough shit.
He does Jujitsu all the time.
Can't do enough.
Sure.
You guys know him.
He was over here for Jujitsu to
seminars.
John Danaher.
He was at one of his seminars yesterday.
Yeah.
Now he's a maniac.
Maybe make wine then.
I think so.
Well,
I think it'd be weird.
The normal.
I think that's a good way of looking at
things.
It's nothing wrong with being weird.
Normally in conventional or the opposite
of weird.
I looked it up.
I don't want to be either of those.
Yeah,
well it depends,
you know,
conventional wisdom is not bad.
It said conventional.
There's,
there's some normal.
That's not bad.
You know,
I like normal cheeseburgers,
you know.
I don't see.
I want caramelized onions.
I want to Friday I want Maple Bacon,
pain in the ass.
I love food.
I eat more than most everyone do you?
Yes.
Yeah.
But your tiny.
Well you put it away.
Well you work out twice a day.
Some days.
I didn't work out today.
It didn't work out.
It didn't work out to work out.
But um,
yeah.
Uh,
I do eat a lot.
My sister and I both do.
We're both like
110 pounds and
we are both like five foot and we both
eat a ton,
but we work where we do work out a
little hummingbirds.
All that energy,
you're burning off pro burning calories
constantly look at each other.
Like I would die without fat.
I need a lot of fat in my diet.
Yeah.
Um,
maynard open up a restaurant to an
awesome.
Yeah,
I know in Arizona.
So some sort of feature is wines
and where,
uh,
where in Arizona,
because I know jerome is pretty far from
like,
I mean I,
my,
my place is in Scottsdale,
so yeah,
he's out in the middle of nowhere.
He's his vineyard probably jerome.
Yeah,
I think it's in that area was on the top
of a mountain.
I mean this is a,
this is a cool place to go if you're
ever visiting Arizona.
Jerome is really interesting.
You kind of wind up this mountain,
you get up to the top.
It's like supposedly all haunted and
it's very bizarre.
But there's.
Yeah,
I mean the last I knew it was a very
long time ago that I was there,
but it,
he has a cool cellar door and there's
some restaurants and whatnot and it's on
top of the mountain.
Yeah,
that's,
that's maynard.
That's the kind of thing he's into and
he's very wise to about balancing out
the rockstar life versus like,
that's one of the things that I think
was attractive to him about creating a
wine.
I'd say that's really important.
I mean I've,
I think I've feel like I've figured out
in my life how much grounding I need to
balance me out and it's not like it's
not just like everybody needs 50 slash
50,
you know,
50 percent of the time walking around in
the woods and 50 percent of the time
doing your shit.
It's,
you know,
everybody's different.
So for me it's like,
you know,
maybe 20 percent of the time I need to
take a walk in nature or do a yoga class
or meditate or something like that.
Yeah.
Do you feel like,
do you need decompression time just from
the whole celebrity thing to being
interviewed and media and people paying
attention to you want to take pictures
with you?
They'll just.
The constant assault.
I don't feel it's exhausting because I'm
listening and I'm paying attention.
I'm answering your questions honestly,
where I think most people can just go
into autopilot mode and it's probably
not as mentally exhausting for them.
I need,
for me,
it's just being on,
you know what I mean?
Right.
Like you just have to be on all the
time,
you know?
Um,
so the,
the being on part is nice to get away
from.
Yeah,
I was.
So it's kind of answering the questions,
but it's really just a matter of having
to like,
you know,
navigating life and people staring at
you or wanting something from you or
thinking they want something from you
just because you're trained because too
many people have wanted something from
you to,
you know,
just the demands of the things that
you're doing and running around.
I mean,
I,
I'm on an airplane twice a week doing
stuff,
so it's.
You just get exhausted from that.
Yeah,
that's unhealthy either.
Right now.
Do you feel like you're going to step
away from public life when you stop
racing?
Do you gonna Fade into the problem?
We'll see.
No,
I don't think so.
No.
I'd love to have a cooking show,
a cooking show.
I guess.
I love cooking.
I'm a.
I'm like,
what kind of stuff?
Anything.
I'm not much of a baker though.
That's because I'm a free spirit.
Baking's all down to a science.
You're like measure everything.
It's got to be certain temperature and
I'm one of those.
Just dump it in a bowl.
Taste it.
Does it need more sugar?
Does it need more acid as need be even
more rich with fat?
Does it need spice?
Doesn't need.
What does it need?
No.
Are you going off of books?
Did you take classes?
Like how'd you.
How'd you learn how to cook?
Well,
when I moved to England when I was 16,
I live by myself eventually.
Why did you do that?
Why'd you move to England to race?
You were racing in England?
Yeah,
I left high school and I was 16.
I moved to England and then I lived
there for three years.
How do you parents handle that?
I think my mom cried a lot.
I couldn't imagine,
but they couldn't.
Um,
you know,
they also couldn't imagine me not having
the opportunities so they let me go when
I left high school.
So it's a racing.
Were you doing there the lowest level
open wheel racing.
So what's that mean?
Open.
We'll just means that the wheels are
exposed versus stock cars,
which are Nascar.
I'm so open wheel wheels open.
Um,
so there was no wings on the cars that I
was driving over there at that point in
time.
So it was just,
you know,
no wing open wheel cars.
So I was just starting my,
starting my career really.
Cause from go carts,
I didn't want to be a professional
go-kart drivers.
So I,
I was like,
I'll just get into cars as soon as I can
have this come up.
Well,
I was 14 and I was at the Indianapolis
Motor speedway and I went into a suite
and there was some British dude in there
and so I started asking about cars and
again,
we're at the race track,
um,
and this,
this family that he works for has a
team,
has a race team,
and so I guess I asked all the right
questions and I'm two years later when I
was 16,
they asked me and my dad to come back to
indy and meet with them and talk about
going over to England and race and they
said I could learn more in one year in
England than five years in America.
And it was not true at all.
But I did anyway.
I'm English pretty please.
Crazy pompous.
No,
I'm,
I might make England people from England
mad,
but there's not many that I've liked.
Yeah,
I love English.
People are the opposite.
They're wondering,
maybe it was just my environment like
they,
that no one,
no one kept in touch after I left and
lived there for three years and no one
kept in touch with me at all.
Maybe you were too intense for English
people.
Well,
they also have like,
like this is where you are in this,
where you stay.
Yeah.
Well you're very like rigid class
structure is there.
Oh yeah.
I have friends that moved to California
from England and they are like,
the people over here are so much more
optimistic about it
and open minded.
Right?
Like,
I mean,
just like bring you in and prove me
wrong.
Instead of like prove to me I got to be
your friend,
you know,
of the European mentality.
A little bit more guarded.
Well also being a 16 year old girl
living there by yourself,
not knowing anybody,
dad.
That had to be
really weird.
I grew a lot so I learned more there in
one year than five years in America from
a personal standpoint.
See,
I went over there and I was very open
and
unguarded and would tell anyone
anything.
And you know,
how that work out for it didn't work out
very well.
I got hurt a lot.
I hated men after that.
Um,
and um,
English accents now,
like when you at from men,
I kind of obey
little bit.
Little bit.
Do a little bit.
Yeah,
a little scarred.
Um,
but,
uh,
anyway,
I came home and my parents describe me
as very cold when I came home.
Very guarded,
very cold.
Did you guys visit back and forth
between them?
Like twice a year and they would come
over once or twice a year.
So it wasn't alienation.
Yeah.
Yes.
But they said you were cold when he got
back.
Yeah.
You became hard.
Yup.
Yeah.
Fuck that.
I know
one of the hardest things in life is
figuring out who you really are.
Like what you really enjoy who you are
as a person,
what you stand for instead of what
cultures told you.
What advice do you give someone that's
trying to do that?
Like,
I have a nephew,
he's a great kid,
but he doesn't know what the fuck he
wants to do was trying to figure it out.
Now.
I mean the first quick couple of things
that you can do to identify what it is
that you're interested in and you know,
something that's true to you as you
know,
just what do you do for your hobbies?
That's very insightful.
What do you enjoyed it?
If you were by yourself,
there's a job for you.
I mean,
this isn't illegal here in California
now was sorta.
So anyway,
sort of legal.
It's like some guru farmer.
Um,
and then also this is like an odd one,
but look at the phone,
look at the pictures on your phone or
look at the pictures that you post on
social media maybe or something like
that.
But whatever you take pictures is also
of pretty insightful for what you're
interested in.
You're not taking pictures of stuff that
you don't care about that true to your
phone.
What if you're all selfies or pictures
like.
Well then I think your ego is very loud.
Do you have any selfies on your phone?
So the,
the only reason why I selfies for me
are,
are so annoying.
But Office Dick.
No,
no,
no.
But I.
The only way I do them as if I am kind
of promoting,
right.
So for me it's a matter of promoting a
healthy lifestyle.
So maybe it's me in the gym working out,
maybe it's something like that where I
can be like post,
like whatever workout I did and perhaps
what you could look like if you did
these workouts sorta,
sorta.
Maybe better really.
I mean,
um,
so,
you know,
those are why I would take a selfie or
if it's with someone you really like,
you know,
you can take a picture with someone.
That's something that I don't think
that.
Does that count as a selfie if it's just
you want to do when someone else.
No,
no,
that's just being creative with how
you're getting a picture of you.
Yeah.
So yeah,
selfies.
The only time I do it really is as
pretty much just to promote either like
clothes I'm wearing for my clothing line
or like workout style stuff for my book.
But for me,
I'm not like,
damn,
my hair looks good today and you know,
I,
I'm like,
oh,
look at me and I say nothing.
You know,
that's just
ego driven.
I know as a woman who is very ambitious
and successful and powerful,
what do you make of these social media
stars now that just do that?
They just stick the butt out and take
pictures and a lot,
a lot of that.
It's a weird thing.
And always will.
Yeah.
Uh,
you probably deal with it more
emotionally yourself because it's a
vicious circle where you want more,
so you have to keep doing more.
You know what I mean?
You end up that,
you end up in a place where you don't
know yourself anymore because you're
doing it to fulfill someone else's wants
and desires more than yours.
Yeah.
Right.
Like going to the next level,
right?
You have to keep your like,
oh,
I wore this like super cute,
like leggings and a sports bra.
Now I got to wear a body suit and now
I'm wearing a thong and holy crap,
you know,
like,
look at me now I'm,
yeah.
What do you do?
What?
Yeah,
who are you and after,
but somehow it's,
it's oddly successful.
Some of them their pages of like 17
million.
Well,
whoa.
Yeah,
I mean,
well,
what it said,
of course.
Then it begs the question like,
what is your definition of success then?
Because if you don't make money off 17
million followers,
then what's the point?
I think they do though.
They do like sponsored posts and stuff
like that.
I agree.
That's why again,
you have to go to the next level all the
time to get more people kind of feeds
the ego is getting fed.
But as a woman who's an attractive woman
who's also very ambitious,
like you could have just been one of
those things,
right?
Like you like
when you see someone.
I mean man,
I don't think men look at it this way
because I don't think there's a lot of
guys that like,
look at guys who just do like workout
instagrams or something like that and
they get looked at this.
And how about use your brains protein
powder,
but as a woman who,
you mean you're not falling back on your
looks is what I'm trying to say.
It's like you have them but you,
that's just a part of you.
You're obviously hyper ambitious on top
of that.
When you see someone who's just.
Do you feel like they're wasting time or
do you feel like that's just them?
I just feel like it's immaturity.
Yeah.
I mean if that's your driving forces,
just your looks and you know,
but there are some that have some
content,
but you know,
and they can use it to drive a message.
I mean,
there's some that I've noticed like that
that really do have really positive
messages,
spreading positivity,
spreading good things.
But I'm promoting good things.
But um,
for those who aren't,
then I just think it's a level of
immaturity and it's going to come to me.
I think it will come to bite them
eventually because it's.
Where does the road lead to?
Yeah.
It's a short live success.
Somebody said this once.
It's a really great quote that beauty is
a short lived tyranny.
Yeah.
You know,
like kind of leads me to a little bit of
a c one similar like the,
I'm not going to get it right,
exactly.
But it's the uh,
the ego is impatient because it knows
it's time is limited where the soul is
patient because it no one has knows it
has forever.
We should have memes on a strippers
instagram.
Perfect.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Kind of ego needs to be fed immediately.
You know,
the ego wants something now and it's not
thinking about the longterm or it's
true.
No sole decisions are,
you know,
perhaps unrealized for sore for an
amount of time,
but you know,
the truth will always come through.
And so if you're not living at
[inaudible],
you're going to have a transition
now when you make like a.
If you put like an instagram post up of
workouts and stuff like that,
do you do that specifically because
you're trying to motivate people?
Yeah,
because it does for me.
I mean when I see somebody hot working
out and see a picture of them,
I'm like,
God,
it better get to the gym working out.
Oh,
maybe put that,
put that chocolate down.
I agree.
I think that means people,
especially people in my line of work,
comedians love to mock things along
those lines,
but I take inspiration off of a lot of
people online.
Yeah.
And,
and I,
you know,
my overwhelm,
like overall what I hope for people too
is that,
um,
with um,
with the book I wrote,
I,
I just,
I really want people to find confidence
in themselves and develop a healthier
relationship with food and exercise.
And I think most people think of food as
a punishment,
right?
They're like,
oh my God,
I'll just eat this terrible vegetable.
Or they're like,
I have to work out the socks were
working out,
can be fun.
Working out can make you feel good.
Food can also make you feel good.
Food is medicine.
Food will make you not only feel good
but be good and look better.
So,
um,
so,
you know,
I,
I really hope that in all of my
motivation,
it drives people into a direction where
they feel good about it all.
And there's a,
there's,
there's more positivity around it.
Don't you feel like there's so much
negativity around eating healthy and
working out?
There's so many people that just hate
it.
There's quite a bit of that,
but I think there's a lot of positivity
around it too.
I think that people are recognizing more
and more today the benefits of eating
healthy in terms of like psychological
benefits,
like your.
Your mind works better,
physical benefits.
You feel better about your choices.
You feel better about your momentum in
life.
Like,
Hey,
I'm on the right path.
I'm,
I'm eating healthy,
I'm taking supplements.
I'm working out on a regular basis.
My body feels have got more energy.
It's tuned in
better.
I mean I remember when I cut out dairy
and gluten years ago and my energy level
finally was up and consistent where
before it'd be like the random day where
you're like,
man,
why am I so exhausted today?
I'm just so tired.
I didn't have any of those days anymore.
Yeah.
When people eat a lot of refined
carbohydrates and then shift to a diet
that has none of that stuff in it,
it's stunning the the effect that it has
on your mid day.
I'd always tell people like if do you
need a nap in the middle of the day?
If you're one of those people just try,
cut out sugar,
cut out your refined carbohydrates and
then watch what happens.
You will.
You will have so much more energy during
not a napper that's for sure.
Yeah.
I mean maybe I like coffee,
but you one of those four hours of sleep
at night.
People.
Actually I can.
I don't need a lot.
I wake up with the sunlight too,
so I'm one of those people and I wake up
in the morning and like I see the light
going on.
Like it's morning.
Is it morning?
I'm so excited.
If it's morning,
I'm ready.
I love the morning and I'm very chatty
and I'm very like up and ready to go and
like comment.
Yes,
I job.
Are you awake?
You are now made coffee.
Breakfast.
Let's go running.
That's me.
I'm really annoyingly up and ready to go
and happy in the morning.
I love the morning.
How are you at night though?
Sleepy.
I'm okay.
But once I get horizontal at night,
it's over.
Like I'm falling asleep.
You have no insomnia?
No,
no,
no.
I don't think so.
No,
I have before.
It's awful.
Yeah,
that sucks.
That's not good.
But I don't,
I don't have it.
No,
no,
no.
I,
I'm,
I'm.
But once I lay down at night and I'm
tired
now.
What kind of Diet do you follow?
Do you have a specific,
you said no gluten,
no dairy,
dairy and then a couple of years ago,
um,
I,
uh,
so I,
I did an IVF treatment to freeze my eggs
because I'm getting older and I drive
race cars and I can't do any of that
stuff.
So I was like,
look,
I'm going for the insurance policy here.
So they,
how do they get those out of there?
Okay.
So he really want to know.
It's a weird method.
Right?
Alright.
So you have a ton of shots for like a
month,
a ton of a ton of shots everyday you
stick them in your stomach and you have
a ton of shots and so they dropped your
estrogen down to nothing and then they
ramp it up and then it multiplies the
follicles.
Like the follicles are what grows the
egg.
So you go in after a while and you start
getting ultrasounds to see how many
follicles are growing on each side.
So,
um,
anyway,
it was good for me.
Um,
but that many grows and they want them
each to get to like one bite,
basically almost an inch by an inch.
Each of them.
And I mean I had like,
I mean this is a lot of information,
but you know,
20 to 30 on each side.
That's a shitload of real estate in my
body.
It got very 30
inches on each side of the.
Each ones.
Yeah.
Like what?
Did people think you were pregnant?
Yeah,
you do.
You look like three months.
I mean it was huge.
I was so uncomfortable filling all the
eggs in there.
It's horrible.
This is bobby.
You're number seven,
Mike.
Uh,
I come from a long line
girl so I'm pretty sure they're all
girls.
Um,
but uh,
it's um,
so I did that and they,
they,
you do this trigger drug thing and then
you know,
36 hours on the minute you go in and you
retrieve it and what they do is they,
you get wheeled in the room is super
humid and warm.
They don't look at it on Google and I'm
so animal wild things in there.
So they put you in like they put you in
like ski boots,
like toes get you and get you up and
ready.
And then some chick was like,
okay,
right,
I'm going to give you a little.
Actually,
I'm like,
girl,
you don't have to tell me.
Just do it.
Like that was what I told her and I was
asleep.
And they go in and every they go in with
a needle and retrieve every one of them
one by one with a needle I think.
Yeah,
they go in and puncture in through the,
through it and retrieve the eggs.
Did you get sucked out of their 24,
19,
19.
We're mature.
Okay.
So 19 potential people.
How do you think you're going to make?
Have you thought about it?
No,
they say you need 20 to guarantee one.
So pretty much guaranteed one.
Wow.
This is an insurance policy.
It doesn't mean I can try a different
way if I wanted to,
but anyway,
so.
Okay.
Back to the back to the point like we
just got way off track here,
but this is part of the story as to why
I decided to change my diet and my,
my workout and why I ended up writing a
book,
um,
was because I,
I gained like four pounds.
Okay.
I'm just people I know.
These people were like,
well who cares for pounds on my frame,
five foot who I'm small little and you
know,
for any girl out there,
you know,
your genes only fit when you're exactly
the size that you are and then you gain
a couple pounds and they don't anymore.
I was just uncomfortable,
just wasn't,
I just gained some weight and not
anything really.
Well,
it was,
it was legit,
like I just gained some weight because
of the hormones.
So it instantly also gave me some
sympathy for people out there with
whether it's dudes and testosterone or
women with pregnancy or you know,
I'm a menopause or whatever it is that
changes their hormones and sometimes you
just gained weight.
I'm like,
Oh my God,
this is,
this is real.
This isn't just some excuse for getting
older and being lax about your diet or
your exercise.
It really happens.
And so anyway,
so I decided to eat Paleo,
um,
for like a week really.
I was going to do it for a week and I
did it,
um,
and I never stopped.
So that was two years ago.
And then,
um,
I also started doing two a day workouts
because I wanted to change it up and
sort of kick things up a notch.
But I also realized that I was out
taking my dogs for walks and I was like,
well,
if I'm walking them I might as well run
and do a workout too.
So,
you know,
instead of mile and a half of walking
around the property,
I would go for three.
Wow.
So when you say you do two a days,
like how do you break it up?
Um,
they're usually a little shorter,
like I would say somewhere between 20 to
40 minutes each and uh,
one of them will be.
I do upper body,
lower body and an ab day and I just
rotate through those really.
I just,
I'm,
I keep rotating through those
[inaudible] look if you do,
if I do it right,
I'm so sore I can't do upper body again
for a few days so I just rotate through
those and then I supplement and if I
have time I do interval running.
We're all like sprint for 30 seconds,
walk for 30 seconds and I'll do that for
20 minutes.
And do you have someone train you or do
you do everything yourself?
No,
I do everything myself.
I write,
I love writing workouts.
I think it's the artistic side of me.
I like the balance in the flow of like
creating something that has fluidity and
make sense and there's good transitions
through movement.
So,
um,
I mean I see your big rogue jim going
in,
so I,
uh,
I'd be happy to program for you if you
want me to,
but it's crossed crossfit style
workouts.
Well,
I do a lot.
Like I said,
I don't do crossfit,
but most of the stuff I do is
kettlebells dead lifts
Chin ups.
Yeah.
Too many.
I got a what's called an awful Golf
Golfer's elbow.
Tell me about it.
My right elbow is feeling so sore for
like three days.
Is it right on?
It's like right on the side.
It's like right here.
It just got to give a shout out to Kelly
Starr it.
He hooked me up with this crazy protocol
for healing up my tendonitis.
What is it?
Is it legal started?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's mostly.
Do you know who he is?
He's the guy who wrote that book
becoming a supple Leopard.
He's a real wizard when it comes to like
exercise physiology and understanding
the body and his book's amazing.
New and improved modalities and he's.
He gave me a bunch of different things,
but also a tool to scrape the area which
is going to be like a blade,
like a,
like a metal.
Okay.
I've had that done before and topical
cbd oil,
which is a really good legal.
Yes.
CBD is illegal across the board.
Okay.
Non Non psychoactive,
but the FDA is trying to stop that.
Of course.
Follow the money.
Yeah.
This creeps.
It's a good explanation for just about
everything.
They tried to put it in the same
classification as heroin.
Solaris.
Yeah.
So stupid.
It's just a hundred percent
pharmaceutical drug companies,
institutions of decision making.
Well,
it's just creepy.
People with money that don't want to
lose money to cbd oil because it's so
much better for you and healthy and
natural and does the exact same page in
how much the drug companies would lose
for gain if they started selling it
fucks just.
They want to monopolize it.
That's the problem.
Patents,
they want to be able to patent things.
You know?
That's.
But that's like we were talking about
before about the things that are in the
Amazon.
I mean that state.
There's so many different plants that
can deal with so many different ailments
that people have.
But then I.
Alaska.
Yeah.
That's one of them.
Sure.
Have you done it?
I haven't,
but it's an interesting.
Have you done any psychedelics?
Not done drugs ever.
No drugs,
no pot.
Never know.
You scared?
No,
I did.
My Dad's scared the living daylights out
of me when I was a kid and he told me
that if I ever.
He's like,
you get tested for drugs and you fail.
You won't ever be a race car driver.
You told me that about drinking and
driving to.
If you,
if you lose your license,
you won't be able to race.
And then what are you going to be when
you grow up?
Then he threatened me with dad remedial
remedial jobs.
And um,
yeah.
So he scared the living daylights out of
me.
Truth be told you can lose your license
still race.
Also,
truth be told,
I didn't get drug tested until way
later,
but we do get drug tests.
You're running a drug farm.
Oh,
well,
one you're wanting to drug farm.
Well,
kind of I guess a drug farm lady.
It's legal above 100 percent drug farm.
It's wonderful,
delicious taste in drugs.
It's her is fucked up on wine.
And what is that?
That's drug addicted to drinking,
alcoholism.
I mean there's a lot of other things
that you can do
altering that aren't addictive,
right?
You're running a plant based drug farm.
One hundred percent cash crops.
So are you doing.
You're a drug dealer.
Well,
let's just go all the way.
if I was going to do something,
what would be the first thing I would
do?
Pot for sure.
Okay.
Nice and light.
Real slow.
Don't take much.
Does that mean don't take much,
but just take a little bit.
You don't want to freak out like the.
One of the major problems that people
have when they first started smoking
pot,
they'll take like two or three hits and
you can take one one,
like that's it.
Put it down,
right Jamie?
Yeah.
Jamie will tell you,
okay,
we'll hit walkaway.
Yeah,
don't fuck with edibles.
Leave those alone.
Those,
those,
you need to build up to those things.
Those are completely different
experience.
Experienced users.
Well,
it's not just that even experienced
users,
they don't recognize the fact that it's
a completely different psychoactive
ingredient.
Yeah.
When thc.
THC,
no.
When it's processed by your liver
produces 11 hydroxy metabolite,
which is four to five times more
psychoactive than thc.
It's way more potent.
Well,
yeah.
Which is why people fall freak out when
they eat edibles and they just don't,
don't eat the whole Brownie.
No couple crumbs.
And then don't even think about having
any more for at least two hours and let
it settle in.
Let it
give yourself time.
Don't freak out after 15,
20 minutes and be like,
it's not working.
Right.
Don't do that.
Sometimes when I'm drinking,
I'm like,
sure man,
this is my third drink.
It just doesn't seem to be working.
And then I hit it harder.
And then,
um,
I don't remember anything.
Brownout or blackout or drugs or do
drugs.
Yeah.
Actually,
one of the,
one of the first times I heard one of
your podcasts,
I think it was,
it was about dmt.
Yeah,
that's the motherlode DMT is the
psychoactive ingredient that's in
Iowasca,
right.
It's the most potent stuff.
That seems like a cleaner,
cleaner way to do it as opposed to
Iowasca where you throw up and shit.
Yeah.
It's definitely probably,
it's also quicker,
you know,
like the worst,
the longest.
It's going to take a sick 15 or 20
minutes,
but there's some places that are doing
it now where they're doing an
intravenously.
So those trips are apparently,
that was how they did it in.
There is a book called DMT,
the spirit molecule molecule by this Guy
Dr Rick Strassman who did all these
studies out of the University of New
Mexico and they were the first FDA
approved clinical studies and it was a
group of people.
Yeah.
He gets it.
It's amazing.
It was amazing.
But they didn't interview.
Yes.
Intravenously.
Yeah.
And they were gone.
So for like 40 minutes,
like pull them off into the office,
into the other dimension.
I was gonna say so other dimension,
right.
This dream state is,
do you think is like a dream state?
It's very similar because they believed
that your brain during heavy rem sleep
also produces dmt.
May think that's because we all have it.
We all have the empty.
Everybody has it.
Yeah.
Everybody has and everyone.
Yes.
It's produced by your liver,
your lungs,
and now they know it's also produced at
least in rats by your pineal gland,
which is literally your third eye.
That's it.
Actually.
Insert reptiles that actually has a
retina and a lens.
It's.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it is.
It is an.
I am always trying to decalcify my
opinion.
Glenn,
is that real?
I get that from them.
Crystal people in Sedona?
Yeah.
They say it's like fluoride.
Fluoride is calcifying your pineal
gland,
man.
Like,
cool thing getting in there.
How's it getting through my mouth and
throat?
Are you sure?
Are you sure you are what you eat?
Sorta,
but are you what you drink wine?
Yes.
I get better with age.
I don't know if you're really.
Your pineal gland actually gets
calcified by fluoride in drinking water.
I.
That sounds like some hippie horseshit.
It does sound hippie horse shit.
I'd like to see some scientific proof,
but hey man,
with all the hippy shit,
there's not a lot of scientific proof
with it.
No,
no.
There's not a sense of knowing.
That's what it comes down to is a sense
of knowing,
like,
do you really feel like this is making
sense to you?
Does it register or you're like,
I don't know why I believe this,
but I just do.
I don't even know where it came from.
Yeah.
I don't know about that.
I'd rather trust scientists.
I like science too.
My sister and I went and saw Neil
degrasse Tyson in Indianapolis over the
winter when it was called the radio
thing.
It was called Dia an astrophysicist
reads the newspaper.
Oh yeah,
so he like pulled articles and just
laughed about them basically.
That's cool.
Pluto came up because he was part of the
people part of the group that sort of
said the Pluto wasn't planet.
Yes.
Yeah.
People get very upset with them.
He also loved to point out how there'd
be something crazy and he'd be like,
let me point out.
This is in the science section of the
newspaper.
Like as if like how did this make it to
the science section?
Right?
He's going to come on here sometime in
February and they're going to.
He's going to talk to a guy who believes
the earth is flat.
Oh,
that guy made fun of that guy too.
He's like,
let me show you a reflection of what it
looks like.
If the earth was flat,
you know,
of course it's a shadow of a flat line
and it's like,
of course that's not true.
Well,
of course it's not true,
but there's a lot of young people out
there today that believed the earth is
flat.
Do you believe the earth is flat?
It's most certainly do not,
but I think it's.
I mean,
do they not think we actually go into
outer space and they think that that's
fake too,
but I think it's just a matter of.
I think we landed on the moon.
If there's anything that I think is one
of the more attractive conspiracy
theories,
it's the moon landing was because the
only time they did it was between 1969
and 1972.
They did seven missions,
six were successful,
and that's the only time in human
history that people have been more than
I think 400 miles above the earth's
surface.
Everything else,
all the space shuttle missions,
all of the space station missions,
all that stuff is inside 400 miles.
The moon is like 260,000 miles there and
back and they've never even sent a
chicken in the space and had it come
back alive.
They never sent anything in this space
other than people like into deep space
passed the van.
Allen radiation belt packs the
magnetosphere.
I think most likely we went,
but if there's ever a conspiracy theory
that's attractive to me it's that one
because I just think it would be
fascinating if during the Nixon
administration they really did fake it
and
there's a lot of weirdness to it.
They fake it.
Well,
first of all,
to show military superiority to the
Russians and again,
I'm not saying,
and I used to believe they did fake it.
I was.
I was heavily on the side that they
faked it,
but then I realized I don't know Jack
Shit about astrophysics.
I don't know Jack Shit about rocket
travel.
I don't.
I mean I'm just talking out of my ass.
So like me saying that they didn't go
was literally an ignorant perspective.
Just a guess.
Well it was just being attracted to
conspiracy theories,
which is fun.
That's the problem is that conspiracy
theories are really fun.
It's really fun.
You have is,
are really fun.
All that stuff.
A lot of stuff to get to the get to the
core because there's,
there's,
there's arguments on both sides.
There is,
but it's also you have to recognize in
yourself that you do not want the
official story to be true.
And I do not an almost every single
thing that happens like,
you know,
Moon landing or Ufo landings were any
crazy shit.
I want the crazy shit to be real.
I always want the UFO thing to be a real
thing.
They do have it.
It's even aliens.
Yes.
I think it's more than likely that
there's something out
to feel like that.
We're the only thing in the universe.
It's a little ridiculous.
It seems stupid.
It seems pretty ignorant and arrogant.
Yeah,
but I don't think that it's what we
think it is.
I think it's most likely far beyond the
places that we can currently travel to
and I think that by the time they get to
a high level of sophistication,
they're most likely not even organic
anymore.
And I think that that's the future of
the human race.
I those of consciousness.
Well I think maybe that,
but I also think there's a real problem
with the possibility of artificial
intelligence.
I think human beings are about to create
life,
whether we recognize it as life or not,
what artificial life is going to be his
life,
artificial intelligence is going to have
the ability to change itself,
multiply what human beings have been
able to do in terms of technological
innovation by a rate of something
insane.
Like in two years they'll be able to do
10,000 years of innovation in terms of
like what we're capable of doing.
So I think that what we're looking at
now is the,
the last days of biological life.
I think 100 years from now,
500 years from now,
whatever it is,
there won't be biological humans
anymore.
I think this will be an archaic.
David will change as we know it.
Yeah,
and I think,
you know,
I don't believe in everything the Bible
says,
but you know,
was that in the Bible?
Well,
so the apocalypse world will change as
we know it.
I think the apocalypse local end is,
we know it right.
But I think the apocalypse,
like the stuff in the Bible,
that's all local.
Like if you,
if you lived where Hurricane Katrina
hit,
you would think the apocalypse was
there.
Right?
If you were in anywhere where something
really fucking crazy happened and you
didn't have any contact with the outside
world.
No cell phones,
no radio,
no TV didn't exist.
Right?
True or isolated.
Yeah.
I think that's what all of our,
our notions of the apocalypse are there
periodic natural disasters that are
unbelievably devastating.
Like they've proven that the entire
human race was,
was down to a few thousand people
because of a super volcano around 70,000
years ago.
So I think there's been a series of
those events throughout history where
the human race is brought down to an a,
an almost unmanageable level,
and then we repopulated and I think that
that's probably the origins of the
apocalypse or asteroidal impacts,
which are very common.
They've happened all throughout history.
I think that ai is going to just
eliminate biological humans.
I think it's entirely possible that
we're going to get into it too,
that we're going to take it.
We're going to first of all become
symbiotic.
We're gonna take something and put it
inside of us.
It's going to enhance us was it's our
ability to communicate whether it's our
ability to see we're going to start
implanting chips into ourselves and then
they're going to have improved body
parts.
Like say if you break your arm and
you're like,
look Danica,
we can fix your arm,
but it's going to take a year.
You have 17 broken bones or we can
replace it with an arm that works better
and it'll feel just like a regular arm.
And I'm going to bring in Mike and Mike
has a fake arm and he's going to show
you how it works and Mike's going to
come in.
I'm so much happier with my arm.
Then I was my face
with my real arm drug pushers.
Like,
no,
this lookout works and it's a free
vacation to um,
if you do this.
Uh,
I,
I've watched some,
I heard some youtube video of like it
was someone who channels other,
one of those aspects.
I think it was channeling the Palladian
so probably totally legit.
And she talked about how it was talking
about how as a,
as a human race we have to be careful.
We don't alter ourselves too much
because then we won't exist as a human
race because we won't be able to
procreate.
And that is what keeps our race alive.
That's probably true.
I mean if you think about where we're
going to go,
but also doesn't have to
keep evolving.
I mean if we got back,
look,
you think like monkeys when they were
living in trees thrown shit
different than that.
Now we gotta be chill.
Otherwise,
we're going to stop being monkeys who
will be able to throw shit at each other
and Dodge Jaguars bananas all day.
Yeah,
I mean,
I think people are afraid of change and
I think the human race is afraid of
change too.
But we're by no means personal.
People don't do things right.
They're all.
Everyone's afraid of change.
Taking a chance of having it be
different.
Maybe it's worse.
Well,
maybe it's better,
you know,
but that's like the hallmark of your
whole life looking at 100 percent.
I'm not afraid of change.
I'm not okay.
I have a moment.
I'll take the arm,
I have a moment of um,
uh,
you know,
fear of like,
Oh shit.
And then there's the next moment is,
well,
maybe it's better than I could ever
expect.
What if they imagined
they'll give you two options.
They give you one robot arm that you
never have to work out.
It will always be strong.
You can get that one or you can get one
that you constantly have to work out.
Oh,
that's,
I,
I would probably take the robot arm.
But which,
which robot arm would you take?
The one that you constantly have to work
out now or would you take the one that's
just perfect?
Probably take the perfect one.
Never have to exercise,
just Bam.
Just jacked all the time.
If I wanted,
I mean working out.
If I still needed to do that for like
the,
you know,
feel good endorphin hormone,
sort of,
you know,
state,
then I would still do that right here by
your brain.
Just
from rush.
Well yeah.
And I would go do a lot more stuff like
walking around in nature.
Mm.
That's good answer because that's,
I mean I really find enjoyment out of
that.
I mean I find enjoyment out of the
intensity level of things and the
confidence that I get or the,
you know,
being able to shift my mindset to this
sort of like all go all in.
Not no pain,
no gain.
That's so cheesy.
But like I can endure and the confidence
that comes from enduring and pushing
through.
I enjoy that.
I enjoy that development of my mind and
my discipline and my confidence.
I do,
but I'm probably just shifting more into
enjoying,
you know,
things that are a little more peaceful
too,
so shifting more and to enjoy nature,
but that would be the most fucked up
thing if I didn't enjoy nature anymore.
They started replacing body parts and
you're like,
you didn't give a shit about the forest.
Oh,
that would be sad.
I'll be sad.
I wouldn't take that body part then
probably wouldn't know until it's too
late.
Until they replace it.
Probably gonna be dead before all this
is real.
So that's what I think
those aliens are.
When people see Aliens,
those gray aliens.
Crazy guys.
I think that's just what we're going to
become.
That's what I think.
I've been thinking that a lot.
I think it's natural if you look at what
a monkey is and then if we were at some
point in time,
like some ancient hominid like Australia
pythagoreous or whatever,
Cro-magnon man,
and then we moved on to become
homosapien.
If we keep going in that direction,
this is what we're going to look like.
We're going to look like a little skinny
things with big heads
lollipops.
Yeah.
That's what I looked like when I had my
helmet on when I'm in my race suit.
People that are to alien.
That's a good point,
right,
because you have a regular size helmet.
That's right.
Yeah.
I didn't even think of that.
Did your helmet.
It's like that would be like a big guy
wearing an enormous helmet.
Crazy.
Yeah.
Do you have a strong narrative?
Must have a wicked neck.
I do.
Do you do exercises with it?
I don't need to.
You don't just carrying the helmet
around all the time.
It's probably that and just looking up,
looking up to my nine foot target for
wall balls.
I'm like,
oh my neck hurts.
Yeah,
no,
I just,
you know,
you're not out of the car,
out of the car that long.
It might hurt a little bit when I get
back in an indy car again because the g
forces are higher.
But you also lean your head against the
headrest.
Usually the only thing that would make
me hurt my make my neck hurt a little
bit as road courses at the beginning of
the road of indycar season.
What is it like to test?
Because acceleration and deceleration,
there's nothing to hold you from like
your neck going head going forward.
I mean there is,
but not to the level that you would
drive that way.
Um,
there's just a device that is in case
you're in an accident but it still
moves.
So you know,
holding,
holding your neck forward and backwards
is a lot more sore than side to side
just because you have a head rest.
So when you use it,
get out of a long race.
Is your whole body tired?
Yeah,
I mean in stock cars it's.
So it's really a lot about dehydration.
Dehydration.
Yeah.
I'm in the car.
It's like 100 and 3,040 degrees in
there.
No.
Do you have a tube and you start to
camelback?
That goes through the front of my
helmet,
a couple of blowers,
the back blower,
a helmet blower,
things that are cooler air,
but I'm here to tell you it's still hard
to sell in there or did I imagine
there's a fire in a gigantic iron block
in front of you when the water and oil
temperature is 300 degrees.
Yeah.
Jesus.
It's sort of a,
it's like a greenhouse in the car.
It's right.
I runs right underneath you to.
Do you think you're going to miss it?
That's a great question.
I was talking about this just the other
day,
like,
am I going to miss the intensity?
Am I going to miss certain?
I mean,
I don't know if I'll.
I think I will miss some of it a little
bit.
Every now and again I'm driving down the
road and I'm like,
I'll probably miss it a little bit.
But um,
but,
uh,
yeah.
Again,
I'm a decisive person so I'm good.
I'm sure you're good.
I'm just wondering more if I'm going to
miss the,
the intensity level of the job and the
highs being so high,
but the lows being low.
I mean that's the,
that's how you get the highest right.
And the duality of the,
of the environment.
I'm wondering if I'll miss some of that
and if whatever I do on the side will be
enough.
What is the age that most people retire
from racing?
I'm 35.
I'm a slightly young.
I would say early forties after while
they just.
Their body just takes too much and
you're just exhausted.
I mean honestly like especially if it's
Nascar,
he was just exhausted.
I mean it's,
I mean that's my feeling anyway,
you know,
you're gone for 40 weeks a year on the
road and these really luxurious places
of the world on the barbecue world tour,
like grilling out of your bus and living
out of a bus for most of your life and
you know,
on the road in and out of airplanes
hours have nothing to do on the weekends
while you're sitting there.
So just kind of the grind.
So I think he kind of just get a little
worn out and I could only imagine,
you know,
I mean even like you were talking about
interviews and stuff like,
yeah,
I enjoy doing interviews that aren't
based around how's your car this
weekend?
You know what I mean?
There's just so boring there really.
Right.
So it's fun for me to talk about working
out or cooking or wine,
food,
you know,
all that stuff.
It's just interesting.
Or aliens.
I can only imagine the boring grind of a
media tour that you must have to go
through when you're raising all the
time.
Danica,
you were moving quite fast out there
today.
You have overperformance I was watching
the uh,
the old south park episode.
They had a bunch of Nascar drivers on
South Park and you know,
it was the,
it was when,
um,
cartman's trying to be poor and stupid
so he could race Nascar.
He was sponsored by badges cell.
He
ate a ton of ads to make them as stupid
as he could.
And he realized that the more stupid he
got,
the more money spent,
some more in debt.
He got and that's how you got poor.
They just bought like jet skis and
I think he says at one point in time,
Danica,
you're not having poor habits.
Poor and stupid as I am.
Oh,
that's right.
You were in.
It was in it.
Did you use your own?
No
other stuff.
I was on the simpsons that year too and
I did my voiceover for that,
but for,
for south park now.
Did you love it was awesome.
I mean,
I don't care what they say.
If you're on a show,
it's flattering,
right?
They to make,
to make tv in a different capacity means
you're being noticed.
Especially South Park.
I think that's the funniest show that's
ever existed.
Yeah.
Especially like all time.
If you look at all the episodes they've
done.
I mean it doesn't even make sense how
creative they are.
That's what I was thinking is how
they're just insightful ahead of things
a lot and definitely clever.
Like with their,
the delivery of it now they're wizards.
Just completely bizarre.
What kind of car do you drive in regular
life?
Please don't feel like a prius.
Know if you like.
Oh,
I just drove,
I was throwing some things into the
recycling bin and I'm like,
I'm just trying to do my part because
let's face it,
I burned fuel for living
in terms of how much fossil fuel,
I wonder if he each chart how much
fossil fuel,
the average person burns would not be
doing well on that.
That would not be a,
I would not do well with the
tree huggers are vegans of the world.
All the people loving animals like me,
I'm all those people.
I love the forest.
I try and eat vegetables most of the
time.
Things like that.
But yeah,
I also don't do my part when it comes to
my job.
What kind of car do you drive?
A.
So I've had cars for years through s
through the manufacturer.
So um,
this past year we were sponsored by
Ford,
so I had a,
I had a ford expedition,
e l I didn't know it.
He element it means extra long.
Oh
yeah,
it was.
Yeah,
they hook you up with a Mustang,
shelby.
Well that's not very practical thing.
We weren't even allowed to customize,
customize the wheels on that thing.
So yeah,
it was bare bare bones because that was
part of the contract.
You get a car but you can't get anything
dressed up with the raptor.
So I could have had a raptor I guess,
but maybe like trucks aren't really me.
Whatever
better than the l
A.
Yeah.
So.
And then I had a Tahoe and I drove for
Chevy before that I would think that you
would want something fast.
Um,
so that I uh,
I bought my first car in the last car I
bought.
Oh yeah.
Long time ago I bought a Mercedes ml 63
amg.
It was like a suv,
souped up suv.
That was a long time ago.
That was like 10 years ago.
Um,
I uh,
I bought a range rover.
So since then you've just been using
manufacturer across from the sponsors
because they're free dollars and they're
not,
you know,
whatever is free.
Is Free.
Is that like a part of the contract like
this,
the only car you're allowed to drive?
I'm probably not,
but,
but that's the only drive in the
racetrack.
Probably driving your.
Yeah,
company car.
Probably good move.
Yeah.
But other drivers have other cars too.
But do you think that once you retire
you will start like going,
God damn,
I'm gonna.
Need to get some car girl?
What?
Nope,
sorry to disappoint you.
Mean how'd you,
how'd you even say those words?
Do you know who you are?
And I'm not in a race car driver woman.
I don't even know how many cylinders are
in things.
I'm just,
I just drive.
I'm just good at that.
You don't know how many cylinders?
I think we have eight.
That's so crazy.
I just lost so many fans.
How can you be such a good driver and
not know anything about cars?
I don't need to.
That's a good way of looking at it.
I don't build it.
I don't.
I didn't have to go to school for
engineering.
I remember the beginning of our top 10
years old.
Ten years old.
I remember.
So uh,
yeah.
I just,
I can drive them.
You need to do so one of those new
shelby gt,
500 700 horsepower.
I ceased announced it.
Oh,
a shelby new one.
Not the GT.
500 or the tea.
That's pretty crazy.
Yeah.
Shelby just put out a new Ma.
Well,
the problem with those four gts,
they're awesome.
But the paddle shifts.
You want a manual stick?
Yeah.
Alex stokes.
It's more fun.
It is.
It's just a more racy.
It's just more fun.
And I have a Bronco,
a 19,
77 bronco.
They're driving.
That is stick.
It's like,
it's not that fast,
but it's just,
just feeds your testosterone.
Mechanical,
mechanical feel.
It's analog,
you know,
I just like my car to be good off the
line.
I bought a Lamborghini along while back
and uh,
it didn't have a cup holder,
so I was like,
well this is stupid.
It's not practical.
So yeah.
So then I bought the Mercedes and that
had a couple older couple of cup
holders.
Yep.
So it was good,
but then it,
you know,
technology evolved and it didn't have
Bluetooth to play my music.
So I was like,
well I'm not going to have to get rid of
this.
And that was when I started driving for
Chevy and then I got to Tahoe and I like
that.
And then I got a chevy and they didn't
give you a corvette.
I didn't ask for one.
How could you not want one driving force
in a practical car?
If I wanted a corvette I could buy one.
I know you're good.
But I would say be like,
come on,
hook it up.
I'm not.
Come on girl.
We went though.
I keep.
I keep wanting to catch you in that lie.
No,
I,
I don't care.
I just,
I have cars or like purses for me.
I just need one.
Nice one.
And where's that?
I'll get a new one.
You don't like purses?
Not really.
Just needed one.
That looks good.
And
what about shoes?
I like shoes.
I have a lot of shoes.
You're a girl?
I'm definitely a girl,
but not purses.
What about a curl?
My own hair today.
Wow,
that's crazy.
How'd you do makeup?
Yeah,
my shoulder hurt
a little bit.
Hairspray.
What is this stuff now?
I'm very much a girl.
I believe you.
That's what if people ask me what,
what is it about you that people would
be surprised and I'm telling them like
much more girly away from the track than
you'd think because I'm really
aggressive at the track and I don't look
very happy and away from the track.
I'm.
I try and be funny and I smile more and
I'm much more relaxed.
Are you surprised that with all your
success and all the attention that
you've gotten from your success as the
only woman on your level in professional
racing,
are you surprised that more women aren't
entering in,
that you haven't like sort of opened the
door or do you think that it's such a
specialized and unique thing to do that
it's just not something that a lot of
women gravitate towards?
I used to say that for 100 men that came
through,
if you found a good,
he takes 100 to find a good one that
comes pretty quickly,
but to go through 100 women takes a lot
longer because there are so few of them.
There are more coming through,
but I just think that,
you know,
over time it just takes a lot longer to
find good ones,
but I don't know.
I don't know.
I,
I think back to,
uh,
this is my ego talking.
I think back to a long time ago,
um,
when I'm.
Paul Newman was still alive and we were
on a late night show to the other
probably Letterman,
and he was asked before I went on,
he was the first guest if there was
going to be another driver,
another girl that comes through that
compares to me and he said he didn't
think so
maybe there won't be.
Maybe there will be no shit.
Yeah,
he knew his shit.
Maybe.
I mean,
you're unique.
I'm sure there will be some day I meet a
lot of women like you because of mma.
Oh,
there's those savages that enter into
mma.
The women that wind up fighting in MMA,
there's a lot of them and I'm kind of
stunned at how many there are.
But when I say they're like you,
I mean they're bold,
powerful,
unique people that are,
does take wild chances.
I mean the type of person that is like a
holly home or something like that,
so I think the big difference lies and
there are a lot of people that are
strong,
aggressive,
confident,
assertive,
bold,
but to then be able to keep it together
and I'm up up above their shoulders.
That's another,
that's the difference.
Keep it together in the pressure of a
race.
Yeah.
And the pressure of whatever moment or
the tablet you're having,
whatever pressures are being put on you
around an event or for one.
I mean those are,
that's really hard.
The right people around you being able
to filter the shit and lead in like keep
the good,
keep your own confidence up.
That's,
that's hard.
That's the hardest part.
And then being able to flip that switch
when you're performing to,
of course then not have doubts,
but I'm more confidence.
I think everything that you said would
be mirrored by what a woman who competes
at the very highest levels of MMA would
say.
I think they would.
They would find all those things to be
factors,
you know,
it's just,
um,
I'm really stunned that you literally
are the only one.
I mean,
there's,
that's a,
that's a incredibly rare position.
Do you ever stop and think about like,
what if you weren't there?
It's not like it's forbidden for women.
I never thought about it like that.
I've mostly only thought about it from
the perspective of like,
have I thought about what I've done in
the sport because it's stuff that people
haven't done before and usually my
answer is,
is that someday I'll look back and be
able to have a little bit more
perspective on it,
but right now just to kind of in the
middle of it.
Um,
but yeah,
I've never thought about it like that.
Like what if I was never there?
Yeah,
I mean,
you're the only one.
So if you were never there,
what it would,
it would just be constantly a boys club
forever.
I mean,
I'm just,
I'm,
I'm really fascinated by complete
outliers and you're a complete outlier
in that regard.
I mean,
there's not like 30 girls,
oh,
there's 500 man.
But there's 30 girls know how many men
are Nascar drivers?
Uh,
well the field is 40.
Yeah.
So 40 men one check.
That's crazy.
And then there's a bunch of people that
are trying to do it.
Like how are there any women that are
trying
our formula is others,
some that do some part time stuff.
And I'm trying to think of someone has
done like a full season.
I don't know,
back in indy car there was some girls
who did more.
There were at one,
one indy 500,
there was like five of us.
But most of the time there's none
or one
comes in waves.
Do you start,
I mean do you think that when you stop
and you look back in your career,
you'll take into account and maybe have
a more objective sense of what an impact
that you've had?
Of course,
but I need distance from it.
I need to gain perspective that way.
Does that make sense?
Does sharing your career too,
like I mean to be able to identify the
things that you've done,
the influence you've had over people
with the conversations you've had with
the,
with the things in business you've done?
I mean it's hard to see when you're in
the middle of it.
Yeah.
I don't look at that.
You don't want to look at that
because I want to get distracted.
That's why people don't in the moment
because it doesn't matter.
Yeah,
but I'm what I'm doing.
A lot of people are doing what you're
doing is very.
It just tends to be a woman that does
the thing that many men think is
probably one of the most manly things
you could do other than fighting and
maybe football.
A race car driver,
like a little boy.
What are you want
to be when you grew up building?
I'm in a race car driver,
but that's just lying to me.
Queen.
I mean it's like a natural thing for men
to gravitate
towards.
His Dad always said he was just like,
Gosh,
I cursed with three girls in the house.
He goes,
my mom and then me and my sister and I'm
like,
Dad,
what more did you want?
Like what more did you want with
you had a boy as a son,
like what was he going to do that's
cooler than what I'm doing?
He'd be out there banging chicks.
That's what he's missing.
You think my dad would think that was
cool.
If his son was banging chicks?
I would think probably that's my boy.
Scared shitless for me.
Yeah.
That's got to be.
I think still in my adult life.
It's like
they had the courage to let you go to
England by herself when you were 16.
I mean that and race over there on
another continent all the way across an
ocean sort of.
You did get hurt to get to.
You would take forever.
Yeah.
Bold.
What is the worst crash you've ever been
in?
My first crash in Indycar,
so my very first race kind of paralleled
getting in a go kart for the first time.
Having a big crash.
But yeah,
it was homestead Miami and uh,
there's a big accident and I was running
low and someone was sliding down the
track that had damage and they clipped
my right rear and shot me up into the
wall headfirst and
slid down the track and I don't remember
that part.
I don't remember getting out.
I don't remember walking to the
ambulance,
but there's footage of all of it.
And I walked the wrong way away from the
ambulance.
I was walking the opposite direction and
then I was kind of stumbling around and
then I got back to the back to the
medical truck and then I got in and
apparently I was very repetitive on the
way to the hospital and I kept asking
them did it look bad?
And they're like,
you've asked us to add a few times.
And I'm like,
Oh,
I'll just stop.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
That's a severe concussion.
That's one of the things that happens is
the people ask the same questions over
and over again.
Well,
then I've had one.
Let's hope I don't have a cte.
I'm sure you probably do.
I probably do.
Yeah.
Just a little bit.
That touch matter makes you more risky.
Why does it does.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
That sort of thing.
One of the things it does,
it makes people more impulsive.
Do UFC people get.
Yeah.
One hundred percent.
Did you see that video?
Is there,
are they doing studies in UFC like they
did in the nfl with.
I'm doing tests after they've passed
away to know if they had cte,
isn't that would nfl had they like,
uh,
there was a study that came out last
year.
It was like almost all but one out of
100 and some had cte.
Yeah,
it was.
I forget the numbers,
but yeah,
there was only like one or two people
that didn't have.
It
hasn't done that.
Doc hasn't been around as long as the
NFL obviously.
So we were not dealing with the same
data pool,
but I'm sure when people
do pass away we're going to find it.
It's just varying levels.
I heard they actually have a test now
for cte.
I was talking to a trauma surgeon that
you're alive.
What would you do if you had it?
Make excuses.
I just go extra crazy.
Well,
that's why I'm gambling.
Naked
bottle of whiskey in each arm.
Chug,
pals.
So insightful.
This question,
did you see the video that just came out
from a couple of days ago from the guy
that hit the off ramp and went flying
through the air and landed in a house in
the second floor of a house?
His car's poking out the side,
but I couldn't.
He couldn't do it again if he had to.
I'm sure.
No,
no.
It's just total random.
Crazy luck.
But it is hilarious.
I made
and see if you.
Once you find it,
go then go to Christa.
Lee is instagram because Taleah had a
hilarious meme that he created,
but this car hit this hit like a
barrier.
Hit one of those cement barriers and
literally got launched into the air and
stuck into the second floor of a
building and.
Oh,
what country was this in?
Morocco?
America.
Margo to people escape the injuries.
Serious injuries.
How the fuck did.
I mean I wonder how they got out of the
car.
I mean it's,
it's the way it's hanging out of the
building.
Hopefully it's front wheel drive and
they could keep accelerating to get a
little further in so they can get out of
the car that's spoken like a true race
cars.
Take it about it that way.
Yeah.
Here it is.
Here's the video footage so you could
see it and there's the car washes it
hits.
See this is that.
It's hard to tell there,
but they literally went across traffic.
You can see it again.
The guy goes across,
traffic,
flies into the air seat.
Go to Christa,
Leah's page,
his instagram page and find the meme
because then you can see that and what
do you.
So let's get this guys.
Oh,
that's crystal.
He is there.
He says,
come here.
Come over me.
I can't tonight.
Her.
My parents were on the first floor and
second floor and I have been calling me.
That fucking car is stuck inside that
building.
I mean you to believe that that was
real.
If you didn't see it.
There
is that need,
that dentist office that he just parked
his cell phone himself after that.
Yeah.
Here's the question.
What do you do if you're in the car?
Like it gets stuck there?
Even climate probably drunk.
You got to be drunk,
right?
I mean there's nobody or something.
So you just,
you opened the door and you wait.
You uh,
you take on the sprained ankle and you
jump and then it lands on your fucking
head.
The thing falls out of the building,
the right thing here.
You call the cops.
You are honest.
You
video
is there a bit coins and then you go,
oh my God,
that's funny.
Who put up the video?
Where's the video from?
Some dudes name?
What is his name?
Kenny homes.
It's k homes live.
He's the guy who had for.
Oh,
he's from NBC.
La.
I guess.
MInor injuries.
That's crazy.
Oh,
santa ana.
Santa ana.
People are out of their fucking mind.
That's where eddie bravo's from santa
ana.
People.
Boom.
Look at that car flying through the air.
It's just the fact that it's stuck into
the building.
That's just so ridiculous.
It's probably froM movie now.
When you drive in regular life,
you a lead foot.
I'm a very aggressive driver.
Yes I am.
I'm,
I have a large comfort zone.
I say people piss me off a lot.
They are horrible drivers and I,
I'm,
I'm very,
uh,
yeah.
The only way I can make sure that I
don't get a speeding ticket is to not
drive.
How many speeding tickets have you
gotten?
Oh,
I've been pulled over at least 20 times.
I got pulled over three times in three
days at one point when I had my mustang
cobra,
my first ever car.
Oh jesus.
See,
that's why I'm surprised you don't have
a fast car.
Oh,
I always make sure iT's a good car,
like that fast car.
But I mean like today,
like right now,
like when you drive,
driving around,
pulling up.
No,
no,
no.
I mean your everyday life.
Yeah,
well I'm driving rentals because I don't
live here.
I mean not.
I mean here in real life and real life.
Oh yeah.
Like where's my sports car?
Yeah,
well I,
you know,
in 40 weeks a year I do that.
So you just get it over.
I got two dogs.
Right.
So you get enough of it.
All my bags,
I feel like I'm trying to sell you a
car.
What car should I buy?
I would say something american,
something american made cars tend to
die.
I don't care if they are or aren't
really why I have a porsche I liked.
I like german cars too.
They're more reliable.
What I like about american cars is I
like the sound.
I liked the way they just is a rumble
throatiness to it,
to it you like to like.
So you like to make noise on the road.
I'm a loud person.
Yeah.
I have a 65 corvette with straight
pipes.
Those pipes kind of know what that is.
I can picture it kind of race car
driver,
but it's a step.
That's what's important.
I,
I
don't care,
but I would feel like where someone like
you,
once you transitioned away from racing,
then it's going to be more important to
you because you're gonna miss the
capabilities of those things.
That might be true.
I might have to.
Uh.
Oh,
there's my car.
that is a good looking car.
Sweet car.
Jay leno,
of course.
Of course he loves cars,
not,
I also don't really like old cars,
so,
um,
that looks pretty good.
It's pretty fancy looking.
But um,
yeah,
I'm,
I'm a new car person.
I like new modern sports cars.
I do as well,
but that car is a 65 on the outside,
but all the underpinnings are completely
modern as a [inaudible] supercharged
engine.
So it does a modern corvette engine.
It's got modern brakes,
modern suspension.
You don't know what any of that stuff
means.
Yeah.
That's cool.
Great.
I know that my very first car,
my mustang cobra,
I drove it so hard that I needed an
8,000 miles.
I was on my third set of brakes.
Uh,
we put stiffer sway bars in it so that
it would handle better.
Um,
it was,
uh,
yeah,
I went through three,
so yeah,
it was on my third set of brakes and
8,000 miles.
And now you say mustang cobra.
Like what year was this?
Oh,
this is when I first.
This is my first ever car,
so I was 16.
So I think it was a,
um,
a 97.
It was,
yeah,
it was.
I'm not saying they're not cool,
but it was back when they were more cool
when you know,
they were a lot less common.
Yeah,
they were okay.
But I kind of back into the cobra.
Cool days.
No,
the 90 seconds.
We're okay.
There are like,
it run the eighties is when they came
out with the five point.
Oh.
And then like mustangs had a little bit
more power again.
So what's your dream car then?
That corvette.
That's my favorite car now what?
Then?
No,
try that around.
Do you drive it much all the time?
Well it doesn't really rain in
California,
so I guess you can.
Well it has top.
He put.
I have no good for you.
Good for you.
It's just a car?
Yeah.
Oh man.
I'm not afraid of it getting wet.
The only problem is it's slippery.
It doesn't have any control or any of
that.
It's just all engine power and torque
and yeah,
that's fun.
Yeah.
I remember driving a camaro around in
the rain and it was handled like trap.
Just get one of the new ones,
camaro.
zl one.
They have a new one,
650 horsepower.
It's fucking ridiculOus.
I mean,
nobody even barely uses the full speed.
I don't know.
What am I?
Oh,
So I was actually going to tell you
about this.
This is,
I did A road and track,
um,
cover article where I test drove,
it was a porsche,
a corvette.
Um,
it,
I think it waS a viper of some sort of
viper.
And then there was um,
A,
a,
a lamborghini mercia logo.
And I'll,
I mean my exPerience was the,
the porsche was loose,
which is this one.
The corvette was tight,
which meant it was the most comfortable
and stable to drive.
Um,
the,
uh,
I think it was a viper.
The viper was just light on its feet,
kinda just didn't really.
It wasn't very stuck and it was just
kind of clunky.
that looks like
it's about seven or eight years old.
Is that right?
Oh,
at least.
Yeah.
And then,
uh,
the,
the lamborghini was,
was also light.
I mean it just went so fast,
but it's pretty well balanced,
but probably a little on the loose side.
So
you know,
they stopped making vipers,
but I know the car for you.
Does it car that's for sale right now
that uh,
I saw this morning.
No,
no.
I'm trying to sell you a car.
This whole giappo link had a rare,
one of the,
this one dealership in 2017.
The country bought up like 90 percent of
the vipers and they ordered them in a
bunch of crazy paint schemes and they
ordered this hot pink viper.
ShuT up.
You got to see it.
I drive it.
It's so fucking bad ass.
I'd drive it cooler if a dude who drive
a pink car and I would drive like some
like stainless steel,
silver,
you know,
I would drive it and then I'd get a
rainbow license plate so people would
just assume I'm gay.
There's no way around it.
I had a rainbow platE.
You've got a pink car.
Just let it out and found it.
Isn't that it's shit.
It was a google news feed this morning.
I looked at that.
I was like,
if I was at church I'd Be my fucking
car,
but it's like crazy metallic hot pink
viper.
Mary kay car.
No,
that's not it.
That's old.
That shit's old.
That's red.
It's a 2017 does.
It might not even be joppa like I might
have.
That was think that was what I was
reading.
Drive it.
You don't have to pull it up.
It's good thought.
But I'm rather have black.
Let me guess.
Black
tinted windows.
Black,
black,
black.
Whoa.
Darkness.
Like a darth vader type thing.
So bad ass.
More.
More masculine than feminine.
Yeah.
Trying to figure out what kind of.
Oh,
there it is.
That's not it.
But that's an old one too.
That's terrible.
But it's all right.
No worries.
So if someone lookS gross,
the other one didn't look so gross.
It's more of a darker pink.
You don't have to find A chamber.
Forget it.
She's.
She's going to hate it no matter what.
She wants darth vader,
Pink.
Corvettes.
That a angelina.
I saw her the other day.
I started driving that know new
angelina's.
Angelina is a woman who,
when I moved to California in the
nineties,
she used to have these billboards all
around California of what?
It's her.
Her like in her bikini line and it would
just say her,
it would just say her name and her phone
number and that's those,
those billboards.
Oh shoot.
That's right.
And so these.
And I'd Be like,
where the fuck is angelina?
And everybody be like,
oh,
I was just like this local celebrity.
And so she apparently is just a wealthy
lady who uh,
all of her time here has done that.
Just got these big biLlboards.
Yeah.
She's doing a split on top of a corvette
grand.
Is that a good thing for her?
Maybe she kept doing it,
so she still does it right.
There's,
you still have a billboard?
Not a billboard,
but I just,
she has at least three different print
corvettes and I've seen,
I've seen her really recently in the
pink corvette.
Yeah.
But not me.
Not,
you
know,
I'm more like,
I'm more of your subdue.
Actually when I got the lamborghini and
I had to go pick my sister up from the
airport.
Okay.
There's nowhere to put your.
Put your bags.
It's like a briefcase for,
for a trunk and it's in the front.
So that was kind of silly and then I
realized that people normally get these
cars so they can just kind of take it
out to dinner.
I don't want to be looked at so I'm not
going to.
I'm more likely to take it to go get
groceries than I am to go to dinner.
So I realized it was pretty pointless
for me.
Yeah,
that's not the car for you.
And if I want performance I go do my job
for now.
For now.
But when it's over it,
that's what I'm trying to look.
I'm trying to keep trying to sell me
your.
You're looking forward.
Yeah.
I'm looking forward after these next two
races.
We'll have to visit again in a year,
a year from now and.
And have to figure this,
figure it all out.
You.
I'll tell you,
you're right.
Probably.
Well a year from now.
Then the new corvette,
zr one will be available.
750 horsepower.
Stupid two seconds.
We're going to use it.
So you might use the zero 1650 speeding
tickets.
So he talking to you,
is it?
It's true.
Nobody.
Ain't nobody got a speeding ticket for
getting the speed limit to quickly
though.
That's true.
Yeah.
Well,
they probably would pull you over.
Anyway,
funny story about when I got pulled over
when I was 16 with my mustang cobra,
I was picking my girlfriend up and
pulling out of her,
her off of her straight onto the main
street and it was wet out and so I kinda
got it going and kicked it sideways a
little bit and looked in my rear view
mirror at the stoplight and there's a
cop sitting there.
Well he comes for me,
so I Turned on the first road I can
find.
So I make a left drive down the road.
It's fricking dead end.
So I pull into a driveway and we
slouched down real low and the cop kind
of drives around and all of a sudden
somebody comes out from the house now
can I help you?
And I'm like,
ah,
what road is this out here?
I mean,
mind you,
it's the road I live off of.
I'm like,
oh,
what road is this out here?
So anyway,
so we're like,
oh good.
Okay.
Thank you.
Sure,
and so we
get back in the car and the cops gone,
so we backed out and head back down the
road again,
trying to get further away from the stop
light,
make a left.
I look over in the parking lot across
the street,
the grade school parking lot cops
sitting there.
So I make the first right I can then.
So I turned right into a neighborhood
and I'm driving along and he finally
catches me in.
I,
I think I cried to help me.
He didn't turn his lights on.
So when you were running from him kinda
[inaudible] this guy,
it sounds like a shitty driver,
like a shitty cop,
but I think I got in trouble for being
sideways.
Not for speeding.
Yeah.
You should say
yes.
So your friend's car.
I don't even know how to drive this
thing,
ben.
Actually a clever approach.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
just say,
I don't know what happened.
I hit the gas and one side was my
getting pulled over three times in three
days episodes.
So that was number three.
I think I cried.
Maybe it was number two.
So is that why you were running from the
cops?
liquor.
I just can't.
I can't keep doing this.
I was just trying to see if I can
get away.
Well,
danica,
I think I've kept you long enough.
It was really wonderful to talk to you.
I really appreciate it.
It was really fun.
I wish you all the best of luck with
your wine and your clothes and your last
two races and uh,
it was a pleasure.
Thank you.
So nice to talk to you about the whole
car situation next year and next year
you're going to want to get something
crazy.
I guarantee you,
once you're done,
when I tell you I'm,
I'm a,
I'm missing the action.
I'll let you just call the car.
I should buy it.
Sounds like a plan.
Danica patrick.
Ladies and gentlemen.