Okay.
Well good.
Yes,
we're back. Ladies and gentlemen. Look,
Greg Fitzsimmons is right in the
letter of Santa Right now plays,
it's not too late next year.
So always next year.
I was thinking about Santa with uh,
the elves.
Isn't there a funny metaphor that like
he's got all these little elves working
to make children's toys for no money.
And then you think about our toys do come
from China. That is kind of fucked up.
But Chinese people weren't elves,
dude to children.
How rude their children are making
the toys, little else children.
That is kind of fucked up.
Yeah.
The whole idea of getting a
bunch of people to work for
way less than they would ever make here
is kind of a weird accepted thing that
we have as far as like our items, our
electronics and the things that we love.
Like almost all of them are made by
people in another country working for shit
money.
That's NAFTA, man. We opened it up.
So what it is the WTO to trade
organization, he has basically, you know,
they used to be slavery and with
slavery you paid, you paid the help,
nothing or very little and a,
you had to house them and you had to
feed them and you have to heal them.
You go to a third world country,
it's slavery,
but you don't have to deal
with any of the overhead
Yo. Cause they don't really care
if they own you all the time.
They just care if they own you enough
so that you show up and do what you have
to do.
Exactly like the,
the idea that you're just free to
wander around and quit and come back.
But if you keep them in economic slavery
essentially always going to be in
slave.
Well that's a mark Saturday
that capitalism depends on a, a,
a certain percentage of the population
being hardcore Unemployable's so that you
can always say there's somebody else.
Ooh,
that's weird.
It's weird because I like the idea that
people can do whatever they want them to
do with their life. They can, they
can make whatever choices they would,
they would like to make. They could take
on whenever, any job they want. But it's,
it's strange when you think of someone
who's so far ahead of the game,
like some Warren Buffet type character,
not him.
I don't know what kind of business
he owns. Sam Walton, some dude,
some what's make up some fucking
billionaire character. Right.
Who decides he can make x amount more
per year if they open up a shop and
Guatemala and they just close up that
one they have here in the states,
a little too pricey. This one's
going to make us, you know,
x amount more on the dollar.
Yeah.
And probably he will never
even know what is it.
He will l it's a fucking,
it's another zero and it column
and in one of his and it,
and it crazy thing is, is that, you know,
I don't know, I'm not super wealthy,
but if I,
I would really
be thinking about a different agenda than
making more, you know, you really feel,
look at the people that
create, um, you know,
an economy within their own country
or within their own community and a,
at the same time live
the life that they deal.
Never fucking eat that money up anyway.
And look at you.
You got your own little
in your little economy,
you've got a little podcast coming off
of yours and you got people that work for
you and comedians that you bring on the
road and you know, it's, it's everywhere.
It's almost like,
you know,
I hate that expression that
Obama used when he was running,
when he was in office about small
businesses. You didn't do that alone.
He didn't do that by herself. Right.
But the reality is his point was,
was right. And it's, it's
right with everything. Like,
you can't sell iPhones if no one shows
up for work in the factory. Right.
If everyone goes, fuck you, you
can't pay me 25 cents an hour,
fuck you, then we don't
have iPhones anymore. Yeah.
But because we know that these
people were poor, not we were not,
we don't have any iPhone factories, but
because they know these people are poor,
they can continue doing that. Yeah.
That's so weird. Man. That's so weird.
They're jumping off the building so much.
They have nets around them.
You look at that, right? He
didn't know that. Nah. God, dude,
the Foxconn factories are terrifying
because those people live there.
They have dormitories there, the
eat there, live there, asleep there,
and they have nets all around them.
And this is where it gets really weird.
You know,
there's always gonna be people who on
the hardcore right will always argue
towards whatever's like economically
best for the company. Yeah.
They'll somehow or another come up with
some justification for what kind of
damage? Tapping an oil well do or
oil spills or, or this kind of shit.
But this guy said to me, he goes, well,
you know, if you look at the numbers,
it's actually very similar to the
number of people that commit suicide and
overall population because
you've got to look at it.
There's like 500,000 people working at
this factory. Yeah. Or some crazy number.
I just made that up. We should
find out what the actual number is,
but it's some nutty number like that.
You're talking about thousands of people,
olfactory complex.
It has a half million people there.
I don't think it's a half a million.
I made that up,
but it might be 50,000 whatever it is.
There's so many people that work there
that there the amount of people that are,
that commit suicide on the job or
correctly portion to a normal city. Right.
Which is okay, I get it, but how many
people killed themselves at work?
I was going to go down.
Okay.
It'd be at my job.
I'm taking a couple people with me.
I really think suicide is
the only reason I would kill,
kill myself is that I want it to
kill some other people and I don't,
I don't want to do the time.
God Damn. That's what a lot of people
do it when they know the Jig is up. Yup.
Let's put that gun in their head.
I just that feeling roof.
Imagine that moment before you committed
suicide. What was what's called high?
Your heart rate would be pacing,
dealing with your own mortality.
The biggest question,
and we both know people who've
done it right. You know,
I know two people that I know.
One guy that did it pretty well,
I knew him pretty well. He was a really
nice time. It was really disturbing.
It really hurt. Like you know you,
you hear the seven was in such pain,
they put a gun to their head. You're
like, yeah, I really liked that guy.
Like that's fucked.
Like I dunno what tipped left or right.
It is a chemical makeup or his life's,
you know, situation and circumstances,
whatever it was. But God
damn, that's a, that's a sad,
sad thing that the game gets
so far gone that Gillette,
there's just got to pull the plug. I just
going to flip the board over. This is,
this is never going to work out
because the instinct to not kill yourself
is so strong at the pain that would
make you do.
It must just be something you can imagine.
You know, I've talked to quite a few
people now with what you would call it,
depression or have had depression and
overcome it or have had any sort of mental
issues and had to take medication
for it and overcome it.
And I just think we vary so much ma'am.
I think human bring our minds and what we
could go our norm, what makes us happy,
like whatever,
whatever your state is that what you
need to achieve to get out of like the
muck, like the, the, the down feeling,
what another person needs to achieve.
It could be very different, right? Yeah.
You know, it's just like everything else.
Like people that are tall,
people that are short, freckles,
whatever the fuck it is.
We vary so much that we gotta be really
careful when we like look at like, yeah.
Wow. How could he do that?
He had such a good life.
Like you might've been good
life for you on the outside,
but that guy was in like some
sort of chemical hell all of that,
huh? Yeah. With the x theory or maybe
doesn't have much to do with the interior.
I mean if you talk about the statistics
of people committing suicide,
I wonder if it's not about the same and
the lower class as it is in the upper
class.
I wonder, you know what
I mean? I don't, I don't,
I don't know if that's really the factor
because I think there's quite a few
people,
like they said,
Mexico is one of the happiest countries
on earth and it was also like not a very
wealthy country and staff community.
Yeah, there's, I think there's,
there's a benefit to that that we don't
recognize because we're so wrapped up in
the idea of community money
accumulating dollars that we forget.
Like that's only part of wealth.
Like the really intelligent wealth is
keeping the vibe good as long as possible.
Whether it's happiness with friends,
happiness with coworkers,
happiness with what you do for a living,
pride in, in your accomplishments,
whatever the fuck it is that it takes
to keep feeling included in a group of
people. That's huge.
That's huge for everybody.
People have always wanted to deny that.
Everybody wants to be the rugged
individualist, but that's too,
well, that's our, that's
our whole mythology
in this country. It's the, you know, the
guy riding off alone into the sunset.
That's America. That's the
cool guy in every movies to
go. Doesn't need the chick.
Right?
You never seen with a buddy.
He's got one black buddy and that guy
dies in the first act. Somehow or another,
he just gets on a horse and it's like,
I gotta go.
It just gets on that fucking horse.
Did you see that commercial?
And I would rarely quote a commercial.
I think when it's funny,
but it's like this chick and she's saying
goodbye to a guy and a, it's a hell.
It's an insurance commercial and she's
in like a big prairie dress with a bonnet
and he's the real cowboy and he's
putting his hat on and he's like, uh,
I got to go off into the sunset
and she's pulling it like, no, no.
And then he rides off towards the
sunset and then he just falls off.
It's just so fucking
immediate. So funny. Um,
yeah, but that's it, man. Being being
loners, um, is, it's an important thing.
I think as a, as Comedians,
obviously that's a solo craft.
Podcasting is, you know,
a solo craft,
but at the same time to feel part of a
group and I think like you and I have
both gone to the comedy store,
uh, it's become part of our lives.
Mine for the first time,
yours for the second act.
And it's like a great feeling
to be doing your solo thing,
but you're surrounded by other people
that have the same background and are
following the same path and you know,
you really feel very included there.
Yeah, it's a really good vibe.
It's a, it's a way better vibe.
And it was the first time I was there.
Yeah,
like I really believe is the Internet.
I think the Internet has inspired more
people to try stand up that were on like
maybe the right frequency
to be to become a comic.
They recognize in their own personality
all the shit that we talk about that's
wrong with us. They're like,
oh, maybe I'm just a comic.
Like maybe like I might be able to
do that. I make people laugh at work.
I might literally be able to do that.
I think more people were inspired by that.
And then also when you hear a bunch
of comics doing these podcasts,
talking about comedy like as an art form
and what's involved in it and you kind
of get a sense like this guy described
it to me and he became an open miker and
now he's actually have a working comic.
You started out doing it from hearing
us talk about it on the podcast,
but doing comedy like I think he
said like two and a half years now,
but he said it's like taking
a master's class in comedy.
He listened to the bill burr and talk
about how he writes jokes it listening to
Greg Fitzsimmons talk about
the differences treatment,
his act now and his act
then where the errors are.
He'd get Joey Diaz talking about like
how we learned to let go and how he had
fear when he was on and always worried
about people accepting them and one day
he was like, fuck you. And I
remember that turnaround for Joey.
This is radical turnaround.
When he was always really funny offstage,
we had a hard time being funny
on stage and then it was like,
like 99 somewhere around that 98 99 boom.
He figured it out. Yeah, just
like out of nowhere. Right.
He went quicker than I've
ever seen anybody go from
having a hard time on stage
to destroy.
Yeah.
Like I remember he gained a lot of
weight coincidentally at that same time.
That was how
didn't give a fuck he got,
yeah.
That's when he went from like 210
pounds to like Mike over 300 pounds,
like in a year. But God
damn was he funny. Yeah, he,
I've seen it happen with guys and
uh, you know, like Jim Norton, man,
he haunted the, the comedy cellar
and those clubs for a decade,
you know, 12 years something before he
got any real traction. And then when he,
when he found his voice, I mean
the guy's, he's just fucking great.
He's phenomenal.
He's a really good comic man.
I saw him in Austin and it was a good
thing for me to see because I was doing
sets that maybe we like too long.
Yeah. And he did like 55, 50,
55 minutes and just murdered.
And I'm like,
that's a good amount of time because you
don't get tired of a guy, you know, like,
I know when people are tired of
hearing me talking, you're going,
but you always feel like there's this
borderline between wanting to give them
their money's worth and just like,
even a great movie sucks after
three and a half hours, you know,
or whatever it is for comedy, an hour
and 10 minutes or whatever the number is.
Yeah. But seeing him, uh,
in Austin was great because
I hadn't gone to like a show,
like sit down and watch a show in a
while. It always been like, I'm at a set,
oh who's on, you know, oh Bubba buzz
on, Oh let's go peek in real quick.
But to sit down and watch the whole
show, his whole set was really fun. Yeah,
it's really fun.
It is weird to sit down.
Like I just was in Vegas with some friends
and Steven Wright was playing, sadly.
I said, fuck man, we was it. It was
great. He was great. Dan, you know,
he was doing a lot of new shit and just,
you know,
everyone was high of course,
and it was just this perfect match.
And then he hung out with us after the
shelf for a while. I told him, my friend,
my friend got so baked,
he fell asleep during the shell
and Steven came out and he goes,
how'd you guys like the show?
And I called my friend Dan fell asleep
and stay right. Could not stop laughing.
And he's like, cause he's, he's been
on my podcast and he's just like,
I in all the years I've done this,
I've never had anybody like throw
somebody under the bus like that.
And he just kept talking
about it for like 15 minutes.
I had some funny thing look about
what people don't want to admit.
They were asleep. All right. All right.
You know I fell asleep during your show.
If you fall asleep,
you been up for 72 hours.
It's the first time he sat still
in 72 hours and Steven right.
If you're going to like that, that's
a, that's not like a Kevin Hart,
like lack of explosion. Yeah.
Steven Wright is the guy. Yeah.
You know like I used to work in a fire,
hard drink factory.
Couldn't park anywhere near the place.
He was like the first Twitter,
you know,
his comedy was Twitter call like easily.
He would have been a monster on Twitter
if he put just those jokes on Twitter.
Yeah. But then they would, you
know, you would ruin the bits. Yeah.
Maybe he should go back and
just take all the Shitty,
never put out and just start
tweeting it because you know,
that guy doesn't tweet. You
probably doesn't give a shit.
Well, didn't he write it?
He was tweeting a whole
book. Oh really? Yeah.
He was doing this weird thing
where he was tweeting a whole book,
140 characters at a time. That's
really cool. I love that. Yeah.
I, yeah, I think you would write like a
new hundred and 40 characters every day.
Oh, he, oh. He wasn't just like he
wrote it and he was releasing it.
He was actually, I don't think
so. I think he was doing it like,
how was he doing it?
How many tweets a day was he doing?
It probably had a limited number of
tweets who's doing every day. Yeah.
Explains it on Conan. He explains it
on Conan. We can't play that though.
Would get in trouble. Yeah.
But whatever it is, uh,
he tweeted a book. He said, fucking
Weirdo. That's amazing. He's the guy,
man that changed Boston comedy.
That was the one guy that
changed the whole scene. It,
at least if you listen to a,
like the guys that grew up during that
time and that France Alameda documentary
when standup stood out.
So great documentary.
It's really cool cause it was like the
generation right before we started,
you had to really let us know
that like how lucky we are.
We got like you and I've
talked about this before,
but we came along at the perfect time
like ever in the history of comics.
That made me now, now it's
pretty God damn good time. Yeah.
There's not a lot less money that me and
you are making money right out of the
gate. Hey, we got a car.
He got his 50 bucks kit.
There was so many satellite rooms.
Yeah we could,
we were living in Boston and
we could go in any direction.
There was probably two or 300 rooms.
Yeah,
right between Boston comedy
between Sherry Hirsch, between um,
pill. He downs. Paul Barkley. They all
had like Boston comedy. Barry Katz,
his organization had married 50 rooms
problems. They had so many rooms.
So there's, I mean, may maybe
exaggerating saying hundreds,
but it was more than a hundred
rooms all around this area.
And so we could just go to a
different place all the time.
They always needed comics.
And if you were,
if you were a good comic and
you were reliable, and again,
if you had a car and you
would pick up the headliner,
you would literally call a guy like Mike
Clark and he would fill seven weekends
on the spot in one phone call and then
you'd call a Barry Katz and he'd fell
seven weekends. And like, you
know, in, in, you know, a week,
you talked to five agents and your
year is booked six nights a week.
And then all you got
to do is play softball,
go to the movies and
drive to the Gig at night.
That's a lot of guys fall into that.
Mike Clark had some of the
craziest fucking gigs. Dude,
I did a restaurant for him once.
I was the one opening week and it
never happened again after me. It was,
it was one of the clubs. It
opened and closed it, uh,
because I told them how it was set up and
he agreed that they couldn't do a show
there.
I was like,
you just literally can't do a show there
because you do standup at a lounge.
First of all, nobody told these
people there's going to be stand up.
So they're sitting there
waiting to get seated.
It was the biggest seafood and like
this part of the Cape. So
there would be, you know,
this giant fucking like room
where people are seeding,
waiting for them to call their
seat and they're now no shit.
So when they're calling their
seat and their name or their, uh,
their name and their, you
know, Johnson party of six,
they're doing it on the
same microphone as you.
So you're on stage, you're on
stage. I'm onstage. And uh,
it became a joke after a while.
I'm like,
this is like truly hilarious cause you'd
be right up and I'm telling her Johnson
party has six, your table's ready. Johnson
party of six. You're table's ready.
Johnson Johnson Party of [inaudible].
And you're like, oh my God. I mean,
I'm not joking man, because they're
not even in the same room as you.
So they have no fucking idea.
No, no, no. It's a big place.
So like you're in this giant lounge
area with these families there.
You're talking about blow jobs
and these families are like,
what the fuck is going on?
And then it's surreal. It's surreal.
And in the middle of your act,
just right in the middle,
out of nowhere,
there's six birds and Johnson
party of six. Your table's ready.
It was the worst. It was
one of the, it wasn't,
it wasn't the worst cause
the people were friends.
Lee, you know the magic. Just go back
to that same place now and you know,
it's the same restaurant with the
same PA system, the whole thing.
Bring cameras and film your one hour
special with, with them. Come project.
Try to work around this.
Work
the Johnsons, they're heading
into the family. Hey, nice
jacket. Well you know what,
if people knew you were filming though,
they would come up with stupid
names and it's just so solar.
You yell out their name.
Take my current party of six.
You're table's ready,
Mike Hunt.
They would probably hate that
kind of comedy out there.
Even no matter how famous you got,
there's like a really conservative
part of the yeah, yeah.
The Cape is very family. It's
very Norman Rockwell tight. Yeah.
Right. And they leave the Cape. And my
friend dated this girl from the Cape,
but she, she became a, a whore and
a crack head. He, she was as sweet,
like preppy girl from the Cape,
came from money,
moved to Venice beach and all of a
sudden she was getting skinny and they'll
send, she had a herpes virus on her lip
and he got it from her and then, and then,
and then he found,
I think he found an ad,
like she had the newspaper with the
classified section where she had put an ad
is back before the Internet for
herself and she was selling herself,
selling herself.
And then she came by and so they broke
up and she came by like a year later with
another dude. She weighed
like 90 pounds. Wow.
Having the Cape on the Cape, man. Well,
there's a lot of sheltered people
up in that neck of the woods.
It's beautiful though. Oh, it's
great. It's so nice. In the summer,
especially in the,
there's something about
it. It's just so gray and the
water is so unforgiving. You know?
It's the something Cooley,
but even being cold walking around the
beach and the winter was always weird for
me.
I enjoy it.
You look at the trees and with no leaves
on them and they just look strong.
Everything is strong because it's just
getting battered by wind and cold and it
also like,
it gives you this sense of cycle that
I think we miss out on a bit of here.
I think the cycle,
the seasons is much more normal than no
seasons and what we're doing is we're
all sort of adapting our,
our like perceptions of nature on this
really unrealistic spot. Yeah. You know,
as power and fucking
never rains stalled out.
I mean it gets kind of hot for a while,
but just go near the water.
You'll be fine now. You need it. You
need the cycle that's in my house.
We celebrate my wife's menstrual
flow change clothes like fall,
we'll go fall and then fall colors.
He had fall colors on her timber
on her September dripping.
Did you see that? Um, I don't
know if this is bullshit or not.
Somebody said to me on Twitter and I
looked at, it was about to get in my car.
I was like,
what?
It was something about women that don't
want to be forced to wear maxi pads or
tampons. I think it's bullshit.
So they're just going natural.
They're just doing natural flow.
Like the literally in your face about
their period blood dripping out of their
underwear. They don't give a fuck.
They just wear it like fluffy socks.
I think they just let it drip down
their leg. I mean, it might be bullshit.
I might be getting trolled right now
because I just looked at it like,
really briefly take a look
at it. They're young, Jamie,
and you tell me with your discerning eye,
I could see that because the tampon
that that's the way you stick inside,
right? The tampon. Yes. Gregory.
I didn't get confused. Um,
the tampon causes toxic shock syndrome.
It can if you leave it in, right?
Is that what happens?
I don't know.
I didn't even know it was help
catalyze the movement. Oh my God.
This is real benefits of
sustainable menstrual options.
What does this sustainable, I'm really
tired of people using that word.
I think the people that use the word
sustainable and the people that use the
word handcrafted should get
together and go fuck themselves.
I'm tired of both of those terms.
All natural. You're sustainable.
What are you taught?
What human beings devour the planet?
Stop with your sustainable.
Yeah. Oh, this is better.
It's better for the environment.
One dump truck of waste per person
versus a few desing reusable pads.
Reduce pollution. They're reusable
pads. Hold on a second. BARF.
Could you imagine you're,
you're cooter is blowing into
this fucking wad of cotton every,
every month. You're scrubbing
out the bacteria in the blood.
It's all intertwined and all the fibers
of your coach area of your underwear.
Man,
get the fuck Outta here with this.
Listen we live in 2015 if we,
you still use paper to write down on you,
we can afford a little cot in
the plug your clam with. Okay,
I'll kick in a few bucks for that.
I'm on board. I mean they, yeah,
there's a few things that we'll look
at that picture. Hold on a second.
Pull that picture. Becca, what
did it say? The Stat, oh my God.
I just,
it says disposable Tampon
Pad user produces a dump
truck of menstrual wastes in
their lifetime and it's showing
you this giant fucking dump truck,
which probably doesn't
have only tampons in it but
that would be great is if every time you
throw out a Tampon you had to throw it
in your truck. Every woman gets
one truck and once it's filled
kill you. Yeah. You have like
a year lead dump of your,
your tampons.
Like for a year they have to stay in
your backyard in a big pink barrel.
Just dogs barking from all
over the neighborhood. Yeah.
You know how you have like trash?
It's like one color of the recyclables,
like Brown, like lawn, lawn
trim is good stuff is bro. Yeah,
everybody has different,
it would be like once a year they
pick up your soiled menstrual plugs.
That's a weird thing with guys
being scared of menstrual blood.
I've never really understood that.
It doesn't bother me at all. I mean,
not a little, not even a little bit.
I don't get it. It doesn't bind.
I mean some do. It's freak though. I had
a friend and he would fucking be like,
I'm never buying a chick on her
period. Get outta here. I'm like,
so your girlfriend really wants
to have sex. She's on her period.
You wanna have sex story. He's like, fuck
that and I want you to own that shit.
I think it seems
better. Woo. Greg is dirty.
Like we were. Well dirty boy.
We were down to Florida one time,
me and a, you know, Mike Gibbons,
my buddy Mike and this other guy, the
guy whose girlfriend became a hooker's,
matter of fact, and it was a, uh, there
was a water slide park and it was,
it was locked.
And we got through the chain link fence
and we went in and my buddy turned the
water on.
It was like a real rudimentary roadside
waterpark and we started going down the
slide in the middle of the night. It's
like fucking, you know, midnight and a,
I remember thinking like, I would not
have had that much fun during the day.
And I think that's what
menstrual sex is like,
you're not supposed to be in there.
So it's like a, it's a special treat.
That's a special treat, but a lot of
girls are horny or when they're on,
they're pretty, oh yeah. Oh yeah,
that's right. Would you push back?
Let me ask you this in all
sincerity, because I've
debated this myself, would you,
um,
if they one day figure out a way
to manipulate human bodies in,
in such an incredible way that they
can actually turn you into a woman,
like turn you back into a woman back
into Greg again. Like would you try to,
would you be a woman for a Doris?
Yes.
For a whole day or how long had
you held on just do it for a week.
Would you take the d?
No. No. I would do the woman that I would
definitely masturbate. Relentless Lake.
You'd stick something and
I would go to some spas.
I'd go to a lot of spas are women
are walking around, okay, what about
this? How about this? What if
here's, we went, we're going deep.
What if you,
they figured
out a way to manipulate genetics to the
point where you could become your wife
and your wife could become you, like
literally become you and then fuck you.
Would you agree to that?
Okay.
And No.
No Way.
You wouldn't let your wife be you and
you'll be your wife just for a day now.
No. Why not? Cause I could never look
at it the same way again. But it's her.
I don't want to be inside there.
But there's so many seat, little,
little secrets that women have and
there's things you wonder about their soul
and what they're really thinking when
you're talking and all those little subtle
things. I don't, I don't
want that. Uh hmm. I see your
point. I want to know that.
That's beautiful. You're a man of
like, you love romance mystery. Yeah.
That's beautiful. I love my wife.
I'm not even talking about your wife.
I think in everything in life.
Yeah.
50 shades of gray.
There was in the book,
there was a Tampon sex scene and they
took it out in the movie. How dare they,
the movie made a trillion dollars
movie cure the deficits. Right. I know.
It's fucking crazy.
Why do you think it,
did you think you think guys went, like,
did, did women dragged our men to it?
Or is that just women going? Mostly
women, I think probably. Right. And, uh,
psychologically if I had to
analyze with all due respect,
and this is again just my opinion,
I think the reason why those like savage
type sexual scenarios like savage,
lustful,
crazy things,
they'll ball gags and spitting
in your mouth and you know,
look a lot of the crazy shit that
seems to excite people unexpectedly.
You know when you talk about like the
average American woman and then you talk
about them. I don't know exactly
what 50 shades of grey hairs,
I'm just talking out of my ass,
but I ran was a lot of like
time you read the whole thing.
Well I was hired to do a parody of it.
Oh,
so I read it will tell me because I
would assume that it's like a lot of like
choking and abuse really light.
It's light.
Like the funny thing is is there's no,
I described it as if you had a seven
year old and you showed them nothing but
porn and then you said write a story.
It's so inane. There's no
fucking story. It's just a,
it's an excuse for a rich guy to
completely humiliate a college girl.
And when get off on it because he's so
beautiful and wealthy and, but there's no,
nothing happened. I mean, I don't want
to ruin the ending. I don't fuck it up.
Spoiler alert. Literally nothing
happens in the, everybody knows already.
I don't think they care.
It's just,
it's just the same kind of shit you'd
see at Cinemax. I think there is a,
a lot of women,
I think there are a lot of women
that don't feel sexually attractive.
They don't like,
they don't feel like anyone ever feels
like that with them like anyone has ever
overcome with lug desire to be with them.
They look at themselves as like,
God, I wish that was happening to me.
And they developed this like
intense need for romance.
It's like the classic story
of Romance Novel Readers.
Like what do they look like?
It's usually like an overweight woman.
Like that's what a lot of people think
about when they think of someone who
reads romance novels. What comes
to mind? Not necessarily true,
but the idea being that like for a lot
of people like that is so attractive.
This, this, you know, this crazy,
maniacal, passionate, little,
even disgusting, an abusive
situation between a guy and a girl.
Cause there's so much lust there is like
lust and depravity and they're missing
that. They're not getting, you know,
they're not getting anybody that
wants to be with them and touch them.
That's like a fundamental need that
people have that we kind of ignore a lot
when we're looking at like social trends
and the way people behave, like the fun,
there's a fundamental need that
we have to touch each other.
Like it's 100% necessary.
Like if you,
if you take people and you give
them no contact with other people,
they literally go bananas.
We need to be around each other.
I was hugged sad people.
Oh.
Like if I meet somebody and
they just seem really sad,
I not right then and there, but the next
time I see them I'll throw a hug on him.
And it's amazing to see the change.
They fucking like you so much.
Yeah, man, I've told the story,
but just in the nature of, uh, this, uh,
discussion, I got it. The first
job that I ever did in Hollywood.
That's stupid hardball show.
I had the situation where I came out
here to not have any friends and uh,
I was out here filming it
for like two weeks and uh,
didn't have a girlfriend in La.
I didn't know anybody.
So I just go to the comedy store and go
home and we have this scene that we were
doing with me and this girl and she gave
me a hug and she didn't even give me a
hug, like a sexual hug. It
wasn't like I was a track,
I mean she was a very attractive, but
it wasn't like that. She was like, aw,
she came over, give me a hug.
And my whole body just tangled,
like not sexually because
he'd been in love.
Like I felt love and like I felt like
a warm hug from a, like God damn.
And I realized right there immediately
I was like, I need this in my life.
If this is something like if you
don't have your, you feel dull,
you life feels dulled down.
Yeah. And unfortunately,
whether it's because of genetics,
because a diet or because of fucking
fill in the blank where some people just
aren't that attractive to other people
and then that's not a politically correct
thing to say,
but that's exactly what it is.
And so they're super excited about
someone being excited about them.
There's an app where you can
hug people where people meet,
they meet out in a public place
and they have here look it up.
They meet in a public place and
they just come. They say hello,
they hug and then they walk away. Oh my
God. And it's worldwide. That's insane.
That is so insane. And I heard the guy
getting interviewed and they were like,
well, it does it sometimes. Like then lead
to Saks like you would naturally think.
He's like now most people just,
they just wanted a hug.
That's why they went on the APP.
That's all they wanted. Wow.
Yeah. That's going to end badly.
Well, my son, yeah. Oh yeah.
Yeah, that'll cuddle. Curious.
Free App makes it easy to score.
Hugs, cuddler. Aw, that's
cute. And that hilarious.
Hugging People's Nice.
It's just the problem is there's a lot
of like overly needy people out there.
A lot of crazy people out there.
A lot of them mean people out there,
a lot of insult people that will insult
you just to get a rise out of you.
And that's just the world. And girls
have to deal that way more than we do.
Like it's the worst thing in the world
when you see a guy hit on a girl and then
the girl refutes him and you know, fuck
you bitch, you know I didn't like you.
And you're like, that is
disgusting. That's like,
you realize like guys like that are the
reason why chicks her fucking weirded
out by dudes. Yeah. You know, someone
who hits on you and then when you say no,
they get angry at you,
they all of a sudden like from,
I want to fuck you too. I
want to hit you. You know?
And that's something fortunately
we don't have to deal with.
Yeah. It's uh, I mean, he can see it.
It's an insecurity. Obviously the guy,
the guy got hurt and so
he lashed out with anger.
It could be that for sure.
I mean it certainly, I think
there's a lot of factors.
I think that's, that's a big
part of it though. Definitely.
I think the other part of it is that like,
I think for a lot of men it's like very
frustrating to try to figure out how to
get someone to choose you
over, you know, x guys,
x number of competition. Yeah.
I mean you're losing, yeah.
I mean that's the reason why men
dressed the way they dress. I mean,
a big part of it for them is like
to try to look good. You know,
like guys who were the right watch are
guys who have the right shoes or guys who
were like a really slick
jacket. Like you're doing it
to look good. You're doing,
I mean, that's why you're doing it.
You're doing it to be more attractive.
You know,
whether you're doing it for yourself or
you're doing it for your business images
ultimately for yourself,
you're trying to be more attractive
and no matter how attractive you are,
because you're trying to, you know,
it's nature. You're trying to attract
the best mate that you can get.
It's crazy.
The guys will,
some guys will go like all out liquid
diamonds and shit and to like giant
watches would crossed it and
diamonds and they know like, look,
I am only going to attract
dumb hose. Yeah, that's it.
That's what I'm shooting
for. Right. You know,
and they'll like walk around with like
giant golden crusted or diamond encrusted
necklaces and shit off.
Yeah. They could pull it off
way better than we can. Um,
you know her at certain cars,
you see a guy pull up in a certain car
and for some guys that makes sense.
You're like,
yeah,
that guy belongs in a Porsche and they
see another guy and you're like, you're,
am I going to say you're not
supposed to be in a Porsche?
Anybody who really likes a should
be in a Porsche, but Porsche, no,
but want to be, no, you
shouldn't be in a Porsche. Right.
You should be in a Porsche.
That's a Porsche, is it? Yeah.
That's what you're supposed
to say. Porsche. Yeah.
There's still a lot of people that are
like car journalists like Chris Harris
who calls it Polsh is a Porsche though.
Is it Jaguar?
Jaguar? It depends on what country
and this is American mother.
Fuck American Jaguar. Good
American. Now you minium Jag.
You are Jag. Yeah. That sounds
like you're cursing somebody out.
Jag.
You all y'all.
You Jaguar Fit Simmons? Yeah, I gotta.
I gotta get that fucking Mustang.
I saw one yesterday. New Ones.
And they wait for the new ones. Yeah,
they're coming out 50th year anniversary.
This is what you want. You want the GT
three 50 don't fuck around. Do not pass.
Go the Shelby gt.
Three 50 coming.
It'll be coming out very soon. Gregory.
How much? I don't know how much.
Stop with the money. You're going to
live forever. Stop. You make good money.
This is what you need to do.
You need to get 500 American naturally
aspirated horsepower under your balls.
Yeah, dude, it's doing
Newburg ring times like low,
low numbers, man. They look like
spectacular results with this car.
It's like got independent suspension
for the first time in a long time.
For mustangs.
Like they had it for awhile and then
they went back to the live rear axle.
I guess I don't know enough about that,
but this new suspension is
supposed to be incredible.
This car cars coming out soon, son,
don't fuck around or get one of those.
Challenger hellcats.
I drove one of those in Denver.
Has the visibility out the back of that
good enough? No, it doesn't matter.
Nothing's coming up behind you.
Look, get that fucking car.
Oh 16 Shelby gt three 15 I like the back.
Good Lord.
That mixed my fast back to
fucking American car son.
That's, that's real American muscle,
but like super sophisticated.
Now they're making these cars like
this car where they're American muscle
meaning like stupid high horsepower.
V Eight awesome sound rumble.
But they handle that
car fucking handles man.
That's how much money do they spend
making that roar sound right? You know,
they got all kinds of acoustics experts
and on that Muffler we'll, you know,
accident. They probably do. I think so.
Especially the Shelby has that awesome
deep throaty like bubbling up in the
morning. Yeah, they sound so good.
V Eight sounds always the best.
Like you can have a beautiful VC
like Porsche's are sixes flat six.
They sound really good too.
But that sounds the best.
That American v eight rumble.
It's just so fucking ball draining.
That's uh,
something about that engine sound for
whatever reason actually stimulates
testosterone in men. There's been studies
dial. I'm sure that's insane. Absolutely.
The sound of an engine, it's like a
lion roaring. You probably hear that and
you gotta grow some. You've got
to grow some balls fast. Yeah man.
If you had lions all around your bedroom,
I bet you'd have so much testosterone.
Imagine if you slept in like you
had this like super thick wire cage,
like really fucking fic where lines
definitely can't get through it. No Way.
And that's your walls and your,
the rest of your house,
like all on the outside, there's
an outside wall way, way out there.
But most of it is a lion sanctuary.
Yeah.
So where you live is like
the outside is like a house,
but the inside,
like where it faces the line sanctuary
is all wire mesh and it's all around your
bed.
So it's like your walls are insulated
with lions and you walk out there and then
you sleep.
You walk out there like a long path
through this thick wire mesh and you sleep
in the middle of the line sanctuary.
And periodically throughout the day they
release animals for the lines to chase
and kill in front of you.
You're brushing your teeth and you see
some poor giraffe stumble out, look left,
look right,
and you see them run towards it and
take it down like fucking Christ.
You hear ball and snap and one of them's
got the neck and the things flop around.
I was trying to kick in a town,
its guts apart and you're 20 feet
away and your chest is rumbling noise.
Allow raw. You can barely hear it
over your electric toothbrush. Yeah.
Oh,
ripping apart some giraffe right in
front of you. Fun splatters on your face,
fighting each other over
chunks of meat swab.
The new male comes into town,
there's a fucking bra and,
and you're just getting manly.
You're either shrinking from
it and becoming a complete
pussy or you're growing
hair on your chest and you're going, you
would look like in Armenian bodybuilder.
That's what you look like. Just
hey, Harry thing. He'd get angry.
You're not even working out. You've
never lifted a weight and your ribs.
Your body's just prepared for
death every second of every day.
You just hear that roar in the middle of
the night. Plus you're inhaling on that.
Fair owns that.
They spray it up the whole time.
They probably piss on your fucking cage.
They'll probably spray your cage.
You probably going to have to call
in the maid and shows the Lion Piss.
All of those things up. The Fairmont's.
I just want to take a nap. I'm,
you know what? I'm not getting pissed
on tonight. I'm putting up the shades.
I'm just, you know what?
I'm not avoiding the lions.
I just don't want to pee in them.
I can handle the lions.
I just don't want to Piss it on my
head while I'm sleeping. It's it. Yeah,
they will. They will piss on things.
Right, like a regular cat does. Well,
especially after they fight and they
spray the area cause they just one,
it's fucking weird to watch man was like
what does that even coming from? Yeah,
you got an extra hole back there.
Like what is that? How's that work?
Cause they spray out the
back like out of their ass.
He has some kind of little gland
back there. How bizarre. Yeah.
Like they have almost like an extra dick,
like a d,
an extra like a blow hole and their deck.
Well it's, I guess it's like pre semen,
right? I don't know where it comes
from. I'd never thought about,
I had a cat that used to spray to really?
Oh Man.
I had a feral cat and at
one point in time, um,
I had a great veterinarian.
Luckily Dr. Craig,
unfortunately he died,
drunk driver hit her man fucking,
he was the nicest guy. He was hilarious.
Like a really funny guy. Loved, loved,
loved animals. Anyway, I had this
feral cat and when it was time,
like most of the time I could pet him,
but there was occasionally
times we tried to pick him up.
He'll fight you to the death,
just fucking freak out and run away.
And I had to get him to the vet
because it was time to get them fixed.
He's just pissing in my fucking house.
Seems like we'd pick up his back.
They like,
is it the pickup is back like his ass and
his tail and he would just see it come
out. You're like you little motherfucker.
And when I trapped him in the bathroom,
he was just spraying
everywhere. Dude, just spraying.
But I never looked at where it came
from because that was in mortal danger.
Like I was trying to figure out how
to get this little guy in a basket.
What I did was I threw a blanket over him.
I wrapped him up in the blanket and
then I stuffed the blanket inside of a
laundry basket and then I carried him out.
I carried him to the vet in a
fucking laundry basket place.
He's like going crazy like that. He was
going bananas. He was going bananas.
He's trying to kill me. He was trying
to kill me, but he was my buddy.
It was the weirdest thing and no
one else could even touch this cat.
If you came out with my head, he
might house, he would run from you,
but he would sit in my lap.
I could pet them up,
I can pick them up and once I started
petting him, he would perse so loud.
But it was like the person like never
got touched. Like once, like he,
it was the weirdest thing. He would go
from work. I'm scared of everything.
You pick them up dude. It's
all right. It's all right.
Like a and really loud
per like the poor guy,
his whatever months of his life where
he was wild before I got ahold of them.
She has fucked his head up.
Like trying to maintain in your home.
A feral cat is a very unique situation.
Taught me a lot.
Did it, did the behavior change
after he got neutered? He never did.
Behavior never changed. No. I mean it,
he was always cool only with
me. That's it. No other people.
That's it.
He liked my cats.
My cats and him were very close
and he would hang out with them.
Everybody was groovy,
but there was no other person
who was allowed to pick them up.
He just wouldn't have it and he wouldn't
have it sometimes for me, like he do.
He knew me from the time he was a little
baby and I had them for at least seven
or eight years. How did you find
him? My friend found him. Yeah.
Her and her boyfriend were living in this
apartment and underneath it there was
like a cat that had given
birth to a bunch of kittens.
And so like she kind of freaked out like,
oh my God, these poor little things.
They're wild and they're
hissing and people.
So they set traps for them because
they were like, you know, they were,
well they would go out to their car and
there's like this litter of Kittens,
like living under your house. Like
it was really depressing time. Yeah.
So her and her boyfriend decided to
trap him. Trap the cats and you know,
they were a little demons man,
just fucking spotter in. And then
you realize like, man, once you,
if you're that fucked up from like that,
like first couple months,
like your view of the world
is that dangerous. I mean,
you literally a wild industry,
no one's petting you. You know,
you're not getting little can of tuna
in front of you. Oh, do you like it? No,
it's full on instinct. You're eating
bugs, reading anything that moves yes.
Fighting other cats to get to the,
yeah. And you know, your parents
are trying to bring you back food.
You're barely staying alive.
And so he goes from that to
all of a sudden he's hanging
out with me in my house
and he's eating cat food. You know,
it was get cat food every day.
You can't believe the food's
still here every day. You know,
it was really weird to see will he overeat
if you leave out food? He's dead now.
But, uh, he uh, didn't
overeat. No, he, he, no,
he normalized to the point where
like walking around the house,
he didn't look like it was constantly in
terror, but if you got too close to him,
he would be like, what the fuck are
you planning? You know, it's like,
it was when he was by himself,
he was fine. Like he was cool.
It was just chill out and who you catch
them like signing himself by the window.
Everything was groovy. It's on people's
got too close to him. You just wasn't, oh,
would never was. Totally. Sure.
Yeah. No, it was totally sure.
Here, reminded me of when you talked
about grabbing them in the laundry basket.
Do you remember back in Boston?
You were out one night with Jennifer
and I was home and I swear to God on my
father's grave, this happened.
I rented Batman Blockbuster.
Uh, and I put it in and I'm sitting at
home and I'm watching it. And then, uh,
all of a sudden I see this shadow and
then I turned my head and I see another
shadow and I look up and there's
a bat flying around the apartment.
And I'm like, what? And I'm
scared shitless of bats.
Like it's like my thing.
And it's like ever since I was a kid,
my aunt had this bar near her and they
had bats and they would be telling me
they were fruit bats. And
if they bite you, you'll get
rabies and you'll die. And,
and so, and we would always be outside
playing tag at night and I would fucking,
bats would fly by and I'd freak out.
And,
and so I'm alone in the apartment and
there's a bat flying around and Batman is
on TV. And so, uh, all I
knew is they go in your hair,
which I think is like not even true.
So I put on a baseball cap backwards and
I had on sunglasses and a tennis racket
suck. Glad in one going in my eyes,
he's going to go from that.
So,
and I'm running around the
apartment swinging at him.
He's taken off, he's like,
you know, he's just, they're
erratic, the way they fly.
You don't know where they're
fucking going. And this
goes on for like 10 minutes.
And then there's like a standoff on a
waiting and then I hear you coming up the
stairs and you came in and you
opened the door and you go,
what the fuck are you doing? And I
got this a bad in here. And you just,
you just grabbed the tennis
racket out of my hand.
And he walked up and he was in the window
and you just bashed him once and he
just went down and then you just walked
over and you had take out in your hand
and you just went into the
kitchen and started eating it.
I'm standing there with sunglasses
and I, Ana, I remember that.
That's hilarious.
I probably wouldn't even killed it if
you weren't already trying to kill it.
I think you, you might, I call
the animal people to come get it
because it looked like it was stunned.
Ooh. He was actually dead sick.
Oh, you mean once I hit it?
Yeah, no, it was done right.
Yeah, I remember I killed it.
Yeah, I remember. I'm like, I'm not
going to have this thing software. Yeah.
I don't remember what I did, but I
remember it was some hitting involved.
I'm pretty sure it was the tennis
racket could have been. Yeah.
I mean you were fearless. I was
like, fuck man. I don't like,
I don't like baths,
but I do know that on very rare,
very rare occasions, bats I've
rabies. Yeah, it's very, very rare.
So like same thing with like squirrels.
Very rare they have rabies,
but I'm not taking any fucking chances.
I'm not getting rabies. Dude, get rabies.
You have some crazy shot they put
through your stomach and he can call in
retrospect. Probably could have tried
to save the thing. Throw, throw.
But it might've been sick too.
Yeah, I didn't want to loan
him. There was a lot of bats.
Neighborhood in Brookline. The
other were raccoons too. Right?
Remember lot of raccoons.
Yeah. Here in la, you get rats.
They're everywhere. The Hollywood hills,
apparently it's especially bad. Yeah,
they're filled with a Mo. There
probably isn't as many birds. You know,
you don't see hawks
flying around that much.
You should see a lot more hawks that,
and they're, they're not around,
so they're not killing
the, uh, the Vermont. Well,
it's also unfortunately coyotes too. And
people hate coyotes. And I, you know,
I'm not a fan because they will
kill your dog right in front of you.
And they would bite children if they
could get away with it. Oh yeah.
There's been many instance. I mean they
don't have like rules, they're just,
they're opportunists.
And if you have a three year old
and it's wandering around naked,
a coyote lead it,
it's just mean it's a fucked up thing to
say because most people don't leave the
three year olds alone. But
you know, coyotes are creepy,
but they do keep rat populations
down and they'd learn.
There is a balance that has to be,
unless we're going to
kill all the rats to like,
we were just going to be the
executioners and fucking natural world.
Like when it doesn't work like that.
So when you force coyotes out of
neighborhoods, which I agree with, it's a,
it's a two edge sword. Yeah. Cause I don't
want coyotes killing my friend's dog.
Yeah. That's a sad thing.
There's a, one of the guys that,
I think it was one of the guys
that worked on fear factor,
I forget who it was in his neighborhood.
This lady was walking her dog in Brentwood
in this fucking coyote came running
up behind her. She said she
just heard click, click, click,
click, click, click, click,
click, click, click.
And she didn't even know what it was and
it just snatched her fuck a dog right
off the leash and ran with it. Yeah.
Just crammed it right in front of her.
She screamed, she let go of the leash.
Coyote ran off with their dog. Wow.
Killed it right in front of her.
Brazen. That's brutal. Yeah.
So I would rather have rat traps out then
those little fucking conti dog's eaten
monsters. Yeah, they'll eat dogs,
man. I mean that's, that is shit.
You're on the Diet because I guess our
coyotes related to wolves. Are they?
They're, they're dogs.
They're all dogs. Right?
So everything comes from wolves
because you gotta think if you can,
if you come from a wealth and
you're now coyote, you're,
you're pretty bad ass. And then you
see an Americanized, like a small dog.
They are not very tough.
Yeah.
You probably don't even see
it as the same species as you.
That's just an easy soft lunch.
Well,
it's fucked as the coyotes are actually
so clever that they will get dogs to
think that they're their friends.
Like they come around and hang out with
them the right outside the fence. Yeah.
Like my neighbor has this little dog,
he has a Beagle and he says the coyote
comes out and the dog starts wagging its
tail. Like, look, my friend is
here. But meanwhile they're Kyle.
He'll eat that beagle to beagle
thinks everybody's like him. You know,
at four o'clock in the afternoon the food
gets put into a bowl and his tail wags
and he waddles his little fucking Chubby
Body over to the bowl and he eats.
And meanwhile outside,
it's just things ribs are showing
and it's gets big long face.
Just design for snatch and
shit up and it's like, ah man,
come on outside and play. Hey, I'm
your friend, Mr Bagel. I like you.
Come on man. Did my dad look at my
tail? Look, the door's open, man. What?
The door's open. Should I come? Oh yeah,
yeah, yeah. Come on. Just who's your nose,
you should know is open to
talk. Come on. Just grab them.
There's fucking run with them.
Poured bigos wasn't playing golf
recently in this, uh, coyote.
We just came out on the
course. Just looked at us.
Didn't, wasn't scared at all.
You know, they're, they're
slippery because, you know,
I'm not saying I hate them.
I think there's something beautiful about
their existence. I don't want to do it,
but there's something
beautiful about this.
This animal that lives like
just adjacent to civilization,
intertwined slightly,
occasionally dips into their
world and steals a cat. You know,
last ones to leave the party. You
see, they've got one of my chickens.
I watched it watch a jump over the
fence with my chicken. Yeah, yeah.
Recently it was,
it jumped over this like I had a fountain
and it jumped onto the fountain and
then right over the fence I
got the fountain right up,
like one of those little portable
fountains with the chicken in his mouth.
And just boom,
just right over ice mail down about 10
times before I had a chicken in one of
the, not in the regular pen,
but in another box. And it
was a, when chickens brood,
you have to a, you have to take them
away from the rest of the chickens.
You gotta take him out of their box,
you're going to force him to sit on a
perch for like usually a day or two and
then they calm down. They get
out of it. But if you don't,
they'll start picking their feathers off.
And what it is is like females
in the natural world of chickens,
they want to fuck a rooster and they
want the egg that they give. You know,
they've make an egg almost every day,
but most of the time those
eggs are unfertilized.
So the exit we eat are unfertilized eggs.
I didn't even fucking know this.
I was in my forties I thought that all
eggs could be chunked chickens if you'd
just laid on them, which
is really retarded. I,
I had no idea that chickens
just lay an egg every day.
Whether or not they're pregnant or not.
I just,
how do they know which ones to sit on?
They don't mean,
you know when you leave the eggs there,
some of them they'll like,
I guess like some of them sometimes
they'll peck away at their eggs, no,
eat them and you have to like
make sure that they don't do that.
They're really stupid man.
They're stupid as fuck.
But when they get broody when they get
broody is when they think that somehow or
another one of these eggs,
even though there's no rooster,
is going to become a baby.
So they sit on it and they don't want
to get off of it and then they start
pecking at their belly and
fluffing it up and it gets ugly.
But you can fix it as long as you
catch it early and catch it early,
you just put them on a perch.
So it was a smaller box and the coyote
got under it and smashed the bottom of it
and stole the chicken. It's fucked
up, man. Clever little cunt.
You ever get attacked by a chicken ever?
They never bit, you know, but if they did,
that'd be the end of their life. That
my rules. Right. I'm just kidding.
But deal. You don't, you don't
raise them to eat them? No. No.
They're like little pets. The pets,
their pets that make food. I feel bad.
I was more sensitive to the loss of
your chicken. No, I mean I would,
I would do that. I named chicken.
Yeah. I don't, my kids do.
I don't.
I'm like,
I don't have any desire to eat
these chickens. Like they're cool.
I like having him around. I like,
uh, I like eating their eggs,
but it's so really weird thing that by
other chicken from the grocery store,
like I'll go to the grocery store and
buy chickens. He's completely murdered,
fucked up chicken. You don't get
to ever look at its face. You know,
you don't have to cut its neck and
see its last blood jump out of it.
You don't have to really recognize what
it is you're doing and you're eating a
chicken, right. You're just letting
the supermarket supermarket hit man.
Take care of all the dirty work for you?
Well, it's almost like we've got this
hamster that's in a cage in our house,
which is really to me the saddest thing
in the world because he's alone and
nobody holds him.
My daughter picks him up like once a week
for about 20 minutes tops and the rest
of the time he knows
on the bars to get out.
And I just think like this is the most
pathetic existential existence this thing
lives in and I hate that we have as a pet.
And then we had a mouse that was loose
and we set a trap and I was like,
this mouse,
that hamster are a fucking chromosome
apart and why don't we hold and pat and
give a little a
bath and a little fucking butter dish.
And the other one I'm trying to
snap his neck with a spring. Well,
how about squirrels, man? I mean,
squirrels have this free ride
in the road and community.
Nobody hates squirrels. Yeah,
everybody hates but squirrels.
All they had to do was get
cute. All them do. Listen,
just stay an herbivore.
Don't go eating animal protein and gross
out in pretty girl big fluffy tail that
looks cute with did a little tail show.
I do little tail show and they chew and
a little nuts and everybody thinks their
cute little kids walk up to these wild
rodents and they'll give them nuts.
Could you imagine this? You saw your
little kid walking up to a fucking rat.
How much you'd be terrified,
but they're there.
Like we were so confident in their
behavior that will just walk up to them,
give them peanuts. I to love our ice, love
squirrels. We had him where I grew up.
I used to feed him all the time.
Give him a little peanuts.
There's a park in north Hollywood that
you could go to. And um, the squirrels,
apparently people have
been feeding them forever.
So they come up to you when they see you,
they're like, you, you got something.
You got something for me. And I watched
this one dude, this old Chinese guy, he,
he laid down on a blanket.
You had a bag of peanuts and it would
just slowly like reach his hand out and
squirrels would come over and just take
it from him. They were so confident. Yeah.
It's just Greg.
I mean he's holding a peanut.
They've just taken it from him and they
just step back just a little bit and
they would eat it. They didn't worry
about him or they're just a rodent.
The got cute. That's it. I mean is
this fight going back to the wolf?
Like the dogs that we have today are just
the wolves that were able to be around
man. They were able to chill
the fuck out, grab some scraps.
Man liked him cause he was protection.
Yeah.
Wolf like the mad because he was
giving him food and he, but he,
but it weeded out the vicious ones
until they got smaller and cuter and we
crafted them to be the
little lapdogs we wanted.
The crazy thing is how short
of a time it takes to do that,
to change these animals.
Like we don't know how long it
took before wolves became dogs,
but they did this experiment.
They do well,
it was listening to this podcast on
radio lab, I forget the name of it,
but it was about wolves and
they did this experiment on,
I was about dogs with dogs and they're
wild nature, whatever the fuck it was.
But they did this experiment with foxes
where this guy was raising foxes and
whenever he would go towards like
the cage where the Fox Fox were,
if the foxes were um,
scared of him,
if they like feared him, if there
was any like aggression towards him,
he'd killed those foxes.
So the only foxes that he let stay alive
where the foxes that were actually like
happy to see people.
And then over time they did this
over a period of like 10 years,
they literally changed
the way the foxes looked.
They changed the way their face look.
Their face became smaller,
their bones became more petite, they
became different colors. They're cheap.
They're, their colors changed their,
their overall, even the males,
their bodies became much more feminine
and they became domesticated like in 10
years to the point where you would go
near the Fox cage and they would wag their
tail and like whimper to be near you.
Like they wanted to be near people
and they were in a fucking for factory
essentially. Wow. They're
killing these things.
And this guy recorded all
this stuff and did these,
these studies over the period of like
10 years changed the foxes that he had
changed them.
And George Orwell buck was just something
about the reaction to adrenaline that
some of these animals didn't have the
same reaction to adrenaline that did the
same, uh, response to seeing strangers.
And that those, by favoring those,
you sort of domesticated this
animal like very quickly.
And the idea behind it was they were
trying to make an analogy towards people
like that were kind of
doing that with society.
If you look at the way people used to be,
like there was some study
recently about um, uh,
hunter gatherers and the difference
between their bones and our bones,
their bones were much more
dense and cause he's, you know,
as people were working from the
time they were babies, I mean they,
they just never stopped like picking
things up and climbing hills and like they
were constantly at work.
But we're becoming like more and more
fragile as we sit at desks all day and sit
in our car to get dark desk and sit on
the couch to watch TV after you're done
and then read a book in bed.
I mean fucking were falling apart.
We're like mush and that,
you know,
when you really think about that,
like that's kind of very similar to
what is happening with those foxes.
It's just a matter of
preferring one type of behavior,
not breeding with the other ones.
And they think their premise was about
like the best way to eliminate like war
and eliminate all these different negative
aspects of our culture would be four.
And people said this for people like that,
to just people stop fucking them.
Stop fucking savages. Stop fucking all
the people that want to go to war. Yeah.
I give as as a,
as a rule like all across the world,
if women just stop fucking
all men who want to go to war.
Well if you think about it and stay with
me on this cause it's a little dark.
But if the people that
are natural soldiers,
they are going to war and they are dying
without breeding as much as the guys
that, that are afraid to go to war. Right.
So in a sense there is some natural
selection. If that is a gene,
if there is a gene that makes you
more, you know, uh, likely to,
to want to go to battle,
um, that kind of makes Hans someone's
car alarm. Isn't that hilarious?
Like back in the day, car alarms were like
something that anybody took seriously.
Oh my God. Yeah. There's
a car alarm going on.
I bet this is a crime now.
It's like asshole, you know,
is in the back or the front
front.
Yeah. You go take a look at it if you
want. Just make sure it's not one of ours.
One of our hardest moves. Somebody hit
your car and that's why the alarms going.
Yeah,
that is possible
is in the back. Oh, then
don't worry about it.
Fuck these people with their gun.
Remember those ones that would
do like different door. My,
I remember in a way I
lived in little Italy.
This fucking Cadillac got tapped and
it played the theme from the Godfather.
Nn Nnn, Nnn, nnn.
That's hilarious. I remember
everybody used to have that one alarm.
That one type of alarm.
Yeah.
That you'd be like,
fuck somebody who was always
so many bumping into it.
Whether they were parking and they do used
to go. They used to go for way longer.
Now usually people are near their car.
They,
it's almost always somebody
set it off by accident,
which means it usually
stops pretty quickly. Yeah.
But back then it would go on for 10 15
minutes and you'd be going out of your
fucking mind. You're sitting there
trying to write it on your computer,
whatever death. Yeah. Those things
are fucking distracting shit.
When they came along with noise,
reducing headphones. Dot Is,
that was a beautiful thing
to be able to sit and have.
If you had like noise reducing headphones
on right now and you could totally
filtered that out. Yeah, most of it.
Well the Mike's probably didn't pick up
on that. Do you think they did? Yeah.
If some of these like got headphones
on. Yeah, but they could hear it.
That was pretty fucking loud. But those
Bose ones, I mean I've got a pair,
I've had the same pair but it this way,
I've had them long enough
that I got replacement.
You know the rubber padding
thing in the middle. Yeah.
I was in a Bose store and I was like, Oh
fuck you can buy replacements. Cause I,
I had stopped using it because they just
wore out and I popped in some new ones.
I haven't, I swear to God, 10 years
I've had these things. Wow. They still,
I don't think they make a better version.
It's like one of those products,
you know,
they make a,
they make a year of it like the Honda
Civic and like 1982 it was like a perfect
fucking car. Yeah. There was a bunch
of cars from that era that are like,
to this day, like they're
becoming like really valuable.
Like Volvo DL land cruisers. Yeah.
They're t those old Toyota land cruisers.
Yeah. People are taking those Land Cruiser
is still the old ones that looked like
jeeps and even the newer ones like after
that and they're fixing them up and
selling them for over a hundred
thousand dollars. What? Yeah, no shit.
Yeah.
There's a company called icon and a
day they make incredible cars, man.
I mean it's like you're talking about
very, very expensive shit and I agree.
I mean, it's not necessarily something
that I would buy it because it is a lot of
fucking money and uh,
but they take these like Broncos
and they take it old bronco,
they take the shell and they completely
redo it with the highest end components,
like the best suspension possible.
A completely modern engine,
you know,
with like 400 horsepower,
they take a coyote engine
from the 5.0 Mustang.
So it's a Mustang gt engine like
this crate engines, beautiful engine.
They stick it in an old bronco. Those
really cool old, I love those body.
You got to see it. Pull
it up. The convertible
ones,
icon Bronco,
pull up the silver one cause there's a
fucking silver one that if it doesn't
make all this money for the non five,
well it's not just the body,
it's the engineering. Like this guy. Um,
I forget his name. I think Jonathan Ward,
I think his name is the guy who is the uh,
the lead CEO.
Whatever the fuck he is
president of this company.
Just leave that thing on there for a
second so I can stare at it. Good Lord.
That's beautiful. Look at
that fucking truck kind of
long. That Hood is God. Damn,
that's a fucking work of art man.
It's like something you played with
as a kid and dreamed of driving. Yeah.
Like when you think about a regular truck,
like regular trucks are cool, you know,
hey, you know you got kids, you want to
pile them into an Escalade, that's cool.
But if you see that thing
driving down the street,
I mean that's like some mad
Max Apocalypto wonder ride.
It's a cool west side car too cause it
looks like you could take it on the beach.
You could take that on the beach.
You can take that wherever
the fuck you want to go.
Well that's what I think about is when
the shit hits the fan and it's going to,
in La,
obviously there's going to be some type
of a terrorist strike or there's going
to be a poisoning. Easy, easy, easy.
Greg Fitzsimmons I want to have,
I've a Prius and my wife has a Toyota
Highlander so if I want to get out,
I know the way out because if I,
if I live in Venice,
I'm the last one in line for the 10 for
the four or five for the Pacific coast
highway.
We were the last ones to leave la,
like lock up on our way out.
Everyone's a front of us. So I think,
well you got two options.
One of them is to jump on a boat.
Like you gotta be able to Jerry Rig.
It's something simple.
Little fucking motor boat go off
to Catalina Island. Waited out.
The other option is like,
cause when I was a teenager,
he used to ride motorcycles on the power
lines because wherever there's power
lines,
they have to have a a path
cleared underneath it so
they can serve as the power
lines.
So if you drive dirt bikes,
he always know if there's power lines
is a good trail underneath it. Wow.
So if you want to get out of La, you,
you get on one of those power lines,
but you need a truck like that. You need
something with like a lot of clearance.
Big Fat wheels.
Dude.
Do you want to live? If the apocalypse
hits like okay, lists their stages,
the apocalypse power goes out.
Apocalypse, that's going to suck. Yeah.
Especially if it's in July.
People are going to be hot as fuck.
No one's gonna know what to do.
People are going to be camping out in
the beach cause they can't take living in
the valley and the,
in the middle of the summer there's going
to be some shortages of food for sure.
It's going to be some looting for sure.
You cannot pump gas cause they're all
electric pumps going to be a real problem
until they figured out how to get
the power back on. And you know,
there's been situations in other parts
of the world where power in a modern city
has been off for weeks.
Like Toronto apparently had some crazy
ice storm in the 90s and you know,
it was like fucking zero below 10 below
zero, something like that. Horrible,
horrible weather, you know,
Celsius. Whatever they do up there.
And these people had no power for like
two fucking weeks. And in Toronto,
Maya in the middle of the winter
so that he could happen in La. Man,
if it happened in la in the summer,
it can get ugly. Quick Stat would be
one that's like one kind of apocalyptic.
I can handle that. That's not that bad.
But the real bad ones, like super volcano,
earthquake,
asteroidal impact,
those are the big tsunami tsunami,
tsunami zone.
You probably aren't because the way the
bay is shaped, you know, you've got,
you know,
from the Palisades down to whatever,
Manhattan beach is all
one half circle basically.
And Venice is in the
center of that half circle.
So as the water is
rushing in from a tsunami,
it's all getting channeled into
one opening, which is Venice beach.
That shit's going to come straight down
Venice Boulevard, take everything out.
The canals, canals of the underwater.
That's right. And it's canals,
canals right through the city. Get
out now, get out. Now actually we,
we moved up the hill. We moved from Venice
to Mar Vista, which is about a mile,
but it's straight up hill.
The people that live on the beach like
right on the water or bold is fuck bold
is fuck. You have to have
some either some mad loot,
whether it's like house number five,
you know,
CEO of Q tips or some shit.
And his house is shaped like a cue tip.
And the servants were placed
with real cotton every day. Oh,
that would be it.
Q tips mad because people are not going
to stop using Q tips and there's no like
nobody wants the generic ones because
the generic ones are like they get flat
qtip stay fluffy shit.
Who's the asshole that makes those
qtip fake Q tips with plastics.
Yeah.
Cut the inside of your ear cause you dig
around the fucking cotton falls right
off. She get us now you got
a cocktail straw in your ear.
Now they get the real cute tips is like
one of those again going back to like
the 82 civic or uh,
it's just there.
They made perfect products in St Louis.
Just you nail it. You got it. Walk away.
Walk away. Walk away. He
know certain cameras like a,
I don't know what kind of camera you got
but die of the uh, those old cannons.
The original like first generation Canon
video cameras, they were high eight.
They were beautiful pieces of machinery.
That's,
I have one that I still use to
this day. Whoa. Yeah. I mean,
if you've got really good shit,
it does the purpose and does
it a really high level, you,
you essentially could
just maintain it forever.
That's what they've been really
doing in Cuba with cars. You know,
if you go to Cuba,
you look at their cars,
apparently a large percentage of them
are American automobiles from like the
fifties or sixties big ass car.
It's crazy and beautiful and
in really good shape. Oh yeah.
I think that's what that
guy's doing with those icons.
He's just taking these old cars and just
putting the best components on it and
building,
you know like what it could have been
guys from Europe come over here and they
buy muscle cars and they just shipped
him right over to Germany, double it.
They're worth a lot of money in other
countries. Yeah, there's a flavor. Those
things have to those American muscle
cars at like the best engineered cars.
My opinion or like the Japanese and
the German and some of the Italians,
they have some amazing engineered cars,
but like the coolest cars,
there's no question like just straight
cool 69 Mustang rolls up 10 just shut the
fuck up. Everybody shut the fuck up.
You have a Ferrari and a Lamborghini,
you doors open up like wings stop.
Just stop suddenly pulls up one of those
Eleanor mustangs and those 67 gt five
hundreds just like good Lord. What
a beautiful car that is. So simple.
They just nailed it.
Yeah,
like those core vets like give her a c
those Corvettes from like like 1968 69
that that the sting ray car,
beautiful fucking and the wide
tires and the wide backend rumble.
That engine,
it looked like a lion about to pounce
with big back conscious and just,
they just nailed it.
You don't know what drugs they were doing
when they were designing cars in the
60s but they just fucking nailed
it. Right. They nailed it over,
over and over again.
Barracuda's Ma, I mean everyone,
they'd be creating these
fucking masterpiece. Yeah,
they're getting back to that now for sure.
Like the cars look better today
than it did for a long time.
But I would really like to know
what the fuck happened, what,
what happened in like the
1980s where things went so bad?
Like I know there's peaks and
valleys and a lot of things,
but in American automobile
design it doesn't make any sense.
Yeah. And at the exact same time as when
the Japanese cars that are coming out,
just when we need it to be at our
best to compete, we suddenly just,
I don't know what the, you know, the
factories where they, I don't know.
I bet there's probably
two versions of the story.
There's the pro union version and
the con Union version. Yeah. Oh,
I'm sure there's a lot of people
that blame the unions. I mean,
it's tough because I just
talking to somebody who's
very pro union yesterday and
I, I'm very pro union, but I'm starting
to slip a little bit in some ways. Like,
I'm, I'm in the writer's guild and
I'm very, you know, I walk the walk,
I walked away from a deal so I could walk
the picket line and my dad was in the
radio union after for his whole career.
That's what left left
my mom a pension and I,
and I believe that there should be a
living wage for people, but I also think,
God, how do we fix these
fucking corrupt procon engines?
Like what? Corrupt, broken engines union
wise, you mean like things like, well,
construction, certain, you know,
a kind of shield, something.
It's really gotten to the point where
you're just getting squoze from every
direction and it's adding,
it's adding, you know, I,
I'd rather see another guy get a job then
see the union just absorbed that much
more money. Well, any times you
have your bureaucracy, bureaucracy,
anytime you have a large number of people
that are involved in something that
really only needs a couple people,
you know,
I mean how many people really need be
involved in going over your construction
plans or how many people
really need, I mean, yeah,
once you establish environmental
parameters and shit,
like things like people trying to fix
their house up or something like that.
Like how many people really
need to be involved in this?
Like are you hiring a contractor? Does the
contract and no one is doing? Yes. Okay.
Well we're good. Yeah. Like let me just
get the fuck out of your hair. Yeah.
Like what do you,
unless you're doing something dangerous
and we're just going to assume that
everyone's doing something dangerous
now there's a lot of people are getting
paid off too. I have a friend who is
trying to get a house built and uh,
they're dealing with this, a commission
in this area, this particular area.
They're trying to develop a house
and they've literally been told like,
you have to like Greece wheels.
You have to like to get things
moving to get things approved.
Do you have to like get
on people's good side?
Like there's saying thanks to these people
like to indicate that I came that you
might monitor by these people,
something you might want to bribe them.
You want to be friends with them. He,
the closer you can get to these people,
the easier they'll lube
this process of like what?
This is so bizarre because it's
like they have power over you.
This is not like there's real clear
parameters. This is how we operate.
Regardless of whether or not we'd
like you or don't like, you know,
there's like this,
like this little wiggle room going on.
I mean that's essentially what
corruption really is, right? It's wiggle,
Bro. It's like it's never, nobody
ever states it as corruption.
Nobody ever says black and white.
I'm bribing this guy.
It's just I happen to take this guy out
to dinner. Well, it starts there. Well,
well,
was that the difference between him going
with you and going with somebody else?
Very likely. Well then that's a bribe.
That's true. Right. And in a lot of ways,
I mean,
you should be able to hire whoever the
fuck you want if it's your money and your
job.
But when you're talking about something
like a union that's involved and
construction are unions involved
and you know, coastal commissions,
those type of things know where people
are deciding whether I like the groups of
people that decide whether or not this
happens to or that doesn't happen. Yeah.
Yeah. Things get real weird. Man
Can, is ridiculous. Apparently. Like,
you know,
uh,
they tried to build a high speed railroad
or they did build a high speed power
and the you the, not the unions,
but uh, you know, the different, um,
levels of bureaucracy within the
government and privately we're squeezing
everybody to the point where the project
was 10 times as much as it should have
been.
And then the train started crashing
because they were trying to save so much
money. They're putting
inferior parts in. Yeah.
That's where the argument
for unions come in, right?
Cause it's not a, um, it's not a black
and white issue. Like I definitely think,
look,
we're talking about Foxconn and all those
people that are being forced to work
for such a horrible waves that
jumping off roofs, you Kinda,
you gotta establish like a living wage.
You got to establish if people are working
for you and this is a valuable thing
they're doing for you.
Like you have to pay them enough
so they could feed themselves,
clothe themselves like you can't. So
like in the in and then, you know,
healthcare and all the different things
that are going to come up. I mean,
you're a piece of their
organization and they're,
they're demanding to be recognized as
a valuable piece of the organization.
Like you can't have all the money.
Like that's what it is.
You have people working for you, you
need to pay them. That makes sense.
But it's like whenever you get a
group that is exploiting these,
uh, these laws that are in
place to protect people,
like that's when shit gets weird.
Like my buddy was in the
automotive industry in Detroit.
He was in the auto workers union and he
was telling me like how crazy some of
the contracts were and some of the gigs
where they had this thing where you
would both work, you would have a two man
contract. Like meaning that this was, uh,
this not a two man contract, a two man
job, like this job to run this machine.
It really only took one guy, but they
would, the union would require two men.
So you guys get two guys get
jobs. So you, you're both,
you would do four hours a day,
like you would do four
hours in the morning and uh,
I would come in at noon and
I would take over and uh,
I would do the job for the next four
hours. And then you go to the gym,
you go fucking have lunch. You literally
would work four hours a day. Yeah.
And that's what they all did. And they
all were making like 150 grand a year.
I mean,
it was crazy money.
He was talking about how much money
these different workers were making.
It's like, you know, if you got to a
certain level, like you got benefits,
you got this.
It was like super expensive to keep
all those people employed at that.
Not only that, but for that
money that you're paying them,
you're also paying a 13% into the union
which pays for the benefits so that you
know,
if what,
what's $50 an hour to that worker
actually costs the employer. You know,
what's 12% of $50 six, six, $7.
Something along those lines. Does it
matter that I need to break down that uh,
no math? No, I don't think, I
think your listeners get it. Yeah.
I think unions if used correctly or a a
nice sort of insurance to people getting
paid a fair wage and getting treated
ethically and having, you know,
money distributed in an
ethical and fair way.
There was no problem with
anything is things don't
always go the way they should.
Best case scenario.
Yeah.
It's almost like you got to start over
again with the unions. You got to get the,
like the Teacher's Union is insane.
You got women in there.
There was a woman that a women,
there's melting,
dare you know you met this one woman
though that works at my kid's school and
she had liquor on her breath and she
was like just ignoring the class and
reading the paper and like they couldn't
get rid of her. They just, yeah.
It was just impossible to get rid of her.
There's so much you have to go through.
We'll 10 years. A weird thing, man.
And I had this professor after three years
as a teacher. That's it. Three years.
Welcome to the jungle though. You got
to survive three years. Yeah. Yeah.
Especially in La. He deserve it. Ooh. You
get through three years of working in La,
babysitting kids, your gray
hair. The women are balls.
He's just beaten down. Yeah.
Ulcers and shit. Fucking how many
kids brought a gun? Just class today.
It's a weird world,
man. It's a weird world.
There's so many haves and
have nots in this world.
I don't know. Doesn't seem to be any
solution or anybody reaching for it.
But that might be the one thing that's
ever going to level anything out when it
comes to unions. Yeah. I mean having,
having groups of people that uh,
are all behaving in an ethical way,
having them in a, in a large number,
like whether it's a, you know,
a big group like the actors union or
whether it's a carpenter's union or it's
just,
it's fucking really hard.
It's really hard to get people all
together in a group like that to act
ethically,
to just always be cool to always do it
gray. I mean, unions just split apart.
There was the writer's guild east and the
writer's guild west, which effectively,
you know, destroy the power of
either one. There was aftra and sag,
which are both actors. Unions have,
should it, they're finally combined now,
but it should have been,
it should right now should be the DGA,
which is the director's guild.
The writer's guild and the actors union
should all be under the same to end a
Yahtzee,
which is like the technical guys should
all be one union because what they do is
the studios, we'll line
it up so that they, uh,
the contract for the actors union
comes up in January every two years,
but then they set up the writer's guild
to renew in February every two years
that they make them off here.
So that way you've never got everybody,
uh, lining up against you want a
union contract at the same time the,
and they can,
they can,
can everybody do what kind
of disagreements or they
have like when you have
disagreements and like the actors
union or something like that.
Mostly it's digital downloads, which is
a battle that everybody lost, you know,
that that should have been,
I mean,
I just got a residual check on
a TV show that I did and I got,
first I got the check for the
reruns on TV, the cable reruns.
Then I got the one for
digital online. And, uh,
the one on cable was like 1700 bucks
and the same usage period on digital was
like $13 and it's like probably more
views digitally than it was on cable.
But we gave that away
during the last strike. Ooh.
They weren't looking down the road.
They were really fighting
for network and cable reuse.
CIJ and they weren't looking at
the, missed it. Yeah. Netflix,
all this shit that's taken off.
We're barely getting a taste.
That's crazy. Yeah, they miss that. That's
a big one. It's the whole future. Wow.
That is so nuts. Yeah. But what,
but there's benefits to having
a union. Like what, what do you,
what do you think are like
the primary benefits of,
well I've had my health coverage cause
I've been in the writer's guild for like
13 years straight,
so I've had my health insurance paid for.
It's amazing coverage, low
deductible, low premiums.
It's like I think I pay like 250 bucks
a quarter or something crazy and I'm
paying third 13 grand. I pay, I was,
I was in the Union for 12 years out for
one year and I'm now I'm back in again.
And that one year that I had off,
I paid $13,000 for my family.
So that's, you know, that's
a lot of money right there.
And then you get the residuals to come in,
which is big and um,
you don't get abused,
you know, you have certain, like you
get meals you get, um, they can't,
they can only work a certain
number of hours. I mean,
there's not too many people that dig in
on that, but the spirit of it is there,
you know,
producers know that they,
if you're in the union
that they're not going to,
I've worked on both sides of it.
I've worked non union jobs and as per,
as a producer,
not a writer because I can't,
but I've seen the hours that you work
and how you writer's guild jobs, you get,
you can take an hour for lunch
and you also get treated in a
pretty commensurate way. Right.
You know, like when you're in a, a sag TV
show or something like that. I was like,
it's pretty across the board
or was professional like
as far as like, you know,
you've got the craft service table, this
is where your dressing room is, you know,
you're out by x amount of times,
you have a 12 hour turnover.
Like they have all these rules
they have to follow by those rules.
When they go over, like they
get all bummed out. Like
everybody gets pumped out.
Yeah, it's a super expensive.
When they start going over time
and money, money talks, that
makes them get, there's no way,
like most shows shouldn't take more
than eight hours to shoot, you know?
And instead it takes 15
why do you think that is?
Because everybody wants to brand whatever
it is that they're putting into the
project. You know, if you're
the hairstylist, he want
the hair to look perfect.
If your, you know, the,
the set Kai you want, you,
you need an extra 20 minutes to do this
as opposed to if there's penalties,
it's like, no, we got to fucking go get
it done and then we're gonna move on.
So I think with cable there's usually
not a strong hand on the, on the, uh,
on the wheel as much as there is an in
network shows where there's somebody
that's a show runner that really has
to answer to the studio and say, no,
we are done at 6:00 PM that's it.
You know, maybe they go an hour long.
But I work on cable shows where I worked
on one and it was a [inaudible] wife,
tiny and her ghetto fabulous friends.
Oh,
what'd you do on it was a panel show. I
was a, what was I on that? I was the head,
I was the show runner on that.
And uh,
they came in and we were
supposed to start taping it.
Four o'clock started at 7:00 PM because
they all were getting their hair done
and it was a cat fight.
The next night we're taping again.
Supposed to be four o'clock
taping seven 30. Wow. Yeah,
it was fucking money. That
is, that's a lot of money.
You're paying everybody just for
three and a half hours. Right.
And then you're going along,
which means now you're going into
overtime wages on the other side.
So
there's many good things about having a
union. So many good things about them.
Oh yeah. Yeah. Some unions that
are fucked, man, there's a,
there's a big dispute right now with
the UFC in the culinary union and the
Culinary Union is the attack the UFC and
make all these like websites and posts
and they have like stories that they,
uh,
they have people write about how horrible
the UFC is because they want the UFC
to give up a station.
Casinos
owns, uh, the UFC, the UFC is owned by
[inaudible]. They own station casinos.
They owned the UFC and
they own a 22 casinos.
And if those casinos went union, they're
not union or non union. And I guess I'm,
I might be speaking as school here. I
don't really know. I believe check this,
that the workers don't
want it to be union.
Like they voted against it because
they didn't want to pay the wages.
But if they did pay the wages there,
ha.
I guess they're happy with what they
make. I don't, I pay the dues, the dues,
but if they did do it,
the Culinary Union would make some
insane amount of money every year.
Millions dollars every year.
Yeah.
So what they do is they have
this like smear campaign,
like constant smear campaign about the
UFC and they hired politicians and one of
them,
I actually just got busted,
one of the main guys in New York that
they had supposedly that had been a
roadblock to getting the
UFC legalized in New York.
UFC is not legal in New York still.
No,
still to this day it's
illegal in New York state.
The reason being because of corrupt
politicians and all brick goes back to the
culinary union trying to keep the UFC,
uh,
it like trying to turn the station
casinos into um, union casinos.
Right?
So they're spending all this money and
like getting people upset about the UFC
and making all these nutty websites. And
anytime anybody says anything fucked up,
anytime anything goes wrong, the color
and union was ditch jumps all over it.
And they're just trying to muscle the
UFC and to relinquishing control of these
casinos. It's a, that's
allegedly the story.
Obviously I don't know all the details
so I should probably say for legal
purposes, this is how it's
been told to me. Yeah.
But ultimately you know that if there's
a lot of money to be made and you've got
some organization that relies on
keeping strong numbers of members,
they're going to be, you know, financially
motivated to try to make things cheap.
I had a buddy was in the teamsters like
when I was a kid and I was like 21,
22 years old. He was a, in the end
he, he would uh, work the docks,
he would filet fish all day and he had a
dent in his hip and the dent in his hip
was from his hip pressing up against the
fish filet table all day looking at a
dent, very like one hip was like
dented in and be like, you're an adult,
your radios ducted.
Cause he just leaned all day and leaned
all day and he always smelled like fish.
Oh always smelled like fish. This
poor bastard. I don't mean to laugh.
I mean the guys making a living, but when
a life, yeah, totally. Shit. He was a,
he was my boxing coach and so he
would, when he would rub this, uh,
like Vaseline stuff on your face and
stuff called Abilene so that like punches
when they, they hit you, they
slide, they don't cut you. Yeah.
The leather doesn't cut. You see, he'd
rub this stuff all over your face.
You just smell fish, fish and Abilene
and he'd just be rubbing it. He,
so he was filleting fish and
training as a boxer. Yeah.
He's one of the craziest
guys I've ever met. He, uh,
he got his finger bit and often a street
fight and they replaced it with his toe
and they curved it permanently so
he could still throw right hooks,
crazy Irishman, Joe Lake,
which tell the big toe,
uh, they took the second toe, not
the big tub with the one next to it,
I guess you don't use, you don't
use that. I guess you don't need it.
Just strengthen up those
last three babies. Keep that
party role on with no toe.
Now. I mean, the thing is,
if you think about a finger,
each one individually is dealing
with things but your toes, it just,
that you don't even really need. And we
could get rid of toes at this point. No,
they do help you. They help you with
movement, with movement and you know,
like they're, they're
adjustable. I, she had a balance
yourself. Like you need toes.
It fucks with people when they
lose a toe, they lose a lot of, uh,
their ability to move around.
Yeah. It's not the same.
I used to caddy for this guy that,
uh,
something happened to him in Vietnam
and uh, his feet were paralyzed,
so like his ankles work but
like is from the ankle down.
Everything was just fucking dead.
And this guy walked,
he walked like he'd have to almost bring
his knee up in the front every time
he'd stepped forward. Like
ski boots. Yeah. Almost like
that. And then he would, uh,
he'd hit the ball and it just, it never
could hit it straight because you need,
you know, you need balance.
But the guy fucking loved golf.
He played like two rounds a day.
Do you have to caddy for him
to be all over the course?
Look over this guy's fucking ball.
Fucking numb feet. That's so weird.
What a weird ailment. Dead Feet. Oh, I
guess probably happy. That was it. Yeah.
Right on all the shit that could go wrong.
I know.
I know a dude who broke his toe really
bad and they told him he couldn't do
Jujitsu for six months if they were going
to fix it to or they can amputate it.
So he said cut it off.
No Shit. Which tell a,
I think it was like the same one by my
success. Which toes are in each story?
I think it was the one next to the
big toe. Yeah. I might be wrong.
One of his toes. If you had to lose
one toe, which one would it be?
Uh, that little. Hmm.
That's a good question.
I was going to say that free loader
toe right next to the little toe.
All right. Fuck it. The ring finger.
Yeah, toad doesn't it does nothing.
I never paid attention to until,
yeah,
look washed out tow a million times
in my life. Never looked at it twice.
Do you go look at my pinky toe?
I'll check it out cause it's weird.
I look at that tiny little nail. Go leave
the stupid nail. You know, I'll look.
It's like a clipping of another now.
It's not even it's own nail but the
little toe next to the pinky toe.
No love gets no lo. Do you get in
there and individually watch your toes.
I used to it now. Now I don't give up.
You got no, no desire slapping on the top.
Slab it on the bottom down. I
wash my feet, you know in between.
I'm always doing stuff barefoot.
Yeah, like I lift weights barefoot.
I do kickboxing, barefoot. Jujitsu's
barefoot. It's all barefoot.
You got to get in there.
You also got to make sure you don't get
athlete's foot like athlete's foot is
what you, when you get that,
those cracks underneath your toes,
like get the base where the the ball
of your foot reaches the
bottom of your title.
Like that gets all dry and fucked
up and cracks and it hurts.
And a lot of that comes from
your toes being dirty. Yeah.
It comes from like weird
fungus getting in there.
And apparently this is the same,
like the same as ringworm.
Like athlete's foot is kind of the same.
Fungus is ringworm.
It's just in a different spot on your body
and Jock itch all same shit. Yeah, that's
right. Jackets, just athlete's foot.
Yeah. It's some fucking funk growing
on your dick boy. Yeah, right.
Yeah. God, I would
hate, I would hate that.
It's important if anybody's
listening to this though,
if you do have some funk on
you, um, whatever you do,
don't use antibacterial soap.
Don't ever use that stuff. If you
use antibacterial soap, soap, I mean,
unless you're a hospital, you know,
pay worker, you're a, you know,
a doctor or something and then you should
use it. But there's stuff called um,
defense soap that is a,
a probiotic. It's a, it,
it discourages the growth of bad bacteria,
but it promotes healthy bacteria
and it's all like natural oils.
They use like um,
eucalyptus oil and tea tree oil and it
just like staff and ringworm and all that
stuff. It's really good for grapplers.
That's why it's called defense soap.
They made it for grapplers,
but for anybody like for keeping
like healthy skin flora that,
and here's a big one, dude,
this is really big probiotics.
Fucking I drank this shit all the
time. Yeah, you telling me about that?
So important. Yeah. Yeah. These
are organisms like live organisms.
You take them into your body and literally
strengthens your immune system like
acidophilus.
I was reading this thing where they were
saying that acid off lists they believe
can discourage when you touch things
like say if you touch something and it's
got some sort of a funk on it and then
you accidentally touch your face. Well,
if you're taking healthy
doses of acidophilus,
apparently acid office will resist
the introduction of new bacteria.
They're like, Whoa, whoa
bitch, what are you doing here?
What the fuck are you doing here?
Whereas if you have that antibacterial,
so your skin is like devoid of
even healthy bacteria. Yeah.
Does healthy flora is just as important,
like you can't like strip it off.
It's just as important to keep the healthy
flora as it is to get rid of the bad
shit. Yeah. The um, uh, somebody,
so we told me I was reading an article
about bacteria and it's like there's a
pretty big percentage of your body that's
made up of bacteria. Yeah. It's huge.
Like the amount of weight and your
body's like 12 pounds or something of
bacteria. This is the way
I saw it explained once. It
really rang that number up.
But it's a lot. This is the way
I saw a scientist explain that.
So I'm pretty sure he's correct.
He said there's more eco lie in your
gut than I've ever been. People ever.
Wow.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Yeah we did. It's just sitting there
while it's doing, it's working like it.
Healthy stomach bacteria is like
very important for digestion.
That's what you're getting when you're
absorbing like these Kombucha is and shit
like that.
You're changing your,
your gut and there's a lot of studies
that are trying to link that to autism and
they think that autism and poor gut
bacteria in the intestinal tract,
bacteria,
it might be an issue,
the inflammation factor that inflammation
might cost or it's all sorts of
distress throughout the entire
body. Like as a, you know, the,
the symbiosis of your stomach,
your digestive tract,
your circulatory system and your brain,
all of them together being affected
equally that this digestive disorder might
also fuck with people's heads.
Yeah. Yeah. I got my guts fucked man.
I fart soft shits pain.
My Gut is wrong. Well,
how's your diet? Diet's great.
Really fantastic. So what the fuck?
I think I got GRD when I was in Florida
like 20 years ago and I never really got
rid of it ever since I got it.
I've had gas,
Johnny are you get that
from drinking water?
The animals shit in right down to Florida.
They don't have fresh water very much
in Florida. So what were you doing?
How'd you get it? Just staying in a hotel.
Me, me and my wife. She got rid of it.
I never did. You got it from
all hotel? Yeah. What? Yeah.
How the fuck did you get it?
Because they don't have a lot
of groundwater in Florida.
They fucking pump all that
shit in from out of town.
So like the tap water cave,
you chop water gave us GRD.
Jesus fucking Christ.
I went on like three different cycles of,
I figured it was tetracycline or something
to the point where the doctor was
like, you can't keep taking this and
it should just, it should equal out.
And I've gone back and it never
has. Oh my God, Dude. That's insane.
I've been far to once we've been in
here by the way, that wouldn't do it.
Thank you. I appreciate
that. I would fart. Um,
it, I did fart in an
elevated recently and the,
someone did the running leg hand in,
opened the doors and they came in
and I just looked at him like, hey,
it's an asshole move.
Mine was an asshole move,
but you don't open up elevator doors
on somebody, so let's take a ride.
So because he shoved his
arm in the elevator door.
No, I had just farted and then I
saw the hand come in. It's not,
you don't like people
showing the hand through.
I don't think you should do that ever.
Unless it's like if you're in a
parking structure in Santa Monica,
that's six stories and
there's like one elevator.
So it comes every 12 and you
could stick your hand in that.
But if I'm into like an an office
complex and there's like six banks of
elevators or a hotel, you don't
stick your hand in the door. Wow.
But what if the guy's in a super hurry?
He can wait for the next elevator.
I'm in a super hurry to always have sim.
It's looking for excuses to
fart on people. Take stand.
Is that what this is yours? This is
just an excuse to force it on people.
Well the other thing is if you put all,
forget that I'm,
that it's valley parking somewhere.
Like if I go to the comedy store,
I always forget and I'll fart before
I get there. And I was like, Oh fuck,
sorry doc.
So
does Giardia like you saw a noticeable
change from the way you were?
Oh yeah. Immediate, immediate damn
fuck no, it's way better than it was,
but it's still there. I got to watch what
I eat. Like I'm lactose intolerant now
my friend Steve or no,
he got Giardia and then he got
trichinosis so she to from bad beef,
but his was for bad bear.
Oozes from eating a bear.
But apparently he keeps it for life.
Like they kill it in your stomach,
like it lives in your stomach and then it,
it goes like it migrates into your,
your muscle cells and it hurts
like a fall. She have like agony,
like muscle agony. Like you're in pain.
Like your back hurts, your shoulders hurt.
They can't kill that.
They just plant spores in you.
So essentially this rude of crazy, the
shit that's in your stomach that's gone.
But the stuff that's in your,
your arms and your legs and your,
your tissue stays there for the
rest of your life. Those spores,
like if you ate him, if you were in
the of the apocalypse came around,
you've got to cook them 260 degrees,
hall. Let me write that down. One to 60
bill. Oh, speaking of which, by the way,
can I plug some dates fall
again? What'd we got? Addison,
Texas coming to see you folks.
February 28th. March 1st. Yeah.
It's not a great room.
Fucking room on the second floor and uh,
it's just a perfect shape.
It's been around forever too.
So it's soaked with
laughter. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Like the, the different sets that have
been in that room. That's a great room.
Addison, Texas, they still have the
piano bar right next door. Oh yeah.
That's a great
a hand job shack to right around the
corner. How dare you, I didn't go.
How dare you even know.
No,
I walked past it and I saw this guy who
was loitering out front and he just kept
like walking back and forth
and I was like, why is this
guy hanging out in front?
And then I looked over and it's,
and it was like a,
somebody told me that you can net Tel
it's a jack check because if it has a neon
footprint on it,
those are the jacket that's like a sign
that it's a happy ending place. Really.
That's what a certain comedian told me.
I don't know if he's right,
but isn't that like a reflexology thing?
That's what they want you to think.
No Shit. Yeah. So you go in, they rub your
feet, just jerk you off. Have no idea.
I didn't even touch your feet.
If I had a choice,
if I was going to do what I would
say as long as I'm in here, you know,
let's get the feet gone first.
Yeah. Some people like get weirded
out about people touching their feet,
only not into it at all.
I like women's feet.
I enjoy looking at women's face.
Well when they're attractive, you
know, I never attractive. It's great.
What is it about that though? I mean,
if not, I'm not asking you personally,
but what is it about like,
like why would a guy give a shit about
a girl if it girls toes took a hook turn
and her feet are all but like what?
Why? What does it even affect us?
Like why is it more desirable
to see like perfect toes, right?
I mean it's just me. My personal thing
is I believe it shows they're evil.
They're haunted hammer
toe equals haunted you,
but she will kill you one day.
At that time you'll be sleeping.
I'll send,
you'll feel this little hook going
around your trachea and you'll look and
you'll see an ankle.
Can you imagine if people
were that transparent where
the way their hands looked
was like how deadly or nice they were?
Yeah. So if people had beautiful, smooth,
clean hands,
you never had to worry about them.
They're all knuckled up and
fucked up after wine number.
Her sisters had those nasty fucking feet.
He couldn't fit in the shoes.
That's right. She was the original
foot fetish. Worship Goddess shoot was,
but maybe she was just a part of a
narrative. That's been going on forever.
Like the Chinese people with
their binding bindings. Yeah.
It's the craziest shit of all.
That's crazy. That's so frightening.
But it's totally logical if you go back,
I mean if you put it in
context of going back,
you could show wealth by saying it
wasn't just the aesthetic of small feat.
It was also saying my bitch doesn't
have to work. I can bind her feet.
That's how much money I have. Good
Lord. Yeah. Yeah. She could never work.
Work in the fields.
That's why Japanese people were fucking
hats and sunblock and gloves because in
their culture having fair skin
is a sign of wealth. Wow. Right.
Once you know in some cultures
are trying to bleach people,
like Filipinos are really
getting into glutathione,
which is I think it's like an amino acid
or something like that. Some nutrition.
I mean I, I take it actually it's like
really good for your liver, but they,
they're taking this stuff and through
some injection process that I don't
totally understand. It makes your
skin lighter so they want to be like,
maybe they're darker brown Filipinos.
They want to be light because light,
lighter state. That's what
Michael Jackson did. No,
Michael Jackson had what I
have. He had vitiligo. Yeah.
If you look at my hands like
you see these spots on my hands,
I'm just a white guy so it
doesn't look that freaky.
But if I get a tan it can look
pretty freaky. Like all my knuckles,
like trauma areas are big areas that
get it like knuckles because you know
anytime you get cuts, scratches
sometimes that can turn to Ville.
Lygo I have to put like a, an ointment
on it to keep it from spreading. Yeah.
But um, plus you, your hairy
so it just looks like patches,
a hair on your knuckles. But
Michael, but I'm a white guy. Again,
it's not that much of a contrast between
the area where I have pigment in the
area where I don't have pigment.
But if you're black,
like Michael Jackson
was when he was young.
It's super traumatic for a lot of people.
Some people freak out,
they have like some really good remedies
for it now they've ointment that can
pretty much stop it from spreading.
And they have these poobah treatments
that they do that re pigment areas.
They're pretty good at it now.
But the Michael Jackson days,
they couldn't do shit. You know, I'm the
opposite. I'm so fair that I try to, uh,
I try to darken like on the weekends I
put a black shoe Polish on my face and I
go sing.
Do you leave like a white thing around
your mouth so you don't fuck your food up?
I'll eat some pattern down.
That's me flooring.
I'm also,
I'm going to be at the helium comedy club.
Oh, I forgot what we were doing.
March 6th and seventh. Uh,
don't forget Denver comedy works. I think
it's your favorite club in the country.
March 12th through 14th.
You just rattled off two of my
favorite clubs in the country.
Helium and Philly is fucking
amazing. Amazing. And uh,
the comedy works where it did my last
special rocky mountain high did that to
calm me down was so great. It's the best
club ever. Yeah, it's the best club.
It's just so perfect. I mean, there's a
bunch of the best clubs ever. You know,
there's like five or six of them all
over the country. Those are two of them.
The top five right there.
And then the Hollywood Improv,
which is definitely up in that,
uh, rankings. That's a great spot.
March 21st that's a fucking great spot.
The Hollywood improv is so that's such
a good fucking room for comedy and such
like a high level room.
You go there,
you see Judd Apatow working out and you
know, I mean you're there all the time.
There's so many good comics there that's
a, that's a fucking showcase spot man.
And they run a tight, they keep it
on time for the most part. You know,
if they had a Arsenio hall dropped in
one night and he did about 35 at the top
of the shell on announced.
And I spent a, I don't know,
16 at my 20 minutes shitting all over
Arsenio Hall for going along and they,
they have crowd fucking went crazy. I
think he tanked it. Oh, did he really?
Nothing like starting to show
off with a tank and going,
you know, over your five it
dropped buys five minutes.
That's all they were giving them. Yeah.
Well that's not good, but I don't know,
10 minutes. What? What was his playing?
It was supposed to do any, hey,
are you listening to Arsenio? Whoa.
Throwing it down. I know that dude.
He's a good guy. He's a very nice guy.
I never met him. He's a very nice guy.
He left before I started.
I talked to him, um,
really recently about a social media
stuff when he was doing the new version of
the Arsenio Hall show.
They took over social media,
like it's Facebook and it's Twitter and
I'll let you, they asked to do that now.
Like there was a, I was doing this
one thing. They asked me to do that.
They wanted to go over my Twitter.
I go, fuck you. Like what?
Are you crazy?
But we're going to tweet for you the
fuck you're going to tweet for me. Yeah.
Like, no, you're not like you want
to start a Twitter page for the show.
Will you start that and then
you can tweet from that.
You're not gonna tweet from my personal
Twitter page just because I'm on a show.
Like the idea that you have to give it up.
Genius in the Digital Marketing Department
brought that up in a meeting and they
went,
sounds like a good idea Phil.
Will you imagine you have to be such
a whore that you have to give up your
Twitter page? Like get the fuck
out of here. No, can't, no,
you can't have my Twitter page.
If you want me to tweet stuff,
send it to me and I'll tweet
it if I agree with it. Yeah,
but you can't take boot for him. He
didn't even think about it. He just,
he like didn't think that it was a
big deal. It was just like Yay, cool.
But now he's trying to get it back.
Like he was struggling to get it back
under his own control after show was
canceled. No Shit. I was like,
this is ridiculous. Wow. They like,
they own your social media presence,
which is worth a fuck load of money. Yeah.
Like, what if you did a project for,
you know, name x production company and
in the project was they can tweet
anything they want from your social media
sites, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram.
They can tweet anything they want.
They're going to get put
out anything they want.
They would just release
commercials all day. Yeah. I mean,
imagine if that was in your contract
and they just started putting out like,
there's a tide commercial on
your fucking Twitter feed tied.
Got My clothes smelling fucking
amazing breakfast Simmons.
And then there's a video and you're
like, watts, yeah, I can't believe this.
And then you call your age and like, Look
Greg, it's in the contract. He's like,
Oh my God, I'm retired. And
they like Mecca. It's funny,
it's about the Greg Fitzsimmons show. It's
funny, but it's also product placement.
Yeah. He'd be like, oh no,
nobody can really write a tweet for you.
That doesn't sound like it's not you.
It's kind of like,
because it's so tight,
it's like it really has
to be your wording. Yeah.
You would have to get somebody who
really knew you well. Like I put out,
when I put out my podcast,
I have my producer put out the tweet
because he's the one that uploads it.
So then I know that as soon as it uploads,
he just sends a tweet saying, uh, so I,
I give him a blurb to write ahead of time
so that when it goes up, it's written.
But sometimes if I don't give him one,
he writes it and it just immediately,
I don't know what it is.
Like something subtle.
You can just tell it wasn't sent by
the person that it says it is. Okay.
Well you get a sense of
someone who they are,
when you read just their
posts on a message board or
you read their Twitter feed,
you don't get it all. But if you're
reading 140 characters a day,
over a long period of time,
140 characters,
a tweet rather over a long period of time,
you kind of get a sense of the terrain.
You kind of get a sense of the way people
phrase things and say how angry they
are. Oh yeah. That's a
big indicator of anger.
You could find out some fucked up shit
about people just by reading their angry
tweets. Yeah. Like what are you getting
mad at? Dummy? Yeah. Like Jesus Christ,
like this person away
from your fucking life
and just everything's like, I have
to watch myself. I can get bit or,
because I think it's funny
to write something that,
and I'm not really being bitter.
It's just like it's the easy
path to a laugh better. Yeah.
And then I looked back and I go, wow,
that was 12 bitter ones in a row.
How the fuck do I look right now?
I uh, follow several people
that I think are idiots and uh,
one of the things that I really enjoy
following is people that are not very
bright, but they give a lot of advice.
Yeah. Like people are not very bright,
but they're,
their Twitter feed is always advice.
Like what you need to do in this
world is go for your dreams. And like
you read their Twitter, you're like,
oh, okay. I think it's an insight.
It's an insight to like someone's
struggling for sanity insight to someone
trying to like find,
find sense in the world with this doll.
Nine volt brain.
Yeah,
it's def.
It's definitely the access to giving
people information has outweighed the
ability to supply it in an equality
way. There's just, there's just like,
I even feel it. Like I can't,
I can't tweet every day
sometimes I just don't really have
anything to say. But you know,
you feel like I should put something out
today and then you write something and
you go, what if I could I
write that for that was stupid.
I liked taking news off of Twitter.
I think it's good to do. Yeah. Yeah.
Cause I think some days I don't have
shit to say. I think taking days off, um,
you know, I was talking about
this the other day we were,
we were talking about stand up in this
way, that taking days off standup,
taking weeks off, stand up. I think
it was Collin was talking to him,
we were talking about how if you go and
go and go your act, it's really tight.
Everything feels really good.
But when you take like a week
off and then jump back in,
the enthusiasm just cranks back up again.
You know?
I think that's the case with
pretty much everything in life.
If you do things too much,
you'll lose your perspective.
Like you lose like what it is about that
thing that you really enjoy. Like yeah,
you need little breaks. Hey, your bit
at big can get a lot stronger when you,
when you walk away from it for a little
while and you come back and you go, oh,
I didn't even get why I wrote that bit.
That's,
that's what I was originally
thinking. It's about this. Yeah.
You tighten it up and you realize
that like for me, you know,
you make a lot of choices throughout a
bit. I can go this way or go that way.
Sometimes you just get to clarity when
you come back to it to see that you were,
that that was a,
you got a cheap laugh off that one time
and you thought that was part of the bet
and it wasn't. It was just a, it
was a, you got lost for a second.
You got to come back?
Yeah,
I have a bit that I just added to
another book that I abandoned years ago.
Like I had it and then I lost it.
Like I had it for a while.
It's like very strong bit and then I
fucked something up with it or tweaked it
wrong and, and it just got too
complicated and I was like,
well there's too many
jokes similar to that. My,
I'll just put aside and I put
it aside for years and years.
And the other day I was on stage,
I was in the middle of one bit and
I started thinking about, oh my God,
that fits right in there.
And like a glove, it just
slid into place and crushed.
It was like almost like I was holding,
it was a wedge that I didn't have a gap
for. Yeah. And then all of a sudden,
oh it's right there. Yeah. And all
its liabilities were out the window.
Cause it didn't like it as a standalone
bit. It didn't have an ending. It's like,
but when I shoved it in the middle of
this other bit that already had an ending,
he just made that bit way better and
you didn't have to work on it and fine
tuning it already done that work.
It just needed a place.
That's why I think standup comedy,
like spending time just going over your
act is like one of the one things that
we all could do more of.
I did this thing with Ari where
I went over a shiny happy jihad,
which was CD I put out in like 86 or
something like that or a 2006 rather.
And um, when we went over it, we're
talking about why you did this,
why he did that.
And I really hadn't thought about a lot
of it and listening to it for the first
time in all these years.
Like I don't remember the jokes.
So like a few of them I remembered, but
some of them were really making me laugh.
Like I didn't, I never had heard them
before. Even though there were mine,
you know, I could be completely forgot
them and going over it like that,
like made me like super fucking to go
to stand up and I got on this like real
rampage over the next few weeks after
that there really helped me and it made me
think like, man, that's
probably an aspect, um,
of comedy that we don't like to do that
we probably all should be doing sitting
down, going over all of your
act, going over to your note,
what's going over all the different bits
and is this the right order for them?
What's a better order?
Why don't we try this order tonight?
Why don't we try this for the first
show and that for the second show.
Well that's just nice
that when you go to a club and you worked
there for three nights as you got two
afternoons where you can take your sat
and listened to it the next day and think
about it and then give yourself some
time to write new shit. And you know,
you really have nothing to do except
focus on your stand up for, you know,
two straight days.
Then you come back to La and you gotta
you go on at the Improv or somewhere and
people are like, wow, you got like fucking
lot of new material there. That's good.
And like you wouldn't have that
if you were just working in town.
Right. Or if you were, you need to
have to be really disciplined. Yeah.
Really disciplined to make sure that
you're just going up and doing this.
Is this 15 minutes is going
to be all about blank. Yeah.
It's just a fun, fun fucking
thing to do, man. Yeah.
Still after all these years,
people who don't know,
we started out together like within a
week of each other. Right. That's crazy.
Yeah. Dude, we're only shy
25 years old as fuck. Yeah.
We're all this shit.
Remember when you were a kid and you
thought of someone who was 47 you're like,
what's Eh, 47 that was beyond
marriage. Like Middle Ages,
40 dead man. Yeah. I remember I was in
high school and I had a thing for Madonna.
I found that Madonna was 26 it's
like God damn, that bitch is old.
She's 26 good Lord. Yeah. Yeah.
I used to like older. I always
liked older women. How old?
Well, when I was, um, I guess,
I guess when I was in like ninth grade,
I fooled around with this girl that was
a senior, but it was like, you know,
she wasn't doing it because
she was turned on by me.
It was just like I hung around or a
lot and she was like, throw me a bone.
So she let me see your tits and stuff.
But then when I was like 19 I dated a
woman who was turning 40 that summer.
It was like a whole summer long romance.
Whoa. She is this big corporate lawyer.
Very successful.
And I was living out in the Hamptons
with my brother and another guy and like
this shitty,
it was a one bedroom just flee written.
You woke up every day covered in bites
and they had a two bedroom next to us,
her and her sister. The Palumbo
sisters and they would, uh,
they had this beautiful two better with
like top shelf liquor and they were
Italian from queens and so they would,
they'd come out and they would cook
pasta and chicken cutlets everything all
weekend and we would just move over there.
My brother was hooking up with one sister
and I was hooking up with the other
one and then we would just like fuck
around and eat and drink and then we'd go
dancing with them at night and then they'd
leave on Sunday night and they'd give
us like all this Tupperware with
all the leftovers in it that we'd,
we'd survive on for a couple more days.
Then they come out on the weekends. Oh,
she was the greatest. Wow. Yeah.
40. Huh? 40 years old. You were 19.
I was 19. How was her body? Good.
Good. You know, Italian girls the age,
well at Brown skin tight.
Was she getting off a big divorce
feet? No, she was a workaholic. Thanks.
She was know she was a corporate lawyer.
She was big time and a lot of money.
Was she on top most of the time?
Yeah. She took control. Wow. So yeah,
she'd ride it. Yes. She'd hold
the base and then it was all,
it was like hers all up to her.
Wow. Standard shift. She fucked you.
She fucked me. Whoa. I pushed back and
she'd yell at me, Whoa, you don't move.
Whoa. You Little Shit. You
spit in your mouth. You're in
high school. Spit my mouth.
Stick her feet and that's where the foot
thing, she would stick her feet. Oh, cut.
Nah, we allow it to be on
top. Oh yeah. No. Look,
I was an adult when I was 19 I was an
animal. I couldn't be stopped. I just,
I just was so horny.
I was so horny that when women finally
let me start having sex with them,
I would ravage them. I would
just, I my hands, I was,
you wouldn't see me laying
with my arms by my side.
I didn't care for having sex for an hour.
I was still working.
I would grab a nipple.
Fucking fishhook hands
were moving all the time.
Can I get one in the asshole that
night then? I am. I'm checking.
I'm going to check the oil, check
it every time. Get Away with here.
How far can I push it on every single
encounter. That was my emo. Wow.
Yeah, you're an animal. Then they stop you
when you go. All right. That's the line.
We don't cross that till
next time we try it again.
If you thought about the
difference between you as
like a 12 year old or 11 year
old and then puberty and then riding
the furious waves of pure beauty,
which is what I call like 16 1718 yeah,
like those years,
like into 19 even though like by the time
you like figure out how to stay on the
wave,
the wave of hormones that your body starts
producing and how different you are,
your observations on life are like when
you're 10 you don't give a fuck about
ass or tits or feet or high heels or
the way a girl puts her lipstick on.
But when you're 17 you're jerking off to
magazines. Like you're taking magazines,
you're beaten off on the girls' pictures,
on magazines. Like look at naked bodies,
you're fading off
and all.
I can just remember going into a white
noise space where nothing else mattered.
I was jerking off and the world shut
down around me. It was just so intense.
It was like, I guess what somebody would
feel like if they went in like heroine.
Nod.
It was so like all encompassing.
Yeah, it's a drug. I mean your
body's trying to reproduce.
Your body's trying to give you
all these fucking neuro chemicals.
These feel good juices to
pump through your body.
Serotonin and dopamine and
love and oxytocin and calm.
Hurry up,
calm.
Ah Good.
We,
when we reproduce and the eggs break open,
the little kid comes out screaming.
You're like, how the fuck?
Cause they tricked you
with that come juice.
That's that feeling that you get
when you just, oh, rub my balls. Oh,
that's how you make a
person that's sweet relief.
It's this weird biological trick.
Isn't that amazing? It's the most,
it's the most intense, incredible thing
you do and it's also the most intense,
incredible feeling that
you're having while you do it.
And if you don't smoke pot,
you don't even know what sex feels like.
You think you do? We'd make
sex feel so much better. Hey,
what did you think of that article I
sent you from the New Yorker about the,
isn't that wild? Yeah. Explain
what it is. Basically, you know,
all the testing that they did on
mushrooms and LSD back in the 60s.
I mean starting, I think they started
and let like the forties right? Well,
Gordon Wasson was the guy who originally
started bringing mushrooms to the
Western world. Who was the one who
started, I think it was a life magazine.
They publish some shit about him or
some shit about, uh, his, uh, his, uh,
trials to Mexico's travels to Mexico and
his experiments with magic mushrooms.
I think that was, I think
that was in the 50s yeah. So,
so they did all these studies and then
obviously the CIA did all the LSD studies
and the fifties and sixties,
they're mostly fifties, I think.
And then all the sudden they
outlawed it and they just said,
bury that data and it just disappeared.
You cannot find any of the testing
results that they did from back then.
And so they lost a lot of good progress.
And so this New Yorker piece is talking
about how suddenly scientists are
getting the green light
from major universities.
Harvard and Yale and Boston University
are all funding studies to look back into
what he called the drug and magic
mushrooms, psilocybin, psilocybin.
And what they're doing is they're
doing control testing, um,
and they're giving it to
people specifically that
have terminal illnesses and
helping them deal with the,
you know, the, their mortality,
literary that they're going to die.
And how do you wrap your head around
that and how do you deal with the
depression that comes with that and
they're giving them the mushrooms and
they're having, their 70% of them are
having mystical experiences like God,
like experiences and then
they are holding on to it.
It doesn't go away.
They are walking through the rest of
their lives realizing that all is love.
They said that's the,
the common thread that runs through all
of them is that it's all about love.
And they get that in their head and
they die with it whenever, you know,
if they last another year or two years,
they don't need another experience on
the mushrooms to get back to that place.
It stays with them.
Well,
I think if you were at a real
transformative period of your life,
I mean that's the biggest transformation
ever, right? Going from life to death,
the ultimate last trip that we all take,
you're probably like super
emotional and very engaged and I would
imagine that under that kind of stress
and that kind of like uncertainty, a
mushroom trip would be even more profound.
But if you have a,
a real powerful psychedelic
trip and it doesn't change your,
your complete total view of,
of reality,
he probably just didn't get a high
enough dose. That's all it is. I mean,
I know I've talked to a lot of people
who've done mushrooms and they loved it.
They had a great time. They're like,
oh my God, we were on the beach.
We were so silly. We laugh for
hours. It was so beautiful.
It was this amazing experience opened me
up to the way the world was and made me
feel like they probably had that wonderful
experience. They really probably did.
But the difference between that kind of
experience and like what they're giving
these people in these,
these trials,
like you give people like five
dried grams of psilocybin mushrooms,
that's like a big breakthrough dose
and you have this overwhelming like
incredible visionary,
like transformative experience
that most people don't get to.
Like the DMT experience is supposedly
the most intense that of all the
psychedelics at,
of all the Wood Mckenna used to call,
like the center of the
Mandalah. If those all, all,
all psychedelic experiences vary,
whether it's Payoti or mushrooms or, um,
you know, sage, which is, um, um, uh,
what is that fucking one that
everybody gets at grocery stores?
It's still available. Salvia,
Salvia divinorum. It's
essentially like a sage plant.
They all like reach some
different psychedelic state.
But the center of the Mandala of the
craziest one is the dimethyltryptamine
experience. And if you
have the dimethyltryptamine
experience, like I said,
it's impossible to look at the rest of
reality the same way again because you
always know that that's, that's in
your head last very, very short.
It's only like 15 minutes. No, but
I'm saying how long does the effect,
it depends on how much you entrench
yourself in the the common threads and
themes and pathways of everyday life.
You can jump right back into everyday
life and it doesn't last very long at all.
It's like this unbelievably
profound loving experience
where when it's happening
you,
you just feel overwhelmed first of all
by the truth in these entities that
you're encountering,
like how much they know about you,
like how much they know about who you
are and then the reality of like that
might not even be entities.
That might be you. It might be,
there are many use that encompass you
just like there's billions of eco lie
living in your gut.
There might be like various streams
of consciousness that are almost like
entities that exist in your
mind at any given time.
And you might be tapping into these and
turning these two 11 when you're on a
psychedelic,
it might be what the psychedelic is
really doing is introducing you the
potential of all the chemicals in your
mind if like optimized and it's one brief
burst of love and color and and,
and just geometric objects,
patterns, just representing
imagination at its
fullest, wild Liz, wildest,
most open flower.
And then that might be what's happening
when you're doing these things.
But regardless of what the actual, you
know, whether it's both or neither one,
the experiences themselves,
they changed the way you view the world
because you know that that's possible
now where you never knew
that that was possible.
You always felt like everything
in my life, you know, if, if I,
there was a scale from the worst
experiences I've ever had to,
the best experiences I've ever had.
Everything is sort of categorized.
So it was like, well, I know what
it's like to be scared. Well,
I know what it's like
to be in a car accident.
Well I know what it's
like to get a blow job.
I know what it's like to play
football. I know, you know,
you know you have all
these things and you say,
well I have a pretty good
idea of what life is.
And then you take three hits off
of this little vaporizer piping
and
he looks like crackling,
like burning plastic and you see this
chrysanthemum looking sort of like the
flower of life. You know, that flower of
life that's described like you, you a,
you see it in a lot of like
ancient Hindu art. Yeah. It's um,
it's a geometric pattern and um,
this flower of like you,
you see this flower of life,
Dmt, DMT. Oh yeah, for sure.
Almost everybody sees it or you see some
version of it, but the things that are,
you're seeing are happening so
fast. It's so diff in, they're all,
they're never the same thing.
Look,
you look at something and
they become something else.
Like instantly, constantly,
always changing. So you never
can really lock onto anything.
Everything is constantly moving
and morphing and looking at you.
And sometimes he's like gestures
and they're giving you the finger.
And then they disappeared,
which won behind these fractal
psych clones of geometric patterns.
It turn it into flowers
that turn into grass.
They turn it to babies coming out
of vaginas that turning to you,
they're turning to
handshakes and hugs and love.
And it is insane.
And it happens for about 15 minutes.
And when it's over, just knowing
that that can ever happen. Yeah,
it's just a matter of whether or not you
remember it. Well, they said also it,
it deals with depression.
It helps people with depression a lot.
And I think it's maybe that when
you're depressed for long enough,
you literally forget what
it feels like to feel good.
And I think that by giving you that
intense of a good positive experience,
it makes you go, Oh yeah, I'm supposed
to try. I'm supposed to, you know,
achieve that in whatever means I can, you
know, whether it's exercise or you know,
sex or whatever it is that you've just
stopped doing because you're so depressed,
it gives you the inspiration to try
to get back there. Yeah. And it also,
it's like a really intense form of love.
You know,
that's a weird way to describe it.
But the psychedelic experiences make
you feel loved, not to everybody.
And obviously, I mean, you
have to Redo it and do it.
Cause some people have mental issues.
Some people,
regular reality is slippery already.
Yeah.
They probably shouldn't be doing anything
right. But the people that do do it,
that are in a good place when they wind
up doing it oftentimes experiences like
profound sense of being loved.
How is it who
you do it with?
Very important set.
That's what it said in this is they
have people that walk you through it,
that are professionals at guiding you
through this kind of experience. Yeah.
That's super, super,
super important. Um, uh,
like a lot of those indigenous tribes
that do these a shamonic rituals,
they have like very like
rigid sort of ideas of like,
this is what we do. We sit down and
we're all going to like, you know,
we're all going to talk,
we're all going to drink this liquid
and this guy's gonna blow tobacco.
Small can play the drums.
And it's like slowly going to come on.
And it's like orchestrated.
Like they're,
they're setting this up and
this guy's going to sing.
And these guys will sing
these things called eco rows.
And these eco rows are these songs
that they sing that accompany the DMT
experience. So when you, when you smoked
DMT and you listen to these songs,
you see these things dancing, like as
they're like, I'll play it for you.
I've played it on the podcast whores.
Now,
if some of these native places to take
the, uh, others, a lot of parents,
there's a lot of them, dude,
oh, I cut into my phone.
There's a lot of these fucking tours.
They're doing it all over the place
and they're doing it. You know,
some of them it's not good to because
there's going to be people that are
capitalizing on those situations
where, you know, they,
they're just profiting.
Of course selling cell phones,
recording it. Yeah. Yeah.
I got it right there.
Oh, it plug it in. No, I'll just play
it on the, the, the thing here. But um,
I think that uh,
it should all be legal.
I think you should be able to do
whatever you want to do as far as a,
you want to,
if you want to run around and you want
to have a good time and do mushrooms or
drink whiskey or you know, whatever it
is, whether it will scare you used to be,
I'm sorry,
I was going to say,
but when you see these studies coming
out about the benefits of it, you just,
it makes you feel bad that all these
people were kept from that for so many
decades that like there's a lot of
people over from 1970 when they made
mushrooms illegal and Lsd and pretty
much everything to 2014 that's horrible.
That's 44 45 years.
While these really beneficial plants
have been illegal and for no fucking
reason, there's no reason that
makes any sense. Yeah. It's um,
man, it was, it was the Rockefeller
laws, right? Is that what the someone,
someone, I don't know who was responsible
for it all, but there was this sweeping
illegalization or sweeping
prohibition act that covered shit.
That's not even psychoactive.
There's like they just started marking
things illegal like a bunch of,
they didn't know exactly what was legal,
what wasn't legal,
but they lumped shit in like
everything that was scheduled one,
there's all nontoxic nonlethal
drugs that are scheduled. One,
like a giant percentage of them, which
is crazy because that just shows you,
this is a giant problem with the way
they're classifying drugs still in 2015
marijuana
federally is still a schedule.
Right, right, right. It's
fucking same as currently.
Ridiculous. Same as, yes. Same as cocaine.
Well cocaine and then heroin is scheduled
to write because I think they have
medicinal uses,
you know,
because opiates they use for painkillers
and there's medical cocaine. Oh,
I'm going to make sure that I'm right
about that cause I think they might've
changed.
Well that was the whole thing that uh,
black people feel like is that,
why is it the crack is schedule one
and cocaine because crack is for black
people and cocaine is for white
people as the, uh, the interpretation,
which is unbelievably racist.
Yeah, right. There's the issue.
It's heroin is one. It
used to be two, I believe.
Now it's one and coke is still too,
which is fucking bananas.
But look, psilocybin,
psilocybin and LSD and masculine.
Jesus,
is there a danger with the psilocybin?
No, you can't freak out on it. Yeah,
you could definitely freak out,
but you come back. Well, hopefully.
So there is a boss.
If you get that close to the abyss,
I mean the experiences that you have in
those things, if you have a weak heart,
it would probably be incredibly taxing
because a lot of people feel like they're
going to die.
They relive their entire life.
They look at themselves through this
really intense introspective vision that
freaks him out. You know, the, the,
the harsh introspective aspects of a
lot of these psychedelics really bother
some people. And if you're like
barely hanging on, if you're,
you're like on the
verge of a heart attack,
it could push you over the top Adderalls
schedule too. I used to take that shit.
Well that's legal now. All that shit they
could prescribe. Look at all that stuff.
There's a lot of stuff.
Yeah, there's a lot of drugs up there.
Look at all those drugs. They were,
they did a special on 60 minutes
last night about, um, that they,
they think they have a cure for the,
uh, uh, Ebola virus. It, I mean,
it worked.
They only had like seven batches of it
and they gave it to seven people and they
were all cured,
but that they,
Dave knew about it since the 70s,
but it's taken them this many years
to develop it because none of the
pharmaceutical companies can make a
profit off of it because the government
wasn't buying it. They weren't really,
you know, actively, you know, they,
they were looking for a cure,
but not really putting any
money behind it. And so,
but in order to make this cure that you
have to like take fucking thousands of
acres of this special
kind of tobacco and uh,
they have to soak it in this chemical
and all to come up with like a dozen
doses. Wow. It's crazy.
That's so strange when,
when you think about what these indigenous
tribes have been able to do with
these plants,
that's when it gets really strange.
Think about the fact that they've
figured out like a big percentage of the
pharmaceutical drugs that we use today.
Big percentage of them
come from like rainforests.
They find these plants how
they fund a lot of play.
Like they're constantly searching the
rain forest for different properties of
plants.
They think that one day they're gonna
come up with some plant that cures cancer.
They're going to find it in the Amazon.
They use him for a lot of different
purposes, which is, you know, weird.
These people figured out some of them on
their own, you know, the Iowasca thing,
they figured that thing on their own.
They figured out how to blend
plants and make a drug out of it.
Like they figured out how to
boil it and the whole thing.
They use a pot and they boil
it and it takes hours. Yeah.
They all figured out a way how to do this,
which is
just lot of trial and error.
A lot of stuff. They tried to,
somebody died from and they went
well, shut that one off. Like the,
the knowledge of what you can
eat and your neighborhood. Yeah.
Fucking super important. Yeah. The Wong,
the wrong little stripe
on a frog and you're dead.
You know the wrong little, you
know, little spot on a bug.
Yeah.
It can kill you.
Knowing how to plant the seeds in a way
that makes them grow correctly and had a
burn out the forest when
it needs to be burned out.
How's just in Yellowstone and there were
tears talking about how that, you know,
that the native people used to set fires,
they just,
they knew the schedule to rotate,
burning the FTF forest out so
that they can get super fires.
And I did the ashes.
Where was that? It? Yeah,
it was the sound that you listened
to and you're fucked up on DMT.
I wish I could describe what it looks
like, but you see the song when you're,
when you're under the aim
for once you actually see it,
like the song takes place
in three dimensional form
that gives a dancing thing.
It's not just a sound,
it becomes like a dancing object
to your mind transforms the trip.
And do people describe it similarly?
But they say, yeah, but it's,
it's hard to describe. So I think
they're saying something similar,
but there's no real words for it. Like
the, like everything that I've said,
the way I described it is really shitty.
It's like that you can't
really do it or you don't,
there's no context for the experience.
The experience is so weird.
There's no context for it.
So it doesn't,
it like if you described it and I
listened to your description, I'm like,
I guess we were in the same place, but
it's not like, yeah, there was this tree,
you remember there was a tree and had
a broken branch and it laid over it.
Oh yeah, I remember that. It was
right near the fountain. Yes.
And it's not like that. Like you would be
describing it to me. I'd be like, okay,
maybe complex geometric patterns
floating in and out of existence.
Constantly morphing in front of you.
It's all love and understand. I guess.
I guess you were at the same spot,
you know, is there a seven 11?
What did smell like? It smell
like Bumpus yes. Bump this.
Oh we were in the same spot. Yeah.
You know, you could talk about like,
oh I went to the ski lodge. You know, you
walk in, there's a big moose in the wall.
Oh yeah. Yeah. I've been out of spot.
You say, you know all we did LSD.
What was it like?
Oh it's just,
I spend an hour staring
in the mirror and uh,
I watched my entire life from birth
to that moment on fast forward. Yeah.
Okay.
That's it. Cause you're not going to
jot it down while you're doing it.
It'd be great if they come
up to technology where they
can videotape what you're
imagination is going through while
you're tripping on something.
And then show it and major
theaters around the country.
That's one of the things that
someone in mind, they've been,
Mckenna again was speculating that
one of the best ways to deliver,
um,
a psychedelic trip to someone was with
virtual reality and figuring out a way
through like CGI imagery to reproduce
the effects of the trip. Like the,
the reproduce what you're saying.
Yeah.
If they could get the technology
to that point where they could,
someone could go to trip,
you know,
do mushrooms or do DMT trip and then
figure out a way to reproduce that.
Then you would take the drugs out.
Somebody could just watch the
trip and feel the trip. Yeah.
Yeah. That it could be possible that
it could be done that way. He was,
it was totally believing it can be done
that way because there's people that
said they could do it with yoga man.
There's people that say they can have
full blown psychedelic experiences.
She'll loosen nations,
visuals,
transport it to the center of the
universe and dancing with angels the whole
deal.
And they do it all through yoga.
Yeah. Yeah. I know with meditation they,
certain levels you can get to. I mean,
I do very basic TM.
I've been doing it for like six months,
but I do it twice a day.
Yeah. What made you start? Um,
everybody I've talked to that had done
it had a profound experience with it.
You know, their lives are better. You
know, you guys like, you know, Seinfeld,
it's done it forever. And um, a lot
of comics that, uh, that I like,
we're doing it. What do
you do? It's really simple.
It's a very unguided meditation. You
just kind of sit in a comfortable place.
They give you a mantra that you do
and you're not tied to the match.
You're not like repeating it over and over
again. And that's all you think about.
It's more of like, it
kind of leads you, um,
it's sort of the way they describe it as.
It's almost like it's off in the distance
and you can hear it, but you're not,
it's not your whole focus. And then your
brain can go wherever it's going to go.
You can go into little daydreams and
then you can gently notice that and pull
yourself back to the mantra and do that.
And you just let yourself go with it.
And it's very nonjudgmental.
You don't ever judge where your mind went.
You don't snap yourself self back to
it. And then, uh, and then it ends,
it feels like it feels like five,
10 minutes and 20 minutes ends.
I set my alarm and then you just feel
totally rested and centered and stress is
gone.
And like my baseline of depression has
been so much higher since I started.
You mean the baseline?
Meaning like,
like I get depression
and this helped me a lot.
Oh, so you're not saying let
like the Depression is higher
now? I would say that the
bad, the bad part of the
depression, the level is higher.
Right.
Um, that's, that's really fascinating. And
what is the mantra? Like, what'd you say?
Well, they give each person a different
one. I, I'm, there's x number of mantras.
I don't know how many there are, but
they assigned them to you. Like what?
Give me an example of what a macho
like ohm is like the classic mantra.
So it doesn't have to be a word.
It could be like, oh, it's a sound.
It's always a song. Yeah. So He'd
just sit there and make the Sanskrit.
So it's different.
Sanskrit sounds
TM is t like transcendental meditation
is all Sanskrit. Right? Wow.
And so just sitting there going home.
Well we know it's all,
you don't say it,
you don't verbalize it in your
mind and your mind, you do it.
But it does have a resonant sound because
they see even mentally there's some
kind of reverberation that goes on.
So this just doing this has raised like
whatever depression that you do get,
it takes a longer time to come
on and it's, it's less impact.
It doesn't stay, it doesn't stay.
And I don't go down as far as I did.
And that's probably the chief reason I
started is that I'd read a lot about it
and it said that that's one
of the main things, you know,
anxiety and depression can be
tied hand in hand. I don't expect,
I don't think I experience
anxiety as much as just, you know,
my family has depression. My, you
know, everybody in my family's got it.
And it's just something that, you
know, you can, you can medicate it,
you can exercise it out or you can,
you know,
there's a lot of different
ways to go at it.
That's a weird way,
um,
that we have to regulate the
minds like to manage the mind,
but just taking a thing like a,
a sound and rolling it over in your
mind over and over and over again.
And it's almost like a cycle,
like a cleaning cycle.
Yeah.
It's like stopping the cycle at stopping
the cycle of thoughts that are nonstop
in your mind. It gives you a break. It's
almost like, it's like doing a cleanse.
It gives your stomach and you're
calling it a chance to clean itself.
So twice a day you're stopping that site.
And that's the thing that I find with
it is that I get bored of the cycle.
Like if I'm going through my day,
I'm having a cycle of
thoughts like anybody does.
And you don't notice that it's a cycle
until you stop and it's all that's in
your mind and then you go, oh,
you're fucking, that's boring.
We've already thought that you
kind of let it go and it goes away.
That's that. I liked that idea
of a cleaning cycle like you,
you introduced like a cleaning agent for
20 minutes and you a nip all the buds
and parcel the problems and settle
it all down. That make sense?
Because me and my worst in my life,
the one I've felt most out of control
and my wife are doing the wrong shit or
you know least in control of my emotions.
I've always felt like I was on like too
much momentum. Like I couldn't stop.
Like I was like the,
the momentum of all my past acts was like
overwhelming me and I was just running
to keep from getting run over and like
something like TM or for me it became a
martial arts and then later the tank,
the tank helps a lot to just get into
that space where you just let it all go.
And once you do let it all go,
you could start fresh. Right.
But when you don't get
a chance to do that,
it seems like you're constantly
dealing with this phone.
What's connected to that thing
that you got to take care of you.
You didn't clean out that thing and
fucking this guy wants to meet you because
you're supposed to do that
thing and it's all done.
It all builds up to
the point where you're,
the anxiety is oftentimes just the data,
the sheer data that you're
dealing with every day in life.
Whether it's emotional shit,
whether it's memory shit, we,
it's work related shit or family
related shit. It's like fuck.
And your thoughts all go to, they all
go back to, I mean not to be Friday in,
cause I'm, I, I'm not
Freudian, but there are,
there are aberrations in your thoughts
in terms of how we perceive ourselves and
what external events, how we identify
ourselves based on external events. Like,
I didn't get this job.
That means, well you can,
you can control what that means
is ways of having, you know,
cognitive changes where you stop yourself
from thinking what you thought from
being a child and having a father that
beat you or even something more subtle,
you know,
things that affected over time,
the way you connected external events
to how you felt about yourself.
And you can go in and you can just
buy by repeating, you know, no,
that doesn't mean that, you
know, that just means that this,
this happened like power of now. It's
like you don't, you don't, uh, you know,
a thought is not a reality.
It's just something that is flowing
through you and you can notice it and you
can comment on it without internalizing
it and going for the full ride.
They say that's one of the things that
people have the hardest time with when it
comes to, uh, suffers.
People that are trying to overcome the
abusive they have when their a childhood
that when they were in childhood because
that abuse oftentimes like defines them.
They feel like they're a shitty
person for have been being abused.
You're damaged because you've been abused
and you'd just sort of define yourself
by this abuse that you've suffered.
Yeah.
Where you can't look at the
bright side of things like you,
you look like it's always bad.
Things are always going to happen to you.
It's like if you've defined yourself in
some way because of the abusive side.
Oh, you even caused the abuse because
you're bad, right? Yeah. You could have,
there was a reason why I was beat.
It's my fault.
So then when anything
bad happens in your life,
you go back to thinking you caused it.
It makes you think if this psychedelic
Lez legislation of the 1970s if it never
had been passed and if these
35 years since that happened,
if people had been allowed to explore
these things and come to these conclusions
and try to figure out like what,
what are,
what are the beneficial aspects of the
way we behave and the way we think and
the way we sort of qualify
and quantify life's meaning,
whether it's financial or whether
it's family, like what did what, what,
what's really smart about this and how
much more could we have done if people
were doing mushrooms,
doing acid.
So much more thinking would have taken
place on these really people could say
they're frivolous, there's just, these are
distractions, but they're not, you know,
these are,
these are these ideas and concepts that
you develop when you're either doing
psychedelics or meditating,
anything where you're involved in sort
of an active assessment and resetting of
your consciousness, whether
it's yoga, meditation,
whatever the fuck it is, tanks,
size,
isolation tanks.
We will you doing is you're allowing
yourself time to reflect on what you're
doing and whether or not it's
beneficial and what can be changed.
And if you don't have
that reflection time,
you oftentimes don't change unless you
fall completely apart and you're forced
to change. Yeah. That happens.
A lot of people they have,
that's what they always say about
drug addicts. They have to hit rock.
I forgot to hit bottom mean
anything gambling, you know,
and you were always shocked by
people's bottoms. Like, you know,
you look at somebody who just
keeps fucking up like, you know,
Brittany Spears when she was really
going down the rails, it was like,
hasn't she hit bottom yet?
No, not even close. Yeah.
And then there's other people like me,
I had a pretty shallow bottom.
I quit drinking when I was
like, I dunno, 24. And uh,
I started drinking when I was
probably 12. So I drank for, you know,
a decent period of time, but like I
wasn't blowing guys for a sandwich.
I was just feeling like it
was controlling my life.
I was feeling like this is something
I'm going to when I'm feeling sad or I'm
going to when I'm feeling stressed or
would a was definitely the relationship to
alcohol I had was bad cause my
father was an alcoholic, you know,
he died at 51 and so I just knew I
didn't want to go down that path.
So I had what you'd call a shallow bottom.
But you know,
just to see other people where it
just can get, it can get so extreme.
But that's the only time you
really change. And so for me,
I think changing it with a shallow
bottom meant that there was so much more
baggage that went with it. You know, that,
that I was bottoming out with feeling
that I was dependent on something and I
wasn't,
I couldn't be myself fully because there
was a part of my psyche that was locked
up in this thing and that was enough
for me to go, I got to change.
I don't want to live my life like that.
You did a young man,
I remember when you did it.
I remember it because I
remember you were almost like,
like you had remorse, you
know, that you had to do this.
Like I felt like there was
almost a sadness about you,
about the having it like,
fuck yeah, I can't do this. I just can't
do it. I'm sorry I'm going to miss it.
But it's over. Yeah. And you
just, you just stopped. You know,
you didn't have to fucking join a what?
All these other comics.
There's a million comics that were in a,
and they were all like,
they had this like real weird preachy
thing about them too. They look at,
you drink in the chick there had,
they were really annoying. You know,
you didn't do that. He just
stopped drinking. You stopped.
Yeah. And it's, it's,
it's funny because Boston Aa in Boston
is a very intense thing because the city
with the same power they drank
with, they got sober with, you know,
they would rage with sobriety. Yeah.
And you know, and look, God bless him,
the people that used it and it
worked for them, that's fantastic.
But for some of them it became
like two meetings day and you know,
you've got three sponsors and you, and
it's like, you know, that's great, but uh,
you know, move, move
along a little bit here. You get a
little caught up in this thing. Well,
it becomes their culture. Yeah.
The culture of sober people. Yeah.
That's a big culture. A strong
culture. Yeah. And if sy, again,
like for some people it's life or death.
It literally is,
those are the stakes with
the meetings. Oh yeah, man.
And also it's a good launching
pad for a lot of comics. Oh yeah.
Get up and do those meetings.
He tells hilarious stories,
wicking up shit face stuffed into
a laundry machine and you know,
they have these ridiculous shit,
their pants stories as crowd of all time.
They're all sober, they're jacked
up on coffee. They love it.
And they know what the fuck you're
talking about. Yeah. You know,
they're having a good time. I remember
going to some, they was just saying,
I think it was called like Miskiw par.
I don't know why I remember that.
But it was in Worcester and the Aa
community gets together and they do these
conventions where they had like,
you know,
a thousand people coming from all over
New England staying in his hotel and just
having meetings.
You know,
the 9:00 AM there's a 1212 o'clock step
meeting and they'd all go and apparently
everybody's fucking everybody because
they got all this energy to channel and
burn off and so it was just hypersexual
obviously very social. I mean,
what's more social then you sit down in
a meeting and the person next to you go,
how you doing? 12 years
sober. Hey, are you doing, I'm
great. 10 years. Bula he did.
Somebody does a motivational
talk. You clap, you laugh,
everybody has a coffee halfway through.
What a fucking great way to meet people
and now you're just like you normally
you would go get drunk and pass out and
instead you're awake and jacked up on
coffee and you all have something in
common. Yeah. Talk about your sobriety,
where you're fuck
drunk with your cock. People
love little groups. Yeah.
Part of a nice little group that everybody
else is trying to run marathons are
marathon runners group together? Yeah.
Oh, we're all owners of Dotson's.
We're going to get our dots. It's all a
little doggies. Look, your bull Godson,
they meant Dotson's cause it's fairly
group people that own dogs or those old to
40 zs. That shit. Yup. I was
a little Japanese sports cars.
Those were fucking bad ass. But
those little groups of people, man,
no matter what it is, they
just, people love being dug by.
You ever go with dog park? But he's
shitting me. Same people every day.
And you know what they talk
about why they hang out? Dogs.
That's all they talk about. Oh,
I got a Corgi. Mine's half Corgi.
Half Poodle. So it's a cook.
She is such a Pomeranian.
Let me tell you,
she's such a Pomeranian.
Sometimes she looks in the mirror and
she thinks this is another Pomeranian she
barks. It's adorable. But
she's protective. I mean
you look at the size of her,
you wouldn't think she protects. Oh,
she becomes an animal, becomes a bear.
You'd be able to hear that. Did you ever
see best in show? Oh yeah. That was great.
Amazing. It was awesome. Nailed it.
They nailed that culture and they
didn't know a subtle enough way,
so it was just ridiculous enough where
you want that would never happen like you
go. That could fucking totally,
yeah. Yeah. Those people,
that people that are really
in then no matter what
it is, it's always funny.
Yeah. I mean even the US,
like the way we talk about comedy,
I'm sure people think
it's hilarious. Yeah. You got
to have something because,
and I think as you get older, the
more you want, cause I think you,
you don't realize when you're young and
having a shared history about something
is going to be so important than
the nostalgia of it. They, the,
the self identity of it. And so as you
get older all sudden, like you got guys,
now they're, you know, just rejoicing
in the fact that they're geeks,
that they all watched star wars when
they were kids and now they get together
and they talk about it. When they
were watching star wars as a kid,
they felt like a fucking gig and they
weren't necessarily sharing it with
anybody.
They were quietly watching it again and
again and then crying in their father's
basement. You know, there wasn't
like a solidarity about it.
No. And you remember when, um, like
comic books used to be like for losers?
Yeah. Like when I got rid of my comic
books, I'm over the girls. Danny was like,
good, why do you need, um, why'd you
have, I'm still here 21. I'm like,
I only got rid of him cause I'm fucking
broke. I sold them to eat, I missed them,
I missed all of them.
I collect those for a long fucking time
and I sold them for like no money and I
remember what it was, but I
had like these boxes, you know,
I had like three or four boxes fill with
comics that I'd collected from the time
I was like 15, no Shim. It
probably even the earlier,
no way earlier because I had a couple of
them from the time I was like 12 that I,
I really started collecting when I
moved to Boston. But before that,
I guess I had someone San Francisco too,
but the point being I'd have,
I'd have him for a good chunk of my life
and I would open the plastic bags and
pull out the fucking hulk and we like
different episodes that were like
valuable. This one's worth
five bucks. Right? You know,
like old x men and punishers
and I love those fucking things.
But you were taught that
you were like a loser,
like you're clinging on to
some childhood stupidity.
Now they have comic con and a million
people fly from all over the country to
hang out in San Diego and they
all wear costumes and shit.
I noticed those magazines would
be worth a lot of money right now,
probably high it.
I had all the mad magazine starting in
1975 I had a subscription all the way
through pro. I'm probably like three,
four, five years and I had them all.
And then my mom just tossed
mall out while I was in college,
cleaned out the attic.
Gotcha.
Devastating. Cause it's like you, I
used to actually go back and read them.
I thought they were hilarious.
Those old mad magazines were fucking
brilliant. Yeah, those were good.
My parents bought those when
I was a little kid. I used
to read them in a toilet.
They used to, you know what else they had?
Our crumb, my Stepdad was into our crop.
Oh Shit. Yeah. You ever
read yes. Comics. Yeah.
I've read that in the fabulous freak
brothers. My stepdad's a hippie and uh,
when I was like seven,
eight years old when we all started
living together because it was like seven,
uh, I got introduced to this
weird kind of comic books.
They would leave in the bathroom,
the fabulous freak brothers and
the San Francisco. Yeah. Yeah.
That's what I was living in San Francisco
from like seven to 11. No, but I mean,
I think the artists there that
San Francisco, right? Was He
out right? Yeah. Archroma San
Francisco. That a documentary.
Yeah. Yeah. Really cool.
He was a weird model. Still is
a weird motherfucker. Yeah. Wow.
He lives in France and he moved to
Paris or something, but as images,
like he would draw these women with these
ridiculous enormous acids and like men
would be riding them and shit.
It was just very strange fetish and
like seeing that as like a little boy.
I remember thinking like, why,
who is this weird fucking kind?
Why is he drawing these
people like this? Yeah. Yeah.
The fabulous freak brothers was a big one.
Like there's all that,
there were a lot of like
hippie comic strips,
all black and white comic books that
were sort of designed for adults.
It was very strange stuff. He, yeah,
it was very, uh, it was very, like,
you could call it perverted, but it was
actually just really raw. It's like,
it was like, it wasn't dirty.
It was just graphic. Yeah.
It was just like, and, and resonated.
It seemed kind of honest like watching
this weird fucking guy with glasses are
crumb like his version of himself that
would do like riding on top of these
women that with z enormous asses and
high heels and they, it was very strange,
but you could tell like for him
this is like this wild fantasy.
I got to see that movie again. It was
really good shit insight into, you know,
a really extremely creative artists
and all that weird demons that,
that flow through his brain that may
come or, or angels, whatever it is,
make him create his very strange art.
Trying to think if there's anything
like that today. I mean there's,
there's all this cartoon is like adult
swim kind of cartoons that are a little
offbeat, but they're nowhere
near as Ra's this stuff.
And I think that if you did
it today, you'd be accused
of being massaged. Oh yeah,
no, his stuff was definitely had reached,
you know, a lot of racist overtones,
but it was, that's what I mean by it
was raw. It was honest. It was like, no,
this is how this guy thinks he's writing.
There's something that you could
appreciate about this guy is unadulterated
putting his thoughts on, on paper. Yeah.
Let's Google our Crum racism
and then look at this. Bam.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
I mean he's doing total blackface
images like Jesus Christ,
but he was like a hero of the
counter culture at the time. Oh yeah.
Like he did a lot of like,
oh my God, look at this one.
Shit. I mean, these are really
fucking racist man. Holy Shit.
But they had a sense of humor
to them that you had to be,
you had to be in on the joke. I guess if
you just looked at it from the outside,
he would just be like, what the
fuck? Kind of hate mail is this. Wow,
this is weird.
This is weird to see.
I had forgotten how racist some of the
shit was and how weird some of it was.
Like there's him and this woman
with these enormous horse like legs,
like there was so exaggerated
the size of their asses and legs.
He was the first big ass
guy way before j Lo way before any,
any of these people. He was
like the first, he was like
really into giant asses,
but he also had like really cool
like political shit, you know?
He had like, here's one of him
riding a woman. Look through that.
How strange that at the legs? Yeah. Yeah.
He would ride these women that
were in cutoff jeans. Jesus Christ.
This is a famous one.
The True Amazon low center of
gravity wide hips strong back.
He like had these weird
fetishes about thick,
powerful women that he would ride.
What did we to sex life wise you think
he was, he must've been paid prostitutes.
Uh Damn. Well who knows? I wonder if
tell us he was to get them
on your podcast. Yeah,
I bet he doesn't do podcasts.
I mean,
I don't know where even is. I think he is
in France or you think he's on Twitter?
I'm going to say no.
I'm going to say that if you got
in touch with him and you said,
I'll come to you. I want to
talk to you. I'm a big fan.
He wouldn't give a shit if
it was a podcast, whatever.
I bet you that guy would sit down with
you. Really? Yeah. That's my guess.
I would say just the opposite.
I'd say he's just some fucking
weird guy likes to hide from people,
but I might be wrong. I mean
one way, just signed down.
I think you'd be kind of introverted.
Some of it is her drawing a blank with
Robert Crumb's, a guardian article.
Some of his work is pretty striking,
but he's hardly worthy of his current
status is God of the literary underground.
Wow. Is it? People are upset.
I wrote, my sister used to work
at an art gallery in New York,
the Alexander Gallery,
and they had an art crime exhibit and
I remember asking her and she said, no,
he didn't come. He was a huge
like month long exhibit. Yeah.
He probably doesn't want to deal with
all the weirdness that he must get from
these kind of strange images.
If you're,
most of the images are like women
with big giant acids and huge legs,
tree trunk legs,
and a lot of them have dudes riding these
women like people would get upset at
you. Those would be uncomfortable
moments by you making me look at this.
What is this? What is the obsession
with women with giant ankles?
I think they put him, I think they
used to put them in pen house.
Really? I think so. Hmm.
This is really interesting. Keep on
trucking. That was his shit. Yeah.
Yeah.
I mean he was like a part of that weird
hippie sub culture of like the late
sixties and the 70s. It's a
strange time to be alive, man.
These are the first people
that were really kind of, uh,
experimenting with Lsd and
cannabis was like, oh my God,
some of these are so racist. I can't
even look at them anymore. I am upset.
Craig foot sevens. I literally can't look
at them. I'm looking at the penthouse.
Yeah. One I would have around, uh,
the house with the kids. Well, I think
people now they look at the content of it,
that kind of what that guardian article
was about. They're like, Hey, yeah,
this guy was kind of fucked up.
Like why are we making them
out to be this amazing artist?
But it is amazing art because
it does something to you.
It gives you this reaction, you know,
it's, is it necessarily all good now?
But it's, it's art. Like this is a very,
this is a very unique
individual viewpoint.
Like this is this guy's
viewpoint and that's, that is
art. You might not like it,
you might be weirded out by it,
but it takes weird people to
make shit that strikes you.
And the way that this
guy's work strikes people.
Well, arts turned into something that
people are supposed to agree with and,
and you know, and it's supposed to not
offend anybody and that's the opposite.
Art's supposed to shake it up.
It's supposed to challenge, I mean,
you think about punk rock and now it's
almost like folksy when you think about
old punk rock.
Yeah,
they have a Mohawk and they peer
stuff and they jump up and down.
But when it came out, it was
anarchy. It was at a time, you know,
when it came out in London, it
was about, you know, there were,
there were strikes going on at the time
and there was riots going on in the
street and you know,
punk rock represented something that was
really fucking scary to the status quo.
Yeah.
It wasn't just your mom won't buy you a
car and now they called Green Day punk
rock. It's like, are
you fucking kidding me?
When Green Day was shitting on Justin
Bieber, we're not fucking Justin Bieber.
It was like,
Oh God.
Oh, did they say if you have to
say that you're not punk rock?
Yeah. I mean, there was something where
they're getting them off stage early.
Do remember that Jamie? Yeah.
He freaked out and he said,
we're not fucking Justin Bieber.
I think he probably apologized to
Justin Bieber after that. Yeah.
I, no offense, like green day's a
great band, but they're not punk rock.
Yeah, they're okay. They're an okay
pop band pop band. Yeah. It's not,
it's not my style, but they
have some songs that I like.
Sure. Yeah. If I hear them,
I think they're enjoyable.
Right.
But it's not like this is like our chrome
was like really essentially like punk
rock comic books. He, a lot of
the racist stuff that he did,
he wasn't necessarily being racist as
he was highlighting like how a racist
would view something and doing
it in a very shocking way.
Like I don't think there can be a,
I don't think I've ever read anything.
I might be wrong,
but I don't think I've read it.
Ever read anything that indicated
that he was actually racist?
No. No, I don't think so. I think he
was actually a big liberal. I think,
you know he lived in San
Francisco, I believe. Yeah.
But I think it was a lot to do with just
being a boy expressing himself. He was,
he kind of had arrested development and
he was in the same way that when I was
12 years old,
the pictures that I would make would
probably be in the wheelhouse of the shit
that he was making. He just made it much
better. And he did it as a man, but to,
but to put big pussy lips and nipples
that are, you know, four inches long.
Like that's what you used to write. He's,
I think he was just expressing that.
Yeah. Well also I guess
what he was doing, um,
with a lot of his images there,
they were racist pop culture images from
the 1940s so he was reviving this very
type of imagery
that was really racist.
And so the real question,
the argument in this article on a hood,
you tell it,
who did,
who did utilitarian.com um,
the argument was whether or not it
was ironic and or parody and like,
whether it's enough to absolve
him of doing, you know,
these images of re reenacting
them or recreating them.
Hmm.
It's interesting.
It's interesting because it's kind of,
it's revealing like a very specific style
of racist cartoons that they used to
do. And in doing so, he's like, you know,
he's highlighting it is showing you like,
hey, like this is, if you're normal
and if you're a reasonable person who,
who's not racist, you're not going to
get racist feelings from looking at this.
What you're going to do is
you're going to say, wow,
this was like how people who are racist
think it's not gonna make you raise.
You look at like a, you know, chaplain was
doing Hitler, you know, f troop. You know,
you're, you're depicting
the Holocaust. Yeah.
In a way that brings some humor to it
and brings a different angle to it now.
And he brought, he had
humor in his pictures. Yeah.
You don't become racist by
looking at racist shit. Right.
The idea is effecting developmenting,
developing minds,
developing personalities,
children, adolescents,
like showing them racist stuff and let
him know it's okay that can plant racist
seeds. But once you're an
adult, like no one's gonna,
no one's gonna like make you racist.
Like if you're Greg Fitzsimmons
in 2015 and you see some,
some fucking ridiculous racist,
racist imagery,
you're not going to automatically
become racist. Right.
So the real concern is like,
are we protecting people from these hat
tire images because we're worried about
the impact of them or
because it's offensive,
it's offensive to some people and it's
only going to be offensive to some people
until things even out. Like
if you do ridiculous racist
versions of white people,
I think it's hilarious. And
I'm white. You know why?
Because white people were ahead of the
curve and if it evens out to the point
where black people and white people and
Chinese people and everybody on such a
fucking even ground and that
racism is completely preposterous,
but the racial differences
of each nationality is
allowed to be highlighted in
brutal fashion and nobody cares.
Yeah.
Like if you like Richard
Pryor sold to white people,
the idea of mocking white people,
hey there fella.
You know the white motherfuckers at work
would, you know, like, and we laughed.
Your Mama Bitch, my mom was a
great old cow. Yeah. You know,
like you could white people never got
offended by that. Oh, never. Never.
It's like awe.
Very cute.
But there's a lot of jokes like you're
not even allowed to joke about certain
people on stage,
like at all.
Like any joke about them is racist,
this is racist or
homophobic or it's whatever,
fill in the blank and that's ridiculous.
Like that's ridiculous.
Like the joke about Rosa parks
and they got a lot of shit about
it. Someone a joke, whatever it was.
Yeah. They something like he was,
she was just to tie,
she was too lazy to move to the back of
the bus or something like that and it
was like a fucking blew up.
It was a black comic. Hmm.
I don't know if it's cat willy. Nah,
it wasn't Katt Williams, but it's a,
would it be,
what do you think about Leslie Jones?
What's he's doing fucking great.
She's just a,
she's going to be in the new
Ghostbusters movie. Who's Leslie Jones?
You know her from the comment? Oh, you
know what? She probably left the Commie.
Still refer you came back. She's black
chick. She's tall. She opened for a cat.
Williams for you?
She's a killer. Okay. I
don't know her. She's really,
I've seen her on TV one.
She's,
she's a big funny,
great check and she's a,
she struggled for fucking 1520
years doing standup, I dunno.
15 years maybe. Good for
her. And then she got,
she got an a on SNL and she's just
blowing up on SNL and that's just got
Ghostbusters.
Wow. Ghostbusters with all
checks. Is that what it is? Yes.
Oh, cast. Okay, good luck with
that. Yeah, that's going to be a
different angle on that new new
remakes of movies. There's just,
it's hard to get behind these remakes
of movies. It's like, you know,
and we're going to flip the switch.
We're going to do Cagney and Lacey with
gay men. Yeah, yeah. We're going to do,
you know,
not Cagney and Lacey.
What was the one where they went
off the fucking dumb and Louise,
they read the film and
Louise, the gay man. No, no.
He did best in guys holding hands,
driving off the cliff and it
driving across the country,
just blowing guys in rest areas,
just blowing guys and shooting women,
women that don't want it to be gay.
That gone down.
And then they're running shoes. No,
let her run first because it wasn't,
wasn't telling the Louise like some
guy did something horrible to them.
The way that guy was Brad Pitt.
Oh Shit. That's right. Right.
That's when it was a young, sexy. Aw, God
dammit. He was good looking man, man. Oh,
the tits on him. That was perfect.
That was a great movie though.
That was like the first chick buddy movie
where the chicks were gangster. Right.
You know,
this was a few of those moments where the
chicks were like super fucking bad ass
in a believable way.
One of the best ones was pulp fiction,
pulp fiction and kill
bill was just as bad ass.
Or how about this? Maybe even better.
What was the, not, not pulp fiction.
What was the one with Kush
Christian Slater that, uh,
turns turn around aunts
dude. Yeah, she was great.
Come on man. What's her
name? Patricia or cat.
Is it Patricia Arquette or the other one?
Well,
there was two movies that were similar.
There was patty Arquette did one. Uh,
and then, uh, what's her name? There's
a David Arquette. Patricia Arquette.
It was a trip. She was the
one in true romance. Yeah.
When was at Gamble Fini
and her have that fucking crazy fight
scene or was it John Madsen? Who Was it?
Who else is in it is Gandolfini in it.
That's all it says for the cast.
Dennis Hopper. But who uh, no,
there was somebody that got in that,
that it was getting a Fini. Yeah. Again,
the Fini beats the shit out of her and
she eventually kills him at the end and
it was just so wa cause
it was like believable.
She was talking shit while I was
beating the fuck out of her and then she
eventually kills him and it's just so
wild and primal when she does and she's
all fucked up and beaten up.
Like you really felt like she had
been in a fight and just killed this.
Fuck did, it wasn't like a Charlie's
angels type thing. It was so real.
It was so real bozo with Juliette Lewis,
natural born killers that was pretty
natural born killers was amazing. Yeah.
I want to get her in here, man.
We, she said she would do it too.
She said she would do the podcast.
She's a comedy Fan, right?
She didn't have a lot of comics.
She's a fascinating person
and she believes that like
Tom Cruise is a victim of
like propaganda when it comes to
like anti Scientology propaganda.
I would love to hear someone who's like
a happy scientist. She's a psychologist.
Hardcore. Wow. Unless she
doesn't want to talk about that.
Do you had at Scientologists?
Not before. No. No.
It's curious how much they
want to talk about it.
I just have one neighbor couldn't shut
the fuck up about it. Right. He loved it.
He was telling me about how his
wife was going. Clear. Yeah.
She was spending 50 grand turned clear,
50 grand.
When you know what
happens when you're clear,
you're no longer negatively affected
by outside influence. Gregory.
That's amazing. It's incredible.
Fixes everything. 50 50 just pay up.
Probably going to be some math outside
influences cause you're going to be broke.
You Go,
this guy wanted to buy a piece of property
and he couldn't buy it because his
wife was going clear.
I'm not kidding.
He was talking about this piece of
property. He wanted to, you know,
it was like adjacent to his,
his property and was thinking about buying
it but he couldn't afford it because
it's trying to get you to a
meeting. Uh, no. Nope, nope, nope.
Explained it to me.
Tell me how much it benefited him but
it wasn't proselytizing. Thank goodness.
Wow. That would have been ugly.
That would be Dang Dong, Mr Ogun.
Oh you're in there.
It's me happiness.
Your happiness awaits its clarity.
Its at the door. It's your choice.
Go with clarity or with none.
The coast is clear Gel.
Don't they like to use
like acronyms they have to,
they use abbreviations or whatever it
is for like all these different types of
people.
Suppressive people.
They have all these different like things
that they call upon when they define
like various aspects.
Negative people that you're encountering
in your life that disbelieved the
tenants of Scientology. Yeah.
There's like orgs, orbs, something.
I read a book about a written by the
niece of the guy who is the head of
Scientology. She broke out. She
talked about being a child slave.
Like they literally separated her
and me while her uncle is the head of
Scientology. So she had juice,
still took her away from
her parents and senator when all child
colony where she was raised and then
brought to Hollywood. So to
live, they kept moving around.
Every time she gets settled in,
they just uproot her,
separated from her brother
centered a fucking Florida,
Sandra de la,
the desert.
And she talked about how the kids built
the entire colony that they lived in.
They did all the, they would just
put them out to work every day.
They work like eight hours just weeding
and gardening and building fences and
all this crazy shit. And they would
get schooled for like two hours a day.
And it was mostly Scientology schooling.
What's the name of the book? Uh,
raised by you remember the woman?
Hmm. I get the worst fucking memory. I
can look it up, Jamie. You'll find it.
He'll fire and it's, I got to
read that and it just tracks
how, you know, then she,
they,
they don't want you to procreate because
babies are a burden on the church.
They want you to work. They want to create
worker bees and they discourage the,
you know, how much does someone like
Tom Cruise have to pay? They pay 10%.
I think it's tithing. Yeah. It's
probably like a 10% tithe Straw.
And they got some videotapes. If you
don't want to pay or, you know, the,
they make it worth your while
to pay the benefit. You, they,
they throw rose petals wherever that guy
walks and this and they're a publicity
firm. They, they, they, whatever
you want changed about your, uh, uh,
p is this the book beyond
belief? Yeah, that's it.
My secret life inside Scientology and my
heroine escape by Jenna Miscavige. Yes.
Miscavige and Miscavige is the name of
the guy who's the head of Scientology.
Wow. Yeah, that's crazy. I mean,
it's really crazy that she wrote it
because she was, when she left the church,
she was threatened by, I mean,
this is her fucking family.
And they would come down and like
threatened her, threatened her, uh,
her brother who was still inside
the church, threatened her mother.
They don't fuck around.
Yeah.
You could've been born there, you know,
I could have been born there and that's,
that's the luck of the draw. I was
born Catholic. It's not, uh, as was,
I could have been, could have been better.
Did you do Catholic school? Oh yeah. No,
no. I did Catholic school on
Wednesdays and then church on Sundays.
I did one whole year. Catholic school.
What grade first. Oh, that's not too bad.
They smack you around a little bit. Scared
me. Yeah. Maybe hit me very gently. Hmm.
Nothing serious.
Nobody beat me up,
but scared the fucking shit out of me
and just saw a row because the walls were
soaked with sorrow.
Yeah. Awful, awful place.
Who's the bloody guy hanging on
the wall? That's the guy that, uh,
you're supposed to be more like, oh, I
should end up like him. And you're good
if you're lucky. We're out
of time. Greg Fitzsimmons uh,
did you read off all your dates? I
did. Were coming up in Denver, Addison,
wherever you go to site again,
fits dog.com
and in the podcast fits dog
radio twice a week tonight.
Greg Fitzsimmons is also going to
be at the Ice House in Pasadena.
Probably sold out.
It was very close earlier this morning.
So most likely it's going to be fun to
Shit Dunkin and Tony Hinchcliffe. No.
And uh, Ian Edwards. Jesus Christ. And
that's how a show. Yeah. Tony Clifton,
Tony Hinchcliffe, Dunkin, Ian
and Greg. God Damn son and me.
So, uh, we'll see you dirty fox
tonight. Greg fits, fits dog.com.
What is it fits dog.com
[inaudible] dot com uh,
Greg Fitz show on Twitter and a,
that's it. Ladies and gentlemen,
we'll see you next week. Until then. Enjoy
big kiss. Be Nice to each other. Bye.
Okay.
Hm.