Uh, hey fucking freaks. What's happening?
I should probably tweet.
I fucked up.
I forgot to tweet this so I'll tweet while
I'm doing it. I like how you did that.
I like how your man,
we got to get better shit at my podcast.
What do you mean what
you guys get the screens?
Anything that you're talking about?
Jamie's really quick, man. He's on it.
Like anything that you're talking about.
He's already got some visuals
and some cutaways. That's huge.
See that quick?
God Damn,
that's an ambulance and serious
production value right there to have.
If you want to talk some shit, I don't
have that. That's what socks. I do not.
I we can hook you up. Yeah, yeah. You know
what? I need to step it up. We'll make it,
we'll talk after the show. I need
to stop. Good cameras and shit.
You went from the you,
you guys like right now
we're at the web cam cameras.
You know there are 90 90 bucks
each I cam or something like that.
That's what all the low budget podcasts.
When I look at it,
you got now shit, they're just cameras
man. But those are like 400 $500 each.
They'd probably something like that. Yeah.
Look at you. They're not cheap. Yeah,
the setup. It looks cool.
And now wait a minute,
are you, this is what my suggestion
are we on? Yeah. Oh my [inaudible].
I think it'd be cool. You
got, you should start.
I'm not just getting one shot of Joe.
Have like four camera shot.
This is not something that talking
about this. Would it be cool?
I need more in my face, bro. [inaudible]
angle me people tired of looking at
that angle. We're gonna mix it up.
I want to make a bloody all right. I did
a podcast recently and I had a makeup,
I'm not joking, there's their cameras.
They had a makeup person. I said,
I don't even wear makeup for work for TV.
I don't work makeup.
You can't put makeup on me. Like we're
just gonna put some anti shine. I'm like,
get the fuck out here. Are you crazy for
a podcast? If you're out of your mind.
But that meant, you know,
that's production value.
It's what they do while they're
doing a television show.
It's not a fucking plate of
carrots and celery shit. Add that.
Then I slowly is tapping into that
television, the television status.
Well I think that's what
they're trying to do.
This podcast or granola
bars at the cheap ones, man,
nature's made Granola,
apple and oats. Like
we have this new a sponsor. We, we
have these things around all the time.
Naturebox is, is uh, our new
sponsor. That's um, they,
they send you healthy snacks
through the mail. Um, naturebox, I,
there was a bunch of people that
were complaining on my website.
There were throwed shoes.
It's pretzels.
The deal with naturebox is
you can go from, you know,
better for you then your standard
vending food. Like, you know,
you're dealing with if you're,
you know, standard vending food,
what you don't have to deal with with
nature boxes. No high fructose corn syrup.
Partially hydrogenated oils, no
trans fats, no artificial sweeteners,
no artificial flavors, no artificial
colors. Like just that alone.
Just that statement alone to me,
that that gives me ease.
I feel better about
whatever fucking snack I'm
eating. And they also, if you have like
any dietary needs, like gluten free,
like I tried to eat gluten
free as much as possible,
so they send me a bunch of
gluten free shit. They can
do low sugar shit. Not Shit.
I'm saying shit, it's really good shit.
It's good stuff. Big Island, pineapples,
delicious. And there's this blueberry
almonds they have. Oh my God,
they're so good. And um, you can
get like, like stuff like that.
Very healthy. Not Bad for you at
all. It's when you get, you know,
into the Pretzel area. What
are you dealing with, man?
You're dealing with doe.
Doe's never really healthy,
but, uh, it's Yummy as fuck.
And they have an awesome selection
over a hundred snacks to choose from.
And like I said, if you have certain
dietary needs, uh, they can hook it up.
We enjoy it. We eat it here in the podcast
and we want you to enjoy it as well.
So go to naturebox.com/rogan
that's naturebox.com/rogan
and you can save 50% off
your first box. I love
the fact that people, uh,
podcast listeners get fucking upset
by shit. Pretzels are not fucking,
that's not healthy. I like
it. I like it. I do. I mean,
it's a little picky, but I get it. It's
good. It's good to be picky like that.
Healthy snacks.
There's nothing wrong with that.
They also have this a pistachio thing.
I forget what it's called.
Like a pistachio cluster.
God Damn. It's Yummy. Anyway,
naturebox.com forward slash Brogan,
you'll get 50% off your first box,
naturebox.com forward slash Rogen and
free shipping anywhere in the u s we are
also brought to you by Squarespace.
Squarespace is one of my
favorite experiences on,
on the web as far as like,
if you want to create something and use
a website, then make something easier.
There's a lot of different websites
to give you a nice, nice, uh,
self help services.
And there's,
there's all sorts of different websites
that can help you with all sorts of
things.
But for the longest time,
making a website was fucking hard at shit.
I used to have.
My friend Andrew made
a lot of my websites.
He's just a really clever guy who knew
a lot about html and knew how to code
flash and he's make a bad ass website.
But I could never do what he did
on it on my own. But now you can,
you literally can anyone,
you could go on Squarespace and make
the dopest website. Actually Eddie,
you should probably do something like
this because you would be really good at
that. You'd be really good at
designing your creative guy.
You'd be really good at
designing your own shit.
And Squarespace makes it super easy.
It's just drag and drop.
You can make websites that seem like
massively professional and you can do it
all yourself. We had a Squarespace
contest where we let listeners, um,
create their own websites and it was
really not even fair because we only,
we only had to pick like quick four or
something like that. It was ridiculous.
There was so many good ones.
It's incredible what you can do now.
So you can make a website
easy and it's so easy, easy.
And on top of that you can make a easy,
you can set up an online store like got
Brian has done them while the show has
been going on.
He set up a website and a store in the
time that it takes to do the commercial,
like he'll just start selling
goofy shit like fake goofy shit.
That's when he sets it up. It's insane.
It's insane. It's literally insane. Huh?
It's better than anything I've
ever seen before. It was car.
As far as like constructing a website.
Well the guys who do it,
they're cool as fuck too. I met them in
New York. So you don't need like a to,
it doesn't need to be super
complex know you don't have to do,
you don't have to like
go to a website company.
I mean I have a website company that
designed mine and they're great and I love
them and they make my tee shirts
and shit to uprise and creative.
They're really cool guys and girls,
gals, women. They're very cool people.
So I like, I like giving them money.
They're bad ass. You know, I'm, I'm happy.
But if I was going to start my own website
right now, if I didn't have a website,
absolutely I would use Squarespace a
hundred percent. Does it have a forum to,
that's a good question. Date of
24, seven support. Um, they uh,
live chat and email. Um, and uh,
they also have a logo creator,
which is pretty dope. You can create
a clean, simple logo in minutes.
Um, it's uh, which is really
interesting. You know,
you're talking about starting up a company
like on it and then we have a logo.
Caveman coffee has a logo,
you know, logos, if you can,
if you could put together a
logo, it's like, you know,
your shit looks more professional than
just text. That's the secret land is,
is to get that logo ingrained in
everyone's brain once they trying to you.
That's why he can't change up your logo.
You got to pick a lug who stick with
it because if you keep changing it,
that fucks up the,
that brainwash process.
Didn't Hicks and Gracie catch some heat
from Nike that Nike wanted that Swish
out of his, uh, his awesome triangle
here. And something about that.
I wish I'd asked him. I saw him this
weekend. That dude's still looks great.
He's in his 50s, like
healthiest. Fuck. It looks great.
Excellent motherfucking Gracie.
Anyway,
go to squarespace.com enter
the code Joe and get uh,
for the free trial and 10%
off your first purchase.
Another thing I like about Squarespace,
they let you sign up. Do everything,
create a website and then enter
in your credit card information.
That's how confident they are of it.
They let you try it first, but try it.
You're going to love it. He tried it and
go, Holy Shit. That's a website. Boom,
and you're going to want to give them
your money. Trust me, it's a good deal.
Anyway,
squarespace.com and enter into code,
Joe Squarespace.
A better web starts with your website.
I don't know why they have that in there.
That seems ridiculous.
Better web starts with your website.
How about just make cool shit here?
That's probably better. Right? All right.
That's how those Alpha brains
are starting to take over.
So that was like 30 seconds of
reorganizing my neurons. Does
that make sense? Can you say that?
I don't know if that's an actual event.
Uh, we're also brought to you by on it,
not com. O. N. N. I.
T we got a lot of big things that I'm
talking to as you bra about uh, on it, uh,
that I'll be discussing in the future.
We've got some, we got some big moves.
Well we're trying to do with [inaudible]
is we're trying to put together a
company that what we call,
um,
the design is a human optimization website
and what we mean by that is we want
to provide you access to
everything that we find.
It's beneficial whether it's anything
that's beneficial for cognitive thinking,
like Alpha brain. If it's for
your mood, which like new mood,
which is a five HTP and l trip defense
supplement that actually helps your brain
produce more serotonin.
Whether it's things like kettle
bells or battle ropes or hemp powder,
hemp protein powder, the best ham pro
protein powder we can find in hemp force.
We just try to find the very best shit
available. That's our motto. Motto is,
what would we want to buy when
it comes to human optimization?
What kind of shit would we want to buy?
And so we even hired artists to make
dope exercise equipment like these primal
bells. This uh, cool. Um, this guy,
Steven's Shubin Jr is a really
cool artist and his, his,
a work that he did on, um,
the Zombie bells and the, uh,
the primate bells would
pull those images up. Jamie,
the primal bells are all the great
apes and the Zombie bells are all like,
you know,
if you want to freak yourself out
that you were getting in shape for the
apocalypse,
what better way to do it then the sling
around at giant Iron Zombie head or at
shine fucking gorilla head. They're
awesome. I love these things.
They make working out fun and I know
people that have in their house,
they don't even use them as a exercise
equipment. They just think they're cool.
They leave them as door stoppers and
shit. Anyway, go to [inaudible] Dot Com o.
N n I t use the Codeword Rogan and
save 10% off any and all supplements.
This Thursday night I am in Miami Bitch.
I'm going to be at the Fillmore,
uh,
the Jackie Gleason theater at the
film war and I'm with the Great Tony
Hinchcliffe. So I'm looking
forward to that Thursday
Miami people. It should be a,
um, uh, it's part of the South Beach,
South Beach Comedy Festivals and um,
uh, thanks everybody that came out
this weekend as well to, um, uh,
to the comedy magic club and I'm going
to definitely start doing more of those.
I'll be doing those on
a regular basis now.
Now that Jay Leno was not
doing the tonight show anymore,
they used to be his spot,
the Sunday spot,
so they're giving them to a
bunch of different comics.
So I love that place and I'll be there
on a regular basis as well as the ice
house boom. [inaudible] boom. And
without that, no further ado, boom,
hit the music.
Young Jamie,
the Joe Rogan experience,
try by day Joe Rogan podcast all day.
Ah,
right where to even begin with this one.
Um,
you think it'd be cool to watch the
fight and instead of thinking of all the,
talking about different pieces of it,
cause it,
there's so many different aspects to it.
We could you think it'd be cool for
the viewer of who watch it and I just
tell you what I'm saying to him. Sure.
But are we allowed to do that? Like
Metamora so they paying people to, uh,
do you have to pay to watch
her? How it is? It's on youtube.
Should we probably should ask though
before we do something? I love it, dude.
Are you kidding me? You're kidding
me. That's what's asked him on,
uh,
I hope I can actually call them.
I think it'd be cool to signal on this
place just kind of sketch, um, for the,
just to give people background and
what are we talking about here? Okay.
Eddie Bravo. Uh, one of my favorite
human beings ever walked the earth.
My brother who, uh, I've
known, uh, we became best
friends. Like almost instantly.
We started hanging out together in
the late nineties, late nineties,
like thousand somewhere else.
I knew you from John Jocks in like 97 you
were the guy who was on an actor who's
on a TV show. You were doing news radio,
but I'd never seen news radio, but oh,
that's that one actor dude.
And you were taking privates and you
didn't do that many group classes.
At first you thought you were
doing the dope shit for the group.
Classes are for the peasants. Privates
are, that's when you get the real shit.
That's what you were thinking. Well, I
thought it was going to learn quicker.
I wanted to talk bad about that dude.
You know,
he was a real good guy that was teaching
me. I really like him, but it wasn't,
it doesn't, you have to roll with a bunch
of other people. It's just the fact,
you know, whenever I hear someone
telling me I'm taking private lessons,
I'm going to do some Jujitsu,
take private lessons. Like, well,
you can definitely learn
more than the average person,
but if you want to really learn Jujitsu,
you got to get dirty.
You got to get in there. And
uh, I didn't figure that out.
I didn't figure it out until
I started rolling with you.
So I started hanging out with you.
It's called Haluk right now.
But uh, the guy was a good guy. He just a,
we've got a story for
you ladies and gentlemen,
this if there's a backstory of this,
but I think he's mad at me, man.
I haven't heard from him. I doubt it.
Yeah, he's mad at me. Don't say that.
He put it out there. He
Jenksen I dunno. I'm saying
hello.
Halogens. Joe Rogan. Hey, before you say
anything, we're on the air right now.
We're live. I just, I wanted to, uh,
I wanted to know what your feelings
were out of respect when it comes to a
youtube,
the videos being up on youtube.
Are you trying to pull those
down because we were going to,
we're going to play one and talk about it,
but only with your permission
because I, I didn't know if you, uh,
if you were pulling those
down off the Internet.
Okay.
All right. Remember, we're on live, so
don't give out any information right now.
Don't get crazy. So we can play it
though. On the podcast and we can,
we can talk about it over it.
Beautiful.
Long process.
Yeah. Well that's, that's a great attitude
too. I mean, let them know like people,
this is a really awesome event you put
on and people should support an event
like that just with their own ethics,
regardless of whether
it's available for free.
That's my feeling is metamorris is an
awesome thing for Jujitsu and we should
all support it.
Beautiful.
That's a beautiful attitude. I agree
1000% that does not even a real number.
Right? You can only get to
a hundred hey listen man,
I just want to tell you whatever you need,
man.
If you want to have me promote
the next ones, I'm totally down.
That was an awesome event.
You had some really high class matchups
with really great Jujitsu talent.
It was a pleasure to watch, man. I
really, really enjoyed it. So I just,
I'm going to support you in any way with
this cause I just think it's an awesome
thing you're doing.
Let's do
it.
Let's do it, brother. Let's
do it. Let's do it. All right.
I'm alive. I'm going to go,
so we'll talk to you soon. All
right, take care my friend. Hey Man.
Hey Dude.
I Dunno,
I haven't heard from him so I thought
he's probably busy and you know,
it was his uncle's probably upset at you.
What happened?
This is what's going on
this for people don't know.
Eddie Bravo is a famous for um,
one very particular upset a
long time ago when in 2003,
we went down to Brazil and Eddie
was competing in the Abu Dhabi, uh,
world submission championships, which is
the biggest event in a Nogi grappling.
It's a huge,
huge event.
And this is the event that gave birth to
legends like Marcella Garcia. You know,
where people got to see him perform for
the first time. And I mean, it's so many,
so much high level matchups
recently chrome crazy who
he had in the podcast head
is a huge victory in Abu Dhabi.
Eddie went down there and Hoya Gracie's
maybe one of the most decorated Gracie's
ever when it comes to competition,
I think probably the most right up next
to Hodgett, right? Yeah. At the top two.
I mean, the boiler is, he's a legend
of a true multiple g championships,
world championships in multiple
Abu Dhabi Nogi Championships.
He won it three times in a row and
no one's ever scored a point on him.
The guys about as good as you
can get for that 45 deficient.
His Dad is Helio Gracie.
His Dad was literally the founder of
presenting digit two along with Carlos
Gracie.
I mean,
what his dad did was nothing short of
like for when you put into perspective the
like the history of martial
arts and different people.
Like Bruce Lee obviously plays a huge
part in many making my martial arts
exciting, uh, getting people into martial
arts. Chuck Norris also huge part.
John Claude van Damme,
a very big pie that gets people
into the schools in the first place.
But when you talk about a person who's
like maybe the single most important
person in all of martial arts,
it might be Helio Gracie.
I mean it might, he might be
the most important person ever.
A small man who uses leverage and
beautiful technique to submit.
People took on all commerce.
We 140 pounds and he's
fighting these giant dudes.
I mean it's an amazing family.
The whole family is just what
a crazy movie type family.
I mean you think about it like a family
that wouldn't even exist in the real
world. How about a family
where one bad motherfucker,
this one jujitsu genius.
Elio.
Gracie has a bunch of sons and they
all turn out to be bad motherfuckers.
I mean whatever.
What,
what other guy has had
like produced 20 killers,
30 killers and his own brood?
Well if you get into the story with
Carlos Gracie, his older brother,
he's the one who actually
learn Jujitsu and showed it to,
to Helia and they both thought and stuff.
But towards the end as they got older,
Carlos fought less and managed Heleo most
cause Heleo became the beast and Haley
was the one who refined and and tweak
the system and made it what it is today
technically.
But without Carlos learning it,
Heleo would have never learned Jujitsu.
So it was really,
they were both very Heleo designed
it and polished it and tweaked it.
But Carlos is the one that showed
him the Ra techniques from uh,
what he learned from my Ada. I
think his name is. Yes. Yes. I mean,
and I don't even when we're saying this,
this is no disrespect, that's a movie.
How come they haven't made a fucking
been out blockbuster James Cameron movie
about the Gracies come on.
Who would play Hixon but you know what?
Jujitsu guys would be so disappointed
because in an hour and a half they'd have
to just gloss over shit and like the
real story is way more complicated. Yeah.
Yeah it would, it would, can
you imagine an hour and a half?
You explained the whole Gracie story
with all the brothers and Carlson and
Helson and all their different stories
and health and high end and that's dude,
they would have to have like the high
end edge would be like 10 minutes of the
movie. That's it. They'd
have to high end wood.
You know there are folks who don't know.
High end was like the crazy
grace called him Gracie devil.
He was like one of the wildest
cause he fought in pride as well.
A lot of them fought in
pride of course hens. Oh,
Henzel fought in pride and
there's so many great people,
great martial artists that
came out of that family, um,
high and Hanzo and how for all brothers.
And they were like,
they were like the Tasmanian devils.
But Hensdale was probably the most,
a friendly,
I think,
high end and how for just ready to
throw down at any time with anybody.
They were the two pit bulls.
How hands on was a pit bull
to and according to the
Machados and their stories,
Hanzo was always the one laughing
and joking and everyone loved him,
but he was always in
the middle of a fight.
Someone would want to fight
them and they'd be a riot.
And you know, hands on has,
Hanzo is like a super happy go lucky guy.
But he has a,
he has a side to him that he could be,
he could turn it on.
And you remember when he live tweeted,
beaten up those muggers,
hence this up. What a bad motherfucker.
Henzel Gracie has any thanked the uh,
the mayor for a not allowing guns.
So don't
worry about my gone.
And he went out and these guys,
apparently they were following him and
they were thinking about mugging him.
And not only did he beat
these guys up like he,
he was live tweeting it
and chasing after them.
I and m for some reason he knew he was
being targeted and that like they were
targeting Henzel Gracie,
what a human would have to be in the
movie somehow they would have to squeeze
that. That would be like a loss
scenes. You know what I mean?
That didn't quite make the story
and they couldn't make it fit.
But that's a crazy,
that's a modern day Gracie story.
Cause you hear about all these old
Gracie Dojo storm stories and there's all
these legendary, legendary stories.
But he tweeted pictures of his hands.
This is modern day old school Gracie
stories. Right. And it's only a couple of,
what is it? A year ago, what
year was it? What year was it?
What did it say up there?
And the crazy thing is I was on
Twitter when it was happening.
I was watching it live
as it was happening.
I was actually on Twitter while he was,
he was tweeting and these guys
are following me, check this out,
and he was taking pictures.
I'm going to lure them and see like some
alley or to your corner fucking show.
These poor guys, he's just took pictures
of his hands. I'll bust it up and bloody,
he's probably has so, so many connections
and Nyp d. You know what I mean?
He knew that if he needed a beat up some
muggers that no one would ever go to
him. And he's stressed. He's so connected.
Well he's also talking about it.
We'd like such glee, you know, reminded
him of a, you know, growing up in Rio.
He really is like, I mean he's
in New York City, you know,
he's about as connected as you
can mother fucking get. Come on.
There's a lot of cops are trained Jujitsu.
We know connected to every,
every side, you know, they know
some serious mobsters and share it.
I would imagine.
Probably knows at least for sure.
Mobsters want to hang out with Hanzo.
You know what I mean?
Gangsters would love to hang out with
Enzo. That's a real life killer. I there,
he's aggressive guy to his
personality is so fucking great.
Like when you're around him, he's always
hugging people and super friendly.
Like she's got a great energy to
them and he's a bad motherfucker.
My favorite Gracie of all
time and, and I, I love,
there's a lot of Gracie's
man that I personally,
that I know person and there's a lot
that I don't even know. I'm like,
I'm never met. Like I've never sat
down and talked to Horry on. Um,
I'm never sat down, talked to
hodge her, you know what I mean?
There's a lot of great Helson. I never
sat down and talked to house and, but the,
the Gracies that I did
have, did have dual, do,
have relationships with and did have time
to talk and get to know is my favorite
all time is rose Gracie. She, I love her
to death. That is one of the sweetest,
coolest chicks on the planet.
And she's real, you know,
you're either come from the Heleo side
of the Carlos side. She's the only one,
her and her sister.
The come from both because hoary
on her dad married his cousin,
Helio Gracie is our grandfather.
Carlos Gracie is a great grandfather.
Weird, right? So rose
Gracie is the most Gracie,
she's grace. He's doubled. She's
double Gracie. Her blood is,
it's like Damn Pyre, Gracie
blood. You know what I mean?
There's her and her sister.
So Gracie,
double Gracie and she's the
coolest one to me. To me,
out of all the ones I've met, I love
her. We worked together and with the,
she runs the Gracie nationals and the
Gracie world and we work together and,
and uh, man, she's, she's, she's
awesome. I can't awesome. I love Henner.
I know. Henner I know here.
They've always been cool to me.
I want to get those guys in
the podcast too. Obviously.
You just heard that I would do Haluk
I would love to do him on as well.
Henner in here on,
I've done a fucking amazing
job of promoting Jujitsu
and in a technical sense by
showing those Gracie breakdowns. Those
are great. Those are really fucking,
they're entertaining.
Henry's like really captivating.
He's got like a great energy to
him when he's a natural, you know,
natural speaker and natural instructor
from all those years of teaching Jujitsu
classes. But he's very, he's very
entertaining, like his cadence,
everything but very technical
and they're Jujitsu delivery.
Their passion comes through. It's very
obvious. They really like what they do.
And I find that infectious,
you know,
those guys are awesome here on is always
been cool to me and her always been
cool. And uh, a crone. Gracie,
I just got to very cool.
Now I've met him and we've talked, he's
so cool. He went to my after party.
That's how cool. He went to my after
party. That's awesome. Yeah, that's,
that's pretty crazy. Right?
And I told him, I go,
aren't you going to get killed for this?
You do here.
This is like a pure
10th planet after party.
Everybody here is 10th plan and he's
just so cool. That's so damn cool man.
I love that guy. Well they, you know,
there's always these inter family feuds.
Yeah. There's a lot of weird shit
that goes on. Um, point being,
here's the story.
Eddie goes down there under dog.
Gracie is a legend. We're talking about
a legend from the most legendary family.
That's one thing you say unequivocably.
What is the most legendary family of
martial arts? The Gracies for sure.
100% there's not even a close second.
Probably the most legendary family that's
ever existed like what other family
has known for something like that.
Again,
like a big huge fan of world champions
known to be experts at strangling human
beings. Not just experts, but think of
the amount of champions, hoists Gracie,
the very first UFC champion who
arguably change the world's opinion.
Instantaneousness of martial
arts. That one guy, super legend,
hoists Gracie. Then you've got
Henzel Gracie, another champion.
You've got Heuler Gracie
the most decorated. Him and
Haji are the most decorated.
Hickson who beats all of them? Yeah. Hixon
who's the best or you ask any of them.
They say Hickson's the best. How
crazy is that? That's insane.
That's what Matt [inaudible]
Hixson Lips, Hicks, Euler.
He webs everybody, you know, but all,
even though they get whipped by Hixon,
they're still legends. They're still
better than most of the people walk.
And so it's so crazy.
The different levels that is the most
legendary for real family of all time.
Yeah. I really think about that. They're,
the family business is breaking bones and
putting people to their death with our
bare hands. That's the family
business. It's pretty crazy. Who's,
who's more hardcore than the Gracies.
There's uh, there's uh, some video.
Uh, it was like a
demonstration that Hixon did.
We're Hickson and Heuler had like a
little sparring demonstration, you know,
I don't know what it was though.
I Dunno. It was orchestrated.
It was like at one of those, um,
Japanese events. It'd be pride. Yeah.
They were just messing around.
Yeah.
They just sort of demonstrated
some techniques, you know,
but the only video that
I've seen of them rolling,
it's like there's some Gnocchi video of
them rolling, you know, but the, the, all,
any video that involves Hickson and his
brothers ultimately leads to the brother
tapping, which is insane. Everyone
gets smashed by Hicks. That's insane.
When you think about that, this one guy
and a family, a fucking super champions,
as one guy rises to the top over all
of them universally acknowledged.
And even the Brazilians
that did you get to that,
there's a lot of rivalries between the
Gracies and then it gets really technical
and there's certain Gracie's don't like
other Gracie's and theirs and that's
normal. And all families,
it's just normal. So the fact
that it's a Jujitsu family,
that doesn't mean they're immune
to what all families go through.
All families have division.
This aunt is not talking to that and
my mom is not talking to her sister.
They hate each other. Three are
like, like everyone says, it's,
that's just the way families are,
so they're not admitting to it.
So it's totally normal.
But uh,
when you get into what's really going on,
man,
uh,
it's just,
it's insane is what it is.
It's like the,
this one family that has created such
an empire of martial arts and in my
opinion, changed martial arts forever.
I think hoists Gracie and victory in the
ultimate fighting championship was one
of the most important moments in the
history of martial arts.
Without a doubt,
if not the most important because
people got to see what really works.
People got to see something in
a way that you never saw before.
He never saw a small man who
didn't look physically imposing,
dismantle other people with techniques.
Yeah,
and the whole,
even the hoary on was the guy that
actually made it happen physically.
The whole family was involved because
Horry on is the one who, it was his idea.
We need to put this show on
in the states and prove the,
that Jujitsu is the most effective
martial art puppet by. We could do this,
but it was because of what he saw Hixon
doing because of what he saw heuler
doing in the, in the Dojo storm
matches and Gracie in action tapes.
It was because what his father
Heleo spread to everyone.
That's what made horian wouldn't have
the drive and the vision if he didn't see
what Hickson was doing on a daily basis.
And when his dad did and know
the history of what his dad did,
all that everybody, Carlson, Gracie,
he was using all the cars and Gracie
fighters and the Gracie and action tapes.
It was all that, all the Gracie, uh,
events and all the Gracie people that
were all involved and hoary on needed all
that to explode the UFC.
So it wasn't just horror
on it was everybody Horian
couldn't have done it alone.
So, uh, that's why there was
some, there was some division,
some guys wanted to go here and say,
you know,
I'm going to do this on this side and
then you know, the people. But that's,
that's totally normal. But, um,
also there was some things
opening up in other countries too,
like kicks in and started doing Japan.
Valley two was around the same time.
It wasn't only one 94
and it just exploded.
Yeah. When, when Hawaii blew it all up,
all the people that were involved down
the chain, Carlson and all those guys.
And everyone, they said, okay,
this is, we're all part of this.
So that then it just grew
and exploded in the Gracie.
It just instantly Jujitsu just
spread all over the world. Instantly.
Everybody needed Hugh Jitsu,
martial arts masters were traveling,
all of their all going into Jujitsu.
All these American guys going into Rio,
you know, just became like,
uh, uh, uh, the thing to do,
man in martial arts is
go to Brazil and then we,
we got exposed to chew Scotty as and
[inaudible] and all that shit's here
because,
yep. And that's one of
the things about, um,
about martial arts at a lot of people
don't realize is that for maybe thousands
of years, it pretty much remained
the same when the Gracies came along.
That was what really kickstarted it
to this level. Right now, you know,
you can say that Jujitsu is not
their most important martial art,
but historically it's the most
important martial art. Unquestionably.
Like that one event.
People where people got to see a guy
like hoists dominate these bigger,
stronger guys and he wasn't a scary
looking physical. It didn't like,
it wasn't built like Mike
Tyson or anything like that
and it wasn't built like
Roy Jones. When you look at them
and go, Whoa, how can that guy move?
That guy moves like a coast. It wasn't
that, it was just technique, you know? So,
uh, pretty, pretty amazing thing to watch.
It's one of the things people don't
realize too about Chuck Norris.
Chuck Norris was ahead of the
fucking curve, man. Chuck Norris,
even though like a lot of people
associated with like Walker,
Texas ranger and you know,
like movies and TV shows.
Now Chuck Norris was a legit kickboxer
like legit champion kickboxer legit
karate champion. He was a
bad mother fucker. And he
really was into martial arts,
into training in martial
arts and learning new things.
And when did he start
training with the Machados
way before the UFC? Way
before the UFC, right? Like,
didn't you have like an eighties?
He had like a purple belt or a brown
belt before the UFC for the first year.
I've said
he was responsible somehow for,
uh,
the UFC getting moved along and there
were, there was some kind of connections,
you know, cause once it, Chuck
Norris discovered Jujitsu,
he was all over and he just immediately
injected it into his Chuck Norris
System. Anybody that's in the
Chuck Norris Affiliation System,
they have to do Jujitsu.
That's a karate association that
requires you to do Brazilian Jujitsu.
Chuck Norris is the map.
Yeah. He, um, I met him twice. I met
him once when I was at you with you.
We met him at some kickboxing event.
Remember when went to see
that world combat league.
Thanks Brad. Thought an hour.
Yeah, dude, there was, that
was a lot. Raymond Daniels
too, I think was on that card.
Um, a lot of great fighters.
I was fun as hell and,
but just meeting Chuck Norris was
like holy, but I didn't get a picture.
This met him again recently. I got
a picture of them. That guy, the,
he's a real deal, man. You know what
he did? And he's such a humble guy too.
Like all these guys I was on this,
uh, diocese does deus too. Um,
it's got Jim Harrison,
it's famous karate champion as well.
They were a congratulating
him and Chuck Norris was like,
he,
all of his stories like involve
like bad things happening to him.
All of his stories involved.
Like, uh, he, uh, he, he panicked.
He couldn't talk in front of people.
So he told this hilarious story about,
I'm not even remembering set,
talking, not even remembering,
giving a speech because he was so
terrified to speak in front of people.
Like very self deprecating, you know,
it was where a lot of fellows, you know,
you're getting to that sort of an
event and the guy looks for it as an
opportunity to go in the glory days and
talk about his past victories and that
kind of shit. Chuck Norris said none
of that. He was laughing and smiling,
you know, just self deprecating.
That guy's a legit martial artists.
Like a real legit martial artist.
Yeah. And, and of course, you
know, with that kind of mentality,
as soon as you discovered that
there's a big weakness in your game,
you want to fill that shit and, and fill
it immediate immediately. So he got it.
He was integrated you jet to then he
started training with the Machados and got
really tight with them and
ended up getting his black
belt from Carlos I think.
And that's why Carlos
went to Texas and yeah.
And that's who I got my black belt from.
John Jacques Machado,
one of the Great Machado brothers.
There's five of them, Hagan,
Johnny [inaudible] and
John Jock and Carlos.
And uh,
John Jog is another,
I mean the Machado family is another
legendary family as well. I mean,
you think he again hodge or John Jock,
I mean that,
that family as well became legendary
for very, very high level black belts.
The we're cousins. Yeah. I mean,
and there's a photo of them.
Look in John. Jack has just a
beautiful human being. I love that car.
No Spartan,
he's just got such a great energy to,
that's a great picture,
right there is,
that's like 1993 five boys,
five boys from Brazil,
all bad asses at Jujitsu.
All five of them. That's pretty
crazy. It was crazy, you know,
because when Jujitsu exploded,
all the Gracies said,
I'm going to make my own shit.
And they all just made their own schools
and hence I went to New York and,
and uh,
you know how of course the San Francisco
and they take their markets and shit
and that Horry on did the Torrance thing.
That was like the main Gracie place and
then all the Gracie started spreading
and some stayed in Brazil. The
machados man, five boys, five brothers,
they all came out and they just opened
up a school together and Redondo beach
and then the second one in the valley and
Tarzana, that's where I ended up going.
But man there, it's
pretty crazy man. Yeah,
that five boys and they're all around the
same age. Can you imagine? Pop, pop, pop,
pop.
You have five boys and they all look,
they all look very similar
and they're all yoked.
They're killers and they're every one of
them. Every one of them is a bad asset.
Jujitsu, that's pretty remarkable,
but the Gracies got, that's,
that's just another day in the park
for the Gracies like every family.
If you're a Gracie man and you've got
a Gracie last name and you're not doing
Jujitsu, what happened? I want
to document. I don't know.
That's a good question,
but that would be a really hilarious
comedy sketch like a Tim and Eric Sketch.
The one grace you didn't want
to do Jiu Jitsu is one grace.
He's just into like dance or
something like that happens.
Sometimes I bet that you know what?
I don't,
everyone in the family does
Jujitsu and then I want to do this,
I want to be an artist or I want to be,
and then you try that for a
while and you're like, shit,
I can make some easy money just using
my name and Jensen and then you realize,
fuck it. You realize what you have.
You know, like you have a great thing.
Your whole family are experts.
It's choking people and taking their arms
and you're choosing this other sheet.
You have this life for you right here.
So you just want to be their
own individual though, you know?
But that is a good question.
What percentage of Gracie men didn't do g?
Zero. Zero. Wow. That would be remarkable.
I think they raised him with it from
the time they were children. Yeah.
Gracie is your last time. You have no
choice. You're going to do Jujitsu. That's
incredible. Right? It's pretty
incredible. So 2003 and we're in Brazil.
Giant match.
Um,
Eddie Beats Gustavo's [inaudible] who
was a very high level Jujitsu black belt
and uh, he taps him. He gets
his back. So I saw that you're
pumped up. You know, you,
you felt very confident, you felt good
and you were, you know, you were zoned in,
but the idea that you were going to
fight oiler Gracie seems so crazy to me.
It just deep knowing what
I know about the Gracies,
knowing what I know about
the history of the family,
knowing what a legendary fan with there
to see you my best friend standing there
with a boiler, Gracie and you guys
are about to grapple. I'm like,
and we're in Brazil, Mike too. This
is a fucking trip. I was starstruck.
Thought it wasn't as I was watching
some three d TV or something.
It feels like you're right
there on the mat. And uh,
Eddie wound up catching him in a triangle
and it was the craziest fucking thing
I've ever seen in my life. And
uh, it was like time stopped.
It was like when you slapped that triangle
on him, it seemed like time stopped.
It didn't even seem real. And you
kept, you kept jailbreaking man,
which is why it was hilarious.
That dexterity that you have with your
legs and you're setting up this alma plot
to here
and you got them in like full,
full rubber guard here.
Yeah.
That Michigan's trolls at the beginning
of the rubber guard, right? Yeah. You,
what you had then was the
ability to control people.
You just didn't have as many
variations on technique to attack with,
but you had this unbelievable fucking
flexibility that a lot of people aren't
aware of.
You got some weird flexibility and not
just flexibility but dexterity like in
places that maybe some people
can grab their leg and put it,
you could put your leg there on its own.
But um,
there's so many guys that are out there
that W it's not that weird flexibility.
It's just getting into Lotus.
Like if you got into yoga and
you've got obsessed with it,
eventually two years,
three years, five years,
you'd have to be able to get into
the very basic low disposition. Yes.
There's a little more than that fell. Are
you being nice? Yeah. That's what it is.
I know what you're saying. But the
reality is you got some crazy legs,
something weird about your legs.
Your legs are like arms.
They move in strange ways, right? Hairs.
If he didn't try to pass right there
and if we had just stayed in my guard,
I wouldn't have gotten them this one.
And a half in this transition. Oh
yeah. He got uh, aggressive and he
shouldn't have got aggressive. He,
if he would've just been conservative,
I wouldn't have been able to go
right here, right into the triangle,
boom over hook. Oh, John Jack right there.
That's all Jay.
You control that wrist and then slapped
it over and now this right here where
you had the triangle locked in once here,
like right there, I was like, Holy Shit.
Because before it was like one of
those things where you're not breathing
because it's not totally locked in, but
once you had it locked behind the knee,
I was looking, I was like, how is this
guy going to survive? And he's tapping.
I was like,
he can't survive like no one can.
It's a human being when you have a guy
your size and you slap a triangle on him
this tight. See right here.
I wasn't sure Pam there.
I knew like when once he dropped out, I
was like, Holy Shit, that's locked in.
You were screaming, man. Oh my God.
And we were the only one screaming
because everybody else was freaking out.
There's Brazilian TV station.
It's set up cameras there.
They shut down the other matches so they
could better light this match because
Hoya grace, she's a hero and
they were going to show a boiler.
Gracie dominating the first time
Abu Dhabi came to Sao Paulo.
When you slap this triangle on them, dude,
all you heard was me and Jamie Walsh.
Me and Jamie Walter yelling out,
pull the head, pull the head.
Oh my God. Oh my God. It was
just madness. Like, Oh shit,
what?
W We couldn't even believe it.
And then once you did pull
the head and once he did tap,
it was like the world froze. It was weird.
It was like a, it didn't make sense.
The world just became some new place.
The world is a totally new element opened
up like the world became a new place.
Now all of a sudden Eddie Bravo was
a champion martial artist. Well,
I didn't win the championship.
It doesn't matter.
You just have toilet Gracie like
you're capable of tapping oil grease.
That's championship level shit. He tapped
one of the greatest guys of all time.
It was,
it was a whole new world opened up.
It was just all of a sudden it was
like, Whoa, this is weird. Yeah, it was,
it was weird. It was weird to watch
too, man. Cause I'm, when I met you,
you're a purple belt, you
know, you were really good,
prayerful belt and we're
crazy moves and shit.
And then all of a sudden you brown belt
and you were a brown belt and Abu Dhabi
Bro. That's crazy. You tapped
them when you were a brown belt.
So 11 long years go by and this
Saturday night they had a rematch.
Um,
Eddie and boiler had a rematch
and metamorris and that's
what we were talking to
at Gracie about on the phone.
They're promoting these professional
Jiu Jitsu matches and uh, it's awesome.
Keenan Cornelius fought,
um, uh, Kevin Casey,
Kevin Casey took out. I'll just
describe the whole event. Um,
a lot of really,
really high level fighters.
Fought a lot of really good a
Jujitsu fighters fought and I'm,
the main event was Eddie
versus Heuler Gracie and uh,
11 years running.
I mean,
it's a long time in between
matches and there was so much talk,
so much, so many haters,
so many believers, so many.
I mean there's so much back
and forth between, you know,
the people that thought that Eddie
winning the first time was a fluke.
And the people that legitimately thought
that Eddie has a brilliant mind and a
creative mind for Jujitsu
that's really unique.
And he can come up with a
lot of techniques and his
deck, like he's talking,
he doesn't want to admit that he's
got weird dexterity in his legs,
but he can move his legs in weird ways.
He can wrap you up and triangles and
stuff and weird ways without a lot of
people have to grab their foot
and place it in places. Um,
so he has these techniques that he's
developed and like really created a bunch
of paths like been and a lot of a Jujitsu
guys do this. This is not unique. Um,
but his past where uniquely his and
that he came up with a lot of different
techniques and approaches and refined
a lot of other approaches that,
so he sort of adopted or
adapted to Jujitsu. And um,
the system in 2003 was really,
I'm not even a 10th of what it is now.
Um,
after 2003 Eddie started teaching
and then it became crazy.
Then the system started growing and new
techniques were added and that there
became guys like Denny proper goes who's
a a a world champion as a brown belt
guys came out of there that
we're showing that your,
your techniques weren't just for
you and your crazy dexterity,
but you had broken down things
in a way that you know, uh,
other people hadn't done before and a
weird way your, your, your positions,
your very unique.
And um,
there was a lot of people that do
want accept that for whatever reason.
And there was all this, oh, he
got lucky. Oh, Fluke, oh this.
So Saturday night rolls around and
I couldn't imagine there being more
anticipation in a room before something.
And it was a cool anticipation too
because one of the things I like about
Jujitsu is no one's going
to get knocked the fuck out.
Even if you get choked out,
you know,
there's something about like seeing a
friend fight. It gets real rough. I mean,
we've been friends with MMA fighters,
but I've never been as friendly with an
MMA fighters. I am with you, you know,
I've,
but no one,
a guy and liking a guy and then watched
him get head kicked as hard to do,
you know, so it didn't have the
date that, that aspect to it,
but it was all positive is what I'm
trying to say. It was all just holy shit,
it's going down. Um, and once it did,
there was no points because
it's a 20 minute match.
So for 20 minutes it's either
submission or no points,
but in that 20 minutes you
swept him on multiple occasions.
You've got side control. He never
threatened you in any way, shape or form.
You swept in with electric chairs.
You threatened him with a neck crank
and you threatened him with his nasty
fucking submission move on his
knee. Which I don't, you know,
I don't know how he didn't tap cause
that was hard to watch man when we were
sitting there watching. That was the
move. I got you on a high time. Yes.
You know that movie vaporizer,
that move is so painful.
Just that photo shoot, that
shit hurt man. It hurts.
And somehow or another a boiler just,
I mean, look, he's a warrior. He just,
he didn't want a tap. He just
decided he wasn't going to tap. Um,
for people who have never
seen Jujitsu before, um,
that was like the perfect introduction
match because it was so exciting.
There was so much madness and there was
a bunch of times where you were, uh,
you were working on shit and he rolled
you over onto your back and then he swept
them again. So there's all these
like saws when he would role,
you'd be on your back.
Oh, she, he's on his back.
But you on your back is different than
a lot of people on your back because
that's how he tapped him in the first
fight. You tapped him from your back.
Your back is, you know your,
your guard is crafty. So it was,
it was an incredibly thrilling match
because there was constant threat at all
times and even from him,
man, he's still Hoya. Gracie,
you always knew. I mean, he's still
that champion. If something went wrong,
if you didn't dot your
i's and cross your t's,
I was not sure I was going to win
this fight. How could you be sure?
It's fucking crazy. I mean, he's oiler
fucking Gracie. He never said that.
I'm going to go out there and just
strangle them. I was just, I didn't know.
I hadn't competed in so long.
Look right here,
I'm faking like I'm going to wrestle
because I didn't think he was just going
to let me pull them into quarter guard.
I thought at this point my
wow. He just, he didn't,
I thought he was just going to
try some totally different ship.
But this is what he always does.
Every morning before I work out,
I warm up on the stair master,
I go to Youtube,
put Heuler ADCC pick one of his matches
and that's how I get that gives me all
the motivation. I just watch him
roll and he's so good at this.
But I thought he would try
to pass to the other side.
And I thought this position,
I thought this position was going to be
the hardest to get and this was the key.
If I could just get quarter guard in this
position, I felt like I could get them.
And there's a bunch of crazy
rules in this match as well.
One of the rules was that boiler was
wearing like these skin tight shorts.
Eddie was wearing khaki pants.
Um,
and Heuler was allowed
to grab addies ski pants,
but Eddie wasn't allowed to grab toilet
shorts. So it was weird to watch man.
Cause there's times where he's like
giving you a Wedgie and pulling on your
pants.
Yeah, he's pulling them down.
I could see my underwear.
Yeah.
And when and when he got to that a leg
lock and he's trying to defend that leg
lock and you're tearing his knee apart
and he's hanging onto your, your cough.
It's saved him. The pat saved him.
Yeah. Cause he didn't have the pants.
I would have stomped on that foot
and got the extra power because he,
oh I mean a man,
his,
I think his knee popped at least
seven times. We were talking.
I'm like we could stop this now. You sure?
He goes, no, I'm fine. And I'm popping.
I'm like what about that?
Because I'm fine. I'm like,
it just kept popping on my damn.
Well you sure cause everything's good.
I said everything's fine. Like we're
talking throughout this whole match.
Like right here. He wanted the
under hook really, really bad.
So I was saying it's hard
to get this time. Huh?
Cause the first time he got the under
under a lot of word that I'm a lot of work
cause that's a hard one.
It's only because I would rather go
against a guy who wasn't really mad at me.
If I could joke with you and get like a,
like this is just for fun. Right? Right.
Then I feel like, okay, I,
I can get this guy now because I could
win because he's not mad, but it was map.
Oh Shit.
Like I would never want to find like a
Diego Sanchez type guy was mad at me.
I'm like, oh no, no, no. I want to find
a guy that's like friendly and shit.
So it's hilarious.
Yeah.
So I was just constantly joking
with them constantly. And uh,
during, like after I swept him, when
I get on top of the electric turn,
I'm holding, I go, you can't move
from here. So just hang on and relax.
I need about a minute to rust. And I
go, you can't do nothing. Just relax.
Because there are some positions
where they're, I don't know,
maybe three or four positions are like
cradles there, like rustling cradles.
And it happens here where the guy on
the bottom just can't do anything.
He's not getting tapped, but he can't
move. He's to completely wrapped up.
And I used those spots to rest. So, uh,
but it's hilarious that you told though,
just relax. When me and John, Jack Russel,
we are always talking smack to each other.
Me and John Jock always goof and we're,
oh, it's always a joke. It's always,
always me and Sean.
It's like a thing we do and I do.
There's certain guys that I
rolled with that I do that too.
I don't like to do it too much to my
students because then it seems like, um,
acting all arrogant against a guy that I,
he's one of my students,
he's a blue belt or a white belt that
would look really Douchey, playful.
But because John Jack can
smash me anytime he wants.
I talk like I pretend like I'm arrogant
cause it's funny because he could do
anything you want.
So no matter how Douchey I get,
we know it's just doesn't make any
sense cause he's killing me. But um,
uh, so same thing here. I have
so much respect for him that,
that I feel like I could just joke around
with them and I don't want him to be
mad at me.
Well that's good.
That's a good attitude to have man,
especially after 11 years
between the matches. Um,
it's cool that you, uh, you kept that
feeling and you were completely destroyed,
completely respectful, rather,
uh, the entire way up to
the promotion of it. Your,
your opinion of him, you know, you were,
you were like praising what a legend he
is and you were very self deprecating
about your first victory to um,
this was a 20 minute match and because
there was no submission, uh, it's a draw.
Metamorris is doing a
unique thing and they,
I don't know if they've got the rules
totally ironed out where they want them to
yet,
but what the,
what they're trying to do is
discourage people from point fighting.
And what that means is work
towards submission at all times.
And you may get a submission and you
may not get a submission, but the, the,
the idea is you're,
you're seeing real Jujitsu here
and they've accomplished that.
Like everyone was going for submissions,
whether it was Guy Mendez or Hoffa
Mendez or you know, Kenan Cornelia is,
everyone was going for submissions.
Um, sometimes they didn't get them,
but it was really exciting because of
that because guys couldn't just sort of
wrestle to a certain
position and then hold. Um,
but if this was a scored match,
you would beat them handily.
I mean you swept him multiple times,
you've got side control on them
and you had two near submission.
This is where he gets the under hook.
This is the crowd goes nuts because he
was been fighting for the under hood for
five minutes and he finally gets it.
And this is the position that
we're in and our first match.
So all the grades it was like, yes, he got
the undercuts. So technical that right.
He finally got it.
And I still have them in quarter
guard here so I was a little worried,
but you see what I'm
doing with my right hand.
I'm going under the knee right here.
I never really do that and I was keeping
him from going, no ham pass. So I'm like,
oh okay cool.
This is nice.
He can't go no ham pass cause I'm
holding his leg out like that.
And I've never really done that before.
This is the first time.
It's crazy to see how my left hand.
Yeah. She can't go. No Ham pass.
I'm holding open his legs,
so I felt comfortable.
Even though I didn't have the under hook,
I just had to somehow get a lockdown,
so for my people, they know,
they see me fighting like this.
All this is every day in the gym. This is
how it looks. I start in this position.
This is how it looks.
So to the Gracie side,
they probably thought he was a winning
right here. My mom was freaking out.
My mom thought he was killing me.
This at this moment you got the lockdown
somewhere in here you got the lockdown
and when you got the lock down here, the
crowd went fucking crazy. That was crazy.
I get the lock down. My guys go
nuts. Yeah. He gets the under hook.
His crowd goes nuts. I get the lock
down. My crowd goes nuts. That was,
it was crazy. The lockdowns way
bigger though. The the what? What?
For folks who don't know the lockdown.
When you got a guy who's really good
at it and he has you in half guard and
slaps it on your legs in jeopardy,
you might tear your fucking knee.
You're getting manipulated,
you've got two legs against one,
and when a guy's really good at it,
a guy like Eddie,
when they're really good at it and
they have two legs against one,
it puts you in a precarious
position and it's,
it makes you vulnerable to
a lot of different sweeps.
And here you're flipping it
backwards. Like that's when
the crowd went nuts. Well,
dude, you're, you're, you've got
his leg in a mangled position. Here
is electric chair right here.
I didn't think this was the plan.
The plan was exactly what happened.
That was the plan. I was going to go,
just do what I do at the gym every night.
This is exactly what I do every night.
This is nothing new.
It wasn't a special strategy for Heuler.
So that was John jocks whole plan is to
get me to do what I normally do the best
shit I'm, I'm at. Uh, did, did
do it out there on him and then
reversed you for a second.
I didn't have the leg on my shoulders so
I go let us go back and boom and get it.
So it looked like he swept me.
But I went back to put that leg back on
my shoulder and I went rock right back
up people. Dude, I do it
all the time, you know.
So now I'm in a position,
this is where you rocked it with momentum
cause you had full control over that
leg. It was just wasn't on
my shoulder. I had to go
and scoop it up.
So now I'm on top and now I'm an,
I'm in the electric chair on top and this
is where I'm talking to him. I'm like,
you can't do anything here. Just
relax. This is where I rest.
I went through a lot of explosion and I
rest right here. I have control of it.
That's why he was doing that thing with
his hands because people would want to
like, why is he throwing his hands
up in the air? Like, you know,
like he did that a couple of times when
you got them into side control and they
did that and then I passed the guard.
Boom in right here. I'm, I'm still,
he's still stuck.
I got him in a cradle,
but that makes sense now because everybody
wondered why he was doing that with
his hands. People are like, oh,
Hoyle, he was complaining. No,
he's complaining because you
were talking shit to him. Yeah.
You're saying you're stuck here and
maybe he was saying, I can't do nothing.
He's holding me. He's like, this is
Jiu Jitsu we're holding, we're square,
we're clinching and squeezing. Right.
You know, and he's all like, well,
how could he complain about that? He's
totally a mobile here. Even though I pass,
I pass, I let go the lockdown
and passed his guard.
The reason why the past was guaranteed,
it's because of the control I have on his
leg. I have a head and arm and the leg,
so that pass was easy.
As soon as I let go,
the lockdown didn't want to let
it go until I rest a little bit.
And then finally I let go the leg
last and now I'm in side control.
And here's the big transition.
I thought he was going to turn into me,
but he turns away. So I'm
like, Ooh, that's even easier.
But he's rolling in a nice way.
But I had to turn it into a 100% here.
So this is halfway.
This is a neck crank that I do to
get the guy to give me his back.
So I'm net cranking them here and if he
pulls his left arm all the way out, um,
I usually transition to the back
and that's what he did right there.
So now I'm getting up and
his left arms free now.
So all I gotta do is get up on my right
knee and then swirled in the back.
That's what I'm going to do here. I
wanted the twister. That was the plan.
The plan was to get them in a twister,
but he did a really good job
of just shrugging me off.
So now I gotta start over again.
So at this point I'm thinking,
this is what I'm really thinking.
Um,
I thought the most important thing is
for me is to go out there and not get
smoked and I get tapped in 20 seconds
or 30 seconds cause that would be,
that would crush me.
I would be the worst possible thing.
So let's make sure that doesn't
happen. And if I lose, if I tap,
at least let me go out there and give,
we have 20 minutes.
Let's see some good 10 planet techniques
from my people just to show that it
works if he taps it. So at this point I'm
thinking I did so much to them. Right.
Their Textbook,
10th planet shit all the way through
note for note that I thought if he the
worst case now if he
taps me on one second,
at least I got some good shit in my mind,
in my mind.
Cause that's how much respect I have for
right. I'm like he could still get me,
I'm not over. We got like 13
minutes. So in my mind I already won.
I go, I want, so when you
think that way and you're,
I thought I already did all this shit.
So the worst case scenario, he tasks out.
I did a good job.
So for some reason that made me
just want to attack a more and go,
let's just keep putting, let's just keep
piling it up. Oh, here's another one, Dan,
and see if I could do another
one. Oh, here's another one.
And the, I just changed.
Should it go? Damn. I'm not
going to go for a twister.
I'm going to go for a vaporizer.
So when I,
when I get them in an electric
chair and he doesn't tap,
when I test this flexibility,
if they don't tap,
I can just sweep them and get on
top and set them up for a twister,
which I already tried, but
I made the decision. I go,
you know what? There's a lot.
He's pretty good at shaking me off the
bat. If I just go to the vaporizer,
it'll justice cools the twister.
And I do it all the time and that's
good enough. So that was the plan. I go,
he's not stopping the electric chair.
So I'm a go back and get another another.
I thought about rubber guard for a second,
third, and I thought, you know what?
You see how he got the under hood? You see
that I went, rubber guard, locked down,
whipped him. He had the under hook, but
that whip boom, I sucked and wham Bam,
that's a little whipped down combo,
a very important combo to master.
And now I got the under it.
So I thought he's not stopping the
electric charge tonight because if he
would've been able to, he can I,
I'm able to do electric chairs easy.
So I knew I could just go back
and more money in the bank.
I knew he couldn't stop it.
He just was perplexed here.
So I go, you know what, I'm,
I got to go to the vaporizers that,
which means I got to get his leg over
to my left shoulder on the other side.
I need to get my head.
I want me,
I just need to squash his leg down and
get on top in a leg drag type position,
but a leg drag with a
lockdown to maintain control.
So right now I'd go back to the electric
chair for the third or fourth time and
I was really confident at this point.
I just knew he wasn't going to tap from
the electric chair and I didn't want to
pass his guard, get on top and tried the
twister. I already made the decision.
I don't know what we're
talking about here.
The electric chair is a move where you've
got a guy literally in a full split
and he could, you're controlling his
bottom leg and the other leg, your,
you're forcing it up towards his head.
Most people don't have the flexibility
to tolerate it and a lot of times they
tap just from that.
You're like literally ripping their crotch
part. Yeah. And, and right here,
you know what I didn't get,
I didn't get the position I wanted,
so I'm letting him get on top
so I can set it up again. I go,
he cannot stop it.
He can't stop my under hugs.
I already knew I had him beat
on the inside. So I'm, uh,
I'm going to set it up again and go back
to the cause. I wanted the vaporizer.
He foiled to vaporize. I lost control of
his leg, so I got to start over again.
So all of these times where he's on top,
where the audience is,
I call the tide has shifted back and
forth. This was just you resetting
did he could not stop my half guard game.
I've just,
the confidence just kept
growing and growing.
So even though he has
the under a guy go watch,
I'm going to get the under hook back.
I was already getting it back.
There's no way you could stop it. It
see that boom, whipped down. I go,
I'm just going to keep doing
it. He can't stop it. So,
and then I'm going to start all over.
I know he's not going to be able to,
he's not going to shake the lockdown.
The lockdown is too strong.
He was never close to ever getting his
leg out. I was so confident at this point.
I was getting a little gassed and um,
I knew I could recover.
All he needed was like a little
time. So, um, um, to, to uh,
hide, uh, the, the gas
enos or the gas in is, uh,
the fact that I would stop breathing.
I'm dying inside,
but I would stop breathing.
You know,
like when Jason Walks into your house
and you're in the closet and you're like,
but then you'd go, yeah, I was doing
that just so he wouldn't smell.
Now I did it again.
I knew I could do it again.
Now I got to get his leg to the other
side. I don't want it. Look at it at sea.
I'm holding onto his leg. I need to get
it to the other side of my body, right?
So I'm like, you know what? Damn, I lost
it again. Let me, let me do it again.
So look at that. I have you do it again.
They thought he reversed me, but I go,
I'm just setting it up now. I've
got the leg over right there. Boom.
That's where I want to be. That's
the transition right there. And I go,
I'm going to go after. It's
like, I thought about it for
a second there, but I got,
no, you know what, I'm going to
roll. I can't just reach back for it.
I got to have set it up. I'm going to
set it up right here. Squash them down.
I thought about it again, but then he
stopped it right there and I go, okay,
let me set it up differently.
But then we got broke up here and
this is where all the controversial,
what the hell was going on here.
I knew what position we were in was top
stoner control. I knew the position.
I'm there all the time. He had
no idea what I was doing. So,
and he didn't know that. I
knew. He thought it was just
some crazy weird position.
And uh, he didn't know where he
was. And uh, I was, I was, see,
I pulled guard right here and I was
going to say, here, look gimme your leg.
Let me throw it over.
I'm going to get on top and we're going
to go back and I show you exactly the
whole thing. I was going to show it. I
was going to do it from the top. See,
I'm trying to do it from step one,
and then I was going to take them over
and I was showing him the sweep instead
of just getting in the position.
He's all confused.
He didn't know what's going on. I'm trying
to, I go, you got to get your leg over.
And he's not, he keeps
refusing. I'm like, man,
he's not letting me get in the position
and look. He's like, no, no, no.
And he didn't know, uh, in his
defense, he didn't know the position,
but I know exactly what's going on.
He refuses to get in the position and
then I'm just thinking I need to rest a
little bit anyways,
so this is bullshit.
I'm not going to argue like we were just
arguing here. He won't let me. I know.
Exactly. I, then I decided,
fuck that. Fuck this shit.
I'm not going to get fucked here.
And the crowd was going nuts,
so you don't replay replay,
replay.
And so Scott Nelson looks over right here.
He looks over to Hallock and he goes,
what do you want me to do?
Hallock Hallux said stand them up,
start standing and when it like he's
going to walk over right now. And I said,
what did he say? And then they put the
replay on, he goes, hey, Alex said,
stand him up. He said, stand
them up. And I'm like, fuck
that. We're not standing up.
And then the replay comes on and everybody
looks at the replay and then it just
gets down and gets into
position. I go, look, look with,
I know a position's going on. So he
let me have it. See he said, okay. No,
no resistance.
Once the video came out there was trying
to sneak that left knee in. Yeah. Yeah.
And this is top stone or control
right there. Right there.
Stolen a control from the back
and there's only half of Tufts.
He didn't have your risks
before. It didn't matter. It
didn't matter. None of this.
What I want here is I want him to push me
away because I'm going to dip and roll.
I'm going to Tuck and roll, but if he
holds onto me, I can't tuck and roll.
It'd be holds on.
So I got to make it look like I want to
smash them and squeeze them because I
could pass it anytime
the past is guaranteed.
Do you want the for sure pass or do you
want to try to Tuck and roll and go for
the kill right away and
go after the vaporizer.
And I thought I'm going
right for the vaporizer.
Fuck passing his guard and then he
recovers half guard and all that shit.
I wanted to go for the kill right here.
So right now I'm on my side.
I'm setting it up.
I need to be up on my knees,
but just all I do is need to get up.
See I'm getting up.
All they gotta do is really get on top,
but I know I could get on top of him
anytime I want. I know this position,
I'm just waiting. Now I'm on my knees.
I collected some gas, I recovered,
he can't get out. I'm in control
here. His legs are all mangled.
So what I want to do is turn to my
right and roll on my left shoulder.
But what I am resting,
all I'm doing is rusting.
I'm going to turn to my right
roll on my left shoulder,
but I need him to push me.
So I see I'm,
I'm selling the fact that
I want to squeeze him and I
want to see to see and now
he's pushing away. He bought it, he bought
the fact that I want to squeeze them,
so this is what I always do. So now
I'm gurgling going like I hate this.
Like I hate this, but look, he's
going to help me see how we helped me.
And he pushed me through. He
pushed me through like, Oh shit,
it's done now you got this. And I
thought for sure he was going to tab.
This is the vaporizer. No one has ever
not tapped to this. This is in my arsenal,
the nastiest leg lock.
This is a,
it's a calf crank and it's a toe hold
at the same time and he can't protect
himself with his other leg is
other legs were on his other leg.
So his other leg is useless.
I can use both my arms as opposed
to the calf crank from the truck.
The calf came from the truck.
You can't use both arms for fear of
getting onboard with one of them. Yeah.
So you need to protect that other leg.
Anyways,
he's got a free leg to break shit apart.
But in from the vaporizer he
can't protect with his other leg.
It's out of the mix and you could use
both arms because there's no arm bar and
it's a, it's, it's a leg
compression and a told in one,
it's the nastiest leg lock in my arsenal
and the fact that his leg popped at
least seven times, it was popping and
crack. And I'm telling them right here,
I'm sorry, I'm asking him. I go, dude, we
can end this. And he's like, no, see that.
He's like, no, I go, we can stop this.
It keeps popping. He goes, that's normal.
That's normal. I go, it
keeps popping. And uh,
he refused the tap. He refused
man. And I was Yanking,
so I thought I'm going to, I was doing
things I never did to that they Bryson,
I usually just grab the toes with both
hand twisted in pool and it's really easy.
And the calf crank from the truck.
Another thing that you need,
you need to stomp your left,
the inside of your left
foot with your right foot.
You got to shove your leg
deeper into the of me nasty.
But in the CAF crank, you need to stop
in this one. You don't need to stop.
You could just keep your legs figure
for both arms. That's enough pressure.
Just leave your legs,
figure four.
But if for some crazy reason
they don't tap like he did,
then you would go to the stomp
to add even more pressure.
But he was holding the Geeky Pant so
I could see he's holding my right leg.
I need to use my right foot and
stomp on the inside of my left foot.
I need to pull it up and stomp on
it and Matt can get his hands free.
I can't get my leg free. You see how
he's holding it? But I mean there's,
so I decided, you know what, I'm just,
I generally don't need
to stomp on that foot,
so I'm still trying to make him tap
like everyone else taps without it,
but see how he's holding it.
So I grabbed his foot,
I'm twisting it and I thought
there's like a minute left. I go,
I'm going to give it everything.
I've got one more time and
I just grabbed his foot,
something I never do when
I twisted it and shoved it,
like try to shove it like in his ribs,
man.
And he still wouldn't tap and gear
this popping and he didn't care.
He just kept going.
He knew that if he didn't tab it would
be a draw and that's what he needed.
He couldn't have you tap
twice. Tap him twice. Yeah.
He has nothing. The fact that he's
holding onto my geek pants there,
that's what's saving him.
You know, he crazy. Yeah,
he's in serious danger right here.
If you had to do it again,
would you do with g pants again? Yes. Yes.
Because the g pant made those
electric chairs so easy. He could,
he was never close to pulling
his leg out of lockdown.
So I mean the pants,
the pants were bad for
him and a lot of ways,
but it saved him might here in this
one position. Yeah, it did save him,
but I would, yeah, I would, uh,
I would have went back to pants anyways
with that whole pants scandal thing. Um,
uh, asked to wear pants. They said, okay,
you can wear pants if you
promise not to change your mind.
I want it to change my mind. They
said, you promised not to change it.
And then so they made me wear
what I asked for. So, um,
I met his lawyer, his lawyer, and it
ended up being really, really cool man.
The guy that was, uh, trying
to protect a heuler from Oh,
situations when you're twisting it. Yeah.
I'm pushing down and trying to smell.
She's obviously in some serious pain here,
but it's incredible. He's not tapping.
What do you think happened to the knee?
If you had to guess it
was this some damage?
Maybe.
Maybe he is knee always pops.
No. Say about him. Is that
he won't tap to joint locks.
Like you remember when a soccer Robin
got him in that Kamora and they stopped
the fight and he's like, don't stop the
fight. I, I'm there all day. I'm fine.
Like I don't get tapped from those
things. Yeah, man. Um, so like, uh,
Hallock said, please don't watch this
on youtube. If you do watch on Youtube,
please support metamorris just go
there and purchase one for 20 bucks.
There's a lot of high level matches
and uh, people, it's really fun.
People kept saying, you were going nuts.
We were going crazy. They go, dude,
you got to get watch video. If there's
video of Joe Watching your match,
you were just exploding. Dude. I thought
I was going to have a heart attack.
I left there, I couldn't talk to
people. I ran when the match is over,
how to get out of there.
Cause I wouldn't, it wasn't,
there's no way I was gonna be able to
have a conversation with like, you know,
like, uh, people on the street, regular
folks I didn't know and I didn't want to,
uh, have that conversation with
anybody. I ran out of there. Wow. Dude.
My heart was pounding. Yeah, they said
you were going nuts. Were you drunk? No,
not at all.
Let me sober.
Where you one of the guys
that that cheered when the
lockdown and where you kind
of worried in the beginning,
cause I was like five minutes of Jochin
was never worried. He got the under.
You don't when he had the under hook?
Nah, I didn't eat. That didn't mean enough
because it looked like the same match.
It looked like 2003 right.
I know too much about your game.
I've seen your role too many times.
I felt it too. I know. What about,
I know that lockdown down is hot
death. You get ahold of your leg, man.
That's scary shit. I hate that
feeling. You're locked down.
It's like you're being
compressed in between boards.
That sort of feels like it's like you've
figured out a way to do it and you do
it so well and you've done it for so many
years that you know the exact correct,
perfect angle to hit it where it's like
bone is digging in to meet your shin
bone is digging into meat and
you just do a thing. You know?
I like the analogy that you always use
with tying your shoes that when you tie
your shoes, he tied his shoes every
day. So when you go to tire shoes,
it's just automatic. It just
goes, it's magic. Yeah. You
don't even think about it.
It's just how he didn't have no command
and that just happened on its own.
And when you do Jujitsu long enough and
you drill long enough and you were in a
certain position long enough,
you develop that too.
You see it with the only
forms of movements that I'm
really knowledgeable about
or striking movements and
grappling movements. But
you see it in those as well.
And I guess you see it in everything.
You see it in throwing a football.
You see it in baseball.
You see it in everything.
When someone gets some shit down
and they really got it down,
like you know like Paul Sass and
his triangle, that mother Fucker,
you know,
if you get caught in that guy's triangle
that that dude's been there a thousand
times, he's just got, he's
got a, just a feel for it.
That extraordinary field
that rarely happens.
Like Ronda Rousey's armbars same
kind of thing and you're locked down.
It's just death. And I saw that once
I saw the lockdown I was like, oh,
he's in trouble.
Like if he let them get that,
we're that confident.
Fuck yeah man.
You know I would say people were telling
me if things you were saying before
that matching or predictions and
man that kind of stuff scares you.
I'm like dude, they like you or shot
very conservative. You and John.
John have so much confidence
in me that that's like man,
like the feeling of getting smoked and
what you guys would think like damn,
like I didn't ever want that.
Look in your eye. That, what that,
that like third or fourth time that I
did a open Mike night where I was getting
a little confidence and that one time
I went on stage and I thought I'd,
I'd thought I'd do something different
and not tell jokes but talk about might
be like a comic talking about
his wife and his girlfriend,
but it's not really his wife and it
ends up being some stripper and he's
delusional and he thinks it's his
wife and I try to do that on stage,
you know what I mean? Like
later, but it was, it wasn't, uh,
no one laughed and I got off stage
and you were like, come on, follow me.
You were like this. We
were like, you didn't,
you couldn't even look me in the eye did.
You're like, no, no, no. You were like,
what are we going to do back with me?
And you took me the back and you fucking
lectured me in a good way. He said, dude,
you can't do shit like that.
You gotta be a bad motherfucker to pull
something like that. No one gets it, dude.
You got to tell jokes,
he can't get up there and and try to
tell a story and it's an open mic night.
He goes, dude, I felt like that was
like you talk about bombing on stage,
eat a thousand Dick's.
I felt that what I was trying to do is
figure out how I could describe it to you.
The reason why I wasn't looking at you
in the Ui. So it was when we, I was like,
come on, come here man. All I was
thinking is how, what is the best way?
Cause this is a very sensitive moment
and I knew that it'd be devastated.
It was a very sensitive moment.
So I'm trying to figure out how
it look that look, that look,
I don't want that look, I don't
want that look of, Oh that's chose.
Look of how can it be nice to tell
me something I did was terrible.
How could he be nice?
Like if I went out there and the boiler
just going ankle lock in five seconds,
like right away, just right away.
Like let's say I did something stupid.
I tried to pull guard and I,
I clowned around a little bit for five
seconds and I pulled guard and it got me
ankle lock and I tap like before
even yank and I just happened.
It was like early tap.
It was the worst possible case scenario.
And what would you, you'd be like the same
thing it'd be um, I'd be like, ah, Shit.
I would just say shit happens bro.
Like what could you say?
Can you say, I didn't want that look on
your face. You know why? You know why?
Because you the more shit you talk to
your friends and all that about I get
Eddie's going to dominate and like
John Talks making bets with people.
He's betting its house
and shit. I'm like, Ooh,
like not only you can handle me
and you like, dude, you fucked up.
But like all that shit you
talked, you're like, damn,
I talked a lot of shit ends on video.
That's not going to look,
that's going to stay. I'm going
to eat all those words. Fog.
So that I think about that shit too.
You talk like John John's town,
everyone like,
like someone from the Gracie family called
him up and they wanted to make a bet
and John Jackson, you, you want,
are you serious how sure I am.
He's going to win a bet your house.
You want to bet your house,
literally bet your house. He made a
real bet and the guy wouldn't take it.
Ooh, that's, that's crazy shit man.
It was when I was a purple belt,
I was in the finals of a tournament
and John Jack was the uh,
the ref and the dudes that
my opponent in the final,
his coach like John John, you can't
rep this match. That's your student.
This is ridiculous. And then John John
said, okay, you're right, this rough,
this match doesn't need a Rep. And he sat
down next to his other coach and goes,
cause go ahead. Start finding my boy's
going to get your boy and an arm bar.
It's going to be as right arm.
And I,
everyone heard that and all
of a sudden I'm like, oh no,
I'm fucked. Talk about pressure.
No one's ever done shit like that.
That is a true story, man. That's
a true story. So what he sat down,
I got the guy in iron bar so he
did it because John Jack said it,
he says that it's almost like he says it,
he wants me to hear it so that I have no
choice to go out there and fuck and go
to war. You know what I mean? Like I have
no choice fucker. You know what I mean?
Whatever he has to say to make it happen,
he goes, I just put, because I like,
I think he, he knows that if
there's enough pressure that I'll,
I'll be forced to do my game. All he
wants to do is play my game. Right.
So he had to play some psychological
warfare with me and my camp. He,
it was all about playing my shit cause
how can I get this motherfucker to do
what he does here all the time. You know,
cause I haven't competed in a long time.
I could easily folded from the
pressure people get the, you know,
jitters 11 years, people fold.
This is a huge match, man.
10 planet against,
you know,
versus a Gracie like right
there and our hometowns and,
and everyone's screaming and there's
some crazy shit, a lot of pressure.
My family and my mom, I
thought my, my son, my wife
was there. I'm like, Holy Shit.
My Mom's and my wife's. I was
just like a, this is like,
like I'm at the MGM granted some
main event. I'm like, Holy Shit.
That's what it is. So much pressure
place was pat my head instructors,
all my students, all the shit you
talk, John Shock, all of these ev,
all this pressure. So I
thought, man, there's a chat.
People fold under pressure.
There's a lot of pressure,
all different kinds of dimensions.
And will I be one of those dudes a
fault? But what I realize is, is that,
uh, I do want to, I did want to
win. I did want to do my best.
That's the most important.
Just clear out all the bullshit.
Do you want to do your best? Yes. The best
thing is to do your shit. Go after them.
Trust your cardio,
go after.
And all those little leaks on this.
Damn,
that was about to burst
with all this pressure,
all these leaks I could fix all these
leaks and how to do is focused on one
thing. Just going after him and trusting
myself. Okay, cool. Cool. So then Bam,
it was all about, dude,
you have no choice.
Go out there and fucking make it happen.
You know you're not folding
under this pressure.
You're going to do it and you're going
to go after him 100% and you're going to
do your best. Did you think
about doing it? Hi. No, not
at all. No. Too much pressure.
Too much pressure.
When you're under pressure,
I don't suggest inhalation of cannabis.
What am I a light edible? No, I didn't
even want to take us so much weed in me.
I want them.
The one thing I learned at John Johnson,
I was never stoned when I went to John
jocks cause I wanted to make sure we
trained at the same time we were going
to compete. I wanted to train right.
There was that same time,
like six 30 ish,
seven 30 or seven and that
area just get my body going.
A million percent shark tank,
like a motherfucker getting my ass kick.
And I never had been tapped so much in
my life going through these shark tanks.
It's crazy.
It feels,
it doesn't feel great to constantly get
tapped by people and getting fucking
wrecked, you know, trying to last
an hour straight with fresh animals,
black belts,
waiting to jump on you and start on your
back and starting the mount sort of bad
position.
I was getting fucked up dude.
And it's the only way to do
it though, right? Yeah. Yeah.
Um, and the swimming, that was really a
fascinating thing that we talked about.
Yeah. The swimming, the swimming was
important because I'm not a real athlete.
I don't ever do cardio.
I do Jujitsu for the it,
for the fun of it and it, the fact
that keeps you in shape. That's uh,
that's awesome. Beautiful. Kill two birds
with one stone. It's fun. It's awesome.
My job is teaching people on a
strangle each other and break limbs.
Fucking lucky. Embrace
that shit. I love it. Uh,
competing is different. You're, there
were days where I got to see my son,
five minutes here, five minutes
there, day after day. I'm like, damn,
I'm not seeing might son that much.
I like, can't wait to get home just,
just to get home before he goes to sleep,
just so I could see them for
five minutes. And Mike, man, uh,
my wife's under a lot of pressure. She's
handling everything. I'm always training.
Everything's on my schedule.
Everything is priority is me.
And that's not the way it's always been.
You know, we work together, but the,
I told her this two months,
I go,
I could lock my way up in big bear and
I'd be away from you guys and do it that
way. That's a good idea. If people heard
I did that, they would think, buck,
he's doing the right thing,
but,
or I could train hard and you let me do
whatever the hell I want to do for this
match. And I don't want to
hear any, uh, I don't, uh,
I have to be able to do with
without any stress. Cause we have a,
we have a baby boy and we, we turn it off.
It's a, it's a team. It's a management.
I got my time. She's got her time, you
know, and we work together. But this camp,
I said I can go to big bear and
you have to take care of them 24,
seven or I could stay here
but you still take care of.
But I get to see him too
in between all this shits.
I'm still here with the
family as much as I can,
but I need you to understand the man.
She was just did everything
and made sure that my geek,
you know,
man,
she's just amazing and I'm so,
it was beautiful though.
The training camp was beautiful,
so I thought,
should I do the Marcella Garcia
thing? He's, and he says,
I don't do any strength and conditioning.
I don't do any conditioning.
I just trained you. You'd it too hard
every day. I don't know how many hours.
See that's what Marcella does. And he
gets away with it. He doesn't do anything.
Actually,
he just does Jujitsu and some sense
you've heard that from several people like
Pedro, his Oh said that all I do is
MMA. That's it. I don't do anything.
I was to do any card soccer.
Robin ever did cardio,
but generally 99% of professional
athletes have a cardio program.
They got a system and they got trainers
and they'd have clocks and they got,
they got the heart rate,
they got the thing on the heart and then
the pull nothing on the arm and it's a
science and they master
their body and Ooh,
look what the body does all
its better here and then,
and they've mastered that
Shit. Uh, Marcella doesn't
do that. So I thought, man,
it's way better. It's
easier, it's lazier. If I,
if I just fucking just
try to just do Jujitsu.
But I thought about that for the first
week of camp once it was official,
but then I thought,
you know what?
I don't want to go into this
match with any fucking doubts.
Let me get my cardio on. The
professional tip, you know,
for once in your life train,
like a professional athlete.
I was already lifting weights three years,
so I was already strong. I was ready.
I go, when I got offered the
fight, I was like, Kelly,
I'm stronger than I've ever been. I was
already in good shape to teach and stuff,
but I never did cardio. So I decided,
okay, fuck it. I'm going to do cardio.
Like a professional athlete. What should
I do? I don't like to run. Sign up.
You run, you swim or you bike,
you know, that's good enough. Uh,
for 2003, I did the rock climbing
treadmill. Remember that Shit at 25,
I can't remember that shit. Right. We
did like three minutes and then pop up.
I don't remember the time thing.
I was just doing rounds. Yeah,
I think it was like whatever the
rounds were. And Abu Dhabi. Yeah. Yeah.
So I don't really remember too much of
what I was thinking back then. Again,
I never, I just, I did
that for 2005. I would,
I'll be too, I thought, okay, this
is fun. Treadmill, rock climbing.
But I got hurt 2005 I would dominate.
So this time I thought,
and then I started swimming when I was
using your pool and I started swimming.
I think that was for the palm peanut
fight. I go, fuck the Treadmill,
rock climbing, let me try swimming.
So I'd swim, I swam a little bit.
And then that the Katrina had, that
didn't end up happening. So again,
I'm not a professional athlete, but
I decided, fuck it, I got six weeks,
let me get my cardio together
professionally. We go in there and uh,
the one thing I, I decided to swim, go
into 24 hour fitness down a big ass clock.
I didn't even know what I was going to
do. I just thought, okay, well let me,
let me do, let me just sprint,
sprint or across the pool.
See how long it takes. There's a, as
soon as the clock hit 12 I sprinted.
And it took me either from like 20
to 30 seconds to get across the pool.
So I decided,
you know what I'm going to do 20 times,
I'm going to sprint across the pool and
and rest the remainder of that minute.
And as soon as the clock hits the
12 Pam spread across again and,
and then whenever I get their rest,
the rest of the minute and every time
they had hits 12 go and I do that 20 times
just because we was 20 minute rounds.
I don't know.
I don't know if it was too much
or too little and said, hey,
it's symbolic or whatever.
So I know sprinting a hundred
percent running 20 times is a lot.
Sometimes you want to do 10 sprints or
you want to do the sand dunes spring up
the sand and six times or seven times,
I've said 20 times it's 20 minutes.
That might not be that much.
But what I learned about myself
is how long it takes to recover.
That was the most
important thing I didn't,
that would have fucked me up
in this fight. If I didn't
do the cardio I want to,
I would have fell apart.
I would've, I would've,
I didn't understand how the heart works.
So Jen, you know, I've been training uh,
consistently since 2003 at my gym.
And the way I treated my cardio
was I would go as hard as I can.
And then once I start
gassing, I thought, okay,
the rest of this round
I'm going to hold on,
sit on my ass for maybe five minutes,
maybe 10 minutes,
depending on I'm not training for anything
and then get my second wind and then
come back.
That's what I thought cardio was,
is like you go once you're out
of gas, hey, you're out of gas.
You're going to need some rest.
Settle down for a while. You got far,
you've got seven minutes,
you have seven minutes before you gas.
That's what I thought it was seven.
I didn't know about recovery and the
mastery of recovery and that gas that you
can recover from that easy.
You just got to know you can,
if you don't think you can, you
won't. So by doing those sprints,
he gave you confidence that you could
use 100% of your energy like around it.
I would see you doing like what
kind of swimming? Just swim.
Basic fucking swimming like a lake, you
know what I mean? Your breast stroke like,
yes. What is that called?
One Rep. Left arm. Right arm.
What does it freestyle.
Okay.
Just like a retard. I'm not
bad. You just trying to,
I'm just ranting. I'm panicking
across the pool. Okay, so by the time,
the first time I get a bye,
the first one,
it's not that I get by like that was
the first one I spent it and I'm waiting
inside of me and I'm like, I could really
just keep going, but I'm just like,
this is what I'm doing. So at, you know,
after like the third one, I was like,
I'm at the edge of the pool.
I got this,
I got 30 seconds,
35 seconds to recover at the 10th one
thinking about quitting after every
spirit. Am I good people at the pool,
there's old ladies by the sauna
there likes to watching this go, Ooh,
this tattooed God.
Dang the,
and I got 10 more to go
dying.
But I know that.
But when there's,
when the clock hits the eight I'm dying.
When it hits the nine I'm dying
when it's a 10 still dying,
but damn right before his day 11 take a
big deep breath ready to go because you
have to go at that 12 and the crazy thing
about it is you don't need a trainer
to tell you to hurry up because you're
going across the pool as fast as you can.
Cause you're, you want an a lot
of time to rest and recover.
You'll racing for that recovery time.
So there's no way,
I never went a hundred percent I had to
go as 100% as fast as I can get across
that pool so I can rest. So as
you never didn't go 100% yes, yes.
I didn't need anybody
to tell him. I go, dude,
I know I'm trying to rest on that
mother about it. I'm trying to arrest.
So it makes me, it did. It kicks my ass.
I want to quit it for tech.
I did a lot for teens, a lot
of them. So it's all good.
I could do it. I still gained, I made
gains the day. I don't have to go 20.
I'm like, fuck, I'm not 15. I'm like, I
could do fuck five seems like so many.
I'm like, fuck, when I'm like at
seven or eight and I'm on my blog,
I've got 12 more. Ha and you
can't stop. You're on a clock.
When that clock hits 12 you've got
to go. You know? So it's a nightmare.
It's torture. No one's forcing me
to do it, but I just fucking do it.
And I did it twice a week.
And to some,
there's some cardio machines
out there that lap at that.
They think that's nothing. And uh, there's
professional athletes go to, we weren't,
well, that's just because
you build up from a base.
And these guys have been going at
it like that for a long time. Yeah.
But what ended up happening? Hah. Uh,
I dunno how football player would do
it or if that's fucking child's play or
whatever. But what it did
for my Jujitsu automatically.
I knew in the middle
of that our shark tank,
when I hit that first [inaudible] I
knew you just tell yourself, dude,
you could recover. Find this place to out
conserve your energy. Wait 30 seconds,
it's going to come back. And
then I'm back. Oh my God. Cool.
So at first you're like,
oh shit,
I want a two weeks ago
before I started doing this,
I would have said it's over son. I ran
out of gas. I'm going to stop. I got,
I did good. I got seven minutes,
got eight and it's got 12 minutes.
That's not the way it was. So out. Keep
going for an hour, dude. My muscles would,
our muscles would be tired. More tired
than my heart. My heart could keep going.
I used to be dead after that.
That shark tank in the beginning for our,
I'll be dead just from the shark tank did.
I wasn't even getting that tired
after shark tank. That's incredible.
There were some, there was times
where a shark tank is people.
You've said that term a couple
times. Um, uh, there's, you know,
you get as many guys as
you want in the shark tank.
It's dedicated at one person obviously
dedicated to me on this training camp.
I'd get in the middle and they'd be, you
know, three to 10 guys sitting around,
black belt,
purple belt and they're all waiting their
turn to get there five minutes with me,
like starting on my back, starting
in the mouth, all these positions,
some like in my guard
or I'm in their guard.
Just all of these positions inside
controlling me on the belly with the under
hook on the back a lot,
a lot,
mount a lot and man,
just fresh guys coming in.
All my best guys coming in get mangled
and tapped and cause I'm trying to
conserve my energy. I'm trying to last
an hour, but you know, then you're like,
dude, you got to trust your cardio. You
can't conserve. You had a bad night.
I was having bad nights, good nights,
bad nights, a lot of shit, Sean shock,
you know.
Uh,
the main thing is I didn't want to go
in there and be too cautious and goes 20
minutes.
I bet it would be.
Cause I would get that way in shark
tank sometimes where I'm like,
dude I got Sean Ballinger next,
I got Jared Carlson,
I gotta save my energy
with this dude cause I got,
I'm looking around as I'm rolling
of the shark tank going, Oh my God,
these guys are coming after me.
So I would just be really conservative
and what that would happen that would,
I train these killers, right? They
know how to close the fucking deal.
So anybody pays cautious with you.
That's part of the game.
You just keep getting deeper and deeper
and deeper. And that's what happened.
I was just sinking in quicksand with
that mentality of trying to conserve and
not really attacking cause the attack
is what puts them on defense and stops
there forward march.
So you have to constantly,
even if you don't have a game
plan right now, just disrupt them.
So what percentage do you think your your
game improved because your cardio bump?
1000% because now I knew.
Now I knew that I would've
thought that in and I would dive.
As soon as I started breathing hard
that it was over done, I did what I can.
Now I'm breathing. I didn't know
that. You can recover over and over.
When the swim sprints,
you're reminded over and over your dad
and you did another sprint. Your Dad,
you did another sprint, you kept going.
You were dead at 10 and you kept going.
You kept recovering and you
recover. Quit. And after,
after reminding yourself that
you can recover during Jujitsu,
during those starts, Angela,
you can recover relaxed.
You're gonna recover instead of panicking
because if you panic and think you can
now you had a downward
spiral with your cardio,
that panic will suck up more than
it's going to be harder to recover.
Cause you're panicking.
You think it's over.
But once you get to the point
where you know you can recover,
you stop telling Yourself, oh, I can
recover it. Relax. You just do it.
You're huffing and puffing.
You're not even worried.
There's not even an ounce of panic.
You know you're going to come back and
that is what that performance Saturday
night was all about is knowing that
I could recover. That was huge.
There were times where I didn't want
to see him smell blood and I go,
I just need the time recover. I would
talk to John John, stop breathing.
I'm trying to recover not just John John,
how much like time and looking over
trying to act like it's nothing,
but meanwhile I just want him to
relax. We're not doing it. Just relax,
relax and there are no, no need to hush
now, but those were all mental games,
but that was only because
I was doing that naturally.
It was only because I knew I
need a little time to recover.
I didn't know the professional
athletes shit before.
This is like nothing new
to professional athletes.
What I'm doing is I'm letting people that
aren't professional answers and never
done cardio.
This is what you discover.
This is why cardio is so important is
understanding how your body can recover.
Kendall Grovesite asked me once after
he did the ultimate fighter said,
learn from Tito. He just said, cardio
is everything, man. It's everything.
He just couldn't stop
stressing and he's like,
I'm a different fighter because of cardio.
Yeah.
If you got the ability to keep going off
to your cardio diminishes the ability
to recover that,
that and knowing that you can recover
and having faith in your body.
You never panic. You just keep
going. You just know this thing.
Not that I'm just going to chill here.
It's going to co there's
back I got now I got power.
Now you can throw a combination and
then you wait for that green light.
Now you can just combination women.
Maury Smith, remember Maury Smith? Yeah.
He used to do a lot of swimming.
Maurice was a UFC heavyweight champion.
He was a champion. Kickboxer he
was a fucking extreme fighting.
Remember he was like one of the first
cars. They were winning by head kick.
I could barely walk after I was done with
20 I got out of the pool and the main
thing is at the very end you gotta walk.
You got to keep your body moving.
You got, so I would walk
around the pony up to walk.
It's good to walk when you're super tired.
So your body gets used to moving while
it's recovering. Yeah. Why is it bad?
They'll just lie down. I've
heard it's bad to lie down. Yeah,
because then your body gets used to
having to have everything shut down to
recover.
You want to be able to recover and
still beyond 30% you know what I mean?
It's probably better to recover,
jog a little bit and then cool down.
You know what I mean?
And they get to the point now where
you're recovering and you never stopped
jogging. That's probably
the best. I'm just guessing.
But for sure when you can barely walk
and you're dead and talk to try to walk
and to try to keep going,
that's the very least you can do for sure.
Lying down is not the cause.
John.
Jack never let me line and get up and
keep walking. You want to recover?
Because when I would get to
that point in the beginning,
I would have walked around. I'm walking
around in John, I could barely walk.
I keep walking,
you got to keep the body moving.
So it's all basic shit
that I'm sure people know.
But for the people that have
never dove into competing or uh,
doing cardio,
I'm telling you a 43 years old and I'm
just discovering the magical powers of
mastering your body and knowing how fast
it can recover and when you have that
kind of confidence, that's, that's
what that performance is all about.
Trusting my cardio and I was able to
do it. It's about putting in the work.
You just put it in a tremendous amount
of work, two months worth of work,
the cardio work along with all the Jujitsu
Shark tanks and all the training and
sparring.
And Roland constantly spent a lot
of time with leg lock defense.
A lot of time. Wow. And
those guys out there,
I was getting help from so many guys at
their Max Bishop, uh, catch wrestler out.
And uh, and uh, I think he's an
Alabama somewhere out there and he's a,
I know him through Alan Belcher.
He was a got helped him with Paul Harris.
He's a lot of guys helped
Alan Belcher with Paul hearts.
Alan Belcher's DVD immunity. That
helped me a lot with, I was, I was on a,
I'm on a defensive a mission now I'm on
a mission to structurize and just get
all the best defense from everybody and
that most of it is from John Shock Cause
John John Defensively is probably the
one of the best ever as defenses is
legendary.
And so I'm just one by one every position
figuring out what are the absolute
best defense that things to do or should
your hands be, where should the legs be?
And when it comes to defense,
it's amazing because it's almost a
hundred times more complex than offense.
There's so much to defense because there's
only a few ways to build a skyscraper
or you know, to build
it right. There's rules,
but there's a million ways to
knock that motherfucker down.
You know what I mean?
There's so many ways that disrupt and
it's so many different levels. You know,
you could come up with all
these different angles,
so many missiles and demos and all
that shit. You know what I mean?
Same thing with, uh, techniques
and triangles there, the setup,
there's so many steps to the setup.
So there's so many different places along
the way where you could disrupt that.
Nip it in the bud at different levels.
And then at the end,
the one thing I've learned is
all these top guys, Alan Belcher,
Max Bishop, Eric Paulson,
uh, go car to beat you.
And I was going to work with them.
I just never got around with it.
But I did work with Caren Darryl
Beatty and from Hyaston, uh,
he came down to a shark tank and
just fucking wrecked my legs. Man.
Current Europeans, a beast. It's
about a mother fucker. Oh yeah. So,
um, I, I dean a dean lister,
we were texting back and forth.
I was like on like texting people videos
and stuff on my leg lock master friends
and they're like Eric Paulson and dean
lister and Manny getting parian and all
these guys getting their advice every,
but everyone has a different
way of escaping 50, 50.
Everyone has a different way of
addressing a straight ankle lock,
everything to heal hooks.
Everybody's,
there's so many different ways to fuck
up perfection, a perfect submission,
so many different ways.
And it's fascinating that there's
way more defense in there,
his office and all these
different things to learn.
And then what I'm doing is I'm so
fascinated with this, uh, it's,
it's just I'm on a quest to make 10 planet
just known for their defense and it's
fun. It's like a new thing. Like
why I'm so obsessed with it, man.
I'm on watching defensive
videos all the time,
just trying to come up
with the ultimate defense.
And what it does is not only is it making
10th planet stronger as an association,
but it's making my game stronger.
Why wouldn't I want to be,
have like amazing defense? I've always
been focused on Gnocchi or fence.
That's always been the problem in MMS.
What I was trying to fix,
that's what 10 plant was all about
is what are the problems and MMI,
the problems or bottom game.
So we're going to be bottom game happy,
we're going to be Nogi heavy and we're
going to have strikes in the mix.
That's the problem.
Would you Jitsu.
The problem isn't that a Jujitsu
guys are tapping on the UFC.
There's all these black belts are tapping.
We need to fix the defense.
Nobody was tapping these black belts.
They just were getting beat on their back.
That was the prom song.
Well, our defense is fine.
You keep working on the defense
over that Gracie Baha. Uh,
we're going to try to fix the pro this,
there's emergency Jujitsu is,
we needed some urgent care here.
We need some scientists on the case
and all my students, all my moon heads,
my head instructors were all there.
All my and our agents and all my science.
We need to fix my fucking problem
for Jujitsu. Keep working on your uh,
uh, passing from standing, which is
not a problem. And mmn it's like, man,
they can't pass standing.
The problem is they're not doing
much off their back authentically.
And that's what we're trying to do or
trying to fix that problem. And um,
Ooh,
what's that?
It's a fascinating thing to watch while
she put together this whole system and
other other guys inside your
system. Watch them add moves. And,
and you know, and, and, and build it all
and figure it all out and watch it evolve.
You know, it's always been
intriguing. Interesting too.
When I get injured and then come back,
get injured, take a few months off,
come back, oh no, we're not even doing
that anymore. We found a new path.
Like there's all these new paths that
come up or a new way to get around
something. And this cuts to the chase and
this is quicker. Someone once made the,
uh,
the analogy of Jujitsu to chess and a,
and most people like love that analogy,
but you rejected it immediately.
You know, I said, Jujitsu makes
chess look like checkers. Yeah.
And there's also so many different
things involved too. Not just the moves,
but also the,
the amount of discipline that you have
to have to get your body into position to
play the game. I mean, you have to like
what you're talking about, what you did.
I mean,
there's not a lot of people that have
that kind of willpower to force themselves
to do those fucking crazy sprints,
to force themselves to do the shark tanks.
To force himself to train and when you
can barely walk and you feel like you
have a heart attack, not everybody has
that in them to push themselves that way.
So it's not just more,
and it's variations in the attacks
and the counters and defense,
but it's also much more complex
mentally and emotionally.
It requires more of you.
But I gotta imagine man,
that like when you put it all together,
like what was that feeling like?
What was it feeling like when it
was over? Look, coiler didn't tap,
but you dominated that match.
There's just no doubt about it.
And even more so in light of what
you're saying about how you want the,
the reversals,
which is,
are you adjusting and then you're
getting back to that position again.
That's how I roll. I mean, um,
it's just, it's incredible.
It's amazing. What did it feel like?
What it feels like when it was all over
before hoists? Gracie
got it. Got Mad at you.
Yeah.
What did it feel like?
So mad at me and I don't know what he
thinks he were talking shit about his
family and about toilet.
Someone lied to him,
someone lied to them because most
of them went up to hoists and told.
And I want to find out
who the hell that says.
Someone told her voice that I talk shit
on the family and, and uh, you know,
maybe he believes that he shouldn't
believe it, but he came up to me and uh,
but before that you gotta I gotta read you
this really quick. Um, you know, let me,
while you looking for it now that I found,
found him in my first book
and the Jujitsu unleashed,
it came out in 2005. This was 2005,
two years after you tap toilet.
This was how I opened this,
opened the book with,
this is a very special thanks.
Goes out to the Gracie family though.
We have different views on the geek.
I do appreciate tremendously what you
did for the world of martial arts and my
world. Thank you Heleo for being the
warrior, an innovator that you are,
who has tougher sons and you know,
one thank you Carlos senior for taking
in the Machados as sons of your own and
introducing them to the fascinating
world of Jujitsu. Thank you.
Hoary on for producing the UFC.
Without you,
the MMA industry would not exist and
I would still be deejaying in clubs.
Thank you [inaudible] for having the
courage to step up and fight and eight and
16 men tournaments just to prove
the effectiveness of Jujitsu.
You will always be a legend.
Thank you.
Hixon for being the superman
of the Jujitsu world.
There is no one I would rather
see in the ring than you.
And thank you heuler for being you
without you and you're unbelievable
accomplishments and the grappling world.
This book would not exist.
That was 2005 and after
Metamora Saturday night,
I was emotional. I was crying. I just
went 20 minutes and they're just,
it was just, man, I can't tell
you. It was like I W I dunno man.
It was just glorious. And, um,
I got on the Mike and I, what I
just read, I just said that again.
I said the same thing again on the Mike.
I just wanted to let everybody
know we all come from the Gracies.
We're all Gracie.
It's not 10th planet against the Gracies.
We're doing this for Jujitsu. The
10 planet thing is to Jujitsu. They
don't want to hear that shit though
because people don't want to hear that
anybody is, you know, they, they'll,
they're idea is that no, you know,
we don't need your help.
You know,
their idea is like we're doing this and
you're doing something different and
your stuffed slugs poke you.
And so then I get off stage,
hugged my wife, hugged my mom. Um,
I mean when I say they're saying
that like, you mean I'm being, um,
they're not really saying that.
No one's really saying that,
but there's no one wants to hear that
you're, you know, they have pride.
No one wants to hear that. You're like,
you're trying to fix Jujitsu, you know?
Yeah.
That attitudes element,
Brazilian Jiu Jitsu community
that had a dead ignored me.
Let's just say that they're just,
well, let's be honest though. I mean,
it's kind of a tricky situation because
no one has more faith than you than I
do. No one, no one believes
just you're just a unique dude.
You can figure shit out. You have a
mind for games and you have a mind for,
for strategy. I mean, you just, and you're
really ridiculously talented, new Jitsu,
creativity aside and all the other things
aside. But people who didn't know you,
they saw this one match
and then after that match,
they saw you fight Leo
Vieira and Leo Vieira, um,
basically dominated you on points.
You hurt your rib really early in
the match and a half way through.
He would have still beat
me anyways. It was, it was,
but what I was going to say is there was
after this incredible emotional fight
and you know, you beat a legend and
then you'd lost to another legend.
You got dominated by another legend.
So in their mind,
they didn't take anything into account.
They didn't take into account
what a crazy experience.
It must've been for some kid to be the
first American ever tap at Gracie and
Jujitsu competition. I mean it was
bananas. The whole thing was bananas.
You were crying. I was crying.
We were freaking out. And
then all of a sudden, boom,
you got to fight again. Now you're
fighting Leo. Vieira it's like holy shit.
Like your whole thought process
was around fighting boiler Gracie.
Like I remember leading up to it.
You just kept talking about to boilers
in my division I might fight a boiler,
I might have to fight Beutler I mean all
the time. What you're training, Euler,
Euler. That name kept coming
up over and over. No, no, no.
So when it did happen and then boom,
and you won much like you know when you
were throwing up on on Saturday night
after the event is over,
like this is gigantic dump and release it.
So after all that, I went outside the
tent and I have this, the tough med.
They're my sponsors. They have this film
crew following me for this documentary.
They're putting together and they follow
me. I just needed a place to throw up.
I ran out of the place,
got on my knees.
It's just like throwing up and then I am
not the no comes from behind and pours
water on me. John Jocks,
everyone's following me.
I thought it was funny
because I actually thought,
anyways, I'm throwing up and then I
hear this voice behind me and said,
uh, is good. You say that about my family,
like and I wipe the
throw out from my mouth.
I looked behind me and it's hoists Gracie.
And when someone says that to you that
that could be followed with a hug or a
shake. Like it's good that you said that
about my family. Right, right, right.
Well good now. Right? Like what's Max?
Is it going to be a pound I had or
it could be something else like,
because you were always talking shit
on my family before and I'm like, what?
I never, that's what he said. Yeah.
He said it was like the craziest
backhanded compliment ever.
He said it's good that you said that about
my family and I turned around and my,
wow. How is Gracie man,
that's hoists Gracie.
That's like Mike Tyson. You know,
the first time you're meeting him?
The first time ever
talking to him I think,
but I've seen him in different places
and we've been in the same events and
stuff. And um, but um, he uh,
he uh,
okay.
Goes,
it's good that you said that about my
family because you used to talk shit on my
family and I said, I ain't never talked
to you in your family. And my first book,
I thank all of you, including you.
And I'm like kind of pointing out him,
I'm a coil or Heleo.
I'm telling me somewhat,
whenever someone told you about me,
they're lying.
I've never said it will only
a retard would talk shit
about the crazies in the G.
And that's in the Jujitsu business.
You're in the Jujitsu business and you
have no respect for the Gracies, right.
What they've done. And now
just physically, what did
he say that, um, don't,
don't put your finger at me.
And then again on my face like
you want me to kick my ass?
And John Jock had to get between us to
like stop him from like getting in my
face cause he thought about now I'm
disrespecting him cause I'm like Kinda
pointing at him. You know he thought
I was, but look what he said.
This is the craziest thing of all
liquid. He said, let me just quote on,
okay.
I don't know what fight he was watching.
I saw what he said.
I'll paraphrase if you want it or not.
Try it here. I got it right here. He said,
uh, I wanted to talk to them for years
but never had the chance to meet him.
Hoist,
hold MMA fighting.
I met him after the fight and he was
there throwing up heuler dominate him,
dominate him so much.
He did so much strength,
but he threw up after the fight.
Right?
How crazy.
I told him that I liked what he said
after the fight but didn't like the fact
that he was always talking trash
about boiler and my family.
He stood up and started yelling.
So I also raised the tone of my
voice and told them I didn't like it.
He said he always gave my family credit,
but I know it's not true.
He said he always kept my family credit,
He always seems,
he always talks trash about my
family enough with this shit.
He said he never talked bad about.
My family always gave us credit.
He kept raising the tone of his voice.
I told him to shut up.
So as John Jacques Machado came in and
we didn't need this and ask Bravo to
leave. Wow. And then he goes, ah,
Gracie said he would not compete
against Bravo in a grappling match,
but seemed open to an MMA fight.
Can we slap each other?
Can we beat each other up
or can we beat each other?
Gracie reply to laugh when asked if
he'd accept a fight and Metamorris I'm a
valid today.
Valerie Trudeau fighter.
I'm not to score points
of fight with time limit.
Let's fight with no time limit with
punches alive. I'm a valid tuto finer.
I don't compete in grappling tournaments.
He's the only competed grappling wise.
See that one while ed smile fire, right?
Yeah. While they strangled him
while he put them to sleep.
That was her after the
UFC. Yeah. So what do you,
I mean after all that stuff I Reggie
there was in my book and then here like
someone's lions to most likely mean,
you know,
people talk shit and people
want to be friends with him,
so they probably talk shit to him.
He's never talked to you before,
so he's never heard you say it.
You definitely haven't said
it in an in print anywhere.
He definitely never set an Nvidia
because I know you haven't said it.
You were always remarkably
composed about that. You know,
you were always remarkably composed you,
the,
the worst you ever did was, um,
asked to do it again. You know,
that was a few years back.
You asked to do it again,
but you were never disrespectful about it.
Yeah.
I thought most people in the late
nineties most small Jujitsu players in the
late nineties our dream
was to go against Heuler.
He was the best for that was the pinnacle.
Imagine, not only is he the best,
but he's the son of Helio Gracie.
That's the, like the prints, you know,
at one 45. Damn, that was the
one that was the one 45. Hixon.
So I got lucky enough to go
against them once and man,
I have a reason to do it twice.
Whether it's like the proof that it was
wasn't a fluke or that it was a fluke,
whatever. It was lucky whatever
you want to say. But I thought,
damn, I can make this happen. I
have a reason to make it happen.
Do you want to keep doing this? Do
you want to keep competing now? I,
if the money's right, but that's one thing
I don't even want to get into. Like, uh,
the last thing I want to do is stress
about my next opponent or, or, uh, uh,
a trilogy with them, which
I'm not. I'll be open to it.
I just don't want to
talk and call people out.
And what are you going to do with
this and what he could do with that.
I want no stress right now.
That's what I want.
I want to spend time with my family,
spend time with my students, have fun,
enjoy my life right now.
I don't know,
as soon as there's another opponent and
looming now I've got to study is I'm
thinking about, I don't want to think
about anything. I just want to have fun.
I think
metamorris has real
potential, man. I really do.
I think there's something they could do.
I think there's something they can do
if they keep putting on these match ups
like this. You know, when people saw that
match between you guys Saturday night,
that was exciting as fuck. That was
really, really exciting. Yeah. You know,
and if they have more matches like that,
more a really good high
level exciting matches,
you get to see real
good technical Jujitsu.
I think people start to really enjoy it.
And the other thing about
Jujitsu as opposed to a MMA is,
um,
if it's especially Nogi,
I see no reason why that can't
eventually be on television. You know,
when I look at like watching
Marcelo Garcia match or watch a, uh,
jock ra was fighting it out with Dhabi
or in any of the really high level guys
that compete, not with Dobie, they're
fucking murderers. Vinny Magallanes.
These guys are exciting to
watch, man. It's wild techniques.
Chrome Gracie pulls off, you know,
it's fun to watch him strangled.
Especially submission only. No master Vic
Vic Dobby loud. She's Spanish. Joe Rogan.
I love that dude.
Me and him are actually,
our first show is June 1st it's the going
to put on a grappling shit going to be
on Spanish TV. It's done. Oh Shit.
It's called Eddie Bravo invitational and
it's going to be two 16 men submission
only tournaments.
One 45 same day weigh in one 70 same
day when and such as sensors for Spanish
television. We're going to focus
on white people and black people,
but we're going to, the spotlight's
going to be on the Latin fighters and,
and the two Latin fighters,
the one we're going to that's already
in his Geo Martinez is one of my black
belts.
Amazing.
He's a breakdancer who just killing
people. He's going to do the one 45,
he's going to be the feature star and
he speaks Spanish and all that. And uh,
his brother, Richie boogey man
Martinez, who's awesome. Awesome.
He's a brown belt. He's doing MMA. He's
for Roche was talking about Spartan.
Both those guys are true. Spartans there.
They both have crazy dexterity to yes,
they're super flexible. Break
Dancers, amazing at Jujitsu and uh,
they're tearing it up right now and
he's going to be the feature at the one
seven. It's going to be at the
Florentine Gardens Sunday, June 1st,
and then the Florentine
Gardens in Hollywood. It's
Hollywood. Yeah. Yeah. Sunday,
June 1st Sunday. June 1st in
Hollywood. We're taping it for TV,
so it's, um, uh, but
we're getting, you know,
obviously we want to pack
the place too and afterwards,
as soon as we finish taping
those two 16 men brackets,
we're going to have 10 planet anniversary
party there too. It's a giant club.
It's, it's awesome. Um,
it's a, it's a big venue.
So I'm home and where we have, um,
now it'd be awesome. And we have like,
schools competing against each other.
Like we got cold Breanna's best guy. Uh,
they say that gonna see, uh, that
they're going to give us their best guy.
They haven't confirmed anybody yet,
but they've all agreed that they're
going to send their best guy, uh,
Fabi these two over doom school. His
best guy. I'm Havi Vasquez, his best guy.
Cabrina the Mendez brothers all,
you know,
we want the best guys submission only
16 man tournament with overtime rounds.
Now let me ask you this. Yeah, that's
what I was going to ask you. What do you,
what happens in a situation
like, um, these, uh,
th th th there everyone's
going for submission only,
but there's no submission.
So as a draw and fight to just clearly
aren't draws. Yeah. Like what do you do?
How did you do to effect and Gracie
nationals and Gracie worlds? Um,
if you're in a 16 man bracket,
if you're both disqualified.
So the brackets ended up being
different, you know, after every,
after every a qualifier or that the
first bracket you see who makes it,
there's going to be some guys
that both got eliminated.
So you have to restructure it.
It's a different,
but you can do it and it works great.
So if the guys, if you get to a draw,
both guys are eliminated. Both guys.
If it's the finals, it's no time limit.
Oh my God. Yeah. So Gracie
nationals and Gracie world,
those are the most hard core.
That's the hardest tournament to win.
The hardest turning all those,
all those great ideas. That's all.
It's all about submission.
But Ebi,
which is what we're calling Eddie Bravo
invitation. We're going to have Ebi,
women, Ebi kids, Ebi, uh, um,
Grand Prix. So who, who organized the
Gracie nationals is that Rose Rose crazy.
Yeah.
That's a brilliant way to handle it.
Those are the best tournament.
And this year Gracie worlds is going
to be in Las Vegas at the Cox Pavilion.
It's blowing up dude. Submission
only is taken over. I mean,
if you're a geneticist, when is
it? When is it a crazy world? Ooh,
it's like a September 21st or something.
Damn it.
Go to Gracie tournaments.
Dotcom, Gracie tournaments.com.
It's sometime in December, I think
it's the 20th and the 21st of December,
I'm pretty sure. Or September,
I'm sorry, of September in Vegas.
Gracie world's submission only. World's
dude submission only. World's, you know,
so we're doing the same thing though, but
we're not doing it. It's an invitation.
We're going to pick 16 guys and 16 guys
on one side. 16 guys in the other side.
Uh, also the other 10 plan
planet representative at
one 70 is going to be, uh,
Nathan Orchard who's one of my assassins.
He's a white guy, but you know,
we're accepting white guys too. He's
going to, he's going to be at one 72.
So we're, we're taking
advantage of, uh, Vic doors,
connections in the Spanish TV market,
which are Jorge's producing
this as well or has involved.
So, yeah, man. So we're just,
we're doing it man. And, uh,
first we wanted to do it and do this
and give $100,000 to the winner just to
ensure if there's $100,000
prize and those guys,
what do we got to do to make sure these
matches are as exciting as possible?
You got to make some serious
cash incentives. So that's
what we wanted to do.
We wanted the first one, we were planning
on doing this. We had some investors,
got a few of them. It's very hard for
people to invest on a first show, but uh,
so we decided to do the first one,
no money.
We're just going to do it for
TV and just to get it going.
And then hopefully we attract sponsors,
but ultimately it's for TV to make it
work for TV to ensure that guys don't
stall, that there's no reason to stall.
You don't have to have, you have to have,
um,
incentives,
all these different incentives that
there's no reason for you to slow down,
slowing down.
It's not helping you financially.
You on the training is going to be
different for these kind of tournaments.
Instead of training for just get really
heavy on the passing and the sweeping
points tournaments, all you do is train,
sweeps and passes. That said submissions.
That's extra. You know, you
know, you're wasting your time.
Just you want to win a tournament
all your time, sweeping and passing.
That's how you win tournaments.
Because we want points. Yeah.
Cause that's what I want.
But if it's submission only tournament,
you still work on your sweet been passing,
but you got to be heavy on the submission
setups because that's how you're going
to close the deal. That's how you're gonna
make your money. So that's the plan. UH,
June 1st contact master
Vick at Eddie Bravo,
invitational.com. If, uh, you,
uh, you think you're a bad ass,
we want the best possible competitors,
the Beth, we'll pump it up before you.
Well, actually hold the event
when it's about to happen. Cool.
Have you in here again? Um,
what, what was I gonna ask? Um,
so this is what I'm going to.
And when you,
when you come off something like
Metamorris huge success, right?
I mean everybody was talking about all
over the, the mixed martial arts world,
Jujitsu world, the, I mean
it really made a big splash.
Why not do another event on the Internet?
Why not do your own events?
Exactly. Why fuck around with
the television show, you know,
cause metamorris there for pay per view
numbers. Everyone knows what good paper,
if few numbers off for the UFC and
let bad numbers and like the efficient
numbers come out and go,
oh shit,
you have c three had papapa
500 pay per views or whatever.
And a 500,000 proof of a Jujitsu paper
view wasn't as an a big isn't huge digits
is like underground. So if you get
like 5,000 paper views on Internet,
that's pretty good.
So the biggest show metamorris day was
9,000 paper views and I was pretty,
I think it was the first one we're Haji
Gracie fought Shesha this one with all
the promotion you did and
the hype and all this shit.
I'm thinking if they did nine
k before there are at least 20,
it could be even crazier than that.
This one could be 50. I don't know.
But you think about at least 20, right?
When did they know? I don't know.
No, I don't know. I don't know. Do
people, I don't know if they tell you,
I don't know how it gets out. Well, my
thought on it was that if I like 'em
RFA, which puts on some great
fights, you know, RFA, um, you know,
there's always some good matchups
um, you, you'd never hear about it.
Like an event goes by and you know,
you have to search the underground to
find results. It's not on the front page.
But if you go to mixed martial arts.com,
boom,
mixed martial arts.com you hit news.
The very first picture is bravo dominates
Gracie and metamorris three and it's
your picture doing this.
That never happens in a grappling match.
A grappling only match is the number
one thing on mixed martial arts.com.
That's crazy.
Ariel Helwani had me on and he's all about
him and my doesn't even like Jujitsu.
And he said, he said, I don't even like
watching Jui Jitsu. I don't like it.
But he said he was, he was thoroughly
entertained enough to want me on the show.
So I just,
I just did his earlier.
Why doesn't he like to just
some guys just like him, a man,
if a good paper view number
for Jujitsu is 9,000,
but for the UFC,
that'd be disastrous.
There's a large percentage of the u s
or the UFC fan base that is not into Jiu
Jitsu.
It would be interesting if it got to a
point where guys would not have to do MMA
to make real money. You know, like
there's a lot of guys like Jake shields,
a perfect example has an
amazing record in MMA,
but a lot of people don't
know Jake shields. Fucking
tremendous grapple. I mean,
a tremendous grasp.
There's a video and this is
obviously a early and John Fitch,
his career, you know, John
Fitch is much better now,
but there's a video of Jake Shields,
uh,
competing in a tournament at Jujitsu
tournament with John Fitch and he fucking
sweep some, takes us back,
choke some and you're like, wow.
Like the way he does it hits
the butterflies, sweeps them.
It's like fucking Jake shields.
Jujitsu is solid. Fuck man.
I would love to see a guy like that.
Like here it is right here. I mean,
he doesn't even necessarily have to
compete in MMA because the thing about it,
uh, Jake shields, like
Jake shields is a, I mean,
he's only lost three times
in the past fucking 10 years.
One of 'em was a, a knockout to
Ellenberger right after his dad died.
The other one's a lost GSP.
And then the most recent one,
he got dominated by Hector Lombard.
And you see him like compete with a guy
like Hector Lombard, especially in, uh,
in MMA. And you're like, my
God. Like, unless he catches
that guy in a submission,
look at that beautiful sweet.
He was working the Guillotine
and he hit that butterfly sweep.
But unless he catches a
guy in a submission, unless
he can get ahold of a guy,
he's going to have a real hard time
beating a guy like Hector Lombard,
like Lombard move.
So fucking fast man.
Yeah.
The way to make it work for TV,
for all those millions and
millions of UFC fans that don't,
that are bored by Jujitsu there,
there obviously that's why there's
such a big difference in numbers.
You got to get those fat. You got to make
Jujitsu entertaining enough for them.
They liked the UFC.
They will like submission,
a submission only Jujitsu.
I Nogi you can't have the gate.
The UFC fan base has not,
even though it's beautiful,
all the burn Bolo stuff and,
and,
and tug of war on the pants when
they're playing tug of war on the pants.
That's a beautiful, complex,
sophisticated, amazing, uh,
technique. But the people,
it's not good for TV, for TV.
It's just not good man. As
a TV producer that go, no,
well John John even said it and he's
like, you know, hey man, I love Jujitsu.
And this ship puts me to sleep. Yeah.
It's, it's hard to watch sometimes.
Yeah. It's got, if it's going
to be for TV, if I'm, if,
if someone said we're going to give you
one season and you know a TV producer or
a network head that doesn't give a shit
about tradition about you just they just
want fucking ratings for sure.
I would say it's not that we're not
going to have anything that that has that
can be described by using the word hold.
If there's any kind of hold in anything,
we don't want any of the grabbing and
yanking. Got To get rid of the geese.
It can't be a point system
it because think about this,
there's still a small percentage of the
people out there that prefer points over
submission only. It's crazy. Now you have
two matches, right? You have two matches.
Their both. Both matches have a
million dollar purse for the winner.
Whoever wins gets $1 million.
One is a points match.
One is a submission only match. Both of
those matches. There's a minute left. The,
and the points match that the guy on top,
he just passed the guard,
he's up three nothing and there's a
minute left. If you were his coach,
the guy on top,
there's $1 million on,
why would you tell them
to go for a submission?
Or would you tell them to hold Tom
Hall? Fuck yeah, I'd be screaming,
hold motherfucker.
Especially if you were the coach
and you've got 15% of that shit,
you already spent that shit.
You already promised your wife a new
fucking Toyota that was your shit.
You would say, oh, there's $1 million.
Don't do as a submission would be the
last thing on your mind, right? His mind,
right.
It would be the dose.
But if it's a submission only
match that end of the match.
We look way different. They would both
be going nuts for that million dollars.
It would look better for TV.
It'd be more exciting. Yeah.
So that ultimately better for Jujitsu?
Yes.
So submission only is better for
Jujitsu. It's better for TV. You got to,
you can't have tug of war. The
pants. It's a beautiful thing,
but it's going to be a niche thing.
It's always going to be underground.
That will never be mainstream.
That what about a standard outfit?
Like you think that you know, I
know you like g pants, but what?
What about if it was only tights? Only? I
think you should do what Abu Dhabi does.
ADCC they figured it out.
You let them wear whatever they want.
They could wear a g if they want,
but when you're allowed
to wear whatever you want,
if you could love the Geeky all
you want and worship the Geeky,
but you are not going to
wear it if you're allowed to,
you're not going to give your opponent
something to grab onto. In pride,
they would allowed anybody to wear it,
but none,
none of the Brazilian Jiu
Jitsu black belts wore their g.
None of them never allowed to.
They didn't want anybody to grab them.
So what you do is no,
you let them wear whatever they want.
Some people like wearing
tight booty shorts.
Some people like wearing board shorts,
some people like wearing tight
spandex shorts to go to the knees.
Some guys like short rash guards,
some guys like long rash guards,
some guys compete and Abu Dhabi
and they don't want any rash guard.
Well here's the deal though about
Abu Dhabi. If I would double,
if you're allowed to wear a gay,
are you allowed to grab the gay? Uh,
apparently no course but you can't
grab pants. I was wearing shorts.
You can't grab shorts? No, you can't
wear shorts. But it's a weird thing man.
Cause if I want to ski pants and he was
allowed to grab them, but uh, whatever,
you know, it's all good. I like
all that controversy at the end.
I liked that the geek that making
me wear the guid backfired on them,
but it also saved them because it really
like all of those electric chairs,
that was all those g pants, man, that
[inaudible] pants or there was huge.
He could, he never got close of getting
out of my lock down. There was no,
he never even almost went to quarter
guard. That shit was locked in.
And the pants were a big deal. A big,
big part of it. That's interesting.
It's interesting to think of what would,
how much different would the game be if
you had to wear tights? Yeah. Tights.
It would still be hard for
them to pull out his leg.
And even if I just wear board shorts
and knee sleeves, that'd be good enough.
You know, um, the question of
what the at first find. Yeah.
The ankle sleeves are huge too.
You put pants, ankle sleeves,
or if you don't wear pants,
you could just wear knee sleeves.
And that's what I did in the first one.
That's why I had the knee sleeves.
Just you don't want,
uh,
I mean somewhere I think in
everyone's mind they think that,
uh, that it's not real grappling.
If it ain't all greasy,
it's gotta be greasy to be real.
And why you trying to stop all the grease
and you're supposed to swap sweat with
your opponent. You're so, you know,
it's like if you were, uh, um,
pants, like, oh, you're cheating.
Don't you want to be all slippery with
another man? It doesn't make any sense.
But I mean, don't the pants, you
said the pants aid you. Yeah,
but he could grab them too.
So it was, it wasn't, uh,
he had an advantage that he can grab
them and it saved his ass again.
And I had an advantage where with
my personal gain, my lockdown game,
it helps it,
I wonder if listened to all this,
if they did decide to do a third one,
if he would say you got to wear shorts,
dude, if I did a third one,
dude, the first rule is I get to,
well with the whatever
the fuck I want to wear,
that's going to be rule number one.
I get to wear whatever the fuck.
So that's the first
clause. It seems like, um,
promoted correctly. There's obviously a
market for this now. Um, and like I said,
I, I, I, I'm committed to helping.
I definitely want to help.
I think that something like this is
something that I get behind and you know
what I'm trying to do, dude, I'm
not trying to make money with Ebi.
I'm trying to create the best shit, just
like you're trying to create with on it.
You're trying to do the best
shit. There's not like, Ooh,
there's a lot of money right here.
If I could manage it to show,
I'm trying to create the
best you just to show.
So I want everyone in the
Jiu Jitsu community to help
pitch in and help me out.
Help us out, help out.
Metamorris I'm starting Ubi,
but I still love them a more and more
metamorris and even though, uh, I'm, uh,
you know, I'm 100%. I'm not going
to be an m four. I still want to go.
You say no. What I'm saying? Well
when is m four? I don't know,
but that ain't happening. It's
not happening. It's not happening.
Taking some time off. Um, I'm
for sure going to take time off.
I don't even want to have, it's going to
do your own shit from here on out. Um,
I mean if you've got 20 k we saw,
we saw what could happen with m three
metamorris three we saw the potential to,
would you say 20? If they said 20 k paper
view that that's, that's a lot. I mean,
if we're just guessing. No,
I have no idea what it was.
That's a lot of money I've seen. That
seems like a lot of people to buy Jujitsu.
I don't know though.
So I just,
I don't want it to really
think about it too much,
but when I do decide to
sit down and talk numbers,
I mean I want to do what's best
for the security of my family.
That's if I'm going to get back
into training camp, I'm going,
you know,
and start seeing my son last and my wife
lasts and distress comes back and I'm
training all day and going through all
that and swimming and hating the swimming
and the torture. If I'm going to go
through that, I want what's coming to me.
That's it. I just want what's
fair. I want to be a dick about it,
but I'm not going to get taken advantage
of. So I hear what you're saying. Yeah.
My man knows his value. Yeah. But I just,
I just want to enjoy life now.
And the,
the thing that feels the best about
this is like everybody who's gotten into
arguments with people
about the legitimate,
legitimate legitimacy of
the system and the style,
the 10 plan of stock,
all the arguments that everyone's got
into with people in the haters and all
that stuff,
I think about how vindicated they feel
and how I gave them a little boom.
I could help them personally.
And their argument now when they argue
with those same guys are like, ah,
like the little I gave him, like I put
in, oh, that feels really, really done.
That things are all really good. A
little dig. Yeah, man. I, you know,
the argument, you know, and,
and again, all I ever try to
do is make Jujitsu better.
And the people that are resisting me,
and uh,
there's so many people on the
Internet who aren't Aquest to,
who are Jujitsu freaks,
who are on a quest to shut me down and
they hope the rubber guard fails and the
system fails and it's a fraud and they're
on a mission and they're generally on.
Um, there's, I have on the Uttama
Forum, I do frequent the Uttama form.
It's the Geeky form, probably
the biggest key for him, uh,
in the world on a mixed martial arts.com
if you go in the tunnel form and I
would say 75% of the people on there,
they are generally not fans of mine.
So I'm like in there like swimming
with the sharks all the time, man.
I'll respond to shit and I read their
shit and there's guys that are just can't
wait for something to happen bad at
10 plan and jump on it. They just
always going to be haters out there.
That shit is such a waste of energy.
But the crazy thing is I know all these
guys in the fake screen names and who
knows what they look like and I know
who they are. It's like the same guys.
And when I, after the fight
I uh, went to my hotel,
took a shower and I'm just like sitting
there for like five minutes and I looked
on the underground and I
couldn't believe the headline.
It was like a one to a one two
punch man who was killed me first.
I looked at the headline and it said
Bravo dominates Gracie and Metamorris am I
want the fucking,
it's like the ultimate review
ever front page of my that's,
that's, that's like my home base
man. The underground Kerrick.
I fucking love Kendrick man and Chris,
Matt.
It was crazy. And then I
immediately, I didn't even read,
I didn't even get on the underground.
I went to the Uttama form and
I wanted to see what they said.
And Man, a Breton, the towel check
your oil. That's his screen name.
He's always on there. He's like that.
He keeps the peace. He's like the,
the go between because he also transit
Gracie Baha is like that. The peacemaker,
cause he won't let anybody trashed term
planet cause he's one of my black belts,
but he's also training in the Geetu
wants to get a ski black belt.
So he's the enforcer there.
So he starts a thread. Fluke.
My Ass said fluke my ass.
I was a threat.
So I got on to get all them dudes
that fucking couldn't stand me.
Not usually when something
good happens at 10 planet,
they just stay off the threat and
they're silent and they're just,
they don't even want to bump the
threat up. They just want to let it go.
Just let it go. Let it
go. Let that video go.
Nice little highlight reel of us
dominating like the Gracie nationals,
they let that go. No response.
Let it go. Let it go. Let it go.
Because they know if they hate,
it's going to backfire because now more
people going to say it. So, but this one,
they all responded. They gave it up and
it was so crazy. Dude, I'm sitting there,
I'll fucking be looking at fucking tears
rolling down my fucking face from that
shit. Like that is the best
compliment Adler ever when guys did.
We're on a mission when guys that were
on a mission every day to follow me
around,
fucking just shank me on the side and to
have those guys admit that we're wrong.
Um, man, I dunno man. That
was, there was a combination,
that front page and
then it was incredible.
Don't want to be haters and they, they,
they become haters and then it sort,
it sort of gets away from them, you
know, they just, they almost can't help.
It just gets out of control.
Joey,
Joey Diaz cold. Yeah, but damn you got
18 and I'm going to work in here. Yeah.
Hung Up. Shit. T and t
doesn't work in here.
Yeah, but a column call it called
Joe wrote Joey really quick.
I think he knows I'm on the podcast.
He probably wants to say something.
It's probably hard as fuck right now.
Joe Rogan, what is he going to say?
Pr Predict. Uh, what he would say.
Eddie Bravo. I told you I told you
cock saga. Electric Chair all day
you have reached the voice.
Oh, something might have happened. I might
of got pulled into a meeting. Joey Diaz,
his Bolo on the fuck up. Oh Dude.
He's selling out everywhere.
He's getting brought in from meetings
and fucking people want them to do movies
and it's just,
it's incredible.
Well, it's incredible. So yeah.
Yeah, he's a, okay. I might've went over
the four oh five or something. This is it.
I have to ask you this. Did the, did
the Indian come out the after party? No.
No, I don't feel it. I don't know. It was
like, no, probably so tired. Right? Yeah.
Yeah.
I just didn't feel it Joey.
Okay.
Oh, it's ringing. Check this out.
I think it's gonna work.
Yeah,
but I'm not sure if he's going to answer.
Feels good to be a gangster.
You're on the radio. Tell him, tell him
you love that you're live on the podcast.
I'm telling you right now, dawg.
Damn. It feels good to be a gay.
Same wouldn't be any problem.
No.
14 you got child's black fucking man.
The fucking doors over there
and vote when the child. Ah,
that's all I love to say.
I love you.
Hello you man. We love
you too, man. Thank you.
He came in and just dropped a bomb
right there. He's the greatest.
Joey Diaz greatest. So, um,
what's next on the music front? I mean,
it a hilarious thing. You know, you're,
you're a Jujitsu master,
but your music,
is it just as important to you
is your Jujitsu? Yeah, no. Yeah,
and I believe just as good.
What's going on with the music?
What are you doing it I just
dropped. Did I just, we just redid,
dropped me and Danny loan or x nine
inch nails x perfect circle we read.
Did drop dude. And I think it's
the best work I've ever done.
Let's play can we couldn't play?
I just go to
soundcloud.com/eddie-bravo dude,
you're gonna trip out what we did
to this dude. Okay, well let's,
let's end it with that. We'll end it
with that. Um, listen, uh, 10 planets,
you jitsu.com ladies and gentlemen, that's
what it is. 10 planets. Jj 10th Planet,
J j.com. Um, I got all that shit.
Is headquarters going to be like
tonight? I Dunno man. Oh my God. I did.
I wish I was training again.
Everything I did in that match.
That's old school shit that I always do.
It's all on mastering the system.
It's all on my website. It's only five
bucks right now. You could let me fill me.
Come to class tonight.
I don't know.
You better get them in the film
when you come to class at night.
Are you fucking kidding me? Are
you fucking kidding me? Yeah,
you fucking kidding me. This
is the class. After that,
that place is going to be mobbed, bro.
I was going to be fucking bananas.
I might even come down, man.
I'm still sore as fuck though.
I'm getting another Regena
keen on my back next week.
My neck is 100% now.
What does that Ricky rocket
make sure he knows he's live a Ricky,
you're live on Joe Rogan's podcast,
so don't say a
any crazy shit.
One thing I do want to stay as the reason
I called because I was trained in this
morning over in the nod and I heard about
all this stuff with boys and I'm just,
I don't understand.
I'm so upset about it and I saw you being
nothing but a fricking class half the
other night.
Thank you man. Someone must have lied
to him. That's all. It's someone.
Someone's been lying to them and we
need to get to the bottom of that.
Yeah,
I don't, I've never heard you say
anything with cool stuff about boys, man.
You used to talk about him back in the
day about how amazing it was that you
came to the United States and did what
he did. And that has with so many people,
it changed the course of martial arts,
you know?
Yeah. Those are facts. Someone lied to
him. The only thing that makes sense,
someone had a lie to them.
Yeah, man, I can't believe I wish
I would've been able to stay.
I had to get home to my kids, but if I
would have been there, man, God, you know,
I could do on my end.
I have no idea what my influence
would you probably nothing.
But if it is just you just
ask me, I'll do it, you know?
Thank you man. How about the
playing drums on one of my tracks?
How about that as I call?
Okay.
Yeah.
No, stop with the twirling of the
sticks. Please. Can you, can you,
can you play one of my songs
about twirling any goddamn stacks?
I don't know.
Hey, but you know what Ricky,
Ricky, I swear to God, man, I,
one of my good friends is Danny
loaner from nine inch nails. He knows,
I mean he's, he's, he's
deep, deep, deep, deep.
And I don't know how many times I've, uh,
always stuck up for Ricky rocket. I go,
dude,
that mother,
the shit you do as a showman with the
twirling of the sticks and all that shit,
that's amazing, man. I can't
do any of that shit. That's
talent. Some people think,
oh, it's just, it's all tricks and smokes
and mirrors, you know? But I really,
really respect your showman,
shipping your drama.
And I think it's fucking amazing,
man. Like Cirque du Solei drumming.
So I always had your back. I always
had your back. You know that.
Thank you Ricky. Take it easy, Ricky.
No problem at all. I have
no idea. Oh Hey, by the way.
Okay. He's, he's hearing you. He
hears everything I say or you,
you just can't hear me
the other night.
Great seeing you too,
man.
Yup.
That's what he was asking me.
This dude. How good is Joe Rogan?
He looks like a fucking destroyer.
I bet he can destroy people. Mike,
have you seen him kick
the fucking bag on video?
It doesn't have like 10
million views or something.
I don't think it to take care of Ricky
ass in person. You can also
kick out verbally too. I mean,
it's like a fucking
these guns in Jiu Jitsu.
This is a beautiful podcast. Rikki rocket
by the way. He's a bad motherfucker.
What'd you rock it from? Poison
is legit. Legit black belt
martial arts his whole life, his whole
life. And a great guy. Super Cool.
And he's competed as a black belt.
He did the,
the world's or Pan Am's and big Ibj judge
tournament as a blackbody competed in
others. He's told you totally legit.
And it, like I said, a great guy.
Just a cool guy.
Um,
let's just wrap it up with our sponsors
and play that song and get the fuck
Outta here.
This is a beautiful podcast.
This podcast is the most people
ever on speakerphone, ever.
We've ever had that many,
three different people on speaker phones.
That's craziness. It's crazy, man. But it
was beautiful. Congratulations brother.
It was an honor to be there.
I got choked up when people were telling
me how nuts you were going. That made,
I gave me the chills like, go do. Jo
was losing his mind and I was just like,
fuck man. Just knowing that, you know,
Brian Count can't shut the fuck up.
He never shut the fuck up.
And by the time we got to fuck with Cha,
I still wasn't breathing right.
Wow. Like my hands were shaking,
my heart was beating and Brian's
is blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Then I said this and this and I
was like, I thought guys, you know,
he's like doing all this shit and
I'm, and I'm, I'm like, Brian,
I didn't even know what you just said.
Half an hour.
I haven't listened to a fucking word
cause he was, you know Brian Callan.
When you know how,
like we've talked about this before,
it's like when you're not thinking about
nothing, you're background defaults.
Did you get to start thinking about
Jujitsu when you're sitting around and you
start going over move when you,
you know,
you got 10 minutes before you have to be
somewhere and you're just sitting there
and there's nothing going on
and you start thinking, man,
I got to figure out a better
counter to start going over there.
That's default for Brian Cowen.
When you stopped talking,
he defaults to gay jokes. He defaults to
him talking about fucking guys, you know.
And I told them, look, I
fuck guys. And he's like,
and I remember looking over in the
middle of him say like doing his shtick.
And I was like, dude, I don't
know what the fuck you just said.
I literally haven't even heard you.
All I've been doing is trying to catch
my breath. I almost had a heart attack,
dude.
I wrote that on Instagram.
And it sounds like you know something
somebody would say, but God damn,
my heart was pounding. It was crazy.
I just want you to catch a man,
dude. When you, when you
went to the truck, when you,
when you rolled that left
shoulder roll the twister row,
which is my favorite move,
but the other side,
it's not a role that you do that left
roll when I knew you were going there,
I was hoping you were going
to hit the twister. Oh,
I was hoping you're going to
adjust and go for the twister. No.
What the fuck was going on?
Like Jeff Glover in the commentaries.
Like I like to think of myself as a guy
as well versed in Jujitsu and I don't
even know what's going. This is crazy.
That's why it's so hard to defend.
You know there was not Natto Magno was uh,
tell them you don't want any game.
You just, no, no. Eddie game. You go
get tap. You don't know Eddie's game.
You're going to get that.
It's funny.
But boiler to his credit would not
top and he's a bad motherfucker.
You got to give him that man.
That guy's got heart. Yeah.
Cause I know there's a photo of us online,
the high time shoot where you got me
in the vaporizer. Just that picture,
like that's a real agony.
Look on my face. I'm like, ah,
and you're not even pulling on it.
Yeah.
I couldn't imagine the way you were
yanking it with two hands and Heuler just
let it go.
He just let it get all chewed up.
Yeah, I'd never gone that
deep with the vaporizer.
Ever. People tap right the fuck
away. That's the worst one.
He's a bad motherfucker. He
hung in there, man. So yeah,
Soya Gracie, you didn't get to be a
Hoya Gracie from tab uneasy. Absolutely.
All right man.
Um,
thanks to naturebox.com
go to naturebox.com and a
naturebox.com/rogan and get
50% off your first box. Uh,
thanks also to Squarespace.
Go to squarespace.com.
Enter the code word Joe.
There's the picture and gets him
to said, yeah, that is fucking, ah,
that's not me. Clowning around that.
Look on my face there. It's like,
that's real agony out
Chihuahua. That sucks. Um,
squarespace.com,
squarespace.com and enter the
code word Joe Squarespace. Uh,
one of our favorite
sponsors and on at.com,
it's o n n I t use a code word Rogan and
save 10% off any and all supplements.
If you want to learn Jujitsu,
my friend,
the 10th Planet Way go to 10th Planet J J.
Dot Com or um, uh, you know,
Holler at Eddie on Twitter.
You could get Eddie Bravo at
Eddie Bravo on Twitter and uh,
you'll find out if he's coming
to your town for seminars.
He does a lot of seminars.
He travels constantly.
You didn't travel at
all for this two months,
the last month and a half.
If you want any information on my
homeschool 10th planet headquarters,
which is downtown La,
uh,
email me@eddieattenthplanetjj.com will
give you the schedule and prices and I'll
let you know I would do shit. We got
warm up curriculum. That's intense man.
So there's a lot to understand
before you have to come to class.
Now it's different.
It's a different name
and prepare yourself for Dick Pics.
Eddie Bravo,
you just gave out your fucking
email address on the internet.
That's how dare you.
They're black cocks are that an
ocean of them are coming your way.
God Damn tidal wave. Oh,
why'd you put that up?
Why did I put it out
there? It's out. Yeah.
And there's,
the song that we're going to close
with is available for free download.
You could at soundcloud.com/eddie-bro
Lorius um, uh, me as far as me,
I got a three dates upcoming,
uh, Miami, which is this Thursday.
I'm at the Jackie Gleason theater at
the Fillmore with Tony Hinchcliffe.
Looking forward to that.
And then a 418 ami in Orlando with Joey
motherfucking and then a four 25 April
25th, I mean Baltimore again
with Joey Diaz. We're going
to have some fucking fun.
Oh, April 12th. I'm at 10th Planet
Beaumont, Texas with the Brian Dabs.
That's April 12th and
the first weekend in May,
there's a Midwest training
camp at 10th Planet Omaha.
Go to the new bureau forum
for all the Info that,
that's the form that's on 10th and a
jd.com. So that Midwest training camp,
we're gonna have geo and boogie
teaching their jump Otello,
Brian Mccaffrey and me. It's going to
be just a wild weekend of just magic.
It's him. Glorious, glorious. All right.
Joe rogan.net for details and tickets
and all the podcasts are available there
as well. Uh, thanks to everybody that uh,
we ran into this weekend. Um, you know,
I tried to take pictures of as many
people as I could at Metamorris,
but it got fucking crazy.
But thank you for all the love and thanks
for all the love Sunday night too at
the ice or the comedy Magic
Club. Uh, we'll be back tomorrow.
You got a lot of podcasts this week.
A lot of cool shit and I'm much love
everybody now dropped Eddie Bravo's new
track. The new remix smoke
serpent is the name of the band.
Just listen to 15 seconds.
Okay.
Fully commit.
They come in with it from the start to
the finish strictly business when I bring
it to you,
next up is called a new rendition.
Mrs Can afford some medicine. This is
solely my suggestion by your merchants.
Metabolic methods for the politics.
Charlotte.
Oh, what's that? Get Commerce
says where you'll live.
Bosch amongst the Cobra in Pasa,
right spot shows dope on them or treat
him the proper number one. Number two,
not in a cock.
My trauma calamity
battling normally troll ballot of trends.
Show balancing with gold watch story.
The folds
was and maintain focus wholly
norm because I know again,
wow.
Yeah, but this crazy before Tom
settled score trend. No leaking skies.
Walk the line.
The first best for skirt
trash,
cause I know what Albert [inaudible],
the way
it's
put the paint
out Bronx,
the way you're saying
the song sang the song
[inaudible].