Recording.
The Joe Rogan experience podcast was
brought to you. Bond the fleshlight.
If you'd go to Joe rogan.net and click
on the link for the fleshlight in enter
in the code name Rogan,
you will get 15% off the number one sex
toy from men and you can shoot loads at
a discount.
In real terms,
if we were going to spend $100,
you're literally spending $85
Zam bitches buckle up ours.
Here's in the house
dropping mad accountant type science on,
you
know,
stereotype there.
Keep on rocking in the free world.
Ladies and gentlemen, this weekend, this,
this uh,
Friday night at Mandalay Bay theater.
I will be joined by none other bin.
Thanks man. I love that place. It's an
awesome place. We ran the liberty theater.
Gummy bears can be Cherries, the cherries,
the diary bootcamps, savage, delicious,
terrible for your liver. Right?
Did these have the Gel in them?
Cause I got me turned onto gummies
with Gel and that's not squishy.
We are willing to eat anything as
long as it as a fucking flavor.
There's nothing in nature like this. No.
You found something in nature like this,
this is bad. This is bad. It's like it
looks radioactive or something. Yeah.
Like what is this? This is a, this
is pus out of some rhinos ball sack.
You know there's not
supposed to be this chewy,
they're not flavored like cherries.
They're shaped like cherries
designing the look jewelry.
So that texture is nothing,
uh, nothing in nature.
And they just pretended cherry flavor
tastes like Cherry Cherry play doesn't his
nothing like cherries. It tastes
like cherry flavor. Yeah. Yeah.
It was just a specific thing like
gray, gray drink, grape drink,
don't taste like grapes. It's
so good though. Yeah, it's
so good. I like the color.
Great. Well green juice, grape
juice tastes like grapes of course.
But grape drink actually a different
thing. I went to Dan to Davin,
he's the other day.
Have you seen those fountains?
So does that have the extra syrup
shots that yeah, the Americano. Yeah.
I went to Daphne's,
which is like this Greek place
and they just have like a regular,
you know like ice and then coke,
sprite thing,
but still chewing a stupid piece of shit.
And not try and get rid of it right now.
It's like they have extra shots where
you can add like you can have your diet
coke and you're like, oh, I think I
want some grape in orange jumpsuits,
grape flavored caffeine,
free coke, zero, uh,
Orange Cherry flavor, caffeine,
everything with anything.
I was watching one of those
episodes have no reservation.
I think there were in Chicago and they
were eating that some crazy hot dog type
place. It was like they have like meat
inside, like wrapped in some other thing.
There was, I don't know what the fuck it
was. It's in a bond and anyway, they uh,
they had a suicide run there
would deal with a soda.
They would just hit every
single stop along the way.
Like a little bit of sprite
and a little bit of root beer,
a little bit of dog coke,
a little bit of Dr Pepper and
just fill it up like gross.
It's disgusting that
it's like the mixture.
You don't know what you're getting less.
It's Mr Misty,
which I agree with Mr Misty suicides,
but it was this to misty suicide.
Mr Missy from dairy queen is
totally legit. Really? Yeah.
Try it out sometime. But when
it's winter, misty suicide,
Mr Misty suicides and if
you get it with the cream,
whatever it's called and
[inaudible] are there,
how many different flavors to Derek rose?
I Dunno. Supposed to must be used to be.
I mean when I was a kid it used
to be on the like you know,
12 different kinds or the
whole run of them. Yeah.
Cause it tastes like a fruit punch and
it was sloshy and they'd get the ice
cream in it and it kind of
tastes like a dairy queen.
Serve Mr mysteries are not like
coke and sprite. No, no, no it,
Mr Misty is a one of their drinks,
which is like a bunch of slushed ice.
Like an like a slush ice.
Like a nice, a nice, yeah.
Wow. Check it out. I will. Just a weird,
that shit feels so good
to us when we first eat.
It's so bad for your body when
you're eating like a slushie,
you're just drinking sugar syrup.
That's blue for some fucking reason.
Like you needed to be blue to
have that extra special kick.
You know you want a visual kick
as well as like a taste bud kick.
It doesn't taste like anything in nature.
Just takes another reason why. Shit.
That's another reason why God's an
asshole. You're like, you made us love it.
It's nature as horrible stuff you made
us. Our bodies react so well to it. Yeah.
It's so weird. It's not supposed to
be there the way it's supposed to
be. As fruit. It's supposed to be
processed in its natural form by the body.
You eat it,
you chew it not broken down to some high
fructose corn Syrup Shit and you know
where your body like is it like,
what is this this?
I'm thinking there's some
minerals in this. There must be.
It's like you know when
your body Taissa an orange,
that orange tastes delicious
because it's really good for you.
It's one of those things.
It's a natural thing.
We have created shift that tastes really
good but is not really good for you,
which it doesn't even exist in nature.
What would our red meat have? Red
Meat, red meats. Awesome. Oh cool.
I'll be willing to take that.
What I'd love for other road be more
excited before you all the fat and stuff.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
You know what's terrible? Eating
red meat and no, not exercising.
When you eat red meat and you exercise,
it's not bad.
Especially if you're eating good meat,
like organic meat. Hopefully grass fed.
You know most folks,
if you get me for real,
that's how you're supposed to do it
and what they serve in and out at all.
They don't serve it anywhere,
man.
Even if you go to a nice place
that's a really good butcher shop.
That nice steaks. The ones with all the
marbling or the grain fed ones, what's it?
Why does, why does it change their meat
to productive or not productive as fuck?
That's what it does.
See,
they're not supposed to be eating
grain cows in the wild eat grass.
They roam around the eat grass,
but when we pen them up,
we forced them to eat corn because it
makes them fatter and that fat or make
some more delicious. That's why a Ribeye
is the shits on. Oh, it's all good.
When you get a eye,
if you knew what the fuck you're doing,
you get that lump charcoal,
lay that shit down.
You don't use it too much lighter fluid
just to touch just enough to get the
paper light under the, the,
the one of those, you know,
those things, those um, um,
they're like chimneys,
little fireplace chimneys and then yeah.
Oh yeah. They could tell it got one
of those fish shit go on so fast.
Oh, it's awesome. 20 minutes.
You've got full white hot coals.
You dump that shit out.
Make sure you got the ride distance
between the grill and the time.
That should correctly trial and error.
Get it right. Huh? That chimney is great.
It lights all the Coles at once. Yeah.
Rib Eyes are fucking have to buy new car.
It's like 25 bucks as a side thing that
you hold and you just dump out all these
hot coals and cows are not supposed
to taste as good as a ribeye.
We fucked them to make them taste that
good because it's all that fat in it when
you cook it and all that fat mixes
with all that meat and oh God damn,
it's delicious. And it's not
supposed to be that delicious.
I get grass fed rib eyes, man, and
they're not nearly as delicious.
They're not good.
I mean there's a,
it's a different sort of a thing and
you get a sort of a bit of satisfaction
knowing that this animal lived a natural,
healthy life.
And I think that's the right way to do it.
And I think if I had to choose between
having delicious steaks are having pretty
fucking delicious steaks
but not as delicious,
but I don't have to think about this
animal being forced to eat something
unnatural,
I'll go that way.
So I buy grass fed just to have a clearer
conscience when it comes to how my
animals are murdered for their murdered,
who sounds ridiculous and very critical.
It sounds ridiculous and
hypocritical, but I there, you know,
I'd prefer that they'd be grass fed,
but God damn,
it tastes awesome when they're not.
Yeah.
But what if these grass fed ones are just
like fucking like the farmers are just
completely assholes to them.
Like they get slapped all day long.
Cow Cow.
It's more difficult to grasp feed them.
So I don't think that that, that
would be the case. It's more costly.
Your yields aren't as big.
I mean those hippies probably don't get
laid that are probably fucking all these
cows.
So you were,
you're probably eating cows that had been
fucked in the ass by hippie vegetarian
farmers that what they're doing
being vegans and fucking car
parks. This is probably
someone who's fucked a cow,
right? Yeah, for sure. Right.
It's gotta be,
you've seen those videos from the um,
on the Internet about
the Colombian problem.
Like there's a lot of dudes in the
mountains, the fuck donkeys disgusting it.
We talk about testing that you have to
have her do that to make it a problem.
But there's a lot, a lot of them are
doing it. They had those guys from um, uh,
what, what does that, uh, that went
to website again? Shit, vice squad,
vice city vice 10 fuck vice guides guides.
Got to travel,
travel day would a VBS.
Dot. TV is the yard. Anyway,
these guys are awesome and they do all
these fucking crazy documentaries about
going to all these really
different fucked up locations.
They're fucking donkeys and
then we'll go to Columbia. Yeah.
It was normal for kids to first test out
sex on donkeys in this town before they
have families. Like people all
knew about it. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
He's fucking a donkey now.
You know, he's getting,
and they interviewed these kids going,
yeah, it's totally cool. It's so sad.
Like a pussy.
Could you imagine if it was all a troll
and that was a really brilliant sketch
that they lived together completely and
totally. Colombians are going, Holy Shit,
Huggies dude.
What if B Vbs TV,
the whole thing was like owned by the
green onion or something like that.
And this is all bullshit to
say, hey man, even if they,
if they are just what they've uncovered,
that really is
real VBS. Dot. TV is brilliant man.
Those vice to travel, the one on
Liberia changed the way I
look at the world, man. It is
terrifying stuff. And they,
they've, they've done a
bunch of brilliant one man's,
if they had guys going to
the jungle and do an Iowasca,
we've had guys going to Liberia,
they've got guys going to North Korea.
Just see what,
what it's like in those places.
You fucking scan it and see what
going on. Yeah. The real story.
They go to Thailand and hanging out with
ladyboys guys like hanging out in his
hotel room with a bunch of lady boys.
This guy climbed into a
tub this bad motherfucker.
I wish I knew his name cause I'm, I'm,
I'm pissed now that I don't know his name,
but this bad motherfucker climbed into
a tub with a bunch of lady boys. Really?
Yeah. He's afraid he didn't give a fuck.
He did it on the Internet. I love him.
I need to find out all the
internet stuff. Yeah. Wow.
See a spots is enough to pay
for those trips and things.
Yeah. Wow. That's amazing.
I don't know who pays for it. Um,
but it was fucking incredible.
It just goes to North Korea just goes
different places and it just says fuck it.
I'll just grab it
guys.
I watched short circuit last night and
short circuit to remember that movie in
the 80s about a robot that
was like Ang Johnny, I
need input. And he like takes a
book and he reads through it like,
like really fast and it goes next book
that's done out of my mind at south by
southwest was here.
Isn't it hilarious?
Like there's one point where it goes out
in the cities like looking at all this
shit and he goes, look at all
this inputs, megabytes of input.
Here's the funniest part.
You know the Indian guy? Yes.
Good young American white person.
I know that's something Fisher.
I know that's how much Indians
were mocked in like 85 yeah,
you want to do it that long ago.
All the only jokes were
just that he had an accent.
And what's really creepy if
you watch short circuit too,
is that it's one of those movies where
like the main characters aren't even in
it. You know, cause they're like,
fuck, I'm not making a sequel.
And so like they was horrible and they
filmed it in Toronto but the whole movie
looked like it was a neat,
it was supposed to be New York City so
it was like all gray skies and really
small buildings.
And then there's like guy wearing a
New York hat and it looks so fake.
It was like to fake cause looking
New York, New York Yankees.
It was hilarious. But I, yeah
it's outdated as fuck so much.
But they need to Redo that movie but
make like make it r rated and make like
Michael Bay or something that attached
to it and make it a transformer maybe.
Cause that that had some funny shit in it.
Transformers.
It was a really good movie that goes.
Some people find that guys name. No, I
can't find it. I'm, I'm on the website.
I just don't want to
keep looking and just,
I dunno what the fuck you guys just
talked about for flavor song circuit. No,
I totally tuned out because I was trying
to find this dude's name cause he's
such a bad motherfucker. I apologize to
you sir. I will. I will find out. I don't,
I don't like Google in the middle
of a podcast. It's very distracting,
but I just did it just because this
guy is such a bad mother fucker.
I wanted to give him his propers.
What does it have to do with
getting me some of those?
How many bears back? Oh, you dog.
Ari's diet is hilarious.
So bad.
How do I stay in shape possible?
It's
not fair,
Bro.
Fucking eating a chopped salad with my
fork dipping and ranch the other day and
I'm like,
he's eating gummy bears are the people
who are aggressive about you not eating
certain things.
You know like people who like get a
actually angry at you if you're eating
shitty food, like, oh my God,
do you even know what's in that?
If you're eating a hot dog or something
and they'll fuck with you like that
because people are dying all over
constantly from these hot dogs,
this crazy cancer causing
things relax a little bit.
Definitely ain't good for it. You mean
you shouldn't be eating them all the time,
but if you want to eat them, if
you can't appreciate it, a hot dog,
you're missing out on a
lot of shit hooker. This,
you're missing out a lot of shit.
He can't just be all vegetables and you
know this a certain time when you have
to say fuck it and go old school and get
a dirty water hot dog on the corner in
New York City.
And then we've got a moist bond and they
slap some sauerkraut on that bitch and
some brown mustard Sha Zam
you don't know this dude.
This dude is probably a fucking terrorist,
you know, just take a lot of vitamin C.
This is probably like a scam,
this thing open. But there's, uh,
some of them are really cool. I
shouldn't say that. Terrorist.
They're really nice guys. There's
one guy, he's got a falafel thing.
It's near a where Sussman has his office.
Remember when we went there with Tom
Jr got damn right near where all in ar.
God Damn, this guy's got some good food.
Fucking hot sauce. Legitimately. Ah,
Oh yeah, I remember it right and
you can't tell me not to eat that.
You can go fuck yourself.
Yeah,
it's two o'clock in the morning and you
know we just got done drinking and been
playing pool and drinking beer
and I'm eating that stupid.
Shut your mouth cops some vegetables in
the morning, but I'm going to be fine.
Okay? I've got good constitution.
I come from peasant jeans.
I can eat this hot dog. If you get killed
by a hot dog, you're a fucking pussy.
I'm not going to eat vegetables
in the morning, but I'll be fine.
I just wished there would only make,
they would have hot dogs.
You get by the costs a little more and
we're only made with douchebag cows.
They would show you videos here. He's
being a Dick Right here. I look at him.
He steps on the baby cow.
What a fucking asshole.
He's stealing the food from everybody.
Knocks everybody out of the way because
he pissed on that little baby kap.
Did you see him do that? Fuck
this cow. Now here he is.
Here he is in in Strip
loin. You have your, uh,
your ribeye biting thing? Yeah.
It's just some shit that account,
if you can prove it,
you can document from the moment he gets
shot in the head to the moment he's on
your plate. Like, yeah, fuck you cow.
If you're asked by FDA, get involved,
get involved in this. Let's
go with, I will pay 25% more.
If I know that my cow was a Douche bag,
I will feel slightly better.
But then again, you've got to
think why was he a Douche bag man?
He's living in a prison system. Okay.
It's two courses. A douchebag cow.
He's being unfairly treated.
Oh,
that's not recommend art can argue
the other side. Yes, please. Well,
why aren't the other counselor specs they
are they just too stupid to act on it
and this guy's the fucking release it.
Indiana Jones. He's the neo in the matrix.
He's the one who rallies
against the system.
He's not a Douche bag where the
Douche bags. How about that? Ari,
you want to Jack in a box like a two
o'clock in the morning are feeding the
beast.
You're imprisoning
these poor cows.
Get some crazy lady on stage last night
showing her badge and stuff. Nice.
Let's not say what club because we
don't want anybody to stop doing that.
That's a good point. But uh,
afterwards these two girls,
one comic and our Australian friend,
they were like trying to help the
girl and get her to the hospital.
And it was like, she
was like, I just can't,
Australia should look down on everybody.
She was like, I just can't look away.
I'm going to care so I have to get
her some help. It was like, that's,
that's total it out. You know, I
don't care so I won't get any help.
And then she goes, yeah, it's
better than what you're doing.
Just laughing and taking pictures.
And I'm like,
don't think you're better than me.
First of all isn't taking pictures.
I was laughing though,
but I just don't give a fuck.
There's thousands of those people
across the city. It's unfortunate,
but some of it is funny, especially
if you're in the right state of mind,
you know? Especially if you
can prove again that this girl,
we were trying to get her off stage
and she took out a wet nap. Whoa.
Put it upside up inside of her
vagina. Whoa. Is that good for him?
Put it in her mouth. No, I don't
think if I can find it for you.
It's like putting it in your mouth.
That's like taking a wet nap and
putting it in your mouth. Right?
Doesn't that your body
absorb all the chemicals?
She put it in her mouth after it. The
Vagina. So either way. Either way. Yeah.
That bitch is toxic.
She's circulating her own toxicity,
vaginal to mouth in a big
tornado of herpes and aids
because she was so directly
mount moist white boy.
She's like that snake that swells. It's
tailed at Eddie had on a shirt yesterday.
That's what she was, man.
Sorry, were you say I lost it.
I just remembered that
if I was really rich,
I would buy the gold plated short circuit.
Short answer. That would be like, dude,
I don't have any nobody.
Then you're,
you're talking about what is
short term five came to life.
I remember in the Eighties
Dodge that bullet,
Steve 22 that instead of like 14 yeah,
I was fighting for survival.
Then it was time to feed myself
and it's pretty children.
It's terrible movie and so racist,
really short circuit is racing about race.
The fact that he has an accent.
I know, but it's not even an
Indian guy that's doing it.
It's a white guy that they
darken up. He, he was like, oh,
this woman at that one part. If number
two guys, hey, so where's your factory?
Where do you live? And you go, oh, I,
I live in my van and it looks like a
suicide bomber van right in front of the
shit. It's the lace is Steve
Gutenberg. Yeah, that was a good bird.
Remember the vehicle?
Gutenberg is a strange cat man.
I've told his story before.
I've told his story about when Phil
Hartman died. What happened to him?
It was very strange.
Steve Gutenberg dressed up in a suit and
went to Phil Hartman's house and stood
in front of the house
and act as if act as if,
and he was in an artist's representative
to the media and that he was asking to
please treat this with respect and,
but it was so clear.
Exactly. It seems, it just, it seemed
like he was doing it to become relevant.
Like people fell out. People
felt like it was a move. It was.
It was really weird and I've thought
about it, I'm like, look man,
I think a lot of actors border on the
brink of losing their fucking mind all the
time. They're just keeping it
together, but as they get older,
their grip on together much like
Mel Gibson, Mel Gibson didn't just,
do you think he just became crazy.
He had to be crazy when he was young too.
He was just keeping it together.
He was just keeping it as also you allow
yourself because no one tells me no.
Everything just gets worse and
worse and worse. Way Worse.
It becomes what you can completely
lose track of who the fuck you are.
If you become some kind of a king like
superstar Mel Gibson type character,
I mean Mel Gibson made some ungodly
amount of money on that fucking religious
movie. Some insane. Any builders
thought he was a black belt in karate.
It's not a new thing. It's like if you're
a star and everybody's telling you yes,
he lives at grip. Yeah, you
could completely lose a grip.
I think a lot of actors
though in particular,
because acting is such a
weird and emotionally draining
occupations related to
age,
it's going to go away.
Especially if you want to be
that Megan Fox type character.
You've got a couple of years of
that hook or good luck, you know,
that's a grind and the girl,
the few girls that if Cameron Diaz is
that make it like decades later, like wow,
more power to you.
You know,
she's obviously a badass bitch
if she's able to pull that off.
But for a lot of them it does a short
ride or they say the first line or a
wrinkle and look go, oh well not only
that man, the whole idea of auditioning.
It's so bizarre.
The one of the weirdest
things about acting is that
to get a role where you act,
you have to prove,
you can act in a situation that's way
more stressful and bizarre and your actual
job. It's a little demeaning. It's a
little harder, like flaky after awhile.
Once you have the Gig man and you know
the words, then it's an easy thing.
Then it's just running over it.
You run it.
We would run our lines together and
then you would go into it and I'm,
and then they aren't thinking becomes
really easy and I'm talking obviously like
Sitcom acting, which is only shit and
they get to know your character too.
But I want to just say, I mean it's
not like Gary Oldman type, you know?
You know like what's his name from,
but no,
even with those guys drink your milkshake
Daniel Day Lewis that those guys
auditioning is a different art then. I
don't think they have to do that anymore.
I don't think anybody auditions.
Daniel Day Lewis, if you do you,
someone should kick you in the balls. How
dare you. Just that guy's body of work.
If there's any ever an actor whose
body of work just speaks for it,
just to let them do whatever the
fuck he wants to do. It's that guy.
Everything he's done, man, that
movie where he played a boxer,
if you ever watch that movie, I've never
watched any day. Now Daniel Taylor,
he is without a doubt the baddest
motherfucker who has ever acted for sure.
He's so fucking good.
He's so good.
He's not just a different person, but
you, you buy it, hook, line and sinker.
There's never a fake moment.
Watch that movie.
Gangs of New York when he plays that
crazy. What does it build? A butcher?
He plays that savage guy was fucking
people up with meat. Cleavers Dude,
you buy that shit 1000% yeah,
he plays insane.
So close to being insane
that it makes you nervous.
Like he might lose his fucking mind
and kill somebody in a movie because he
really falls so far and it was character.
But I think about this, that guy,
when he started,
he had to read two pages of something
and decide how with no idea who the
characters are and what the time period
during the conference room in front of
like some video camera and some p
at you like you're reading with a PA
oftentimes,
and the person is not an actor at all,
so their words sounds so artificial
and false. They'll like, tell me Ari,
if this is what you really want to do,
will you be me when you don't want to do
this anymore? And you're like, oh my God,
I have to pretend this is real.
Like you're supposed to be crying and
yelling at me. You sold last month.
That was a bad mother fucker in that too.
He's a bad mother fucker and everything.
Dude, that movie where he's a boxer,
he's literally the new world. No,
no, no. It was a long time ago.
He used to play at an Irish guy who's
like went to jail and became a boxer,
but he was like a legit boxer.
If you watched him in that movie,
he looked like a real boxer. Like there's
guys that play like, like Mark Walberg.
I'm sure he probably really does know how
to box. I mean everybody says he does,
but when you watch him in that
movie, the fighter, you're like,
this doesn't seem like a real fight to me.
This seems like a boxing movie,
boxing scene. It doesn't look real to
me. Whereas I'm watching Daniel Day,
Lewis and his hands are in
perfect position. The way
he gets hit, it looks real.
He's moving correctly. He's boxing
man. He's the waste throwing punches.
He's throwing punches exactly
the way you're supposed to do it.
There's no holes in his technique.
His technique is picture perfect,
which is better than
most professional boxers.
A lot of boxers have hitches and their
technique and they get away with it.
Like Roy Jones Jr always
had terrible technique,
but he was so athletic and
his timing was so brilliant.
He could get away with putting his
hands down real low and that's why he's
getting fucked up now. Yeah, he's getting
fucked up now because he had all these,
these skills that were based,
they were like reflex based
when he was really fast,
like faster than anybody by far.
And he was,
he had his technique was not correct but
he was so effective at it that he could
get away with it. He's was so powerful
in his, his punches were so fast.
He caught guys with things that they never
saw coming and he was able to do that
for the longest time.
But it was all based on him being able
to cover great distance. Like real fast.
And what soon as you got to hold
that shit went away man. Wow.
And then just left himself open. Yeah.
That's what's up. That's what happens.
[inaudible] it's what other movies
was in cause I really want to see it.
No, no Daniel Day later.
But the big, big one,
there will be blood or look them in the,
I say I haven't seen any of these.
I'm just, I wonder if I have something
against him cause I had to have to,
you have to see his movies. I loved
there will be blood. I loved it, man.
I loved it. I thought that
would be brilliant. I thought
it was, it was intense,
man. He's just, he was,
he so believable and believable is that
guy that was a complicated guy that that
was all kinds of fucked up.
You know,
the way he took in that kid and yeah,
I don't want to,
I don't want to feed you anything, but
you need to see that. No you don't.
You don't need which one's
the best one and wait,
when people tell me that that's the
latest one, I don't need to see it. Go for
it. So it was probably like a really good
acting scene. If you want to look up.
That makes me not want to see a movie.
Especially if it's in subtitles. Oh,
you're got to. Yeah. Yeah. Oh my God.
You haven't seen our launch Vaughn
dish though. I want to see that.
That dancing wine,
Portuguese cheesemakers it's brilliant
blocks. Water's amazing movie is it?
It's an amazing movie for any artists.
It's about performance.
Like a horrible,
you should watch that movie as a conduct.
You'll appreciate the same stuff that
strive for perfection in your art.
So one's in love.
Johnny Ma'am,
she love it. Natalie Portman. That
movie is just not good. Holy Shit.
Can you hear about Tracy Morgan?
Completely off subject,
but he got in trouble
again for saying retard,
but what he said was part of his act man.
I know you said that,
that he said retarded kids. Uh,
strong. They're like baby chimps.
It's funny man. It's funny shit. It's
a part of a character, but he's also,
he's also using to the
right. It might sense. Yeah,
but I mean it looked to say retarded kid.
Is there a better term than that?
There needs to be,
he needs to just fucking figure out if
he wants to do stand up or if you went to
a TV show because he's like
completely in the right,
but like he needs to really just say,
you know what, fuck this is my act.
But if he does that, then he
loses his TV show. You know?
It's just like you should
have to censor himself at all.
And I know you have to see what's what,
what the tone was,
what else was going on in
the room. There's something
to his act that satirical.
It's satire. It doesn't seem a
hundred percent real when he goes way,
way over the top like
that. I'm thinking, yeah,
I'm laughing because I know he's saying
the most ridiculous shit possible when
you know when, when he's talking
about, we're taught to kids.
John's like boob with chimps.
You know what he's doing?
He's trying to make people laugh
at how ridiculous he is. He's like,
he's trying to make people go
with this guy's a fucking great.
You have to get the tone was
earlier on the set. Look, dude,
I don't care what you say. That's
fucking funny. It is funny.
It's terrible that pill children
have down syndrome. It is horrible,
but it doesn't mean it's not funny.
When someone talks about a little down
syndrome, kids be strong like baby chimps.
Look, it's kind of funny. Over sensitive.
It's just everyone is just needs to
chill the fuck out. It's more like,
or they're not supposed to be
recalled. Retarded. You can,
you're not supposed to say retarded
anymore. I would say I'm retired.
You have different problems like down
syndrome and there was different,
it was different specs,
specific ailments that some of these
kids have and I appreciate that.
But you can't say that.
I can't use the word retarded because
retarded does not mean down syndrome.
They're retarded means you're
being a retard. You're being
slow, you're retarding.
It means slowing down. You cannot tell
me I can't tell someone they're slow.
Fuck you. I'm wicked. That's what
we're, then I feel tired today.
That doesn't,
it's like saying the word gay their side,
because you're using that
somebody, but you're not. Look,
there is something wrong with them.
It doesn't mean that it's not a terrible
thing that there's something wrong.
But how are you gonna pretend like
they're talking about us? All of us.
But let explain. I'm, let me explain. When
you talk about a friend, like I say,
Oh Ari, God, you're such a retard.
I don't mean you are a
kid with down syndrome.
I mean you're a step behind where you
should be. You go few were retarded.
You are slowed down.
That's what it means.
And if you call someone a
retard that's high school,
why don't we use the word retarded
was to say you're a retard.
Well there's that too.
I do think that that steak was retarded.
Do you think that's going to use it good?
Use It as good, like Oh my God. Yeah.
Avatar was fucking retarded changes.
Meaning isn't that funny how you,
I'd say retarded as being
really good all the time.
Like avatars is a perfect example.
I remember clearly saying, dude,
that movie is fucking retarded. It's so
good. It's so good. It's, it's insane.
And, and you know, you can't say
that. You can't use it that way.
You can't use it at [inaudible].
I was so high. It was,
it's harder not to see this.
Here's my point.
I totally understand saying that you
shouldn't be making fun of, you know,
people who have an ailment but
completely removing a word that doesn't
necessarily mean that it's not
going to cure that ailment.
The real issue is the fact that there
are children who have to suffer with this
terrible roll of the dice.
And that that is really a horrible
thing and we all feel that, man,
I've been around children that have
down syndrome. You're like, man,
this is kids in this state where
he's never going to be like us ever.
He's going to be in this state and it's
a terrible roll of the dice for that kid
and it's very unfortunate,
but that doesn't mean that when your
friend trips and his beer flies and hit
someone in the head and you're
like, retard, okay, it's not,
it's not what that means.
You're not calling him someone
with down syndrome. We,
we have to acknowledge that
there's a bunch of different,
like when I say you're retarded dude,
I don't mean that you have down syndrome
and I remember when when that you
spilled your beer,
it would be like you were totally booked.
That would go along with it. You're
clearly, it comes from that same place.
There's some of that there. You know I
used to do that bit about Noah's Ark.
If you tell the story to an
eight year old retarded boy,
he's going to have some questions.
I probably wouldn't do that bit today.
Yeah,
and when you would call your thought of
when you're calling your friends with
target, it was building a beer. You're
calling. I'm that guy. That character was
making fun of religion and were making
fun of the idea that tell you something's
insane story and you just buy it.
And then if you ask an
eight year old retarded kid,
he's going to have some
questions and that was the thing.
They sat down and sends it to neglect.
That's just complete [inaudible].
I apologize, but you don't
really mean that. I call my cat.
Probably should stop doing that.
Does that mean anything bad? Shoot.
You know what that means
on the only attention?
I think it's a funny sounding name,
but yeah.
How about if someone calls you
a girlfriend? A cunt balls?
I don't think that would be hilarious.
If somebody called my girlfriend a
cunt ball, I would laugh and giggle.
That's okay.
You should use the word negligent.
That's just me. Is that like a real word,
baby nigger? That's what your sense,
what you're saying. All right.
You better stop saying that. This is,
I'm going to be on NBC again. Dude,
you can't shop for me. You what if your
factory announced today? Oh, bad ass.
I can talk about it. Cause entertainment
we clean sweep. They broke the story.
Yeah, I had a fucking think
about it man. But ultimately,
ultimately arm a now is there
any change you couldn't,
I couldn't sit back and watch somebody
else do it. It would be bummed out.
I was watching on TV and you know David
Spade was hosting a fear factor but
dammit Mccartney show up in my car and
shit's going down. Is there any changes?
Is there any changes to the show at all?
It's going to be more awesome or awesome
or cause I'm fucking smarter now. Uh,
I think it's going to be pretty much the
same thing but high definition cameras,
the same total setup. Three stents.
There's going to be, the way do,
we're going to do eight of them, eight
episodes. We're going to do eight of them.
Two of them are going to be two hours.
So it's six regular ones and then two,
two hour on.
Are you going to make it interactive?
Are you going to have like a fear factor
application with behind the scenes
footage? Oh, I'm sure. Yeah.
Maybe you should get involved
with some of that shit son.
Are you going to do that? We could
probably make some money, dude.
Fuck some behind the scenes ringtone.
Let's make an APP.
So people contacted me because
I talked about this. Uh,
there's an APP for mixed martial
arts.com. It's fucking bad ass. And uh,
they asked me to check it
out and I checked it out and
I always try to help that
side out cause it's a really good site
and the people who run it are cool.
So I put a, I put it up on,
on Twitter and you know,
all these people checking it out and I got
it. I was like, God damn, I need an APP.
Like this thing is that shit probably
Kelly isn't, oh I need an APP.
I kind of went through Libsyn but that's
like adjust the podcast, right? Yeah.
What I need to come up with. So with all
the stuff that's just to the logs in it,
everything.
I want to have my blogs,
all those blogs that I
wrote years and years ago,
I wouldn't be able to update it.
So if you're bored,
you can read that shit on a train.
I said number one, I think there's,
there's millions of people that know
how to do apps now. Actually have it.
I know a company that that I'll get you
in touch with called the APP company
here in Santa Monica.
I should take my old blogs and read
them and make MP three files of them and
make it available for download
for sale. Yes. No, no, no,
no. It just put it fucker.
You got to give people things.
Son is important. Trust me.
I know we're moving this bitch into a
studio. We have at least one a week.
We're going to,
we're going to put this place in a studio
now we're going to get some bad ass
space and so that guests don't feel
weird about coming over my house and plus
I'm tired of telling my daughters to
be quiet while we're doing the podcast.
I think that's rude.
You know they have to hide.
They have to hide down there
when the podcast is going on.
So I'm thinking of getting some,
a bad ass space so we look legit.
So easier for people to get through to.
I'm sure it'll be not as far as those.
Yeah, this is tricky. And
plus we're going to be on,
we're not serious about going
harder to be the other way.
Not what you're going the other way.
No,
I'm going to go to Zuma beach please guys.
Come on up here.
It's a short half hour drive.
You want to leave yesterday?
How bad ass. What are you
talking about? Cause I got to
Joe, I'm asleep at the studio
and you know long day of work.
Find yourself like a gangster
when you said that there's some,
there's some fucking people
in Malibu that have I,
have you ever seen like those aerial view
photos of some of the houses in Malibu
that was like huge plunge. Johnny
Carson's a state up there and all these,
just some super,
super rich.
These GI to fucking yards in Malibu where
they have acres and acres of land on a
hilltop in Malibu. The SPEC
acular estates. It's like there's,
there must be some of the richest people
in the world by your taxes in that area.
Yeah. Fire targets for
sure. He lost his place.
A lot of people have red hot chili
peppers. Man, that's a danger zone.
I know some stuff.
I remember when we lived over there when
I lived in across the street from that
shit and we were like on the road
and my ex fiance was like, ah,
they're telling us we need to
evacuate the house. And I'm like, oh,
just grab my computer. And I'm like,
what the what? What else do I grab?
We have a cat say the technology evacuated
once and I've been evacuated twice
from, from fires, the fires. But Dude,
they're insane when you see it coming up
the fucking hill and you can't believe
that there's an attic control fire within
eyesight and there's helicopters are
constantly flying over and the
dropping water on it and you're like,
that thing's out of control. They can't
stop this. Yeah, you can smell it now.
Hollywood 20, 30 miles away. You could
smell this to ash. Dude, we went,
we had an episode of fear factor that we
shot and we shot it out a place where I
think it's called Lake t Haun Tai,
I forget where it is. It's way out.
Way Up north. Right? It's like
an hour, hour plus away. Uh,
once you get on the highway. Yeah, I'm a
way up there on the way. So anyway, uh,
maybe, maybe it's an hour and a
half from the city, so maybe um,
we get there, it's like 10 o'clock in
the morning. We set up, we start filming.
We had to, we got the stunt done, but
we got to stunt done barely in time.
Now when I left,
the fire was in Santa Clarita,
which was over an hour driving by car.
Okay.
That's when I left my house. That's
where the fire was. When I came back,
when I was leaving, going
home, the fire was where I was.
It just spreads out,
spread an hour's driving
three or four hours.
It was going 2020 miles an hour,
probably spreading at 20 miles an hour
at 20 miles an hour. It had to be
because if I think about all the,
all the miles that it covered and it
covered them and only a couple hours,
it was a really quick stunt.
Like a lot of times we have a stunt
and it's not that big of a deal.
It only takes like a couple hours for the
first through last contestant to do it.
And this was one of those, cause I
remember we got out in, everybody's like,
we need to get the fuck outta here.
You could see it coming over the hill
and dude driving home. This isn't it.
This is what an hour for
one solid hour driving home,
going at a normal pace. 50 to 60 miles an
hour. Not Fast. No one was driving fast.
The entire right side from my passenger
window out the entire right side of the
world. It was on fire. That's crazy.
The road right there on the road.
The road on the
road. Yeah. Pitch on the road too. I
remember you posted on the road. Yes,
you could feel the heat, you can feel
the heat. If you roll down the window,
you could feel the fire. Okay. And
you could see ash falling everywhere,
like it was snowing and while we're
driving and we're just hoping that somehow
or another, this fire can't get us, but
it can't get you when you're on the road.
The only way can get you as if there's a
firestorm with a heavy wind and there's
literally tornadoes of fire.
So we're both like rip it across and
they could catch your car on fire.
And that is possible.
It is possible that that could happen if
there's enough fuel near the road that
it catches and runs to it.
It's like one of the reasons why
you're supposed to clear off the brush,
like near your house and around your house
so that it doesn't mean they probably
have rules for the road too. So for over
an hour we're driving and it's like,
it's like lord of the rings,
Bro.
What you remember when the fucking tower
came alive and all the goblins came out,
dude. Yeah, exactly. The eye. It's insane.
It's all fire. It doesn't seem real.
It seemed so artificial. And everyone
was driving around like slack. Jawed Oh,
and that's right. Some guy got hit by
a fucking car. I forgot about this.
He's not looking because he's looking
at, the guy died. Yeah, he died.
He got hit by a fucking car.
He's something happened to his car and
he tried to run across the highway and he
got nailed. And you've got
nail. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
How would it get away from
the fire? Something? Yeah.
I don't know the exact specifics of why
he was trying to run across the highway,
but he didn't make it.
And I believe one of the producers
of the show actually saw it happen.
It was like several cars ahead.
He actually saw the guy get hit,
he got out of his car and
try to run across. Yes.
He tried to run across the road and they,
you know,
and he got fucking crushed. It's
so terrifying. And then, you know,
so you see this thing where there's
cops and ambulances and everything and
they're, you know, they're,
they're tending to this guy and
you're trying to rubber neck.
And then after you get past that,
it's just like literally you're waiting
for demons on black horses to come
rolling over the top of the
mountain. Wow. Dude. It's insane.
And you can't stop it. You know, that
Shit's going on right now in Arizona.
It's completely out of control or it
was at least a couple of days ago.
It's completely under control in San Diego
for the fires down there. Yeah, I did.
Yeah. Well, you know what happened? Um,
I was booked at a theater out there.
I forgot the name of the place.
So it would alternate between doing the
house of Blues and San Diego and this
other place, which was really cool. Yeah,
that's it. Yeah. Fourth and be right.
That's what it's called. That's what
it's called. Right. So, um, anyway, um,
white before I was
supposed to go down there,
the fires hit San Diego and
San Diego got fucked up.
So many people lost their houses.
So I didn't feel right about just going
in there and not giving them something
and not, not saying, hey, you know, you
guys just got fucked up. You know, I,
I want to send you some appreciation.
Give you some love. So I,
I gave them all the money that
I made. Like a concert. Yeah.
Give it all to the Red Cross. So it
was cool. So I felt good, you know,
and so like I to his point,
well it's like I did the show
cause I wanted to do the show,
not because anybody was, you know,
everybody who paid money, they didn't,
none of that shit went
to me, not a sin. It
all went to the Red Cross and it was,
it was fun.
And so that way that felt like I have
like a moral compass when it comes to shit
like that. And if I feel like, Ooh,
I'm pulling money out of this and this
is like a place that just got hit with
some natural disaster. Like I shouldn't
be pulling any money out of this area,
I should be giving that money right back.
Right. So, you know, it's, I feel like,
look,
these people lost everything.
At the very least I can lose my
salary for a show to help, you know,
just to say thank you.
This is important, man.
You have to go on those instincts.
Mpr there,
this study wants about giving and the
endorphins, it releases inside you.
You actually feel happy. Yeah.
Just like after sex, you know,
and after certain things, just chemically,
your body enjoys giving. Some people,
they say they don't. Some people
say, I fuck them, I'm from Fargo,
I'm out from me Bro.
And they'll laugh about it.
But I get that and that's
what the owl thinking it.
But the actual act of doing when
you do it helps you in some way.
It's not stronger to do that.
There's people that think
that it's stronger. I go,
fuck, fuck everybody
else. I'm out from me.
And then it's like this hard ass to
approach is pragmatic approach to life.
No one's going to fuck me over. I'm going
to fuck them over. Fuck you. But that,
that approach is really the weak persons
way out. It's really, you know, yes.
You're going to run into a
lot of douchebags in his life.
How about help each other. That's why
he took his son and Jen so long to um,
meet everybody else on the island.
Oh
Wow. Yeah, man. They made that Asian
girl. I have to be a dirty whore.
Demean her out there having an affair
on that. Nice man. You put your,
but it's okay. He drove her to it. Yeah.
He drove her to it. Yeah, he was. He was,
he was, he was a monster. I guess that's
how they was just trying to get by. Yeah.
He had to beat that guy.
He'd beat that guy off so that he'd be,
it became a bad guy now.
Yeah. Have you heard a theanine, theanine,
serene lift? Where? Laura here,
here's what you're talking about.
Is it a supplement? Yeah, it's, yeah,
it's a, a Dunkin turned me onto it.
It's AI thing. I think it's found in
green tea a lot really? But he says like,
you know, you take a couple of them and
spell it for the folks at home. All right.
UH, t h. E a. N. I n. E.
Next word is s. E r e n.
E. N. N with low Aurora,
R e l o. R. A. And what
is it supposed to do?
He says it's like a natural relaxer,
like it takes stress away and kind of
calms you down and stuff like that.
And he's like,
I took three and I felt like I had,
it was like on Vicodin
or something like that.
So I bought some and I took four
yesterday and it was, it was very nice.
Kind of like a chill,
relaxing kind of moot.
Do you want to Joey Diaz mode? Fucking
mama off the joint. You shut the fuck up.
What are you going to want?
Shit on amazon.com I go down a Cushman.
I stepped back, I gave him $40.
We say hi, I'm about my business.
You know you're doing with that fucking,
you buy on amazon.com
it would not work, Brian. It would
not work on him. Where's television
Brian?
But would,
what would it be like if you ever feel
irritable or anything like that with they
of that kind of like anxious
edge and stuff like that?
It seems like it'd be great for that.
Yeah.
I like some Endeca for that
because I had that, I had the, uh,
yesterday and the jeopardy Tosha, yeah.
Drop. Not all the time for me man.
Like sometimes it just amplifies that
shit. So you like to try this stuff now?
Yeah. Well I W I used it
yesterday or did use it, so yeah.
And it totally just took that away.
I had that question.
It's like kind of on the edge or two days
ago. I'm sorry, I have a question. So,
so dark.
He goes,
I took three of them felt like
biking or whatever and you're like,
I'm going straight for for,
well,
I did research on it and then on the
bottle it says recommended dose two.
And I'm like, well, I'm going to
do twice the recommended fuck that.
I'm not going to die,
die off green tea.
Do you want to try it and see what
drugs start low and then move up slowly?
It's not really a drug, right? Isn't it
a drug? No, it's not. It's like, well,
let's explain that then, because if it's
altering your mood, it's gotta be a drug.
Um, it's uh, it's not an illegal narcotic.
Holy Basil Leaf extract and I saw all
you're going to get fucked up on basil
where you're gonna die. Uh, be careful.
Can Be Amino acid.
L theanine I guess is what to support
one of those trees in my backyard. Yeah.
You know when you get a Mozzarella
Caprese Mozzarella, like the good stuff,
especially that burrata stuff or
grotto that you get from Italy,
that real juicy Mozzarella and
then you have those beef steak,
tomatoes and then they put basil on
it. I eat the basil to Bro. Really?
Cause that's how I roll.
I don't give a fuck the law plucked that
Bazell off and they'll actually aside,
I eat the shit out of that base.
What about that little green thing?
I'm a savage show. Green. What's
that? Just trying to like a gorilla.
That's that green thing that sometime
they add that's the hawks dick that up
like garnish. Oh what is it like put
it on top of like an orange sometimes.
Yeah.
Or like Danny's parse.
It's like something like it's more
just for looks. It's not deal.
Looks like the leaves of a deal.
Just like it's like green.
It just makes it cheap. Diners
use it cheap. Diners do it.
When you buy like a blue fish,
you buy the grain thing
fucking clear. So you know we're
talking about what is that thing?
How do we not know the word for this?
This is a store in a word.
Is it really Italian garnish but I don't
know. Green Shit, not parsley. Parsley.
You sure? I'm not sure. Honestly.
I'm not sure. I don't know.
I always thought it was partially that
you throw on Shit when you want it to
look pretty. And Greg
is parsley. Well fancy.
I think that's more like fancy place
where we're talking about like old diner
where they have like that green thing and
not even edible. Like you're like, Ooh,
oh really? What is that?
It's just shitty person.
It's weird where there's some
shit that Chinese Kale, Kale,
Kale is the shit that
I make my, my, my lean
shakes out. It look it up. There's
no way it's Kale, Kale, bro.
Kale is like a lettuce. Stupid
idiot cow. Fuck it through a bit.
But I guess you could if
you went to a vegan place.
It's very possible that get sprinkled
Kale and your food if they really shredded
it, but it's pretty uncommon. That's
not what we're thinking. I know.
It's delicious though, man. They have
like a, like a dried Kale, like big,
they make Kale chips. Oh yeah.
These are like Vegan Kale chips.
They're fucking delicious, man. There's
so good. It's hard to believe that.
They're like sort of like super
hippie, healthy. Oh yeah, man.
It tastes awesome there. There's not a
lot of bang for the volume. Whatever.
It's like light bags. Yeah,
like, well, you have a big bag,
but they dissolve so quick in your
mouth. It's like, yeah, it's weird.
It's like as you eat it, it
dissolves really quick, but fuck.
They're delicious man.
And plus you get to feel really
good about the environment.
Why Kale? Man? I'm eating Kale.
I'm like helping when you eat kale. Kale
is like saying, I do yoga, really Kale.
I'm going to kill them into yoga. I'm into
Buddhism. Very spiritual. A lot of Kale.
Yeah. Construction workers
don't talk to you about Kale.
What are you eating for lunch,
Tommy? I got a Kale Salad.
Posters it up a little delicious,
Bro.
It's got organic coop
gumballs in this thing.
Load it when you start calling a fear
factor there. Go the end of the month.
The end of this month. Yep. Bam. So out
this month, July, July. Are You Angela?
The party roles? Don't, don't, don't,
don't, don't. I can't it all job.
You want story storyteller
show in Montreal. Are you
doing one when fuck stories?
We're doing a four days.
All about sex club. Good.
Because you can mix in some
material on that. Yeah.
Well some of my stories that turn into
that, definitely. Yeah. I, when I do your,
your storytellers show,
I just figured out what material did I
have that covers the subject and I just
do that.
I'll tell a little bit of a story.
I'll fuck around a little bit. It's like
this one time. Does that make it a story?
If I said I'm gonna go right into my bits,
I just feel like if I'm in front
of a large audience talking,
I'm way better when I'm just doing comedy.
What bill burr did last time. Yeah,
he did it also did a story that was a
from the podcast too. It was really,
really good at Ranson stuff. He's
hilarious man. He's a fucking monster.
He's one of those guys. There's, there's
a few of those guys out there that,
you know, I, I really enjoy going
to watch cause it gives me like, uh,
an inspirational creative.
Joel Chapelle was always like that.
Like I would see him and you know,
a Nick Depaulo.
I saw him in New York and it gave
me like a big jolt want Norton.
When I saw Norton in Austin, he
gave me a big jolt. You know,
you see a guy who's really good,
you go, Ooh man, that was fun.
I want to go fucking right again and
going on stage right now. You know,
it makes you really excited about him.
It's where he's filter you up.
Cities when I was like, Ooh,
I want to go roll tonight.
Something you need to get back in
and dude, don't, don't, don't listen.
I can help you out, man. This
is what we're going to do.
We're going to get you on a weightlifting
program for a good solid six months
before we throw it in there.
Take us kettlebells. Kinda
fucked my knee up. Yeah,
because, well, you know what?
Now that have been working with Steven
Maximal exercise, Steve Maxwell,
world renowned fitness coach,
he straightened me out on a bunch of
different shit and how to do things
correctly.
He made like a,
a bunch of little videos from me on my
iPhone like he would do the elaborate
technique. Yeah, it helps. It helps.
Having somebody who study with the
Charles Atlas School of weightlifting.
Well we can do for you though, Dude. It
start you out with no weights at all.
I can, I can devise a really good
routine. That's all bodyweight shit.
All Body weight squats. You'd be amazed
at how hard bodyweight squats are there.
Easy for for three or four and then maybe
for 10 but when you get to 30 and 40
and 50 and you start doing
102 hundred know my dad is,
you know the guy who was the ms who's
the the wrestling champion now and I've
heard of WWE wrestling champion. He
was a contestant on fear factor. Yeah.
And even back then he had been on it so
he was, yeah, he was a reality show guy.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. This was he
on road rules. Piper's pit.
What was the reality show you get
whatever he was on. Cool asphalt,
the road rules, something like that.
Maybe it was a real world. I don't know.
Cool ass fucking guy. Very, very cool guy.
He and really impressive
athlete like dude,
he was the most impressive athlete
in the history of fear factor by far.
It was a stunt that they had to do.
We had a dive underwater and you had a
see like you had to like go through all
these things and get all these different,
I think it was like flags like retrieved
flags and sugar water and no one came
close to what he could do.
He went and dove under,
held his breath for like
more than two minutes,
accomplish the whole thing
faster than anybody. He's like a,
he's a freak athlete and what he would
do is bodyweight squats every day.
He would say that,
you know when he was learning how
to wrestle they would have them.
One of the conditioning things they did
is like Karl gotch is like this famous
wrestling conditioning guy and he would
advocate these bodyweight squats to,
they're called Hindu squats and
they do 500 of them every day. Dude,
you will have tree trunk legs
and without any weights at all.
You don't have to lift any weights.
Just straight pushups man.
We'll get you in some serious condition.
Yeah, I was the chip collect college.
I would do like just push
us before showers sit ups,
push ups and push ups like yourself on
like a real routine where you're going to
do three sets of 53 sets of 50 pushups,
three t you're going to build up to it.
But this is going to be the eventual
routine. Three sets of 50 uh, you know,
depths three sets of 1500. If
I could even do it now, yeah,
you probably could,
but we want to build up to 50 where
you can really give yourself a couple
minutes break and get right back in there
and try to bang out 50 and if you've
got to get on your knees for a couple
seconds and then dive back in just but
finish that fucking set first,
that set. And then dude,
you'd be an incredible shape.
You don't have to lift weights.
There's a bunch of guys who advocate just
all body weight exercises and there's
a bunch of them on the Internet.
I don't want to say their names because
I think some of them are crooks,
but there's some good enough ones that
you could find some shit online. And, and,
and, you know, without
paying anybody, you know,
when released these exercises as a
result of his time, you really shouldn't.
Everybody should be,
I totally believe in paying for a trainer,
but I also taught to believe if you're
doing some shit that everybody already
should know, like how to do a pushup,
you know, fucking put that online master,
keeping that shit to yourself.
It's a system, I guess,
that they're putting out over
those things. He's having parks.
We can do the exercise stations do. Those
are awesome. People used to do those.
I think I did them once ever once ever.
I did it once when I was fighting.
I was like, well, he's always said
that this is what I'm gonna do.
I'm going to get in real good shape by
doing this every day before sparring and
I just go in to all my sit ups and
Chin ups and pushups and Brian,
just check the fuck out.
Notice that we started talking about
fitness and Brian's like done nap time.
I do that sometimes because you guys
talked about technology. I just like,
it's not even, I'll just, my mind wanders
to things that I have any idea. Look,
we completely lost Eddie yesterday.
Eddie told a story about,
it's a boy that he thought was his son
and he completely checked out to the best
of the blood. Gas and Ufo is man. Yeah,
fucked up.
That was the real story.
It was very sad and it was like I was
almost checked out of it, but I was like,
oh, I was just thinking about it. He's
got some shit that I knew this story.
I knew the story already.
Obviously eddies one of my closest
people on this planet. But, uh,
yeah, I really think that in order
to be a guy like catty, you know,
in order to be like one of these
super creative weirdo types,
you almost have to have like a really
fucking completely just jacked life as a
child, you know, in order to be
bro, all of us that have, you know,
the,
that I know that I hang out with,
all of us have come from some
fucking bizarro childhood situation,
like every single one of us where it's
almost like you have to have some shit
parents every now and then in a
culture to jolt people out of the norm.
Definitely will. There's plenty of
people come out of those. But yeah,
there's a lot of people that come out
of that and they become Super Christian.
Yeah. A lot of people that come out of
Shitty childhoods and they, you know,
just fine. Yeah. They,
they've managed to deal with it or they
have a drink every night and try to
forget it. But, you know,
I think Alex on people,
but I think everyone that I
know that's really brilliant.
All my brilliant friends have like a
weird, some fucking nutty childhood.
What we're looking at me and like
bill burrs, like I don't know.
Well I know Bill Byrd was violence
with his brother and like talks,
he's got some great stories about it.
They did it. Your storytellers show. Yeah.
You know, and he's talking about
about how to shake their hands. Yeah.
I believe he's Irish.
You know,
the Irish in Boston are fucking
savages and that is just a fact.
And I don't think people can really
wrap their head around how nutty those
fucking people.
You know.
And I can say that cause that's where I
grew up and I'm one quarter Irish and I
understand it 100% but they're
like a double negative of site.
It's a hard town son. And you
know, you grow up with your,
your son and who knows what his,
you know, his dad was like that.
These kids were getting away
with this behavior. You know,
who knows what the fuck was happening.
But it seems like the whole
family likes to argue.
That's why bill's birth
such a brilliant comedian.
Cause he became amazing at arguing when
he was the youngest guy in the smallest
guy. So he had to be
the quickest wit. Yeah,
they do that are basketball
players whenever they're like,
I need to be forced to the dinner table.
I didn't get any food like up did.
He told,
he told a brilliant story about the
first time he beat his brother in a fight
and then he felt his brother quit and
then it just killed him and he was like 35
or something and he was like,
Oh I shouldn't be beating you up.
You're my older brothers. I think. No, I
think it was younger when that happened.
Then there was a fight when he was
older we grabbed onto it and held him.
He said he wasn't going to fight him.
He wasn't going to,
his brother was trying to find them,
but then his brother got winded cause he
was a suit. He was really a funny story.
I used to be five minutes, 50 seconds,
just no, we'd round twos and five minutes.
He's like sitting there holding his knee
and breathing but just still burns this
five minutes, you know, and look man,
look how brilliant Pilbara
bill burrs you got to,
you almost like have to go through
something to be that guy, you know,
to be very few comics that
I know that I hang out with.
Have parents that are together
or have any sort of like,
well my mom and my Stepdad are actually
very happy and they've been happy since
I was seven years old.
It's real weird.
All my damage shit came
from my real father and all
before you were seven? Yeah,
before I was seven. That's all
the damaging shit. My father,
my real father was crazy. He was like
a psychotic person. Really? Yeah.
He was be beat the fuck out of him.
Like he would be the type of come up
with the fuck out of my cousin. Yeah.
He'd beat my cousin up. He
picked my cousin. I'm buying
his hair dude drugs. Oh No,
no, no, no, no. My cousin had
done something. He had hurt.
Somebody was playing hard and hurt
somebody and he was a bigger kid.
He was like 16, and my dad picked
him up by his fucking hair on,
never forget the rue him and
he was a big guy, big scary,
crazy cop from New Jersey.
Oh yeah.
So that was all my shit from when I
was like really young. I got to see,
I got to see worst case scenario,
someone who just can't keep it together,
smacks women to shit out of kids,
uh, beats the shit out of them.
So I got to see that really early. But
then my dad, my Stepdad is a hippie.
My stepdad was a computer programmer,
computer programmer,
and he was an architect.
He went to school for architecture after
he stopped doing computer programming.
That's why we lived in San Francisco.
But that's weird.
You're too well in a negative way,
but it's like your dad's a Weirdo hippie
like that Kibo was raised by lesbians
and all that.
Like people would make fun of me when I
went to school because my dad had long
hair. Yeah, yeah. He's my Stepdad.
His hair would go down to his ass.
And I still wasn't accepting him as a
father because I was a little snotty cause
I was seven years old and my dad was my
real dad and my real dad was in this bad
ass guy and know that you
didn't know any better.
It was a stupid kid because my
father wanted me to be like him,
so he would do shit.
Like one time I had a fight with
my cousin because I liked Godzilla.
He like King Kong, one of those fucking
things instead of going like great, great.
I guess I like King Kong and he like
Godzilla and he wouldn't stop saying that
God's Zillow would fucking hung up. So it
turned into a fight somehow or another,
you know, kids, kids are retarded, you
know, full Q when you're King Kong,
we were sweating, you know, it got
broken up by someone's mom. And then, uh,
you know, my, my dad pulled me aside and
just pull me in a room, shut the door.
I'll never forget this because I
was five years old and he, you know,
and there's a very few things that I
remember about him. This is one of them.
I remember what the dresser looked like.
I remember what the fuck and the sheets
look like on the bed. And he goes,
what happened? And I said, you
could not lie to him. There was no,
there was no lines. Just, you know, this
sounds like the beginning of a rape story.
Yeah. Okay. Conveyed. It's mine. Mine
rape. What happened? And I said, uh,
me and Mikey got in a
fight. What happened? I go,
we were talking about King Kong
versus Godzilla and you know,
I liked one and he liked the other and
we've got in a fight. You didn't cry,
did you? I go, no, I didn't cry.
He goes, don't ever cry. Oh.
And that was the hook.
And he patted me on the head and
he walked out of the room though.
You didn't give a fuck
that I was in a fight.
He just wanted to make sure there was
no crime bitches in the street. Ah,
yeah. It was his hack, right.
Advice for a five year old was punching
everybody after that, I was like,
all right, you're getting punched.
Talk some shit. I'm punching her cry.
I got the green light,
I get the green light to punch kids.
As long as they keep it dry.
It was so stupid.
It was like the worst way of raising
a child ever. Especially boys.
The worst thing you can ever do to
boys is encouraged amongst, oh my God,
it's the worst thing you can ever do.
My friend has a boy and a,
it's really fascinating to watch
this little guy grow up and he's a,
he's like two now and his personality
is fucking hilarious cause he's like a
little bad ass,
you know?
And he hits things and pushes things
around and it's naturally in him.
You could see it. He picks the
sticks up and wacks him on things.
Like that's what he wants to do. He's
two, he's fucking to Matt violent breed.
Yeah. And when he gets older. If that
kid have a dad, like my dad who was like,
you know, you know this is how
you fucking hold your hands up.
If somebody gives you any shit,
he hit him with the jab first.
That way they don't see
the right hand comment.
I was like four he was teaching
me how to fuck people up crazy.
Just ignore police. They'll go away. Oh
No. My Dad wanted me, he was a karate guy,
so he wanted me to enroll in
karate to when I got older,
but there was no karate
classes for four year olds,
so I had to wait it out and he would
like show him some shit watching
beat up on. I would watch
him beat guys up at this bar.
He owned a bar and I was five and I got
to hang out at the bar when I was five.
When I was five. I would sit there and I
would, I would put money in the jukebox.
They would let me put money in the
jukebox and everything and then I'd watch
them beat the fuck out of somebody.
That was fine.
Those are all my memories of my father.
So I go from that to this other dude who's
like super nice and he smokes pot and
he's really smart.
He's a mathematical genius.
He's a computer programmer and he
decides to computer program is not
artistically satisfying.
So he wants to go to school and he takes
my mom and he marries her and we move
across the country and all a sudden I
have this new dad and it's like this hippy
guy and you know, and he was only
24 years old. Oh yeah. So you know,
my mom was like 30 you know, not even
know. My mom wasn't even 30 what's the,
I was seven. So my mom was, yeah, she
was like 27 or something like that,
or 28 cause she had me when she was like
2021 so everybody was very young and no
one knew what the fuck was going on.
And then all of a sudden I'm living with
this hippy guy in San Francisco around
a bunch of gay people. That's when I
went from an hour we then right there.
Okay. Then, so I went from
living around these Italian,
New Jersey psychopaths to all of a sudden
I'm in San Francisco and it's all like
peace and love.
It's the 70s man.
This the 70s everybody had long hair
in San Francisco. Not really man. No.
Carry over at all. No, no. I was pretty,
I was pretty humbled and really shy,
you know, real nervous and I didn't have
a father anymore. All of a sudden end.
He wasn't contacting me anymore.
Yeah.
So all of a sudden I'm like out here
going on with a fuck is life. You know,
what am I doing?
I was very insecure and that's when I
really got into drawing from then from
like seven until like til high school
to my high school art teacher was a
Douchebag, killed my
dreams. But up until then,
from seven on that was just doing
art constantly, constantly drawing.
That was like my, my outlet. It's my high
school. People used to always tell me,
they were like, I bet you'd really
be good at art if you tried.
That'd be good for anybody who's never
done it. You could do anything, Dude.
You could do anything. You
know, if you're, it's the,
the Miyamoto Musashi quote that I always,
they always talk about once you become,
once you know,
the way broadly you can
see it in all things.
Once you become really good at something,
you figure something out.
Like you figured out, stand up, you
figured out a way to construct a bit,
you figured out a way to go on there
and just kill in front of a group of
strangers can be figured out.
Yeah, you can do anything man.
You just need to have the
love and passion for it.
It doesn't mean you can do anything that
sucks, you know, you might not want to,
you part of like being good at
anything is being excited about it.
I was talking about, and he's
pretty much just writing now and um,
and he's like, I'm trying to write
like sitcoms or script and it's like,
it's tough,
but he understands.
It's like I'm going to write a few that
aren't going to be good so that they
will then get good. That's the
path to make something good. Yeah.
You've got to suffer, you
know, to get good at anything.
It's sucks man. You know,
I just started doing Jujitsu again because
my, I took like two months off man.
I kept reinjuring this part of
my back like over and over again.
But then I started getting,
um,
a cold laser therapy on it and
I went to deep tissue massage.
Massage by a dude was just first time
ever I got massaged by a dude once back
when I was fighting. That
was really good. Wait,
why didn't you just tap out right there?
No, no, no, because this guy is a,
he's an expert in, um, it's called,
I'll tell you what it's called. Shit.
It's like neuromuscular education.
I was like neuromuscular reeducation.
It's a specific type of stretching and
deep tissue massage. At the same time,
there was developed by these people who
are strengthened for fitness trainers
and this guy was the former head
strength and fitness coach for Purdue
University.
He's got like all these cutting edge
techniques and it hurts like fucking shit.
It's like,
it's not like to go and get a massage.
You go to a chiropractor's office,
you know,
just like out of the phobia keeps us
from getting a massage with stronger next
to this guy. This is clearly not
gay. I'm not trying to get there.
But the dude dude who breaks
me down is like, he's two 60.
He's a fucking crowd.
He's like six foot three.
So one of those 50 year old dude's, it
looks like you beat the fuck out of you.
He's like 50 years old. These
giant hands, these giant arms.
You need a dude like the
sounds gay as fuck somebody.
Please do not make this an animated little
clip and put it on the internet or me
getting a boner. But I'll tell this
guy, it should be fucking do shit.
He can do shit that those little
Thailand women can't do. Man.
He can hurt you dude. And the breaks
all your scar tissue up. And the, the,
the key is when, as I understand it, when
you, um, anytime you do any activity, any,
any physical straining exercise,
when you're sore,
it's lactic acid and it's also a muscle
tears, little, little tiny muscle tears.
And that's what makes you stronger.
Your muscles have a little little tears
and they heal up and becomes stronger
though. So, but in the process of
doing that, it's been explained to me,
you develop scar tissue in there and
you have to break it up in order to get
full movement of the muscles.
If you don't,
it results in injuries and when you
exercise a lot but you don't get your scar
tissue broken down and broke, you are
more likely to suffer from injuries,
from being tight injuries
from being locked up.
And I was having that until I started
going and I gave in and started getting
massaged by a dude.
This is the reasons why I'm not going to
go back to digit to know all about this.
I enjoy a Jujitsu man. When I'm doing
Jujitsu, I don't think about shit.
I just think I try to do that when I'm
playing pool. But when I'm playing pool,
it's up to me. You know,
when I'm playing pool,
it's up to me to zone out and focus on
a thing. But when you're doing Jujitsu,
you have no choice,
man.
I just don't like the risk of me limping
when Adler for I know what you mean.
I'm willing to deal with. Again,
I'm not worried about it, man.
I know a lot of people. I know a lot
of people do it. You can get hurt.
It is possible, but if you roll
a smart people and you, you,
you roll intelligently.
You don't try to use too much physical
strength and willing to tap out.
If you're in a bad situation,
you're not really in danger, man.
As long as you're rolling with
friends, you know. I mean,
I haven't the hurt somebody else.
Every falls last time. Yeah.
The last time I heard somebody was an
accident, complete accident. A guy was a,
I was passing his guard and
something popped on his leg.
He tried to post up and his leg gave
out like a ligament came out. Well,
good to hear it pop. I felt
terrible, but it was nothing I did.
It was just part of rolling your,
you'd try to get a grip and that doesn't
work was on my back and my foot was
down and it just, he was heavy. He didn't
jump on me or anything. He was just,
and then just buckled over
my foot and I'm like, no,
that's just to stop immediately.
But it was like, it happens Ruth.
But you know what,
man,
I think there's so much benefit in
doing it for me at least everybody's
different, Brian. I don't,
I really believe him when he says he
doesn't need it because everybody's got
their own physical requirement for
them. Yeah. It's not just that,
it's physical requirements.
You know,
like some people they have
to blow off steam. Oh right.
You know some people like and,
and they're intense people and
they have to blow off that steam.
And if they don't blow
off that steam in the gym,
it can leak out into everyday
life and make them unreasonable.
And then they'll blow up about
things that don't make sense.
Like they get mad at things.
There's only one reason to get mad
at something that doesn't make sense.
You have some extra tension.
Sleep. Yeah. And you're approaching
the situation. You're already at a five
before you walk into the door. Yeah.
It's first here to irritability goes.
So this person comes at you with a two,
which should be like, Oh man, really?
Oh what instead of you like this is the
same fucking shit with you owe to him.
And really you're raging
against is your own shit life.
That's what you're raging against.
But everybody else gets caught
in the fucking crossfire. Yeah.
Norton talked about that as unmasked
interview without [inaudible]. Yeah,
he was like when he was off on break he,
it's so much thinner cause he needed to
fucking pull off Craig's team. You know?
But if he had ona, he can
do that every morning. Yeah.
He used to write great blogs too, man.
Norton road, some hilarious blog entries.
But he stopped doing that also when he
was doing ona all the time cause he feels
like creatively fulfilled.
And you know what,
that's an important thing
about being creative, man.
You don't want to work too
hard and it sounds ridiculous,
but there's a certain amount of time
where you should be dedicating to having
fun as well. Building up new members
to write about. And, and not only that,
just living your life
man, you know, and you,
you can only spend a certain amount
of time, you know, working on,
on anything that you know is,
is it like a creative venture and we'll
are doing like radio show and you're
doing four or five hours a day and then
you're doing standup at night and you're
writing this, you don't have much
downtime in the middle there. You know.
And a guy like Norton,
it's probably way better for his happiness
to just chill out and those hours,
I'm sure he's not chilling eyes getting
hookers and doing some dirty now more
and more lately if I had like a spot at
the store and it's like a late spot and
like I'm doing something fun
like I'm at a party or something,
I'm like no I should be here.
I'll get more creative like out of here
that I will just rehearsing in front of
eight people.
It's a part of your job.
I mean one of the reasons why I moved
to Colorado. Absolutely true. It was,
I'm like, I am getting some
fucking material out of this
for sure. And I did. Yeah.
And you know, at a cost, but
you know, sacrifice. No matter.
I mean, I think about that all
the time. Like I put myself,
that's why I wanted to meet some
of those ferries. That's why I'm,
I'm thinking about, uh, I
went to a furry convention.
Oh, furry. I talking to Eric to
get a flying around all the time, giving
me advice. It's size from Tim Ferris. Not,
not that kind of fairy. This guy is
not, I'm not like that. How dare you?
How dare you? I'm sorry. Don't
put those thoughts in my mind. Um,
what the fuck were we just talking about?
Furries for convention? The shining,
that one scene that somebody posts that
I remember it. Was that the first furry,
I don't know. Maybe that'd be furry.
Something that existed like forever. Yeah,
late seventies,
early eighties,
something like that where somebody sent
me a photo of, you forgot about that.
Somebody sent me a photo of Osu,
like this furry people at night
and it was like seven of them.
And they looked like scary kind
of distant. It was in Cleveland.
It was in Cincinnati, Columbus. But yeah,
there's a Columbus. Yeah, I thought so.
We're wherever it is. I heard about
it. I didn't see the photo though.
It was a crazy, yeah, it's weird.
What was it? What was going on? We,
we're talking about this yesterday.
Yes sir.
On the podcast.
So people that have already heard this,
I'll just give you the brief version of
it. There's a thing called being a furry,
and I know people that
are sexually attracted to,
you know about it.
There was a convention of
them in Pittsburgh last week.
And so what were they doing there? What
was that at Ohio state. Well, they have,
somebody came and somebody sent me a
photo of them just across the street. Oh,
just hang out in a barn. No, we
haven't been Columbus, Ohio too.
And they all hang out on the streets
and stuff together. It's kind of like a,
like a gang of mascot stuffed
animals are so weird, dude.
And you don't know what's, you can't read
them at all. And it's all sexual. Yeah.
Well, it's sexual, but it's
also just fantasy. You know,
they'll get together and they actually
play like dungeons and dragons and shit.
Like this is like the recreating like
the like a like whatever like Giles and
stuff. No, no. Their version of
that like well sort of. Yeah, yeah,
yeah.
I wrote a blog entry about that too,
about going to the renaissance fair
and it seen how fucking strange it was.
And there was a one particular thing that
was really strange. Most of the people,
it was really kind of admirable because
most of the people stayed in character.
Most of the dam,
no standing here having a
pound your chest at the world,
you know,
I wish I wasn't too cool for that,
but I just couldn't bring myself
to the puck and go full out.
Well it would probably be a good test
of your ability to act, you know?
Because if you could go there
and just throw yourself into it,
like really be zen about
being one of those guys.
I thought it'd be probably a good exercise
if you like a crazy person wanting to
act. But when we were there, um, one
of the things that was fascinating,
it was most of the people
were in character, but this
one lady, man, this one lady,
you could tell she's only in the
renaissance faire because she's like,
she needs to be in some sort of a group.
It's like,
when is she going know you're
going to play Bingo? Okay,
I'll be down with the renaissance fair.
So this,
this woman was sitting there and the
woman was all in character and shit and
this other lady was talking
to her about her problems,
but she was talking to her or
like in normal terms, she's like,
so now Mike has to figure out which
prescription to take the one doctor.
Like she's, you know, to do it like
that one lady that doom and gloom.
And so, um, the other woman
won't, won't crack. She goes,
what tough my lady mean by prescription.
So word I've never heard before,
you know? And so she starts, you know,
fucking weather while this chick
is trying to complain to her.
How would she react when she really,
well,
she followed her and then they walked
away and I didn't want to follow them and
be that obvious listening
in on the conversation.
But it was obvious that one chick was
being a little cunty and she was bringing
her boring shit into this
beautiful land of make believe.
And I'm pretending I'm a maiden here and
you're talking to me about, you know,
your, your, your, your husband,
Mike's Prescriptions, you know,
you do what the fuck we need to do, lady,
you know, this is not the time for this.
Maybe afterwards if we're going to go
have a drink and a cigarette, you know,
you want to sit down and talk to me about
your life, that's cool. But right now,
you know, all this God damn maiden,
their work at renaissance fairs,
they're all fucking at night. Oh,
they just get together and bang.
I talked to people. One of the guys
just work the breakdown prop, uh,
always quit for those two weeks
while they're here and I'm there.
So I asked them questions for two weeks
to go hang out with them. Yeah, awesome.
That is awesome.
And he'd go through Lizard works there
every year and I'd like to think people
like it's her fucking going on. He
goes, that's all that's going on.
See that's seven o'clock you can do
that when you don't have kids. Oh yeah,
you can go to renaissance fair. I fucked
the shit out of everybody. When you're,
when you're totally single,
I know you don't have a girlfriend.
Just going to have been a science fair
and just clean up knocking out of the
ballpark because they're supposed to
have origins. They had origins back then.
No one's got a cell phone.
It's Renaissance Times.
Put that fucking cell phone away right
away and complete this train. Yes.
You don't have to worry about
like getting on the Internet.
Everybody's like sticking to the code.
This is the color.
It must be so easy to be a whore back then
he uses lie, you know, like just bang.
All kinds of dudes everywhere in the
little pictures from back then you would
have sex with your cousins and sisters
too. They just fuck everybody back then.
Yeah. I don't think there
was a bad thing. It really,
when do you think that incest
becomes a bad no, that was our,
they had Christians in the renaissance.
How common is it assessing the animal
world? It's common with dogs, right?
Zero incest. Incest in the animal world.
Yeah. In the animal world. Pretty common.
Right. They bang their,
their cousins for sure.
The banging his sisters because
they don't know any better.
They'll bang their sisters. Right? Yeah.
If you leave them alone under
bite was created. Yeah. It's like
stay away from their own exact
siblings. I'm like, Woah,
don't they go off on their own?
I don't know how that works.
I'm not sure if they do it
or not. Hmm. I think, uh,
that's one of the things that they say
about certain Labrador retrievers is that
they are inbred. Yeah. That's what
they say about a, a bad genetic,
what you mean what they say it about them?
That means most of them that
don't do that or wouldn't do that.
I think most of them,
most of them don't,
but there are a few would in the
puppy mills and stuff like that.
I'd be surprised who know
I'm talking to my ass.
I don't know what the actual number.
So tiger and a lion wants,
but it's like that'll never
happen in nature. Yeah. I wonder.
Hmm could it? Yeah, sure. But is there
a place where there's lions and tigers?
Is there a place Zeus. Oh, both
of them together. You Man. Yeah,
cause I think tigers are in Asia and
you know in Africa is where lions are,
right? Siberian tigers through. They're
all over. Yeah. Siberia is though.
Isn't that Kinda like Asia Ish is Europe.
What is it? Where Europe and Asia.
Russia, my geography slash.
Afghanistan. What is this?
Where you fuck up? That's all I know.
When we were kids, when you fuck up,
they sent you to Siberia.
Siberia is the worst place you gets.
Get all cold notes. It.
No clothes or anything.
You done fucked up son. You got to
go to site. Ever wrap my head around.
How do people not just die outside?
Remember when rocky was training in
Siberia to prove how bad ass he was.
He was lifting weird. That's how he's
trained lifting. We're tire up though.
He was running out in the snow and he
wasn't doing any boxing and all we had for
motivation or was a picture of Drago.
He was going to completely olds glue
throwing logs and the snow and running
uphill in the snow.
It's hard. It ended up,
the crowd starts chanting his named
switching over from the home tab.
Now we want a brilliant film.
Awesome.
This awesome this and its purest American
rechargeable killed Apollo creed. Okay.
A perfect example.
That
movie is retarded. Yeah. Okay. Okay.
I like the knitting of the word. Yeah,
that's what it is, man. You know, look,
we shouldn't be mean to people for sure,
but you shouldn't make words off use
when they have a bunch of different uses.
I think a bunch of
different matters really,
but it's definitely come from making
fun of the idea of being retarded,
but honestly it's worse. Yeah.
I don't want to be retarded.
I wouldn't mind being two
inches shorter or taller,
but I definitely don't want to be
retarded. It's worse for sure. Yeah.
You make a comparison of that
to say that's a bad thing. Yeah.
What you shouldn't do is like make fun
of them. The same things about them,
but to use the word, but they all laugh
with them and stuff. That's different.
I guess if you were standing next to
someone, here's the argument though.
I guess if you're standing next to someone
and they had [inaudible] syndrome kid
and it wouldn't be on the phone going,
dude, you're being such a retard.
You wouldn't say that because you would
feel bad that that people could hear
that. So my argument just
fucking shit the bed. Yeah.
My argument is it's totally feel bad
about it. Now that you've read it.
You're right.
You shouldn't say it,
but that's stupid because you should
definitely make sure there's no, um,
to say to retard takes away the idea
that we ever call them retarded.
That's work.
You know,
Thompson chorus had real problems with
that bit that he does about midgets.
Oh yeah. Real problems. Like people
are mad or like don't say it. Yeah.
People don't want him to
say they don't want them.
They certainly don't want to making
fun of midgets and it's a funny bit but
supposed to fuck her funny.
But it's like I get it doing it in
Kara Haughey midgets but it's like yeah
that's the bit and you know,
people have come to these shows and then
like cried and yelled at the manager.
Really have a son that you know has
just leave
with ridiculous as that family
guy gets away with it every week,
every week they got everything.
I got in some trouble.
You think I never hear about family guy
getting in trouble and they pretty much
do. They have that it's
harder character on it.
They got an a little bit trouble trouble
cause they'll never remember.
It's Tracy Morgan the most in trouble
that you can ever remember right now.
A celebrity or celebrity or comment.
Mel Gibson was one murder obviously Oj
assumption. Uh, Charlie Sheen. Yeah.
It's like those bigger ones than that.
But like little things like go, I'm sorry,
I just hit the guy in trouble for what
he said. Oh, that guy, the other guy,
a faggot and wouldn't back down off.
It really? Is that what happened?
How he did it? That kind of it.
Tim Hardaway, who's Tim Hardaway,
the basketball player. I went
to Utep. You tips to step.
He was really good and he played for
the heat I think, and a bunch of it.
And they were interviewing him.
This is the late eighties, I think,
maybe nine days. Um, but anyway,
and they were like, you know,
what do you think about that
might be gay NBA players.
And that was like a big
thing, right? And it goes, oh,
I don't want to play with them. I
don't like, because I don't like them.
I don't want gays around me. I want him
in the locker room. And they're like, uh,
the guy who was interviewing was
giving him a chance, like, okay,
you don't want to get misquoted
here. So try not to, I mean,
you'd obviously don't mean, you
know, like it as it goes. Oh No,
I don't like homosexuals.
Whoa.
It was like really bad and he
never did another endorsement ever.
It was like he was going after that. I
shouldn't say ever, but like he was just
now you can't do that alone.
Yup.
Funny people got in trouble for it. Yeah.
Things have changed. People are, well,
I say that's, it's gotta be a good thing
even if I don't believe in some of it.
I think that, uh, you know, here's
where I like idea behind it is good.
I like about the gay community because
whenever somebody says that what they do
is they take, give a donation
and be a spokesman. No,
they don't hold this shit against you. Or
they're like, it's okay, you fucked up,
but one you won't fuck up anymore
public and you're going to help.
You're going to use your celebrity to
help kids feel normalized. Well, you know,
I mean, look, that's always a good,
they'll do it. That's always a good thing.
But you know, when we get back
to that Tracy Morgan thing,
it seems like people are,
everyone's getting mad at Tracy Morgan
now because they can get away with it
because he'll apologize. Yeah, fuck, it's
so bad. I can't, I'm terrible about this.
I mean I really hate it. Brian Holtzman
say shit a thousand times worse.
The Tracy Morgan, but nobody knows
Brian holds cause nobody knows him.
I remember this one time,
this guy, and it's context,
there's one guy in the audience,
I was doing something about using the
n word as like Jews were the original
niggers.
I said whatever,
but I wanted to use it as is and the guy
does a jovial black guy in the audience
like fun and big and goes, no, no it's
Nigga you got to say Nigga with an a.
And I was like, okay, so no matter what,
then it's okay. And he goes, yeah, yeah,
totally cool. And I started
saying, so you degenerate,
Niggas are taking all of our money
from the government. You Niggas,
I don't want to Nick God dating my
daughter. And he was dying laughing.
We were all okay, but if you put that
on paper and take it out of context,
it's towns and seems so much worse.
Yeah.
There's a button pushing thing that you
do on stage where you say this shed that
somebody thinks but would never say and
you know saying cause you believe in it
because St cloud is a ridiculous thing
to say because it's like Louis Ck has a
bit, I think about hitting his kid, you
know, a punch you in the fucking face.
Like I believe that's a line. Somebody
what did that in a message board recently?
You know, did I get to see somebody going,
you shouldn't advocate child beating.
They were comparing the satire of him
saying that to what Tracy Morgan said,
that it's obvious that somebody he's not,
he doesn't really mean that he's saying
it because it's a ridiculous thing to
say and that's fun to do. You can't
hold a comic hostage, you know,
or hold them accountable for the meaning
of something that's said in a standup
comic way as if it was their actual
true thought. Because if you do that,
you're restricting that kind of outrageous
comedy that I think is really funny.
But the only way you can create that
training a bald eagle to land on his head,
his head, he only way you can
do that type of comedy though,
is to have the freedom to say really
offensive shit and know that people are
gonna know it's satire.
There other people are gonna
know that you're fucking
around. Yeah. You know? Yeah.
So if you don't allow a guy like
Tracy Morgan to say fucked up shit,
you're going to kill a whole
genre of awesome comedy.
You know the Jim Norton Genre of comedy,
like his, some of his shit. I mean, dude,
he's, it's really offensive
to a lot of people I'm sure,
but fucking hilarious.
I like to say this.
If Sam Kinison was coming up in la now
and comic, he wouldn't get staged. Right,
man, you're white. You're right.
Nobody put that guy on too.
How about his bit about aids? Yeah. He
goes, cause some fags fucked a monkey.
No, I got to wear a condom. But honestly
that's what people thought of it.
Then it was the only gay disease.
Yeah. I would never, I would never see,
I've never,
I stopped using the word Faggot,
but I would never use it for a gay person.
I use it to describe the
fact that I don't use it.
I need to bring up,
I just like to hear the crystals,
how it cracks off of your tongue,
but like a hack. Here's the problem.
Your own roles. Here's a pop.
We've been saying this for a six
and seven, but I don't, it's hard.
I don't just take it for so long.
Well,
unless like Louis Ck says that give a
fuck. They did anyway. Kind of really,
that's another brilliant Louis C K bit
about if they're being faggots are people
from Phoenix Venetians. Cause like
you're being a faggot. It was uh,
a bit about the correct use of
the word. You know, look man,
we all know what the fuck it is. It's
context. Context is what matters little.
We've, we've created these
a hot button words man,
and they're undeniable power to them.
Yeah. Undeniable Improv. It have power.
There's hypercharged you
know, and I forget all the
time. I forget all the time.
I'll say something and I'll see someone
get shocked and I'm okay, I guess.
I guess you don't think the way?
I think all the time somebody
drops an f bomb or says, yeah,
I guess an f bomb or whatever.
Then it's a, you see a crowd.
People turn around and get quiet.
Fuck yeah.
If two gay guys adopt a kid and
a little babies that a fig lit,
oh dare you. How dare you?
What is a word for this?
You don't say fag. It would be fabulous.
It would be family. It would be fashion.
Rogatory term for it is not nearly as
offensive camp. It's a bat preposterous.
What? Black Baby? A black
gay baby. Yeah. Dare you.
How dare you Brian. This is not
funny. I'm fucking gonna lose my Gig.
We hard obviously can fuck it all up.
Fucking Goddamn Prague. But that's
the problem. The money man does it.
Yeah, exactly. Here we are.
Three people, three friends,
three great friends sitting
around shooting the shit.
How many a conversation,
obviously with no malice towards anyone.
A lot of the shit that we've said today,
especially if you take it out of context
like that holds the thing that you did
about Nigga though do it.
If someone took that out of context,
I'm pretty terrible and I
wouldn't want look terrible.
They will turn and then we would have
who would have to go back and get the raw
video and edit, if you will. The
youtube thing. And here's the context.
I think I was quoted to that. They're all
saying like nuts, not the exact quote,
the quote they put out there
as if I had a gay baby,
I would take out a knife
and stabbed to death. Right.
But he said something like way
different than that. Really? Yeah.
I kind of wish I knew what it was. That
context of it though, was that the, the,
the, that's what the guy wrote
when he left the show and got mad,
wrote off Facebook and started
cutting everything up in arms.
Guys been popped without a video.
Cause it doesn't seem like there's
a video of it. There's not. Yeah.
That's kind of weird. I've never seen
anybody, one person did not film that.
Mel Gibson. Yeah, that's all cops.
But they have leased officers stating
what he said. It sounds more real.
That's true. Yeah, it must. Well everybody
thought it was a possibly bullshit though.
It's like maybe these officers
were Dick heads. Right. You know,
maybe they just being an asshole and
they don't like him for whatever reason.
So they put it, but then when he went on
that crazy, but it did it another time.
That crazy rant that he did on that
chick's answer machines is answered all
questions real. And that was like, no
one's ever going to hear this shit. Ooh.
That was, that was intense,
man. That was some intense shit.
It's like you see that and you
realize you want to become a star.
So girls like all galleys girls and
they'll stop driving me crazy and it never
gets any better.
It's because what are you
looking to change things?
Well, it's what you get. It's,
it's, yeah, it's what, what
are you putting out there?
That's exactly what you're going
to give back. You know, if,
and especially with him,
I think Mel Gibson has got something
wrong with his brain. That's what I think,
you know, I think there's,
there's a, there's a pathology
there. There's an issue,
there's an imbalance.
It doesn't seem to be just as simple
as he believes wacky shit. You know,
like his dad didn't, doesn't believe in
the Holocaust. It's not as simple as that.
There's a programming situation.
Yeah, there's a chemical situation.
There's something wrong. He's
a crazy person, you know,
which is why that fucking beaver movie
was so bizarre because it was about,
I mean,
what a crazy fucking idea for a movie.
And then imagine talking people into
making this movie and then this mother
fucker goes crazy right before the movie
gets released. Sort of perfect for it.
Not really though, because nobody
wanted it. They didn't like him anymore.
People are done with Mel Gibson. That's
second, second strike. They're like,
it's what just mistake man know
the eyes are on you. Again, when,
when people talk about
like knowing somebody,
and one of the beautiful things about
this podcast is that this is a kind of a
format,
and you and I were talking about this
for we're playing pool where you really
completely get to know somebody. You know,
it wasn't up talk. You're talking two,
three hours a day, you know several
times it, that is who you are,
you know that that is who you are.
But for most people they're shooting,
they're shielded from anybody ever seen
who they really are. And because of that,
we're like,
we were talking about celebrities getting
crazy and going nuts because they have
all this power. It's almost like that's
like the norm. It's like then they need,
they never show you who they really are.
So every calculated interview is carving
out this completely artificial idea of
who this person is. And he's been
pulling this off. It's called life.
So he probably doesn't even
fucking know who he is anymore.
So when he gets alone and he's wishing
this fucking Russian bitch was over there
blowing him. So He's like, what?
You get over here and blow or your job.
That's the real Mel Gibson. That's
the, that's the heart of the beast.
And that's why people are
like, Dude, you can't act.
You need to get your shit together.
And people say,
well you shouldn't have to fire
somebody just because he does it.
He's not getting fired. People just
don't watch her go to his movies anymore.
Used to watch it because he
was cool. Yeah. He's not a
viable commodity. And Yeah,
when he was mad max, he was the
shit when he was brave heart dude.
Could you, do you remember how
powerful that fucking movies
and there was another movie that he
directed, right? Mel Gibson in Braveheart,
the shit. Wow. Mel
Gibson was the shit son.
It just cause someone's crazy doesn't
mean they can't be good at an art form,
bro.
I got out of that Braveheart movie.
I wanted to grab a sword and join the
battle. That movie was incredible.
It was incredible.
And it ushered in an era of movies where
giant groups of dudes will run at other
giant dudes who agree to meet on a field.
We did the same movie and called
it the Patriot and it was like they
just
did it.
A different time period is a shit.
He did Redo the same shit. Yeah.
It was like a mannequin. A mannequin
too. It was like the same mood
was mannequin the mannequin to both
have the same woman? No different woman.
Only thing the same Hollywood. That black
guy that was like the Gay Black Guy,
I think it was a comic. The Gay Black
Guy was in the corner that made it.
He made it again,
but it was just a different city
mannequin coming to life again and a guy
falling in love in a window dressing.
It was like, what is that other stupid?
His premise of all time,
oh,
some loser is in a store for some reason
after dark and the mannequin comes
alive and he does.
He,
he doesn't even bone her
movie saw what happened there.
Did they really kiss him?
He's just got a kiss and it wasn't like,
it was like just something that
happens in a movie man. Just kissing,
just kissing happens in movies.
Everybody's happy.
The dude doesn't date
rape you to have his bit,
but I could never make it work where
it's like where it's like in the movies,
whatever reality cause you go for that
first kiss and beautiful and magical and
you're like right,
you lean in and I'm dunes out,
you find the go and you
just kiss for awhile.
Right after that almost every guy it'd
be like you got to go back to my place.
But they never do that and
that was the kiss the enough.
You want to see how far you could get it.
Some dude's though are careful.
I know dudes who like,
especially as they get older and they've
been in a few loony toon relationships,
Dell,
Dell should go slow with a check to try
to figure out what the fuck's going on
behind that icing.
You know?
Cause there's some people that can put
on an awesome show of being a really
special person for a few weeks. Even,
you know when you're dating him,
like this is the greatest person ever.
But then as they get tired of playing
their acts or eventually they order what
they order at restaurants. If you dive
right in and start banging all the time,
then the problem is those bitches
are usually a really good in bed.
The crazier they are.
And I've always said that my
friend Tony Zara says this best,
he said psychotic and erotic
are next door neighbors.
The more psychotic that CIC is,
the more erotic they are in bed.
And this motherfucker would purposely
date crazy girls just because he would get
that rush out of banging
these like incredibly crazy
broads. I just want to bone.
It's like that's gotta be first
and then I can get to know you.
We can have some fun.
Yeah,
but what I'm saying is you gotta be
careful who you connect with because once
you start fucking a little bit,
you need each other all the time.
No Man,
you need to know.
You need to be careful who you connect
yourself with in your life. Man,
it's one of the most important things.
I agree. Dude's dive into relationships,
and I have guilty as charged
cause girls are hot. Oh, you see,
he doesn't do relationships
are see what he wants. He,
but he thinks that that's normal.
That's what's hilarious most.
Most people get into relationships,
but he's like,
oh no time for the good way for
her to follow her. If a weapon,
I used to be married showed up,
I've been there.
You can't tell me how to live my life.
Go Away, please. God just seems so bad.
Not Man, it's great when it's great,
but you have to have the right person.
That's the key. You have
to really, he's got it.
I just don't have any desire by now,
but I got to tell you,
if I didn't have children,
it wouldn't be nearly as appealing.
And one of the most appealing things
about it is the little babies and this
little connection that you make with
this woman and you have this new life
together. It's a completely different
trip. But if there's no wimp,
if there's no babies in charge,
then the human animal goes into this
mode of fucking all kinds of different
things, which is where you're
at right now. And I just,
I just kind of like my alone time,
but a lot. Well, yeah, you're,
you're also an artist, you
know, and you need weird time.
You can't be on it like a rigid schedule.
You need time to sit down and
reflect about things like I,
I think there's an equal part discipline
involved in creating things, but,
and then life experience.
I think you have to have both to be able
to sit down and write things out and
you have to, you have to have a work
ethic. I think that's very important.
But you also have to have fun, you know?
I think that that's a part of your job.
Yeah.
I like to have experiences with women.
I like to enjoy them and really get to
know them and like them a lot and fuck.
And it might be different
than pedestrian lights off,
off to any of those experiences.
Nothing wrong with that dude. Yeah.
Until she starts shitting out kids.
Then little Ari Juniors run around
the house and you're like, oh my God,
I don't want to fuck this kid up.
I don't want this kid to be like me.
That's where I get caught up. I don't
want my kid to be a comic. Is there,
there's an Alpine is sure.
Of course there are black or on some
weird white hair and red resize white
iPhone or they would look like some like,
like snow Ninja robot in a video game.
Yeah. I really have one red eyes today.
Albinos. Some do they have
red eyes? It sounds like,
like something in mortal combat.
You know you're playing some Albino
Asians that live in like northern area of
China. They could ever get away with
making an albino care. Yeah. They could.
Might not represent them.
You know, they found,
they found weed on some Chinese dude
from like some insane amount of thousands
of years ago. I thought an Egyptian tomb.
Was it a Chinese to him? Maybe that too.
I know they found weed
in Egyptian tombs too,
but they found a Chinese guy with weed
and his stash. He had like a little bag,
really thousands of year old weed,
little Ziploc made everybody lawyers.
That's the way it smells.
Gross people that are trying to exume
William Shakespeare because they want to
test his body for cannabis because
they want to test is to luck with that.
I'm going to do, how important
is it to you to prove a point?
You fuck does this scientists
live in a Volkswagen, if you will?
That was a very funny line.
That was steel opening Anthony's bit.
That was the line of the day.
It's so true because when you
think teeth are long gone,
right?
I mean it's not going to happen.
Say I can see the DNA being
able to test that shit,
but that they're never going to French
medical sciences. Crazy. I got a purse.
I just got French. You
should watch it. It's fun.
It's why x files.
William Shakespeare,
1564 God damn son,
1585 and 1592 we began a successful
career in London as an actor,
writer and 15 hundreds see,
that's some shit that you get when you
go to England that you just can't even
fathom. Here in America.
You can get it a little bit.
If you go to Boston and go on
like one of those little tours,
it takes you to these houses from
like the 16 hundreds like there's a,
there's a bunch of really old buildings
that are still around and especially
tombstones.
There's a bunch of fucking really old
tombstones in Boston that I like from the
17 hundreds and everything. It's
a really, it's a trip to look at,
but this is 15 hundreds man and this guy
was out there writing things and then
people would perform what he wrote
in front of a group of people.
There's no microphones,
man.
Here it is. Here it is. He just talking
and they believe apparently that he
was a stoner. I have of course he was.
I think everybody back then was they
tested his pipe apparently as this
what I've read on the Internet,
that they apparently tested Shakespeare's
pipe and found residue of the
marijuana. And why do they want
to test to see if he was doing,
just to see if he was doing it because,
well,
because of what we all know that
it enhances creativity. You know,
Carl Sagan wrote a brilliant piece on
marijuana and why he uses marijuana and
just look up if you want
to find it, just, yeah,
just look up for the people listening
at home. Carl Sagan, marijuana.
And it was a sort of a lifelong ode
to marijuana and that he was a daily
cannabis smoker.
Yeah.
And that he said that what he had
learned from marijuana, that there was,
there was some real lessons that
he brought back from that state of
consciousness that he could
apply to, uh, to other, uh,
aspects of his life that he could actually
learn things that he believed weren't
learnable. Like, well, we're,
we're an available to him.
This thought was not available to him
without cannabis. This is his, his belief.
And this is, you know, Carl
Sagan is a great mind, a
fascinating person. You know,
a guy who turns so many people
onto cosmology and his, you know,
his words were so,
you know,
there's so much of what he said
was so appealing that they've,
they've taken a lot of it and put it on
videos where they show like space and
then he'll be like going on some rant
about the size of the cosmos or some
incredible yeah. And you know, and there'd
be so hypnotic. So guys like that are,
you know,
and then people will argue with that.
He wasn't the most
brilliant scientist ever.
And what did he actually
accomplished is science.
There was any scientist is smarter
than you. Yeah. For most people. Yeah.
And on top of that,
like you can't deny his contribution by
getting people excited about astronomy.
You know, people know, I know his name.
How many scientist named do I know? Yeah.
Jesus Christ. You know, Steven Lock
door. Yeah. I could have made
ted butter. Yeah. There's,
there's not that many men.
This is a small amount.
So he says he couldn't have done
certain things without his exact quote.
I would bring it buttoned.
Right.
Your version of that is a flying
squirrel posted people. No Way.
I can come up with that without weed.
It's true. I am a, I believe that there's,
there's reasons why all this stuff
is around. That's what I believe.
I believe there's reasons why there's,
you know,
every different substance
that exists on the planet.
There's reasons why there's
coffee. Beans, I believe does to,
everything has to be good for you.
There's reasons. No, it's just,
there's things that are terrible for you.
You know, strict nine. There's, there's,
there's plants that are, that'll
kill you. You eat those plants,
you'll fucking die.
So what are the reasons for the open
ecosystem is probably not connected to me,
man. You know? But everything
else that is connected to you,
you should be aware of.
And when, when someone,
like Carl Sagan tells you that cannabis
connects you to the universe and it
makes you look at things in a different
light and it makes you, you know,
a more sensitive person, it makes
you more creative. And it, you know,
it's helped him,
I think a million different thoughts.
I think it's easy for people to just blow
off of those people. So like whatever,
but then it's like, okay, but
think what if a guy was right?
What did he possibly be a scientist
that everyone's heard of? Well, that's,
see these right people will get upset
at me if I talk about Ponte too much and
like to,
you're always talking about pot like,
and you need to lay off the pot talk.
Look,
I'm only telling you this because
it's of benefit. It helps.
And it's helped me. And I think that if
you just approach it with discipline,
it can be spectacular for your life.
And I think that what it can do
is that it can enhance your life.
And I really truly believe that,
man,
nothing.
Oh,
I was just gonna say it. Don't you
love it how people tell you what? No,
you should not talk about this. You should
not talk about that. I'm like, dude,
listen to us.
Who are you to judge what we talk about?
If you want to listen in to what
we're talking about, listen then,
but don't think that you have the
control of what they have access.
But it's like if you had a sitcom or
you're like more Newman or less Newman.
Yeah. But it's like they're
not gonna listen to you,
but I can just send you
liking something more or less.
I can understand you're voicing your
opinion and just don't be a Douche bag.
It's all that simple. You
don't have to here. Yeah.
How about Justin Moore, Joey
Diaz and people, you know,
there's a lot of people to
give Brian a hard a hard
time. You get, you get a lot of shit on
that message board dude course. And uh,
you know, people don't
appreciate, you know,
you and I have a very unusual relationship
and I think sometimes people don't
appreciate that.
I think there's a,
there's a reason for everybody
and there's, there's a,
a method to having fun and to,
to, to good times. There's a,
there's a, there's a method to
like keep that ship on track.
And one of the methods with our friends
is that we're all, we're kind of silly,
we're all kind of silly and I go off
and get dark sometimes and I go off on
weird tangents and I go,
you know,
I'll go on these strange
rants and apocalyptic ideas
that I take to the fucking
the ant most degree.
Yeah.
And then Brian will bring up some ass
spray that he got that he makes people
stick their finger in and it all sort
of balances out different styles.
It's like, no, I think
everything, you know?
Yeah. So I like Brian, don't be
hating. Stop being so negative online.
There's certain things you're not going
to like about every fucking show. I,
I can't, you know, look, I'm a
huge fan of the Howard stern show,
but everything on that, I'll
change the channel. It does study.
It's just the way it goes. It's taught
me if I said this on the podcast before,
but there's a study that
they did that showed how a,
when you're negative online or whatever
you do online and leads over to your
regular life. Yeah. So you feel like
I can get it. They go but I want,
nobody even knows me here.
But that kind of behavior,
that's actual behavior that you're doing,
you being mean to someone
and so when you're normally,
you just get a little meaner when
you actually see them face to face,
like you're affecting it.
So if it gets super positive online
that'll affect you at the other way.
It's up to you.
You clearly identify yourself with the
way you behave and how your behavior
affects people.
Even if you only,
it's implied like you know
that if you said some chick,
I hope you get watched in your current
and your fucking pussy falls out your
asshole. You sitting there saying, send
her a message on Twitter to [inaudible].
You know,
say it like that.
Your rip rob nine six two you can
say the most fucked up shit hospital,
but don't think that you're
getting away with that for free.
Somewhere in the back of your mind you're
going to know that you're a piece of
shit.
You're going to,
you're going to define yourself by your
own actions and you're going to also
think, how would I judge me
if I wasn't me? You know?
Got Great. You're a jerk. Oh,
congratulations. It's not hard to
do that. Anyone can just be a jerk.
Just terrible. Easy. It's very
easy. It's really being an asshole.
And we evolved all done it.
I have done it. I'm not,
I was clearly an asshole
for a good chunk of my life.
We've all been there. We were, we
were caught up in our own bullshit.
And sometimes we'll take it out on other
people, but it doesn't mean you're,
you're unfixable. So what we're saying
is not that people are unfixable.
I don't even mind the people in line are
real mean that they would make a joke
about it because that's gotta be really
funny. It's got to be really funny.
And it couldn't be,
it shouldn't be something where you just,
you feel like someone's just trying
to take somebody down for no reason.
Like you should have
something funny to say stupid.
And if you don't have something funny to
say, stop being such a cunt, you know,
like what, what is your issue?
You're, you're creepy man. You're,
you're angry all the time. There's
so many God damn angry people online.
I view it as a way like
trying to get attention.
It's just like trying to get life in some
way and you see a gazelle when it gets
killed by like a lion and it's being
held onto or mountain lion or anything,
you know?
And it'll just like sort of stopped and
the kicks a few more times real quick,
like just a last ditch effort for those
people are doing that for attention.
So like here's main, yeah,
show me attention. But it
just, if it doesn't work,
they'll try something else.
It's definitely a lot of that man.
There's a lot of people
being shit for no reason.
But my experience online is obviously
very different than most people's because
I always post as myself.
I never,
I never go on a forum with
some sort of a fake name,
but I have thought about doing it
before just to see like how would I be
accepted in this community? Even
in my own website. I thought like,
what would I be like if I
was skippy 12 six you know,
instead of a Rogan cause then everything,
I'm Joe Rogan and the underground.
I post as Joe Rogan. I'm the,
the pool side I go to is Joe Roth know
where you're getting a completely honest
version of of people.
Everybody's nice to me.
I've ever wanted your
thoughts on the or somewhere.
It's some comedy club and
someone was like, oh, I heard
that an astral yuck. Yeah,
they were an asshole to me and someone
else like, yeah, and you're like,
well they'd never been anything
but nice to me. He's like, yeah,
you're a sellout guy.
It's a nice deal. I wish it were
simulations and things like,
like like life experiences. Like what
if you could just simulate like, hey,
let's make molestation popular and legal.
Then see how many youtube
comments I was thinking of.
Let's simulate being a jet fighter pilot
and you're flying through the mountain
range.
That's what I would like.
I wouldn't want to simulate incest
to fucking Weirdo or comment.
Anger goes up by like,
it's gross thousand percent don't bring
that shit up when they have those videos.
But what I'm saying,
what I'm saying is that that it's almost
like you have to remember half these
fucking angry people are just young
kids to it and that it, it, it's like,
like I get so upset with people on Twitter
and message boards and stuff and then
I got a lot of, oh yeah, this
kid's probably like 12 years old.
He probably fucking got molested by an
uncle and he's fucking being angry to
everybody, you know, maybe or you
know, like it just be an asshole.
There's mom wasn't very strong.
Let them get away with a lot when he was
young and I always become a big client
and he's older. In my head
it's a molester kid. All right.
Kids molested. He gets Dick on
other, when somebody's mean to me,
if it wasn't molested a child.
All right, Brian. By the
way, that Tracy Morgan thing,
we say people will really show
themselves like Mel Gibson,
like on tape or whatever,
right?
That's why sports casters and newscasters
love Twitter because they're getting
an actual feed into the real them so
that like we're, we're countering.
This is a real new source,
right? You know? Well, it
isn't real news source to them.
So our message boards now,
the stories are written about,
people say things like message boards,
do it.
If you were of celebrity and what you
had just said would really get you in
trouble, let's say if you were celebrity,
somebody could quote you saying,
yeah,
this Molesey they're getting disheartened
and how you're laughing about kids
getting fucked.
I would have photo ops with black babies,
me kissing black babies,
please stop fucking digging
yourself in trouble.
You heard about that? It was a, he was a
running back for the giants for awhile.
Retired kind of early to be a
sportscaster for a couple of years.
Now he's going back to a football.
So He's in training.
So before he made this announcement,
it was like big news to his
agent was hiding him, was like,
you can stay at my place. It was like
some nice, polite, whatever. He goes,
I got a guiding him. Why?
Because he didn't want anybody,
the media talking to them at all.
It was like he needed to be away from
them for like two weeks. So he's like,
I got a guest bedroom upstairs,
you can take that.
So he was stuck in an attic and he
goes, Anne, a Jew was keeping him there.
And he goes, yeah, I kind of
understand what and frank was doing.
I've got to be stuck up there all the
time and the Uja or whatever it was.
Who'd nodded? Jewish defense league. Maybe
they jumped all over them. Just make it,
yeah, it's like it's making light. It
like it's not making light.
It's using her as an example.
What's a better example that I'm
stuck in an attic for two weeks.
I'm a hostage in an attic.
Like,
show me a better example of
that would stand up a line.
And you know what if you said it,
if you were there you could
say it in a heartbeat.
They can get away with it cause it gives
you a character or nothing cause right.
Cause I'm a Jew and no want to
said anything. They can't say shit.
They couldn't say shit. You, you could
totally get away with that. You can.
You got like at least
three giu references.
I can go pretty deep before anybody gets
upset. No, come on man enough you can go.
You can get a cheap one in there.
You can get,
you can get a bunch of them in there.
I'll pick on Jews because you are Jewish.
That's a crazy thing.
We've always allowed people a nice green
light to make fun of their own kind.
You know, I could say the most
mean shit about Italians. You know,
housewives. I want to talk about
real housewives of New Jersey.
I talk about them being savages,
that they are just more
ronic growing thinking apes,
they're savage of the
women are based women.
Could you imagine if I said
that about black people?
what I said about my own people?
If I just decided to say that about
black people, Holy Shit. I would be,
I would be straight Tracy Morgan and
right now in front of a bunch of black
people saying, I'm so sorry. I did not
mean that. I was only joking around.
I don't think that you're savages,
but my people,
I can say you're a fucking savages.
You dirty,
greasy fucking stone cobbler workers,
peasant monkey people.
They're all the same short.
Why savages? I don't know. I do. I
get a free pass. I'm Italian. I can,
I can tell you for sure.
I know exact grew up with them.
My grandmother screamed at my fucking
grandfather every day he was alive.
Dow there fucking savages growed
eggplants and monsters eaten beef,
steak, tomatoes and screaming
at each other monsters.
If you live there, you'd be a monster
too. He'd be caught right up in that.
Co Does Zeitgeists of that.
That area is.
There's a reason why that Jersey shore
is a fucking popular show because their
behavior is so extremely horrible. Whoa.
You're like, what the fuck is going on?
How common is this? And
you want to know, oh,
there's a whole goddamn enterprise
of them. There's, there's a,
there's a whole Goddamn crew of people
that live like that, plus worse.
Those are the intellectuals of the Jersey
shore movement. You know those people,
they can handle themselves on television.
They can go on dancing with the star talk,
literally don't answer interviews and
Shit. That fucking situation guy, he said,
God damn genius when it
comes to the Jersey shore,
there's some animals live in,
in that state. Dude, that's a, that's
a savage state of monkey people.
All my relatives, man, they're
savages. I see them. I'm like,
you people would just here feeding
off of each other. It get out.
Get out now before you kill yourselves.
So over the top,
I'm allowed to say that. Yeah, I
would say that because it's me.
It's my own relatives called Janet
Jackson Nipple. It's fault two.
That's when it started, right?
Well, it's already started with Pc.
It started turning a rabbit relative
point. I have a relative that sent me a
photo of some of my cousins
that I've never met before,
and it's all gold chains, slicked back
hair, and everyone's neck is this wide.
And everyone's sitting there like this
and they all have gold chains and they're
all like,
wear their Sunday best suit.
And it's one of those weird
backgrounds where they get,
tell them what they went to the mall and
went to this little photograph studios
where it's like the blue and
white speckled background.
They're savages hot sandwiches
with their shirts, their gold.
What is that type of the flat la like,
I want to say a leaf,
some sort of a leaf parsley.
You know,
I think
the type of, um, uh, chain
type of gold chain there,
where that flat, here's the thing,
describing them, hating them. Like,
yes, I would agree with all my, God would
say that those are my God, their melody.
Remember when we meet,
we always talk about this when me and
you were at the sky bar with Joe and uh,
we're with Brett arthritis in this town.
He just comes out of them and
we're been while you drink good.
I'm doing price for some reason you
got a lot better. He got better.
He just doesn't sound like that anymore.
But this was a long time ago.
He Italians it up really amazing. Super
Italian. Now he'll unbuttoned a short,
a couple more buttons. I love Brent ours.
We've got to bring him on the podcast.
I've never had him on here.
No,
he hasn't been on her grandparents is
awesome too because he'll go off on some
fucking crazy,
you know when Thomas Jefferson,
when he originally wrote this and
he'll tell you some shit. You're like,
what the fuck are you holding me
hostage with this history lesson son,
the steroid a Superbowl party wants.
Because if for some reason he got on it
that Irish people in this country had it
worse than blacks and we're like, oh
my God, whatever you read this report,
we're like,
we didn't stop talking about it.
And everyone was gone within 10 minutes.
You refuse to give at all,
and it was like, just shut the fuck.
No one cares. He and I got into it
once about the Bible, some
crazy rants about the Bible,
and he was like, you know,
it's been proven.
The factual fact that Jesus did
exist has been proven by scholars.
Fuck, are you talking about he's
fully aware of it now, by the way,
that everyone says like cotton,
an Ernst black hole.
He's just talking at you, but like
this walked away from him. I'm like,
I'm not going to argue with you about
this. You, you believe in, what?
Did you even research the history
of the fucking Bible he called?
He knows how many other versions
of those same stories exist.
All if you've ever heard of are
like, okay, I get, I don't know.
You're just telling about this
information right now. Hey,
I saw a documentary and I must ask
you about this because I know that you
studied the Torah.
I saw documentary and I've been quoting
this documentary ever since I saw it
where they were talking about ciphering
the Dead Sea Scrolls and the real issue
is that they know so little deciphering,
not dead sea scrolls rather than the
old whatever the oldest ancient Hebrew
version of the Bible is that the,
the real issue was that they,
they didn't know all of the words that
they can only lost some of them that he,
they were saying in this documentary that
it was three quarters of the words had
been, but 25% are still up to debate.
Does that, is that accurate? Well,
here's what the debate is.
It's like when you get a word in the
English language and you look at all the
definitions and you see way
back down, it's like fag, right.
And met some sticks put
together. Right. Okay.
That is one of the usages of the word.
So if you really do the English language,
we will be aware of that
usage of the word fag.
And also the fact that if I get that
also cigarettes like you should know,
but I think a faggot is a bundle of sticks
and that's why they would call a, um,
uh,
like they would call a man who was weak.
They would call him a faggot because he
was like a woman because he was like, oh,
is that a woman was like a bird.
Yeah. It was like a bundle of sticks.
Like it was a burden that you would carry,
you would carry this
bundle of sticks around.
And that's how it started with
calling gay guys. Yes. That's,
that's the original word.
It's not that you would burn them,
it's that they would be like,
like hard to have around.
They're very flammable
and they're flamers.
And then you get words like love
or enthralled or, or, or lust.
They're very disabled. We're absolutely
correctly, cause I don't know,
I feel like I'm missing something in
my translation of it, but the words,
they know, they're only sort
of aware of their meetings.
They're not aware fully of their meetings.
There was a whole thing
about the entomology of it.
It was correcting people that were saying
that it was because a bundle of sticks
was easy to light on fire and
they were saying that's not true,
that that is not the uh,
the, the original. Uh,
that's like all the reasons why for 20
as a thing, that's like a part time.
That's what it's called. For the
CAHSEE unsubstantiated associations,
it's sometimes claim the modern slang
meaning a developed from the standard
meaning of Faggot as
to a bundle of sticks,
presumably with reference
to burning at the stake.
Like this was even on
Louis' show and I knew,
I had heard before I saw it on his show.
I was like,
I don't think that's true anymore.
I think they mean nothing to say
that people haven't burnt gay people.
Of course they have, of course, people
doing terrible things to gay people,
but that the,
just the actual entomology,
I believe that's the correct word of the
word, is not that it was, it was, it was,
it was a bundle of sticks and that
carrying a bundle of sticks was like
uncomfortable. You know what I'm just
realizing that's why now as you said,
like you wouldn't say the word retard
or about somebody who had a retard.
It's Stalin or doubts or whatever
because it would hurt them. Right. I,
I really got to get that word and
the f word out of my, my dialogue.
The faggot word. Yeah.
Because you don't want to,
you wouldn't say it if
there's a gay guy or as true,
if somebody is struggling with it and
they hear you say it, it's like, yeah,
you got to feel worse about yourself.
Yeah. But you know, it's better. I
can think of other words like that.
It's weird because we had, uh, this girl
on, on the desk squad podcasts and her,
she was talking about how your,
her younger sister is
a special needs and oh,
just start sounding like hermit for a
second. I get out of my throat anyways,
but she,
she caught her retarded and it was her
daughter or her sister and you know,
that the whole family kind of did and
it was kind of like accepted still.
They still talk color and like
the whatever. Yeah. But listen to,
it's kind of interesting.
Yeah. I would, I would say a,
I should probably only do it when I'm
calling the word for or actually saying
right over the word actually
means. Yeah. But only that,
I think everyone just needs to calm down.
Just don't obviously don't call
it [inaudible]. The point is,
what we talked about earlier is that
you don't want someone to feel bad.
People feel bad. Right. And it's like not
that should have to calm down. I should,
I should be able to,
I'm a writer with a better word.
Like we've been talking about the words
and teasing now today. I, you know,
we've been talking about the words, he
should still be allowed to talk. Oh,
the actual words. If you're
on the stage, you know,
calling people retards and stuff,
and they had the assured,
then you don't do that.
Here's, here's the argument against,
here's the argument against it.
The reason why it's closing in the
reason why people are closing in on these
offensive words is because everyone
can have an impact on a large group of
people. Now by putting something online,
Twitter and stuff like that, people,
Twitter, and even this podcast,
you know what we're, we're,
we're saying on the spot,
you have an impact on a lot more people
than you had before where it was just
you and your friends in a bar. And you
know, and someone says the n Word Ha,
and you'll laugh.
And that's the end of it.
But if you say that shit in a
tweet and then put that online,
there's a reason why everybody's closing
in on this shit is because we are
trying to stop people from lashing out
and causing negative energy and hurting
people. And even though you feel
like you're not doing anything wrong,
I'm not saying anything wrong,
that the energy behind that,
what you're doing ultimately
winds up being a negative force.
I was the lines of making people feel
like shit. So even though like this,
this rush to PC is a bad thing because
there's a lot of people that are just on
the bandwagon.
They're looking to point a finger at
somebody and the reason why they're upset
about this is because they have the
license to be upset about this and if it
wasn't this, there'll be something
else that pissed them off.
They're looking for something to be
mad at and so their take on it is not
reasonable or it's not, you know,
it's, it's, it's not charitable.
Their take on it is aggressive and they
want you to apologize. They want to win,
they want to get you.
It's like half of the fund for them
is getting you to feel like shit.
But some people will say like, well how
come the blood can use Edward? No camp?
It's like a contest man. There's no
winning or losing it. They shouldn't.
Maybe use it either, but you don't
want to make someone feel bad. Exactly.
Exactly what you do and
then fucking go for it.
I guess it's the reason why it's
all happening. It's all natural.
It's all natural and it's a byproduct
of our integration with each other,
which is unprecedented with social media
and Twitter and Facebook and you know,
all this shit.
Now.
The r integration with each other is
deeper than ever before and in response to
that,
people have gotten more sensitive.
I think if people wholeheartedly
like all the time,
use the word Judah mean bargain
like they use to a long time ago,
don't you be down? I think that would
probably make me at least start,
like if I heard it at a table next to me,
like I'd be like, uh, no. Okay, I'll come.
Okay.
It was weird.
I said that in front of a friend once
and he got really bummed out at me.
I forgot it was Jewish.
I didn't think it was a big deal.
I wouldn't get bummed out just
because I'm like, oh, Yep,
that's using that as a joke. It's a joke.
People would have thought it was funny,
but he did not think it
was funny. It was very funny because when
they use it was very sensitive rather.
Yeah. I said, um, I saw, I just tried to
Jew me down and then after I sat out like,
oh, like, I'm sorry I shouldn't say
that. He's like, you shouldn't say that.
Why do you say that you're upset that
you said it because I'm around. I'm like,
you're right, but you're right.
Also that, I shouldn't say it
so weird to say I'm, I'm the
same way because I, we didn't,
like I've talked about before we
hit didn't grow about or we didn't,
I didn't grow up with it like black
people, Asian people, Jewish people,
all that said we'd like,
we have one Indian person and he farted
all the time and they had to like pull
us aside and like know school was
all white mashed potato people. Yeah,
for the most part. But we weren't
racist like that one Indian guy.
We were just like kind of more like,
oh, he's different than all of us.
But it's weird like when
you say the Jewish thing,
like I didn't know what a Jew was for a
long time. And I used to always say like,
don't be a Jew or be Jewish,
but I didn't know you didn't even
know what it meant and what I meant.
I thought it was a term. How old were
you at 40 I'm coming like 1312 you know,
I used to use it as a term.
I didn't know what Jews were.
I was like some Jew hearing that and know
being a little idea that we're feeling
a weird, can you imagine
though, if they were on,
if some 12 year old kid heard next
at the table, so yeah, absolutely.
Might feel weird. Absolutely. Faggot.
Retard does to someone who
knows those people. Yup. Yeah,
it is. It is the same shit. And until
we can get rid of fags and retard,
so what we're saying is rotten them
off. Not My fault. This, listen,
these are just jokes. Ladies and
gentlemen. You do not feel this way.
I thought we were on.
No.
Ultimately,
I think we're,
we're both right about this because
what we're saying is that we know,
and what I said earlier,
that if someone was around me and I knew
that they had a child and the child,
I wouldn't say that word.
So really,
I probably just shouldn't say that word
because there just going to move people
around you that you don't know.
I should come up with a word that I use
in response or in replacement like idiot,
but the, you know, but then
people will rage up and
they'll say, no man, fuck that.
We're losing all our words,
man. Don't give up retard too,
but don't stop retard too. It's
like, yeah, let's stop it. It's okay
man. I thought I made up that word earlier
that I use. I don't want to use now.
I didn't know that, that you guys all,
it was a real word, but you shouldn't.
Cute man. No, no, no. I'm being
serious. I'm being serious.
How could you make up that word? You've
heard that word of her. Maybe I have.
Maybe I have,
but I would call my cats that I,
and I think it's just a funny sounding
word that's based off a bad word,
but I didn't know that
actually people use the shop.
Shut the fuck up, let it go, let
it go, let it go. Shut the fuck up.
They would have this note when you go
into a black going to chant is going to be
jail. Eventually he say
something bad about black people.
They're going to be able to
take that clip and then you go,
this motherfucker needs 30 days.
That really they're going to have you 30
days locked up for crimes against black
folks. What people did, it's
like, you know when you do
any sort of a sexual thing,
like if you get caught peeing outside
and it's like within a hundred yards,
you're on the APP. You could be a
sex offender on the APP forever.
So that's what's going to happen with you.
Trying to think of other
words you get and they put
you in a crimes against
black category in jail.
So just like someone who
goes to jail for sex crimes,
some shit thing by accident. My mom says
I'm about luck. When I was little, little,
I was like, look, schmuck. I was trying
to imitate like daffy duck. Right?
And she's like, don't
use that word. I'm like,
there's Glauco weird Jewish thing
that we're not allowed to talk about.
What is schmuck mean exactly,
but it's like,
it's an app that the other day talk
soccer. It's like it's just an insole.
It doesn't mean exactly what it means.
The new about schmuck is that.
That's something that Lenny
Bruce used to use all the time.
We used to turn the schmuck if the
Schmuck, it's like a, it's like a sort of,
it's not that harsh and Jewish homes.
I got in trouble, they bastard,
but really my mom wanted me and my mom
pulled me aside because I was you playing
Atari 2,600 I'm like, die, you
bastards. She goes, Whoa, what the,
that's a bad word. Where I fuck you
can't say that Brian. Wow. You know,
and fear factor. It used to be
able to say hell and I can't.
Then somewhere along the line hell became
a bad word while we were doing fear
factor because at the end of the day have,
after we're all done with the stunts,
I, Brian, congratulations.
Let's get the hell out of here and I
would leave it and people started writing
letters or you shouldn't bring up David
writing letters saying that I shouldn't
be talking about the imaginary place
where everybody burns and fire because we
don't want people thinking about how
while we're watching our nice TV show,
he's up there cussing
you. He, he said, hell,
I remember when I lived in Florida too.
They would say that that hell was a cost
cross hockey days. H E
double hockey sticks. Yeah.
Hell was a curse. How fucking dumb or
that's amazing that it was okay then.
It wasn't just like South Park where
they showed Mohamad and they shut it.
We can't show you episode,
but we'll show you an old episode
that we were allowed to show them on.
We'll just block them out. What
the fuck? It's like things,
but it's all the interconnectivity.
That's what it is.
Things are becoming only people are
becoming more and more sensitive.
They're aware and I always,
yeah,
I always feel like that's probably a
natural cycle. I think there's less,
you know how people,
like you say like people from Pittsburgh
or like this and people from Boston and
like this. I think with the
Internet, with TV especially,
there's less and less of that,
right?
Because you're exposed to more and
more things as the world is, you know,
so you don't have to have it.
This kind of accent you don't have,
you can see other forms,
but except when laws are applied,
like California pot laws are
different than somewhere else.
Did you ever look at someone that's
doing something like someone,
there's a surgeon or something that's
incredibly difficult and you go, okay,
what if I just started all over?
How long would it take
before I could be this guy,
this 50 year old dude who
specializes in replacing, you know,
fuck a lot of work.
Nick neck spacers know one of those
dudes that fixes bulging discs with
artificial spacers.
Like,
like what if you had to go starting
from about all the training with tech
fucking Amen. Do you ever think
about like live in someone's life?
Like how difficult it is to get to him
to get to be who the fuck you are at 50
or 40 or whatever the fuck you are.
You know,
like if you had to start all
over and go from scratch,
that's probably the most terrifying
thought about the universe. What is that?
What it, what this all is, is some
endless cycle that just keeps continuing
over and over again and you live this
life over and over and over again.
Imagine till you get it absolutely right
until every step of the way you do the
right thing every time you receive
enlightenment and then you move on to the
next stage of existence.
But that is one of the, uh,
the idea is attached to eastern
mysticism that this, this,
there is a possibility that this life
will be repeated until you get it correct.
Which is a pretty fascinating, you know,
you just keep trying over and over again.
The same eastern religious character
that said enlightenment is achievable in
this deck in this lifetime,
that it is possible to
achieve enlightenment in this
lifetime, but you have to,
you have to get to a state
where I want to get along.
You gotta be perfect for like 20 minutes.
Like what are we talking about?
Is there a certain shit that you did
like that you can never recover from?
You know, how much can you bounce back
from? I think when people say things like,
like those people just have to calm them
down. Like about people liking them,
whatever. Like those people are getting
too crazy about racing or a piece they,
I think that's just like we didn't grow
up around them and we don't understand
their expanse, so they'll look well
I would never be racist against both.
In the Midwest of course it's both because
the hate that all these other people
jump in,
jump in hate where something happens
and someone like Tracy mark and says
something and everyone decides to
be angry at Tracy Morgan. There's,
there's a bandwagon stuff and stuff.
Is it direct imbalance to it?
It seems to me like some
piling on bullshit and that's
what I don't like about
it. And that's what everybody is
railing against. And they say,
fuck all this piece. He Shit
because they're railing at
all these self righteous.
He fucking Prius driving cigarette
thrown out the window con I would say no,
you shouldn't say these things,
but you shouldn't be put on a steak
when you say exactly. It's like relax.
The punishment shouldn't be that hard.
Dot. I was asked to get fire forever.
We should decide. Yeah,
don't listen. Right.
I don't like hearing those words and we
should describe what we find offensive
about them and debate it and sit down
and talk about it reasonably like human
beings. And you know, if a guy fucks up
and said something on stage like that,
it's different between,
there's a difference between that and
the guy actually going out and stabbing
some gay people.
Well that obviously is a criminal and
you got to remove them from society.
He's a danger. You're like, I'm in
jail fighting and rewriting some words.
Just like come on. Yeah,
but, but to, to say it,
you've got to somehow or another you got
to let him know peaceably and in a more
enlightened place then he's coming from,
you've got to,
or from a more enlightened place,
you got to let him know, hey man,
this is what's wrong with what you're
doing. And then once he just saw,
once he acknowledges that and he
steps forcing it talks about it, look,
I'm just onstage. I'm sorry. It's
okay. We accept it. We move on.
But all his extra piling on all those
people that are just railing and forth and
it's become like this main focus
of their life for a few weeks.
Those people are comments.
Those are all cons. Like I said,
it was problem in Israel when I,
when we talked about explaining to
your non religious friends what you've
discovered about Judaism
or whatever and you're,
you're sort of not judging the same scale.
If you weren't raised with
being orthodox Jewish,
you were raised as conservative and so
you don't think you have to get kosher
outside.
Do we didn't finish
that, that thought about, you were
talking about, um, the differences in,
in the words. Oh yeah. It's the nuances.
They don't fully understand it. Okay.
The worst three always means
tree, let's just say. Okay.
But the word love can mean a lot of like
slightly different things depending if
you use the word love or if you use the
word, um, and Namor mint, I don't know.
So whenever there's a debate,
like,
so if they say three quarters of the
words in ancient Hebrew have been
translated,
but the other 24 are still up for debate.
The debate is based on a bunch of
things that were really similar.
They know it could be one of these
things. I love hamburgers. They're like,
does that mean that he's, that he has a
lust for hamburgers or I hate Mondays,
right? There's a slightly different
use to describe your Dick and new,
we understand those slight differences.
They're still trying to understand them,
right? So they get that. It
means something positive.
Like love would mean something positive.
But I don't quite know how positive.
Like, you remember when Russell
Peters told us that, uh, he, uh,
someone told him that he the, oh
it's the Mondays. And he was like,
what the fuck does that mean? I'm
using that all the time. I love it.
Russell Peters was talking
about some guy understanding,
understand about the Monday Mondays, you
know, the Mondays go there and he goes,
what's the Mondays and the guy who was
black people, oh, I've never heard that.
He goes, yeah, he goes, he goes, cause
nobody likes Mondays. Oh. And so we were
how they were like, Oh shit. And so
now, once that's out there, you know,
out in the lexicon, you know, if you wrote
something in the blog, you know, like Oh,
and then we went to the club
and they're with a Monday,
then it would make sense
because otherwise you'd be like,
what the fuck are you talking about? So
that shit was in the Bible. Oh look there.
And went to the, we went to the
desert and it's filled with Mondays.
Like the fuck did they mean by that?
They meant a Syrian.
It's nobody wants to hang
out with those people.
Was this homeless person sleeping in the
other day and I was with my girlfriend.
I'm like, oh, look, a Monday fell
down. Oh Dude. That's just like,
what the fuck are you talking to,
man? You'd go to the wrong place.
Brian actually had no idea what it went
to the wrong place. You actually used it.
All right? Who's Day fell
down? Don't do it. Don't do it.
Don't try to defend yourself, son.
You're not bright enough for this job.
You're going to hurt your career. It
can hurt your future. You're lucky.
You're lucky you start him. It's
all been achieved on a podcast.
It's you to have a fake image too,
of like someone who was like
wholesome Christian first one.
You're not those people
that read the news.
I always look at girls that read the
news and they turned me on whenever I see
pitches, read the news
because I know, first of all,
they're not creatively fulfilled and
they're probably bored and they're looking
for things to do so they're probably
just thinking about Dick. You know,
whenever I read,
see some chick or reading the news,
I read that girl's probably just behind
the scenes is just a fucking freak.
She's probably freak tastic you know,
she's all buttoned down,
acting all unnatural and that TV show
for 90 minutes every day. Listen,
there's some give and take to this world.
There's a yin and a Yang and
if you get it up all day,
you got to Yangon up all night. You know
what I'm talking about? What the fuck?
Cock sucker. Fuck yeah. What I'm saying,
that was a total Joey Diaz logic moment
and I'm saying this Yin and Yang,
you fucking unit ended up all day with
that fucking suit on Yang it down at
night, right dog. And he would go like
that. He make you touch, knock right dog,
right. To understand what
you're talking about. The yes,
but I'm not positive and you're
like, I'm, yeah, yeah, that sort of,
but I couldn't explain it.
I let him talk about anything.
He doesn't have to make sense. Every now
and then I asked for some clarification,
but if you don't even have to do that,
you know what I'm talking about bro?
The Meat Sandwich at fucking that Deli
in Philly, right? Dog. You remember that,
right? What does that mean and
just go, it doesn't really matter.
It doesn't matter.
It's Joey Diaz colloquially
just pollution will be this
Friday night joining us in Vegas.
I'm really excited for this show.
That was so good last time
and taken a road trip there.
Shazamm are you going to drive you
crazy answer cause I think it might look
around with the salt mines and stuff
also. He's the salt and see. Yeah.
Well we're going to do that
podcast. Got killed. Police
killed and eaten. I just want to
check it out. Yeah, I like road trips.
Then we're going to do this.
We've talked about this yesterday and
we're going to do this and Ari's down to,
we're going to drive,
we're going to take my truck and we're
all going to pile into the truck and
we're going to drive out the salt and
seat and we're going to make a video and
we're going to film it and then we're
going to do a podcast from out there at
the salt and say, I just think that'd
be an awesome thing to do. Sit down.
Maybe we'll get a shave motel room
up there. How about a good one?
I don't think there are any.
There might not be one and a gun.
Let's find that gun. The pest, I
don't want to say I'm bringing a gun,
but I'm bringing a gun. Is it? It goes to,
but there's still places nearby
there just in case in Saturday,
like Joshua tree where it's like Eddie
Bravo says there's 400 people live in
there. I have not researched that
so I'm just repeating what he said.
But that John Waters a documentary
right there. Plagues, what does it say?
The bottom one plagues and lakes and
pleasures. On the salt on city. Yeah.
Well I'm going to watch that tonight.
I want to, I want to go there.
One experiences,
it sounds incredibly bizarre
and apparently it's like
a post apocalyptic world
surrounded by an outpost of just a few
hundred stragglers that decide to live
near this crazy lake that's like ultra,
ultra salty and has mass fist die offs
and we're going to be getting there in
the summer. So probably there'd
be a bunch of fish die offs. Oh,
it keeps happening. Yeah, every year.
But I thought they millions
of them die every year.
Whole place smells like dovish.
A lot survive. Yes. That's like,
apparently there's like 10
million fish in this lake,
but every like couple of years
a million of them will die.
It's probably like nothing's
getting new ones in there though.
It's probably like we're going to be
at this shitty hotel and we're probably
like five minutes and going,
okay, this was a really bad
idea. Why the fuck are we?
You know, we'll be like,
we're going to tie cancer.
One of the reasons why I want to go there
is because I want to have like I want
to internalize the idea that things
can completely fall apart and you can,
you can see it like within a lifetime and
the salt and seeing the 1950s was this
incredible resort inland and now here we
are visiting in 2011 barely a lifetime
being only three quarters of a lifetime
later and there's nothing. It's,
it's crazy. It's odd that lift it
have been like 2025 and gone like, oh,
it's a fun place to go on the sound
of the winter or whatever. Yeah.
It's the amazing thing to be. When you
see places like that you can see scale,
you can find the understand how big
they are in relation to you and your own
eyes as opposed to pictures. We're
sort of guessing. Right, right, right.
You got to go there and see it.
The Coliseum.
I don't really understand quite where
I would be in a scale model of that.
How small it would be.
Well,
I think you get to see that because you
see cars driving around the coliseum,
which is so strange. Like the,
they put the road right next to it.
Like the Colosseum in Rome. Yeah.
The fucking road is like right there.
So people are just driving right by the
coliseum and was going to collapse one
day. Like a bridge. Oh my God. Humble
people think so man. It's pretty bad acid.
It's lasted this long.
You're at the Mandalay Bay theaters
are still tickets and everything.
Like there's some, there's
some, but it's going quick.
We would put it on the Twitter and yeah,
it's going to be sold out last time.
Why is it that shit? Oh my God, he's
gonna. It's gonna be a good time.
It's going to be crazy ideas. Had One of
the best sets I've ever seen last time.
Yeah. Well he's, Joey is a rise to the
occasion type of motherfucker. And when,
you know,
when there's a giant crowd,
like Joey deals will throw it out and he
fucking threw down in Pittsburgh. Dude.
God Damn, he fucking destroyed
in Pittsburgh. He's so crazy.
He's so crazy. And he's always doing
new shit and it's always like just he's,
he's a 15 minutes of fury
type of comedian and he'll,
he'll stretch it out for 30. I'll kill
pace himself, you know more. But those,
those 15 minutes of fury sets,
there's not a fucking human alive that
can fuck with Joey Diaz when he's in full
clown. When he's red in the
face and sweating, you know,
just still going to hell.
You're going to hell the fuck are you?
You know,
he'll be there.
Uh,
Doug Benson is going to stop in and do a
guest set and then everybody's going to
be at the UFC the next day
cause it's going to be the shit.
It's an office or Saulteaux. Ralphie
may be across town, like the duties.
Ralphie may follow new, everybody's
going to be in Vegas. This is crazy.
This weekend Ralphie may was just to
believe that he was a Pittsburgh while we
were in Pittsburgh. We got offstage at
art show, signed a bunch of autographs,
took a bunch of pictures for like an hour
and then went to Ralphie show and hung
out with Ralphie there. That's cool. Yeah,
we went to watch Ralphie and you know,
um, there's uh, who else
is going to be there?
Sam Aaa Naughty show at that strip club.
This club is awesome.
Uh, fuck I to go there bro.
And girls and Milligan.
It's like sapphires or something.
Something like that. Yes. Sapphire,
I might have just made something up.
Got Some company cause some other place.
Their, their um, their attendance.
It's a treasures treasure.
That's right. Don't go to south
or do, maybe it's awesome.
I don't want to be a hater
treasures is where Sam shuffle,
who's going to be though, so we're going
to be, we're going to be Friday night,
Mandalay bay 9:00 PM show nine.
That's a good time.
If you can get, just Google it, you
can get tickets online and you can go,
this is a link on my
website and Joe rogan.net.
Click on the calendar and I and click
on the event. It'll take you to,
I believe it's just Mandalay Bay
dot. Or don't go to stub. Okay.
I'm telling you it out.
Stub hub buys a bunch of tickets
and there are scalping sore site.
Really just Jack shut up on that shit.
It's like 160 towards your bucks.
There's still tickets available for
40 or 50 and these places are already
selling it for four or five times as much.
And you think that's the only place
as good as you can get them. Yeah.
Don't go to [inaudible]. They're
owned by Ticketmaster. Whoa.
They're already evil empire.
The only thing left is lab
stub until they sell to fucking
sell tickets. Use. He uses brown. No,
but I think Ticketmaster has
got a piece of them tonight.
I think that what that is,
that's like the Ebay of ticket sales.
Like meaning dogs actually putting
it on Brown paper bags or something.
That's the way they do when
these companies get big enough,
ticket master comes in and fucking
change them slightly. So there's Nope,
we'll get it. No, I think the content
was still tickets left and right.
You better stop talking shit
about the evil empire son.
They're going to fucking there.
Come down on you.
Just like they did on the left though.
It's a band that came down on Pearl
Jam came down on Pearl Jam. Right.
Until Jim refuse to go.
Unless you're charging 20% extra,
we're not allowing you to take that off.
Our fans,
they went to Congress and what happened?
How'd that work out?
Program kind of fell off the
map for a long time. Yeah.
Fucking albums. Songs to
shit. Half era, you know.
I mean after that there wasn't had at
their height they weren't 20 live because
they could only sell tickets
on Ticketmaster and it was low.
We don't want to gouge our fans.
I think green day,
I remember somebody ingredients.
I like how you said it best.
Why don't you just lower your charge list,
but no one should have to do that.
That should not be the reason
why Ticketmaster's. Okay. Yeah,
but master till he's asleep. They
shouldn't be selling tickets for free.
They shouldn't get 20%
though, right? Yeah.
$2 $2 and $50 ticket
getting 20% service charge.
That's a computer.
There's no service. Yeah.
Well they have an infrastructure
to sell. Take a monopoly. Yeah.
It is kind of a monopoly because you
can't choose to do well now that you would
think with the Internet it would be pretty
easy to set up some sort of a virtual
shop and have everything the
tickets available online.
Like some places like the
Atlantic theater, it doesn't sell.
There's the Fandango and stuff. They
just sell the arclight side. Okay.
But let me ask you this.
Say if you wanted to rent out a place you
wanted to rent out the Orpheum theater
and he wanted to, uh, you
know, to, to put up with bull,
you can rent out the Hollywood bowl
and you could sell your own tickets,
show your own tape. It's hard to
get where you want to do. It's like,
how would you get the letter
by the printed online,
but they would have to go to the planes.
It works with airplanes. If you're,
I mean,
you can get a ticket printed online.
I would imagine you can get a ticket for
a comedy show printed online with some
sort of a barcode. But the, why
is everyone using Ticketmaster?
What's the advantage to the venue?
Because it's easy and you reach more
people though and you take credit cards.
Bam. There you go. Maybe
it's just the end, you know?
It's like it's happening now.
Like I see people a lot of times now
I'm at the airport when they don't even
print their ticket up,
they actually have it on their own
and then they scan their iPhone.
It was just pretty wild.
My friend at whoop,
I just told me that there's this
application. Yeah, that, that, that,
that you know there's little things we
were talking about yesterday with that,
that you put her, any key chains
for like the grocery stores,
grocery stores have all,
you just have all your information in
there and then they scan that dormitory
keeps your phone up. Three of them,
they don't work. What do you mean?
I've tried three of them and they don't
work from it. That keep your numbers.
All you have to do is type in your number.
Like, oh, when you scan the barcode,
you don't have to scan it in.
What it does is it saves all your numbers,
like a key chain.
So if that doesn't work with scanning and,
and he just sit there and go,
all right,
my number is one eight oh four seven two
five you can do that. But the scanning,
should we just write your number down
unlike your notebook and not have to
download some silly fucking
application notebook around here.
All your notebook on your phone.
Yeah, you could do that too.
I know book on my phone has all
sorts of great notes, but I use,
this was supposed to be the barcode,
the UPC Barcode we're supposed to work.
Like if you get your Ralph's
Clower cvs card and whatever.
So you just find that one
on the APP and just scan it.
It works rarely and not very really.
I used to Starbucks a application.
I wear it every single day.
But all you have to do is know your number
and then you can enter your numbers.
But that's not the same as
being able to scan it. Right.
But why would I get an application when
you just fucking write down your number
means it's just one sec.
Cause it's easier because you just,
you just go to your car.
Right. But that's in there.
How many digits is your number?
I mean it's,
he's what he's saying is this application
you're supposed to be able to be like,
oh you got the great,
right. Yeah, but it depends.
If it's seven like a phone number,
you should be able to remember it easily.
Or if it's a hundred
cvs card at Barnes and nobles car.
True. But if you have a little
fucking notepad on your phone,
like that notepad feature on the iPhone
because on that do you write comedy on
that thing? I write on the other. Oh
yeah. Sears. That's a pretty big number.
That's like,
that's like a social security number or
number 10 numbers where the APP worked.
It'd be great just as a fully work,
a little thrifty bastard you,
he had a bunch of little
key chains on that thing.
Do you collect your words for
Kush Mart and all that stuff?
You got money back? I took
already to my spot today. Zam Son.
I got some tanks shock. I tried to
text her for the first time though.
You were in the, uh, the card system,
man. They got rewards cards lately.
You should have come with us dean calmly.
You're right, you're right. I apologize.
I can't really just throw
this specific one. Sure.
For the folks who were eliciting and
going, what the fuck you're talking about?
It's like a liquid. You drop
it, a little liquid drop code,
Glycerin Toe and it puts you on pollute.
Oh,
Eddie Bravo wrote a whole movie.
He,
he drank a whole bottle of that stuff.
Did he really serene? Yes. No, no,
no, no wheat. The wheat oil or
whatever the fuck it is. It's merit.
It's marijuana and some
sort of a liquid form.
And he drank the whole bottle of it on
an airplane and he said he had the most
intense dream and he watched a movie play
out in the movie was called Shit Baby.
And it was,
the movie was about a guy fucks this
girl in the ass and the shitty loads leak
out of her asshole and goes into
her vagina and she gets pregnant.
She smells like shit. It's a shitty
babies. You said you watched it play out.
Was this in his head? He watched
it. He said he watched a whole,
the whole like shit baby going to
school and everybody hates shift baby.
He like watched this whole
movie play out in his mind.
He wrote it down when he got home,
but he said that it was like
the most intense like this,
this hallucination that he was under
because he was so high from this.
You can go for it man.
It's like Jesus, man.
No fear. Just die. Well, he
didn't know what would happen.
He drank the whole thing.
It didn't know what, what happened. He
had it on him. He brought this little,
little tiny liquid. This is bad.
Just to keep this in context,
they told me one or two drops will
requeue drops. I've eye eyedropper.
Well they said one drop is about a
half a breath strip and half of breast
tripled. Fucking nothing.
Like half a cookie.
Half a cookie will knock you on your
ass depending on the cookie, but yeah,
you get the real shit.
They got the real shit at that place.
You got the kind of guy made us in
Chicago and then I place that I go to,
everyone's so nice,
you know,
and that's what I love going to
do when you go to the weed store,
everyone's so friendly. They are always so
friendly. Yeah. Hey, what's up? What's up?
You high five and what's going on?
What's up dude?
Dude's telling us about his employment
history and homes are tough and we're all,
we're all just sitting there
shooting the shit, watching a little,
the news is on and people come in and
everyone's friendly placing orders.
This is how it's supposed to be. You can
ask the questions but like, you know,
I want something for munchies. What
do you got for that? Like I need,
and they'll tell you, they'll help
you through it, help you through it.
There's showman. You haven't you
poor bastards living in Nebraska.
Just get you get a masters.
You poor bastards.
They're just trying to get weed from
some Indian Dude who works at the casino.
Ruined my land. Okay. Can I just get
the way you did? Just give it to me bro.
Please. Can I get the weed? It's
great if you're a good customer,
have to weld like, oh, you gotta try this
new strain here for your APP. Just take,
they always given away free
shit, man. You are joint prayer.
It's very rare that anybody
gives you free alcohol. You know,
nobody gives you a free McDonald's
fries at Mcdonald's for two years.
I never get free ice cream because you
bought maybe do maybe just ice cream
rewards,
whatever bitches Friday night,
Mandalay bay 9:00 PM that people
know this shit is going down.
It's Joe Diaz. It's all Recia
fear. Doug Benson will stop in.
I will be there to let us know.
Uh,
UFC hunt for the edible on a
Oh, that's right. On Saturday.
The UFC Humphrey edible. So the way to
get a part of this is through Twitter.
If you follow Ari shift fear at a r I s
h a f f I r follow Ari and Ari will be
hiding marijuana edibles,
allegedly, allegedly, allegedly.
This might be just a joke throughout
the casino. This may be just a joke.
If you're a police officer, I'm going
to tell you right now, this is a joke.
This is not real. So for you,
it's not real. For everybody
else, it might be real.
And so nothing to do with this
person.
I barely know him. I know very little
about his past. I can't vouch for him.
I wouldn't be willing to sign for
him to get some sort of a passport.
I've got to write a letter.
Joe India is really,
I'm gonna write a letter for Joey Diaz
to get a package out to where? Dog,
I want to go to England anywhere.
Talk those pitches off. Yeah, right.
A little bit about, I
don't know, criminal.
And a lot of people get to
look at him and go, Damn Dude,
what did you do when you're here for
what? That was months ago. Listen dog,
I'm a new man. I'm a
new man. Friday night,
Joey Diaz will be with us pitches.
The shit is going to be epic.
We're doing these shows now on a regular
basis in Vegas and they're fun as fuck.
I really, cause now we're getting
all the podcast fan. Yeah,
dude with the last one was fucking
awesome. It gets up later. Yeah,
they get drunk later. Go to the show,
then get drunk. We'll get drunk with you.
How about that?
Beers while you're there,
we're going to be there and we'll
take pictures and answer uncomfortable
questions and you could put your sweaty
armpits over people's shoulders and take
photos. He, is this a loop or is this a
cell phone and it's just a ticket? Listen,
this fucking show is over tomorrow
depending on how sick my friend yon is who
wrote the crazy books about him.
Mushrooms.
We're going to have to call him
up and find out what's up. Yeah,
but he's a fascinating dude and he
wrote a lot of books about religion and
mushroom. Two books. Not a lot. It's not a
lot. It's a lot. If you don't write books,
what the fuck am I rambling for?
Go to Joe rogan.net to thank our sponsor,
the fleshlight into
utilize their fine product.
And if you click on the link@joerogan.net
and entering the code name rogue,
and you get 15% off
your number one sex toy.
I wonder if NBC is going to have a
problem with my endorsement of this number
one sex toy. You are who you pretend you
are. I am who I am. I should make a chai.
I'm like, Popeye, bitch. I got mud. I
am. And that's all. But Hey, by the way,
let me just say this. Yuk Yuks in Toronto,
uh, July 20th through the 23rd Oh shit.
July 20th through the 23rd,
Ari Shaffir comes to Canada bitches.
He's been with me several
times up there in Canada.
Is the shit so fun in the zone and that's
it. It's fucking shows over. All right,
we'll see you. We love you. We'll be
probably back tomorrow if John's not sick.
But if he is sick and dice clay
apparently wants to do the podcast. Yes.
Oh, big fat fucking ace. Oh.