We live about is about,
we're talking about g Gordon Liddy,
so gigo this episode of Miami Vice was a
sergeant in Vietnam and right when
Saigon fell,
he held onto 300 kilos of pure heroin.
He took it to the United States and dead
bodies.
This is what the episode's about.
Nineteen 86.
Miami Vice.
They bring it to Miami and he sat on it
for 20 years until the value with all
the way up,
just like an investment and then he let
it loose,
but by that time it had gotten
contaminated.
Started killing junkies all up and down
the east coast when a brilliant episode.
So they had to go in and dig for g dot
Gordon Liddy and this motherfucker shows
up right for like this board meeting and
that's when I had to leave the house.
He shows up to this board and he's like,
yeah,
the heroin was my boss.
He,
because I guarantee they called them
sergeant real estate and in the episode
he goes,
I guess you guys forget who the hell I
am.
He turns around,
he goes in his briefcase and he throws a
chain or is on the table when he walks
out.
Oh,
that's it.
That's the episode.
Tremendous.
Haiti,
what?
This is [inaudible] 86 to seven percent
on Miami.
This is way before American gangster was
talking about it.
This was already out that they were
bringing Vietnam heroin and dead bodies
and that's how the episode starts to
report.
It takes Don Johnson to the morgue and
he opens it up from Vietnam and he goes,
this is your friend.
Stick your hand,
and it was just pure heroin.
That was what they did,
right?
What they were doing towards.
Yeah.
I don't know at the beginning that was,
but it was really the CIA that blaming
it all on some black guy from that
Harlem.
Well,
you know,
there's a guy named Mr.
Nice.
I forget what his name is.
Something banks famous.
A drug dealer when he said was,
it wasn't the CIA.
What it was some people in the CIA.
He said it's some cowboys in the ca and
that's what makes the most sense to me.
Like this idea that the big
organization,
the CIO would be involved in drug
smuggling seems like so crazy.
Joe Rogan.
It's too many,
many heads,
plenty of people,
plenty of people that did do it look
like.
There's plenty of examples.
Like there's an example right now,
this thing called the Silk Road,
you know about the Silk Road.
The Silk Road was this underground drug
dealing like network that this guy had
created and they were just selling mad
money.
Matt,
Matt drugs like underground and they had
created this thing like it's,
it's,
it's a total.
What it is is it operates like
completely under the wire and these dea
guys,
I think it was tea,
they infiltrated it and they got into
the Silk Road.
One of the first things they did,
they started stealing money.
Now these guys are in jail.
They're going to jail right now.
They're,
they're in court right now and they're
wondering like whether or not this case
is even valid because these guys for
sure had access to this guy's account
and part of what they were trying to try
this guy on his,
his complicit in that he was complicit
in the drug selling and there was also
some possibility that people were
murdered.
Although there was no body.
There's a lot of Kinky shit going on
with this and the kinkiest part is that
the agents were stealing money.
Bitcoins,
yes.
There were stealing of thousands of
dollars in bitcoin.
So they,
they realized that there was a lot of
value in this.
Like that shit is always gone on.
I think the reason why you have guys
like this that are showing up in the
Silk Road case,
there's always been cowboys,
but I think there's been good guys too.
There's been guys who were in the CIA
that really did it for America.
I had this guy,
Michael Baker in them.
I'm pretty good at recognizing bullshit,
you know,
and he's a longtime CIA operative in a
fucking great guy.
I mean,
he really does seem like he loves
America,
like I don't think he's bullshitting.
I think there's a lot of those guys,
they get in those positions and they get
a group of them together just like they
did with ramp part,
but those fucking bad cops,
they get a group of them together and
go,
look what happened.
Oops.
Pop that out.
They get together.
Go look.
All these guys are making money.
Right?
Fuck them.
They're all criminals and scumbags and
cons.
Let's just get some of this money,
man.
Let's just get some of this money.
Come on,
man.
You know,
we're going to stop these fucking
people.
This is what we do.
We keep,
we keep throwing a few of them in jail.
We do whatever the fuck we got to do.
We were the were the gang here.
We got the law on our side.
Let's fucking make some money.
Well,
what's the CIA?
I shouldn't have said that.
You're absolutely right.
There was factions like,
yeah,
a brown bag,
like a black bag faction that wedding
after,
uh,
the marines would go in and they shoot
everybody and throw cards.
You know,
whatever the fuck it was when you have,
when you're shipping heroin from
wherever the fuck that is considered all
the way to the United States through
three or two different airports and
people have to unload them and you have
a,
you know,
whatever.
People walk into your plane when they
first come in to inspect them.
That's a lot of people.
You got to grease.
It has to be somebody huge.
This isn't me and you get a boat and
going to Columbia and paying some guy
with me and read back and we just shoot
across with police scanners and try our
best to to make,
to infiltrate the.
To bring in that amount of heroin.
You have to spend a lot of dough.
That's where your costs come in.
That's where you set the wholesale and
the retail prices.
You know,
years ago,
20 years ago,
they would,
they would smuggle it 60 miles and 70,
45,
50 miles in from the United States
around Miami and they would dump it
overboard with weights and 12 hours
later the boom would explode and the
bales would rise up and you'd come by,
a fishermen will come by and put the
bales and meanwhile the dea was looking
for that boat that was speeding across
on their radar,
but they would throw,
you know,
that's,
that takes expensive equipment to devise
something to throw you 50 pounds of
cocaine,
100 feet under the water.
And then 12 hours later everything blows
and your coke rises to the top.
And now some guy comes and just picks it
up.
This is brilliant stuff.
So this is what the Jay listens.
Really what they did.
That was one of the things.
They get old after a while to beat the
federal government.
You got to,
you got.
And it doesn't listen,
man.
What,
uh,
what the budget is for fighting drugs
and what a drug dealer spends a month.
I'm talking about a guy that's bringing
in a thousand kilos a month,
the powder,
whether it be heroin or cocaine,
that's big powder.
Somebody has got to be turning around
and they were flooding the market with
heroin and I remember being a little boy
in New York and going to visit my
godmother and my mother's friends and
seeing people everywhere.
Not early.
New York to me was a fucking this shit
that they.
What's the show now where people dead
walking around Atlanta walking and I saw
that growing up.
I saw that growing up as a kid row where
they used to have in Harlem,
Spanish Harlem.
Harlem is scarier than all those.
You know,
they had people not,
not the lights.
People waiting to cross the street and
they not at the fucking lie.
They don't have though in New York that
they have here in La and New York.
All these cities of buildings,
there's like these streets have there.
Whether these were.
These people are.
It's like these are places where other
folks go like,
you got all your homeless people.
He got,
you know,
your,
your poor people.
But there's cars that go through those
areas and it's,
you know,
it's well traveled like New York blends
more.
La has these blocks that are just
homeless people.
And when I mean just homeless people,
I'm talking thousands,
like they're literally might be a
thousand pounds on this block.
Oh Dude.
You've seen them.
Oh yeah.
You get,
you make a wrong turn and you get right
in the middle.
It's a Michael Jackson video.
It really is.
It's insane.
In downtown,
there's a.
well they call skid row.
It's actually says if you go on Google
maps and type skid row in Los Angeles,
it actually says skid row and there's a
like a mile long.
I mean it's a couple blocks launch.
It's a lot.
There's a lot of it.
There's more than one area.
There's like one long street.
But we used to work when we did fear
factor,
we used to work in these buildings and
these buildings were,
a lot of them abandoned textile
buildings or they were renting amount.
So we're American apparel actually is
made.
It's really weird.
We were in the American apparel factory.
We had to go through the American
apparel factory to the get to the roof.
We've watched them like make their
clothes,
you know,
they're like,
they do make them in downtown La.
It's like one of the things they pride
themselves on.
Jesus.
Fuck.
Fucking frys Joey.
Yes.
But we would go to the top of these,
um,
hang up on a Jesus Christ.
He checked into the fucking is the.
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
We would go to the top of these
buildings and you could,
you could literally,
there was areas where,
you know,
you could see them like leaking out into
the rest is treats and if you drove down
there who drove down the street,
I'm not bullshitting.
You would see hundreds,
hundreds of homeless people just
swarming the streets.
And there's these areas where they have
like,
um,
it's crazy.
Joey,
they,
they have these areas where they have
like they give them food or they have
areas where they can get medical
assistance,
stuff like that.
And those areas are particularly dense.
Now when I shot Myp,
the blue eye shadow at a downtown
location,
that's the pool hall kind
of shorter and they had time to homeless
people.
When I was standing there,
I heard people going in talking about
how they had day rentals.
The government would pay for 15 days and
they'd be out in the street for 15 days
like that,
but I didn't see that look advil.
This is,
this seems mild compared to what I saw.
When was this?
What year is this come?
Maybe they've cleaned it up a little.
Well,
it's.
It's also during the day I've gotten
through the night.
Oh yeah.
Curious.
Go back.
What?
I want to see what the statistics were
good people in every city and it's out
of proportion and some cities more than
others.
Pause on that for a second.
Skid row's near downtown La.
Two thousand sensors.
The population of the district was
7,740.
Skid row is defined as,
oh my God,
what the fuck does that mean?
Does it defined in a decision by Jones
versus city of Los Angeles?
The area east of main street,
south of Third Street and west of
Alameda Street,
so it's kind of like a block.
It's like an area,
but that area has 17,000
homeless people.
Is that right?
That's a Goddamn Kevin Hart concert.
That's Kevin.
Kevin,
Kevin Hart sold out Madison Square
Garden.
Three fucking shows in a row.
He's a monster.
Comedies on and off time.
Huh?
She's the biggest comedian of all time.
Kevin.
No one's ever been as big as Kevin Hart.
As far as like popularity.
No one even close.
I can't think of one person.
I think there's a couple of guys that
got up to that edge,
but I think he's totally taken it to a
totally different stratosphere.
Like Dane got pretty far.
He got on that edge,
louise on that edge,
but Kevin Hart is routinely doing these
crazy arena shows.
He's doing 40,000
plus people who sold 40,000
plus tickets are ready for a show in
philly where he's filming a special
dude.
It's just total next level positive
energy shit.
And if you go to that kid's a instagram
page is instagram is all about like
positive,
like energy,
like get going to work.
I'm doing what I love to do.
I'm working.
Shows him in the gym,
putting work in five days with people
and they see that they would chase them.
Last week in Boston,
I flew into the five fucking reality
show.
He ain't never stopped.
Got his own line of underwear.
I do whatever the fuck he wants.
He's an animal.
It would suck.
Keep going in those concerts though it
and being like the back that can not be
enjoyable hearing screens,
huge screens and the way they
acoustically setup these things used to
be a problem.
I'm like,
I told you that I used to work at great
woods,
is kind of a funny story because,
uh,
it was during a bill cosby show that
there was an issue there,
a bill cosby and um,
there was uh,
a Rodney dangerfield show the same
issue.
And the issue was the way great woods is
set up,
it's an amphitheater,
so you're indoors and part of it and
part of it is outdoors in the back of it
leads out to this like lawn area or at
least did when I worked there.
And so you can hear if were under the
canopy,
there was like an acoustic canopy above
all the seats in the front.
But then the back there was no seats.
So it's like you had monsters behind
you.
So he tried to watch a show.
Like there was one big fight,
I think I want to say it was,
it was Judas priest was a Judas priest.
No,
jethro tull.
It was jethro Tull was a jethro tull
concert and there was a fucking mad riot
because people started lighting fires up
in the hood up in the grass area.
They were just lighting fires and there
was not enough of us to sort of control
it all because it was getting really
fucking crazy.
So I put my security jacket,
I put a Hoodie on over my security
jacket,
zipped it up through the Hoodie,
over my head and said,
fuck this job,
and I just quit.
I was like,
you can't pay me nine bucks an hour to
get killed because this,
this is fucking madness.
I saw fistfights,
my friend Larry,
who was like one of the nicest guys in
the world,
punch some guy and I was like,
Oh,
I'm fucking that.
If Larry's Hinton people.
Larry is like the sweetest of
sweethearts and I'm like,
this guy's hitting people.
I am God.
This is a madness in the air.
I've got to get the fuck Outta here.
I got pistol for the jethro tull
constitute because he breaks up the
flute,
breaks up the flow.
Like,
what the fuck is this?
People from the east coast,
we don't like fluids,
stuff like we don't like flutes.
My point was in the backyard of the
green,
the green grass area,
you couldn't hear the words.
You didn't understand what the fuck it
was.
It was all echos.
It was all blah,
blah,
blah.
Like people were pissed.
They go,
I don't know what the fuck he's saying,
and Ronnie was killing too,
and so it was caused because he was
killed.
We were just.
Jamie and I would talk on about a red
rocks if you've been to red rocks,
you get so impressed with the sound like
cheat and I went like 80 something and
then I went like a 90 something and it
was like being indoors.
That's amazing.
Fiddler's green,
which is a little smaller.
I think on the other side of the Denver,
they had an issue there,
but now even the Hollywood bowl,
Jesus middle of people are there.
What's the popular?
Not too many.
That's insane.
Because you do stand up there.
Do you ever do they do it?
They do it.
Then suddenly got.
Roy was doing a set.
Yeah,
so I'm just doing like a movie night
where we'd host and do some comedy.
Yeah.
Brody Brody didn't get paid for that
one.
That was one of the brody didn't get
paid for.
They fucked him at.
I think so.
Well we were re tweeting it.
Yeah.
He's like,
that's my money.
If I contact number three or whatever,
see what they did was crazy.
It was crazy.
He had a two shows.
One was in a small theater and one was
in this big theater was doing the show
in the smallest theater and they go,
would you like to do a show in the big
theater?
So he goes,
yeah,
sure.
Thinking he's going to get paid.
They ask him,
do you want to work?
He put his name on the bill like you
show.
He tweeted pictures of the lineup.
They had his name in the lineup.
It wasn't like a guest set or anything
like that.
It was a guy they had scheduled on the
show and nobody wants to go first.
You don't want to go up first in front
of fucking 15,000
people.
You want to get the crowd warmed up
first.
Brody had to go up there and do the
hardest spot of the night.
Was second hardest spot of the night.
The hardest by the night is like
following someone who crushes.
Like if you're going on after Diaz,
that's the hardest part of the night,
but any.
The second hardest part of the hardest
part of the night is the first guy,
the first guy,
his first couple of minutes is kind of
like a throwaway and you've got to kind
of get everybody loose,
get everybody feeling good and then
boom,
hit them in the material that has got to
have very few bumps in it because you're
trying to hypnotize these fuckers.
So like the early material,
it's gotta be like real smooth.
The more herky Jerky,
the earlier stuff is less likely to
trust you.
You motherfucker,
you can't even get me into Goddamn
Trans,
slipping off your words,
you know,
but if you go out there just smooth
style and just walk right into it and
really know what the fuck you're doing
to get things started.
You know,
you,
uh,
you forget about that.
I forgot about that.
I opened for Callan when he was doing
his DVD and I owe.
It just opened.
It was the first time I had done that in
forever.
I was like,
Ooh,
this is interesting.
This is like a different.
You kinda gotta get everybody.
You feel it.
You feel like they're not quite there
yet.
You gotta Kinda like massage and,
and then then you start the fucking
crank it up and make them keep up,
you know.
But it's definitely a different thing.
Got slow them down,
suck them in.
And then the store,
we thought we'd show,
you know,
everybody talks about suicide.
I had a kid I grew up with Steve Mann,
cine and one day he just said,
fuck it.
He went to Cavo.
He walked with suicide bridge.
He this Sunday because glasses off,
we put him down.
He jumped and that was it.
Didn't leave a note.
Nothing.
He was always a little fucking crazy.
Every time you saw him he was quoting
the albums and shit like it's starting
to filing brain.
So you know,
he was disturbed somewhere along the
line,
but nobody gave a fuck.
Like even today when I go home like a
Web Mr.
Bench and fuck him,
he jumped.
He committed suicide.
Times have changed.
People give a fuck.
You kill yourself or it was just hurting
soul.
Twenty years ago you'd kill yourself.
Fuck that motherfucker.
He's in limbo.
Isn't that funny?
Because it was more like back then,
like a fucking,
you're an idiot.
Like back then,
like you said,
you will have forgotten that they have
no mass feeding.
Right.
When you watch yourself,
you can't get messed that you can't get
messed up.
When you die,
they barrier.
You don't go to hell or heaven.
You got to like limbo.
You floating around with other people
carrying the rope.
We never heard about like mental illness
when I heard about like completely crazy
people that were locked in an asylum.
But the idea of like your aunt taking
pills because she's bipolar,
like what are you talking about?
We call them because it was accepted and
everyone knows like,
oh yeah,
we used to take volume and what's.
I think it's the opposite.
I think you just get used to people
being fucking crazy.
You know?
You didn't feel like you had to medicate
them.
You know?
I think people were way more crazy in
the sixties and seventies.
I'd do Johnny Reid.
I tried to kill himself,
but he jumped off a building.
Atlanta in the dumpster.
God,
how bad was he?
Broken?
Fucked up.
Fucked up and he throw punches.
Johnny Reid was a trip and he got a
check from the government and he gave it
to you first.
That's what people thought,
but he lives like he banged his head on
a dumpster on my fucking dog.
He lived and he gives his check from the
government and the first to the
bartender and he torment the bartender
to that check was done.
Then they throw them after the first and
they will last a little about the 18th
and 19th.
When I was a kid,
I met Johnny Ray.
He through an east coast.
He locked the bathroom from the APP.
You liked the bathrooms and the outside
of these coasts.
When you leave a bar at night,
when they close up,
they locked the bathroom.
Then they put like a lock box.
Have you break in?
They can't.
He would go into the bathroom.
Johnny [inaudible] like 11:00
in the morning that we lock them in
there.
We leave them in there until like 6:00
at night.
We come back to have a drink.
He'd open the bathroom and he'd come out
like nothing.
I swear to God like nothing happened.
He was hilarious.
One day put my Dick on a chair next to
him sitting my friends,
see what happens,
and he's like,
wow.
And he just got up thought Johnny
relived like maybe 12 years ago.
We used to give them bumps at coke and
get them riled up at the bar and they
just leave.
Fuck you motherfuckers.
I'll fight of this and he just fucking
leave.
Hilarious.
Anyway,
Jew a Jew.
You ever have a great day to kill
herself?
No sugar.
I put that fucking helmet granted
permitted you fucking Dick.
You should kill yourself the first time
and when you get to your destination,
killing yourself once you get up to
heaven.
I'm not forgiving me.
Are All your ex girl still alive?
But there is.
Well,
I was going to bring it up.
It was like one girl that I knew.
She didn't kill herself.
Well she kinda did,
but it was with drugs,
but she wasn't ever a girlfriend.
She was a girl.
I knew when I was young.
Then I hung out with her again.
We were like adults,
but not much.
You know,
we would,
we'd talk on the phone every now and
again.
She was fucked up.
She was,
uh,
some,
some form of opiates and I don't know
the whole story,
but uh,
she was sweet girl.
It was a real bummer.
Is there,
was really depressing when you hear
about shit like that,
it's like,
Ooh,
that's so depressing.
It's so depressing when someone just
can't keep a hold on it or just gets
caught up in a spell and then their life
just slips away.
I know more than,
I mean more than I like a lot.
I know quite a few people have a real
problem with those God damn pills.
Especially those pills.
They're so fucking available,
Joey.
They,
they'll stare so available that given
you hurt your,
you got a boo boo.
You got a booboo here,
man.
Become a fucking angel.
Take this.
Go into Lala land.
Melt into your pillow and float away in
a cloud of love.
Go ahead and old g going to have to get
off that.
If you want your life and they give
these people these pills and you tell
them,
hey man,
you got a few weeks off of work,
you know you hurt your back,
had to get surgery and you'll start
popping these fuckers watching TV and
next thing you know,
Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo.
That's your life.
Your life is at.
I'm fucking sharp.
You know sharp has goddamn super
athlete.
Brendan charms is big,
giant gorilla,
UFC fighter.
Pretty straight edge dude.
Pretty clean cut dude.
Four months in,
he's taking these fucking pills and his
friends have to tell him like,
dude,
you got to stop.
His friends had to take his pills from
them.
They fucking get you,
dude.
Yeah,
I know a girl that's going through it.
She buys a Vicodin and like,
like,
uh,
I was talking to dealers.
Yeah,
she has.
She gets Viking in any downer.
And then,
uh,
it's weird because then she can't sleep
at night.
So it's her all pilled up just talking
like online and on periscope and you're
just like,
what the fuck?
It's weird watching strangers on
periscope also.
Just,
you know,
late night.
Hello for somebody tells himself on
periscope.
I think it's already probably happened,
right?
No,
it's crazy.
I had a girlfriend in the eighth grade.
I really dug.
I met her.
She was a cheerleader.
Pretty cute.
This is fucked up.
And uh,
Irish chick,
just red hair.
I just dug know we'd hold hands and eat
a slice of pizza after the basketball
game with,
at the movies we may be swaps,
but one day we're talking about dry
humping or whatever the fuck we're
doing.
We went back to her house.
I never forget this.
I was dating like maybe two or three
months just on the weekend.
And I'd walked down and you didn't city
and when they asked,
I said,
what time your parents got on?
She goes,
something like that gets home at five
and my mom is dead.
And I was like 12 or 13,
Joan.
My head almost exploded.
I was like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
She's like,
when my mom died at childbirth,
you know,
and I was like,
I couldn't even make out with her.
I felt I couldn't do anything.
I was just,
I just remember going home and going,
I can't see this girl.
Wow,
what the fuck,
how come you couldn't just thought and
had never entered my mind.
So it was just too sad.
It was too.
It was mind boggling,
like not having a mom.
So I called her up one day and I stopped
dating her and I started dating the
southern Irish chicken.
I never thought about or again,
you know,
I know she was mad and then uh,
my mother died and I was like,
that's the first person I thought it was
this poor girl.
Like I knew what she fucking felt like.
No,
I never,
I could never imagine that pain when I
was dating him,
when she told me like,
what are you fucking talking about?
Your mom dies.
My fucking mom dies.
That's the worst thing I've had.
I think one of my girlfriends died,
one of the girls I dated earlier on
about two years
ago.
I'm still friends with her brother.
We didn't really date.
We messed around a little bit.
She was fucking crazy and she ended up
dying from pills and booze.
Nobody really know Joe.
We started off with guns.
No,
we went to 10 times before they asked
me.
One of my girlfriends killed himself.
So it's,
you know,
it's weird when people that you really
care about aren't there anymore.
It's a weird thing because they just
vanish.
They just don't exist anymore.
And it's a sadness that is just so.
It's,
it's so forever,
you know.
I mean,
my friend Johnny is a,
who was my best friend for a long time.
It's a great guy.
Fucking loved that dude.
Couldn't wait to see him.
Every time I go to the east coast we'd
hang out,
flew them up here and now when I flew
them up here,
he was detoxing.
Same thing pills.
He was,
he's the oxys and he was into um,
he was in heroine,
like strong shit,
you know,
he liked strong opiates towards the end
and it took a few days for him to get
off of it and then then we can go around
and hang out.
Was just at my house,
just sweating for like four or five
days.
And when he died,
man,
I remember thinking like,
I can't believe I'll never talk to that
dude again.
I can't believe.
Like he was like,
there's one of the things about johnny
is like,
he had this real clear view.
What the fuck is going on?
A key he was,
he had him.
His life might have been chaotic as far
as drugs,
but he knew exactly what everybody was
up to.
He knew he just knew he was a very smart
dude.
Very good at reading people.
And you could see like,
he's like looking around.
Shit.
When I met you,
that was the first thing that I noticed
when I met,
when I met you.
It's like there's all these people that
were scared of you who was so weird.
There was all these people that were
like nervous around you.
You know,
they felt like joey did.
He's a bad guy.
Like this is like late nineties or
whatever it was when we first met.
And I was like,
you're out of your fucking mind.
Like,
this guy's great,
you,
you seem to me to be a lot like him and
the only to you and are the only two
real original humans I've ever met or I
can't.
I don't know anybody else like you and I
didn't know anybody else like him.
Just completely original characters.
There was one of the first things that I
really liked about you because we met
like,
what was it,
like 95 or some shit.
Like what was it [inaudible] 97 after
school that was still on Newsradio
radio.
So it was only saw that when spent two
years into news radio and I'm having
those kinds of friends.
Whose phone was that you were showing?
How dare you?
It's uh,
it's,
you know,
friends like that.
So important in your life,
friends who need people to clear you up
from time to time.
That's why I call home every morning I
got or five different guys
that whenever I talk to,
I talked to them and everything gets
nice and smooth that,
you know,
every one of the other.
And right now it's really weird because
now I have two friends that haven't
spoken to in 20 years.
When I went on the,
on the land to Sarasota,
that kid hit me up on an email.
He goes,
I need to talk to you.
And Him and I,
when I went back to New Jersey,
he,
one of those kids,
he was in San Fran.
So you know what there is to do with
Sarasota,
1982.
Not so when I went down and he was all
excited.
He's got a partner,
you know the thing about him is he was
shooting fucking becker and his biceps.
I mean seriously,
he was shooting them in his shoulder
caps and his traps.
He was,
he was gone.
You know what I'm saying?
She was just a balloon and he was
eating.
He was eating,
what's the German five milligram?
The shit that just puts,
not testosterone that decade.
The problem that he was eating at really
shit,
we're guaranteed the game.
Not but people.
Debo,
it's Diana and Diana.
This is 1982 people.
So if you want to look like a fucking.
So everything on him,
he was popping those Diana balls,
he was supposed to eat three a day.
He was eating like a,
the debt.
He was eating a double prescription
bottle and then blast and off the
fucking shit and is for.
I mean it was huge.
I love them though.
I got them.
So when I left,
he always got mad at me.
He called me man.
He hit me up on an email,
my website,
read all them back.
What's up dog?
It took me a couple of days when I'm
like,
I don't want to hear this shit.
And he goes,
Hey man,
my dad died.
And he goes,
I got tell taste something.
I think about you every day because I
can't imagine how you Ama shit at 16.
Then my other buddy,
his mom died about a month ago.
I sent flowers and he keeps calling me
every morning going dog,
I don't know how to fuck you did it at
16.
I got the most respect for you in the
world.
It's like now I'm paying them back.
Wow.
For them taking care of me when I was
younger,
it turned around.
I missed my dead bodies,
Bro.
I had misread that crazy dude.
The bodybuilder that was fucking,
uh,
you know,
we would take them to bars and we'd get
on top of the fucking stage and Po's who
goes to a butler,
he didn't give a fuck.
And I take them to the UFC bar going up
there.
But this is the guy that you told me
that it was doing a line was mother's
Danny beat different guy.
This is a line in front of his mother
while I was on the phone or his mother
shot steroids in his ass while he was
doing.
He's talking about in the fall at the
same time.
This is brilliant.
Tell me that wouldn't be like one of the
muscle area scenes and we've talked
about it.
He comes to my shows.
Danny comes to my shows.
He still falls into the podcast.
That guy,
he just put a picture of him on twitter,
dressed in flux and full army Gallia
with like fucking five generals behind
them.
Him Nineteen years old.
He was a soldier of the year in the
army.
That's why he was doing this,
this,
and this at the same time,
because he could do that.
That's how crazy he was a soldier of the
year.
They would do an exercise
and fucking Beirut and four guys were in
a rap.
The rap tip over the saved all forming.
It made them the soldier,
the fucking.
He went to the White House.
Two years later they discharged him and
he was selling blow on the fucking
fucking crazy is that they dishonorably
discharged them for running a gambling
operation and the fucking North
Carolina,
wherever they were stationed.
But this other.
Oh,
sorry.
Keep going.
I know this other kid that I showed you,
the crazy one that he won,
like Mr New Jersey.
Darrin.
I miss him every morning and he was the
guy that died young from steroids.
Uh,
he died from everything.
He had everything.
He had hepatitis C.
Oh Jesus.
Sharon needles A.
Well,
he was already shooting in highschool by
wally button by something by March of
82.
He was already coming to my house when I
talked to your doctor.
Talk to him,
man.
I think that's the first person who
ever,
ever sat me down and he's like,
listen,
let me tell you what,
and he was coked out.
We were doing coke and it was like a
secret inside his heart because I have
to tell you something,
man.
He took off his shirt and he started
doing pushups.
Like somebody just starts doing 50 push
ups in front of like,
what the fuck's going on?
He got up and started flexing.
I'm like,
what are you doing?
And he goes,
I go to this person's house and they
were gay and 82,
these two guys were gay,
but he grew up with them and he remained
friends with diamond.
He didn't care.
They were gay.
Nobody knew.
So they were Shannon and vitamin B
shots.
Who is Sharon?
Oh,
deca no good ever comes out of.
We were sharing a needle,
but nobody,
nobody.
Nobody.
Nobody fucking knew.
That's like,
you know,
listen man,
when you're that level of a guy and that
type of gym situation,
think about you and I have never been
that guy,
but they're guys that,
you know how people smoke a joint in
rocky the other day.
I'm watching the beginning of rock.
He goes to the corner,
that's 18 guys sharing a wine bottle and
he takes the wine bottle,
takes a sip of it.
I'm thinking to myself,
that's fucking the flute,
but in those days and those days you had
to do that to be part of a guy.
You in a gym,
you all yoked up.
You have five foot 10 year 240 pounds.
Read best shoots.
Deca Redmond for me to flip you and just
take it from them and stick it in my
game,
but I could see it.
Yeah,
I could see it.
That's the bond you on the street with.
These were living in skid row with
thieves.
You were me.
Everything we take,
we split down the middle.
What you think's going to happen after a
year,
so we'll go fucking clint eastwood
movies with the Indians.
They would cut their hands,
the hands put together.
My brothers,
I could see two guys shooting needle me
and you were not in that world and red
band were like,
oh,
you know,
but to some guy,
bullshit dude,
what's the guy that said let's do the in
person.
My favorite impersonation you'd do,
or the guy in Boston he gives you night,
night time with the jet.
Remember like I'm blessed in his se,
this guy,
you know,
oh,
Joe Lake,
my left,
my left.
This might night.
That dude in high school that was doing
steroids.
He was enormous.
He was so much bigger than everybody
else.
It was crazy.
He came from another school when we were
like,
I think I was a,
I guess I was a freshman and he was
like,
he came in as a sophomore because like a
year older than me and he was with these
crazy stretchmarks.
We're talking about a 16 year old kids,
17 year old kid,
massive stretch marks all over his chest
with these watermelon,
tits.
He just had watermelon.
Tits are giant,
giant arms.
I mean literally the guy would walk his,
his arms like,
you know,
guys fake that this is a really how he
stood.
He was massively muscular and he went to
a party one night in college.
There was these college kids at some
college kid's mouth off to him.
He knocked out three college kids.
It was like a bowl.
He would just charge at people and
punched up.
He was so juiced up.
He was always angry.
Like everywhere you,
if you like,
looked at him like you want it to be
like real nice to them.
It was like being around a crazy,
like frothing at the mouth gorilla.
Then I saw him years and years later,
like not that many years.
Like I was like 21,
so he was probably like 22 and he
weighed 160 pounds.
I was like,
what the fuck happened?
What happened?
I just got off the stuff.
He just got off of it and his body
became like a normal size,
but you lose all your fluid or you lose
your muscle also.
But he was never.
He's a weird guy.
Like he didn't have big hands,
he wasn't like some earnie shavers dude
or go or like a,
you know,
it's just a big like you are your big
fucking thick guy.
He wasn't.
Yeah,
that's smaller hands.
It was just,
it was all steroids.
He just taken this thing and changed it.
Like the amount of muscle that his body
would carry around.
It's just way more.
It was real weird.
I didn't know what the fuck he was doing
until after I was out of high school.
I had no idea what was going on.
I just thought he was just a big,
strong guy.
I wasn't in weight lifting.
I didn't play football and in taekwondo
we,
we didn't do any weight lifting like,
no,
we did like some calisthenics,
but there was no weight lifting at all.
So I didn't no idea like what the fuck
was going on with the student body.
But seeing him when I was 21 and seeing
him like just like this deflate it
person.
I was like,
this is the weirdest shit I've ever seen
in my life.
But back then,
no one knew what the fuck it was.
We're talking about like 1988.
It was when I was 21.
I didn't know what that meant.
I didn't understand how he got smaller,
like it didn't make any sense to me.
Like I didn't know anybody that was a
bodybuilder or anything,
so it was just weird.
It was just weird to see them small.
And then as I got older and started
talking to people,
especially when I was working at,
um,
that was working at Gold's gym or a
nautilus plus,
that's,
it was nautilus plus
in revere.
And I knew this dude in there who was a,
he was a bodybuilder and he kind of
schooled me on some of it.
I go because he was huge and I go,
do you take steroids?
And he goes,
dude,
fucking look at me.
And what do you think?
Of course I fucking take steroids.
He was the first guy I ever met that was
like super open about it.
He had these like he would wear like
those daisy duke short back then
bodybuilders or were those daisy duke
shorts.
And this kid had these fucking giant
tanned legs.
They were enormous Tangela.
He was fucking you.
I hope that look comes back.
Male daisy dukes.
It's not even coming back for girls.
So over.
Do you think there is certain clothes
like that that will never come back?
Like bottoms bell bottoms?
I could see bell,
but they tried.
They tried,
but people realize it's stupid looking.
I rocked him.
Yeah.
You know what?
It worked back when people had long
collars.
See that's the difference.
If you want to have those long collars
that they had in the sixties,
you know,
like those,
those crazy jackets that you see like
Jefferson starship in those.
And then you had platforms.
People were wearing platform shoes.
Remember those.
So like those all worked with the bell
bottom.
Right?
But you get to like flip flops and bell
bottoms,
flip flops and it gets annoying.
You're stepping on your bell bottoms.
That goofy,
that getting away.
He needs stilts.
You know what's really sad about juicing
that people that juice for a.
What do you call it?
Aesthetics.
Not because they're athletic.
Yes.
The further look,
it always ends up very bad because I was
around them.
I grew up around it.
It becomes instead of snorting coke and
drinking,
they go to steroids like that,
like the wrestler was on and there's
warrants,
Wesley and he goes to cop.
Did you see when he caught.
I didn't see that movie.
Okay.
This apart.
When he comes to the gym,
he's copping fucking shit that they gave
Nazis,
like you know that guy,
the ball that and you could tell it's
like $2,000
bucks.
And he goes,
what do you got right now?
500,
because you're giving me a restaurant.
It was a bag.
If you know that world,
you know that for him,
that's a six week supply.
That's a year supply.
Then when he has his heart attack in the
movie,
the doctor tells him,
he goes,
Bro,
fuck you,
put in your body.
Are you fucking kidding me?
It's a slow death because it becomes an
addiction.
I saw it.
I saw it go from once every six weeks to
four cycles a year to fuck.
I ain't getting off it,
but fuck it.
I'm going to have a super stack.
They call it stacking.
When the next thing you know you're
taking fucking for things and you're not
competing.
You're just going to a bar on Friday
nights.
I never got that in my head.
I never got that and it always ends bad.
You see those guys a year later,
they have a heart attack.
They get deflated,
something happens and they go to prison
and then they can do.
When they come and you ask them what the
tattoos or fucked up now it's always
ends bad.
Yeah.
I knew a guy who.
Yes,
it always and people,
you know,
I watched that documentary and eye
contact.
We contact with each other by talking
the Sterrad one that doesn't harm you
and I believe you're stronger.
Faster.
Yeah,
I believe that,
but I also believed that.
I saw,
you know,
you look at these guys down to the
Jersey shore,
right?
You look at these guys in New Jersey,
still got that little bicep or then they
got time to go to the gym.
They do six curls.
They threw a fucking man of all that go.
Suntan.
They rubbed number fucking SPF number
two and that's the result you get and
they do sit ups.
That's exactly what they do and they do
diamond pushups and they blogged for the
summer and then they like it,
but I'm telling you I was part of that
crew.
My friends.
I remember the chatter driving back from
the shore on Sundays out.
They couldn't wait to get home because
it was the second respite until it was
going to be the biggest thing.
I'm thinking of going home,
taking a shower and going out because
I'm huge,
huge.
It's Sunday,
it's my second one.
The second day,
Sunday you're the biggest.
So these guys on the way home to my off
day,
I'm going to get some pussy tonight.
My veins look at my bicep and just
driving fucking hilarious.
It becomes something else.
I think it's like.
I think it's like alcohol,
like you could drink alcohol,
you could just have a capital,
a beer at night.
You could have a couple of glasses of
wine with dinner or you can be that
motherfucker that just gets hammered all
day,
every day,
and we all know that person.
We all have met a bunch of those people.
Some people just get addicted to shit
day drinkers.
You,
Oh man,
there's a lot of those out there.
And especially in the entertainment
business and then we can do whatever the
fuck you want and nobody can tell you
what to do.
Nobody tells you what to do.
That's why you're on periscope all day.
It's also people that I think that,
that did cocaine,
right?
That,
that,
that have an addiction to cocaine drink
all day because they can,
even their filed supposedly some people
that,
uh,
Duke,
you know,
I've never done it,
but the people that have done like,
a lot of it will tell you that they
always want to have something to calm
them down afterwards.
Take the edge off of it.
I didn't snow in the daytime.
I wasn't a fucking vampire.
I started at night.
It would fuck my whole day up if I even
did the line sometimes.
See,
I wanted to have the coke ready at 8:00,
but sometimes I got a phone,
I'd have the 60 bucks early in the
daytime and I'd shoot over a fucking
slob.
I go over there and take the 60,
have to hide it in my jacket.
I have to sit there for four hours,
just coconut,
my jacket calling me and they have to
know.
So I would do a little bump and then get
paranoid and jerk off and fuck up my
timing at Nih.
That would fuck up my whole day so I
wouldn't do it in the daytime.
I was always a nighttime guy,
so if you didn't cook during the day
would fuck up your set.
Everything.
It fucked up everything.
The rest of my day,
my,
my timing because my,
my soul wasn't intact with my central
nervous system.
They were apart.
Now it's a part when you do blow and you
go on stage.
That's why I never understood that
concept.
It always made me laugh when people go,
oh,
you funny,
because you do coke and go on stage.
Okay,
okay.
You fucking dummy.
I freeze up.
I freeze up,
I can't talk to people and I did blow.
That's why I went to my room and hit the
fucking turn the phone off.
You think I did that because I couldn't
talk to people.
I don't know what the fuck you're
talking about.
Isn't coke make you talk though?
It doesn't work.
That doesn't want to started when it
started.
You're chatty.
Kathy.
You want to talk to everybody and shit
yet.
But let me tell you something.
I started doing coke like in the
eighties and I got on stage and 91 for
the first time and in [inaudible] 92 I
got on stage with the guys from dendrite
to the St Patty's show and right there
was the first time I discovered cocaine
in the stage at the boulder broker.
I did two bumps and tried to go onstage
and be cute.
That shit didn't work.
I thought Richard Pryor,
Richard Pryor did coke and what I'm
saying.
So I tried it.
It didn't work.
That was put to anybody known to do coke
and go and stand.
Fuck yeah.
I think a lot of people do token and
then Miami I would do the first two
shows were sober,
but the third show it takes a book that
coke in my pocket for enough is enough.
Enough is announced deal before the
third show because I didn't know it work
because you'll have a tyra tyra,
but I didn't care.
They knew I was coked up.
Wow.
So they knew the people who were coked
up new and they loved it.
Oh,
look at him.
He's got an.
I thought it was cute too,
so I went back to my room and got fucked
up.
But no it doesn't.
It never clicked to me.
Don't.
There's a motherfuck and go on state red
band.
You Miss Friday night.
I know.
I heard about this Friday night how I
fucking almost had a nervous breakdown.
He was.
Remember when you and your wife were
asking me questions and I was
physically.
I was having a nervous breakdown.
Right,
because you think I'm fucking with you
guys though.
I don't know.
Friday night.
I bombed so hard last week.
You know,
sometimes you get a transition pair and
you've got all these bits that aren't
ready and you bring them up and it's
like you got three of them,
so you bomb for two weeks,
but all of a sudden one night they all
come together.
Now you become a force.
Now it's a different game.
I was in that process for like two
weeks.
I was in limbo.
I had good sets in Boston,
but anything I tried out of the ordinary
in Boston wasn't clicking for me,
so I just stuck to the original.
And then I came back to the comedy
store.
I ain't shit somewhere on Monday night
and I went to the academy store,
Thursday opened up,
but then suicide joke that didn't take
me very far.
And then the second time I told him the
story about my friend who tried to
commit suicide,
she failed and she wanted to the store
and she bought a gram of coke from Chile
and as we were doing it I said,
you know,
how did you get out of the crazy house?
You try to kill you.
So three days ago,
and there was a big.
Graham was one big line.
She did the whole thing.
She looked at me and she goes,
I ain't crazy.
They let me out.
That was it.
I told that story of that one.
Got some last minute.
I in your rate and their main room and I
just died.
I had a file deleted.
I just died.
I just died a slow death.
I was trying new stuff.
I wasn't going nowhere.
I wanted to talk about trump and I just
died.
So Friday I went to the store and I
swear to God guys,
I didn't eat nothing.
All that smoke some pot I worked at.
I went to the y,
I did chest and the other thing,
I smoked dope before I left the house.
It was a little brown.
Seventy Milligram Brownie.
I had like maybe 13 cops left for the
day.
I was fucking started this little.
He is right there.
It was a half a pack of an attic.
He edible.
They give you two brownies each.
Each.
Each Brownie is 70 milligrams.
That's so crazy.
Scary.
I rub my balls.
There's 70 milligrams,
you understand me?
Seventy milligrams or uncle Joe.
He was like an that,
but it's like an Aperitif,
so even supplies to the rest of the
world.
Seventy milligrams of put you into a
fucking hole.
You know,
I gave him a 500 last night.
He split split,
split,
split thousand milligram.
A book chain song down at all.
Oh my God.
Listen to me though.
We split it at 3:00
in the afternoon.
Oh my God.
What are you trying to prove?
Like 7:00.
I was so flattered by 8:00.
And you know,
usually when you eat your that animal.
Fuck No,
this turned on me.
Annabelle turn savage.
He beat me into submission.
At one point I had the cheese doodles
that belongs to the baby pirate's booty
on the floor.
They were just coming out of my face.
I was just stuffing,
stuffing pirate's booty and my face and
a pair.
There was a bunch of fruit and pirate's
booty.
I couldn't stop.
I kept beating the beaches and pirate's
booty,
pirate's booty,
cantaloupe and pirate's booty.
I must state the whole baby.
My wife was like,
well,
because I had my turn to them so they
couldn't see me.
My wife's like,
what the fuck are you doing it in?
Listen,
I got to go to bed.
She goes to bed already.
I went to 45.
I slept up for.
I got up.
I didn't know where I was.
Thirty minutes,
like Mad Max.
I just laid there four in the morning
and 30.
I woke up with a of energy energy.
I wanted to show.
I washed the car and went for breakfast.
I want to wash the car.
My wife had to have a butler tar stains.
Oh my God.
I was fucked up and I kept calling Lee
and certainly if the cubs Koi don't
answer the phone,
he goes,
well I haven't camps on the court and I
got on,
but.
So again though,
you ate too much at the comedy last
night?
No,
last night I didn't have anxiety guys.
Santi,
70 milligrams a dick in my world.
Okay.
I go down Laurel Canyon.
I right.
I go to the corner store.
I pull up no drama.
I get upstairs.
I don't even go upstairs because I know
the room was packed.
I can't go upstairs,
so I'm alone at the comedy store.
I go into the original pack,
I walk around a little bit like going to
the vip patio and I just sit there so to
to listen to music.
Some black dude was smoking a joint.
I mind my business.
I look straight ahead.
I'm thinking about more material.
I'm going to say how I bombed.
It's just whipping me now and I'm
starting to get scared.
I'm like,
Jeff comes over to me.
He goes,
Joey,
go onstage.
I walk over as I walk up the stairs.
It's a soul.
That room,
Megan Mooney,
Morgan Morgan Murphys up on fucking.
She was and she was texting her right
now and she was fucking killing right?
She's killing Megan.
Moved from whatever fucking lame is.
Murphy brought the dog.
Um,
she was freaking me out and then she's
killing on stage.
I walk up to the first landing guys and
it hits me.
It's like,
oh my God,
I'm getting anxiety attacks on 70
milligrams.
Not,
not.
This can't be happening to me.
This ain't happening.
And all of a sudden I'm standing there
and it's getting worse.
Guys,
it's getting worse now.
There's one seat,
open up the whole comedy store,
Mitsis Chair.
I sit in there for about a minute.
She's got the blue light on,
the pressure's on.
I got water in my hand.
I get back up and it's getting worse.
Guys.
I turned around,
I looked down to where the payphone used
to be and now I'm getting the anxiety I
get when I'm getting the needle,
which means I'm going down.
So I got to look for day light for air.
I know this,
I'll look for air,
but I know if I go down those stairs,
if she calls my name and I come back up
those stairs,
I'm really gonna have an anxiety attack.
So I go to the corner and I just started
looking at the wall and I start
breathing through my nose and some guy
comes up,
he's like,
Hey Joey,
how are you doing man?
What's going on?
I go,
nothing like keep looking at the wall.
And then he gets to hit the walkaway.
Then some other guy pops out and he's
like,
Hey Joey,
I'm friends with such and such.
He goes,
do you know where he is?
I don't give a fuck.
What did you see me staring at a fucking
walk.
The Jeff comes up to me and I go,
Jeff,
hold on one second,
Jen.
I'm going to faint.
I got a really bad anxiety attack.
I'm going down here.
Tell Pauli to go on stage,
and Jeff also wants to ask me questions.
He's like,
dude,
do you know if Paul,
he's going to go up on stage.
I don't give a fuck.
He's the closest person we put in stage.
She's about to call my name and all of a
sudden he goes,
well,
let me go ask.
I'm gonna fucking go ask him a fuck.
I'm about to fucking faint and now
you're going to do this to me.
So he walks over to Paul and he starts
asking Paul and Paul,
he's like,
and now they're getting into like a
conversation about it.
Instead of Poli going,
he's got an anxiety attack.
Let me go up there.
I'm watching this go down.
I get so angered.
I go,
fuck it guys.
I'm like,
who the fuck knows what he said?
Instead of going just red
bank,
go up,
go up red band.
I got anxiety.
You Go,
okay,
Joey,
and I'm worried about you letting you.
Okay.
Yeah.
Was Go,
no,
these guys are having a conversation.
Bureaucracy.
I got so fucking angry.
Then I go,
fuck you guys.
I'm going to go up.
And I went up there,
Joe Rogan to set up my life off of fear.
I think I caught myself at the 14
minutes.
I was like,
Oh man,
I just yell.
Did you record it?
No.
Why would I do something like that?
You have a fucking retard.
I fucking went up there and just draw
and no,
you know,
you never hear me talking like this.
It was all unfair and I remember walking
out of there,
man,
I got in that car and Paul,
he goes,
man,
you shouldn't have anxiety attacks more
often than shit.
And I was like,
man,
I was fucking dying.
I like how you have Mitsis voice when
you do the impression of the same voice
you do any.
Do Mitzi?
Like all this shit?
Sure.
Share one.
Joey Diaz,
voice Joe.
Have you ever had that where you were
like either to stoners so you just
didn't feel good and you're about to go
on stage and you almost couldn't.
You almost don't think you could have
done it?
No,
I know what you're saying.
I've never gotten it,
but I don't.
I don't.
I won't take that kind of,
but before I go on stage,
I've fucked up and gotten too high
before I went onstage,
but never so high where I'm like,
I can't do this.
I can't do that.
I'm having an anxiety attack.
No,
but I've been hired and that hasn't
happened to me.
Sometimes it just catches you in time,
especially if you have a rough set.
If you had a rough set the night before,
if you're working on some new stuff and
it doesn't go over right,
you can't recover.
I mean,
we've all been there.
If you haven't been there,
it's just because you haven't taken
enough chances.
I've been there all the time.
It's like those moments after that are
shaky,
like you know,
it's a shaky one or two days,
you know,
sometimes sometimes it's not.
Sometimes it makes sense and there's a
reason you could just get right back
into it,
but sometimes there's like a little
shaky period.
So the shaky period,
that's 70 milligrams was enough to whack
you.
You did to seventies once.
The other 70 was from a couple of nights
just for the general public 70.
We'll fucking send you down a tornado of
despair to the bottom Pitsa your soul
just to,
just to know,
don't try to do what he's doing.
Like I won't.
I don't fuck around man with anything
more than like 30.
Do you think that that,
that even matters what it is though?
Really?
I do think it's that accurate where 70
is even ballpark 70 or maybe he just got
something that had 600 in because it was
like the bottom of the barrel.
Well you certainly can,
you know that bit.
I do a bit about the guys who make that
stuff.
Yeah.
It hasn't gotten any better.
Like Colorado,
they have it down to a science,
they're doing an in Colorado,
the way they would make regular cookies,
like if you buy like some,
you know,
like Nabisco chips a whole or some shit
like that.
They do them like a factory.
There's not much difference between the
way they're making some of these
cookies.
They have these big machines and they
have all these people working there.
It's
pretty fucking down to a science.
They're not just throw,
throwing their own ingredients in home,
cooking,
all this stuff.
They're making a lot of money.
They had this like I'm one of those news
report shows.
Forget which one was it?
Sixty minutes.
They went to Denver and they
participated.
They got high,
they got high and fucking Limo with
these people and they,
uh,
they went around to all these different
places and watch these people make these
things,
that plate.
There's a revolution going on in Denver.
Like it's so off the charts there,
it's so crazy there.
They'll like you watching this thing on
television.
It just starts to sink in.
Like they're changing the whole culture
around that town.
Like the whole culture is going to
slowly chill out.
They're violent.
Crime rate is so low now.
They're fucking drunk.
Driving rates are the lowest they've
ever had.
It's nuts.
It's changing everything.
And it's only been a year to like how
many years has it been since it's been
legal?
What's the official?
It'll be two years.
Is it going to Jamie?
If I find out when,
when the,
uh,
the law went through,
but in Oregon they're going to have
lead.
We tax free.
Oregon's taking it to a totally new
level,
but Washington just a,
I just saw a red or a part that
Washington it had like I think
$70,000,000
their first year of tax revenue.
So that seems like a lot of money just
to,
that's a lot throw away.
But I agree with you.
I think the,
the taxes that the,
uh,
the Colorado and poses which are really
high,
I think those are great.
Yeah,
I agree.
Because it's still better than going
drinking if you go drinking.
Okay.
If we have a few drinks,
like if I go and get us around and all
four of us went out drinking and I look
at this kids shots and a beer and that's
like 100 bucks right all together.
Then you got to tip the guy that like
200 bucks for the weed.
Jesus Christ,
we the four of us with 200 bucks,
whether we'd,
we'd be fucked for a month and we could
take home.
So yeah,
$200.
That's a lot of weed.
Especially if you're buying edibles.
Oh my God.
You could almost die on $200 worth of
weed edibles.
I mean if you ate them all.
What's happening last year?
Beginning of last year.
So they 2012 voted at the end of 2012
and started at the beginning of 2014.
Well,
oh I see,
I see.
So there's a,
there's a delay.
That is one of the,
I gotta be honest with you that as one
of the funnest four days you'll have as
a comic is,
oh Denver is.
Especially if you stayed down because
you eat at Sam's that motherfucking
Green Chili for breakfast with those two
weeks or some wheat toast.
A bowl of fruit.
God.
Oh my God.
What're you going to talk about?
The crowds?
No,
you got the weed store.
Then you've got the comedy world.
I mean it's like a three.
It's like you can't lose for three days
ago.
The gym you cannot lose.
It's a triple fuckin head of the with
little weed store.
They got the.
They go out on the recreational side.
They have some strong stuff.
But yeah,
that's a great
spot.
It's a great little weeds.
One of my favorite places.
One of the few places I would live
besides here.
I'll tell you what,
you made me laugh because I thought
about something,
right?
Band,
you know what pill when I was growing
up,
had a lot of mistakes with them.
What pill?
Like if they made 100 of them,
10 of them would always be quite loose.
Really kind of,
um,
we're always done what they done because
it was corruption.
No,
it would dodge because the guy who was
making him his,
his flaw was lopsided.
You know what I'm saying?
You put them in the oven.
Who the fuck knows Joe Rogan?
I don't fucking know.
He was lopsided right now.
This table chemicals go down to the bike
for every hundred.
The most ridiculous idea.
Pills ever.
Let's just say the power goes to this
side,
so you need 10 biscuits and nothing
would happen and people would go,
oh my God,
I got a dud.
That means the next one's gonna be good.
That was a philosophy around the.
But that's a different philosophy to it.
What if cosby gave one of those guides
to one of his freaks?
Just see.
Yes.
Yeah,
and it was a big black dick waiting on
them pills to heather and shit and
that's a great bit.
That's it.
Do you
think that he could get laid?
He could have probably almost any of the
girls he wanted to drug anyways.
Probably.
Why do you think he did that?
It's positive.
It's part of is free.
I mean we could speculate all day long,
but obviously he's sick,
right?
Obviously,
but we kind of knew that anyway,
it's not the new sick to the extent that
he is,
but he's got this like creepy arrogance
about him and uh,
you know,
we played that clip once,
or Wanda Sykes who was like the sweetest
person in the world was interviewing him
and,
and the way she was talking to him,
I guess he didn't like it.
So he corrected her.
He corrected her,
you know her,
her use of ebonics or what have you,
Rod Mcqueen,
kind of just not a nice guy,
just not a nice guy.
And he was wearing sunglasses.
Like he's just,
you know,
when you're indoors you're wearing
sunglasses,
like unless you've got glaucoma,
what the fuck you doing?
Like what are you doing?
Why do you have sunglasses on?
Unless you're black,
you get away with floyd mayweather,
you with sunglasses or whatever the fuck
he wants as far as I'm concerned.
He can wear sunglasses anywhere he
wants,
but you know,
it's like those.
Anyone who does that,
like,
you know what I mean?
It's just weird because I could see
where it looked like a normal person
would drug it to cut,
just to get laid.
It just seems like,
you know,
he built fucking cosby creep.
Did he like the girl just being passed
out like it's dry.
He likes dry sex or something.
He might.
He might like to be the God.
He might like to be totally in control
of their life.
It might like the idea that,
that he tricked them and they now they
to do his bidding while they're
completely unconscious.
I don't know how unconscious they are.
Maybe they're in like a halfway dream
land where he could talk to them and
doing stuff,
you know,
like lift your legs up and they'll just
do it and they just don't remember it.
It might just be so fucked.
I don't understand.
I talked to you gentlemen,
this four of us in this room.
We're all men here.
I may use,
have had an experience.
I mean maybe fucking red bed homies,
event experience where you brought a
woman to your room and nothing happened.
Looked me in the eye and tell me the
truth.
Gentleman,
it happened.
Okay,
so if that's what,
let's just with four gentlemen here,
I'll just be on the show.
We're at 80 percent.
If you bring a woman to your hotel room,
eight out of 10 times,
you're going to fuck her.
Guys told me the truth.
We just guys,
it depends.
Probably read bad.
You're a nice guy to bring them over to
get high and they get naked feeding,
but those,
those netplus talking about,
you know,
you're a nice guy.
I have some time.
You know what happens entirely on the
individual.
The intent when you're a guy like bill
cosby,
he's a superstar,
multi,
multimillion dollar women.
They've got to go to his room without
sucking his dick.
Let's be honest.
Not a whole lot of them.
All of them.
I've got to go into that room.
Whether that married or that half of
those bitches got a different story
also.
Okay.
He drugged you because you were alone
with him in a fucking room.
He had plans.
I'm not blaming them,
but when joe were men here were met.
You know when you go into a hotel room
or his trailer,
you know what the fuck,
so he had to put a pill into your thing.
He's a dirty mother Fucker,
let's get that out of the way because he
enjoys that faint woman,
that woman that's half dead and that's
what he his.
That's his freak.
Some people still bodies from cemetery.
Some people want to get jerked off with
their feet.
That was his.
I had a friend who was after a while I
was doing and he said they were jerking
off his feet because he was scared of
the hip,
so he just happened to jerk him off of
his feet.
Their feet with their feet.
Yeah,
I wouldn't do that either.
That's just as worse.
Hooker feet.
So we'll hook a dirty concrete and
sperm.
That shit don't mix,
but let's face it,
he,
he took those women to his room and he
has a real interesting take on this.
He had a real good taking this and there
was another guy that got charged for.
It was like cee Lo Green guy was giving
girls ecstasy or something like that.
Yes.
Grandma's getting molly and Eddie was
talking about like what it must be like
to be like a really famous guy who's
really rich but you're also like maybe
not the most attractive guy in the
world,
you know,
so like maybe some of them they want to
get to know you,
but then when you want them to like be
sexually attracted to you,
it doesn't happen.
And so if you're a creep you start
drugging them and that's what Eddie was
proposing.
Who's saying like maybe like he just got
tired of them saying no and he thought
he was better than them and just dropped
it in.
I forget exactly the words but I hadn't
considered it like that.
I hadn't thought about it like that.
Like maybe maybe they're not all saying
yes.
I mean maybe it is a weird thing with
them where it got really frustrating and
then he just decided to do it or is it
possible?
That may be.
This was like a much more prevalent and
accepted thing in the circles that he
was running in the 19 sixties.
Is it possible that people like you
would talk about people giving people a
Mickey or he did a joke about Spanish
fly that Spanish fly Joe,
is it possible that more people were
doing this back then and we're just
finding out about it now?
I don't know because I mean they
slipping the Mickey thing was totally.
I mean,
and the Spanish fly thing was almost
common like people talked about like on
the tonight show.
I think bill cosby talked about it like,
you know,
and it seemed like it was more accepted,
but I was,
it they weren't aware was it like,
but I don't know anybody who got like in
the sixties or seventies who got a
mickey slipped into them.
It's like,
why was that such a common expression?
Charles Bronson never did it.
James Colbert never did it.
Steve Mcqueen never did it.
Fucking burt reynolds never did it.
Can you,
uh,
do me a favor.
I wanted to show Joe Rogan.
Can you get me the beginning of the
longest show?
And I want to show Joe Rogan how much
times have changed.
You know what it is?
It's really dark.
There's something really dark about it,
like you can imagine like what is just
what is,
what's,
what's going on,
what is his essence?
You know,
what is his soul?
He's doing that.
Was there a movie that made it look sexy
back in that day?
Like a James Bond,
like,
oh,
I got some Spanish fly that seems like.
I remember there was,
you know what,
there was a movie though,
animal house where he had to decide
whether or not to do the right thing or
the wrong thing.
Remember the black on the show has the
angel was saying,
Hey,
you know,
she's blacked out devils.
Like fuck her,
suck her tits fucker.
And,
and you know,
he couldn't figure out what to do.
Like you could,
you probably couldn't even do that movie
today,
but as a joke,
you can't mean.
It's one thing if this was.
You can obviously have a horrific rape
scene if it's like a drama,
right?
But if it's a comedy and you're joking
around about right,
you can't have that.
No one will accept that.
The last rape scene that made you
uncomfortable for use with movies,
just always rape scenes that make you
uncomfortable,
but what I'm saying is that you couldn't
have a joke about potentially raping
girl,
like Animal House,
like you could have.
You could have a horrible scene in a
realistic show,
but we're the devils on your shoulder
and a gone fuck her.
Fuck her.
Like,
whoa.
Like that's A.
I don't think you could do that today.
We'll watch this for a second.
Jamie,
did you find it's in the.
It's in the opening scene from the
original longest.
It's watch this.
You're going to die.
You're going to say they could not do
this in the fucking movie at the time.
Yeah.
Let us get.
This is the original log.
Original longest yard firsthand and long
as you are is so fucking off color,
but it could not be done today.
I will.
We just watched it by mistake one day
and we're like,
oh my God.
That's fucking bad.
Really.
I never listen.
I ran in those circles.
I'm gonna.
Look you guys in the face.
I never heard of people spike and girls.
That would not be acceptable.
I came from.
Don't get me wrong.
I've gotten checked coked up to the
gills to suck my Dick.
Right.
But they're awaiting that.
Margaret and I had the tension.
You know what I'm saying?
I felt bad the next day,
but they did the blow.
You do the devil.
You got to drink the side of.
You know what I'm saying?
This is.
This is just crank it.
Yes.
Bastard.
This is terrible.
I watched this dog.
I told you not to touch my goddamn car.
You can't do that today.
This terrible.
Dude.
This is so bad.
This is 1973.
I can't believe how bad it is.
Tricky in the garden.
That's what people did back then.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Chewing gum.
Smile in chewing gum up.
Drinking.
What kind of shit boxes he driving
though?
That's it.
Alrighty.
In 1973.
That's what a Maserati lights.
You just said don't touch my.
Isn't that funny?
That that could be like a cool car and
the cops are now coming after him while
he's drinking.
It throws in the backseat.
This is Berlin and the god of his life.
He's out running the cops with his
Maserati here.
This is hilarious.
They're in a go kart race.
A car is such a shit box.
Look at it that had that car.
That's your dad had that?
I think so.
I think he had an old one.
Giant,
big goofy American cars chasing it.
These cars handle so bad.
God damn good.
Chasing the best.
This is so ridiculous.
Well timed by Jesus.
God damn price you'd call the car chase.
The car chases in those days was so
tough.
When you see that movie with Mcqueen and
they chasing them in San Francisco.
That Mustang.
Oh,
you fucking that.
That was so much tougher to drive that
car.
Oh yeah.
That shit.
Now today it's easy.
This is when you had to be a fucking
monster.
Know these cars are dog shit.
Like,
look how skinny his tires are.
You see how skinny those tires are.
There's like no traction on those
fucking things.
Mechanical Grip is nothing.
This guy,
oh my goodness.
This bad mother fucker.
Terrorists shit up in this country.
Seven.
This is before Cannibal run,
right?
Yeah.
This was when he was still.
I liked how savage got the trunk
magically closed fist now.
Now he still listened to the same songs.
I don't care.
He don't eat.
He hit.
He hit rewind and track.
Look at the cigarettes.
He smokes too.
He ain't fuck.
This was him.
Okay.
This is a different America.
This was him against Clint Eastwood
Against Charles Bronson Against James
Coburn.
You had to do this crazy type shit.
Smacked bitches and shit together to
drive this car often in the shop because
he doesn't want them to catch him.
Don't you understand Brian?
Yeah,
but how did he put the gas back then?
The coast cars with dog shit.
You can just fucking forward button it
goes to the car while he goes to the bar
and the cops come in and he's sitting
there fucking habit and then like step
away from the ball and the little guy
goes,
why did you throw up car on the ocean?
Because it needed a carwash.
Jamie put on the chase scene from
bullet.
I watched bullet this year.
I was up in Canada and it was on tv,
but you got to sit there and go,
what the fuck were they thinking?
I watched it from the beginning to the
end.
It was full of Steve McQueen cop movie
in San Francisco and they have a crazy
scene with the 68 Mustang where McQueen
is chasing this guy.
This guy's chasing him and a dodge
charger.
Oh,
it's one of the all time.
Great car scenes.
Look at this shit.
This guy's got this gigantic dodge
charger and he's got this dope 68
Mustang,
which for cars back then handled a
really God damn good.
I mean that was a lightweight car,
was a good amount of power,
but you know the drum brakes and shitty
suspension and so these guys are driving
around the corners in these bars.
Let's pull it back.
This was when you were a stock man.
This guy's in the hospital.
Fuck fate is.
That guy actually got thousand stitches
and
shit.
That's when you fucking were a stunt
man.
They didn't have pads or nothing.
You did it with wranglers on.
How much a Steve McQueen zone driving.
Did he do?
I don't know how much in the movie
because he's obviously doing some of it.
He could drive his asshole.
Yeah,
he could drive his ass.
He used to write the movie.
He played with this.
What was the name of them?
Let the mom.
He plays a great movie that I forgot all
about that movie.
A lump and it's another movie that there
for like 10 minutes.
Nobody says a word.
That's the thing about this chasing.
One of the craziest things about it is
how well orchestrated it is.
How cool it is.
Like that skinny ass bitch just would
not work for other people to walk out of
this movie.
Are they?
Would they have?
No,
not me,
but today the attention span for a big
time movie for sure.
People are used to these smash cuts and
they used to MTV style editing,
you know,
like music videos,
like the champions of like quick editing
at Eddie Bravo again.
Explain that to me.
He was talking to me about how they make
music videos.
Have you ever noticed they're constantly
switching angles.
Constantly changing the way it looks.
He goes,
you don't have a static image for like
60 seconds,
you know,
like someone's standing there.
He goes,
that's really rare.
Most of the time,
especially pop songs are constantly
trying to move the image around to keep
you interested in it.
But this movie like,
look,
we're watching this guy,
load shells knew his shotgun for like 20
seconds.
Fucking.
They set everything up in a different
way.
If the beginning of the mechanic,
that's not a word for the first fourth
pain minutes,
he just watches the guy and sets them
up.
Same thing.
You're sitting there going,
what's going on man?
Fuck it up that dodge charger.
Oh,
between this movie and the Dukes of
Hazzard,
more people fucked up.
Dodge chargers hurts my soul.
I watched the Dukes of hazzard and
watched that fucking car make a jump and
wants to frame bend and then they just
drive away just to.
And you know that the car that they
jumped with is not the car they're
driving with.
Where they put you put.
They put a kid on it,
correct.
Well,
you know,
they just got a bunch of them and they
just broke a bunch of them and they.
But they did have some fake ones too,
like some other cars with like a charger
body shell that they would sacrifice
Miami Vice.
All those scars were just kids.
Yeah.
Oh,
for those Ferrari's Johnson's was a kid
that was the fuck at Testa.
Rossa wasn't really.
It was a kid.
It wasn't a real test to Rosa.
No kidding.
Wow.
I've seen a Miata and somebody turned
into a Testarossa.
No,
not on me.
I'm sorry.
A fierro.
Remember those fieros Pontiac fieros my
sister had.
Was the trade in value on those was when
you brought those back there,
like 800 people would crack right there.
Like a statue.
I paid 8,000.
Oh Shit.
I forgot about that scene.
The guy loses the car and goes right
into the gas station and it blows up.
Oh,
he almost lost cars and muscle cars.
They still have them today.
I was looking in the back of a one of
those,
a hot rod magazines and they had this
kit car thing.
It was like not that much money either
for the kit and you put it together
yourself and you have to.
I think you have to put an engine in it.
You have to do the whole thing,
but some people actually do that.
They actually build their own cars.
For my first car when I was 15,
that was one of my options.
It was to get a army kit car where you
build your own arm to get the juice with
two other 50 bucks.
Yeah.
I'm pulling out a different frame,
but something crazy.
Yeah.
It was advertised in comic books.
I think there's a car thing.
It's called the noble,
I think it's called,
but it's a car.
I think it's from England and they ship
it over here.
It's this beautiful,
crazy looking sports car.
They ship it over here with no engine
and you have to get an engine put in it
so I can.
So it's not really.
I mean it's,
they don't consider it a car when you
buy it and that's how they could sell it
to you because it's not,
you know,
doesn't have all the.
It doesn't pass all the regulations that
you knew how to do that.
Is Maserati the Italian car?
Yes.
They had it when they were shipping cars
over in the seventies.
They had to take the edge inside and
shit.
So the mafia couldn't steal the cars.
Really?
Yeah.
They also,
when they sent the Italian shoes over
after a while they would just send cog
was right shoes and then goes with left
shoes because life that they wouldn't
get robbed.
That's hilarious.
Fucking hilarious.
They would rob the fucking fucking docs
or the Italian shoes?
Well,
the docs have always been known,
has been like one of the places for
organized crime,
right on the waterfront with Marlon
Brando,
my buddy Joe Lake,
we were talking about,
he was a teamster.
He was a longshoreman and you know,
long shoreman like that.
That whole world has always been
depicted in movies as being organized
crime headquarters.
They make down by the docks.
You know,
there's always like,
people like that,
you know,
that are like the rough hard tumble
travel alone dime.
You could buy jackets that comes off
those four.
I have a friend till this day I talked
to him yesterday.
Still drives cars off the ships.
That's true.
Those were 11.
Wow.
So the ships come in with like Honda's
and shit out 40 fucking dollars an hour
plus overtime drugs since he was in high
school.
Oh,
this is what I was going to ask you
earlier,
but I didn't want to interrupt your
story.
The reason why did they grow heroin in
other countries.
I don't even know if you know the answer
to this,
but they grow it in other countries
because they can't grow it here or did
they grow it in other countries because
it's not financially viable?
The poppy seed.
Well,
listen,
let me tell you something.
If I need a drug dealer,
could grow poppy seeds here and
eliminate the travel,
they would have done it,
but would they have what I'm saying?
What I'm thinking?
I could cut that cost out.
Eliminate that whole fucking journey.
I don't.
I think you need a lot of land.
I think it's one of those things that
would be really hard to do indoors
because I think it's something that they
do like when they make heroin,
you need a lot of land to make a smaller
amount of heroin than you would think.
Seed.
This comes from heroin,
comes from the poppy plant and I think
it's high out.
It's like coca leaves,
don't they grow cocoa?
Lucy,
are you fucking.
That's exactly the same question,
but I heard now that that's a big a
market now.
People important coca leaves people in
Beverly Hills now having coachella
parties,
which cigar will you choose and you
smoke a cigar and drink one and people
get fucked up.
That's the room at like $300 of leaf.
I don't know what the deal is.
I've never eaten no fucking leaves.
I would.
The people in the high altitude out
Peru,
they have bags of these things they take
with them.
It's really kind of freaky to watch and
they packed their mouths with it and
they.
They have like a squirrel size lump on
the side of their face and they just
chew these fucking chewing tobacco.
Only cocoa leaves except it's actually
kind of healthy for you.
It's not bad for x before you read the
good,
what was I?
There's a fucking new drug that you see
this.
This crocodile?
Yeah.
It's been awhile around for awhile.
What the fuck is this?
Where they take the lottery.
They processed it to something else.
They put two drugs in this.
That's a Lane and Red Sofa.
That should tell you right there.
That's not the drug for me.
Right or wrong.
When you put gasoline and then it eats
to skin.
Yeah,
it's causing some of this get you.
I think it starts out when they just
have like a little bit of like a bruise
area are fucked up area and then they,
they just get hooked on shooting it in
and they keep shooting in that spot.
It keeps getting worse and worse and
it's just not getting better.
And then it starts really going down the
hill and then they get super depressed
and they keep shooting in there.
I think it's a,
it's a real bad drug,
real dangerous,
scary drug.
And apparently they're doing it when
they can't get heroin,
you know,
that's,
that's how a lot of it got started where
I read online.
But uh,
the images of their.
Correct.
It fills a real images of people's
bones.
Poked out of their schedule.
Yeah.
That really is true.
That's a spooky as fuck.
Like when your bones are exposed,
you got a problem.
It's a problem.
It's a real problem.
I used to cope with a guy that while he
was talking to you,
he'd have to get the straw and then put
like a paperclip and his nose because
the skin had collapsed,
so we had to pick the skin up,
put the dollar in there,
and then Snowden,
oh my God,
and this was navy.
I can't.
Now he's missing this.
Knows like he ain't even breathe and eat
fucking five.
Last time I spelled it with that guy and
they would have to pick up the wall from
Jamie.
Find out why they don't grow cocaine.
The United States.
Imagine that Shit.
Someone on the message where it says it
takes an acre of coca leaves to make a
kilo so that you need like slave labor
to collect process.
That does make some sense.
Some brother,
they could do it here.
They would have done it trust.
They had the financing,
they've had the fucking money and that's
something they could have hit it back
then,
right?
No,
they can't do it.
There's a reason why they can't do it
here.
It's about the out the to this.
Something in the soil is some reason
both of those things,
if not some drug dealer with a high and
a chemist and said,
bring it over.
Some Chinese guy,
okay.
With tons of loot where they got another
genius Chinese guy 30 years ago and
said,
teach us how to grow this shit in Jersey
and that's it.
It would have eliminated everything,
but there's some reason why,
you know,
you just can't.
They made synthetic heroin yet,
but you need that Chinese white shit on
this coast.
They have the Mexican that thought that
Shit,
you just shoot and you smoke.
But on the east coast,
that's that white powders with suburban
kids.
Like that's what the models get hooked
on because it's two bunks and you're
done.
You're done.
It's like,
well now they're making a pure of the
never.
It's,
it's,
you know,
because it's coming from Afghanistan
gum,
you know,
this,
next war.
This last war when this started after
nine slash 11,
this picked up heroin again.
It started coming in here again,
especially in the Detroit area.
Detroit is not as fucked up as it is
because you know,
it's fucked up.
It's because they just through heroin
and that I couldn't fucking handle it
man.
And the same thing happened in Newark.
New Jersey had happened in a couple
areas I know about because I have
friends that you and they'd tell you
this and you're like,
hmm,
that's interesting that this happened
after nine slash 11.
Wow.
So,
well,
I mean the production,
the heroine has gone through.
The roof in Africa was done through the
roof now and there's all sorts of
reasons why they have excuses why they
let them do it or why it's happening or
why,
you know,
the,
the army helps them.
So pills or at their all time,
highest and heroines at their all time.
Highest.
Or were they making the pills from,
do they need actual heroin to make those
pills?
Do they need poppy seeds that need
something to a poppies to some of it is
probably something.
It's probably all synthetic.
Right?
But what does that mean though?
Like what,
where are they getting the compounds to
put it together?
Like what is it?
Where did it come from?
And they have to have like a raw version
of something that turns into heroin.
Right?
I mean when you say synthetic,
it's not like you press a three d
printer and heroin comes out.
You have to.
There has to be things that they like a
lot of pharmaceuticals we think of them
as pharmaceuticals,
but a lot of them they're actually
getting some of the chemicals from
plants,
you know,
that's one of the reasons why they mind
the rain forest.
They're always looking for different
plants that they can exploit and they
can make pharmaceutical drugs out of.
It's kind of like A.
I remember when I was a Hippie,
lot of people had synthetic pod and I
don't know what that even means,
but I think they just took the
compounds,
whatever makes you know,
a real pot and just recreate in our
somehow.
It's like,
isn't it like ingredients?
Well there was a store that I read about
Coca Cola,
[inaudible],
Coca Cola uses real coca leaves.
Real coke is still today.
Still today.
They use real coca leaves and they don't
have cocaine anymore.
What they do is they get these coca
leaves and they bring them to this
medical cocaine supplying and they take
the coke out,
sell that to New Jersey,
exact company in New Jersey and they put
it into pills.
They put it into medicine.
You're right.
So that's all coming from coca
leaves,
which is really crazy.
Like you wouldn't have thought that you
would have thought that like synthetic
cocaine or line of can or whatever the
fuck it is they're using,
which whatever versions of medical grade
cocaine they use,
he would've thought somehow know that
that's coming from chemicals.
That's what we would think.
It's synthetic.
We always like to say shit like that,
but what does that mean?
Like there's got to be like Ra compounds
that are used to make this stuff.
Where are those coming from?
It's coming from the origin.
I think synthetic means they take some
of the origin and they put other shit
and get the matching.
They make it cheaper for you.
You know?
It's like when you go to the store now
and you go,
hi,
I'm here to pick up my medication.
They go,
well we have to ask you a question and
you want the original oxycotton or the
Melecan,
which is the same only made in
Switzerland,
but instead of $80,
the prescription is $28,000.
Right.
So I shouldn't say synthetic heroin.
Synthetic opiates.
Where do synthetic opiates come from?
The rived from opium.
Well,
there's a bunch that are derived from
opium.
Wow.
That's fucking bloody list.
Morphine,
codeine,
heroin,
t bain and or have been.
Huh?
I didn't know
coding,
heroin,
heroin and morphine.
How similar are they?
Right.
It's like the same.
Really.
That's what I've heard.
I mean I don't use them obviously,
but that I've heard that's true that
I've done heroin.
Gay Cousin.
I was on a morphine drip when I go to
the operated on my first time.
It was amazing.
Oh my God.
I kept hitting that button.
He hit the button whenever you want.
This is like 1993.
They didn't regulate you,
so I was lying in this bed.
My knee was killing me and I hit that
button and it would be like Nyquil,
like taking Nyquil,
like clip clip.
That's probably what heroin.
So [inaudible].
It's pretty sweet.
Let's do it.
So I've done it.
So there you go.
I've done heroin.
I didn't even think I did,
but then I remembered that uh,
that one night that I had to stay in the
hospital and um,
I had my acl reconstructed.
That's where they,
they had me there and I was done with a
patellar tendon graft.
That's how they did it back then.
There was a good way to do it.
Sometimes they still do it that way
today,
but they're taking a chunk of bone off
my knee and a chunk of bone off my shin
and a sliver of my patella tendon.
And then they open you up like a fish
screw this piece of meat and use the
bone piece that they cut out of the Shin
and the bone piece that they cut out of
the a kneecap and then they reconstruct
the knee and it hurts like a
motherfucker.
Dude.
Woo.
It's like,
like,
like lightning bolts shooting when
whenever you cut into bone and drills.
Like it's the one.
The other one that I had done,
I had done with the cadaver,
like way easier.
I mean,
I mean like almost nothing.
Like I went to uh,
you know,
Matt Lichtenberg,
I went to his birthday party five days
after the operation just walked.
It was fine.
Like,
I,
you know,
I had a brace on it.
I didn't want to hurt myself,
but I didn't need crutches.
I could get around like it's totally
different than the Patella tendon graft.
Your leg blows up like a fucking blue,
but I'm lying in bed and they have me on
this continuous motion machine.
From the moment you come into the
operating room,
they put you on a deal.
They don't want your leg to stiffen up
because then it's really hard to get to
get moving again.
You know,
once you,
once you get really rigid,
you know the trauma sets in and it's
really difficult to straighten your leg
out.
So right away they have you on this
thing.
It's like boom,
boom,
boom.
So not only you in agony but your leg is
on this continuum machine.
More morphine is commonly related to his
morphine sulfate.
Heroin is diacetyl morphine that is,
heroin is simply morphine with an asset
whole molecule attach a subtle,
subtle,
more molecule attached.
So it's basically same shit.
It just is.
So it does it faster.
Yeah.
In terms of the effects,
they are exactly the same and medically
interchangeable except for the dosage.
In fact,
they're both converted to the same form
of morphine when they get into the body.
Fascinating.
Thank you.
Yeah,
it's all this.
You know,
when,
when you had surgery I had given you
heroin.
Isn't that amazing?
Given your age,
different forum.
It's not the street level,
but it's a form of what you're getting
this tremendous.
Who doesn't like that?
Uh,
my friend's mom had a cancer and uh,
she went through all the channels and
she was on her way out and she decided
to go out on her own by taking all and
morphine just said,
look,
what a beautiful way to do it.
Just do it.
Like this.
Just took it all,
you know,
they were giving her something for pain
and I guess she had enough to stop the
thicker and she just says enough.
I was just like,
I'm wasting away you.
She goes,
there's no hope.
Like it's over.
Like her body was.
It was over.
It was like the last few days.
But that's how she decided to do it.
You got to respect that,
you know,
like the fact that that's illegal,
I know it would be abused.
I know it could be abused by people that
want to kill people.
You know,
all my mom wanted to go,
you know,
you could,
you could run into those types of people
that would actually kill family member
to get some money from the will kill a
wife,
you know,
those,
those kinds of things.
But I think that still for someone who's
dying,
man,
for your,
your mom or something like that,
when it's the last days and you got to
watch her just in agony constantly with
no light at the end of the tunnel,
you know,
she's 90 years old or whatever the hell
she is like fuck man.
Like you,
you gotta have a heart man.
That shit should be legal.
You should be able to do that.
And in some places it is,
right?
It's legal in Oregon,
like there was at one girl that was
trying to um,
do that change.
Moved to Oregon.
Did she do it?
Yeah,
she ended up delaying it a couple days
and then she and she did it.
It's crazy shit man.
I think you gotta be there to really
make a decision on that.
It's just some people get tired of
fighting,
you know,
you get tired or you get weary from the
illness just draining you.
And then the chemotherapy drains you
sometimes even further.
And it's hard,
you know,
the last days,
what's amazing is how many people
benefit from cbd for marijuana and how
few people are getting it.
You know,
the more I read about this and the more
I talk to people that have had it and
talk to people that have loved ones that
have tried it on cancer and had
incredible results can be.
It just drives me nuts.
It's just so hard to believe that that
stuff's still demonized,
that people are still pretending that
it's one of the worst things that
society can make legal where for just if
it only did that with cancer,
forget about the getting high part.
If it only did that for cancer,
do you know how magical that drug would
it be?
It's like it's got this creepy passed.
It's like a,
a stripper that wrote the most amazing
book,
but nobody wants to listen to it because
she used to be a stripper.
It's got like marijuana has this like
seedy part to it and that CD part keeps
people from recognizing the textile use
the uses as a commodity they use for
making houses they use for food.
Like if it was just all those things and
didn't get people high,
it would be our all time favorite plant.
It would be the number one plant in the
world.
We would be using it all the time.
They say that this hempcrete.
Have you ever heard of him?
Crete.
Concrete they make with him.
It's supposed to be like,
well,
some of the most durable,
lightweight fire resistant insulation.
It's,
it's,
it's great insulated properties,
insulation properties and it's made out
of hemp and you can make it cheap.
You know,
it doesn't,
doesn't cost a lot of money to grow
hemp.
They just can't grow it.
Like in that you can't even get high
from this shit.
I mean,
it's really crazy if you stopped and
thought about it,
if it was a plot in a movie,
if there was something that was as
powerful as the marijuana plant,
it was something that had so many
benefits and it was somehow another kept
illegal and somehow none of the
propaganda kept people thinking that it
would be one of the worst things for
society.
If they were to make this legal,
you would lose your fucking mind.
You would.
You would go to this movie stupid like
this movie is dumb.
People would riot.
They wouldn't do it,
and come on,
you got something that cures epilepsy in
kids.
Little kids that have epilepsy.
Have you seen any different?
Fucking kids have benefited johnny
rotten.
Yeah.
Our buddy johnny,
his kid was having all sorts of
seizures.
He moves up to Seattle.
It gets them on the medical marijuana
program.
Boom goes away.
It goes away.
It gets 100 times better and the kid
starts communicating,
changed his life,
change that kid's life.
Fuck man.
It's just weird.
It's one of the weirdest parts about
being alive in 2015 is that there's so
many improvements going on.
There's so much fascinating shit
happening in our culture and yet this
one thing,
it's like this hold out this clawing
thing that cleans to the sword.
It's not that.
It's the people's reaction that gets me
still like I'm the type of guy that,
you know what man?
I didn't eat Sushi till 1995,
but I came around,
you know,
when I was in New York,
fuck you raw fish.
You know what I'm saying?
Real fresh.
You know what the fuck?
But then one day I came around,
I never said I hated Sushi.
I just said it wasn't for me at the
time.
And you listen to a fucking moron like
governor Christie,
who just aggravates me.
It aggravates me that this guy is
running for president this fucking
years.
President fucking list is horrible.
Thank God I'm.
I'm happy I got felonies to vote like
these motherfuckers from the Cuban dude
to Christie will bad shape those
ridiculous.
A ridiculous,
ridiculous person.
He's so ridiculous.
Oh my God,
I cannot fight.
I'm so happy I don't live in Jersey,
man.
I'm so fucking happy,
but you know when he's so marked I just,
I can't imagine him ever and he's got
that whole bridge things gonna hold them
back so that he's not going to get
enough.
But what he will do in doing this as
raise his public profile and maybe he's
pretty good at debating.
He's pretty good at talking and maybe if
he has these conversations in front of
America,
you know,
the way he's been having them in New
Jersey,
maybe in a big public forum like
presidential debates,
it can be kind of interesting.
Could be interesting to hear him talk
because he as Moronica as he is,
he still a very good talker.
You know,
he gets,
I,
I disagree with a lot of the shit that
he says,
but I got to respect the fact that the
guy knows how to communicate sometimes.
That's all you need in this goofy ass
world.
Somebody writes you a good juicy script.
You have a bunch of people behind you.
They give you a little makeover.
They tried to do that with them.
They got them on that fucking belly
band,
but somehow or another it didn't work
like he still big.
Right.
I mean he did get on that.
Find out if he did that because that's
ridiculous.
It is.
The way I look at it,
I grew up in northern New Jersey.
I grew up in politicians home and I know
that to be a politician in New Jersey,
somewhere along the line you got to take
an envelope and when you're running for
president,
it's pretty tough to take an envelope
and people have to fuck them.
Raised their hand.
It's like Donald Trump when he raised
his hand,
I could not believe it.
Yeah,
just what he did in New York in the
eighties.
You know,
if that guy even moved.
What did he do in New York and in New
York in the eighties when he was
building all those things.
Hold onto when we do once the rant.
Start going,
don't pull it up.
When he went in the eighties when he was
doing all of that developing.
Okay.
He shut up like Rogan construction.
Rogan construction was started by you.
I'm just making a name.
Right.
Okay.
He rogan construction was a company
started by your grandpa.
No.
Work and his two brothers and then he
hired the sons and now they have 12 full
time employees and they've been putzing
along since 1948 doing new construction
houses and remodels,
but whatever they're keeping their
lights on and all of a sudden the GC
comes in who's a general contractor on
this job,
who somebody like fucking trump and he
hires people like Rogan construction and
a search electric and who?
God's fucking plumbing and got sucked my
dick concrete,
you know,
whatever the fuck the name of the
company is selling to make a teacher and
it would stiffen and all these companies
went out of business.
All that construction he did in New York
and New Jersey in the eighties was very
such bad.
Number two,
before he raised his hand,
I hope.
I hope that he's just intelligent.
Let me get that water.
My brother.
I'm sorry to fuck up your little.
I hope that he called the congressman or
governor or somebody in Colorado and he
said how barry this sammy the bull
gravano and he get the TMZ.
Can he get through a phone because all
those deals he had going on in the
eighties,
he was in bed with the Mafia.
It doesn't take a fucking genius to tell
you that.
Okay.
Just a dumpster.
The one that Johnny Reid Felon,
when he tried to commit suicide,
you know those dumpsters.
You guys see a square dumpster to get
one in Colorado in 1987 was $200 for the
day.
You know that same dumpster was in New
York in 1987.
Twenty $200.
That's how high the construction costs
were.
Some of it where the mafia attacks.
Well,
there was a lot of organized crime,
organized crime.
So somewhere along the line this trump
was embedded with organized crime.
Had to,
had to be the trump plaza in Atlantic
city.
Just look at the locations.
Doesn't take thought of this.
We started this.
I always knew this idiot did not.
Could not raise his fucking hand and if
anybody is smart,
go to the Sammy the bull book.
He talks about it.
Not so many ways really,
so I guaranteed the feds have their
files and as soon as this guy moves up a
little bit,
they're going to take a look at it.
It says a sammy the bull told us,
how can we take care of this?
A donation to the fucking a buffalo bull
company or fucking blind kids.
Whatever the fuck it takes.
Because this guy was the major
contractor in New York in the eighties.
All these small businesses,
he put their lights out.
You know how I know.
I'll tell you how I know for a fact when
I got locked up,
one of the conditions of me getting out
was I had to get a job to alleviate the
state of Colorado.
My attorney came up with this paper,
listen to if you let him out,
he'll leave next week.
Tomorrow.
We've got a plan for him.
As soon as he gets out of your fucking
jail,
we'll take them out of new job.
We'll get them back to New Jersey.
But to do all this,
I have a promise of employment and I
called around New Jersey and my friend's
uncle had a window door trim sash
company,
you know all this shit for your door,
that's a sash on the bottom by the way,
and trim around your door and the door
and and shades and they sold all that
stuff and they had like an 11 man crew,
like six guys on phones.
So he goes,
you want to go?
He made me send me the resume.
That guy's uncle and I called him.
We spoke on the phone and in fact I
wrote the guy while I was in prison back
and forth because he would tell me,
keep your head up.
You got a job when you get out,
don't be down on yourself.
When I got out of the,
into the halfway house,
I called him and I said,
hey man,
I got to sit in the halfway house but 90
days,
but I'll be in Jersey by June.
And he goes,
I don't think I got high.
We were working on this construction
company and we got stiffed.
It was that fucking guy trump.
We lost everything.
We had any investment really.
You know,
these were high rises.
You had to pay for all those windows and
he's only paid,
you know,
they might have got a deposit or
something from the GC,
but not enough.
They got stamped and then just put them
under.
Yeah.
But he would go onto,
like he would go to,
he was the top builder and he would go
to Joe Rogan construction and he would
put it all on your name.
So you went down to wow.
So he done all this.
He ruined fucking family businesses and
all of a sudden he has this short memory
when you run for president,
they look at you in a fucking a
microscope microscope and you know,
I don't know what happened with the
birth certificate and Obama's birth.
I never paid attention,
but he was born in Kenya.
This is something you cannot overlook
with this guy.
This guy's a prick.
He doesn't know any fucking this.
Well he was,
he was one of the guys that was going on
and on about Obama's birth certificate.
He was like one of the main guys,
first of all,
don't look,
just look at them as human beings.
Like when you hear them talk and you,
you kinda like what they stand for.
He's my favorite president ever.
Who Obama better than Clinton?
Yeah,
I think Clinton,
you know,
Clinton,
you had a lot of flavor and he did some
good stuff too.
But I think Obama has been the most.
Maybe it's just the times that we're in,
he's the most,
the most noticeable when it comes to
like spreading this like what I think is
like an improvement in the way people
think,
you know,
first of all by being black.
Second of all by supportive gay rights.
Really like blatant support.
Like where they turn the fucking White
House rainbow when it got passed.
I mean that's crazy shit man.
That's never existed before.
When you see,
when you saw that picture of the White
House being rainbow colored at night and
I was like,
this is nuts man.
That wouldn't happen with Nixon.
This is some shit that similar to the
fucking abolition of slavery.
It's similar.
I mean,
it's not as extreme a slavery,
it's not as extreme of trap.
That's so amazing.
I mean,
but it's similar in the way that it's
going to change the way people look at
gay people.
It's going to,
it might not be now,
it might not be the generation of our
parents.
It might not be the generation,
uh,
of our older brothers and sisters,
but it's going to be the generation of
our kids.
The generation of our kids is going to
understand that gay people.
It's just like being mad at people for
having red hair.
It's just who they are.
Like,
what do you give a fuck?
And if you give a fuck about that,
what else are you gonna come creep it
around about what are you going to fuck
with people about?
What is it you're going to fuck with
people about the way they're dressed?
They're going to fuck with people about
the way they talk.
Like what is it like leave people the
fuck alone.
And the more we do that,
the more we could
sort it all out and find out what is
really bothering us.
What's really bothering people was a lot
of what's bothering people as people
intruding on other people's lives and it
doesn't get any more inclusive than in
the fucking bedroom.
You're intruding on people's bedrooms.
You care if people want to get married,
if they love each other just because
they're two guys or two girls who gives
a fuck and if you do give a fuck Europe
problem,
you're a problem in this free world and
this is just one thing that you
ideologically attached yourself to and
it might be religious based and my who
knows what the fuck other shit you got
going on in your head.
You don't want people to do.
You know,
who knows what other weird kind of
sharia law shit you want to incorporate
in the society.
Who knows?
I don't know.
You think people shouldn't be able to
get married just because there are two
men or two women that's intolerable in
2015.
That's Archaic Shit and I think that is
one of the archaic things that's going
to slowly but surely start vanishing
from our world.
It's not.
Maybe not now.
There's still a lot of homophobia now,
but you know,
there's this woman from Brazil who's a,
did an interview,
um,
think it was Jessica on Drudge,
a MMA fighter,
and she was talking about how many
people in Brazil are homophobic in
comparison to United States.
And she's like,
it's really nice to see the United
States doing this and hopefully more
people in Brazil think this way too.
And he realized that a lot of Latin
American countries,
especially like you were talking about
Cuba,
you were talking to me the other night
about Cuba.
Russia chill.
Yeah.
Actually pass laws.
They passed laws against gay people.
Listen man,
this is,
uh,
something completely new to some people.
It doesn't affect me.
So it doesn't bother me.
I know.
Like I said it,
my joke on stage I lived next to
transgender is across the street.
Great.
But the gay girl with the dog,
I talked to him every bag,
goof around.
I go on fucking big Mike and Leslie,
you know,
I love him.
I don't give a fuck,
you know,
but there's some people were still
living in 19 fucking 17 man.
Yeah.
And those people are stuck in their own
fucking lunch.
So I just keep walking,
just keep walking.
What are you going to do?
And everyday they watched the longest
yard,
long for the days when you could smash a
chick's face against the wall.
I was explained to you the other day
that the most foremost community in Cuba
is the gay community.
I grew up with gay Cubans around me,
my mom,
my mom at the fucking bar.
What do you think?
Buckle keeps the lights on.
White dudes in the daytime.
Those gay fucks that come in and spend
it,
you know.
And in those days that were doing blow,
that was selling blow and I grew up
around them.
I never had any hatred or anything for
them.
But my stepfather,
he used from the other side of the cube.
Okay.
Where they can't be in a room with a gay
guy,
no hatred,
no whatever,
but they just can't be in the room that
manhood and not be in a room with a gay
guy.
You know?
And I get it.
Some Latin American countries is just.
But who are the biggest gay guys in the
world?
Fucking Lens.
They're the ones.
So
what do you think that is?
Do you think it's the whole thing?
What?
What is it like in Sicily?
On that island?
What would it be like in 1950?
The big gains.
Sicily to bang each other a lot.
I don't think so.
I don't fucking think so.
I think that's where the Catholics are,
but I think that you'd be.
I think that you would be fucking
totally against it.
I think northern Italy,
those hardheaded motherfuckers,
you can't tell those motherfuckers yo
friend or whatever the fuck they call
them.
Right.
But that's also where the Vatican is
like how ironic is that?
That doesn't make any sense because that
is the biggest gay sex organization.
But they don't want to know that they're
going to be one sale.
That pedophilia.
Okay.
The biggest pedal.
Nobody wants to know that.
Do they preach fuck each other or they
only fuck kids?
How does that work?
Who knows?
You've got to bring me down with that
book now and Shit.
But I'm just curious.
I didn't,
you know,
I,
I just know how it was when I was
growing up.
I know the Vatican owned the gay
bathhouse.
No,
the building the Vatican owns was home
to the biggest gay bathhouse in Italy.
That's crazy.
We should go play some synthetic heroin.
Yeah,
let me,
I'll pull up the story because it's
fucking ridiculous game.
Jamie Polish it up,
put it up on the big screen.
It's ridiculous.
They own their mean.
There's so blatant.
They've been doing this for so long,
you know,
like this,
this gigantic crazy cult that's running
the Catholic empire.
They've been in charge for so long,
wearing wizard costumes and sitting on
thrones and people.
So many people have bought into it that
look at this,
the Vatican pays the landlord to
Europe's biggest gay bath house,
and by the way I say this,
I went to Catholic school.
I'm allowed to say this shit.
Three landlord to.
They play landlord,
the Europe's biggest gay bath house.
The church paid $30,000,000
to acquire a building that houses a
senior cardinal and a huge gay sauna.
Wait a fucking minute.
They have a senior cardinal and a huge
gay sauna.
That's it.
That's his own private gay bath house.
The guy owns a bathhouse.
They paid 30 million.
First of all,
how crazy is it that the Vatican has 30
billion bucks to buy houses with like
they have so much money?
Look at that.
The 75 year old printer,
that church enjoys a 12 room apartment
on the first floor of the imposing
Palazzo at two via cod Duci just yards
from the ground floor entrance to the
steamy flesh pot.
He's.
He's above it,
smelling it.
There are 18 other Vatican apartments in
the block.
Many of wind,
which house priests,
Cardinal Ds,
who is seen as a social conservative
even by current standards of the church
hierarchy,
is no doubt horrified to learn of the
activities taking place a floor below.
My goodness,
I could not imagine it's apartment.
Mildly,
smells like buttholes mildly.
It's probably a tornado and it's
probably a black man.
One of those fucking car,
those trees hanging over your rear view.
That's a weekly bed light feature in
Bruno,
very overweight past two assaults who
dresses in the Catholic vestments
naturally is free to the music of his
clergyman remaining in a funk because I
got to do that.
I'm going to be the new blue.
No,
fuck it.
I'm going to slay some big.
Where the fuck he wants to expose body
and soul according to the Independent.
Barry Knight also features a buffet
because exposing one's body and soul
works up in appetite.
This is a hilarious article.
Isn't salon?
This article?
Who wrote this article?
It's very funny.
You know Joe Rogan?
You read Katie Mcdonough.
You're really funny.
After you go to Catholic school and
you're raised Catholic,
it's fucking.
It's fucking mind by like.
It's just like firecrackers when all
figurehead.
For some people it's like cosby was dope
bitches.
It was mind boggling from.
They grew up on cosby.
You said,
look at this fucking Jarrod guy.
Look at this fucking Jarret guy
somewhere.
The kids at the FBI,
you know,
I hope this isn't true,
but they arrested one guy like in the
organization,
right?
Did they just investigate jared or did
they have a suspicion?
It's his house.
I'm being investigated.
It just goodness separated his business
ties with subway.
Right?
He's got one of those little.
Well wait,
I didn't hear about this.
What happened to the subway guy?
Child porn investigation.
Yeah,
man.
What the hell?
Losing weight on keeps people all got a
creepy fucking freak and it comes out
eventually.
Just let it out before the fucking gets
out.
Just let it.
I love the little boys and fucking
bikini.
You know,
eating a subway sandwich.
Oh my God.
I sit there.
So do you think that like maybe he sent
it to jared and jared kept his mouth
shut.
Do you think jared was sending shit
back?
What do we.
TMZ is that asked me if you didn't have
a life.
If you didn't have a life,
you want to,
you want to yell.
You know,
when I first started hearing this shit
about the Catholic church,
I ignored it.
I was like,
this is crazy.
I've been.
I was a fucking.
I was one of those kids,
those kids that fucking help the priest
for a body six months.
I did that shit until I got thrown out
of that.
You know,
I,
I believe,
you know,
I gotta tell you man,
like when I get,
I get dark dot sometimes I'm about to go
to sleep.
I just get dark fucking thoughts and
just,
you know,
just from being around Buddhist in
Boulder,
I learned that they chant a lot.
And in other words,
a chant is not any different than a
prayer,
you know?
So sometimes I got a bad thought.
I'll say a fucking Lord's prayer,
man.
I'm old school.
You know what I'm saying?
So when I hear this shit,
it just does something to you just like.
But it's for some people it's like
getting punched in the stomach.
You trusted somebody.
It's like having a babysitter.
That Melissa Kitty,
you're numb for a week.
Man,
you're really you.
But this is our
whole fucking society.
Every three days we get dropped with
some that we go,
what the fuck?
How did this happen?
How did this fucking happen?
Yeah.
When things like this happen,
you always got to wonder like what sets
something like that off in someone's
brain?
Are they born with that?
Does it happen because someone does it
to them?
Does.
Is it a chemical imbalance?
Like what the fuck is it that makes
someone sexually attracted to kids?
What a bizarre thing to exist in nature.
You know the.
I mean,
it's almost like a suicide gene.
It's almost like,
like you like in having that,
like your,
your body is so weak,
your mind is so weak.
Everything is so off kilter.
You're trying to get yourself killed and
there's no better way to get yourself
killed in fucking someone's kids.
Like,
do you know any people?
You remember that video where the guy's
walking through the airport and uh,
he had molested.
He was a karate instructor and he had
molested some kids and this guy's a,
this.
One of the kid's dads waited for him in
the airport and as he walked by with the
cops,
walks up to his head,
boom,
blows his brains out,
just drops the gun on the ground.
In fact,
I got off by the way.
Did it?
Yeah,
you got it off.
You got to get off.
That's a great defense.
You lost your mind.
They abuse your child.
Yeah.
He got off.
He,
uh,
he didn't do any time.
He shot that guy right in the fucking
head in front of cops and then drop the
gun.
What state was that?
I don't remember.
I want to say it was in New York and
once it was in New York,
I forget.
It might not have been though.
It might've been somewhere else.
Just some things that if you get there
before the cops you would.
Yeah.
That's before the cops.
You fucking win this guy shot them in
front of the cops.
Lost my mind temporarily.
Temporarily and sand.
And the cops like fucking handcuffs from
going that a boy.
This is it right here.
Father shoots son.
Father shoots and kills a son's
kidnapper an airport.
Refer revenge.
So wait,
they're going to show him shit.
Oh yeah.
Oh No.
Yeah,
no.
He was just a.
He just couldn't take it man.
He got this guy away.
Look at this.
Boom.
And then he puts the gun away and then
he had a crazy hat on the cops hold them
down.
It was his son.
Man.
That's so good.
I mean,
it is right.
It's fucked up.
But it is.
I mean,
I'm not usually for this kind of shit,
but boom.
I mean that is about as.
I mean as far as like,
what's fair.
I'm for it.
I'm not against that.
You know,
you've been my friend for a long time.
I have a horrible,
horrible event.
It's in my blood.
You know,
you do.
When they went down to Cuba and they
tell the fucking Maya Lansky that they
tell the Jew that fucking they soul
rebels.
What does he say?
He goes,
these motherfuckers savages all their
lives.
They've been savages.
They always been savaged dog revenge
Jane.
And it's horrible.
And no
cop would stop me.
You're crazy.
I wish I would have hit somebody with a
car and go to the same jail.
I'm one of those motherfuckers like,
once I have it in my mind,
you're done.
It's in my blood.
That's what my whole life and movies,
outlaw Josey Wales,
that Jewish man on fire,
man on fire out there,
how bad he is,
which I missed that scene until a month
ago.
He talks that dude into shoot
themselves.
There's only two motherfuckers in the
movies that have done that.
Uh,
what's his name?
And my boy in silence of the lambs.
He talked to them motherfucking to hang
himself from the other cell.
That's right.
I remember a man because he talked me
into fucking swallow on his own fucking
thumb.
Merrick's was the guy who said throw ges
and people's face.
My friend Jon Tobin,
you should call me migs selling high
plains drifter was um,
that was when he was painting the town
red.
That was the one where they killed him
and he came back.
He came back and they put the shield on
so crazy Monday shooting the body and he
kept going down.
They thought he was a ghost when he was
a ghost,
a beat the to death with a whip.
And then he came back as Clint Eastwood.
He came back to boast and fuck that town
up.
It was a great movie.
That was a great movie at the time.
I remember seeing the first time I saw
high plains drifter,
I was like,
Holy Shit.
Yeah,
that was dope you had to throw.
That's what I'm talking about when you
see the machismo and burt reynolds.
It's because that motherfucker just
watched bullet and he goes,
wait a second.
Yeah,
I got out that motherfucker,
you know,
I got to put on this corduroy suit.
And then Charles Bronson came along and
he's got to outdo everybody because he's
ugly.
You know,
he was the baddest motherfucker ever.
If I'm going to watch a movie from that
era and uh,
like if I come home,
like say if I go to a hotel room,
hey,
you know,
you're bored.
You're like,
what's on TV?
And you turn it on and you get this,
you get excited.
You Go,
Oh shit.
You know,
you thought you're just going to be by
yourself watching some terrible movie.
And it turns out high plains drifters on
hbo or something like,
Fuck,
they don't even really show these on
Hbo.
Why?
Why can't they?
They have to show new shit all the time,
right?
There's a channel.
About a month ago,
they showed a not high plains drifter,
but the other one,
but you wanted with no commercials,
man.
That's the way you want.
You don't want these fucking things on
regular tv to watch these movies.
Joe Rogan.
Why?
Because it makes me fucking crazy.
These movies,
you find your why.
You're an American pro.
These movies where they made them in
Italy.
What we talking about when we came in,
it's time to put a strap.
It wouldn't live in this fucked up times
and you really.
You're.
You're anxious about this.
Lately I've got a wife and a kid that I
worry about and I don't know what I do.
I shoot the whole fight.
Be John Wick.
I told you I got to get one of those
gentleman wake during you that John Wick
the first 20 minutes or until he hooks
up with the check.
Once you've done put the checks.
That bothers me for awhile,
but then you click it down with 45
minutes left.
That is one of the best kick ass scenes
since Bruce Lee and enter the dragon.
You better check your watches.
That's 30 fucking years.
He cleans out.
He's using bullets as strikes and he's
shooting them up close and blowing their
fucking heads up is a bad ass.
And when you see that movie,
you know he trained with Keegan and
laugh.
He can fucking fuck them.
I'm anxious to go see him tomorrow to go
see.
Yeah.
Like on the way home,
I called my brother,
you're going to teach tomorrow.
I be there at 11:00.
That's it.
That's always say to each other.
I see 11:00.
He comes with an Indian Dude and heals
your body guy lasered down all by
energy.
Guy Looks at you and goes,
you show the Bob and you're like,
God damn it.
You know,
every week it's like a game of chess
with them really?
And he lays it down.
He does his Cherokee shit show that kind
of India.
He picks up the arm.
He touched a Cherokee thing.
He releases the Eagle,
got to it from your bud.
You Got to see the upload k and after
the Eagle is.
Yeah.
He shows.
Put an Indian.
He fucking wants nothing.
Nothing to guys and old rodeo clown dog.
He broke every bone in his body.
Oh my God.
So this guy adjusted a roofing and he
was like dog last week.
Some to do with them.
Met with a fucked up at.
The guy was there this weekend.
Clone fucking psychic Rodeo clown.
She's crushed the most thankless job.
It might be one of the most thankless
jobs ever.
Nobody gives up.
There's no.
Not One Lance Armstrong or the Rodeo
clowns.
You know what I mean?
It's like Ken Block.
It was like a famous driver,
right?
There's like a skateboarder's Tony Hawk.
You know,
there's one guy in each discipline.
Tiger Woods.
You know what I mean?
Everybody knows tiger woods is a golfer
who's the one rodeo clown.
Name one.
They get no respect.
It's probably one person that we've just
done now.
It's like a Mexican superhero or
something like that.
They don't really use rodeo clowns.
They have a mean in bullfighting mean
this like bull riding.
I'm pretty sure is an American
tradition,
is it?
I think so.
I think,
uh,
in Mexico obviously they have a lot of
bullfighting in Spain,
Spain,
they have a lot of bull fighting.
I guess that's where they got it from,
right?
They imported from Spain.
I'm open because that's what Mexican
Mexico is.
It's like the indigenous Americans that
came over when the Spanish came over,
they taught them Spanish and started
fucking them.
And that's a main Mexican.
That's why I get like Mexicans,
like Oscar de la Hoya,
you know,
who's like this beautiful looking,
European looking man,
like kind of fairly pale skin.
And then you'll get a Mexican,
like,
you know,
Juan Manwell Marquez was like much more
Mexican looking.
Inca Inca,
the darker skin and like the,
you know,
darker hair.
It's interesting,
man.
This is a,
the whole North American continent is
fucking fascinating.
It's fascinating to think that if you
came to this spot 400 years ago,
there'd be very few people here.
Very,
very,
very few.
A few nomadic tribes of native
Americans.
No cities,
no nothing.
Oh,
you think,
how interesting is this?
There was a ds on the boat with Columbus
under Valdez,
really Diaz on the boat with all the has
come from.
I didn't say that.
I didn't say Tetra Dad and they spell it
with a z and then one of the biggest
lieutenants in Sicilian history is the
as with a seat and then we just saw that
priests within.
That's a dance with a C,
Z,
and then you have the fucking lunatics
up in Stockman and then Mexican and I'm
sitting here in front of you and I'm
Cuba as can be.
That makes you think like the as the as
the and the as as a lieutenant and Diaz
was on the ship as an Italian Talon,
ds,
Italian as an Italian.
Valdez with Z.
my mother's side of the family's Valdez
and the darker than that and my father's
side is diaz from come away and they
came from Spain.
They speak,
but the thing that I've either faith,
they speak like Jaguar was like those
people.
So you have to think how to be as get
the Mexico.
How did this diaz get here and how the
Diaz with a z,
the Diaz would.
That's.
These are all very interesting things
that I look at.
You look at evolution.
We were talking about how they found
that fucking pull up the whale in
Wyoming,
but years ago we have no discussion on
the podcast.
You know,
this is things that have always baffled
me.
Like how come there's Nate Diaz and his
brother that Mexicans are not income
Mexicans too though,
right there,
the other Mexicans.
It came from somewhere else and he
robbed whatever.
So it's very interesting.
You know,
what's interesting to me,
I'm.
One of the things that's been getting me
lately is this water situation in
California.
It's pretty bad.
It's a three years going on four years
now.
And uh,
the drought is pretty ferocious.
Like they're,
um,
they're saying that California was used
29 percent less water last month.
So people are working to try to solve
it.
But what was occurring to me when I was
thinking about this as we know for a
fact that there's areas of the world
that used to be lush and then they
became desert,
like that's a that we know for a fact
about the Nile Valley,
like in Egypt where the pyramids used to
be where the where the pyramids are.
Rather before that 9,000
years ago,
they know there was like a rain forest
there and slowly over time shit just
changed and then there's not that much
rainfall and that could easily happen to
California.
But would we stay with everybody stay
here when they just keep pumping water
artificially into this spot or when
people go,
you know what?
This ain't working the same word.
We know how many fucking we got to move
on.
Like we've always had to all throughout
human history.
Whenever the climate
got bad people to get the fuck out of
there.
When the ice age was happening here,
no one was living in Canada.
No one was living in Canada during the
ice age because it was two miles thick
of ice and a lot of spots.
You wouldn't,
you weren't,
you weren't living on ice,
you're right,
you would find a way to get to a place
where it's not ice,
you know,
but all the places that were covered in
ice where there was a massive amount of
Canada,
so all when all that ice receded,
that's where we got the Great Lakes
from.
The Great Lakes are fucking puddles that
are melted glaciers.
I mean,
that's how fucking crazy this place was
just 10,000
years ago,
if we had a house and it was there.
You can't be stubborn when the ice
starts coming.
You can't say,
we're just going to keep chipping away
at that.
Over a year I get a certain point in
time.
You've got to realize,
okay,
there's two miles of ice and it's as big
as fucking Canada or half a Canada or
even a few states where those few states
are,
you can't live.
You gotta get Outta there.
You gotta get out of there.
And if that happens here,
we're so arrogant.
Our idea that we can control nature is
so arrogant.
No one considers leaving California like
everybody talks about like,
well,
California is California.
We got to do something about the
California water crisis with.
It never rains again because guess what?
That could happen if it doesn't rain,
but once or twice a year or 10 times a
year or 20 times a year,
there have been way crazier things than
a shift in our climate.
To the point where it rains zero,
that's totally possible.
It's totally possible.
If it's possible to rain one day a year,
it's possible to rein zero.
If it's possible to rein 10,
it's possible to rain one,
it's.
It can be horrific,
disastrous.
It's totally possible and it would be
normal.
It would be something that's happened
all throughout the world.
They know that like a lot of deserts
used to be like lush areas and then
somehow or another,
like for whatever reason things changed.
Things shifted.
You know,
and you can blame people you want.
I'm sure we have a lot to do with it.
I'm sure global warming that there's,
without a doubt as some element of human
civilization is a part of it is too many
scientists that believe it does.
There's gotta be some factor,
but even without that factor,
it's super possible.
That shit would change on its own.
It's,
it's,
it shifts.
We don't control when it rains,
it could fuckin shift.
It easily could shift and if you're in a
spot that sucks,
you got to make a decision.
You have to figure out what the fuck
you're going to do.
Good rains more in Phoenix.
It rains here.
Earrings in Phoenix a lot.
Actually.
I didn't know that in Ohio and in
Houston.
Look at Galveston.
It's raining so much that,
that they're shit water everywhere and
people are losing their sight because a,
it's overfilled.
All the sewage and stuff that you
haven't read about this site.
Yeah.
This,
uh,
this girl lost her sight just from being
in the water because the,
they tested the water is,
it's all shit water.
It's in Galveston and Houston and
they've had such bad flooding in the
past month.
It's been horrible.
Horrible.
God saw some of the photos back when we
worked at a stone.
I was there.
They were
thinking about that Sunday floods been.
That was two months ago.
No,
no,
no.
The last stop on the way back in the
west time.
I have to remember when they closed that
hotel.
We used to stay up.
Yeah,
they flooded.
That day was flooded up to the third
floor.
It was a time I was that.
I'm sorry.
The the comedy club was on West Grey
going down west style fecal matter water
advisories.
Oh my God.
Let me read that whole thing.
Fecal matter.
Water advisories issued for some
Galveston county beaches.
Fucking a man.
Shit in the water.
The girl who legal blindness.
Oh,
that's insane.
Damn fucking subway already.
Cut ties with Jarrod came up.
At least the UFC.
Waited three days and shit with John
Joseph.
These motherfuckers,
they think Bain is tough.
Fucking subway don't play.
They don't even give a fuck whether he's
guilty or not.
If even if he.
If jared didn't do anything but knew
about it,
if he knew the dude had child,
porn is still response.
What do you hold them up
was this is the article a woman loses
sight in one eye after a mud run,
a young woman went blind in one eye
within 24 hours after catching a flesh
eating bacteria during the blood run in
Dallas this month.
Uh,
because of all the flooding.
Oh God.
How do you flush it?
Just,
it says,
a woman said that debrief cut her eye,
allowing flesh eating bacteria to
destroy her cornea.
It just completely melted off my eye.
Oh
my God.
Fuck.
That's fucked up.
Do we just shit into the ocean?
How does that work?
Oh Shit.
More than a thousand runners get
diarrhea after Monday.
Event,
of course,
while you're definitely getting some
bacteria,
if you get a mouthful,
mud,
that's 100 percent.
You're not supposed to do that.
By the way.
You're not supposed to drink still
water.
You know you're lucky if that's all you
get.
You know you can get something way worse
than that gentile shit jumping in a
puddle of mud.
Stale,
you're wiping me is you got to fucking
jerk off.
At least the polar bears jump in the
ocean.
They jump at the fucking cold water back
on the empathy.
You want to jump in mud after you
fucking been running a Snellen,
whatever the fuck it been for a month.
God knows what's in that fucking mud.
I used to think of those polar bear
people were idiots.
Those people that would jump into the
water.
So you want it to freeze it.
Yeah.
And then you said,
God,
there aren't the something.
Ms Dot Johnson.
The ocean managed cold and does
something,
especially when it hits like your bones
for a minute.
When you come out of that,
you feel like a fucking knew man.
I've jumped into the fuck of Atlantic.
Is that where we're at?
And which one's cold here?
It was cold.
Oh my God.
When I used to jumping on board.
And Are we getting in Seattle?
That's fucking own.
Whether that's freezing,
that's when you feel a bulge in your
feet and shit,
but it's probably really good for you.
Yeah,
it is because this cryotherapy shit.
This stuff is my fucking body.
It's changing the way my body feels.
It's amazing how well it like cures.
Any like weird shit.
That's bugging you.
Inflammation back pains.
Back pains had been fucking with me
forever.
They just dissolve it.
You just do it all the time.
It's your body produces all these anti
inflammation responses to the cold
weather,
so that's probably what they were doing
when they were jumping in the ocean.
You get out of it and your body's like,
you just get this fucking charge.
When it gets hard real fast,
the pop side of that motherfucker like
yum.
Yum.
Has been served and Shit.
I'll never forget you saying any ex
girlfriends kill herself?
No.
They showed a part of you suck my Dick
in the eighties.
You should have killed yourself.
There's a girl on facebook that I
thought I saw one night.
The last time I saw this check was the
knife Faludi.
Doug flutie threw that touchdown.
This is winter of 83.
80 four maybe.
I saw at a bar dog this,
this,
and they called a lorry.
The Jack.
That song.
That Jack?
No,
Jack by ACDC.
She's got the Jack.
She's got the jacks.
Has something like a disease.
They didn't have the Jack.
She just didn't have a wet pussy so
they,
cause no,
they call the fairview New Jersey
because it was a dry hump.
These motherfuckers so sabic they will
give you nicknames for everything is
Jersey,
you know,
and I saw her out,
man.
I don't know what the fuck have we
started doing blow.
She was a babysitter for this family.
Louis Denato.
The guy was a freak.
We went over to their house and I saw
the deposit bag from the bar and I
robbed it and we got more blow and tower
room doing power and she's like,
guess what,
color my underwear.
I don't know if we get that.
She's like,
if you call it guest the Color Miranda,
well let's,
I'll take a more.
I'm like read.
She's like a green but fuck it.
Take them off.
And I saw on facebook and I'm like,
do you remember what happened that
night?
She's like,
no,
I go,
you don't want to fuck it.
No,
you wouldn't be here right now.
It'd be fucking killing yourself.
That's disgusting.
All that Shit's disgust.
Disgust.
You know,
with all these transgender talk I was
telling these motherfuckers on stays the
night that,
uh,
that chick show this a pussy in Las
Vegas.
There was a transgender.
Do you remember what you called it?
What did I call it?
Open
did,
it was tight and it looked like somebody
put a bomb in it with a decode was and
clean with that.
Remember when Doug and I were doing the
man shown,
we had that really beautiful.
We had two of them that were really
beautiful.
They were transgender.
You remember the one of them that was
preop and she,
uh,
she showed his dick to the or her deck
rather to the audience she showed his
dick.
That's what I just said.
But it's hard to say her deck,
you know what I'm saying?
Like I was treating her correctly by
calling her is she
and I got to the Dick.
I'm like,
she showed his dick.
But um,
she was beautiful.
So beautiful that she was walking up the
hill,
are driving up the hill,
you know,
by the.
We used to be the hyatt next to the
comments to her.
She was driving up that hill and Eddie
Bravo and I were coming down the hill.
We were walking and she was coming up
and Eddy looked at.
He goes,
God damn,
like,
and I go,
oh,
that's my friend.
I go,
she used to be a dude,
and he goes,
you know,
are you sure?
Are you fucking with me?
You fuck with me?
I go,
no,
no.
She was definitely used to be a dude and
then she said Hi.
And I said,
oh,
what's up?
How you doing?
Everything good,
but blah blah.
We talked and then we went down there
and he goes,
oh my God,
I can't believe they used to be a guy.
I can't believe it.
He was.
Now I'm so confused now.
I don't know.
I thought I would be able to tell.
I thought,
totally ideal spot one.
I'm like,
you can't spot her.
She's,
she's an inch inches dick.
She's as girly as it gets.
We should pitch that show where the
transgender set like normal guys with
they see if they guess it,
see what the reaction is.
The next day guys would get violent.
That's how Jenny Jones got canceled from
TV.
Don't you remember?
Shannon Jones had an episode where it
was like,
my secret crush in the guy had a secret
crush on this.
Uh,
this dude that he worked with and the
dude that he worked with had no idea
what the fuck was going on.
He was on the show and we're here to
tell you that someone has a secret crush
on you and the guy gets out may I
always,
you know,
he,
he got out there and he was like really
flamboyant.
And the guy got angry,
went over to his house and shot him,
fucking killed him.
And they just sweat to pull the plug.
We won't do it.
So it doesn't exist anymore.
Check that's already had the operation
side.
After they fucking suck.
Then you break it to them like with a
guard.
This guy comes out with a gun.
No,
they did it after the show was over.
The guy went to his house and killed.
He killed them.
I a couple of days,
but that's fine.
Listen.
Okay,
that's fine.
And somebody tells you,
you ain't leaving the house for a week,
dog.
This is what you do.
You film all the episodes in two days.
So if they die,
they die.
Fuck,
you already made your vague.
You gotta fucking 100 episodes in the
can.
Fuck him.
He's probably going to kill people.
That's no after I fucked that.
You sit them down and go,
how was your day?
It was great.
I'd never been with a woman.
So magical.
What did we tell you that I am?
It was really thick.
The Jack.
He just a dick back in the eighties on
the sunset strip and the guy just fried.
I mean,
what?
What could you do?
Like he's going to kill somebody.
Someone.
You don't get the wrong.
If it happened to you,
what would you do?
Depends how good the buzzy was.
Good.
Then he was really a woman all alone.
Here's the was meant to give back
monkey.
Here's the total.
Here's the total rub.
Okay?
This is the 100 percent dudes are
willing to accept a artificially
enhanced breasts,
right?
No problem.
I mean,
some guys don't prefer them,
but they're willing to accept
artificially enhanced breast,
so breast that change your body and they
turn
your body into something that's more,
more womanly or more,
uh,
for whatever reason that activates that
part of your lizard brain that sees the
big,
fleshy tits and thinks that this,
this girl will be able to take care of
my babies.
Well,
she's,
she's very fertile.
These are good genes.
That's the same gene that gives you the
big ass,
like the big ass and big tits like that
sparks the is like a flame.
It's not as a matter of someone giving
you affection.
It's a matter of someone giving you
affection in a very specific shape that
that rings in your brain.
Well,
they can do that and do that absolutely
perfectly and they will be able to
eventually,
if they can already right now and turn a
guy into the exact shape of a woman
that's hot as fuck.
At the end of the day,
you can search around for some fucking
hidden cracker Jack Toy.
It can lift her up and look around and
try to figure out,
okay,
I know I guess is this a woman?
I just looks exactly like a woman.
It feels like a woman.
It talks like a woman,
goddammit is as a woman and you'll
eventually decide that it's a woman
because your brain processes that as
female,
your brain processes the words is
the shape is female and if someone could
figure out how to do it just perfectly,
just perfectly genetically,
they figured out how to go in there and
fucking tweak this shit.
They're close to doing crazy shit like
that.
You saw that thing that I'm Rhonda.
Patrick tweeted that I retweeted with
about the pigs.
Look what they do.
They're doing a pig's man.
They figured out a way to delete a gene
and pigs and they come like incredible
hulk pigs.
She,
uh,
she put up a photo of it today.
They're doing all kinds of weird shit
with genetics and they're already doing
this on people.
She says in China,
she's coming on the podcasts soon to
talk to me about it.
I can't wait to talk about it,
but look at these fucking pigs,
man.
This is crazy.
They're hulk pigs.
Live the ass and that pig.
It's like a bowl.
A lot of you are in a pig,
but.
But you know what I'm saying?
Like this is a.
This is a new thing they're doing to the
bodies of these animals.
They're gonna be able to do that to
people,
to a man and they're gonna.
Be able to turn a man into a woman like
perfectly.
There'll be able to literally get in
there and dig around,
switch this,
turn that off and turn this on and
you're a woman.
I mean it's going happen.
It's just a matter of time mean I don't
know if they're ever going to be able to
turn a dick into vagina without surgery,
but I kind of imagined one day they
will,
one day they'll just be able to.
You could go back and forth.
There's an APP for it.
One day it's the government will have a
switch,
will just decide,
today we're going to be a girl day
today.
Everyone is going to learn to be more
sensitive to women because we're all
going to be women and just hit a switch.
An entire city is a woman and then
that's when the mongols invade come over
the hill and fuck everyone,
including all the Alpha males.
They just kept fucked like chicks and
here's a secret.
They like it.
They like it because their checks.
Now,
Joe,
do you have a tight pussy
today?
Got To replenish with.
I got a new shot at the doctor.
I went to the dentist.
He cleaned my teeth and made my pussy
tyler.
To kind of be able to do that at home
with your own printer.
You're going to be finger printed,
artificial vagina,
and that just like way tighter.
You're going to hit the right keys.
Apple one click,
you know,
and your vagina just out.
You're going to have chips in your body
that tell your body what to do.
That's 100 percent.
There's going to be artificial blood.
Nano bots,
those little,
they're devising these tiny little itsy
bitsy blood cells,
sized machines.
This is what they're going to eventually
have.
Some day that'll fight cancer,
so if you have like a cancerous growth
in your body,
there'll be able to send these machines
through your bloodstream to attack these
six areas of your body.
I mean,
we're going to see some fucking nutty
shit in our day and a man turning into a
woman that was like the least of the
nutty shit.
If we could stay alive,
we could all in this room stay alive to
100.
What can I see?
Some shit.
But he hasn't cut this DICLOFENAC.
Caitlin,
when we're that like someone questioning
were in the middle of a conversation in
your own head and he introduced it to us
and brought him up.
Everybody's all excited,
but he hasn't cut his dick off yet.
So why is everybody jumping up and down
for?
Well,
because,
uh,
he is allowed to keep his penis and
still be a woman job.
No,
no,
no.
Don't worry.
His deck off.
Step stepping.
He's taking pictures.
Everybody's jumping up and down.
He still hasn't gone through the forum.
Once you go into the forum and cut that
motherfucker off,
then you come see uncle joey.
That's a true story.
Until then,
once you go to the farm,
then come back and say,
he hasn't gone yet.
This is a trick by the wife.
This is a trick.
This is a fucking train ratings.
Something's going on something man.
He got his face fixed facial surgery,
so fucking stolen.
Everybody got that face to face?
No,
not like this.
Like he went through feminization
surgery where they like shortened his
jaw and change his lips and the whole
deal.
Have you seen the recent photos?
Look at the vanity fair across the
street.
Big Mind.
He put a pussy in there and he hasn't
changed his job.
He's out there sucking Dick two nights a
week.
Yeah.
Let's put it in there.
No.
Mike is under construction store.
I don't really.
He's got a bald spot.
He's got to pull the wig over it.
But his roommate,
Leslie did everything.
She got the cheeks,
the face.
So she was a man?
Yes.
Okay.
Say this is.
Look at these photos.
Look at the photos,
like a closeup ones or the face like
right there,
like he had a shitload of things done,
isn't it?
May seem like a high maintenance guy.
Oh yeah.
He's crazy
as fuck.
Well,
here's the thing,
man.
You know when we were,
when we were watching that interview,
when he got interviewed by,
what was it?
Diane Sawyer,
Zoho.
It wasn't interviewed him.
What?
He was loving all the attention.
He was loving it.
He's loving the opportunity to talk
about himself and talk about having the
hold up that pull that image of Jesus
Christmas.
I love.
I was trying to hide those giant canoe
feed.
That's the fuck out of here with those
size 38 flippers.
It must go up.
Skirt thing going fucking Munich free.
Then motherfucking jumped in Munich and
shit.
Look at it.
It's just.
It's very strange man.
I mean that.
That is a very feminine looking man or
woman.
Joey,
you want to transition?
I should say.
You know I mean in transition.
She's very feminine looking like what
they've done,
their face if they,
if she really looked like that.
So this is the thing.
When you're looking at something like
this,
this has been through more fucking
computers,
I mean more screens and filters and we
all know that we all know about the
difference between what someone would
look like in real life and so on look
like in like a super well done
photograph like that.
It's a big difference,
but a man good for her if that's what
she wants to do now.
Same thing we were talking about before
about gay marriage.
Good for her.
If this is what she enjoys,
I'm glad that she can be on the cover of
magazine and it could be a fun time for
everybody.
You know,
when we were kids,
this could have never happened.
No,
never.
It's weird though,
right?
And it did happen when we were kids that
happened because I watched the report or
when it happened,
it happened in another country and we
just didn't know about it.
It happened like in Germany or
somewhere,
somebody like in 1940 and some American
did it.
We just,
there was no internet so we weren't very
hip to it.
You know,
when I was in Seattle,
young comic,
we had to read it,
read had done the operation.
Rita was a Japanese man,
but became a Japanese woman,
but she died because first off she had a
lot of psychological problems that came
after the surgery.
I loved Rido Rido let me for the house.
My first fucking head shot.
I never forgot that man.
I pay the back and everything read it
died because I head was too fucking big
from being a man.
What?
So her balance was off after the surgery
balances.
All of those comments.
How's that possible?
What about Brad was like,
if I become a.
it's like A.
Brad becomes a woman.
Oh,
his head's gonna be fucking ginormous.
And his balance is going to be off from
time to time something happened.
They did the surgery to him,
to her that her balance got taken off.
She died because she suffered a fall at
a disco and bang,
the head read.
It was an open mic comic.
They used to run with us in Seattle and
she'd come out.
She had the nails.
I mean,
nobody's gonna Fuck Rita out.
Trust me,
nobody ever thought of fucking read off
my hands will fucking hard.
It looked like Herman Munster hand.
She had the nails and she would get
Nachos and then she'd go to get a drink
and we'd take her Nachos and she'd yell.
She had a very feminine voice,
like yes darling.
But she looked at who's getting matched
with go it was fucking scary and to make
money.
The government or the doctors gave her a
certain amount of a month and she became
a pill addict because the pain from the
surgery plus all the psychological and
everything.
Like she,
you know,
she,
she was raised in like the fort,
you know,
when I met Rita in [inaudible] 95 read.
It was 50 already,
you know what I'm saying?
So I was 20 something,
maybe 30.
So she was telling me that when she was
growing up,
my mother and father would beat her when
she would tell him that she was really a
woman.
Wow.
Like it was just too much abuse in her
life.
And then once she finally became a
woman,
there was so much baggage,
you know,
I'm doing it like in talking to him at
the comedy club and her telling me,
you know,
as creepy as it was that,
she was,
she would have to go see a shrink three
times a week still.
What was,
what was the big that she's talking
about with the big issue?
Was that transition,
was it a transition transition?
You know,
but she ate a lot of bells.
She did a lot of powder.
She had tons of money.
I don't know where she got the money
from.
I know she sold drugs.
Uh,
she even came down here to see me once
when I was at the comedy store,
like in [inaudible] 99.
And she died shortly after that.
She fell off the stage and went into a
coma and died.
And we're joking around.
And it was true.
Her head was too big.
There's a lot to do with their pills.
She's taking pills is more likely I'd
been in contact in my life that maybe,
uh,
maybe two or three transgenders,
man,
you know,
like on the streets when I was a kid in
New York City or something and something
was always missing,
you know what I'm saying?
Even after they did the surgery,
something's always not right.
You're wrong.
And they just did something major,
Major.
It's a major step.
We're just strolling it around with
these fucking idiots and they're going
to start throwing it around like a
tattoo.
That's the part of it that I don't like
that.
Now every time somebody feels feminine,
they're gonna want to have this fucking
surgery.
You know what I'm saying?
Like one day you feel confused or
whatever,
you know,
this is the part of it I don't like.
I get all this gender stuff and I get
it,
man,
that you're a woman,
that you were born feeling this.
But in today's society we got too many
sheep that too many weeks olds out there
though,
you know,
it still argue about,
no,
it's not good.
And those are the people I worry about,
those people that,
you know,
you ever go somewhere and you hear
people talking,
you know who's there just to try to be
there.
It's like,
I'll never forget this.
I went through a a restaurant or it's to
Santa Monica and there was a guy behind
me and I'm always eating.
I said,
nobody's this gay.
Nobody could be this guy.
This guy was not born like this.
This one.
This guy is something that he does to be
accepted.
He doesn't even know what he's doing in
six years.
He won't be gained no more than six
years.
You don't have a wife and a kid living
in Idaho to be a farmer,
but he's just doing this to fit in this.
Just like I have a lot of that.
I feel a lot of that with people today
in our society a lot.
I feel people are not completely in.
There's some people where there's not
people in,
they're not there.
And that's why I tell people before you
go in there fucking think it over,
whether it's hanging out with devil
worshipers,
hanging out with drug dealers or
whatever the fuck you want to do.
Because once you're in,
you're in,
you're going to end up kidnapping
somebody with a machine gun.
Don't tell me what the fuck I know.
I know.
When somebody is faking the funk.
There's people that one.
When I was a kid,
Jimmy [inaudible],
who was my brother,
I knew he was gay.
I knew he was slinging dick,
but no fucking genius to tell you that
my brother,
I grew up in his house,
but his other three brothers,
you couldn't tell he was gay.
If he came to me today and said,
I'm a transgender,
I would hug him and go dogs.
It's great.
I can tell you what Dick suck.
I didn't have no doubts in my heart that
you weren't going to suck Dick even
though you were fucking girls in the
neighborhood because you were so good
looking.
You know what I'm saying?
You grew up with people that you look at
it and go,
who's sometimes you go to the store and
you see people that you go.
It's like when you see Eddie Murphy in
person,
you're like,
this guy could be a fucking go go
dancer.
On the weekends when you see Eddie
Murphy,
I always said Eddie Murphy should win an
academy award because when he in the
movie,
he's a man of many men.
When you see Eddie Murphy in person,
you're like,
the room is could be true.
Something about him and I ain't mad at
that.
I'm to one of his biggest fans.
I'm just telling you the truth that as a
man,
you're around other fucking men and you
know,
right?
You know who you might be able to talk
to,
suck a Dick at three in the morning.
We all have that person that we go home,
we loved that person.
We accept that person,
but you know one night if you have a
pill and acquaintance,
you might be able to clock this guy a
guy in boogie nights.
There's people like that,
that they walk around,
you know,
little ticket,
they acted,
they got into a tight spot one night.
Okay.
And that night in Hollywood,
I really.
And I felt bad about what I was
thinking.
I felt this guy was just doing it.
So the bowl with these guys on Tuesday
nights,
you know,
20 years ago,
what am I the only retarding the room
man.
Hey shh.
When lesbian that she did,
she not,
she was Baiting fucking ellen.
You are that one fan to become famous.
So she became a lesbian and she takes
out a brass balls and now what is she
got?
Okay.
The husband,
you know,
stick.
I think people,
a lot of people move to Hollywood or in
society and just to fit in.
They'll do shit.
No do shit.
Then they realized,
well this is where I fucking got.
They do it man.
We live in a sheep fucking society for
that.
We're all trying to be the same person.
If you look around,
we're all looking the same.
When you go to silver lake and do motlow
and you get on stage,
look at the people and the 80 percent of
people look the same.
They all got the same fucking glasses,
the same tight jeans,
the same fat fueled the Chinese sign.
Everybody's wanting to meet up insanely
everybody's.
You know,
you wake up in the morning,
walk into a studio for an audition.
What does everybody have in front of
them?
A couple of what?
Starbucks.
Starbucks,
and if you ain't got starbucks,
you weren't invited to the fucking
party.
You see,
starbucks raised their prices 20 percent
again.
How much more are you going to pay for
coffee?
They got you hooked.
It got you hooked.
They want that money.
It's not.
It's not coffee.
Everybody got coffee.
It's the status of going to starbucks.
Oh my God,
isn't it scatters.
I'm like,
God,
how many times you see who's impressing?
You go to starbucks over the car.
I go to coffee bean.
They have better croissant.
It's doesn't matter.
You don't have to.
Today's society.
When we were growing up in Boston or
Denver,
you lived at your grandfather's and
newer people that have a little fucking
blue cup that's in coffee and then went
to a diner and you said,
give me a.
What was the,
what was it called?
Do you remember these times?
The Greek stuff,
like little Greek guys.
What's it called?
The coffee medium.
What do you.
How do you want a coffee?
Regularly?
Regular.
What's regular milk and sugar and two
coffees and now look what we have,
but we didn't carry the coffee cups like
a bud was sick.
When you go out and let you take a
picture with somebody,
what do they always gotten?
The hint but the fucking beer down.
But nobody could put the beer down.
God forbid they don't party out.
God forbid dental part out.
Let's put the buckets so they can tell.
I'm drinking.
What the fuck?
Put The beat down your fuck St.
Copy that society.
Everybody wants to fucking drink that
and coffee.
You ever had someone look at your comp?
The boys that fucking coffee bean.
What?
You can afford starbucks,
Bro.
Yo.
Step Up.
No starbucks.
Why would you wait in donuts,
Bro?
I wouldn't relate on that line.
When you sat in 11,
got the same quote and now like know,
he says St Louis.
That Brazilian bold.
We'll keep you up to three days.
That's what I use is drinks.
Don't me.
My fucking pissed with the iced drinks.
Coffee.
Fuck you.
They drink fucking.
You have a drink.
You have a drink with zilliant both and
fucking Dunkin donuts.
Swap you.
Can everybody be bionics and that type
fungus doughnuts and get fucking bolt
and liquid.
Fucking fuck at Dunkin donuts.
I agree with but not seven.
I don't even like them.
Can dollars because has seven,
11,
seven,
11.
The Old Brazilian bold.
Now they got it all fucked up.
I don't go for Dunkin donuts.
No,
go for you.
Don't go for 7:11.
A Dunkin donuts in Encino.
By the time I dropped out.
Crash the fucking car so I can make the
fucking house.
I make the trip at the house.
What do you think?
I'll
tell you about the carrot cake cups.
Right?
Why do you think that Jamie?
Jamie,
get the manicure it take to have them
still right in the car.
Why do you think I lead the Tom these
pills so fast?
Because I gotta catch my stomach bugs by
men that into a Pumpkin at midnight.
Oh my God.
I drink the flat white.
The small one at midnight.
So you go right down the street to the
one that's near a is at eight.
Magnolia,
Magnolia and riverside.
It's open til 12.
Drive and is open till midnight.
I got up this morning at 4:15.
I got nothing to do.
I shoot right to the tribe is open at
4:30.
You know,
one of the things that I would do when I
was writing,
because I'd make a fucking pot of coffee
at night.
Like you.
You'd be like midnight.
I start writing.
I'll make a pot of coffee.
That's what I know.
I'm there to work.
I'm going to,
you know,
big fucking French press you.
You said you got the white chocolate
Mocha.
I get the flat white.
I don't drink milk.
Flat White.
White chocolate.
You got to get out of here,
right?
No,
no,
no.
I'm talking about 15,
20 minutes.
I love the flat white from.
It's like,
oh,
it's like a fake fake on late yet.
I'll drink a small.
You know what I'm saying?
But if I'm home I'll crop that
motherfucker.
I'll do a double bustillo bleed right
after that though.
Right?
Like cocaine for a cup of coffee.
Don't do nothing but uncle joey.
That's a double boost fellow.
I think I have add or some shit because
sometimes I'll have a cup of coffee and
I'll get sleepy.
Yeah,
me too.
Me Too.
We'll still.
Nothing must come down.
What goes up must come down.
Must come down.
Must that guy.
That body.
And yet you got no home spinning wheel
that Chicago,
isn't it?
No,
I don't think it's.
Is it Chicago?
Maybe.
God Damn.
I don't know.
Is it three dog night?
Chicago.
It's got to be one of those fuckers
spinning wheel.
Spinning wheel.
Sorry.
You guys are listening to the new apple
music radio station.
No,
it's interesting because it's spinning
wheel on Tla.
Say to stay away from it.
Blood,
sweat and tears.
Joey,
you blood,
sweat and tears.
That's crazy.
Are you fucking kidding me?
What a brilliant.
Put a fucking jam on dog.
What are you got to put the video on so
I can show you motherfuckers end the
book by Aerosmith.
He describes when he met his daughter
for the first time at a concert.
He was onstage and his daughter.
Yeah,
the chick.
That's a norm again,
steven,
for the first time.
No,
that dog.
she didn't know who the father was.
It was between todd.
Brandon.
Todd glass was between Todd Rundgren and
Steven.
Steven Tyler,
and then her mother took her to see
aerospace.
She goes,
that's my dad put up.
Todd rundgren a hello.
It's me.
Listen to this challenge.
Well,
last time you heard this,
I haven't heard this in forever.
Listen to them.
I don't even know how it goes.
Oh my God.
This is when singing is when you had to
have a voice dog.
She's gonna Knock.
Kick you off of Youtube and Youtube.
Yeah,
listen to that.
We might have to edit this to the kids.
Don't put the videos.
A lot of work for this guy.
It's not that simple,
but you to see the village,
see what it looks like.
This is him.
This is suicide music.
Now there's a bad jam.
This tie rod,
this tremendous.
Yeah.
This is one of those songs you listened
to over your grandmother's house.
To get outside for a walk is a bad jam.
I got to get out of the house guys.
A fucking snowing out.
I don't care.
I got to walk.
Going to be dressing an eagle.
Thinks is a bird.
You have to see this guy now.
I always wonder what happens to these
guys are like rock stars and then they
just stopped.
They just stopped.
Like,
what is guaranteed?
This guy had so much talent.
This guy wrote for people.
He gets a fucking.
He gets residuals from all this dough on
the radio,
you know,
with all this classic rock and all these
serious and the same money we get from.
What's that check?
Which sends us a check once a quarter
for our shit on the radio they got.
And the in boulder.
I used to be friends with a guy that was
a radio police.
Okay.
He was the radio police and what he did
was he made sure that you got paid for
your stuff.
The radio.
Polly was there.
He worked for the radio.
Police have a badge.
No,
he dad.
He was a white guy at the car wash.
What's in here?
Keurig?
K Cups.
Hash oil.
Marijuana and the K Cup for him.
I got to put some sugar in this
motherfucker.
You Ain't,
you don't like sweet enough.
The universe experience.
Very sweet.
No.
Uh,
but we told Stevie is empty.
Have you tried the liquid Stevia stuff?
We got Marvin.
Oh,
we got sugar for you.
Y'all take some sugar.
Liquid Stevia.
That's dangerous.
Eyedropper yet second hand.
Let's do like a one or two drops.
It's so strong.
Stevia can really fuck up a drink if
you're not paying attention.
Hello?
It's me.
Yeah.
Well,
you know the fuck.
What's he gonna do?
What's this sugar bitch?
I got.
I'm Cuban.
I got a sweet tooth.
You're going to get me two packages.
I got diabetes.
How many packets to use?
Raw Sugar.
How many agents?
A half a cup of coffee.
How many sugars would you put it in
there?
Normally?
I don't.
Fucking raw sugars.
Kinda wasn't that Stevia's shit in
there.
Now it's broken.
No,
the other shit.
That's what I use.
I use the sister sweetness.
Your boy sent me Stevia.
Whatever the fuck.
He said sugar at all.
But yet you're using for the fuck you
guys.
I'm partying with you motherfuckers.
You know what I'm saying?
We all partied.
Once you drink that,
you drink that fucking one of the atlas
and I did my first morning joining the
9:00
AM.
This is what the fuck you been.
Oh,
I wanted to talk to you about that.
Your periscope show your stairs for Joe
and I got it.
I'm good.
This tastes like this.
Tastes like.
I don't know what the fuck you talking
about.
It's not supposed to be good.
When I drank a star.
It's fucking good.
It's Gel.
Drink that.
This is Dick.
No,
no.
Taste like a guy that smoked pot all
night.
You suck his dick.
Get Salad Queen.
Hello?
It's me.
What's the story you periscope show you
every morning you do in the joint?
What does it say it again?
Tell me about the morning joint with
Uncle Joey.
About.
I do it about five after the baby lets
me go after eight in the morning.
Yeah.
You stand outside for a couple of
minutes and just do pairs for me for
both two different weeds,
maybe a little hashish and I wake the
people up.
I give some motivational times.
I tell the people at grabbed that Dick
like today,
the saying of the day was either they're
going to suck your dick or they're going
to suck your Dick.
Either way you wouldn't.
You know what I'm saying?
Wow.
That's really clever.
Did you write that out?
Sure.
And Confucius says you suck my dick
today or something,
but you got to suck my dick somewhere
along the line,
Dick second going,
how you have to leave the house in the
morning when I leave the house,
I'm scared.
I got fucking get myself fired up in the
shower and let people know that when I'm
going out that somebody is going to suck
your dick play whether they want to not
be scared of.
No,
I'm scared of fucking.
Do you ever have them delete any of your
stuff?
No,
not about periscope.
I just do them and I fucking move on
with my life.
That'd be alive.
They will visit.
You're showing up with some mad
motherfucking sunshine in your heart.
Ball sack.
Yeah.
They had said they got two options.
Study the suck.
Good Dick Quarter.
Suck.
Good Dick.
That's their option.
So who gives a fuck?
What's up with the Janet?
Janet,
you know we've been waiting for 20
fucking minutes now.
You want to show up a day late and a
dollar short,
but let's get this fucking party
started.
We're going to open up today with the,
with the Zombie.
We.
By the way,
I know exactly what I'm doing tomorrow.
I'm setting my alarm clock and I'm going
to be a part of this.
I usually watch you right when I'm going
to bed really early sometimes.
Sometimes you know what I'm going to do,
man.
I want to get one of those iphone things
for the car.
You know you got one that illegal.
It's illegal to do it on the have a
windshield mountain in California
windshield windshield because it's in
front of you or anything on your
windshield.
So you can do that on the windshield.
You know,
you could do it like on the fence.
They have the ones that snap and events
and.
But it's not,
it's not illegal at periscope while
you're driving.
I think it is.
I definitely think it is.
Really.
Yeah.
Because you're kind of not paying
attention to the road you are.
If you just turn it on while you're
driving.
If you're parked,
he turned it on and you go,
okay,
it's on.
Here we go.
We're going to work.
I think
that's the biggest step you can take.
That's fine.
You can drive like that with Gopros
because that's how those shows get made.
Like drive that drive channel on
Youtube.
I was with those guys that Matt Farah
Dude,
he's got all these gopros inside of his
car.
So you could definitely do that.
I uh,
I,
I drive all the time but I delete them
right after that.
Cloud is shit.
The fucking forest fire fighting 30
1:00,
they deleted one of my periscopes
because I have this thing where I eat
shitty food in the shower and like
review it and I was doing Taco Bell,
like I had like a Nacho Belgrade day and
I was just drinking all the water and
like,
like a soup I got deleted because it was
too gross.
I think.
What the fuck you eating food.
I know they censoring.
They,
I think they might,
I don't know why,
but it was available for like an hour
and then they just pulled it and I don't
know if it was.
I heard that people have said at you
that you're wasting water.
Six minute shower and I'm taking a
shower while I'm eating.
Yeah.
But you're not defending or attacking
you.
Right?
People were upset that you were wasting
water.
Well,
I understand those complaints,
but I,
uh,
when I,
when I do a periscope,
I tried not to shower for four days
straight.
So,
uh,
it's uh,
can argue with that.
Ladies and gentlemen,
show off your fucking high horse.
How many minutes shower can I take?
What?
Five minutes?
Ten minutes ago,
who fucking shuts down the golf course
and when does that happen?
Because until then,
fuck yourself,
because they're using millions of
gallons of water until you shut down the
golf course.
Fuck off.
That's 100 percent for entertainment.
A hundred hundred percent.
He's at least taken a convert.
Tory effort of entertainment and a
shower.
I take two or three shows a day and I
take my time.
I get the slew foot.
Nice to get the asshole.
Get the fuck you have to live with a
stick.
That's.
I made an asshole.
Loofa dog.
A little looser with acute tip.
Just don't wash the barnacles around the
muffler.
Get stuck in there and you won't even
know until I did the colonoscopy.
I looked at my ad.
I didn't want to go with they with a
dirty.
Yeah.
So just use the shower for your
colonoscopy.
Cocksucker.
I've had a finger in my butt.
No,
not the finger.
When they stick the camera,
look around.
Dr.
a check around.
They had to look around.
Very uncomfortable.
Yeah.
They really are.
Make icon.
Look around your asshole.
Yeah,
I'm avoiding shoulder surgery.
I've got some tears,
small pairs in my labor,
so I've been going through a regena
keen,
had physical therapy and all this
different shit for it.
So my latest health issue,
it's fascinating.
Shit.
The feel your joints given out and to
realize,
oh,
I didn't have to get fixed.
I'm gonna have to get this one fixed.
It's not quite at the point where I got
to get it fixed.
I think I could rejuvenate it to the
point like it's.
It's weird because it's still strong but
it just gets sore after I use it and
there's apparently some bone chips in
there from Jujitsu for my knee hurts,
but what Americaness going to cry,
I'm going to knee hurts again.
The one I just had.
You should.
You should look into that.
Regina.
King Shit was with Jenna came magenic
kings or the bloods spinning procedure.
They take your blood outs with coby
Bryan and all these guys used to go to
Germany for now they have a place in
Santa Monica and it just massive and
they take out some blood.
That's where we have a problem.
They to whatever,
to busy,
you got to know they've got a few to
know they need and they're big too.
They're taken too big tubes and a couple
of small to get that bass drum and
fucking compressor and they fucking
banged it out of him.
Blood flopped you.
That's why I didn't go to the thing.
The Salvation Army.
Sixteen ounces of blood of your blood.
They've got to go.
You've been doing and I try.
I try to give blood.
Once a month I go to a doctor with some
fake fucking excuse because people.
That's why women don't get heart attacks
because they bleed once a month.
Why?
They change up their fucking blood.
That's why women don't get audited
because every fucking blood,
but we don't bleed like women go get
blood.
So your body rejuvenates new fucking
Even if it's for fucking announces.
What do you think it dealing with?
Because that was true.
Then dudes,
you did.
Coke would bleed more than noses,
so they would probably live longer.
You talked on them about telling you
right now that the reason women don't
die as many audit taxes matters because
they don't believe that the fucking
monkey,
the reason why they probably don't die
as much because they don't date as many
women.
If you're over 40,
go give blood once a month.
Just a couple tubes so your body starts
from scratch.
I'm telling you,
Joe wrote when women are not dating
women,
it saves a lot of stress.
It's good point and I thought this gay
marriage thing,
you're gonna see a rise in heart attacks
on women once they get the bill from the
lawyer,
the alimony.
What fucking out bitch get a job.
I didn't get breakfast.
You didn't have fucking kids with me.
God dammit.
Melissa etheridge was really funny when
she was talking about that.
She gives alimony two different checks.
I go,
what happened?
She goes,
bitches are crazy.
Child support is a bad ass bitch.
She's a lady.
I say that with all due respect,
I call you a bad aspect so I can call
anybody I love about ass.
Bitch.
Look at you.
Bad ass bitch.
That's,
that's 100 percent respectful.
Where are you at this weekend?
You suck the data.
Just see,
um,
the car theater at the mgm with Tommy
[inaudible] and Tony Hinchcliffe in
Vegas for the big fights.
I'm gonna miss you guys.
I miss you too.
Where are you at?
I'm at the Atlanta impro.
I heard that's a good spot by spot.
Brian Campbell's a king.
He's a king there.
Yup.
That's,
they don't have the punchline anymore,
but they did a punchline comedy night at
a fucking backyard the other day.
They had some gated community.
They have some crazy community and um,
and uh,
somewhere outside of Atlanta.
It's like one of those engineered
communities and they have all these
recreations and gated community,
but they have this,
the punchline had a punchline comedy
night and all these people are sitting
outside and they decided to have a
comedy night at their,
uh,
you say the punchline is not open
anymore.
It's on open.
What happened?
What they did to the building?
I think they lost their lease,
I'm assuming,
but they've been there for ever forever
or they might've decided it doesn't make
sense to keep the lease.
I don't know exactly what happened and
they're looking for another spot.
Greenroom sucked.
Anyway.
No,
I was kind of cool.
That was the green room that had a
little sign on the wall and said,
quit trying to be Hicks.
Yeah,
got trapped there because you had the
only way to enter and exit.
That green room was walking through the
whole entire audience.
That's also the green room where Seth
Petrocelli Fuck Kimbo slice and I called
the fight like right before it happened
because Ken shamrock got injured warming
up for the first fight and then all of a
sudden instead of Ken Kimbo slice out of
fight seth pictures,
Ellie and I went,
what?
And as soon as I saw it,
I'm like,
oh my God says package.
I was going to fuck him up.
Like this is a terrible fight for him.
Petros.
Ellie's a bad motherfucker.
So I watched that.
I was like,
this is a terrible match up.
And everybody's like,
you're crazy.
Kimball's a world beater and like,
dude,
you wait,
do you see what happens here?
And it happened within like eight
seconds.
Just as soon as the fight started,
Petrocelli knocks him out and I go see.
I called it south patches.
Oh,
he's bad motherfucker.
But I was like,
but I didn't call it.
You would never see this.
This would,
we would hide this.
It was a crazy little green room,
man.
That was a good little spot.
Yeah.
I mean just walking to the back door or
something to it.
Yeah.
Walking suck.
But that was part of the fun of that
club was that it was kind of Wonky,
you know?
Is that weird?
Wonky upstairs member.
So weird spot know show.
It wasn't manly.
Beard got goddamn growing.
Another beard.
I always done a slug.
I thought that was that.
I always die.
This would now guaranteed.
And people know what the fuck you're
doing.
When I used to bring you there,
people don't know what to make of you on
there were so confused when you were in
his position back then were either they
got it or they didn't know,
but I wasn't working hard than either.
I was going up that coat up like the
night before and not even feeling that,
you know,
when you have coke and get blood from
the night before dog does it depress
you?
The next day wasn't the depression.
It's like,
you know,
you got high,
like I would get high like Mondays,
Wednesdays,
then the fucking weekend coach coming,
you got a walmart,
you know,
and the first night you'd have like a
good show.
There is nothing to have a good show.
But then I got ahold of that shit and
then Friday was rough and then Saturday
was even referred because you're more,
you're more,
this communicated,
you're more.
This disconnected is the word.
So I would go up that dying to see those
people and I fucking hated them and they
hated me.
You know?
It was a.
So for the longest time for you that
cocaine was a real,
like a real anchor around your neck.
Thirty fucking years.
I was telling my wife this morning,
the whole nineties.
You figure the whole nine these.
How'd you.
How'd you kick it?
Kick it.
Told you I just kicked it.
I don't fucking know.
I guess I just didn't want.
I didn't want listening bro.
Like I told you my.
I have a fucking revenge.
Okay.
It,
you'd rather fucking get 10 takes up
your ass.
Didn't have somebody come to you and
say,
Joey Diaz died from an overdose.
I was not going to let that happen.
I was not going to let people come up to
you and go see.
I told you and I definitely didn't want
my wife to find me on the floor
listening.
You can find me on the floor.
Red Band could never handle red band
will never be the same again.
If he found me on the floor,
never read,
Bam would fucking God because he doesn't
have that DNA.
This poor guy you do you to find anybody
on the floor.
It'd be tough for you to deal with the
league about that.
It'd be tough for you to deal.
You are strong.
You know what I'm saying?
You would put it in perspective a lot
quicker.
Little Red Bag.
Could red band would take two years
talking about.
I'm like,
he's not right there.
Not saying something bad about red band
with bands.
Got a great soul.
When I first met red band,
I would talk to this kid would leave the
room.
They didn't know what to make of the
Columbus days.
Yeah.
When I first.
He didn't know.
So what I'm saying is that some people
could find a guy on the floor and live
with it and there's some people who
can't digest it.
They can't.
I didn't want to things I didn't want to
terrify me on the floor.
I definitely don't want to die in a
hotel room on the fucking road.
And that was my main playground.
You know what I'm gonna go get a hotel
room.
Naked juice on your leg hopefully.
And some chick who left at three in the
morning and then people going to say,
I told you Joe Rogan,
that was never going to happen in my
lifetime.
In my lifetime.
That was not going to happen.
I was not going to hold me from cope.
I couldn't give them the satisfaction.
Even after the fucking fact.
That's how deep my revenge genome runs.
That's hilarious.
So you,
you,
you got clean because you wanted to get
back at the people.
That would be.
It would have been happy.
If you die,
I'll place would have been happy if I
died from that.
They would have loved to look at you in
the face and go.
I told yourself there's people that live
for that shit that once they have an
opinion,
they live by.
Let me tell you something now.
I said,
I told you.
Sell a Shitload of times.
Now I get to say I told you so.
Now I get to say I told you.
So.
It's a lot of fucking agents.
I've had some.
I had some stupid conversations with
people back in the day,
stupid where they're trying to tell him
you were in town to,
if you weren't funny.
I'm like,
you need to shut the fuck up.
I was just talking about,
listen man,
when you're on the drug,
when you're running a drug,
you get stuck in that emotional state
where you started that drug with that
drug really became something else for
you.
Listen,
when we do,
when I go right when I leave now and I
go to the pharmacist and I get such a
great hit,
one out of all three times,
it's an antibody kind of ours,
uh,
steroids,
steroids to get the burn pit.
Oh,
okay.
I've heard of that.
Okay?
But once I started saying that,
that thing,
then it becomes something else.
Why don't check started coming up to me
and going,
God,
we love your arms and we'd love your
backup becomes an emotional thing.
Shooting,
shooting.
Right now I'm starting.
I'm chasing that dragon.
That feeling.
Well,
when you start doing,
you do a fucking line of coke because
you're in an emotional
fucking wrecked.
Okay?
When you do it,
you don't even know what at times you
become an emotional wreck from any drug,
those pills.
So for me,
I stopped.
I got stuck emotionally.
The angle was stuck in me.
You can't move forward.
We've had this discussion can move
forward.
Well,
you've always said that it,
like,
it shuts off your soul.
Show it.
That's the way you described it.
It was like you just became a blank
shirt.
I wasn't happy.
I wasn't sad.
I wasn't mad.
I wasn't any of the above.
I had no emotions.
You fake the funk in away in those days.
You still were.
Joey did.
Oh,
I can still grow some fucking eat if you
caught me after two days if I sat down
with a notebook.
But it wasn't until you know,
you,
you still had a lot of talent.
You know,
there's still something about you that,
that just,
it,
it was about,
uh,
you catching it.
I remember one time we,
uh,
we worked together rascals,
the West Orange,
western rascals and wants to orange.
And it was at the time when you made the
transition,
you know how Nicole or Caitlyn Jenner
came,
that was a transition.
There was a transition where you went
from Joey Diaz,
the guy wants to be a comedian to Joey
Diaz,
a great comedian.
And then I saw,
I watched it happen and it happened
really quickly.
That was what was weird.
I was like,
you have this period of time.
We were real hit and miss,
you know,
and you know,
if you went down,
you went down hard and you would go to
that sometimes you had bomb,
like multiple sets in a row and just
wasn't,
it wasn't clicking click and then boom,
you,
you hit on it and figured out what a
fucking,
what it was.
And it almost like you released
something like you had like a demon
inside it.
You pulled it out and you've released
it.
And then all the sudden you were
crushing.
I remember,
I think it was tripling.
And I were in the back by the,
uh,
the back hallway.
And it was like one of the Times where
you just really started crushing.
And Tripoli was like,
Joey Diaz is on another level.
I go,
yeah man.
Like what the fuck?
Like you just caught it,
you caught a wave and all of a sudden
you were surfing and then from then on
you figured it out.
It was crazy.
Like you went from being like a really
funny guy offstage and an occasionally
funny guy on stage,
but often mediocre to a monster.
Just monster.
Like there was nights and the or will
you destroy and we were falling out of
the back stick.
We would leave like laughing so hard.
We would go down the backstairs out into
the hallway and it'd be like two or
three guys slapping their legs.
Laugh.
I'd be dying.
I love that original room.
Listening to original room brings
something out of you.
We're out of time.
There's only one time where I was.
I love you man.
Anytime at our fourth of July barbecue
too.
Right to see you,
Jamie.
Yuck.
I'm going to go home.
They'll take us swimming.
That's always a photophobia.
His daughter just says Yuck.
And everything.
First time she met me,
she kissed me.
Kiss to everyday.
Do you want to have some of this?
Yuck,
but I showed her some ice cream and
you're like,
oh,
that was our best friend.
Now the ice cream man.
A Joey Diaz.
What is it?
The periscope.
How do people get to it?
I don't know.
Oh,
I'll just follow them on twitter.
Is it up on twitter?
What time in the morning?
Five after five after eight.
You got to check that out.
Get you get your day.
Started off with that.
Of course.
A mad flavor on twitter,
a red band on twitter or show someone
else next week and Toronto and this
week,
Wednesday comedy stores.
Steevo.
Good googly Mowgli.
Alright friends.
We'll see you soon.
Bye.
Bye guys.
Love you guys.