How strong are these?
Shouldn't have to write.
I definitely wouldn't have two of those.
Okay.
I'm talking trust.
So it's a 240 milligrams of caffeine.
Now I can feel it rising inside of me.
That baby.
See why you want to ruin star wars?
What?
Ali's kidding.
I'm not going to do that man.
I heard a lot of people are saying that
they,
uh,
they heard it was crap and that it
wasn't good.
But everybody I know that saw it said it
was awesome.
I loved it.
You loved it.
I didn't like it.
It's like,
what are you thinking,
man?
What did you think we are going to go
see?
It's called Star Wars.
Like it's the most obvious kind of
thing.
I don't know why people have
expectations for star wars.
It was the expectations I guess they're
looking for or a plot.
I guess they're looking for.
No,
you know what I mean?
I guess they're looking for some kind of
like deep like meaning or something like
Quintin Tarantino or some.
Some kubrick ask thing.
It's star wars.
It's a space opera.
It's like I go in there with no
expectations,
be happy for the colors,
that's it,
the beautiful colors,
and then after that,
if there's something out,
it's things flying through space and
lasers.
It's a very confined genre.
It's very confined and you know it's not
going to step outside of the box.
It's not going to be weird sexually not
going to have some strange murder
tension because I'm going to be any like
any unrequited love.
There's going to be just some normal
space themes with Joseph Campbell's
hero's journey.
That's it.
It's mixing with a lot of mystical stuff
that you can connect to you,
which is beautiful.
It's great.
I had lucas talk about his friend Joseph
Campbell,
like literally wrote star wars based on
Joseph Campbell's steps of a hero's
journey.
Fascinating.
They were.
There were good friends.
Yeah.
The hero with a thousand faces.
This is classic book and then he did
have you seen his interviews with Bill
Moyers?
Power of myth.
That was fantastic.
He's awesome.
So Joseph Campbell used to go up and
give a lecture at Lucas ranch every year
on mythology.
Lucas ranch where George Lucas ranch up
in Morin or sonoma and so he would go up
and when they were working on the
original star wars and give a lecture to
the crew,
everybody about mythology every year and
then when Campbell died,
your friend in mind,
Stanley kripner filled in for him.
Oh Wow.
That's interesting.
Wow.
Stanley's amazing.
Till I just saw him a week ago.
Dunkin happened to text me while I was
talking with doing the podcast with
Stanley or just finished and I said,
oh,
you gotta meet my friend Duncan.
He's really interesting.
He's,
yeah,
he's a comedian,
but he's really into the spiritual stuff
and he just got back from seeing a
hanging out with Ram das in Hawaii and
Stanley says,
well,
does he know that Ron doss was a standup
comedian for a time?
I feel like he got him mixed up with
Timothy leary because I know timothy
leary
went on tour doing like some some kind
of thing called stand up,
but I don't think rahm does did it,
but I know Timothy leary tried stand up.
Well,
he said he saw him in the village and
the club does.
Why not?
Man?
He's probably on acid.
Richard Alpert.
He was probably thinking,
fuck it.
Why not?
Let me give it a shot.
I mean,
he's a good.
He's a great speaker and he is pretty
funny.
Yeah.
You said he's like a very humorous guy
to talk to him.
He's super funny.
Yeah.
Which is I,
I've noticed that seems to be a quality
and people who have a real spiritual
practice like funny.
They're always funny.
They always have this real specific non
bullshit style of humor.
It's really hard to offend them.
That's quite often.
That's how I can tell if somebody's got
a real practice is usually impossible to
offend.
Like there isn't anything that you can
say that's gonna make them upset,
but you know the alarm bells start going
off in my mind when you get around
people who you say something and you
see,
oh shit,
I triggered the alarm system.
I have offended this person,
which is really curious to me like,
how are you?
How are you in tune with the universe?
And yet still something that a monkey
descendant says out of the end of his
feeding tube,
it causes you to feel results in
durable.
If you're so tough.
How you,
why are you such a pussy?
It was a truly,
well,
well not,
not like,
it's like the opposite of tough,
but you know,
I mean I agree like sophisticated.
Well until you know what's going on.
It's the way,
the way they've described it or I've
heard it described,
which is super cool when they,
when they,
whenever they were I'm das talks about
is his guru,
neem Karoli Baba,
is that there was nothing there.
Like there's no obstruction.
Like anything.
Everything was just sort of going
through this person,
you know,
as opposed to like me,
I get on the phone with Bank of America,
they've frozen my card because I went to
Australia and like I'm saving with rage.
Fuck.
I haven't another fucking country.
My fucking bank,
you know,
and you know,
or whatever it is that triggers you to
freeze up.
Some people they get to the point
theoretically or that like convulsive
seizure,
like freezing up.
It
doesn't happen.
I'll tell you,
I can get that in spurts.
I can get done in spurts from Yoga and
here's what I can prove it.
A guy fucking nailed me on the highway
while he wasn't paying attention,
hit the brakes,
skid.
I watched him plow into my fucking car
and my,
my white Porsche,
the expensive one.
And it's a rare car too.
I'm like,
fuck,
I hope he didn't total the car.
I got out and the first thing I said
was,
are you okay?
And I go,
I'm okay.
We're cool.
And I literally wasn't upset at all yet.
I wasn't upset but I've been doing yoga
like four days a week and I was a little
high,
you know,
probably still from the afternoon.
I think I was probably like,
at least under the influence of cannabis
to the point where I was like a little
bit more.
But
I just,
I,
I can only get there for like bursts
when when you're busy with work and life
and it can overwhelm and you get mad at
someone doing a shitty job,
parking,
like come on,
fuck,
head punk,
your car stupid.
You know,
like you backing up again,
oh my God,
look at this retard,
let's get back up again.
And um,
and then I'll be like,
I'll catch myself.
Like,
why not even talking to this guy,
this guy's in a car 100 feet from me and
I'm,
I'm openly mocking him out loud.
Yeah.
And
eroding your insides as you do it.
And I heard Wim Hoff talking about this.
Maybe it was on your podcast and he was
talking about being under the ice in his
retinas froze and he couldn't find the
hole to get out.
And whoever was he was talking with
asked him like,
so,
you know,
what was the panic?
Like what,
what?
And he said,
well,
you know,
when I'm in those situations or like
when I got lost in a whiteout on Mount
Everest in my shorts,
uh,
there's no stress because then it's all
just like,
it takes you back to yourself to who you
really are.
And I know in my,
in my core,
I am like a competent and confident.
And uh,
so he was saying it's been demonstrated
that you can generate more stress
hormones laying in your bed and just
thinking about something stressful than
what actually happens when you're in a
moment of actual danger.
You sort of shift into another gear when
that car hit you,
that changed your whole world.
Right?
He's like,
now now you're framing it as am I going
to survive this?
But I knew I was going to survive
because he wasn't going that fast,
but I was just taking.
My car's going to be told you're
watching him in the rear view mirror.
Yeah,
I was stopped.
And you know,
people,
Dude,
some guy almost hit me today on his
phone with his phone literally on the
steering wheel as he's texting and
driving and just went right into my
lane.
I think it's constant.
People are constantly doing it.
They're just not paying attention.
And if something happens,
when the guy rear ended me,
the lane was closed for some reason like
construction.
So everybody had gotten to that,
that onramp on Hollywood and or the one
on one and highland exit and it was shut
down for whatever reason.
So we were all stopped at a big line and
this dude just barely paid attention and
then all of a sudden shit and I could
see his face like gritting his teeth
pulling fan.
I'm watching my rear view tensing up,
my car stalls out,
goes flying into another lane
where you don't want to be on a
motorcycle.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
That's so dangerous.
If you get hit like that on a motorcycle
who you might be paralyzed,
you might be dead it easily and you
can't get off and it's not your fault.
That's the thing.
And I rode a bike for seven and a half
years and I always felt like I'm,
I've got everything under control,
but there's that,
there's those tiles off if you have the
time to jump off and get the fuck out of
the way.
Well I never,
I wasn't like a competitive,
you know,
dad and you see a guy coming from behind
you.
Do you jump off?
You let it hit you?
What the fuck do do?
I don't
know,
but you're hyper aware of all the space
around you on a bike.
So I'm always.
If I'm stopped and I know like on a
highway situation,
I'm always watching behind me because
you feel you developed that vulnerable
sense.
Scary man.
Bikes back.
Remember Bill Byrd
telling us what he has I guess at the
Ice House.
He's like riding a motorcycle is like,
imagine sitting on the.
If your car driving that way.
He looked down at the road buzzing by at
70 miles an hour and it's like I could
reach out my toe and just grind it off,
you know?
Yeah.
But you know,
but it's like,
it's like a metaphor for so many other
things in life,
right?
Do you really want to be set?
You want to have the illusion of
separation or do you.
Are you actually safer being intimate
with the danger of what's going on?
So you're hypervigilant because in a car
you're looking at your phone,
you're fucking with the radio because
you've got the sense that I'm in a room
and everything's cool until he hit the
tree,
you know,
there's definitely that you can
definitely get to detach and as things
get more and more automated,
it's going to be weirder and weirder as
a.
Now you can tell your car things like,
uh,
like you've used that.
Hey,
Siri function.
Yes.
You.
So you asked your car to text people,
text people,
tell us to send less time.
I was on your podcast.
You did this whole thing and I saw a
bunch of people tweeted,
like,
fucked up my phone off.
They're listed in the fuck in the car
because I'm like,
how hard is it for you to press the
button?
All I have to do is press the button and
then I say it,
you know?
Yeah.
I don't have to uh,
to say that do the Hey Siri thing.
But my point being is they have the
Tesla's now that they're coming with,
they have a new download that allows you
to have your car automate itself.
Like you set the directions and it
navigates drives.
Yeah,
it fucking drives itself.
So like then it's gonna get real weird
when we switched back and forth between
that and then actual driving like the
space out factor of people.
Like when they have to drive again,
they might not be used to it.
Yeah.
It's the space between automation and
like semi automation and full automation
that is going to be really dangerous.
But man,
that dream as you leave your house,
your car looks like a little living
room,
a little pod with a couch in it.
Coffeemaker,
a TV and you just sit on the couch,
tell the car where it take me to vegas
and it just takes you there and you just
relax on the sleep.
You can look out the window.
The interstates are just going to look
like houses.
Yeah.
She miss you with your aviator.
Sunglasses on the gloves hair.
You driving gloves about driving shoes.
Let's get crazy.
Oh yeah.
It was a little nervous driving shoes.
That's shifting the gears.
Let's say you have like a,
an old Fiat or something.
Cool.
Will you look like you're a poet or
something?
Sure.
I'm sure there are people back scarf
over your shoulder.
I'm sure there were a carriage drivers.
Imagine,
think of missing that last last.
The horses back smell or the farts like
everyone always.
There's a nostalgia attached to
antiquated technologies,
but it's like,
sure,
great,
but I'm going to be sitting in my
pleasure pod with vr goggles on is I get
taken to Florida.
We're off the sacred river flows,
which are missing the pleasure of the
wooden wheel.
Losing traction on the muddy road.
Exactly the box,
not aerodynamic box.
Being dragged by horses starts to go
sideways near the edge of the cliff.
What an adventure.
What a great time to be alive,
but I don't even have to ride the horse.
I can ride in a box behind the horse.
Not our technology is awesome.
Progress being that box with fine silk
like seeding.
Everything would be made with pushup
Bra.
The core sets,
the core sets lots of ruffled skirts.
Fucking trying to bang a chick,
one of those skirts.
Which disaster.
Okay.
Then you've got to make a choice.
Either you don't see her vagina or you
don't see your face.
It's one or the other.
He can't have it both ways.
If you push that thing up,
she's gone.
Hold on.
You know his citic Jews have sex through
a sheet with a gun in it.
My friend John Joke about it that the
women used to look.
Look at the clothes line.
So you had the biggest hole,
Jon Tobin.
The thing.
Think about that stuff man.
Like who's the for like someone had to
be the first person to be like,
you know what?
Let's put a big sheet over you and cut a
hole right over your pussy so I don't
see you anymore.
Like that.
Didn't evolve,
didn't even touch it.
It's not just a not see you that your
bodies don't touch to.
So someone invented that though,
right?
There was a person who's like,
I've got an idea.
Let's start putting the women in
blankets and fucking a whole right.
It doesn't evolve,
right Chris?
It's like there's a per.
There's one person who's incredibly
crazy,
I guess evolved,
you know,
it may have just been like a hankie over
someone's face initially,
you know,
and then it grew.
You can never know.
It may have started as a blindfold,
but you,
it implies the communication about it.
Like you have to tell your friends like,
well,
you know,
I put a handkerchief over her face last
night.
Maybe you guys should start doing that
with even crazier that it took off.
It's not like one guy doing it like
Hasidic Jews.
It's a huge population of people in
America.
In New York City.
There's a very big community of acidic
Jews and they're all doing that with the
blanket.
I don't know if they do.
I don't know the.
And I think the women all shaved their
heads and were widows to shave.
I see it as an x,
no makeup and no talking.
What the fuck?
Damn team.
They had to wear a wig.
I think about it and the Arabs make them
cover their hair right here.
I think it's an expression of anti
eroticism,
anti pleasure,
right?
You're only going to have kids.
There's no pleasure involved.
So we're going to do as much as possible
to remove everything that is in purely
functional.
You know,
the thing that you're talking about,
the Tesla thing.
The thing is bizarre about that is in
the fine print,
it says it's in Beta.
You went to your car,
self driving car that's in Beta.
It says that they're not responsible for
any accident.
So you should always watch the road and
be prepared to step in if something goes
wrong.
Like,
well thanks for nothing.
Back in my computer making days.
I used to have friends that would get
the latest builds of software of um,
um,
operating systems rather.
And so they would run like Beta versions
of like new windows operating systems
and the shit was always crashing,
but it was kind of half of the fun half.
The Fun for those guys was like saying,
hey man,
I'm using windows nt,
you know,
Blah Blah Blah and this is the new shit
and it's really only for server.
So I have to have a workaround with
certain drivers for video cards.
You know,
there's all this crazy shit they used to
do.
Remember though is like when you got
windows,
you had to get this giant pack of desks.
Sometimes you'd get two of these tubes
filled with those things.
Remember,
you would start off with a floppy.
You'd have to start out with a floppy
that was like your install your foods
that worked.
The floppy was like,
you'd stick that in and then you'd have
to stick cd roms and like,
what the fuck?
All right.
My first exposure to computers was when
I worked in real estate in New York,
in the diamond district full of Hasidic
Jews.
That's there you go.
Uh,
and uh,
the guy had a computers the size of a
refrigerator and one of my jobs was to
backup the discs every week.
And you'd pull out these drawers and put
this thing down and turn it and pull it
out.
And the disc was about that big.
You're showing your hands like an album
a lot bigger than an album.
Yeah.
Like I'm large pizza,
a large pizza that Herman Biggs was on
that,
I don't know.
I think it was megabytes.
Oh my God.
That's hilarious.
This was 86 or so.
That's so funny.
It's so funny.
Like the amount of storage space that we
have now,
it's kind of nuts and then also like
that.
So much of it is in the cloud.
But if you'd noticed like on the new
iphone software,
you're doesn't download all your songs.
It shows you all your songs,
but when you go to play them it streams
them.
Yeah.
I don't get that because I want the shit
on my phone.
So if I'm not connected or I don't have
to pay for the data,
it's my fucking state.
I got 128 gigs on my phone,
fill it with
music.
I can't sit here and how to do it.
Well you set it so that it's available
offline and then you download all of
them.
You have to download all of them.
It's super annoying.
I didn't know hotel the other day.
It's like now downloading 847 songs and
I was like,
what?
The fuck,
but you know when you're in a place that
doesn't have cell phone service and
you'd go to your music list.
I was trying to use it in the gym.
There was no service.
It was like,
Oh,
you fuckers,
it's not on my phone,
and I had to figure it out.
It's complaints back in the day.
Yeah.
It wasn't your complaint in the carriage
and your fucking slippery right over the
top of the mountain where you might wind
up eating all your friends because you
gets stuck up there.
Crazy man that we are constantly
surrounded by some cloud of invisible
data that consists of all information
that has ever been recorded.
That's crazy.
Did you hear about that guy?
That was.
He went to see.
He got shipwrecked at sea for like over
a year with another guy and he made it
by like drinking rain water,
needing turtles and all kinds of crazy
shit,
but it's the nuttiest stories.
They're kind of raft for a fucking year,
but his companions family is now suing
him because they say that he hates them.
Yeah.
He ate the other guy,
the Mexican guy.
The Mexican fisherman,
they Mexican,
I dunno,
I dunno if they're Mexican,
but just the thought behind it.
Jim Probably stores just the thought
behind it and banks sued.
That's what's funny.
It's cannibalism.
It's on a criminal complaint.
It's a civil suit.
I don't know what it is because I don't
know if it's American.
I don't know if they have a different
legal system.
I don't even know what it is,
but I don't even know if they're suing
or if they're trying to accuse him out
and murdering him or something.
Eating them.
It's the eating that bothered,
but if he's dead,
eat him.
Well,
he said that's what I say.
Eat me if I die,
but what they say is that this guy shirt
by the way,
was claiming that he kept the dude on
the boat with them for company for six
days.
Then throw them overboard.
They sued for $1,000,000
for you,
but here's the thing,
like how they prove that he ain't.
How do you even accuse a guy?
I think he.
He talked about it.
He talked to me yet because he's
Salvadorian,
but they got.
They were in Mexico and they got swept
out that I've read about this one.
So he talked about eating the guy.
Yeah.
So I think that's how the story says
that he just threw the guy overboard.
It seems like you would want your family
member to have like given his life for
somebody.
It kind of makes your family member or a
hero or lots of cultures.
Ether did you know when someone dies
they eat them.
Yeah.
And it's an honor that is incredible.
More than a year and see,
um,
see if,
uh,
he admitted dreamy find it safe anywhere
he admitted he paid this guy to
accompany him on a short fishing trip
off the coast of Mexico.
Wow.
Yeah.
And he wrote a book.
So they want the money from the book.
Yeah.
He might be right
or you might have ate that dude.
It looks like it looks like you need to
do,
you know,
I used to think it.
I think most people think some cultures
were just cannibals for the hell of it,
you know,
like they were just especially evil,
right.
The aztecs or whatever.
And then others just weren't,
but you know,
if you think about it,
it doesn't make sense.
So Europeans killed just as many people
as the aztecs did.
They were just as ruthless.
They're burning them at the stake,
you know,
they even cook them,
but they didn't need him.
Right?
Right.
So then I read this guy,
Marvin Harris,
this anthropologist who wrote a book
called Cannibals and kings.
He went back and looked at societies
that were cannibalistic and those that
weren't,
especially in the South Pacific because
some islands worse.
I'm islands weren't whatever.
And in Latin America.
And what he determined was that the
societies that were cannibalistic had,
um,
a lack of protein,
there were no animals that could be
domesticated.
And so when they killed people in
battle,
they ate them because they were protein
hungry or starved.
And.
But Europeans had plenty of domesticated
animals.
So they didn't need the protein because
they had the goats and the pigs and
whatever.
But if you think about Mexico,
there's nothing that they could
domesticate except turkeys or dogs or
animals that eat the same food as
humans.
So you need to domesticate an animal
that doesn't eat what humans eat,
so it's not competing.
Right.
And there were not in in North America.
So that's why they were cannibals.
Wow,
that's crazy.
That's fascinating.
It.
It's also important to note that I.
One of the key tenants of Catholicism
involves the kind of metaphysical
cannibalism,
which is,
you know,
at the,
at the communion,
the body of current body of Christ,
and they call that conversion of the
wafer into the flesh of Christ.
They have a name.
They think that when you're,
when the priest is doing the ritual,
it's turning it into the flesh of Jesus.
The trends.
Transubstantiation is the name for it,
and that's where you're shifting the
wafer into the flesh of a god that
you're eating.
But that's totally real.
Oh,
that's totally,
totally real.
You can taste it,
but they get the right stuff.
It's kosher.
Many of them do think that that it is
real.
It's,
it's Godflesh,
which is actually a really old,
that's a very old tradition,
which is you eat,
you eat a god,
you eat the sacrifice God to get its
energy or something.
What high deval originated with
entheogens?
There's no,
no doubt that at all.
Immediately what I thought of is the
Amanita muscarinic where the
psychoactive component stays active
after it's metabolized.
So the pis of the Shaman who's eating
almond eaters,
Scalia will get you high as shit.
Yeah.
I just saw they fed them piss
at that.
Apparently Amany to Ms Dot Mascara is
very hard to get.
Right.
I've never,
I've never gotten hired off of it.
I had,
we tried it once,
it didn't work,
but then we tried siliciden mushrooms
with it and we had a fucking insane
journey so they might've worked together
and sort of sort of synergistic way.
But um,
apparently by itself it's really hard
and they think that it might be like a
geographical variant like and then also
like seasonally and then genetically
like you have to get the right stuff and
the right stuff might not even exist in
most places anymore.
Right.
That's pretty interesting,
isn't it?
All that follow the last pharmacology
they staff they will never even know
about.
Like a Soma Soma.
Yeah.
What is it like?
What is this stuff you hear about this
all the time?
All of these old technologies that are
just gone in the illusion mysteries.
I didn't realize this until recently.
The Shamsi Lazy Lazy days or however you
pronounce it in Paris.
That's the illusion.
Mushrooms,
so it translates is illusion and
mushrooms shops,
right?
Jumping Melanie's.
There's unquestionably without a doubt.
There were people that lived a long time
ago,
the discovered psychedelic plants they
had to have and all.
You have to just consider.
I mean this is the most rational way to
look at it.
If you lived at that time and you had no
science,
you had some,
some myths and fables and some rules to
live by and you found those things,
you would think that you had found God.
You would definitely think if you,
if you just ate,
you don't have a scale.
You're just eating these mushrooms that
you find and you eat 10 grams of them
could lord,
you're going to meet God.
You literally will be transported to
God.
I never let you know.
People will listen to this kind of shit
and they'll go,
oh man,
that's so stupid.
No,
you're just tripping.
He's just hallucinating.
You got to take this into consideration.
I know I've said it before,
but it is important to repeat when you
haven't experienced.
It doesn't matter if that experience is
like you could put a scale or hit it
with a stick.
It's a real experience.
So you,
even though you're no one's saying that
you're meeting God when you do
mushrooms,
but what I am saying is it's the same
thing as meeting God.
Like the experience is so profound that
you.
It would be like doing that.
It would be like having.
When you do DMT,
perfect example,
it is like meeting the highest power
around you.
It's like meeting a god.
It's like eating a sea of gods.
It feels like there's a place where
things can be both true and untrue.
I think you know,
and and what you're talking about is
that overlap for me.
It's where,
you know,
like placebo effect.
You say,
well,
it's just a sugar pill.
Yeah,
it's just a sugar pill,
but it has demonstrable,
measurable,
repeatable effects on people.
Hypnosis is another one,
like wow,
the fuck does that work?
Nobody's explained this and,
and I think when,
when you're talking about seeing God,
that is ultimately a subjective
experience that happened or didn't and
if it did,
then it did.
And there's no,
there's no one from outside who can say,
ah,
it's just bullshit or that you know,
some sort of Richard Dawkins denial of
the sacred because you experienced
it.
And so I'm sort of sympathetic.
I mean,
I trash religion as much as the next
guy,
but I'm sympathetic for the experience
of someone who says,
look,
I go there,
I have these rituals,
I smell that stuff.
I was raised in this tradition and I am
transported to another world that makes
my life better.
I can't say that's not real despite the
bullshit of the Bible or whatever.
Yeah.
No,
I agree with you.
I,
you know,
I think is problematic.
Is the label,
like even how I said it,
like you'll meet God like that.
Just that word is so loaded.
Right.
That's,
that's a big part of the problem,
a big part of the problem with just the
idea of religious religious ideas like
forget about the words that you're
using,
whether you're using the word prayer or
scripture or whatever the name you have
for your deity.
Those are just noise is you're making
and they correspond to like whatever the
cultural context is of the Hindu God or
the Christian God,
but if you just think of the feeling of
wanting to be a good Christian,
right?
The feeling of wanting to please God.
Not by billowing up abortion clinics or
any.
There's none of that.
None of the wacky aspects of it that we
sort of connect to it.
We think about like radical fundamental
religion on any side of the fence,
right?
But with the feeling that you're
getting,
like you're feeling.
If you're all together in church and you
really are praising his name,
you really are praising the idea of this
loving God that wants fellowship and
wants camaraderie and brotherhood.
Like whatever that feeling is and
whatever that thought is.
Take out all the words,
Jesus Christ and you know,
praise Jesus and Buddha and Muhammad and
Allah,
and take out all those words and what is
the feeling like that feeling is search
for this positive,
this positive source,
like this thing that ultimately we can
all eventually reach if we put aside all
of our ridiculous monkey behavior and
greed and jealousy and anger and lust
and just get to us at our very best,
you know,
and it's almost like it's like a guide
to get you there,
but we get tripped up on the words that
are attached to the guide,
like the word God or the word Muhammad
or the morgue.
Allah or Krishna Krishna go down the
line
and the fucking parasites that latch on
to this and start selling shit.
And you know,
making a structure around the rules.
Controlling people with Duncan started
off talking about how you can recognize
someone not just as a spiritually
enlightened person,
but as a just a person you want to hang
out with.
If they are really hard to offend,
if they have a good sense of humor,
if they don't have a sense of humor,
there's something wrong,
you know,
and but you think about the Old
Testament God,
he's the most easily offended
motherfucker imaginable.
You know,
like the book of job.
If you ever read the book of job,
it's fucking amazing.
Like job is this great guy does
everything he's supposed to do.
Everything's cool and the devil and God
are hanging out one day.
And the devil's like that.
God,
the devil says like,
people don't really like you so much,
man.
You know,
you think everybody loves you.
And God's like.
Of course people love me.
Look at job.
He's perfect.
He does everything I tell him.
And the devil is like,
yeah,
but he only does what you tell him cause
you've been good to him.
Fuck with them a little bit and you'll
see what happened.
So God being the fucked up asshole that
he is apparently killed job's wife and
kids.
You know,
that's not a,
it's not meant to be taken literally
though.
I mean,
that's not a literal,
that's a.
that's a story of the fact that,
no,
God,
Duncan,
of course it's to be taken literally.
You question what kind of truck driver,
motherfucker.
This is how cocky Duncan is dark and
it's like,
well,
I think what Jesus really taught wasn't
so good with his words back and since
I've gone to college in North Carolina,
he's got a phd.
I had been talking to God,
God gave me a phd,
but no,
I think that you run into trouble if you
start looking at mythology and like is
though.
That's really what it means.
I get to actually do it,
but look at the god that's being
depicted.
There were,
there was whatever the story is,
he's easily,
he's jealous,
he's capricious,
he's cruel,
he's a fucking alcoholic father.
But that's.
So if you look at it,
the universe,
like right now at this moment,
mothers are dying of cancer,
kids are getting exploded by bombs.
All of it.
Dogs are attacking fucking old people in
the farm.
Like,
you know what I mean?
So this is the story of job has always
struck me more as a kind of like a story
of how look man,
you can't understand the infinite.
Like when I step on an ant,
you know what I mean?
To me it's like,
well I stepped on an ant today to it,
but for whatever that aunt tiny little
subjective universe happens to be,
I've completely obliterated it.
I wiped it out that and could never
possibly understand the internet action
that just happened there.
But it was a real interaction.
So it seems like the story of job is
more like,
what the fuck are you universe?
This incredible thing that I'm
surrounded by that seems to vary
capriciously at random times just
destroy people and lives and like,
shit man.
I just heard about this family driving
under an underpass and that like a bird,
like a concrete block fell out of a
truck,
landed on the Goddamn Range Rover.
Damn.
Entire family zapped out of this
universe.
And to me job was.
That's the stats,
what the story is like how,
how can someone be a servant of love?
Like what you were talking about,
how can someone connect to this desire
to like give love and happiness and joy
into the universe when it any second
guaranteed for any human being there
could be in there will be a tragedy,
more devastating than anything you could
ever imagine because that's just the way
the world works.
You're going to die.
Your,
your,
your wife,
your family,
your friends.
This is the reality we're in.
And how in that kind of swirling vortex
of chaos and violence,
do you find a place where regardless of
all of that,
you will still be committed as much as
you can,
uh,
to,
to do that thing you did on the road
when the fucking car hit here instead of
getting out and fucking pummeling the
guy because you're agenda,
adrenaline's flowing.
You ask,
Hey,
are you all right?
That's wild.
I mean,
to you it might seem like not that big a
deal,
but if everyone on planet earth started
doing that,
Whoa,
Holy Shit.
It'd be a whole new.
Uh,
I think,
uh,
I mean I agree with what you're saying,
but I think there's an underlying is s
assertion of the cruelty of the universe
that I think is distorted.
Okay.
I think that,
you know,
I was watching this nature program a
couple of weeks ago and there was a
seal,
I may have even talked with you about
this last time when it was on,
but there was like a seal playing in the
waves and then you hear the like do,
do,
do and you see the shadow coming up and
it's a great white and it hits the seal.
And then they,
the guy,
the narrator actually says we slow this
down to a one 40th of normal speed,
right?
And you see the teeth of the and the,
and the seals flopping around and
there's blood everywhere.
And,
and in the meanwhile the narrator saying
the struggle for survival isn't ever
over.
And so I'm watching that and I'm
thinking,
well,
but seal seemed Kinda happy to me.
Right?
Like how come they're not more stressed
out?
Because all the seals I've seen relying
on rocks and chilling,
chilling,
and bargain and having fun.
So I looked up.
This seal is a harbor seal.
I think they lived to be about 30.
So let's say this one's in its prime.
It's 25.
Okay.
It's whole fucking life.
It's been lying on warm rocks and eaten
fresh fish.
And then in half a second it's dead.
Okay.
And we're looking at that as evidence of
the cruelty of nature.
That what's the ratio there?
You know,
what's the ratio of good days to bad
days?
It seems like it's pretty fucking good.
True.
And I read this amazing account of being
pounced on by Elian by,
I think it was who searched for
Livingston in,
in Africa.
I remember livings,
Dr Livingston,
I presume.
Anyway,
that guy,
he got pants on by a lion and he talks
about how he didn't describe it this
way,
but the endorphins that are released
when you're dying,
right?
Especially in prey animals.
And he was completely detached,
completely relaxed.
Watching this lion tossing him around.
Well,
they think there's an evolutionary
advantage to both species,
both the Predator and the prey in them
having this endorphin release when they
get got,
because when,
when lions
attack like antelopes or with big cats
catch deer,
the deer kind of given man,
they get Jack,
they nexia,
but they don't.
They kind of like fight a little and
then they kind of give in,
but like bears,
like those kind of animals,
they don't really give in like that,
so they don't like if a,
if a cat and a mountain lion or or or a
mountain line rather than a bear go at
it like the bear isn't just going to
give in to the mountain lion.
As the mountain lion bites the bear and
it's neck,
the bear is going to try to turn and
bite them back and they're going to
tooth and claw it out.
They're not going to give wonder if he
would give into a dinosaur.
Whew.
That's a good point.
Something where the power is
overwhelming and you feel it.
Like there's.
I ain't getting out of this.
If that.
What triggers the release?
That's a very good point.
That thing that you're talking about
right there is the secret of happiness,
which is that fucking release because if
you really look at it,
man,
we are in the mouth of a super predator.
It's the entire universe and it's slowly
killing us right now that it's true.
It's like,
I mean,
it does sound like dire,
but on one level it sounds dire,
but then the idea is like you have to
accept the situation that you're in and
it is true.
We are like being like we're in the
mouth of the most incredible,
most powerful,
most omnipresent thing ever.
We earlier when you were talking about,
uh,
you know,
you smoked Dmt,
you have this experience of God.
You see God,
whatever it is you have,
you see this incredible matrix of
consciousness or when you're on a per
theoretically on Ios guy.
I haven't done it in mushrooms,
but the funny thing about it is right
now minus the Psychedelic,
you are surrounded by an entire universe
of which pieces of the universe are
alive and aware of you and are talking
to you,
to psychedelics sorta just force feeds
you that reality exactly,
or it paints it to.
It puts a different coat of paint on top
of it,
so now it seems unique novel again,
but you,
you.
It's just another level of the same
experiences happening,
which is that you are surrounded by a
living,
partially living,
a universe that has a tendency from time
to time to produce life.
This universe that we're in produces
life and you're part of it and you're
surrounded by an infinite ocean of that
tendency,
so that's very overwhelming I think for
people,
which is why they begin to accept that
this was just completely normal.
This thing,
this,
and then that's when you take the
psychedelic and you're like,
Holy Shit,
I saw God.
It's like,
no.
You saw the exact same thing that you've
been seeing.
It's only that you saw it in a different
form.
For whatever reason,
people don't want to accept this stuff
that's happening around us right now as
God.
They don't want to accept it.
They don't accept that.
What this thing is around us is super
natural.
It's crazy to see.
This is what Joe was talking earlier,
a
foragers finding these substances.
I was thinking exactly what you're
talking about because we take those
substances and it's like a revelation
and the veil is pulled back.
What is the veil?
The veil is culture.
We live in a culture that is constantly
trying to put out the fire of mystery in
us.
It's constantly saying,
no life is about having this car,
this kind of house.
Get a new air conditioner,
go to work.
Don't,
don't be looking for mystery.
Just go to work and punch the fucking
clock.
All right,
go work in your mind or your cubicle or
whatever.
It's trying,
constantly trying to get us to accept
this bum fucking deal,
right?
Whereas foragers,
they're surrounded by mystery everyday,
everyday everything's alive.
Everything is full of spirit.
There's the spirit of the river.
The spirit of the clouds,
the spirit of the air,
they're surrounded by spirits,
so I wonder what their experience with
psychedelics is like because I don't
think it has.
I mean I'm sure it heightens everything
and is amazing and obviously has as
sacred value,
but I don't think it has that same
revelatory aspect
for regulatory thing because they're not
confined to the bullshit of like
buildings and streets and traffic lights
and taxes and all these things that we
hold in the forefront of our mind,
our consciousness that are really just
retarded.
We've created these things.
The most of the things that people come
up with to occupy their mind during the
day are things that we've come up with
that we've discovered or be or created
and be decided that there are
significant tax laws or jobs or social
status for breeding.
I think.
I think it gets back to this point.
I think the whole thing is an edifice
built to distract ourselves from our
mortality.
I think that's what civilization is.
It certainly could be or it could be a
mechanism for us to continue to create
technology and innovate because the best
way to do that is to not have a good
perspective,
not have not realized that if,
if,
if we,
if our perspective is really good and we
realized that we're these temporary
beings who just love each other and
spend as much time together in comradery
and friendship as possible.
We're not going to get shit done.
We're all going to look at all the
phones we have now and then go.
We're good.
We just keep using these phones and
everyone's fine.
We look at our tvs and that is a very
big TV.
We're good.
My computer is super fast.
My Internet seems fine.
Let's just leave all this stuff alone
and hang out.
Right?
That's right.
You need the discontent to create the
technology.
So the question is whose but,
but whose interest is all of in that
because it's not in ours.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's the super organism.
Marshall Mcluhan,
quote,
Marshall Mcluhan's sex organs,
and the machine was my favorite quote
ever.
And I think that one of the things we've
done by lighting everything up also is
we've gotten rid of the psychedelic
vision that is space.
You no longer
see space,
uh,
you have to,
if you go on a trip to the desert and
you go out to the desert in the high
desert and you look up at night,
you're like,
wow,
you get that majestic vision of the
cosmos.
We don't get it in la anymore.
It's gone.
We smoked it out.
We smoked it out with streetlights.
When you got tomatoes,
that'll look good for a long time but
haven't been fucking flavor.
Yeah.
And roses that don't smell like roses,
they don't what they smelled like
nothing because because they've got to
breathe that they will last much longer
looking good.
But it doesn't have the smell,
but just spray perfume on them,
Bro.
That's what they do.
Seriously.
That's what they spray rose perfume on
roses.
I went to dinner once.
This French chick made me dinner.
This beautiful,
wonderful French woman.
And uh,
but I didn't like anything she liked so
it was a difficult relationship,
you know,
like she liked sailing,
she had this little sailboat and for me
sailing is like skin cancer,
guaranteed skin cancer.
Like I'm going to be a pale because I'm
super pale.
I'm out on the water,
no shade,
you know,
we're waiting for wind,
I'm dead,
I'm dead.
Anyway.
So she made this dinner for me one night
and I went to her place and everything
was beautiful and it was all set up with
candles and,
you know,
nice silver.
And uh,
it was escar go fucking eat escargot go
man.
I'm American.
I don't eat snails,
but I was going to go through it just
because she went to all this trouble.
Twenty eight,
29 something.
And uh,
so she has this big pot of escargo
shells in the sauce tomato sauce and she
puts it on her.
And so I pick up the first one and suck
up the sauce and there's no snap and I'm
like,
lucked out.
And uh,
then it picked up the next one.
Same thing again,
no snail.
And I'm looking at her across the table
and she's getting this weird look on her
face.
There were no snails.
She'd bought the shells.
They sell the snail separately.
You have to put the snails back in the
shells.
What?
I don't know.
Something about you spraying perfume on
roses with no smell reminded me of that
is so ridiculous.
So she made a big pot of snail shell,
snail shell suit tomatoes.
Snail's shell suit.
That's hard to say.
Snail shell suit.
Snail shells.
Yeah.
My mouth doesn't want to say that.
Snare snail shell suit.
Snail Shell.
Snail snail.
You're right.
It is bizarre that they would separate
them.
Why would you take the snails out and
make people put them back in maybe to
clean them?
Shipping.
Yeah.
Maybe a cleanliness issue.
But then you would know that they
weren't fresh.
Like the whole idea is that you want to
catch them and they do something to
them.
No,
that's something that,
uh,
I was.
There's a guy online who is a wild game
cook,
a famous wild game cook.
And he's been on Steve Rinella,
his television show.
And one of the things he does is
he takes wild foods like mushrooms and
stuff,
and it incorporates than likely if he,
if he eats like a deer,
he cooks at deer meal,
he'll use like a lot of the local
ingredients like local plants and local
mushrooms and things like that.
And uh,
he did that with some snails and he had
to purge them.
So I guess you do something where you
take them and you like leave them in
water for a long period of time or
something.
Like let them dedicate and let them
pass.
I think that that might be.
That makes sense.
Yeah.
You don't want each snail pissed now.
That's what you eat lobster,
right?
That.
Hold down the last line we talked about
fecal transplant.
We have definitely.
I haven't stopped talking about it.
It's pretty bizarre.
The idea that microbes from another
person's poop can actually help your
body.
Yeah.
That's pretty wild.
High being born vaginally.
You get your mother's microbiome all
over your skin and in your mouth and
stuff from her genital secretions.
So when kids are born csection,
they don't get that.
They're much more likely to have asthma
and all this stuff because they.
So what you got to do,
even if you have a c section,
is smear pussy juice all over the kid's
face.
Literally.
I don't think you should say that.
We should probably edit that out.
That's just what the doctor ordered.
There are new rules,
this society and your pussy juice
anymore.
That'll get you fired.
I think it was Yale,
but over that.
Sorry.
We were talking about before the podcast
started about the Social Justice Warrior
placemats that Harvard had given to
children to take home with them.
And I say children because if your
parents are paying for your education,
your fucking child,
you're still a child.
I don't care what.
I don't care if you're 18,
I don't care if you could vote.
I don't care if he can go to war.
They,
uh,
they sent these placemats home with
these kids explaining how to talk to
your parents if controversial issues
come up.
Like if your parents exhibit xenophobia
or sexism transphobia.
And so they literally are there.
They're giving them these placemats.
Yeah.
We'll pull it up.
The Harvard just apologize for it today
for the place mat.
Well,
some intelligent people probably got
ahold of him.
What the fuck are you doing?
You're teaching people how to be only
liberal progressive thinkers like think
only the way you guys want them to
think.
Can they?
Are they allowed to have a nuanced
opinion on subjects that are
controversial?
Like there's some things you're not
allowed to have a nuanced opinion about.
You're not even allowed to debate it,
and that was what happened at.
Yeah,
when they were talking about offensive
Halloween costumes.
Here it is the Yale student active tips
for talking to family members.
Oh my God.
This is hilarious.
Listen mindfully before a formula and
thoughtful response.
When people express strong opinions,
affirm,
clarify the difference between the good
intentions and the impact.
Speak.
Speak from a place of mutual interest,
sharing personal experiences and
emotions.
Oh my God.
And they talk about black murders in the
streets.
Why don't they just listened to the
officer if they,
if they just had obeyed the law,
this wouldn't have happened.
Response.
Let me come on.
Look at this,
this hilarious.
Do you think,
do you think the response would be the
same if it was a white person being
pulled over,
like look at what they're doing here.
This is teaching people how to talk to
their parents about controversial social
issues like Islamophobia.
Oh my God.
What is this that we shouldn't let
anyone in the US from Syria.
We can't guarantee that terrorists won't
infiltrate their.
This is the worst fucking Christmas
dinner ever.
Horrible.
This is not the Christmas dinner.
There's a fucking o'reilly factor.
US has been accepting refugees from the
war torn areas around the world for
decades.
Remember the wars in Central America?
They were extremely violent in the US
accepted refugees.
All right.
Whatever.
It's just boring Yale student activism
one.
Why are the black students complaining?
Shouldn't they be happy to be in college
response?
When I hear students expressing their
experiences of racism on campus,
I don't hear complaining.
Instead,
I hear young people uplifting is
situation that I may not.
You know what my dad's doing it at this
point when I'm reading this,
my dad will start making ozark start
going.
By the way of lifting is not a fucking
verb.
Yeah.
Know.
Could somebody tell her fancy boys sign?
You need to,
but there's a harvard placemat.
It's about the ell student,
but look,
listen,
if non black students got the privilege,
get the privilege of a safe environment,
I believe that same privilege should be
given to all students.
Like you just said nothing.
That is a nonsense statement.
You don't hear them complaining when
they're complaining.
Well,
that's bizarre.
If people are complaining,
they're definitely complaining.
Very good.
Exactly.
There's nothing negative about
complaining.
They might have a very good point.
If you don't hear complaining,
then you're not paying attention.
Black murder section.
Now that is.
That seems pretty logical.
The response read it.
Do you think their response would be the
same if there was a white person being
pulled over in many incidents that
result in the death of a black body in
the street?
These victims are not breaking the law
and are unarmed with Tamir seems right
on.
He was a 12 year old boy playing in the
park.
When the officers pulled up,
they gave no verbal commands and shot
within two seconds of arriving at the
scene.
He was not breaking any laws.
You know this.
It's just because I just watched someone
made a youtube montage of cops shooting
people.
It's insane it
you've seen that.
Yeah.
It's crazy.
And,
and I was thinking my Christ man,
if I was black and got pulled over by a
cop,
I'd be shitting myself.
Oh yeah.
Because they just shoot.
Not only that,
you're dealing with someone who is
encountering bad people all day.
Most of the people that cops and counter
all day or breaking the law,
most of the people that are either
pulling them,
pulling them over for going too fast or
they're doing something stupid or
they're trying to steal something and
they're trying to rob somebody or
they're showing up at a scene after
someone's done something fucked up.
Yeah.
So just think about the stress that a
normal person's under and multiply that
times 100.
You get paid like 40 grand a year.
People want to shoot out.
Yeah.
You weren't a goddamn bulletproof vest
and you're going to someone,
someone's car and it's a young black guy
and he doesn't use his rap.
Music is loud.
He's not even turning it down.
You're like,
God damn it is today.
The day I get shot and killed,
or I say the day I die
and let's not forget that a lot of these
dudes are coming back from wars.
So a lot of them have ptsd and they were
trained where they were an occupying
force.
So they,
they take that training and they apply
it to joining the police force.
And the population is the enemy.
Everyone is a potential,
uh,
you know,
it's a suicide vest.
I got into a conversation with my uber
driver,
this black dude,
and he was like a talking about getting
pulled over recently.
And I told him,
man,
I haven't been pulled over and like,
I don't know,
nine years.
And he's like,
what?
I'm white lol.
He gets pulled over all the time,
you know?
And so like,
that's fucked up man.
Like that's like that,
that to live in that kind of world where
you realize that you're just,
you just have to accept getting pulled
over and you have to accept the fact
that there is some chance if you make
the wrong move or if the cops snaps
because of for whatever reason you're
dead.
That happens all the time.
There was that one where the cops pulled
a guy over and there's a video of him,
the completely different interaction.
The cop described,
the guy pulls his gun out.
You could just shoots the guy in this
fucking car.
No one's in trouble knowing scared.
No one's in danger.
Terrible people
just shouldn't be cops.
There's definitely people that shouldn't
be cops.
I think most people.
How about that and what about these
cases where they like swat the right
into someone's house in the middle of
the night and shoot them in bed and then
it's like,
oh,
wrong house.
Or they shoot a dog.
They love shooting the dogs.
Yeah,
and taking the property.
That's the other thing.
This country,
they're motivated.
Motivated,
motivated,
motivated.
Yeah.
There's a word they're incentivized as
far as two to get into shit,
you know,
to get,
get into trouble,
find trouble because they get the house,
they get the car and there's,
you know,
in 2015 cops took more property than
burglars did.
Yeah,
I saw that.
Wait a minute and that goes right into
the local police department's budget and
he doesn't even go to Washington and
they bought Margarita machines and the
North Carolina to
see that.
I didn't see that.
They will pull them over and they just
take it and say,
well,
you have to figure out a way to prove to
us that this money was made illegal.
The asset forfeiture surpass burglaries
for the first time ever.
That's crazy important point.
You don't even have to be charged with
the crime.
They can just say,
what are you doing walking around with
10 grand in cash and you have to.
You've got to prove.
And also think about how much of this is
related to drugs and then so when you
realize the asset forfeiture is actually
happening for something that shouldn't
be illegal anyway.
Like do you watch,
have you watched,
it's called drunk tank.
Have you seen this show where it's like,
I dunno,
it shows it's a show where after someone
gets pulled over for a Dui,
they get thrown in the drunk tank and
man,
there's to me,
nothing more viral than seeing a cop
smugly like searching a person and
pulling marijuana out of his pocket and
being like,
well,
well what do we have here?
Marrow wanna.
Look at this.
That's going to be something that
history is going to judge in the most
intense way.
Every single cop that's been on a
reality show,
smugly taking someone's weed for them,
putting handcuffs on them because they
had weed for eternity,
they're going to be looked back on in a
really fucking awful way.
They're going to want to scrub the
Internet from some of that footage
because they're enforcing a law that.
I mean,
we all preaching the choir here,
but there's something so foul about it
that smugness,
you know,
it's so disgusting for nothing,
for nothing,
for literally nothing.
Literally nothing.
No.
Well,
not less than nothing.
Something they enjoy.
It's not just for nothing,
it's,
it's more we're
discussing that because it's positive,
it's beneficial,
it enhances their life,
it makes food taste better.
Right.
Well,
that gets us back to the seeing God in a
mushroom,
right?
Yeah.
Every culture that's ever had access to
hallucinogens have seen them as the
greatest gift of the gods.
Right?
The most sacred,
the most beautiful gifts they've been
given in our country,
in the United States.
You go to prison for longer,
under minimum.
Mandatory for having a LSD.
LSD.
Yeah.
Right.
LSD.
Then for second degree murder.
Think about that.
So it's not only wasteful and weird and
awkward.
Now it's the and and to me that,
you know,
ties into my argument that we live in a
culture that it sets out to deny
mystery.
This is where I differ from you.
I don't know the culture sets out to
deny it or if all these things are kind
of in place and they all benefit each
other and the overall result is that the
culture denies it's reality.
I don't necessarily think there's any
design involved.
I know,
well,
see this is it designed versus
evolution.
I agree with you,
I think it's a system that replicates
itself and supports itself and spins out
sub that support
the central mechanism.
Yeah.
I don't.
I don't think Henry Kissinger's behind
it know I.
I know you don't,
but I mean,
I don't think there's anyone that
doesn't want us.
Anyone that doesn't want us to be aware
of art.
I just don't think anybody's attention
entire advertising industry doesn't want
us to know the reality of what they're
selling.
They're not even.
Oh,
that's different.
Yeah.
Okay.
That's.
They're trying.
I mean there's a whole,
you know,
Edward Bernays,
right?
The Great.
Yeah.
The Guy who founded advertising
essentially and also worked for the CIA
also came up with the word defending
freedom abroad,
justification for American military
adventures.
I mean he was central and he very
clearly said like,
we need to create reality for people
because if they are allowed to create
their own reality,
they won't buy stuff.
They won't do what we need them to do.
They won't vote for who we need them to
vote for.
So there's an elite that has to create
reality for the masses and it's logical.
If you like,
if we will,
if we got assigned to and we are
assholes and we got assigned to some
massive group of people that we needed
to control and we needed to,
like we needed them to think that we
were in charge.
That was the first thing.
You would have certain rules that you
had that they had to abide by and the
first rule would be don't let them take
psychedelics man,
because if they start fucking tripping,
they're going to realize we're just
three dudes just like listen to us
anymore.
Which is why I think there is a five
year mandatory minimum when it comes to
lsd because when you take Lsd,
the entire thing seems absolutely
absurd.
From money to the government to jobs at
all seems like a ridiculous thing that
everyone else seems to have accepted as
like,
yeah,
this is just how you do shit.
Right?
But question,
the people that are enforcing the laws
are not the people that created those
laws and the people that are enforcing
the laws most certainly have not
experienced these things.
That's why we need to get comps
tripping.
Yeah,
but you're right,
I agree.
I think that there's,
there's a certain momentum that these
laws and that this propaganda has sort
of set in motion that's going to be
really hard to slow down and stop and
we're starting to do that with pot.
The availability and the relaxation.
The way people view pot in 2015 is way
different than 2005 or two.
I mean there's,
there's a approved research going on,
there's a fantastic clinical
application,
you know,
and the old guard has to die.
Well yeah,
it works.
You know,
people that started those laws,
the fucking Joe Friday's dragnet guys
like those guys are dead.
So like the people that like started
this whole sweeping psychedelic
legislation act of 1970,
I believe it was when they made
everything scheduled.
Yeah.
Were just trying to batten down the
hatches.
We have to stop these fucking hippies.
Like everything was crazy.
The response to Vietnam War,
but he wanted to get out.
It was,
it was the culture
explosion that was going on and they
were trying to throw a wet blankets on
it.
We're trying to figure out how to do it,
but those people that did that,
they're all dead.
So these new sort of dea people in drug
enforcement officers,
they're there.
They're operating under this assumption
that what they're doing is in some way
good because it's been in place for a
long time and this is just how it is.
And look,
there's a reason why heroin is illegal,
son.
There's a reason why cocaine's illegal
son,
what?
Marijuana is going to rot your brain.
So you do marijuana.
Like why are,
why are mushrooms illegal?
If you've done mushrooms,
if you've done mushrooms and you think
they're illegals,
something went wrong,
something went wrong.
Either you tried to fight it and the
trip took you sideways or you know,
you didn't get enough of it or you did
it with assholes.
If you were to have the,
um,
there's a thing you probably net,
there's a name for it.
When somebody gets invested into a
religion or a cult,
you get no called and after you've
invested yourself for a certain amount
of time,
when you get really like sucked into the
cult,
uh,
the,
just the fact that you've been in it for
four,
five,
10,
15 years is enough to keep you in even
though you know it's complete bullshit
and see you stay in it only because like
you've,
you've invested too much energy.
Like when they predict the apocalypse
and then it doesn't happen,
and those people just like,
well,
that doesn't shake their ego is
completely committed to it.
Imagine if like your entire life you had
been enforcing legislation that was
completely absurd,
that wasn't based on anything,
that in reality,
that in fact for your entire life,
you are a enforcing legislation that was
in some way dampening or pushing your
society back,
pushing back the evolution of your
culture and you have to come to terms
with the fact that you did that.
You are an agent of the state and you
enforced laws that shouldn't have been
there at all.
Man,
that's a fucking tough pill to swallow.
The fact that you may have killed some
people use,
there's people out there who have put
bullets in,
in people just for growing marijuana,
something out of the ground or for being
an Afghany adolescent,
you know,
I mean,
think about all the soldier.
That's what the PTSD is all about,
right?
They're coming back and they're like,
what the f?
I interviewed three vets on my show.
I did sort of a series of interviews,
tangentially speaking,
available on itunes.
Thank you.
Uh,
and you know,
that's some of the stuff that comes up,
you know,
it's like fucking shoot people because
you're there and that's what you do.
And they moved and they had,
you know,
whatever.
It's got to come to terms with it,
you know,
they just have to come to terms with it,
but you have to come to terms with it
because it's cowardly to continue to
fucking enforce a goddamn thing.
Even though you know that it's no longer
a relevant.
There's no need to do it.
There never was a need to do it.
You just have to take the bitter pill
and go through a few fucking days of
feeling guilty,
you know,
and understand that,
that what you did was wrong.
It's a real easy thing
to say,
but the problem is until the laws get
changed,
it's not going to seem real to people
that are still caught up in the haze of
culture because culture has kind of a
haze like you get.
You get sucked into it and you're in it,
and that's why people do different
things in different places and it seems
normal to them.
And then we see it though what they eat
with sticks,
right?
What are they?
Fucking crazy,
right?
Well,
they know about spoons.
It's like culture becomes the norm.
It becomes what you accept and right now
our culture accepts the fact that you
get locked up for drugs and you don't
want your kids to be a druggie.
You don't want your kid to be a loser if
you,
because they become potheads and become
lazy.
We have these thoughts that were really
all the seeds were started in the 19
thirties with all those crazy reefer
madness.
It just means it's the same stuff.
It just has gotten less and less
ridiculous,
but no one,
like even to this day,
if you talk about getting high,
talking about smoking pot,
the vast majority of people look at it
the same way as if you say,
I got fucked up.
I,
we went and drank and I got hammered.
I was so blasted.
But there's a very big difference in
what it's doing to your body.
Like one of them is closing off
awareness.
One of them is opening up awareness and
we're putting them in the same category
and this is not a knock on alcoholic.
I'm a fan of alcohol.
Enjoy it,
but it's a completely different
experience.
But when you explain it to people,
they'll look at you the same way.
Ah,
you guys got stoned,
Huh?
You fucking crazy kids,
you know.
Meanwhile you got stoned and might have
realized exactly what was wrong in your
relationship and you know,
and,
and tried to fix your life and like
wrote something down.
It's going to be like the new chart,
the new path of your destiny.
Like more,
you got drunk and shit.
And your neighbors along because you try
to be cute,
you know,
and this cat and it is cute.
Put It on youtube
that we're talking.
Is that cat fucking line a dig at me,
man.
No Man,
no man promised who weren't going to
talk about that.
That,
that thing you're talking about,
man.
That thing where you're like,
well,
well guess you're high right now.
That's deep North Korean level
conditioning.
That's what it's no different than
people in North Korea praying the dear
leader.
It's when you.
You have been.
If you,
depending on how old you are,
you have been a in a war.
The war on drugs.
It's a real war.
It's a war where people have been killed
and imprisoned and as part of all wars
propaganda,
you have to have private money and
money,
but you have been conditioned by some
very intense brainwashing that was
created by the CIA to try to control
your mind.
And so you have been infected with
propaganda.
If you think that drugs should be
illegal,
you are a victim of the drug war and
another know another fucking casualty of
the drug war.
Truth man,
I was thinking like how much I lied to
my mom.
I was in high school taking Lsd,
having these powerful life,
changing experiences,
beautiful experiences where I was
realizing so much about society and
myself and a lot of Shit I didn't
understand and I would have loved to
have talked to my mom about it,
but I couldn't talk to my mom about it
because if my mom found out I was doing
fucking Lsd,
she would freak out and parents,
they go through their kid's drawers.
They become agents of the state.
They're digging through their kid's
drawers to try to find a substance that
has been on the planet for a very long
time.
Marijuana or a substance like lsd that
is profoundly beneficial to a person who
takes it and the right way and they've
become agents of the state and they're.
They're forcing this in their house,
in the home,
which should be a place of absolute
truth and trust and acceptance and
growth.
It's been transformed into this kind of
Weird Gulag.
It's been turned into this bizarre
prison place where the parents somehow
have got to enforce these absolutely
arbitrary laws and that I can't,
I don't think that anyone is ever going
to be able to calculate how much damage
that is done to society that we have
placed our teens into a position where
they have to fucking lie to their
parents about having the most profound
experience accessible via chemicals.
But there's a lot of people that think
that you shouldn't fuck with any
entheogens,
any psychedelics while you're a,
you have a young developing mind.
Well,
I'm not one of them when I can't,
I can't be.
I didn't do all that all through high
school and I absolutely am so grateful
to that.
I'm so grateful for the information
stream because I didn't have the
Internet man and like,
uh,
you know,
my encounter with a,
what lsd was,
was through pure government propaganda.
Like it was like finding books where it
talks about Timothy leary is an insane
lunatic who lost his mind,
uh,
that paints a picture of people who were
advocates of the psychedelic experience
as being some kind of evil drug addled
lunatics as opposed to being what they
really are,
which is rebels and heroes and a
completely insane a war that has
destroyed countless lives.
So I didn't,
I wasn't able to like go on the Internet
and look this shit up and find out that
indeed this experience that I'm having,
which appears to be beneficial is truly
beneficial to a great many people.
All I had was bullshit.
Like you're gonna,
you know,
if you take five hits of acid,
you're legally insane.
Or the old classic image show to take
five.
So I'm covered if I do something good
clover,
same lost my mind.
So I'm going to do,
I'm going to talk like from the 1940
[inaudible] from now on the fly.
I'm in saying,
what do you mean by this beneficial
experience?
Well,
it's sad,
you know,
it really is.
And it's what's really sad about is like
other wars,
the casualties,
you know,
we build walls with names on them and
other wars,
but in this particular war,
so many people who were just farmers
and alchemists are laying in their
graves and nobody realizes that these
were heroes.
These were people who were in the face
of insanity,
making the decision that regardless of
what the state was telling them to do,
that we're going to follow their hearts.
And a lot of them went to jail for a lot
of them are in jail for political
prisoners.
That's the word.
That's it.
This is very strange how hard it is for
us to break momentum of habit.
And that's part of what's going on is
there's a momentum of habit that looks
at all these things as being negative.
Well,
and there's a governmental system that's
supremely unresponsive to new ideas,
right?
Because of the way Congress has set up.
But one of the things is changing that I
think is what's happening in Colorado
with the tax revenue in Oregon in
Oregon.
But Colorado has a longer history of it
right now.
They've made more money for the first
time ever from marijuana and taxes than
they do alcohol and crime goes down.
Crime went down,
drunk driving,
went down,
crime went down to record levels.
Drunk driving when real estate went up,
13 percent.
Prescription overdoses down because
people are using marijuana for pain
control and tourism up hot girl moving
in part and time.
There's negatives to hippies freaks a
lot of lazy bitches moving into lot of
hippies.
Attracted like metal filings.
I slept and Terence Mckenna's bed the
other night.
Well,
just jerk off.
I felt it.
No,
no.
Shut up.
No beautiful.
Whereas Terence Mckenna is.
It's a bed he slept in often in mill
valley.
Oh yeah.
That's awesome.
I always wanted to buy his house in the
Big Island,
but it burnt down.
Burned down with like thousands of
books.
Yeah.
How the fuck does a house burn and
Hawaiian rain forest.
He lived in a rain forest.
Volcanic eruption?
Yeah.
It's called girlfriend with kerosene.
You guys know I'm a nominated for porn
award,
so I tell you that a porn awards nav.
An award.
Wow.
Okay.
So good.
Yeah.
Best non sex scene in a movie.
What movie was this?
It's called marriage.
Two point.
Oh,
and A.
I'm up.
I'm up against Ron.
Jeremy.
Dick tribbles.
Yeah.
That's broken.
Has nothing to say.
Congratulations for given some amazing.
I hope you win.
Well.
I was going to ask you if you guys would
go to Vegas and accepted on my behalf.
Send Red Band.
He'll be there anyway.
Get it for us.
Yeah.
I,
um,
those things just seem like too much
sadness for a guy with daughters of the
avn awards and just definitely.
Maybe,
maybe I'm wrong.
Maybe it's a party.
Brian says it's all like a cam girls
now.
That's like the majority of what it is.
I think there is.
I just read about this documentary about
the shift in pornography that like the
way that pornography's,
that that industry is kind of
disintegrating because of the Internet
toll free.
One of the many fucking disrupt the
Internet is disrupting everything.
Man Isn't from Warren to taxi cabs to
everything is getting reconfigured by
it.
It's so fascinating.
It's unbelievable.
It's a very weird time.
Not just taxi cabs.
I told you,
rental cars,
the skirt rental car company to just
drop your rental car off and then they
pick it up later like they bring it to
you,
sort of like uber for rental cars so
they could just get a sofa in there.
We'd be in Duncan's future,
some sort of a pod.
I always thought they should make cars
with cameras.
Right,
and so you actually sit backwards in the
car and look at a screen that's
projected of what's in front of you and
you drive backwards because you think
about if you're in a collision,
you're,
you're good.
If you're driving backwards,
not really.
You're fucked if you're going to get
crushed,
and it's not good to not know when
you're impacting.
Well,
you would know as far as your.
It's like a virtual.
It's as if you're looking out the
windshield,
but you're actually shifted backwards
and it's cameras projecting on the
screen.
My brain hurts and probably throw up
constantly.
That would be weird.
I just feel like you wouldn't want to
see the car coming at you rear ending.
You don't know.
Yeah,
you wouldn't because you'd be closed,
man.
Did you see that at the video of Ilan
mosque finally landing a rocket fucking
cool man.
Oh yeah,
it's bad ass.
It's just like straight out of like old
50 Saifai.
It's like exactly the same thing.
He did it.
He landed a rocket and that guy I heard
that he is part of a,
uh,
him and some other people have said that
they're going to give a billion dollars
to create a new artificial intelligence
research research center or something
because they're terrified.
Elon Musk and the gunny in England,
the Stephen Hawking you through the gun,
like weird that it's fun.
Oh yes.
They're terrified.
And they're,
they're,
yeah,
they're really.
How do you feel about artificial
intelligence and artificial
intelligence?
It's very rare.
You have a right to the phone.
I'll check my texts.
Give me your thoughts on this idea.
A hundred percent.
What I did just busted both of us like
my impression of a,
but you can't help them fucking things
or heroin.
They pull you.
Just want to check.
Maybe the next tweet is going to be
amazing.
Do someone's going to send me the
coolest part of in my life to
read it and I'm just going to learn.
But do you read articles?
I,
I find I store them.
I'm like a fucking squirrel and October
man,
I got so many tabs open and so many
things in evernote to read later.
I'll never read all this style,
but I've got this acquisitive thing
like,
oh,
that'll be interesting.
I'll save that.
That old.
I don't know.
They'll go there and that and it's just
a mess.
It's a massive.
I'm like a hoarder.
I'm an intellectual hoarder.
I try to practice mindfulness when I'm
going through my phone so I kind of
watch myself as I'm doing it because I
know I'm addicted and I can see what I'm
in is at really awful pattern and it's
like when,
when you,
when you go through it and you analyze
what's happening,
you,
you see that it is a form of drug,
you see that you are getting like little
hits off of it.
You are getting like weird little like
moments of like strange information
intoxication.
Like you get these little white uptake.
So like when you find a particularly
like,
oh shit,
a fucking vice documentary on the
liberation of the city in Iraq.
Whoa,
there's a cat eating a fucking man's
leg.
Holy Shit.
Uptake,
uptake,
uptake.
You're getting these like weird little
hits and it's kind of cool and it keeps
you stuck in a cycle.
But that pull you're talking about,
man,
I had this like a awesome goth friend
who was into like,
God,
I can't remember if it's the,
there's a differentiation between death
metal and black metal and I always get
in trouble for mixing them up.
But like he was like explaining to me
about a vlog vagueness burzum.
I always get in trouble.
I get the whole story mixed up.
But basically it was explaining how
these guys are actually burning down
churches and they were really hard core
man.
So he plays this a burson,
this death metal for me.
He's like,
listen,
I was super stoned.
He's like,
listen,
listen.
I'm listening to what he's like.
Do you feel the pull?
It's like,
shit man,
I do a little bit.
I know what you're talking about.
It's got a weird dark little gravity to
it that if I'm allowed it to,
I could see how I would start getting
more and more and more into it.
It's the same with these fucking phones,
man.
They have a true,
a weird,
magnetic,
subjective magnetism where you always
feel it's almost a physical feeling,
man.
I'm like,
you almost feel it.
Pulling your attention towards it.
They're like black holes for attention.
It's interactive.
That's the big factor.
The big factor.
It's interactive.
You Click on things,
you can make things happen.
You can open things.
Look at pictures.
It's one of the things that people like
about instagram.
You're.
You're clicking on it and go,
oh,
look at that picture.
Look at this picture.
Oh,
I'm going to comment and you're
interacting,
not interacting.
It's like some bizarre introduction to a
new type of society.
It's this is.
This is.
These are the first steps,
these social media steps.
These are the first steps.
This new type of integrated
communication that we're experiencing.
Yeah,
but like we were talking about what the
city.
The city separates us from the
realization that we are just temporary
beings collecting things needlessly
because we're only gonna be for a short
amount of time,
but yet we spend all of our focus trying
to accumulate the largest pile of shit
before we die.
That's sort of the same thing is going
on with phones.
It's the same thing that's going on with
everything.
It's like it's solely that pulling us
into it's trance and the more we feed
into it,
the more we work hard,
the more they'll make more of these,
the more they'll make better ones of
these.
The more these things will deeper and
deeper integrate themselves into your
life until the point where they're
symbiotic until the point where the new
google contact lens.
Have you seen that shit?
Google's coming out with a contact lens.
New goddamn contact lens is going to be
Google glass.
The contact lens.
It's going to be able to tell your blood
sugar if you're diabetic.
Oh,
project two and everything.
you can see shit on it.
It's going to do everything we can to
have like porn going in your left eye.
Twenty four slash seven and you're
right,
I porn your left.
I threw my people see it,
people see and I think it's just a
matter of time and it's a matter of time
before they create eyes that are better
than these eyes.
These eyes that we have that I need
reading glasses now to read things that
are fine print.
I can't like,
I can't read a book anymore.
I have to have a pair of glasses.
I'm reading a book about how to
strengthen your eyes when I wear reading
glasses.
When I read the book.
It's hilarious.
And you know that the Myopia is out of
control and they say it's because kids
are indoors all the time.
I think it probably has a lot of
screens.
A woman named Katie Bowman,
Katy Katy Bowman was on the show and one
of the way she described it as a cast,
she said,
if you're,
if you're always looking at something
that's the same.
It was Katy Bowman,
right?
They product this up,
pretty sure.
Um,
she was saying if you're always looking
at a certain distance in a certain
space,
then that becomes like a cast,
so if you put your arm in a cast and the
muscle atrophies,
but when you are outside like a normal
person,
as you're looking at things that are
close,
you're looking at things that are far
away and it doesn't distort your lens
when you're staring at a screen all the
time,
which I am all the time either doing a
podcast or going online or whatever that
fucks with your eyes.
That's why you know,
people who would read all the time,
we'd get glasses and people would
correlate it like,
oh,
I fucked up his eyes from reading.
He would always say that.
And then they said,
oh,
that's bullshit,
but don't say I'm white or some
bullshit.
If you read enough,
you're looking at that space,
has it right in front of you.
Only something really close up,
but it fucks with your eyes yet.
And also masturbation makes you go
blind.
No,
no,
that's true,
right?
No,
none.
If you use your left hand that you just
need balance.
It's all about balance.
You need,
um,
he bounced,
but this is this thing you're talking
about,
aren't they?
Finding out that there's actually
something about that,
like the energy being radiated from the
things at night.
Like it fucks with your sleep cycle to
like,
oh yeah,
the blue,
the blue wavelengths.
So get,
get f Dot Lux,
Lux.
It's great.
In fact,
I
just interviewed a sleep scientist,
uh,
two days ago in San Francisco.
Really interesting guy does research at
Stanford,
Dan Pardi and we were talking about
that.
It's the,
it's the,
the blue end of the wavelength,
which is what you get from sunlight,
affects the centers of your brain that
Sorta tell you what time it is in your
circadian rhythm and all that.
So as you get toward a evening,
you want the light to glow more and more
gold,
yellow and eliminate the blue.
So this app just automatically filters
your screen based upon where you are and
what time it is.
And it's,
it's good.
It helps with the sleep because if
you're looking at blue light right
before you go to bed,
your brain thinks you're in the midday,
you know?
That makes sense.
So plain plane that they're doing,
they're creating this new plane,
they're going to make it out of carbon
fiber and they're going to adjust the
light in the plane to match the light in
the area you're going so that your
circadian rhythms don't get interrupted.
No windows and apparently in doing this,
somehow or another,
they're going to eliminate the type of
jet lag that a lot of people suffer
from.
Yeah,
because by the time you arrive,
you're already calibrated.
Yeah.
I don't know how the fuck they're doing
that.
It doesn't make any sense to me.
I've 16 hour flights.
You know,
I've seen this.
I heard about this new kind of a light
that they have that you can put in
basements that somehow perfectly
replicates sunlight so that it's,
ah,
I don't know.
It's amazing because you can grow weed.
No,
it's not heard of those two.
Have you heard of it?
I get some places growing tomatoes.
Fucking go down Ventura Boulevard and
there's like 15 different stores selling
you indoor tomato growing supplies.
Fuck,
I just think that's what it was like.
Shit.
Yeah.
There's a lot of indoor farmer's.
Another heirloom specialists.
Well,
did you hear about the a former FBI
agents whose house got broken down?
They broke down the door.
Cea,
a dea agents.
I think they shot their dog.
I don't know that they loved sheepdogs.
You.
It's in the constitution,
arrested them and then found out that
they were just really grown tomatoes.
They literally were growing tomatoes,
so these people were for agents.
These guys were retired agents to try to
grow some vegetables,
make a nice salad.
They got a fucking gun to their bad
Karma.
Karma in that at least if not Karma.
There's a recognition of the system that
you participated in for most of your
adult life.
There's your career.
Here's what you did.
You Fed this machine and machine that's
looking for too much electricity and
using your basement,
which could be indicative of plant
growth.
Plant growth in your house while you
fucker.
You're probably a criminal time to kick
your door in with guns,
but dammit,
we talk about this all the time,
but if you really let yourself accept
the fact that right now at this moment,
flying over neighborhoods or high
tech helicopters scanning the third,
the radiation from the houses to find
out if inside their growing plants that
aren't accepted by the state.
That's really weird man.
And that's why I'm leaving.
I'm going back to Spain where they don't
do that shit.
They don't do that.
Don't do Portland neither though,
Dude.
You say Portland.
Don't have the resources.
Go to Eugene.
I could definitely not do it.
It's nice.
But you've seen the new um,
radar that they have now would,
they can hook deepened or x Ray?
They look deep into your house.
They can look in your house and see or
silhouettes as you.
So you can watch people fuck.
Like they could look through this screen
and literally see you inside your house
blinds drawn,
banging your wife on the bed.
But who wants to see two skeletons?
Fucking.
I really,
really love it.
Why not?
I don't think it's just.
I think it's like a,
I think you could see images like you
could see the outside of the body as
well.
It's not just as simple as like you see
the scallops actually,
you'll see.
I'm sure they'll figure out a way that
to interpolate whatever data they're
gathering and turn it into something
that isn't shadows,
it's just a matter of time and it's a
matter of time.
Any technology that is being controlled
by the state,
uh,
because it's too expensive for normal
people to obtain eventually more than
likely will become less and less
expensive and everyone will have it.
So if right now there is some,
some insane technology that people are
using to look through walls and see
shadows,
fuck.
Then it's at what,
10,
15 years before it's going to be
something that you could just order or
something that you can download on your
super sophisticated drones for Christmas
is using mobile x Ray Vance to spy on
unknown targets.
Patrol was a friend of mine used to work
for the company who makes those.
And what they were doing was they were
scanning container ships coming in and
out of the country are coming into the
country so they could look for drugs
without opening up the containers.
Look what this says.
Stop right there for a second.
New York City won't reveal how often
cops bombard places,
vehicles,
or people with radiation,
or if there are health risks for
residents,
they won't reveal it.
If you don't talk about the technology
was used in Afghanistan before and b
being loosed on us streets.
Each x Ray van cost an estimated
$729,000
to $825,000.
It's a big fucking difference.
I will not talk about anything at all
about this New York police commissioner.
Bill Bratton until you paid for it.
Wow.
How's that going to the range of
security and counterterrorism activity
that we engage in added.
They're not used to scan people for
weapon,
but you know what's hilarious?
They've used the terrorists acts like
various terrorist acts all across the
world to catch people selling drugs.
Because you could sell drugs as an act
of terror that falls under financing.
They pay,
they just pass some new Patriot Act,
you know that right now the new Patriot
Act that was quietly,
secretly past.
Is that the CIA,
NSA,
whatever the fuck it is,
where,
where Obama said I'm going to watch star
wars.
And he apparently just sign this demonic
thing and that.
Yeah,
it's scary.
Well,
this,
I mean they,
there's a lot of leeway now for what
they can and can't spy on you for what
they decide to look into your life for.
So let me,
if we follow up what you were saying
about how something controlled by the
state,
you know,
it gets miniaturized and cheaper and
eventually becomes available to everyone
if we apply that.
Same thing to weaponry.
I've been thinking about this for a long
time.
Nukes are getting smaller and smaller.
They've got suitcase nukes now,
John.
Yeah.
Much more convenient.
It's so annoying.
Yeah.
But pack nuke.
I'm tired of suitcases.
Right?
So are we going to come to the point
where any terrorist group,
so called terrorist group,
and I use that word in air quotes,
can have access to these things.
What's that going to mean to world
politics?
Are we going to come to a point?
Kind of like everyone in Switzerland has
guns.
You know that this philosophy,
if everyone had guns,
everyone would show out and be nice to
each other.
Are we going to come to that point
internationally where if people are
aggrieved enough,
they can really fuck up the game and so
then the attention will shift to not
having people so aggrieved because right
now we don't give a fuck,
right?
We'll go blow them up.
If they're.
If they're that pissed off,
they're going to come for us,
then we'll send drones and kill them
all,
but if they could come for us with a
speedboat and nukes,
is that a game changer or do you think
the whole thing just shifts to another
level and us have to address the root of
the problem?
If it was that accessible.
Now it's like the ultimate statement of
an armed society is a polite society.
Yeah.
It's almost like the ultimate expression
of that,
like in a well armed nuclear society has
fucking super polite.
Imagine,
knock on your neighbor's door and tell
him his dogs barking too loud when he's
wearing a fucking nuke vest.
Flow up the way you saying my dog is
making too much noise.
Okay.
Fuck it man.
I want to take care of them.
Do you want the dog?
I'm going to hit this button.
Let's just do this.
I'm going to wipe out the whole block.
No Man.
What?
What you're talking about.
I,
I did an interview up a very good point.
I didn't interview at Singularity
University in,
in any,
in.
He brought up this exact thing any,
any and and which is that,
you know,
he was explaining it in terms of bio
weapons that people are creating these
like apparently are like fucking around
with genes in their,
in their,
in their garages.
And then you were saying like things
like the ability to launch satellites
and just about anything you can imagine.
He's what he said,
and I,
I think he may have,
I mean,
I don't know.
He didn't say he was exaggerating when
you said we're looking at if technology
continues to accelerate as it is,
we're looking at a point in human
history where anybody,
if they wanted to,
could destroy the entire,
are caused massive damage.
And so,
uh,
you think to yourself,
all right,
well,
let's imagine that that was the case.
And somehow by some miracle,
every government of the world suddenly
figured out a way to address everybody's
personal issues.
There was still going to be one or two
more likely a thousand people who are
like,
no,
that's cool man.
But I think I'm going to detonate this
nuclear bomb that I created in my three
d printer,
getting from fucking,
who knows how.
I mean,
it's a big question mark or something
even worse than that.
So this thing,
what you're talking about,
I think is the,
uh,
that awful race,
Terence Mckenna talks about that we're
in,
which is that here we have this race
between absolute destruction and some
kind of via tech technology that doesn't
even exist yet.
And some kind of Utopian awakening.
I know this kind of stuff probably makes
you want to punch me,
but I want hug you.
It's ridiculous.
But,
but,
but these are these two,
you know,
these are these two races that are
happening right now.
One of them is without question,
technology is going to get to the point
where every single human has access to
some kind of device,
more powerful than any other human in
the past ever had access to.
And the question is,
is that gonna happen before some other
form of technology emerges that makes us
all unifying to one organism or some
beautiful thing happens.
I mean,
it's a pretty terrifying.
It's a terrifying relay race man.
It really is.
It's a tear.
It's not really,
it's a terrifying race.
And um,
but isn't that kind of always,
always
the case?
Like we need some sort of a problem to
overcome it.
We need competition.
We need the Yin and the Yang.
We need a dark and a light.
We need the,
you know,
we need to tide.
We need like a cycle.
It's almost like we need this resistance
of like us building towards this,
this technological singularity almost.
It's going to be in your fucking iphone
and everyone's going to have the ability
and well,
we have to fix humanity in order to have
this happen.
The only way that we're going to
survive,
we fixed humanity and so,
you know what I've been thinking,
it's just something I'd never talked to
him economists about this,
but in my own stupid head,
um,
I think we're going to run into a
bottleneck with technology and I think
one of the big bottlenecks is technology
is all about access to information,
right?
Technology like as far as what's going
on,
it's like your,
your ability to do things,
whether it's to project images on
screens or to download things faster or
to number crunch cruncher,
the various different things that
technology can do.
But what we're using,
the way we're using it today was a big
factor is the ability to exchange
information and the access to
information and the access to each
other.
And it seems like it's getting closer
and closer and closer.
Right?
Access is getting quicker.
It's more information,
it's easier to get to the boundaries
between people are getting smaller and
smaller.
What's the bottleneck?
Bottleneck is going to be money and
money is ones and Zeros.
That's what money is.
Money,
right?
If of all,
ultimately all information becomes
available to all people at all times.
That's ultimate enlightenment,
right?
Instantaneous information constantly
available to everyone.
Well,
isn't money information now because
money's not sacks or old.
You're not talking about,
you know,
I've got.
I've got 15 bushels or gold.
How many of you got when you know?
No,
we're talking about some weird ones and
Zeros and plastic that makes these ones
and Zeros transfer your magnetic strip.
You slide on the machine.
You Punch in your numbers is not real
anymore.
It's information and in transferring our
money to inflammation,
the bottleneck is going to be money.
We're going to come to this ultimate
point where we realized,
look,
we can't protect money anymore.
We can't.
You can't say this has duncan's money.
This is Christmas money because it's
going to be just mine.
It's going to be just money and I mean
maybe there'll be some sort of a merit
based system where you can have access
to money or use money and we'll have to
figure out some sort of a way around it,
but it'll have to be some sort of like
ethical thing that we all agree on.
If I'm looking at it correctly and I'm
looking at all of this,
these trends that lead to quicker and
quicker access to information,
more and more availability of that
information,
access to information becoming
universal.
Well,
what's the money?
Money.
Money is information.
It's ones and Zeros.
It's all it is.
Well,
how are you going to stop it if that's
the trend of the trend ultimately
becomes instantaneous.
Constant access to all information for
everybody knows secrets.
None exist anymore.
They don't exist.
I could read your email.
You can read mine.
We're all communicating with each other.
That's it.
There's no more secrets.
How does money fit in there?
Unless we go back to fucking collecting
clam shells and putting them on strings
and this is a.
This is my company,
not so I have a mushroom.
That's what I'm used to it.
We're going to have silver coins and
shit.
What are we going to do?
But.
But I would question the premise that
money ever was real.
You seem to be saying that we're
reaching a point where it will no longer
be real like bushels of gold.
That's just symbolic too.
I don't think money ever was anything
more than agreement between people that
we're all going to pretend this is real.
It's true,
right?
Because it it locally.
Your money is different than someone in
Greece.
You,
you mean you go with your money there.
There's some sort of exchange.
You have to make an agreement.
Do you accept my money will accept your
money,
but it's not really worth a dollar.
How much is it worth over here?
Seventy five cents,
God dammit,
but last month it was a dollar 25.
Well Times have changed.
We don't like your money as much anymore
and they make deals.
Our central bank who's staffed by people
we don't know.
I mean,
there's a lot of mystery at the heart of
it is to be able to go to Canada and it
was Canada and it was awesome.
We do Montreal and you'd get like a
dollar 50 for a dollar,
something like that,
and it was amazing.
Like food would be cheaper,
everything will be cheaper.
Like,
ah,
your money goes a long way in Canada.
And then it shifted and then the
Canadians would come to America because
the money would go a long way here.
Money was worth more than ours.
Have you ever heard of Grant Morrison?
Yeah.
Do you know Graham?
You should have them on the show,
man.
He's just refresh my memory.
Grant Morrison is that he writes a bunch
of incredible comic books.
One of them I'm super into right now,
graphic novels called the,
uh,
the invisibles,
but he's really smart.
There's a,
there's a grant morrison lecture,
a descent.
He was like at a disinfecting gathering
and he gives this really cool lecture or
a talk.
And one of the things he said is that
the super elite,
they have gone back to a barter economy
because money doesn't mean anything to
you if you have billions and billions
and billions of dollars.
So the normal way to get someone to do
something is to say,
okay,
I'll give you x dollars for you to do
this thing.
But if you've got infinite money and
someone asks you to do something to give
you more money to add to your infinite
pool of money,
it's not an incentive anymore.
You're not incentivized by money.
So it's more like,
what can you do?
For me what it's like a,
it's a.
It goes back to some kind of weird,
maybe you're going to barter power,
maybe you're going to barter some access
or something like that,
but money is irrelevant to the super
elite.
Money only means something to people who
are in the lower and middle class.
Once you have an infinite amount of this
shit,
it's completely an absolutely
irrelevant,
which is what you're saying.
Everything then theoretically would have
to go back to some weird barter economy
where
would never going to reach a point of
ultimate resources where everyone has
the same access to things at the super
elite does because there's just not
enough.
Well,
this is where you get into like this is
where you get into the idea of
experienced generation.
You know like if we get to like Google
this thing,
you're talking about Google contact
lenses,
it's not going to stop at the right.
Technology is doing the thing to us that
the fucking face suckers on aliens do.
It started off far away.
It was our phones.
It was our computers than it like a.
It was on our desks.
It was a nice safe distance.
Then it got into our pockets.
It tried to climb onto our face with the
google glasses,
but nobody liked that.
But now it's getting into our eyes and
it's not gonna stop at our eyes.
Technology's gonna,
merge with our consciousness and when it
merges with our consciousness,
the theory would be that it could
somehow create experiences that were
indistinguishable from reality,
which means that really what's the
difference?
There is no more.
You can't like.
You know what?
We're already using bionic parts on
people,
right?
Sure.
Hips,
yeah.
Yeah.
All sorts of stuff.
My wife has ocular implants.
She has lenses surgically implanted in
her eyes.
Yeah.
This is.
I mean,
this is not new stuff.
They're doing artificial knees.
They're doing artificial hips and how
long is it gonna be before someone comes
along and says,
listen,
dumped.
You have two choices.
You can either wear glasses,
you have 2,400
vision and you know we have classes for
you.
Didn't.
That's fine if you enjoy it or is a
really simple procedure.
Takes five minutes.
We were placed your eyeball with an
artificial.
You don't feel any
pain,
but you'll have to put up with ads every
60 seconds.
Well,
you can click that ad.
You can click the ad.
You just reach up.
You've touched.
This is what.
What's the name of that that thought
experiment about the ship?
Somebody ship,
you know,
the one where it's like,
it's like the idea is like at a sailor
is sailing across the ocean and the
mast,
he needs to replace the mast until we
replaced the mast and then he replaces,
I can't remember his name.
The different shifts,
different by the time it gets there,
it's all new parts,
but it's still his ship.
So it's like with the,
with technology,
it's the same thing.
Like what if we keep replacing our
spirit is the ship of theseus.
That's it.
Yeah.
So yeah,
the idea is like when is,
when do we,
when,
what is humanity or when do we stop
being human?
The whole idea about downloading
consciousness,
right?
Way To put consciousness into a
computer.
And how do you know when you've done it?
Like how do you know what consciousness
is?
I mean his consciousness inexorably
attached to your physical being or is
consciousness something that's out there
that you're just,
you're,
you're consciousness is riding around
this meat wagon.
Is that what's going on?
We don't.
There's no agreement on that.
Also,
we need to define what we mean by human
because I would argue that we've already
left human experience and we're already
well into something else.
What would you call it that we're into?
Um,
I equate it to do.
You might know this,
that every locust starts off as a
grasshopper.
And what happens is there's this,
uh,
particular,
the best example is in North Africa.
It's this species of grasshopper that
when the density of the population
density gets tight,
sufficiently tight,
there's a trigger point and different
genes are triggered and activated in
the,
in the body,
the preexisting gene.
So it's the same DNA,
but it changes the shape of the head,
changes the legs,
changes the coloration,
and changes the behavior.
And that's when they become locusts
swarm.
And so I think that humans are like the
grasshopper locusts.
And I think that with agriculture we
became locus and started swarming and
we're willing to swarm behavior at this
point.
And so for the sake of argument,
I would say human,
the way I would define it is hunter
gatherer,
which is 95 plus percent of our time on
the planet.
That's human behavior and what we are
now is shifted into this other,
you could say artificial.
You could just say emergent behavior
pattern that conflicts with our
grasshopper illness.
Right?
And that we're suffering from.
That's what this latest book is about.
And so,
you know,
I would say we're no longer human.
It's like we're a bunch of poodles
talking about when we stopped being
wolves,
you know,
I'll tell you this,
if I was a fucking locust and there was
a grasshopper that's like,
I'd be like,
awesome,
because I can fly.
I'm flying,
I've evolved.
This is our major disagreement.
Years.
You want to be a grasshopper.
I'm cool with being a locus,
but.
But it's,
it's an interesting thing,
right?
Well,
what I think you're saying is there's
more inherent biological happiness into
remaining of grasshopper or remaining of
human right?
That's why the things that make that
resonate most deeply with us are the
things that reflect the culture alive.
You hunting for example,
you're not having trouble focusing your
mind when you're hunting.
You don't think there's your tapping and
if you ever caught a nice fish,
you've got fishing.
I know that feeling when you catch a
nice fish,
there's a like a feeling.
There's a primal reaction.
I'm saying a nice fish because it's
easier for people to accept because it's
a cold blooded animal.
Like something about like saying there's
something about when you get a nice deer
in your sites and you're ready to end
its life.
People like,
no,
right when I'm about to eat a bear,
but you say a fish.
They go,
oh,
he caught a fish.
They eat other fish,
whatever.
It's just for whatever reason,
people don't care if you catch a fish,
they don't give a fuck.
We,
we,
we differentiate.
We have more value in warm blooded
animals than we put in in fish for
whatever.
Fucking you can't scream.
I mean,
I think if,
what is Mitch Hedberg,
it's got that great joke like thank God
the fish can't scream because the ocean
would be the scariest Jackie each other.
That's true.
That's right.
But there is something about their
expression.
Listening is that many people,
I think they don't take care of their
young.
That's a big one.
Like this woman said that to me,
one of the reasons why she eats fish,
she doesn't eat chicken or any other
animals.
I go,
why?
She goes,
well,
the fish don't take care of their young.
I was like,
damn,
that's gangster.
She drew the line in the sand and they
eat each other.
Well,
they're cannibals like almost
exclusively.
I mean,
I mean almost a universally like trout.
One of the best ways to catch trout as a
little baby trout floors that looked
like a trail.
Large mouth bass,
large mouth bass lowers occasionally
catch them with those,
you know,
they don't give a fuck.
They're just here to eat whatever they
can eat done.
But it's innately inherently meaningful
is what I'm saying.
Right?
And the reason it's inherently
meaningful is because that's the animal
that we evolved to be.
And now we live in this society that's
distracting us from that.
Trying to sell it back and little
pieces.
Maybe you can afford a hunting weekend
in Utah at this ranch.
Uh,
and what,
what the hell was the point of losing
the humanity?
When do we stop being human?
Yeah,
I think we already have and I think
that's the major fucking ailment of our
time as far is a part of it and I
certainly think there's a series of
reward systems in our bodies that are
not getting checked off like they used
to like rewards,
like fear,
overcoming fear,
difficulty,
physical exertion,
all these different things that people
did and then the,
the,
the thing of seeing the fish,
catching the fish oil.
There's this visceral genetic response
to getting a fish like you got it.
Now you're going to eat and that and
your friends are going to.
Yes,
and when you pull a big fish like ah,
there's this weird feeling where
everybody,
you get a little charge like we were.
We were.
We had a successful gathering.
You got something,
now we can eat and that's any built in.
It's built into your system and it
doesn't exist.
When you go to the supermarket and you
pick up that salmon steak that's already
in Saran wrap and it's already got the
little styrofoam bottom that you don't
feel a damn thing.
You don't feel anything but eat the same
amount of nutrients.
It's very strange what we've done.
We've done,
we've completely removed all the natural
elements while needing those natural
elements at the same time.
So we removed any connection that we
have to like we're eating this.
Chris has brought this amazing ham.
What does this stuff called?
Again?
I'm on Google.
It's delicious.
And explain it because it's a really
cool way they,
they make it
right.
It's this,
it's made from pigs that are the same
race of pigs that the Romans brought to
Spain originally 2000 years ago.
There.
It's called Pata Negra,
which means black foot.
And this is so in Spanish Ham.
It's a,
there are different gradations and this
is the highest gradation.
And uh,
all they do is eat acorns.
They live out in these big open fields.
Beautiful.
I've driven through there and the extra
my daughter on my motorcycle and then
they're cured.
It's not cooked at all.
It's not smoked.
It's cured with salt.
Lots of salt and then hung up and
certain temperature.
And how long is it good for?
How long does it sit for?
Forever.
And you can buy these.
I mean,
I would love to bring you one,
but I don't think they let them in the
country,
but you buy the whole leg.
Whoa.
Like a whole ham.
It's cured.
Yeah.
And in most Spanish houses they'll have
a ham and it'll be there.
And so they've got this holder and you
have a long knife and you slice it
really thin.
So it just doesn't go
bad at all.
No,
because it's cured.
That's incredible that you could have a
whole ham leg sitting out
all the way inside.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
So you put a,
you put a towel over it or something so
that flies,
don't get on it.
And that's it,
you know,
and it can be there and it's a
traditional thing around Christmas to,
you know,
give a gift of a ham and a in it'll
last,
you know,
five,
six months,
whatever till they're done eating it.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
So my point being that this,
this meat is in front of us.
It's delicious.
It was from an animal that wasn't even
the live on this continent.
Someone killed it in Spain.
Did all this stuff to you.
Brought it over here,
we're eating it.
We have zero connection to any of those
activities.
We don't want to have.
We just eating it and it's delicious.
We're loving it,
but it's all on.
Not as much as if we'd raise the pig and
been involved in the process.
You know,
I cooked a ham.
I smoked a ham.
I haven't done one for about six months,
but the last one I did was an animal
that I shot and I smoked it in my brined
it for six days and then I smoked.
It was like this big project that I did
and yeah,
it was a way different sort of a feeling
when you're eating and it's like,
like I have a leg,
I have a peg leg of a full ham on the
bone.
That's about that
big that's sitting in my freezer that
I'm eventually going to Brian sometime
soon and I'll stick that sucker in this
w like water with garlic and salt and
brown sugar and it sits in there for
about six days and then I smoke it at
like 250 degrees for hours and hours
until.
It's just as juicy,
delicious,
and a 140 degrees in the center.
So you know all the parasites,
potential parasites are dead.
God.
So good.
I got a big green egg and I got to say,
man,
there's nothing.
There's some weird peace that comes over
you.
What's agreement?
It's like it's a,
it's a really cool grill man.
And it's a fire grill so you've got to,
you know.
So there's no,
it's not a gas grill so you have to
adjust the.
There's all these wonderful dials you
have to adjust to get the heat.
Right.
But yeah man,
like when you're sitting over an open
fire cooking if feels good.
I mean I know what you mean and I.
and it's like you,
it,
it's like this thing like,
Oh shit,
I missed this feeling like this feels
this feels as good as when I jump into a
swimming pool or something.
It's like elemental and so on.
Or like a nutrient your body needs that
you're not getting and then you eat it
and your body's gone.
Please,
thank you.
Give me more.
It's also this link.
There's moments that people throughout
history have had success hunting and
then eating that meal over a campfire
and when you do that,
that is the most rewarding of all fires,
like I've eaten meat that we shot like
hours before from a deer on a campfire
in the middle of Montana and it was one
of the greatest nights of my life.
It was amazing.
Me and Bryan County,
Steve Right now and my friend Ryan
Callahan,
a bunch of other friends were on this
show and when we were sitting around
this fire eating,
I was like,
I can't remember it.
More enjoyable meal because there's fire
and there's an animal that was just
killed and we're cooking it and
preparing it together.
There's all this camaraderie.
There's the successful hunt aspect of it
and then there's this,
this primal satisfaction that you get
from watching meat cook over fire and
the warmth of the.
I don't know how cold it was.
Very cold.
There's a sense of accomplishment,
like we're comfortable because we're
smart and other something.
I love sleeping in a tent when it's
raining and you're like,
wow,
like arm's length from me is miserable,
cold drizzle and I'm warm.
I got my candle and turn.
I got my doobies.
I'm like completely happy here.
I love the sense of,
okay,
accomplishment that that's another great
feeling.
The feeling of rain when you're safe
side,
you're sleeping in a van even though you
know,
just to the sound.
So I think,
I think this is the key to human
happiness that,
that we're ignoring,
that our society takes all these things
that were free and daily reality for our
ancestors.
Takes them away and sells back cheap
copies along with antidepressants and
antianxiety meds.
Right.
I think that that summation of where we
are,
do you think that it's possible that we,
like you said,
are no longer human,
were becoming a sort of,
that this is a drawn
out process and we're just caught up in
the wake of it domestic.
We're in the process of being
domesticated.
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
I mean,
that's why I think when you look at like
the extreme progressive left movement
that are just like so,
so focused on like using the correct
gender,
pronouns do not offend,
don't use this,
what we're talking about with this
Harvard placemat that they're handing
back.
This is like an uber domestic
domestication thing.
I mean it's almost like domestication.
You look at the veteran,
the American male,
I mean talk about getting your balls
snipped man in the last 15 years.
It's become offensive to even be a man.
It's become offensive to express a
happiness with masculinity,
right?
Like to be able to be a straight.
You can't be a term for it.
I think that if you look at what the
real problem as it seems to be,
the people have mistaken language with
intention.
So that's where the problem is.
It's that words,
you know,
certain words.
I mean,
I've been,
I've had it happen on twitter where you
get,
I think I did a podcast with a opry and
he said the female perspective and so
someone on twitter gets into an argument
with me over how that you shouldn't say
female perspective because that's,
and I,
I always saying,
well look,
you know,
I know about the female perspective
because I see from it a lot because
inside of me I've got like a lot of.
I was,
I have a feminine side of me that,
so I know what that is.
It's the,
you know,
uh,
Carl young was telling you about the
anima and the animus that,
that there's a masculine and a feminine
inside of everybody that they're just in
you,
not me,
bro.
I know you're growing,
you're free of it.
But,
but,
but just pay for yourself bro.
But it's that.
It's that,
uh,
when,
when people get caught up in the symbol
versus what the symbol is representing
and,
and completely ignore the fact like,
think of how many different forms of
fuck there are,
like the term fuck or how many different
forms of the word Shit there are.
And all of them are intention based,
you know,
like that.
You could say,
if I say there's so many ways I could
say fuck you to you.
Like I'd be like,
fuck you man.
I could be like,
Hey,
fuck you man,
and it's two different fuck use or you
could do something awesome and I go,
dude,
fuck you.
Yeah,
exactly.
That works too.
Or exactly.
Or like,
man,
I'm,
I'm gonna.
Fuck you joe.
But the point is there's like every
single one of these has behind it and an
energy that has been encapsulated into
the sound and that energy is all that
matters to me and the fact that everyone
has been caught up in the sound itself
and forgotten the fact that the energy
behind it is all that matters.
That's where things are getting fucked
up.
Exactly what we were talking about
earlier when we were talking about
religion.
Exactly on drugs,
right?
We're talking about why people are
addicted to drugs.
We're not talking about the emptiness
of their lives that leads them into
those heroin and prescription drugs and
all that.
Also terrorism.
We're talking about bombs going off and
people getting killed.
We're not talking about how,
why someone's life is so empty that you
put on a suicide vest in the first
place.
We're not.
We're looking at the surface of things
and we're not interested in what's going
on behind.
I was watching Fox News the other day
and there was some woman who was on on
and she was doing like one of those open
letter to the president things and she
was doing it all.
Fox News,
you know,
and she was saying that this country was
founded on Judeo Christian values and
she was going to this thing about
responding and Obama's response to the
terror attacks in Paris.
Not sufficiently burrowing.
Exactly.
Not,
not,
not sufficiently aggressive or didn't
make her feel comfortable on top of it.
Your job is to keep me safe,
but it's just really an opportunity for
her to step up and you know,
and proclaim,
claim her ideology to be the greatest
ideology and this other ideology that's
killing people.
Right.
Is representatives of this ideology that
there's the enemy of this United States
of America,
which was founded by my call.
That's
right.
That's it,
man.
That's interesting.
Yeah,
because you.
You realized that like that.
What's that?
There is a kind of war that's raging
around this planet,
but it's like a war against people who
are,
for whatever reason,
intent on expressing anger into the
world and 10 on expressing power over
other people into the world and people
who are thinking,
I think there might be another way.
Maybe there was a way that we can
readapt or maybe there are evolved to
fit into this society or maybe there's a
whole new way where we don't have to try
to constantly punch back at a person who
has punched us.
That's the war.
It's just a war between when you get
fucking hit on the interstate when your
nice car gets hit because some asshole
isn't paying attention.
Do you get out and scream at him or do
you ask him if he's okay and there's a
whole group of people who think,
no,
you fuck that motherfucker up.
You teach them a lesson.
Let them understand if he's not paying
attention,
he's gonna get fucked up.
You become the hand of God and the world
read,
you know,
bringing vengeance as much as you can.
Or the other version of it is you try to
overcome that desire and you become a
servant of some concept,
which is that the most important thing.
Even if we've lost everything,
man,
even if we become locust and that's all
gone and you know,
the more you talk about it,
man,
the more I do know what you mean.
Earlier I was like,
ah,
my low kids,
but I do hear what you're saying.
I think it's very sweet and actually
kind of tragic and sad,
but if this is the case,
then we still have to figure out a way
to like even now as much as possible put
out into the world love and it doesn't
matter what language we're using,
if love is behind it,
I think that's the highest thing.
By the way,
I think that's all that matters is like
that meal was good because
you were with people you love.
If you are sitting after that hunt with
a bunch of people that you disliked or
assholes,
I bet it wouldn't have been as delicious
as of a meal.
Yeah,
but here's the problem with that
thought,
it wouldn't have been as good.
We had several meals behind the campfire
where we didn't kill anything there
wasn't as good,
but.
And also you're in a love.
You're a love supporting environment
that you're working together,
you're in nature,
you're around a fire and you're
successful at something that's
difficult.
All those things.
Even if they were assholes,
you'd probably find more common ground
with them there.
Then you would sit around a conference
table.
Yeah.
Well,
it's definitely a,
there's also a separation from society.
Complete total separation.
When you're up there,
there's no cell phone signal.
You don't hear anything.
It's complete silence.
It's a very strange feeling of almost a
lonely detachment because you realize
you are not,
you're not just off the grid.
The grid is nowhere to be seen and we
need each other.
Yeah.
You need each other.
You got it.
I think that's right
where we come from.
We come from this place where we need
each other.
And where were the first thing you
think,
you know,
like hunter gatherers,
they,
uh,
they share arrows and so like,
yeah,
they typically share Arrow.
So I make arrows a certain way.
You make them another way,
whatever,
but then we all give them to each other.
They're constantly flowing.
So you might be on a hunt where you shot
the elk,
that Arrow that you shot is in the elk,
but I made it and it's a way of
obscuring who gets credit for the kill.
And that's cool.
And you find this universally among
foragers,
whether it's in the internet or in Papa
New Guinea.
They do these,
they have these mechanisms to make sure
that the sharing happens not only of the
meat but of the reputational aspect.
That's interesting.
Everybody's cool.
There are all these mechanisms built in
to keep anybody from getting too big for
their Britches,
you know,
till the cannibals move in and then they
start killing
people and eating them because there's
no protein because they couldn't get any
elk.
It's a problem that cannabis will move
in
fuckers.
You got to be ready.
But here's the good news about the
locus.
They do switch bank,
take grass offers.
You can be aggressive.
Stops.
Yeah.
Eventually.
And then you can't fly anymore.
You fuck.
And Lucas are cannibalistic and
grasshoppers aren't to tie it into the
whole cannibalism.
Yeah.
That's why they swarm because if you
slow down,
the one behind you will eat you.
Oh my God.
That's where we are working at Amazon.
That's what it's like working in New
York City working on Amazon.
Supposed to be crazy.
Right?
There's warehouses they'll run around
this time when you have a timer.
Have you ever.
There was a,
I think it was a radiolab podcast,
was one of the podcasts I listened to
that talked to an ex employee at Amazon
about what kind of stress it is to work.
Like say if you order something,
like say if you order a led flashlight
and it,
it shows up on their.
They have like a little pad,
like a,
a tablet device and it has a timer and
it's like you have to
go find this and you have to grab it and
you have like 30 seconds so you like
literally running,
looking for this flashlight and you have
to get it to the sorting and put it in
the box and get the label.
They had this terrible game show.
There was a show like that when I was a
kid when we had to run the money maze or
something like that.
I remember that you had to fill your car
up with the most expensive things or
something and know this is a different
one.
This is where you got like couples and
you got the the like the wives up on a
platform and the two husbands down and
there's a maze like where the walls
seven feet high and the women can see
where the money is and they're yelling
to their husbands like rats and like,
no,
go left.
I said left that and the husbands are
scurrying around in the maze and whoever
gets to the money pot first wins.
It's a good divorce generating game show
like so many of them.
What do you think,
man?
Do you think it's hopeless?
This you like when you talk about it and
you talk about it and then I think about
it,
it's like,
so it fills you this as a kind of like
weirdness Dahlia.
Like you think my God,
this there's a type of life that is
clearly still accessible to people but
maybe not accessible to everyone as a
whole.
Do you have any idea of like how you
would reorganize or restructure?
What I say in the book is,
is where there's no way we're going
back.
That's over,
right?
Because there's 7 billion.
They're going to be 10 billion in 100
years.
There's no way.
There's not enough land or animals or
whatever,
so we're going to live in an artificial
environment,
but you know you're going to live in a
zoo.
Do you want to live in the Calcutta zoo
or the San Diego zoo?
Right?
I mean,
come on.
The San Diego Zoo.
It's built with an understanding of the
natural environment of the animals that
are enclosed there.
So I want to live in a natural
environment that's got my interest in
mind and in order to do that,
you have to understand what kind of
animal homo sapiens is,
which means you have to cut through a
lot of the bullshit propaganda that
you've been here in your whole life.
This hobbs and bullshit about how
prehistoric people all died in their
thirties.
And it was a struggle for survival and
predators lurked in every shadow.
And it was this terrible,
you know,
dangerous world.
You actually look at the anthropological
data.
Hunter gatherers are chilled out,
happy,
relaxed people who are not dealing with
the sorts of chronic stress we are.
And you hear all these bullshit
arguments that wouldn't last a second if
they weren't propping up the
civilizational edifice like that.
Everyone died in their thirties and
hunter gathers.
That's absolutely untrue.
But I just heard the dean of the Medical
School of Columbia University say it in
an NPR interview.
It's,
it's everywhere.
Not The worst thing to happen to die
young.
Well,
there's certainly some benefits to
modern medicine.
One hundred percent,
but there's,
there's also some negative consequences
of our overly complicated society.
There's no doubt about it.
I mean the,
the levels of depression that people
experienced
in the levels of discontent with their
existence.
You know,
we were talking yesterday about people
wanting to take a chance to go do
something.
They want to do something outside of
what they're doing for a job.
Like maybe they have,
maybe they like making pottery or
whatever it is,
but they just don't have the time.
Maybe they want to be a tattooist.
They just don't have the time to
dedicate to jump into it.
And then along the way get saddled with
debt and maybe a family that you have an
obligation to feed.
And then you're stuck in your trap.
That trap that,
that feeling of discontent with one's
own daily existence.
You Day by day life is more commonplace
than not.
It's way more common.
It's essential because we were saying to
keep you running on the wheel,
you got to believe x is going to make
you happy.
The cars going to,
the next thing is going to do it.
That's.
And that's a pernicious lie that,
that we've heard so many times we come
to believe it's an,
it's an aspect of reality itself.
And it isn't.
And that's,
that's,
you know,
if you look at the hunter gather data,
what you see is,
is these people who,
I mean you were talking about it
earlier,
how we need something to like a
challenge to take us to the next level.
For them,
the challenge is like we're going to go
hunting,
you know,
and it'll feel great and,
and we'll eat and if we don't eat they
will eat tomorrow.
Well that's why those subsistence shows.
Have you ever watched those shows and
discovery channel shows?
Those shows are extremely popular today
because people are sort of recognizing
that like,
wow,
these people seem happy and all they
have is like five dogs.
They live in Alaska and they just take
their sled out and they chopped down a
fucking tree to build a house with like
these people are living on the stamina.
That's the thing is immediacy.
Just to play devil's advocate here,
isn't this a different version of what
you're talking about?
The modern human thinks,
if I have this thing,
a car or whatever the thing is,
the nicer job,
better or whatever,
I'll be happy.
What you're saying is if I have an
immediacy,
if I'm more connected to nature,
if I moved to Alaska,
if I become a hunter,
I'll be happy,
but both of these things have within
them the idea that I need some other
thing to be happy.
Whereas the what I keep hearing and what
I subscribed to you is that to be happy,
you have to be in the present moment.
Wherever you are,
whatever situation you're in,
whatever's going on,
whether you're in an office and a job
you don't like in a marriage you don't
like with a bunch of kids that you don't
like.
Instead of fleeing from that by planning
some fantasy of becoming a tattoo artist
or a potter,
they're real way out is to allow
yourself to be fully in the experience
of what's happening right now and not
that thing itself.
Just doing that and maybe that is what
happens when you're in nature as you are
more in the present moment,
but that makes way more sense when
you're in nature because if you're
working in an insurance company and you
just go on over client's claims day in
and day out,
it's super hard to be in a joyful
moment.
It's super hard to be when you really
want
to get out of there and make music like
you have songs and ideas in your head.
Do you want to put them to wax,
but your fucking kids need formula?
Well,
it's not.
It's not.
Jus.
The thing is it's like that.
The idea is,
sure,
for sure,
but this is where you're at right now.
That's it,
right?
That's where you are.
You're not at a situation where you're
going to start a band and you're not in
a situation where you're going to become
a potter right now could be in the
future,
but the trick is that even though you're
not in the fucking Anna rondex hunting
and you're not fishing,
even though you're wherever you're at
right now,
get into that place.
Let Yourself,
and it's not about happiness,
it's certainly not about joy or bliss or
anything like that.
You're not feeling joy and bliss.
You're feeling a kind of claustrophobic
horror at the concept that what the
situation you're in right now is going
to continue forever and so your mind is
fabricated and escape route,
which is this thing or that thing,
whatever it may be,
but the true,
the true situation is that until you
train yourself to be in the present
moment,
it doesn't matter where you are,
you're dead.
You're not alive,
you're not.
It doesn't matter.
You have to train yourself to get in the
moment.
Then once you're in the moment,
then start making the move.
Okay.
Now you say in the moment like how do
you address that?
Like what?
When you're thinking about you being in
the moment,
like your own personal experience,
what do,
what do you do to try to achieve that
sort of centered feeling?
Well,
it's,
well,
it's the practice of mindfulness.
So it's the idea of,
you know,
what it's,
I will notice from time to time when I'm
lucky that I've been carried away by my
thoughts like that fucking thing you
were saying about laying in bed.
You can generate more stress chemicals.
I'll recognize like,
Holy Shit,
I've been in a vortex of thinking for
the last two days.
I've been caught in this like endless
recurring series of worries or scenarios
or whatever it may be or things I need
to do or things I uh,
I just did.
And,
and suddenly I realized I haven't been
here at all at all.
I've just been caught up in what's
called in your head.
You're caught up in the thought pattern.
So the,
uh,
the practice is,
and this is something like,
you know,
uh,
Jack Kornfield talks about how the Guy
who taught in meditation,
Adrienne Shaw,
uh,
was saying to him that I'm,
one of his students was saying,
I'm too busy to meditate.
I'm too busy to Metadata,
have time to do that.
And his response was our youtube busy to
breathe.
Are you too busy to breathe?
You can breathe,
right?
That's all you need to do.
All you need is your breath.
And no matter where you are,
what you're doing,
where you're at,
you can begin to put your attention away
from the incredible array of worries
that you have incredible array of
fantasies that you have incredible
arrays of.
If this had happened,
I'd be happier if I could do this,
I'll be a better person and just bring
it to your breath in and out and through
the nose,
out through the nose.
And then it's not going to stop these
fucking thoughts,
but instead of you being controlled by
them and caught up in them,
I mean,
you talk about looking at your fucking
cell phone.
Get rid of cell phones.
People are still looking at cell phones.
It's just their various worries and
things that they're constantly
ruminating over.
It's another form of the cell phone.
You're fixating on these endless
recurring worries,
so you bring it to the breath,
the worries emerge,
the happiness,
whatever it is is there,
but it's not you.
You're not identifying with it anymore.
You're not identifying with the specific
emotional state,
this specific intellectual state the
specific thing anymore.
You're just observing and watching and
that thing,
that consciousness,
the more you become that,
the more you will find yourself
experiencing what you were talking
about.
These rare moments of peace,
these moments of like,
Whoa,
Holy Shit,
regardless of what's happening around
me,
I'm still centered,
untouched,
unfreaking,
unanxious.
I'm just watching.
So that's the,
that's the,
uh,
the concept.
And it's a very hopeful concept because
some people do not have access to the
kind of zoo you're talking about
prisoners,
for example,
people who are incarcerated right now,
they don't get to get out of that
system.
So they have to find a way in the midst
of all of that negative phenomena to
allow themselves to experience the same
kind of peace or tranquility that you
were experiencing with your friends in
front of that Campfire,
and that is why the concept of
cultivation is so important in Buddhism,
which is the idea that these experiences
which in various many different world
religions say it,
their route,
what is so wonderful about them is love
that feeling of love,
which is also compared to the feeling of
coming home,
being at home,
finding your home,
coming back home.
It's all the same because the feeling of
what is the feeling of being at home.
It's a feeling of being at what did you
call it,
a situation of acceptance and love.
It's that feeling of being sick,
truly safe or not safe because of the
government,
but safe because you're surrounded by
people who love you and you're loving
them and you know that you can be taken
care of.
The concept is that feeling can be
cultivated in that cultivation starts
with some form of the practice of
mindfulness or whatever you want to call
it.
I think what you're saying actually
isn't in conflict at all with the the
other point,
you know,
the because the mindfulness being here
in the moment.
I think if you're like,
if you've got a shitty job in a cubicle
and you're trying to distract yourself
from it,
you're listening to podcasts all day
while you shuffle paperwork or whatever,
right?
Um,
and you're not really being in the
moment.
It is advantageous to be in the moment
if it allows you to see
that the moment is fucking killing you
and then you make a realistic.
You're not going to be a hunter
gatherer,
but you make a realistic plan to change
your life.
It can be abused,
right?
I mean,
if you're in prison,
that's a different deal.
You're going to be there for 10 years.
You're not gonna like don't try to
escape is my advice,
but if,
but if it's just a dead end job,
I mean I got this great email a couple
days ago from someone who I had these
guys on who,
uh,
live in camper vans.
Several,
one guy,
funny guy,
he,
uh,
worked in a tiger sanctuary in Thailand
teaching baby tigers not to eat people.
Essentially.
He was like the Guinea pig.
It would go in and play with the baby
tigers to teach them like,
don't eat people.
People are cool.
Anyway,
he flew to Chile,
bought a VW Camper van and drove from
Chile to Alaska in this camper van and
just picked up people along the way and
you know,
had all these adventures for years.
I think he said,
wow.
Anyway,
years of driving.
Yeah.
I mean off and on,
you know,
it would break down.
I think he,
he swapped out the engine five times or
something cause vw vans and known for
reliability.
Anyway,
so somebody who listened to this series
of podcast I did with people who live in
their vans,
some guy's like,
yeah,
I quit my job.
My wife and I bought a van.
We'd been in it six months and it's
fucking awesome.
You know,
it's like he completely changed his
life.
He's and he's thrilled.
I love to hear,
if you live in a shitty situation like
that long enough for the job you hate
and bills that don't make any sense and
for stuff that you don't even want or
enjoy anymore than that idea of getting
in that camper and just driving across
the country seems amazing.
It seems like freedom and it's doable.
It's doable if you're.
If you're willing to give up a lot of
the bullshit,
you know?
That's right.
Yeah.
That's the thing,
man.
My friend Steve Maxwell,
he doesn't even have a camper.
He just lives in hotels.
He has a bag for all of his belongings.
He's a pro.
He's a personal trainer and he's like
world renowned.
He puts on these camps and seminars and
stuff like that and him and his
girlfriend,
they travel all over the world.
Constant travel,
that's all they do.
They stay from hotel to hotel and he
trains people everywhere and he used to
have a big gym and he used to have a
house and then he went from the big
German house,
get divorced.
He got like a camper van,
like with a like a,
like you're sleeping.
It got sick of that,
sold that fucking things that,
you know what?
I'm just going to get everything down to
a 10 gallon bag.
He's got a 10 gallon bag with all his
worldly possessions and that's it.
Yeah.
Digital nomads,
you know about them.
There's a growing,
thriving world of young people who have
jobs where they do stuff on the
Internet,
right?
They either coding or editing or
whatever.
Something you can do through the
computer.
So if you're making money through the
computer,
why he living in la where you're paying
two grand,
three grand for,
you know.
So they moved to places like Bangkok,
Ecuador,
there,
there's like hotspots around the world
where there are thousands of these
people living out of backpacks,
they live in guest houses and they work
in cafes or wherever they get Wifi and
that's what they're doing.
And it's a
funny thing because they're ahead of the
laws,
right?
So tax laws don't know what to do with
these people because you don't,
you're not stable anywhere.
And the laws are all set up where you
pay tax,
where you are.
Well I'm three months in Bangkok,
then I'm off to Chile.
Then I'm off here like,
well who do I pay tax too?
I'll take it to the next level.
What if you switched everything to
digital currency and finding more and
more people are accepting bitcoin and
other forms of digital currency.
So they start using that to pay for the
rent,
pay for their food,
pay for their drinks,
pay for their travel,
no record of animal,
what the fuck.
And then they live in Thailand
sometimes.
Yeah,
sometimes they don't.
Wild Man.
And so it should be the idea of you
being constrained to a patch of dirt and
you have to have a piece of paper to
show other people and the other patch of
dirt so I can cross over.
Can I enter into your kingdom?
Depends.
Did you at one point in time drive your
carriage under the influence of wine,
but I was in the call was denied entry
into my kingdom of doubt of you're in a
car with someone and they're drunk and
you're sober and you get pulled over.
You're going to get a Dui.
If you get that.
Yes.
If that person's drunk and you're an
adult and you're sober and that person's
drunk driving,
you can get a dui to try.
You can get in trouble for allowing
someone to drive a car.
I don't know what exact for polk.
Find out what exactly the law is.
How the fuck would you mainly similar.
It's extremely similar,
if you will.
I believe in.
It might be a state to state basis or am
I just made it up,
but I'm pretty sure it's true.
If you are drunk,
I made it up.
I really,
if you,
if you are drunk and you have a
passenger in your car,
that passenger I think in can get
arrested as well.
Wow.
Even if they don't have a driver's
license,
if they're an adult,
I think they can get arrested as well if
they don't have a driver's license at
all.
That's a good point.
That's interesting because then it's
like,
well officer,
you know it took the wheel but you're
driving without a license.
Like,
well yeah,
but my point being they won't let you.
In Canada,
if you have a Dui they'll go fuck off.
Get out of here.
They turn you around.
They want no douchebags in Canada.
If you have a violent assault and you're
on your arrest record.
I almost got kicked out it.
I almost got not let into Canada had a
will for having stolen a snickers bar in
Alaska in 1982.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
I went to prison.
I think I told that story.
Yeah,
you did this area.
So.
But I was told when I did four days,
you know,
and then I went before the magistrate
and he said if you don't get arrested
again in a year,
this will go off your record and all
that.
So ever since when I've been asked if
I've ever been convicted of a crime,
I always said no because I figured it's
not on my record.
I don't want to confuse everybody and
you know,
whatever.
And,
but the first time we went into Canada
at BC,
you know,
he asked all these questions and we went
and sat down and he called me up,
you know,
just,
my wife and you.
And he's like,
is there anything you want to tell me
about 1980 to 1982,
I don't know.
I was college and
I don't know what he said,
the arrest and conviction,
fairbanks,
Alaska.
I'm like,
how are you kidding me?
And I told him I eat a snickers bar and
the fucking grocery store and it turned
into this thing and.
But they told me it wasn't on my record
and he said,
well,
Canada gets your FBI records.
So.
So if you're ever so like there's a
federal level where that shit doesn't go
away,
you know,
it's even more deep because Eddie Bravo
got arrested and never even went to jail
and it shows up every time he goes into
Canada.
He got arrested because he worked for a
check cashing company and so he used to
drive around with large sums of cash on
him.
When he got pulled over by the cops,
cops pulled them over and he said,
officer,
I want to let you know that I have a
loaded handgun in the car.
Here's my license to have it.
They go,
please step out of the car.
They handcuff him,
they check everything,
make sure it's all kosher,
everything checks out.
They let them go.
But that incident is on his record.
So when he goes into Canada,
they pull them aside.
Every time I got stuff with him once,
now I fucking,
if we go to Canada together,
I left that to get ahead of me.
Like,
y'all fucking meet you outside because
he gets dragged into that room.
Then they start asking you questions
too.
And I'm like,
dude,
at least they're Canadian.
Yeah.
Hearing hearing were coming the other
way.
It is
you.
If you can't offer a convincing defense
as to why you weren't driving,
you may also be arrested and charged
with reckless endangerment.
You're arresting.
Officer will argue that you put
yourself,
the driver and members of the public in
danger by allowing your friend to drive
drunk.
Their case may be bolstered by the
presence of other passengers in the
vehicle.
Wow.
Yup.
You'll need to prove that.
The paragraph before that said,
you need to prove that you're not
currently licensed to drive.
Don't know how to drive or have a
medical restriction that prevents you
from driving crazy.
Yeah.
See.
So I'm kinda right.
Better off being shit faced.
So if your shit faced and your friend's
driving,
then you're okay.
Yeah.
You're shaking.
Your friend's driving like,
I wouldn't fucking drive home drunk.
I'm so drunk.
I didn't even know he was drunk.
So if you get pulled over and you're not
drunk,
hit that bottle for the splash whiskey
all of your face.
You're hammered here.
Okay.
He should play as play.
Sleeping or just say I took acid more
than five times.
I hadn't legally insane.
I couldn't drive to the real scary thing
about what you're talking about as far
as like getting in other countries
because it shit on your record.
This is something that when I
interviewed Aaron Frank at Singularity
University,
they,
they try to like think about like what
are the implications of these
technologies?
So you know,
the um,
the recent terrorist attack or they shot
up that people that couples shout out
the people and apparently even though I
think this got disproven,
Bernardino San Bernardino,
there were talking about how one of them
was a professed jihadist on their
facebook page and they're saying,
well we don't check social there.
So whatever they've posted on facebook,
we don't do that.
And you know,
a lot of news stations are saying,
a lot of people are saying,
what the fuck?
That's crazy.
You should check that.
You should definitely check that.
So at singularity university there
saying what happens if the society
changes so much,
that shit that you've posted online and
admitted to doing becomes illegal.
What happens then when all of that stuff
is infinitely accessible by all future
governments?
What happens when if like who knows?
You know,
this is the scary thing that may happen
right?
With mccarthy and the the ride communist
shaken shift.
Just that and that's the terrifying
thing and I don't want to put negative
energy out there.
I think we're all beings of love and
ultimately everything's going to be
okay,
but the but the one scary thing about
when you look at like for profit or for
profit conflict and you and you look at
the fact that there is a benefit to some
awful thing happening in the United
States on a big scale.
There's a monetary benefit to a great
many people living in the United States,
weapons manufacturers,
legislators,
people who are just get off on
controlling other people and you realize
that it not only benefits them,
but they're also as a huge incentive for
people in other parts of the world to
create that event.
Knowing that all it takes is one
catastrophic event.
One catastrophic event were away.
We were like,
what?
One dirty bomb away.
One new September,
11th away from experiencing one of the
greatest dimunition of personal liberty
that has ever happened in this country
and the people who.
There's a lot of people who would like
that to happen and they're not just
terrorists.
There's people who would like that to
happen,
who run prisons.
There are people like that to happen who
like says who want world war three to
happen because they sell web.
There's so in.
That to me is fucking scary to think.
And if something like that did happen
and when we enter into some new or
wellbeing awfulness,
it didn't.
In all your shit that you've posted
every single one of your podcasts.
So you're going first man,
what a moving to Canada.
It doesn't matter.
You can't get into Canada.
You can't get into fucking candidate
with the stuff you posted on your
facebook page and you will know.
I mean we're talking about what said,
I think you got to get out now.
That's what I'm going to be.
Australia saved nowhere,
so it seems like a good move.
Australia is awesome over.
Melbourne's amazing.
Although they're Sudanese perinos know
Melbourne's got,
they've got some seriously strict drug
laws.
Man.
I was at the,
I was,
I was in Australia at the uh,
uh,
yeah,
no,
actually that was,
I was in New Zealand,
not Australia.
Sorry.
I think Australia is strict drug laws in
New South Wales does help bring sniffer
dogs around,
you know,
like we're out in public.
Just try to find.
We're
locked.
Then you can't even wash the weed out of
your hair.
How do you going to smell it to bang a
cat?
Cat up a tree.
Well,
again,
I think we're there.
I mean,
you keep phrasing things in terms of
like what if we're on the verge of.
And I keep thinking,
dude,
we've been there for a long time.
I mean,
Eisenhower's,
you know,
his parting speech,
the military industrial complex is,
you know,
he was warning at.
We're in a situation after World War Two
where the army doesn't stand down all
these industries.
That sprang up Los Angeles as a result
of World War Two,
right?
A Raytheon and Boeing,
they're all on the west coast because
they were pumping out those airplanes
and ships to go beat the japs and then
they,
they're looking for something to do
while they got to keep us on a war
footing forever consulted my Harvard
placemat and you shouldn't say zap jabs.
Oh,
I thought I said Nips.
My cries even worse.
Your cultural appropriation culturally
appropriating their work.
She,
the,
that always gets me that we'd make up
names for countries we don't like the
name they use.
What do you guys call yourself?
Nip Paul.
We don't like it.
We're going to Japan.
Japan please.
We just decide like,
this is a bunch of them.
Like that.
That was quite a few countries is in
Greece.
Grease the.
They didn't call themselves grease right
where they call himself.
That's great to me.
Uh,
use
a Turkey to Turkey.
They call themselves Turkey.
It was a few countries and I don't
remember what does the word they use
mean Turkey?
I don't know.
You know,
I don't think.
Yeah,
it's weird that it's the same as that
bird.
If it wasn't for Thanksgiving,
would anybody give a fuck about Turkey
country whole hunt or.
No?
Nobody likes to eat Turkey.
I mean,
it's good,
but it's not.
The best grain is better than Turkey.
Can we agree?
Yeah.
There's no Kentucky Fried Turkey.
There's no Turkey stores now.
Chicken stores is Popeye's chicken.
There's.
There's A.
There's Kentucky Fried Chicken,
Turkey King Edward Bernays.
Turkey Bacon for breakfast is is
completely an invention of this
advertising guy.
He was hired by the company.
I forget the name of the company,
but they're still around in some form
that hired him to sell more pork and so
he came up with this idea like bacon and
eggs.
That's what's for breakfast.
You got to like integrate it into the
cultural traditions and ever since then
it's been considered breakfast meat and
boom.
Meanwhile it's awesome.
So congratulations.
So he was also behind the fluoridation
of the water supply hired by Alcoa
because they had all this,
all this.
I'm a byproduct of making aluminum,
which is fluoride.
And they wanted to like,
what are we going to do with all this
stuff?
You know,
we've got to find a way to sell it.
Who can we sell it to?
And he figured out like,
Oh,
we can,
you know,
it's good for dental.
It'll save everyone and get the
government to buy it.
It's so funny.
We accept that man because like if
someone comes over to your house and
you're like,
do you want some water?
And they're like,
yeah.
And you're like,
do you want me to add some fluoride to
it?
I'd be like,
fuck yeah,
it is a chemical that kills you.
So yeah.
Could you put a little fluoride in your
head can kill you.
It doesn't take a whole lot.
Like how much kills you?
A couple of teaspoons.
Full.
I don't know.
I have no tie with white teeth.
But is that real?
What's going on with dental hygiene
versus.
I mean,
is it Florida in the water that makes a
difference or being conscious of dental
hygiene,
dental hygiene.
It's made the difference in tooth decay
and people.
Well,
I mean talking to you,
talking to me,
I'm always going to take it back to
foragers.
Foragers have amazing teeth meet and
roots and shit.
Well,
some sand in a Weston Smith.
What is this?
We put in this.
Oh,
this is bernays.
Said that.
Get the Bacon for breakfast and he is
also responsible for fluoride in the
water and Dixie Dixie Cup.
Jamie is just like Dixie Cup show and
then I'm not full of Shit.
I love it.
Jamie.
Thinking that they were drinking out of
unsafe.
What?
Look at this.
His campaign for Dixie Cups.
Scared people into thinking that glasses
they were drinking out of.
We're unsanitary and can be replaced by
disposable cups.
Wow.
Did you read this for you?
Put it up.
That's insane.
And it was the beach nut packing company
that's hired.
This guy was amazing,
but the bacon he got right.
Oh,
he got.
He got everything right.
Dead on with the Bacon.
Bacon.
He also was behind the Virginia slims
thing like,
oh,
how can we use feminism to get women to
buy cigarettes?
It's a feminist cigarette and it's come
a long way,
baby.
I bet that guy got laid like crazy.
I bet he was just a fucking maestro and
he was Freud's nephew.
Oh my goodness.
So he had the benefit of psychological
examination under his uncle and he's
proud of himself,
like he doesn't slightly ashamed dead.
He just died like 10 years ago.
Interviews with them where he's like,
yeah,
I did all this.
Shit was happy.
His success ratio is amazing,
right?
Oh,
he hit every one out of the park over
and over.
If that's what you're trying to do and
nobody tells you it's evil mean no one
really.
You know what's really fucked up is
those God damn drug commercials,
those drug commercials where people are
happy and they're walking hand in hand
and meadows and then they start talking
about explosive bloody diarrhea,
but they always do it in that voice that
I think we're being trained to ignore.
There's that voice at the end of the
thing.
Side effects may include whenever they
me to just ignore what I'm saying and
watch the pretty picture.
Watch a pretty picture as your dog.
Exactly about this bullshit.
They should have to show you those side
effects while they're doing this.
Is this is hilarious,
I don't know if you've seen this.
I tweeted this the other day.
The Australia came up with this thing
called a stoner slaw and it's so stupid
that people.
It's backfiring and causing people to
smoke pot.
Also stoner slot.
If you go to stoner slot.com,
it's an actual weed website,
so what's funny about it is that it
actually brought all this business too
because if you go to stoners,
sloths.com
dot a U.
I don't know the exact.
Yeah,
there it is.
Yeah.
If you go to stoners,
sloths,
whatever their website is dot a you.
Yeah.
There you go.
In the only sell Endeca and that's
right.
Yeah,
there it is.
Your worse on wheat,
so that's a.
You now take the.
Hey you off.
I haven't tried it.
I might embarrass myself here,
but an article I read,
they said it goes to a weed website.
I guess not.
Maybe somebody bought it.
Who know the government social network.
They have a stoner,
sloths social network.
What do they think it's going to turn
into?
The next thing is going to turn to the
next facebook,
but yeah,
this is like a big embarrassment.
Let's play it because it's fucking so
stupid.
It's so stupid.
It's awesome.
I haven't seen it.
It's so dumb,
but it's like that fucking thing.
Here's the thing about,
um,
the talking dog commercial that we all
enjoyed back in the day.
Yeah.
Those were made by our partnership for
drug free America and the fucked up part
about a partnership for drug free
America is they are funded by alcohol
and tobacco companies and pharmaceutical
companies.
And my joke was that's like hookers
doing commercials against strippers and
it really is like them doing commercials
pot.
It's insane.
Like they're not against drugs,
just drugs that they don't sell here.
Slaw in class.
You're worse on weed.
Stoner.
Sloth,
but little did the creators know.
Oh,
I see that stoner.
Sloths.com.
Somebody put it down.
Is also the name of an online cannabis
product.
Retail.
It's not on.
It's not up anymore though.
That's what's weird.
I wonder if their website got crushed.
Yeah.
Maybe stoner.
Sloth.
Yeah.
Well this is.
This is something that Australia is
doing because they're kind of behind the
times when it comes to marijuana
propaganda,
they.
They're still buying into some shit that
we thought of 15,
20 years ago.
New South Wales government ads.
This is just so stupid.
Yeah,
so Australia will be perfect if it had
weed,
but that's the thing about the world.
There is no perfect place.
You go to the most amazing jungle island
habitat and you know,
well you got to hang out with these
fucking people.
Right?
You know Australia though.
Other than that,
other than their stance,
I lead a Melbourne's.
Most of my favorite places I've ever
been.
Remind me.
A lot of San Francisco Sorta cafe
vibe and progressive and very smart,
very smart people.
You guys should do the.
I went down there to do this thing
called the festival of dangerous ideas.
You guys,
you guys would both fit right into the
vibe.
It's really cool.
You get.
It's like Ted,
I think we might've talked about it.
but without the sort of brand
protection,
paranoia and that's a great way to put
it down and then protection.
They're just like,
you know,
just say something crazy and provocative
and we just want people to walk out of
here talking about whatever you say and
that's great.
Bringing shame shape because we're not
getting on a fucking plane and fly
across the ocean to sound provocative
and your country where they do what they
do at the Sydney Opera House.
That's pretty cool.
Yeah,
I played there.
That's,
that's an awesome spot.
Sydney is awesome too.
I like Sydney as well.
I like both.
I like Sydney,
like Melbourne was interesting because
uh,
the food was fucking sensational.
Yeah.
Of that Asian market.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Have you,
did you go up to the barrier reef and do
all the announcements?
I didn't either.
It's only up there for a few days for
the fight,
for a,
had a couple shows.
Oh,
you were there just recently for the
lousy thing.
It's amazing how wrecked your brain gets
when you come back.
Like wrecked for days I would work out
and I'd just be like,
where I'd normally be able to do like 10
reps of something.
I'd get to like six and I'd be like,
fuck,
I got three more,
seven,
fuck two more.
I just couldn't do it.
I almost couldn't do the same physical
things that I used to do.
I mean I could get to it,
but like if I was going to do 10 reps,
I'd probably get like nine or eight,
but the,
but getting to it would be way harder.
But just like I couldn't believe it man.
And everyone's like,
you're going to be fucked up for about a
week from that.
And it's true.
It really does.
Requeue does something weird to you,
like you just,
you feel like your battery is broken.
Well this Guy Dan who does all the sleep
research,
uh,
this is his area,
like he's looking into why,
why that fucks you up so bad.
Can you change Melatonin and you know,
using different medications and
different techniques.
He works with seals and stuff.
He's like hardcore guy and apparently
there are all these techniques that you
can do a changing your sleep cycle
before you go and you know,
time.
So you wake up at a different time and
all that.
It just seems like too much trouble to
me.
You know what they say too?
This is very bizarre.
It's way harder to go from Australia to
the United States and it is to go from
the United States to Australia like
apparently that doesn't fuck up your
circadian rhythms as much.
You're going east is harder.
We're just so weird because we want to
think of ourselves as being very simple,
very simple,
very autonomous little beings that I
just need my food,
my vitamins,
and I'm normal.
Now.
You're like tied into the cycles of the
earth itself.
The light and dark,
the literal rising and setting of the
sun has a direct effect on the rhythm of
your body,
your biological operating
system,
falters.
When you throw that and it has to
readjust and set things back and think
about women who are menstruating with
the phases of the moon every month.
I mean that's really intense.
Here's my favorite one is when a bunch
of chicks live together and they start
smelling pussies and their,
their,
their bodies don't even realize it,
but they get these coinciding menstrual
cycles.
How strangers.
Then if that's happening,
what other stuff is happening that we
don't know about,
like how much are humans harmonizing
with each other and other ways that we
aren't even aware of it,
but my favorite example of that is this
guy bruce vet weekend in Switzerland who
did research that become known as the
sweaty shirts study.
I don't know if I've talked about this
on the podcast before,
but so he.
He wanted to understand why women's
sense of smell is so much stronger than
men's.
Women can smell about seven times more
than men.
Really?
Yeah.
Which is time.
If you come home with smelling funny,
you're not going to get away with it.
That sucks for them,
man.
You need to come home smelling funny.
Like smelling like pussy.
Exactly.
Yeah.
I don't think you're going to get away
with it.
So anyway,
so he wanted to understand why is this
and his hypothesis was that women are
picking up information about men's
immune system from their pheromones,
from the way they smell,
because you'll hear women often will say
like,
he's a cool guy.
He's got a good job,
he's funny,
whatever,
but the smell smells not right.
It's a deal breaker.
The smell,
they'll say the smell smell,
and it's not that he smells bad,
it's just the smells not right.
That'll be a deal breaker for a lot of
women.
You never hear him say that,
right?
Yeah,
but you do.
People do smell better.
Like some people just smell good,
smell them.
They just want to squeeze them.
They smell good.
You know,
and I'm not talking about like perfumes
or just body.
I kind of a little bit offensive.
I've always felt like perfumes,
a little offensive.
Like I want to know what's going on
here.
Why?
Because it's a masking.
Your fucking smoke bomb thrown down.
I can't.
Trying to find out where.
Where's the real you?
And they're like,
well no one's ever smelled a woman like
a healthy woman and go,
man,
I wish he'd fucking spray some roses on
this big.
You know,
France in the old days.
Well that's a different thing,
right?
You're dealing with personal hygiene
issues,
but today when you're dealing with
people that take regular showers,
bathe so you don't stink,
sorry,
just to finish the story.
So check this out because this is
important knowledge for people to have.
So he,
he,
uh,
got a bunch of guys who were deficient
in one part of their immune response and
then a bunch of women who were also
deficient in one part,
the immune response,
it's called his immune
histocompatibility index and let's say
it has five elements.
So they would find a bunch of guys who
are low in one or two or number three or
number four,
whatever.
And women who had the same different
deficiencies.
That hypothesis was that a woman who's
low in factor three won't be attracted
to men who are low in factor three,
there'll be attracted to men who are
high in factor three because then the
babies be healthy,
right?
So he gets these guys to wear tee shirts
for three days and nights with no
deodorant,
no showers,
no soap,
nothing.
Then puts the tee shirts in plastic
bags.
Then he has the women's smell,
the bags and mark on a piece of paper
how attractive they thought the men were
based only on the smell of the tee
shirts.
Right.
And he found that with 80 percent of the
women they chose as he predicted that
they chose the men high and the thing
that they were low in and they avoided
the men who were low in the thing that
they were alone,
but in about 20 percent they seem to be
choosing randomly.
So he went back and looked at the women
again and found that those 20 percent
were on birth control pills,
birth control pill,
short circuits that response.
Well,
so think of how many couples who have
gotten together when she's on the pill
and they both,
like Louis Ck,
Joe's looking into just looking into the
distance.
Was she on the pill?
And I met her.
Uh,
I talked about this at an interview in
San Francisco on the pbs station down
there.
And as I'm talking,
the guys going,
making the gesture like that happened to
me,
but be quiet,
don't say.
And after the interview,
he's like,
dude,
that's exactly.
My wife went off the pill and she was
done with me.
She didn't want them sleeping in the
same bed.
She didn't want me in the same house.
Suki,
a lot of marriages are falling apart
because they got together when the woman
couldn't smell,
he is compatibility and it's not his
fault.
Shit.
Yeah,
isn't that?
That's a mind blower.
And it's one of these things,
like Dumbo was saying,
where we ignore these natural reflex is
to our detriment.
We pretend we're not animals.
Fuck that.
Of course
we're animals.
We're just the coinciding menstrual
cycles alone.
Obviously there's some crazy shit going
on,
but that is like another level crazy
shit that I didn't even think about.
All the factors that would lead to you
being out of whack if your body's
constantly thinking gets pregnant.
And that's what.
That's what the pill does.
It tricks your body into thinking,
don't get pregnant,
you already pregnant.
And that's why a lot of women have much
less libido when they're on the pill.
Oh yeah.
Already pregnant.
So I'm just really bad.
And I dated a girl and she off the pill,
she was so fucking Horny,
but then she got on the pill and it was
like it just stopped.
And then she got off the pill again.
She was like,
we gotta figure out something else
because I don't even like sex when I'm
on the pill.
She was like,
I'm totally disinterested,
but off the pill she was crazy horny.
It was.
It was like a switch went off.
It took like two days.
She started taking the pills and then it
just wouldn't just shut down.
She would be dry.
It was like his crate and then off the
pills.
She's a freak nuts.
That concept that there's this data
field,
like a chemical data field surrounding
everybody makes sense that you can tune
into and understand aspects of like deep
aspects to know a person's like some
specific deficiency in their immune
system just from your nose.
That's crazy.
And that kind of stuff lends credence to
idea of telepathy or clairvoyance or
people who can read other people really
well.
Like maybe they're just somehow better
at detecting whatever chemical field is
around the person.
And can decode it in a certain way.
What are we doing with like people were
have a whole culture of women that are
taking pills that trick their body and
did not being able to recognize the
clues of compatibility.
You think about how many kids are born
with health deficiencies because of
this,
because people low in,
you know,
number three and get together and these
kids have.
Wow.
Yeah.
There's all sorts of,
you know,
we were talking earlier about smearing
vaginal fluid on a newborn baby who's
born through csection.
Again,
we're pretending we're not animals.
We're pretending there's not a huge
benefit in,
in being contaminated with life,
you know,
that were these sterile creatures that
exists separate from our shit and Piss
in her.
It's one of the things you realize from
grappling in Jujitsu when you start
getting really into it.
Do you have to keep a healthy biome?
You have to keep healthy skin floor.
It's critical.
Like one of the first things they tell
you when you start training is you
should start taking supplements like
acidophilus something,
probiotic,
because you want to keep your skin flora
healthy and you want to not use
antibiotic soap like a lot of times when
people get infections,
one of the problems is they've created a
barren wasteland on the surface of their
skin,
so infections to take hold and then you
treat those infections with more
antibiotics and you kill off all the
natural healthy like acidophilus in
particular is supposed to be aggressive
towards certain types of infections so
that like if you keep a healthy skin
flora,
you're less likely to get things like
ringworm or things along those lines.
Well,
this is also what they're talking about.
Either this,
there's a new kind of antibiotic
resistant.
What does that.
Can you explain that?
Because I keep reading about it sounds
terrifying.
Well,
it's,
you know,
the,
the pathogens are constantly mutating,
right?
In response to whatever antibiotics has
been developed and we've come to the end
of this particular line of antibiotics.
So there's no more.
There's no more variations on this
molecule right?
They keep tweaking it,
tweaking it,
and they've tweaked it every way,
every which way possible.
And this pathogen has mutated once again
as we knew it would.
And there's nothing,
there's nothing.
There's no response.
So if you get this infection,
your dad back to the 14,
I put this way back,
it puts us back to wherever to the play
or whatever your arm amputated.
And we had um,
you know,
Rhonda Patrick,
have you ever listened to her?
Dr Rhonda Patrick.
She had a pretty significant Murcia
infection of staph infection that just
wouldn't go away.
And you know,
she fixed it with topical use of ground
garlic and grape seed extract.
The ground garlic apparently has this
radical effect on,
uh,
on mercer.
And another thing that supposedly helps
to his cannabis oil.
Cannabis oil is supposed to be really
good
at fighting off staffed staph
infections.
So what else is good?
I mean,
I don't know about staff,
but seawater,
seawater,
seawater is good as my wife.
Irrigated wounds with seawater a lot in
Mozambique and pissing on your feet
keeps the athlete's foot away.
Isn't that weird?
Yeah.
We were taught that in wrestling,
if you've got athlete's foot,
you're pressing,
your feet are just pissed on your feet
every,
every morning,
especially that first pice is really
because it's full of uric acid
accumulated overnight,
just piss on your feet every morning in
the shower and you just don't get
athletes,
so that's why people drink their pis.
They would drink their first pice of the
morning because it supposedly has all
our vitamins and nutrients and it's very
bizarre practice.
I don't know about that.
I've done it.
I've drank my piss a few times to
experiment.
I don't know.
I'm probably not.
I'd probably better off with like a
multivitamin.
It seems to me if you were meant to
drink your pis then you wouldn't piss.
Yeah.
Well your body would just send it right
back in.
Right.
But this.
Why were you why your balls and the
outside to keep them?
People can kick them.
No,
it's to keep them cool.
Okay.
You know what I'm saying?
Like there's some flaws.
That's the wrong metaphor for me,
man.
I don't think Pistons a flaw.
It is.
If you know,
otherwise you would go,
you would dehydrate.
I mean if like,
if you never dehydrated,
your body would never express water in
that way.
Like you take water and you keep a
healthy level and it's like oil in your
car,
like you know,
your levels there,
you're good.
But no,
we're like constantly getting rid of it,
but I guess it actually cycles through
your body and it takes impurities out
and actually there's a lot of other
things going on when you drink a lot of
water.
That's why one of the things that
happens to people in,
they're dehydrated,
they get kidney stones and get
crystallized things in your body and you
know,
you have to piss those out of your Dick
Hole.
I had,
I had a kidney stone.
We dehydrated.
I don't think so.
This beer count.
Um,
what else?
Diarrhetic.
Yeah,
I know.
I don't know the hall's diarrhetic
right?
Yeah.
But they say it dehydrates you.
Alcohol ultimately,
you know.
But here's an interesting fact.
Did you know that all animals pissed the
same amount of time.
All of them.
It's this bizarre fractal thing.
Yeah.
Jimmy can confirm whether as Jamie,
Jamie,
Jimmy,
call them young Jamie young,
Jamie A.
Yeah,
apparently it's like the size of the
bladder and the volume of the urethra
is.
It's like a fractal thing where it could
be a mouse or an elephant,
so a full piss takes the same amount of
time for an elephant as it does for a
mouse and elephant piss.
It's like Jesus.
So waterfalls and drinking that.
It's insane.
Most mammals take 20 seconds.
Same with humans.
Not if you're drinking beer.
Well your bladder,
right?
So it doesn't matter what's in it yet,
but if you fully hold your pis in for
like a long time and you finally get to
a bathroom,
you're like,
uh,
I've definitely piss along on the 22nd.
That's really nice of them.
Do include an image of a Beagle in case
you wondered what the least offensive
penis that they could find.
One that doesn't represent the
patriarchy illegal.
Couldn't get like a pit bull.
They got racehorse in there.
Did you see that?
It Will Piss pee for about as long as a
rhino.
A racehorse because people say high
pitched like a rain or I got to Piss
like a race horse,
but I think there's talking volume.
You ever seen a race horse piss.
Good Lord.
Yeah.
The volume is just stunning.
Comes fast.
Sti Pressure.
Yeah.
It's like Wah.
So I'll tell you what.
This kidney stone made me think there is
a god and he loves me or she because it
was a horrible thing.
You guys haven't had a kidney stone.
It's just like.
So I wake up,
I think I told this story on a live
podcast I did with you in San Francisco.
I don't remember.
Long time ago.
Yeah.
I remember thinking why am I telling the
story?
But uh,
so I,
I woke up excruciating abdominal pain.
Cosillo my wife who's a doctor,
thought I had a gas bubble in my
intestines.
So she had me upside down on the sofa
with a funnel stuck in my ass.
And she was born in Hollow Party at
Chris Ryan.
She's foreign extra virgin olive oil.
Oh my ass.
I remember laying there upside down.
That's what I remember thinking like
honeymoon was over.
We're into marriage now,
this is marriage,
but uh,
cuz she's like,
she's a doctor,
she's completely like the bodies of the
body.
She doesn't give a shit clinical.
Um,
but anyway,
it turns out it was a kidney stone,
long story.
It had already gone into the two between
my kidney and my bladder.
And so that's what the pain is,
that it's sort of scrape and it's way
down the tube,
but it didn't block the flow so it
wasn't having the kidney infection,
which people sometimes get that's really
dangerous.
What they do then they operate on you.
Well,
what they wanted to do is they send
sound waves in from your back,
from the back and the front,
and they calibrate it so that the waves
meet right where the stone is.
And you say the back in the front,
you mean your decoding your bottom in
your abdomen.
It's going from your kidney in this
little tube down to your bladder.
Well,
how do they get that sound in there?
So they,
they do,
uh,
an x ray and find exactly where it is.
Right?
And then they have like sonogram
machines,
right?
That are sending vibrations and and they
meet at the point where the stone is in
the break it into sand and then you can
piss it out.
So yeah,
it's great.
But unfortunately mine had already
passed through the tube into my bladder
by the time they got around to it.
So they're like,
well if it's in the bladder,
we can't do it.
We're going to have to go in through
your dick with needle nose pliers.
They go up and grab this thing and then
pull it out,
take your awake.
What is happening?
And I asked and I had the meeting with
the anesthesiologist and I'm like,
can you just put me under for this?
I do not want
to be awake when someone
can your eyes.
She says,
see the screen behind you'll redman up
boy.
So I was like,
not into this.
Right?
And I'm on the waiting list and it's
like any day they're going to call me
and I'm going to go in and they're going
to like put this thing out my dick.
And meanwhile it was new year's Eve
[inaudible] and I wake up in the
morning,
New Year's Day morning,
we have sex,
I go downstairs to the bathroom and I'm
pissing in the bathroom sink because we
have this Asian toilet squat,
toilet.
So if you paste it,
if I piss in that standing up,
it splashes all over.
So the deal is I piss in the sink and
rinse it and it's fine.
You never noticed.
Never noticed.
So I'm pissing down the side of the sink
and put outcomes.
The stone paintings,
how many was it?
It's like half.
I don't know.
Is that a centimeter?
Something like,
you know that about the size of your
fingertip?
It's a real rock.
It was like a,
it was like a snowflake.
It was a wafer.
A thick thicker than a snowflake.
But like a wafer,
it just pumped out and somehow it had
gotten into the tube and the orgasm.
The ejaculation pushed it right up to
the end of my Dick.
And then when I pissed it just popped
out.
It was no pain at all.
It was masked by the orgasm.
So it looped it up.
It looped it up and it and it,
you know,
filled my head with endorphins or
whatever when I was having the orgasm.
So I didn't feel the pain.
I felt like a slight burn.
But like,
yeah,
whatever day it was.
Fantastic.
So that's my kidney stones story.
So I do,
I think I've looked over a cassie took
it to the hospital and had it analyzed
or would they say uh,
well they,
I guess they can by looking at the
chemical composition,
they can tell what causes it.
If it's a chronic thing or if it's
dehydration or whatever.
What if it was from another planet,
Bro?
You're pissing out million.
Rob.
Getting a tiny little writing on it.
When Doug and I,
we're doing that.
So help me.
I'm stuck in here when Duncan and I
doing that silly show that Joe Rogan
questions everything show.
We ran into these people that do think
that they have implants in their body
that aliens have it and they'll find
like some bizarre imperfection,
their skin and they'll swear that wasn't
there before and that there's something
in there and one of them was insanely
hot and we got Duncan to talk to her and
was like,
yeah,
I mean
probably.
I mean,
totally makes sense.
Good journalists.
He was.
If it was a ball fat,
like,
wait a minute,
why do you think that that's an alien
implant?
It's a scratch.
I missed that episode.
No,
you're questioning my journalistic
integrity.
You were amazing when you talked to the
underground bunker guy who was going to
start a call now.
That was intense,
man.
I'll never forget driving around in
that,
underneath that mountain with that guy
was a pretty man.
God
has an underground mountain base like
ready for the apocalypse in the space in
New Mexico or something where it was.
I can't remember man.
I just know it's out of nowhere renting.
You can rent a space like a park in a
parking space and make your camper van,
but they had this like underneath this
mountain,
there's,
you know,
he'd set up example homes that you could
live in,
in this paradise.
And he kept saying how like there's
going to be a wine bar.
That's one thing he kept saying,
but everyone you know is dead.
But there was a woman,
but it was weird is that you got out of
him that he was kinda be going to kind
of be the king.
That's right.
Yeah.
He was,
he was going to be in charge man.
And he had set up an rv with a little
bit of astroturf in front of it and like
some playground equipment.
So like that's what the future looked
like under there.
It's like your kids will be able to play
in the darkness of this massive cavern,
uh,
after,
after.
And he kept saying how they were about
to have like an air tight door put in
and really,
really spooky.
There's a lot of different places like
that.
There's a lot of caverns that people are
planning on living in the progress.
This guy dig it out or did,
was it always those?
Uh,
the military had used it,
the military dug it out there.
We're using it as some kind of storage
facility.
And so he bought it from them and then
converted it to this like this.
Well,
theoretically dystopian future place
that you go through to save yourself on
the bombs go off.
Sounds like an alien movie.
Like they just didn't tell them that
they're stored alien artifacts in the
same location and while they're there
that's cool.
It comes alive and like we have movement
in the corridor.
What?
It's nothing in the corridor but us,
we've double checked and triple checked.
Well we just found this manuscript and
we're not sure what to make of that.
But if that's,
it sounds like the movie room to me,
you gonna see which rules a room roots.
It's about this woman who's like
kidnapped by this dude who locks her in
a room and rapes her and it's a terrible
thing,
but she has a kid and the kid doesn't
know there's a world outside and so she
and she wants a kid to be happy,
so she tells them all these stories and
all the stuff and the kid grows up in
this garage basically thinking like
that's the whole world.
And you think about it.
That's applicable to mean talking about
a metaphor,
you know,
we're told what reality is,
we're told what to believe.
And so matrix,
it's all these things.
The Matrix gnosticism.
It's the idea that what we are in right
now is actually a,
an interdimensional prison and we've
been trapped by these super advanced
beings that have kept us here called the
dark are cons and that they like,
they like power and authority.
And so,
um,
anybody.
So basically this idea,
I think it's called Discordian Asm,
but the idea is that because we are in
an interdimensional prison where we've
been had reality like where we like had
this consensus reality given to us by
people like Bernays,
chef Bernays,
who whipped up this reality tunnel that
we're all existing in a because we are
in this situation,
uh,
anyone in forcing the reality tunnel is
a servant of the dark art con.
So anybody who's like trying to uphold
this bullshit reality that we've all
gotten trapped in there actually a form
of Satanists.
And so as a religion or any time that
you do anything to break a ridiculous
rule,
anytime you do anything to break a
mundane law,
anytime you do anything to subvert the
authority of someone getting off on
their power,
you are actually taking part in a kind
of holy war.
And subverting this very ancient and
terrible prison that all humanity is
trapped in where people parade around as
though they have some kind of right to
authority.
Kings being the classic case,
people used it.
They somehow convince people that they
were gods on earth.
Clearly just human beings,
the ultimate liars.
You're not a god.
You're a human who's convinced as that
you have some kind of power and so
anytime you do anything to subvert those
people,
whether it's some fucking asshole,
he's wearing a crown and is convinced
you that ease the divine being sent here
or whether it's some son of a bitch and
one of those reality shows.
He's like going through your pockets for
weed.
Anytime you do anything to even disrupt
that system a little bit,
you're doing a holy act in the great war
against the interdimensional prison
keepers who are keeping us trapped here.
Look up this accordion ism.
Yeah,
that's awesome.
That's it.
Three hours in there.
I was going to say,
I can hear that rant already on youtube
that people have already with,
with animation and fucking dark lords.
Ladies and gentlemen.
That's,
uh,
that's it though.
What are we calling this shrimp raid
over folks?
Thank you everybody much.
Love.
See you soon.
Bye.
That was great.
I got up,
I got to Pittsburgh.