It should be actually happening.
It says live and recording,
but I'm a fucking idiot.
So I dunno if that's true.
If this is all badly as a gentlemen,
I did not plan this out this well
and I'm trying to do this myself.
Just me and my man Brian.
But I really need my little buddy red van
to help me out with the technical shit
cause I don't know what the fuck is going
on so I got to go online to see if it
is actually online.
No,
I don't want to go social
with your fucking Facebook.
It seems like it's on.
Okay,
we're on.
We're live.
Yes.
Fantastic.
The Joe Rogan experience podcast is
brought to you by on it.com on a.com has
some,
a,
a bunch of new shit in a,
first of all,
the hemp protein powder,
which is a sensational,
very delicious.
I use it daily.
Is it?
Yep.
You protein proteins.
The Shit.
I got to give you some of this,
a hemp for stuff.
It's sweetened with Stevia and yeah,
it's got raw cocoa in it.
Not a good spokesman for protein powder.
That's not like we're looking
at Brian can I took a shower,
eat you,
what do you do?
Do Dance?
Do you dance in the
rain dancer's physique?
If,
yeah,
if you want to do I have protein powder.
Brian Cowen,
he's a dancer in the rain.
That's the,
that's the,
that's a commercial for
hemp protein powder.
Me Dancing in the rain because I look
good wet when rain pitter patter is off my
body.
Have you ever tried battle ropes?
Uh,
you mean the roles?
I have some in my house.
I call him,
you call him battle ropes.
I call a Mussel ropes
dude to throw the shit.
That's the only thing.
We just started selling them at Onnit.
Uh,
and that's,
uh,
one of the other items
that people are good,
so fucking expensive for rope.
I'm telling you it's not all right.
It's,
it's as cheap as you can buy.
You cannot buy battle ropes online
cheaper than the ones that we're selling.
Ropes are fucking expensive when you're
getting 40 feet of giant thick ass rope
that's not cheap and it comes out to be
like 100 bucks or something like that.
The same thing as Kettlebells,
kettlebells that we're selling.
They're not cheap,
but here's the deal.
First of all,
they fucking will last you forever.
You don't ever need other gym equipment.
You needed a chin up bar and
some fucking kettlebells bells.
If you want to be in some badass shape,
those kettle bells will
last you for a lifetime,
for a lifetime.
You will be able to have,
there's so many different exercises
you can do with kettlebells.
Just looking off of youtube,
there's fucking hundreds of
different things you can do.
These canon balls with
handles on them are the shit.
They're fucking the most manly
shit ever for working out.
You feel like you're fucking like,
you're some crazy Russian dude.
The worse,
the worst workout I ever did was
I had to push a weighted sled,
then do the battle ropes.
Oh,
I call him Mussel ropes
and then do kettlebells.
I,
I've,
you know,
wrestling,
all of it.
I've never in my life Jujitsu,
I've never,
ever wanted to die.
And it was,
by the way,
it was in a six and a half minute workout.
Oh,
here comes Brian.
Almost nowhere online though.
Six and a half months.
Do this online.
Alright.
Hey,
little fella.
Oops.
Here we go.
Hey,
little fella.
We're on the air right now.
Well,
are sleeping.
How dare you?
I'm,
I'm in a panic because I can't get,
I guess it doesn't matter,
but I can't get that dissolve thing to
work where you can't see the text at the
bottom of the screen.
Yeah.
You know how you can
make the text fade out?
How do I do that?
Should I sing background
music while he did his?
Yeah,
his name.
Okay.
Right.
Click on the scene that you're on.
Okay.
Edit shot
long eyelashes.
It's a really nice contrast.
He's got a wide face,
not
black shale,
so on and,
but he's got,
see,
I don't see that.
That's where it's confusing.
It's just too,
he's,
no,
I have,
it's just you.
I was trying to put Brian's name
up because it's your name on it.
He's got shoulders for
days and a really wide
shoulders is that are really low.
So what should I do?
The last one is Christina Ppas.
It's gain.
It's got like a names on it.
Oh,
the last seat on the far right,
Nia.
That one's just me now.
Back and forth from Brian to me.
Oh,
be sac.
Sac.
Thank you for bearing with
us in this technical break.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'm going to keep singing
the song about Joe Rogan.
He's kind of well,
okay,
well we'll have to deal with this.
So the,
um,
the text,
there's no way to get rid
of that text on the screen.
He's got a lie back and
he's really flexible.
It name is Joe Rogan.
He's got a wide neck wad,
faith and a short neck.
See,
I don't see that though.
When I'm trying to do that.
I can't,
it's not letting me do that means
he can absorb punches really well.
Should have been a fighter buddies.
Jason,
gentleman harm this is boring as fuck.
I'm sure it shows logic,
camera logic,
camera built in eyesight.
Those are the options.
I'm thinking.
Background music did builtin input.
Uh,
it shouldn't be anything on,
it should have been a gymnast.
He should have been.
I don't know what the fuck I'm doing,
dude.
We're going to have to have you,
uh,
get an a,
this is a good job security for you.
The whole show goes to
shit without redband.
Okay.
All right.
Well now for some reason
it says Eddie Bravo.
I must have changed it.
I don't mind being Eddie Bravo.
Okay.
This is Eddie Bravo.
Now they used to,
well,
we'll just give him plugs to our friends.
I'll be at the American comedy.
Oh yeah.
Let me check this Thursday,
Friday,
Saturday,
Sunday.
Everybody,
uh,
the American comedy shows
your mother flusters yeah,
I should turn up my volume.
Are you,
what is he talking about?
I'm just giving,
I'm just,
uh,
I'm talking to Brian Cowen.
He's talking on the podcast.
The same songs about,
you name is Jill rogue
and he's got a wide band.
Just trying to see if this
thing is actually online.
It's kind of long eyelashes
and he's really flexible.
He can do impressions.
Nobody knows that.
Here's Joe Rogan.
He's really muscular.
Got a wide face wide
phase Santa Short neck,
which means he can take a punch to
his fucking knows better than you can.
His name is Joe Rogan.
Joe Rogan.
I'm trying to come up with other words.
Oh yeah.
Okay.
It's working.
Right.
I'll see you tomorrow,
Jamie.
Kilstein later.
Bye.
Let me,
can I plug my a Gig this weekend?
Oh Dude,
for we're going to plug the shit
out of your Gig this weekend.
Let's not do it here because
this is a only the commercial.
Let's do it.
A link to the podcast.
We're going to plug the fuck out of you,
son.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Joe Rogan podcast.
What is it called?
The experience?
Something like that.
No.
What the fuck this is?
It's just,
it's why label it.
Do I have to label?
Maybe when I'm going to
not nit label them anymore.
I'm going to stop calling
it the Joe Rogan experience,
but when I call my podcast,
the man thoughts,
the problem,
if you don't label it,
you can't sell tee shirts.
Well,
you got to make it bumper stick money,
dog.
You ain't got no label.
The label don't take man thoughts.
That's mine,
right man.
I like it.
It sounds powerful.
I'm calling from Bryan County,
showed up to,
man,
you should be you doing
fucking battle ropes.
That should be like your avatar.
Exactly.
Just you with battle ropes.
Dude,
look at that.
Swinging him around.
He played golf or watch
Conan the barbarian people
were calling you d hired Jay
Joe Rogan,
because we pranked
without sound on a 10 minute podcast.
He goes,
he goes,
that's my pockets by the way.
And he goes,
um,
he goes,
uh,
you're,
you're like Joe Rogan
before you add the water.
We di we fucked around with the crowd.
You could watch the video of it.
I actually put the video of it on Youtube.
Oh yeah,
it was great.
Well,
yeah,
I'll,
I'll talk about that when we're
done with this commercial A.
Anyway,
go,
go to [inaudible] dot com
check out the kettle bells.
Check out the battle ropes,
the new hemp protein,
pouty,
pouty.
What does that kind of a
spokesman or like Jesus Christ.
I haven't had my Alpha
Brain and gentlemen.
I have it right now.
I take them right before I do the show.
I don't even know if it helps.
Well,
you know what,
at least you,
you do your own products,
you use kettlebells,
Mussel ropes,
and you take your own product.
So here,
here,
yeah,
there are those gentlemen,
dude,
I'd take it because it's awesome.
If they didn't,
if,
if they weren't my own
product that's still taking,
I'm addicted to it.
So is,
uh,
Lorenzo Fertitta owner,
the UFC.
He's addicted to this shit.
Every time he sees me he goes,
dude,
it's fucking Alpha brains.
Incredible.
Because when you fly around a lot,
why aren't things are happening?
I'm picking right now.
How many did you take for
God's for I'm a savage here.
An extremist.
I am a little bit right.
It might be a little crazy.
You're my canary in the coal mine.
Everything you do,
I'm always like,
is it safe
podcasts?
Is it safe?
I'll do it now.
Stand up.
I guess I'll try.
I'll do it again.
We'll talk about this later.
This is a fucking commercial,
Brian Calendar.
Sorry.
It's for God damn on a.com.
That's o.
N.
I.
T.
Um,
and what is Alpha brain that I just took?
It's,
it's a,
it's a competent Tori
sort of a supplement.
It's all a bunch of different nootropics.
And what nootropics are is nutrients
that have been shown to have a positive
effect on brain function.
And you can take gold on at.com and
there is a plethora of information on the
subject and look at Google too cause it's
a controversial subject and you know,
some people are not into it and you know,
they don't want,
they don't want to believe
that supplements can help them.
And that's fine.
I'm not,
I am not pushing it on
anybody that's not interested.
But if you're a person
that does supplement your
vitamins into your person like
me,
who absolutely knows that
it affects your health,
it does.
I sometimes don't get enough
nutrients from my food.
You know,
in a perfect world we would all be
eating mineral rich vegetables and a,
we would all be getting the perfect amount
of water and we would all be having,
you know,
the best food ever and grass fed diet.
But the reality is it doesn't
always fucking work out that way.
And a lot of things get
affected by not supplementing.
Uh,
I think,
uh,
I have,
it is most certainly enhance my health
and the supplements that have been most
interested in are nootropics
and this along with a neuro one,
which is Bill Roman House keys formula.
That was the one I first discovered,
Dell Rom asking Greg
Gray middle linebacker.
He had problems with concussions
and he developed these,
uh,
this,
this series of supplements to aid himself.
Like it was his idea to eight himself
and I took a shit because a no name.
It was a radio DJ,
uh,
in San Francisco a few years back.
He was raving about this guy
and the formula was pretty,
pretty interesting.
Here's a little caffeine in it,
I believe.
Um,
which I didn't want in,
in Alpha brain.
You know,
I think caffeine is something
that's kind of tricky.
It,
it absolutely can help
your brain function,
but I don't think it should be
in anything unless it's obvious.
You know what I mean?
Like caffeine I think should be in coffee.
Caffeine should be an energy drink to
take something with a lot of caffeine.
And feel like,
wow,
this is what's working,
but you fuck up and you don't read the
label and you take it while you're taking
coffee and you have a
goddamn heart attack that,
Whoa,
that was what the Fed did.
Yeah.
Right.
A lot of those people
that are on diet pills.
Yeah.
All this stuff that we were,
we're talking about here at folks.
It's all vitamins.
It's nothing that you have to worry about.
Nothing that's dangerous.
And the thing was on it is we want to
make sure that nobody ever feels ripped
off.
So your first 30 pills,
it's a hundred percent
money back guarantee.
You don't even have to return the product.
That's how confident we are of the product
and we know that you're gonna enjoy
it.
And two,
how the ethics of this company is,
nobody wants anybody to feel ripped off.
We want to sell you the
best shit that we can find,
the best supplements as far as health
and athletic performance and the best
nutrients we can find,
the best late lifting
equipment that we can find.
We use Troy kettlebells.
They're the best in the world.
They're perfect.
The,
you can't get anything better.
They're the highest quality available.
They will fucking last
through the apocalypse.
You buy those bitches,
you're done.
You're done.
You have them forever.
They will never wear out their cast iron.
Fucking cannonballs awesome.
So this stuff is not cheap.
Um,
but we're selling it at the
most reasonable rate that
we can and we're trying to
provide everybody with the best
possible products that we can.
That's the ethics of on it.
And that's what we're all about.
Um,
and if you use a code name,
Rogan,
you will save 10% off all supplements.
All right.
You dirty freaks.
Brian counts here and I
don't know how to turn it.
Musica
heavy guitars and wind
blowing my hair back.
It's the fucking park.
It's the Brian Collins on the
podcast with Joel Role Gum.
That was the,
that was a very interesting
way to answer right there.
Yeah.
That was like a brainiac.
It's like a gay Kenyan dance.
I'm bringing,
I'm bringing back some shift from
like the 70 [inaudible] if you cook,
if you cook and cast iron and it's an
excellent way of getting iron in your
diet,
which I didn't know.
Yes,
yes.
They say stakes in cast iron,
like you're seriously fast,
too much Ferris oxide and your
diet and you have to be careful.
So Tim Ferriss says in his book that a
lot of these guys will like actually take
a day and eat no iron to yes to
bring their iron levels down.
So there it is.
See Ferris is fascinating.
We've been going back and forth.
He's going to come back
on the podcast again.
Well let's do it.
Let's look it up.
He's a great guy.
I got to get him on cause
I had a conversation with
them after I read his book
and I loved him and it,
he just knows so much.
Yeah,
he's apparently got a lot of stuff cooking
and he's in the middle of writing a
book as well.
But uh,
man,
I love talking to him.
I just love talking to do's done that are
just filled with information like him.
Rob Wolf,
the Paleo solution author.
What was that like?
Fucking great.
You know,
because I'm reading the guys
filled with information.
It's controversial.
Well,
but I just,
I just read the China study
I talked to you about it,
which is about,
he's a very,
very credible science and he looks at
a lot of science says whole food plant
based whole food diet
is the best way to go.
Problem is that I think
like we talked about,
if you're doing sports
and lifting personally,
I went,
I went like about a week
eating just whole food,
plant based Diet.
I eat a steak.
The other day I wolfed it down.
I inhaled it.
I,
it was literally like,
I was like,
oh,
I made and I've never felt better.
I mean,
I just need some meat sometimes.
Don't think that you can have
the same diet for every person.
Right?
I don't think,
I don't think everybody needs,
I don't know why it needs a stake.
There's a lot of chicks out
there that don't need a stay.
They really don't.
There's a lot of dudes don't need to stay.
Jamie kills teens coming
on the podcast tomorrow.
He's a Vegan,
he's healthy,
he's happy,
and he loves it.
It's real fitness.
He does always constantly
doing martial arts,
Jujitsu and shit.
And he's a Vegan,
weighs eight pounds,
but he's a Vegan.
I'm not kidding.
He weighs eight pounds.
I always look at it.
I always like,
you can't find too many Olympic
athletes who are vegans.
Well,
Mac Dansik,
who's also going to do the podcast,
we,
we're going back and forth.
I love that dude.
He's a really,
really interesting guy.
He's a UFC fighter who's a Vegan
and he's also a photographer and a,
you know,
it works.
His,
his reasons are that he loves animals.
You know,
that's it.
And I respect that as well.
Look,
I,
uh,
I love animals too,
but there's a cycle of life and I
think factory farming is horrific,
but I think wild game,
I think that's where it's at.
I think in a perfect world,
we would buy meat from hunters and
that would be a new fucking industry.
We'd have to make sure that
people were at poaching,
buy meat from hunters.
I think she'd be able to hunt a lot of
them because deer are fucking everywhere.
The idea that there's a,
they're glorify cows too and we could
grow more of them too by the way.
We can grow more of them,
but my point is when they're wild and
they're running around and then you just
hunt them and killed them.
The,
I think first of all that it's the whole
thing is way more humane because they
live the real life.
They lived a real life.
That is,
no,
the deer's never lived a better life.
They have one life that
life forge for food,
stay alive if you do that,
you've won.
They're also,
by the way,
they're also,
they are food in the wild and
one of the things that are,
that's why they're there.
What are they?
Joseph Campbell.
All I said that one of the,
one of the problems with my original,
the original sort of peoples in their
mythology was that date they would look
around in nature and
realize it life eight life.
And if you look at a lot of like,
uh,
whether it's native Americans or whatever,
the tradition of killing animals,
they were always fairly,
most cultures were always fairly
very uneasy with killing an animal,
which is why when you killed an animal,
there was a ritual around that.
There was usually prayer said there
were rituals because human beings,
we're like,
they felt the connection.
Yeah,
we're taking it were to end when you
actually have to kill something with a
spear or a bow and Arrow or a knife and
you feel its heartbeat and you smell
that animal and that's,
that's very intimate and it's very,
it's physically intimate.
It's very,
and almost all,
almost all original or aboriginal cultures
had all of that I can think of had a
sort of a ritual around that.
They would say prayers.
They do all kinds of things
because it makes sense.
What we've become is so
removed from our food.
We're so removed with
factory farming and things,
it feeds a lot of people,
gets a lot of protein and people,
people don't go hungry anymore.
I always remind people 30 years,
30 years ago,
I mean half of half of India,
China went through major famines,
uh,
and certainly most of Africa.
But now that's,
that's becoming more and
more a relic of the past.
It's because we've become very efficient
at getting food to a maximum number of
people.
But there's,
there's a huge disconnection.
Yeah.
So when you eat a pig,
when you eat bacon that's
been in an a gestation crate,
you know,
and goes crazy cause
it's chewing on the bars.
You're not really thinking about it,
man.
I'm just,
I'm just hungry.
You're not thinking it's a pig.
You're thinking it's just a piece of Ham.
We've actually given these
really euphemistic names to,
uh,
meet.
Having said that.
Yeah,
it is.
We,
we,
we do that beef ham,
you know,
you don't think of feel veal.
If you ever go to a farm though and you
were like playing around with the lambs
and the goats and fucking,
I mean and playing around them,
but you start to,
you get kind of,
you,
you realize,
oh wow man,
that thing is a living,
breathing creature that is reacting
to me and reacting to its environment.
Lock this door.
I forgot the lock.
This door keep talking.
Yeah.
And it's,
it's,
it's a,
it's an interesting thing you,
if you talk to farmers
who are round animals,
they're there.
They're very,
very tuned and keyed into animals and
nature on a way that most of us are not.
They just have to be,
they're very aware of the cycles
are very aware of all the things.
You talked to dairy farmers,
there was a mad cow scare and this,
this woman was being interviewed because
they had to kill all our cows in front
of her.
And then they had the burden,
the cows that was,
that was a government policy
and Britain at the time,
cause it's,
you know,
these premiums were very dangerous.
So they took the,
took out the whole heart and she was
so devastated because she got to,
she knows she knew her cows.
She had every one of her cows.
She knew how to its own personality,
had its own name and she had her
own relationship with it for me.
I went to fucking cow really?
And it was devastating for her.
She was going to butcher those
cows where they dairy cows?
No,
one of them had mad cow disease and
they they in the law at the time,
this is about 10 years ago,
they had to put down the whole hurt.
Was she raising these cows for butchering?
No,
of the dairy.
They were dairy cows and
they were also there.
I believe some of them were
for butchering as well.
But this was a dairy
farm for the most part.
So did they feed the cows?
Fucked up things that they
feed them like cow me.
What the,
apparently what happened with,
with the development of these prions
in the central nervous systems of cows.
I'm not a scientist,
but that from what I read,
I remember you could eat a,
if you had a cow that had mad cow disease,
it wasn't eating the muscle
meat that fucked you up.
It was when you ate the brain.
Yeah.
The brain tissue,
spinal cord.
And they would ground that up into
hot dogs and things like that.
And you can take those prions,
they're called preop I think.
And you can heat them up to 500 degrees
and they still don't die and you can
still get the mad cow disease.
So you can't,
it's not the stairs.
You can't stay more
than a thousand degrees.
It's crazy.
And,
and so,
um,
apparently that came from the fact that
you had cows cannibalizing their own
tissue because when you slaughter cows,
there are certain parts I guess,
that you don't necessarily need.
You take 5% of that and you put it
into the slop and they'll eat it.
They were doing,
I was chicken fucked up.
It's become illegal now.
What's fucked up about it as
if they could do with pigs.
That's okay.
Pigs actually are omnivores,
but you do it.
Cows like
you're just jacking his whole system.
Is that the reason you don't want an
animal cannibalizing itself is because it,
it,
it leads to these really weird pathogens.
These [inaudible] actually
in the book of Leviticus,
which regions are private,
I think it's called preamps,
but the,
the,
the book of Leviticus you were
talking about in your show.
The video is actually,
um,
a book in the Old Testament.
That route goes into really stark detail
about what you can eat and what you
can't.
And in,
in the Old Testament,
they always talk about the fact
that you can't eat animals of prey.
You can't eat a,
so you can't eat a leopard or an Osprey,
uh,
an eagle,
a hawk.
Why?
Because those animals eat
other animal protein and you,
you still don't find
people eating leopard meat.
Even in the mountain lions,
I think actually bear and stuff like that.
But you wouldn't do it.
There's a reason we don't,
it's,
it's a rarity.
And we say,
I think they do because for the most part,
no culture is ever eaten the protein.
I except for fish,
but a lot of animals
that eat other animals,
apparently it's not.
Apparently it's not healthy,
but we kind of make sense
if you think about it.
Yeah.
Well it's also,
they're probably,
they probably taste creepy.
Yeah,
I've heard,
I've heard that when you eat
bear meat until really oily,
really like Gamion oily bears.
Bears are mostly her before it's actually,
unless you're talking about polar bears,
which are complete and meat eaters.
Yeah.
We were actually just talking about this,
about going hunting.
We're saying that I didn't want,
Steve Rinella asked me to go hunting with
them to go bear hunting and I'm like,
I don't want to kill a bear man.
I don't want to eat it.
I don't want to have,
if it's not something
that I really want to eat,
like I like venison.
I'll kill a deer.
Venison.
I like die mouth waters.
My Dad and I went to to uh,
Alaska.
Okay to go hunt bear.
He goes,
I want to hunt bear.
I go,
I'm not hunting bear.
He goes,
why not?
I go,
well,
because I don't want to kill a bear.
Oh,
and by the way,
either do you,
somebody talked him into it.
He goes,
well I'm talking about guy.
I go,
well what do you do?
He had already bought a rifle.
That's how susceptible.
He's like,
the guy was like,
well come by,
I'll pile rifle.
He bought like literally like a,
like a $12,000 rifle.
Some crazy with the scope and everything.
So we go there and I go,
I'll go to Alaska with you,
but we'll go fishing.
He goes,
I'll call you right back.
Cause man,
yeah,
you're right.
I don't want to kill a barrier.
Let's go fishing.
So he buys a crazy amount
of fishing equipment.
We go there.
We didn't catch one fish,
not one fucking fish.
We're not fishermen.
We lost all the lures.
We literally lost all
knew how to tie knots.
I don't know how to do any of it.
And it might say,
just took chances.
Like we went out there,
we paid all this money for this guy.
The guy who comes back,
good knots,
man,
the guy,
the guy comes back and he goes,
we go,
we don't have any more lures.
And he goes,
but you had all the thing.
He goes,
yeah,
we lost him.
He goes,
what do you mean?
We were casting over
the lake into the trees.
He literally goes like this.
He goes,
how'd you lose?
All the Lords were like,
oh,
we never caught one fish.
And then he'd say,
he goes,
I want to cite my rifle.
This was,
he brings his rifle,
I want to cite it.
So the former marine
wants to sight his rifle.
So he lies down and showing
us how to shoot prong.
Right.
Problem.
When you,
when you're in the marines,
you're shooting military weapons,
they don't have the kind of recoil that
a three 70 or whenever the fuck it was,
I can kill an elk from half a mile away.
So he's like,
he's got his face right up
against the scope and he's like,
all right here.
And I'm like,
right behind him,
right?
And I'm like,
all right,
I'm going to shoot that log.
I go do it.
So I'm right behind him and I don't know
if you've ever heard a fucking elephant
gun go off when you're close to it.
Oh,
it was so loud that I Prac,
I think I shat my pants a little bit,
like a little duty,
flatter mass.
My face,
the sound like hit where
it was like a fire stick.
I'm,
and I was like [inaudible] he,
so he goes to shoot and he goes,
he shoots,
I'm right behind him and it was so loud.
I went,
Jesus,
he hit me.
I fall back on my ass.
He looks up,
he's got this really deep around cut in
his eye because the scope came back and
hit him in the eye.
So for the rest of the
fuck that Alaska trip,
we're walking around like a couple
of losers don't stand next to me Bro.
You look like such a fucking tourist.
He has this huge around,
is I like a half a raccoon?
That is a lie.
I don't know who that guy is.
I know he looks like me,
but he ain't my dad and I'm like,
how are you supposed to shoot that
through the scoby supposed to back way up.
Yeah,
you fuck,
I don't know.
I've to three 70 or whatever it,
you just have to brace it.
You've gotta to you've to brace it better.
I shot at six times and I couldn't shoot
it any more because I literally don't
have the meat and my shoulder.
It hurt that bad.
Jesus like the kick is that bad
and one of the tricks you do,
but when you don't have your plugs is
keep your mouth open when you should've
gotten that loud because it will cause
the sound has somewhere to go steak
rookies make as they
keep their mouth closed.
Really?
I see you keep your mouth open
and loose and I'm sorry life.
We supposed to keep your mouth.
That's I was told by the way,
any soldiers out there,
I don't know,
maybe I don't know what
the fuck I'm talking about,
but that's what the guy told me.
This guy named Swede and he said,
keep your mouth open.
That's how you do it.
Cause he was shooting no problem.
I was like,
doesn't that hurt it?
The sound was so loud.
It hurt my face for getting my ears.
It's crazy to take it to
like a level like that.
It's like the,
they get guns to the point where
you get to like the 50 caliber,
right?
Like what are you doing?
What do you do?
I'll do,
what the hell are you doing?
I want to kill something from a mile away.
It's anymore.
This isn't like a,
I mean that's like some army shit.
Like why?
Why is a regular person
buying so army shit.
That's when you get a,
when you get one of those high powered,
the hunting rifles,
it's to kill an elk.
Do you think half a mile away,
you know with this a raging gun
control debate in this country,
do you think that there's any,
there's any possible way you
could make this a safe world?
Here's why.
Here's what I always say about gun control
is what I talk about with my standup.
Speaking of which,
I'll be at the American
comedy club this weekend,
Thursday,
Friday,
Saturday.
That's down in San Diego.
San Diego,
Thursday,
Friday and Saturday.
That's right.
Shit,
I can't win.
[inaudible] club by the way.
We did a desk quad show there.
We had a fucking great
time and we did a weekend.
We did two shows and doing all new stuff.
I'm excited about my new hour,
but,
but one of the things I always say,
my stance,
what,
what was the thing I
was talking about with,
with gun control is gun control
in this country in my opinion,
will never work in,
in,
in terms of what people
are calling for it.
Because I think that men like their guns,
not because they're
shiny and they go boom.
I actually really believe most
men own guns because it's the,
it's,
it's for them.
It's certainly for me,
a feeling that at least
I can protect my family.
If the shit hits the fan because a golf
club or a sharp stick ain't gonna do it.
I want an arsenal in case,
and I think most men go
when a politician says,
and they have good points,
but if a politician says,
we want to take your gun away,
Americans in particular go,
I don't fucking item that because you're
not going to be there when somebody
tries to break in my house
at four in the morning,
I could call nine one one but the feeling
of a phone in my hand versus my Mazda
20 gauge,
you know,
pump action,
shotgun feels a lot better to me.
The real problem is
that guns are out there.
That's the real problem.
Guys didn't exist.
Then you have an ego and
be a different issue.
But here's where the debate actually
lies for me after this terrible tragedy
with the Batman thing,
I do think,
and the Nri Ras,
from what I can understand,
isn't that cooperative with us.
I do think there's a debate to be
had about the lethality of weapons.
Do you need a drum that
holds a hundred rounds?
I don't think so.
Do you need a fucking elephant coming?
Right?
I don't think that you necessarily need
an assault weapon that goes through a
car engine or goes through a building.
But you know what,
all the law abiding people out there,
like my friend Anthony [inaudible] from
the opiate Anthony shows a gun nut.
Why shouldn't he be allowed to have?
Well,
it doesn't bother me at all that he,
I just want guns and I,
I'm,
you know,
I agree.
I mean,
I wondered then the other
dependency is a 50 caliber Jesus.
He has one of those and things.
I don't know.
I mean,
I,
I think that there was a politician on,
he said this about it and
it was really kind of,
he was honest.
It was really interesting.
He said,
what can we do about these mad men?
And he said,
unfortunately in a society like ours
that's free and as big as we are,
you can't ultimately do
anything about alone.
Crazy,
demented human being who is
whatever he has schizophrenia.
I think though the debate lies,
can you though create a situation
where you can keep very lethal,
um,
uh,
efficient weapons,
like machine guns out of their hands?
That seems to be the debate.
I mean,
I don't think you're
ever going to stop crazy.
He's from getting guns
and shooting people,
but I,
it'd be nice if they got just a glock as
opposed to a an ar 1415 with a drum of
a hundred route.
No,
this is where the conspiracy theory kicks
in is we're all these people believe
that the government has brainwashed people
like this joker guy to go and commit
these things so they can clamp down on
gun control and that when you he see what
does this Eric Holder and
you see like first of all,
the nonsense of them selling illegal
guns to Mexico and having those guns be
used on American border
patrol agents and murder.
They're retarded.
That was actually,
it comes out,
it's actually a way to track weapons,
you know,
attract whatever they sold guns bad.
I think that is the dumbest
idea in the history of dumb.
I don't know the details,
but does it sound very well?
Alex Jones of course,
put your tinfoil hat on,
believes that they did that
shit on purpose and they're
making money off of it.
And they wrapped it up in in a ridiculous,
completely implausible plot,
like a completely implausible plan.
The problem with a guy
like Alex Jones Johnson,
my opinion is whenever you
talk about the government,
the government is so diversified
with so many different interests.
There are so many people that actually
are against gun control and government
and passionate about it.
There are a lot of people in government
that are very for gun control.
I think there's a lot of debate even
within the U s army and the army and the
FBI and the CIA about what we should
do with our w about everything.
I think you're misunderstanding
his tone though.
What he saying is it's a much more
sinister thing than the government itself.
What he's talking about is like the world
banks and the new world order getting
together and physically engineering a
situation where they can clamp down on
people to take away their guns because
they're worried about the economy going
into the toilet and then you know when,
when they're passing things like it is.
It is.
However,
when they're passing things like the,
the NDA,
when they pass,
things like that and you realize what
well they are slowly but steadily taking
our rights away in a
place in a time where the,
you know,
it's really not necessary.
This is where there is
no personal attacks.
I mean there's no,
there's no tax going on here in America.
I didn't need to,
I,
I agree with you on that but I think
it's a little bit more insidious and a
little bit more subtle than that.
I actually think that that it's kind of
what the founding fathers warned about a
long time ago.
A lot of times human beings will invent
laws that take their own power away in
the name of things like safety in
the name of look at the Patriot Act,
right?
You know,
those kinds of things
where before you know it,
there is um,
there is a fire and I keep
telling you about this.
My father,
I did a podcast with my dad on
the Bryan County jail and he,
he was talking about how he spent
a lot of time in government.
A lot of time down there.
I walked how it really works.
It's not that politicians are bad.
It's not that you know,
Republicans or Democrats,
a lot of people have good ideas.
They're trying to get shit done.
Obama's not a soldier.
It's it's governments in
the business of intent,
you're in the business of intent.
You have an,
you have a law and you have an intention.
The problem when you have an intention
is that there's so many different
interests that you have to appease
to get that law whole and passed.
And what happens is what you intended
usually has other consequences,
which would make sense.
And I think what we have to worry about
is like what you're talking about,
where we start losing our own power,
but it's almost like it happens.
It happens without us even realizing it.
Like you pass a law that
seems to be a good law.
It has other unintended consequences,
right?
And whenever you do anything that
compromises people's freedom and liberty,
right?
Then you have to say,
well,
what is the end game in this?
Because this seems like
even in the name of safety,
you're going to clamp down on freedom
and liberty and safety isn't going to be
worth nearly as much.
You have to really look at that.
My,
my,
my father was talking about corporations.
He at one point
ran the biggest investment
bank in the world.
He knows a little bit.
It was an amazing podcast.
A lot of people really,
really enjoyed it.
I was so proud of it.
It's,
it's,
you can get it on,
on,
uh,
on Brian callen.com or
if I wasn't so selfish,
I would listen to it.
Yeah.
Well,
no,
I did this.
I think you'd really like
them cause he soaks fair.
He's so,
he's so,
he's so he's just about personal liberty,
but he also understands that he's
very moderate about that stuff.
But,
um,
you know,
he's,
he's somebody who,
who,
who talks about,
for example,
whatever your intention,
whatever your intention
as government grows and,
and both sides of responsible Democrats,
Republicans,
it's,
it's human.
As a government grows with
tax revenue or whatever it is,
what happens with corporations,
they behave just like you.
And I would,
which is why I got a lobby,
my government,
so I can get a favorable outcome here
because everybody else is doing it.
So pretty soon you've got
everybody feeding out of or
influencing the government
trough.
It's just how you can't do
business otherwise you can't
be in business as a bank
without having very strong
ties to the government.
You can't,
you just can't.
And there in lies the argument.
So no matter what you say,
yes you need government.
Yes,
there are good ideas out there,
you know?
But just be aware that regardless,
the bigger it gets,
even if its intentions are good,
you're going to have,
you're going to lose.
The argument goes,
you're going to lose
some of your liberties.
You're just going to,
that seems at least to
be what history says.
And it seems to be that it's so easy
to let something grow completely
unnecessarily out of control.
If you wanted to,
you could micromanage every single
aspect of society in order to create new
jobs.
If you wanted to create new jobs
and give more people the work of,
you know,
well they'll look what we were just
talking about this this weekend,
not explain to me how in any
way making hemp weed marijuana,
illegal marijuana is illegal.
You and I were hanging out at a bar
this weekend and I remember I said,
and there was somebody acting
up and they were drunk.
And I said that I've never been
bothered by a pothead like that.
Right.
But,
but it's always somebody
who's drinking now.
Alcohol causes way more damage.
We all know the story and clearly,
but why?
Why is,
why is marijuana so why are those laws,
those federal laws so difficult to repeal?
Well,
I'll tell you why.
In my opinion,
and it goes back to what you brought up.
There's a lot of money and enforcing
a lot of money and enforcing,
enforcing marijuana laws.
There's a lot,
a lot of money.
Yes.
Talk to talk to the DA.
You,
you've got a lot of people
whose jobs depend on this stuff.
It's not anybody's fault.
It's what happens,
Matt.
Yep.
We are all,
anytime you have a critique of somebody,
just realize that if you were in their
position you'd probably be the same
goddamn way.
You hopefully not.
But that's what happens.
That's why we need clear cut laws to
protect people from their own instincts to
protect natured.
For you,
a person who's outside of it objectively
looking at the situation from a,
you know,
a a knowledgeable point of view,
you can sort of engineer
what is and what isn't legal.
We have to avoid this
so you can't take money.
We have to avoid that.
So you can't do this,
you know,
and unless you stick by
some well thought rules,
it's on like,
you know,
you need a scaffolding for humanity to
grow on and when you give people power
with no scaffolding,
I never,
I never arguing more about a lot
democratic or republican platform.
I never do that.
Not My argument always
centers on one thing,
which is hey look,
you got your political point of view.
That's great criticisms that we
all agree we need some government.
You just need some government.
Yeah,
we need some moral boundaries.
We need some engineering of our culture.
You need law and order,
you need roads,
you need,
but we need way less than we had.
Well,
there you go.
And so then the question becomes
how much less do we need?
A lot less.
And that's where the debate should,
that's what we should talk about.
Why and why?
What is the objective to
preserve personal freedom?
Liberty,
if they had less laws and more cops would,
the world would be a way better place.
And if the cops were paid better
and treated better by people,
if more people got their shit together.
So it didn't look at the
cop as like someone is going
to come and arrest you for
doing shitty things.
Just don't be doing shitty things.
Right.
If we,
if we could figure out a way to
elevate our society to the next level,
you know,
I think that could be a way,
I was just reading an article
about my thoughts of a competency,
like,
like a security person,
like a friend.
Like let's put it this way.
Instead of thinking of cops as like,
someone is coming to bus to
you or someone's going to
take your shit if you had
good cops in a community.
It's like if you had a fucking fort and
your buddy was the guy lied to watch the
door with a gun because there's,
there's,
you know,
crazy Indians or who knows
what the fuck could happen.
You need that.
Like that shit is very important.
You have to have some of the garden,
the wall.
And it did.
Somewhere along the line it stopped being
that and it became an us versus them,
the society versus the cops.
I do think though that,
that,
um,
a lot of police forces that's not
lost on a lot of cops and a lot of,
uh,
a lot of the brass,
for example,
and in New York,
I just read an article that crime
is down since the 90s by 80%.
That's amazing.
Isn't cool.
And mostly mostly in black
and Hispanic neighborhoods.
Mostly Giuliani came in
and just cut the bullshit.
And it was Bratton and their
notion of a quality of life laws.
If you'd,
they said if somebody graffiti's a walk,
they probably do other
things that are bad too.
So we're going to start
enforcing those small,
those small crimes because
they lead to bigger crimes.
That kind of notion.
And it's interesting how many people
were like so down on Giuliani doing that.
It really upset that
he's ruining in New York.
I was in New York,
I've shot a movie there three weeks ago.
Whenever it's better than I've,
I mean I've been,
my family is from there.
It's better
than I've ever seen the city in my life.
It's incredible.
It's,
it's a better place to
be than anywhere I've,
I,
it's the best I've ever seen it.
It's the better place to be
than anywhere in the world.
Well,
in some ways I don't
want to get carried away.
What's the greatest part about it?
To you?
Accessibility to everything.
That's everything and
feeling safe doing it.
Um,
you,
you've got,
first of all,
you've got the lower east side,
which is totally different
than the lower west side,
which is totally different than the upper
west side was totally different than
midtown,
which is totally different than
eating the upper east side.
And there's an experience to be
had in all quadrants of Manhattan.
You can get there in 15 minutes
by cab or less and or by subway.
And most importantly,
you're no longer walk around New York
feeling like you're going to get mugged or
anything else.
So that's what people,
that's the feeling that people still have
about Manhattan is that weird feeling
of worrying about being mugged.
Sure.
Cause it's so big.
But if you look at statistics,
the police had done an amazing
job of policing and you know,
who else has done a really good job as,
I can't remember the,
uh,
our police chief here and,
and um,
la,
but they've done a really good job,
really good job at controlling
gang violence in this,
in this.
And it's an almost
impossible in such an area,
huge area.
But they've done a really innovative job.
You know,
comparatively they've,
they've,
they,
they've learned,
they learned a lot from,
from the gangs,
closings in the eighties and the nineties
and they've done a really good job in
a lot of places.
It's kind of fucked when you
really wrap your head around it.
Like that should be the laws
that people are concentrating on.
What is,
what is causing that kind of shit?
I know it's called,
I have an opinion on that.
The gangs,
I think a lot of it comes,
starts with,
it's like a family.
Exactly.
I talked to a principal in Kansas City.
I said,
what do you,
what would you do about education?
And I wanted to get into a talk about it,
you know,
and he said nothing.
Our schools are great,
our parents are fucked up.
They had good parents and be fine.
I was like,
Ooh,
Geez.
I never thought he goes,
my school was great.
I just got parents that don't,
they're not present.
They got three kids
they can't take care of.
And it,
it comes down to that
gangs are about kids who just want to
feel significant and belong to something.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Everybody has the need to
belong to a team or a tribe,
you know,
I mean,
that's why we call it
solves a death squad.
You know.
That's why I love being a
part of 10th Planet Jiu Jitsu,
you know,
that's,
we,
you know,
when you,
you,
you become a part of like a team,
you know,
you become,
you feel stronger.
So some kid who's out there on his own,
you know,
it was family just fucking sucks
and his whole life has been shit.
And you know,
he's there with some dude who
will shoot a dude for them.
That's what the podcast is too,
isn't it?
I mean,
you know,
you,
you have a really,
that show we were with,
Joe did a show,
um,
this,
this weekend in Denver
and that crowd was so,
they were so unbelievable.
It was like a rock star.
I went out as Joe and I,
and I said,
what's up?
You fucking Frakes.
Yeah.
We wanted to see how long
it would take for people.
Really thought it was me.
And they must have been like,
what the hell?
Joe got Skinny and a
little taller with a beard.
That's weird.
But anyway,
but they went crazy and I,
I,
and I'm,
and then watching all these people in
line up just to take a picture with you.
They both,
they feel like they
belonged to an experience.
You know,
they feel like they belonged
to something.
Like even the,
the,
my,
you know,
my 10 minute podcast,
well I noticed a lot of young men,
they,
they come on to that kind of humor.
You know,
they,
they liked the silliness that we
do cause it's Kinda like recess.
It creates a f you,
when you create a following and
you create a core group of people,
it makes them feel like
they belong to something.
I think that's why they
root for a team that,
you know,
you haven't experienced with it.
It's the same kind of thing.
This is an even more intimate
experience because you know,
you're in people's fucking heads.
You know?
That's why people get so annoyed.
If you say something over repeat things
or if you do something they don't like,
like the euro,
the people are allowing
you like the most intimate,
uh,
sort of like input into their brain.
You're in the fucking your buds and
you're literally playing inside their ear
and you're,
you're talking inside their
head and if you're annoying,
that's a mind fuck.
But if you are really genuinely on a
good path and you really are a genuinely
promoting other people to
be on a good path to and,
and just brotherhood.
You know,
Tom Rhodes sent me a text today that
was a really fucking awesome taxed cause
Tom just did the uh,
ice house chronicles show that we do
at the desk squad at the Ice House,
the Ice House,
amazing old comedy club.
And we've been doing these shows and
we're going to do one this Friday night
where we have all these comics go well,
but it was Damo rarer,
you know,
this week it's Greg Fitzsimmons,
Joey Diaz,
Joey's on all time per
crusher was there this week.
I mean,
these,
these shows are fucking incredible.
Okay.
And were hanging around in the back room
and we're doing a podcast and it's me
and crusher and Tom Rhodes and Dama rera
and Brody Stevens and we are laughing
our fucking dicks off.
It's so fun.
It's like the stuff we always did,
but now thousand hundreds
of thousands of people.
But what,
what Tom said,
he's just,
he goes,
I really love the feeling of comedy,
Brotherhood,
you know,
and that's what it,
that's really what it was.
It's like we have like a
comedy brotherhood and we
really genuinely like each
other,
love each other and want each other to
succeed and are happy when each other's
succeeds.
That's the one thing that's missing in
our group is that weird comic neurosis
that often exist where people can't
be happy with other people's success.
Bitter,
bitter,
like narcissistic or bitter,
kind of like damaged like islands.
That's what you'd get a lot
with like standup comics.
They haven't been told,
man,
it's,
it's like,
it's like learning Jujitsu wrong or
learning to play the guitar wrong.
You haven't been told the way to
manage your mind and what you,
what you don't realize is that even
though you are separate from other people,
you're really not,
and you get something from them,
positive or negative,
and that affects you and if
you can generate positive
feelings and other people,
then you will get more positive
feeling in your own life.
You know,
it's really weird.
I'm reading this book called the sociopath
next door written by this Harvard
psychiatrist.
She's a sociopath.
I read an excerpt about that where they
were saying some frightening numbers.
We were just,
you were just talking about connection
and how important it is and the feeling
you get from when you move other people
and then you and you get in and you get
moved from other people.
And most of us who are normal,
we get this socio paths.
They don't even get that
from their own children.
They don't even get like,
like they could be very successful,
but they don't get any
satisfaction out of being at,
you know,
getting the adulation.
The only thing that they usually get
pleasure from is winning and controlling
other people's reactions.
Isn't that wild?
So the idea is you,
whatever they can do power over people
is what gets them off and winning.
That's the only thing that gives him the
satisfaction because they can dominate.
We know comics like that.
There are a lot of people like that.
I think we no one at least.
And the ones that's usually the ones
that are in trouble for being unoriginal,
it says it's the desire for conquest,
most supersedes everything.
And they really don't have any
problem fucking people over.
Right.
And that's where it gets really weird.
Every time I've ever fucked anybody
over my life is left a bad feeling.
Like we were talking before the show
about a steel in material and uh,
I said,
uh,
when I was an open mic or I totally stole,
I stole Greg Fitzsimmons
and stuff and like,
we stole it on perfectly.
We,
we spoke about it to each other.
We said like,
dude,
if I'm on the road and I'm bombing,
I'm doing your shit.
Like we made agreements with each other.
But even though I told those people
his joke and it wasn't my joke,
I still felt like I was full of shit and
it was like fucked with me for years.
You know what I do every,
every time now.
I do stand up.
My Buddy Sam Brown,
who was a great comic,
died of pancreatic cancer
about two months ago.
And uh,
I was really close when I knew him for
20 years and he was the first headliner
it ever seen.
We would cross,
he was from Boston and now
every show I steal one of his,
uh,
his jokes,
I just,
it's like my little homage to him.
I just put it in there.
I just kind of slide it in just this,
my little like,
cause I know I wrote on his deathbed,
he,
unfortunately he couldn't talk,
but his wife read it to him.
I wrote,
um,
I said,
listen man,
you know,
you're one of the greatest comics
are you always made me laugh.
If there's any way I
can have your material,
I mean,
you know,
I fucking rock.
And she read it to them
and I don't think he,
I don't think he was able to,
I don't think he was conscious about hope.
He can hear and I hope I made
them laugh before he died.
I literally,
by the way,
I'm,
I,
I recorded two podcasts with him.
One he knew he was dying on my,
on my,
uh,
on my podcast.
So it's pretty,
pretty cool.
Pretty Pretty.
Uh,
pretty moving.
You could do my shit if I die,
I'll do your shit.
I'll always,
that's what I want to see my friends.
I knew some of my notes.
He had great,
great bits,
man.
He had a fucking great
pitch and he's like,
he would talk about smallest
ticket me behind the Greg.
Oh Dude,
no,
no.
You fucked the order of jokes man.
Your jobs would be hard to steal though
because like I was watching you this
weekend and one of the things I loved
was it was almost like you were,
you were,
you were.
Cause I know a lot of
this stuff is new and so,
so much of it was just you
of having an experience.
It's like,
what I like about your standup is you're
always kind of having an experience and
you're doing it for you and you're working
something out and you're looking at
how weirdly how weird we
are structured as a society.
Our minds are why we do
things that make no sense.
Why contextually something makes sense,
but then it doesn't in this case,
and it was so fun to
watch because I was like,
you know this,
the comedy is almost secondary
to the experience La.
Yeah.
It's funny.
Yes,
but you're almost like,
I think I really think people are
watching you kind of have your own very
authentic and unique experience.
Verbal experience.
That's what I felt like.
Like I come away with a
very different perspective.
It's very inspiring to me because
I started writing differently.
Really?
Yeah.
When I see you I go,
I,
it's a really nice,
it's what I love about like
having friends that inspire me.
What you've always done.
Like it's just like you have that,
that's,
that's who your friends should be.
You know?
I know you,
I have friends that are wonderful
that are I play grab ass with.
But then you have friends that are like
that really inspire you to be better and
push you just by their example.
Well they make you better.
They make you to make be better.
Good.
I like hearing that we all
make each other better,
but you always right.
You have,
your bar has always been,
oh,
I don't know how to describe
where you place the bar,
but I always would watch you
and I've seen you at your best.
I've seen you when you're shit is fucking
so tight and you're just a machine
gun.
Like I remember when you were younger,
I'd never seen you did something
to a crowd in New York.
I remember was I was with Patty Jenkins,
you are a fucking machine gun.
It was like literally these New Yorkers,
like all these comics gotten them
and then Joe Rogan gets up and it was
literally like,
we were like looking at each other going,
what the fuck?
What the fuck is this?
And it was what it was,
was somebody who had never taken a day
off and had only been working on being as
authentic with their experience.
And what a lot of people don't
know about your early stuff,
that you were so good at.
Impressions,
you did all of it.
It was funny but really truth.
So for me it was just literally
like a fucking tsunami.
We were like,
Jesus Christ,
that's how you do stand up.
That's how you do it.
Good luck.
Anybody trying to follow that fucking
ball of fucking energy cause you just come
on like certain bits that I couldn't,
I couldn't follow myself.
Oh my God,
you were so physical,
like muscular,
but really flexible.
Like you do weird shit
like fall into the splits.
I remember one time we had a meeting,
remember that we were pitching a TV show
and we're sitting on a couch and it's
like,
I think it was Eric with Eric Tanenbaum
and like big producers and you go
[inaudible] and we were talking
about martial arts and you go,
yeah,
I'm flexible.
And I was like,
yeah,
I'm flexible too.
And you go,
yeah,
but you can't do this.
And you grabbed your ankles and fucking
pull them up and you did the splits in
the air and we were all like,
what the fuck is high?
What is that?
He's like made a rubber and you
used to bring that shit to the,
to the stage and it was just,
it's just really wild to watch.
You kind of continue to grow
and change your expression,
you know?
Well you,
you just keep adding information
to the pile and you keep euro,
you're learned experiences.
So if you're still into it and I,
you know,
you,
you don't diminish your focus.
And my focus is a real
wrestling match because I,
you know,
like a,
in Steven Pressfield's books,
it talks about distractions and,
and different things that you and I will,
I certainly battle with those things,
but I also battle with
other things that I enjoy.
Like when he calls distractions like that,
I think make me better.
I think the better I get at pool,
this seems really strange,
but the,
the better.
I am at comedy and right now I've never
been better at comedy and I've never
been better at pool.
Like I've got this weird
thing going on where,
um,
I can,
I can tune in to,
it's,
to me it seems to be about tuning into
whatever the fuck I'm trying to do,
whether it's Jujitsu,
whether it's pool,
whatever,
w but it standup company.
But I have to have that same
sort of intensity and energy.
And if I dwindle,
if I drop below a certain level,
I can't rely on my learned
experiences with stand up.
I can't rely on the past.
I have to constantly be maintaining
a certain amount of current interest,
writing new stuff.
Yeah,
that's what I was going to say is,
well,
what's what I think the
secret to your success is,
and I always try to tell people this
because people get very frustrated and
discouraged by the process
of accomplishment because
there are so many plateaus
and you're always always
like a lot of people,
well this didn't work out and and,
and what what we in,
I'll just say this to everybody because
I've been pretty successful and I have
people come up to me and they,
you know when you do a show they
want to take pictures and they,
they,
they look at you as a success in this
business and you being one of my closest
friends,
you had a critique of my,
my recent special on showtime,
which I wasn't very happy with.
But what was great about it is you said,
Hey Brian,
you could be a great,
you could be way better than you are now.
I shot a fucking show times
special when people are like,
Whoa,
you shot a special,
I'm,
I'm at working on my second.
But you said you're,
you're putting a little too
much English on the ball.
Okay.
Little too little too slick
playing around and what that does,
what an adequate,
no,
it's a trick of course.
Of course.
I,
I've done it.
I look back at my old
stuff where I did that.
It's the grossest feeling of all time
because what,
what did,
what it means is that no matter
where you are in your career,
you've always got to be assessing.
You've always gotta be taking yourself to,
to task and kind of taking a look
at yourself objectively and go on.
I gotta,
I gotta I gotta work a little harder.
I'm watching my last
special that I edited.
It's the best shit I've ever
done and I can't even watch it.
I was like,
Oh,
I look so stupid.
Fucking talk too much.
Even when I stumbled through like,
uh,
like one also I'll fuck up the,
the,
the one word,
you know,
one one,
I'll have one little stumble in there
and it's just like watching a puppy get
hit with a hammer.
The first time
I saw myself on camera with was a wrestler
and I was 14 and I walked out onto
the mat when I,
and I used to think I was the
baddest guy on the planet.
I looked at video and I went,
well,
where's,
who's the,
who the fuck is the kid with rickets?
Fuck,
is that,
it was me.
I've never been more devastated.
I was like,
I'm that skinny in a single let,
I'm never wrestling again.
I'll go out in the Burka before I
fucking go out in a single let that's,
that's a fair,
and that's a horrific,
my,
my buddy wrote a book,
um,
which I told you you should
have them on your podcast.
His name is hunter Mott's.
He wrote a book called the straight a
conspiracy speaks 10 languages fluently.
This kid graduated from Harvard
with a biochemistry degree.
Okay.
And I said,
why did you write the book?
He said,
well,
I said,
oh.
well,
how do you learn 10 languages fluently?
And,
and he's fluent.
And he said,
oh,
it's because I,
I know I can do it.
And everybody who learns languages or
math thinks they can't because they have
an emotional context around it.
That's all.
And I don't know what does that mean?
He said,
I'm writing a book about it.
I'll tell you about it later.
I had him on my podcast.
He wrote a book called
the straight a conspiracy.
And He,
and,
and if you look at all the math,
all the science around
learning and which he did,
one of the things that they find for sure
is that people have these myths about
themselves.
I'm not a math person.
I am a math person.
I'm artistic,
I'm not artistic.
I'm musical.
I'm not musical.
If you actually look at the science
that's being done about learning and why
some people are very good at
some things and others are not,
I'm talking broad scope here.
Um,
what you find is that the emotional
context with which they learned something,
it has everything to do with whether
or not they're going to excel at that.
Everything.
So in other words,
whatever emotional state you approach,
learning something,
growing at something means everything.
It's,
it's what it's all about.
If you are in a pleasant environment
where somebody makes it fun for you,
okay,
you're going to learn it.
Why are a lot of Asian people,
so the stereotype goes like Chinese
people good at math and a lot of Americans
aren't.
I'll tell you why.
If you read Malcolm Gladwell's book,
the outliers and my buddy's
book straight at conspiracy,
it has to do with a culture that says,
well,
yeah,
this math problems really
hard and I guess I'll,
I'll be here for the next
two and a half hours.
Americans are like,
I'm not going to sit here
for two and a half hours.
I got shit to do that.
This is fucking really hard.
Guess what?
Not a math person and
then your parents go,
yeah,
he's not good at math.
Isn't it fascinating?
The culture that is the least inclined
to do that hard work is the culture that
has the best art.
Well,
we also have the best math and
science and surprisingly because we,
we have,
we have immigrants and capture the
competition's fierce and the possibilities
are pretty intense.
I also happen to believe that that's,
that is the reason we're so good
at art and things is because it is,
we place emphasis on the individual.
It's your individual expression is what
you can benefit from it and we have
freedom to do it.
You can't be expressive.
Imagine having your podcast in Russia to
imagine having my podcast in American a
few years.
That's what's really a problem.
What's really a problem is the more
you get shit like this national defense
authorization act,
the more of these different
laws are passed that slowly but
surely take away your right
to say certain things.
They just outlawed protests
at military funerals.
The government has,
uh,
recently reinstated propaganda.
They're allowed now.
They haven't been since the 1940s to
actively use propaganda on the American
people.
That's legal now and all this shit is
going on while the Internet is growing,
while people's access to
information is just flying out them.
It's like this desperate last clawing
attempt at a dying culture to hold on to
power and it's disgusting.
It's disgusting that anybody would ever
allow the government to use propaganda.
I mean Munis,
lead,
lie,
and and,
and distort the truth for the public in
order to emphasize their point of that,
you would give that power to the
government is so beyond sick,
but as long as you realize that that is
always going to be the case and that you
have to always be aware of that.
Right.
The problem is that's happening though.
The problem is that it's a trend.
It's happening and it takes
a lot to stop a trend.
It takes a lot to back it up.
How do you stop and you
write to your representative?
I mean,
what happens after a while I started
to feel like I'm not represented.
Right.
I start to feel like if I'm not a
corporation with a lot of money to buy it,
but to by lobbyists,
no,
you're not.
I don't have a way of
influencing my government.
For example,
New York Times wrote an Ra.
Ra ran an article recently about,
I travel a lot as to you and when you
walk through the two boxes where you put
your feet and you actually
put your hands up,
y'all not talking about the
foam that goes around you.
I'm talking about the two,
the two boxes you walked.
Well that's radiation and in New York
Times wrote an article and it was about a
week ago.
If you guys want to look it up about the
fact that they actually aren't too sure
how much radiation you're getting.
They think it might be
one 10th of a chest x Ray.
Some in some cases,
more importantly,
they don't maintain them as well.
They had some crazy number
of maintenance requests,
mum,
many of which were not met.
You're,
you're putting your trust into the Tsa.
They're probably good people doing the
best they can and in some ways they do a
great job.
But the fact that I didn't know that
I was being blasted with radiation,
no matter how small,
not doing it,
I don't do that.
I have them pat me down.
And
did anybody ever get creepy with you
when you asked for a pat down was I was
hoping they would,
but they didn't the fuck.
Not Creepy sexually.
I mean,
Graham Hancock,
uh,
who's,
a guy who I've had on the podcast before,
he's from England,
he came to America and he didn't trust
the radiation of the machine and he said
they violently like almost assaulted him.
He said it was very rape.
Like grab his cock like the
no,
they were really polite to me actually.
They went,
all right,
no problem.
I think it's,
you know who you get,
you know,
we might get some guy that
doesn't like English people,
you know,
dude has an accent.
He's like,
I'm not going to go through,
they're impressed with the TSA and
how professional a lot of them are.
I'm actually impressed with how Curtis,
you're such a fucking Fox News.
Contrarion I would have known that you
were gonna say that if we brought up the,
what about Tsa cons?
You know what actually
statistically the Tsa,
I like everybody.
I have no like resolved by the way.
Just for the record.
Everybody.
I finally all my rules in the show.
I don't believe as an actor I should
be talking about anything including
politics,
but I can't help it.
I'm like anyways,
in the actor,
how could you say as an actor,
as a comic or a comic,
if you're a comic,
you should be feel ridiculous idea
that you should be able to talk about
anything except religion or politics.
Well,
the,
that that alone is just like a cry or a
call rather to a middling state of mind
to a non communication.
You know?
It's like if you're not politically
committed to some extent,
then it's at your own peril.
If everybody wants to be ignorant
about what's going on in their world,
in politics,
then then good luck trying to change
anything and more importantly,
good luck being able to see what,
what's happening.
Most people don't have the fucking time.
Man,
that's a part of the problem.
Most people have lives.
They have jobs and children and all that
other stuff that goes along with them.
Hobbies,
you have time to develop a philosophy.
You don't have to worry about the minutia.
Did you have time?
My point is that what you were saying
earlier is that they don't feel like
they're being represented so they don't
feel like their efforts put into it.
Have any great reward.
You know,
they don't,
they feel like completely,
there's a lot of people,
I think a good percentage,
more than half,
I feel completely
alienated from the system.
And that's a conservative estimate.
If you say that half the people in this
country feel alienated from the system,
that's a failing system,
no matter how you look at it.
And the problem is people
don't feel rewarded for
investing in a failing system.
When a guy like Obama gets the Nobel
Peace Prize and then since 30,000 more
fucking troops to Afghanistan
and everybody's like,
Jesus Christ,
man.
Like what?
What kind of system is this?
Who,
who would have,
who would have said that?
That's okay.
Who would one of their sons to go?
Who would one of their brother
to go get the fuck Outta here?
That's nonsense.
That's craziness.
But yet it's happening.
So we don't feel represented.
We feel too,
I wonder if Obama himself feels,
I want why it's like a,
like a listless play thing.
I wonder,
you know what I mean?
Like somebody,
I bet you his biggest complaint is the
fact that he doesn't have any power at
all.
I bet you that he makes it.
Well,
he knows that if he makes one decision,
he's going to a appease 50% of the
people and piss off the other 50% I mean,
it's gotta be a strange job if you just
stop and think about who you are before
he become president.
If you take out all the nonsense,
the tin foil hat stuff about the
illuminati running things and you,
let's just pretend for a brief moment
that maybe elections are real okay.
And maybe Obama is just a regular
dude who became a senator,
who's a regular dude
who ran for president,
who activated a big wellspring of hope
and it's people and then they put him
into office and then
once he gets in there,
then he has to deal with
these international banks.
He has to deal with
things like Halliburton.
people like Dick Cheney,
Rumsfeld,
think about all the people
that were in power before him.
Think about all the people that
he has to communicate with.
Think of it all the shit that
went down in that office.
Think of it all the people that died all
over the world because of the actions
of the group of people he replaced and
think about what that must feel like to
step into those shoes.
And then all of a sudden you realize
you are at the helm of a murder machine.
You are at the helm of a thing that
is in every single part of the world.
It's also a huge octopus that is
not being run by one particular,
no,
it's being built by a bunch
of different interests,
but they're profiting like massive,
massive amounts on war.
Deon and all those companies that have
that make a lot of money off of what,
what they,
what Eisenhower called the
industrial military industrial.
And so as a,
as a president,
do you feel like,
you know when you get in there you
just slowly tried to put on the brakes?
I mean,
how much control does a guy have?
Cause it doesn't seem like much.
I think we deviated much
from Bush to Obama at all.
And in fact they cracked down on secrecy
issues and crack down on prosecuting
people for leaking information.
And Obama was,
was very,
um,
very much about the drone programs,
special forces.
He made a joke about using the drones
if someone tried to Dre to a date,
his daughters,
he made a joke in one of those,
you know,
they do as one of those functions
where he does one liners.
Obama got up there and he made a joke
about if you were dating his daughters,
he has one word for you.
Drones.
Yeah.
Well,
uh,
kinda funny,
but not if,
when you're the president,
that's not when thousands of civilians
have been murdered by drones.
Thousands of innocent civilians.
I don't know what the number is now,
but it was in the thousands.
Someone sent me all the
statistics on Twitter.
Give killed a lot of bad guys.
But again,
it was what we were talking
about with farm factory farming.
When you have people in Nevada and Florida
who go to a room and they kill people
who are a thousand miles away via,
you know,
camera and with these drones.
I think about that.
My joke was the war hero in 20 years
is going to be the Chubby guy with huge
thumb muscles.
This smells like Doritos and we'd write,
cause he's,
he's a Gamer.
He's hooked up on Alpha brain there.
There is a,
there is a psychological model when
you're removing yourself from the actual,
you know,
when you're a marine,
you're drawing a bead,
you're shooting a guy and you know you're,
you're running and you're and you
just see the guy die and stuff.
When you're in a room in your
country and you go home after,
after operating these drones and
killing whatever it might be,
maybe it's one person in
the 25 whatever it is,
or you drop a thousand
pound bomb on a shoot,
a Hellfire missile,
whatever comes out of those things.
That's kind of really,
that's,
that raises a lot of questions.
It raises a lot of questions when we're
this removed from the actual experience
of killing
what we were talking about earlier.
It's all connected.
The sociopath does not have that feeling
of connection and only feels pleasure
when they win.
And what is war but completely
sociopathic behavior.
And what is friendship other than none.
So sociopathic behavior,
the connection that you get with people,
the being the most important thing we
were talking about when we're doing this
podcast that we've created an environment,
we've created a,
uh,
there's,
it's not as simple as this is a show.
It's a bunch of people tuning into the
show and getting like a positive thing
out of it and having conversations like
this and these conversations take place
in their head and they experience it.
They learn from it.
They,
it gives them hope.
It gives them a mindset that they can,
uh,
they can accomplish something with
it gives them a fucking people.
I've had come up to me and go,
dude,
since I've listen to your podcast,
I've lost 70 pounds.
I start drinking Kale shakes,
I think come to me every fucking show.
It's incredible.
It's also important when you have a
debate and we have a discussion like we do
to to actually take a look at the,
where to place,
where to place the focus,
for example,
allowed.
Well,
I'm a,
well the military,
there are a lot of people in the military
who are carrying out these who are
doing these things that never agreed
with the war in the first place.
I mean,
we have a civilian government
that controls the military,
that makes these decisions
for the military.
The military just carries out orders.
That's how our government works.
And the military has a job to do.
If you send them into a war zone,
they're going to get the job done.
Um,
and a lot of guys,
I mean,
I know I w you know,
I went to Afghanistan,
but I know enough people
in the armed forces,
a lot of,
a lot of men in the armed forces and
women have an ideology that they believe
in.
It's this country.
It's the things that they'll do
when they come in and they're,
they're loyal servants,
they risked their fucking
lives and they go do their job.
And a lot of them get Maine,
they lose their arms,
they lose their friends
and everything else.
I think that when you start to look at
how this war's gone over the past 11
years,
and I'm talking about
the Palestine in Iraq,
you've gotta be,
you gotta be very,
very conscientious about not
only how this really started,
who were the,
who were the architects,
who was the intellectual force,
who was the argument behind it?
How did this happen?
How did this turn into a huge snowball?
And the reason you should know about
that is because your lives and other
people's lives depend on it in the future.
Yeah.
We just get ourselves,
we'll get ourselves
into another situation.
You know,
my buddy,
it's not weird though.
That's what's really going on.
I'm sorry.
It's not,
we're going to get ourselves
into another situation.
Somebody else's going to do it.
Well,
my buddy,
I think I put it on on red bands a thing,
but my best squad,
but my buddy who I interviewed who was
a special forces guy who was a real,
a real,
I don't know what he does,
but I know he's very much involved
and he was the baddest guy I ever knew
growing up and he said he,
he was,
he just said about the war effort.
He watched what's happening,
had been in Iraq for I guess
seven years and he said,
Iraq is a country now.
We've created a mini Saddam in this guy,
Molokai.
He is now,
he's a Shiite.
He is got police squads
that report directly to him.
So what we,
we go into Iraq.
There's this notion that while he's got
the fourth largest army in the world,
we've got to stop him from,
you know,
dropping a weapon and okayed his hands.
There was the arguments and stuff.
What we'd done in some ways,
if you look at Iraq with the
exception of Kurdistan and stuff,
is that we really destroyed that country.
A lot of people are dead and we've put
into place somebody who is keeping his
people or has a potential
of keeping his in
the same kind of oppression
technically as Saddam did.
Now what is the objective?
What are we doing?
Was this worth it wasn't worth
killing all those people.
Was it worth all those soldiers didn't
come back and many more who are wounded?
That's the question and more importantly,
what lessons can be learned?
What do we have to learn
from Iraq and Afghanistan?
What do we have to learn so we don't
get an arm ourselves into the situation
again,
sometimes wars,
inevitable men.
It is.
That was an inevitable one.
That was one that we got tricked into.
Okay,
but then how do we not get tricked the
next time we have the Internet now?
I think we have a completely different
sort of playing field than what existed
back when Bush and Cheney
dragged us into the Iraq war.
I think the Internet has
evolved far past where it is.
That's why things like wikileaks are
so terrifying to the powers that be,
it's real hard to get away with
shit on the Internet to others.
So much countervailing information too.
Like you get one argument
and you get another,
but that's just debate.
I'm talking about straight information.
Um,
I think that the,
the access to information is ultimately
changing the world that we live in and
it's happening so quickly.
And these kinds of conversations really
weren't commonplace when we were kids.
Yeah.
Well we were 16 and 17.
Our parents weren't having
these kinds of conversations.
They just weren't,
it's a,
it's a different world.
We know more about how things work and
because of that it makes it harder and
harder to accomplish fuckery.
Still going still going on right now.
But ultimately it's got to die
off in order for us to have,
you know,
uh,
any sort of religious society,
we're going to have to evolve past that
and realize just as you and I realize as
friends and as members of our community
that it's not necessary and that that
kind of a,
an energy that you put
out to control people.
And to and into,
to,
to profit from other people's losses is
totally non beneficial to you as well.
You just because you're pulling it off
under the guise of a corporation doesn't
mean that you are immune to the negative
rebound of that because you're not,
and you want to call it Karma,
you want to call it what
goes around comes around,
whatever you want to call it.
It's real.
Okay.
I have experienced it.
I am walking proof of it.
My whole life is proof of it.
I have been,
I the,
the negative things that
I've ever done in my life,
I have felt in great deep detail and
rebounded as much as possible to turn that
terrible feeling into positive energy.
And that is why I've been a
happy person my whole life.
But do you think that's because,
cause I always wonder,
I try to help people,
a friend of mine who's going
through a tough time now and,
and I,
and I realized that the,
one of the reasons that he's going
through a hard time as he's not in any way
actually really confronted and
asked himself what he wants.
Yeah.
You can't,
you can't get a guy to do that though.
But,
but don't you think that will be success?
Is the fact that you've already,
you've always been able to
see and technicolor what
you wanted and what you want
it to be or,
or is that what you know what it is?
Um,
uh,
first of all it's just pressing forward.
That's constant doubt that that constant
need to write new shit to do different
things to the constant
need to be in motion.
The constant need to be doing something,
whether it's doing Jujitsu or playing
pool or writing more jokes are getting
onstage that forward momentum.
That is a constant that,
that,
that is,
that is the reason why
I've done everything.
And you can transfer it.
It's like the meal multi Musashi quote.
And once you understand the way broadly,
you can see it in all things.
So like the idea that once you lock on
to what it is to really focus and get
good at something,
then you can keep,
but it's also that it's really
satisfying to accomplish things.
It's really satisfying to write things.
It's really satisfying to do shows.
I don't know even know why I did it,
but I've always wanted to play the drums.
So I've,
I've been taking drums for a year now.
It's actually changed not only
my comedy but my sports like,
like I pick up on shit really fast now
because with the drums I'm having to do
something.
One thing with my foot,
one thing with this thing
with this and one this,
so my brain is firing,
it's firing.
So it's changed the way I read.
It's changed the way I do stand up.
It's really wild.
I'm I,
it's a really good mental and
I'm listening differently.
I'm never going to be
in a band by the way.
Right,
but you just enjoying it.
I'm just enjoying love that.
I think that's very important to
life and I think a lot of people,
like there's,
there's like a lot of people that have
falsely rewarded being a lazy cunt and
it'll like,
you'd rather just sit in front of the TV,
chill,
wouldn't beers watch TV?
Let me tell you something.
This is the real reality of,
of life.
If you don't earn something,
you won't appreciate it.
It's why people win the lottery and
they lose all their money within a year.
When you earn something
you appreciated it is,
it is a golden,
steadfast rule of life and if you're
laying around on the couch watching TV and
you haven't done anything to deserve that,
getting drunk doesn't feel good.
It doesn't feel good.
It doesn't,
you feel like a fucking loser.
But when I do something,
like if I write and I blast out like
three or four hours are really good shit
and they're like,
fuck yes,
I feel good.
I feel fired up.
I can't wait to do a show.
I can go watch TV and I can enjoy it.
Yeah,
I can go watch mountain men and I
enjoy watching these fucking guys.
Here's what I think is really
like forks for me as I go,
I sit down and I go like this.
I go,
what do I want to,
what do I want to do and what
am I going to regret not doing?
When I,
when I'm 90 I say to myself,
I go,
what do I really want to do?
And I go and what do I want to do in
three months or six months and stuff like
that.
And then I literally,
I structure my day and I think you
can do this no matter who you are,
you structure your day.
So you go,
you wake up every morning and go,
what action.
Just one action,
maybe two actions,
whatever.
What action can I take today just
to get a little closer to that,
that goal.
I just want to just to
get a little closer,
whatever,
whatever it is.
You know,
maybe it's 20 minutes of practicing
your takedowns or it might be,
I want to get my black belt in Jiu Jitsu.
I want to be able to play drums in a band.
I want to,
you know,
whatever it might be.
The only going to speak a language,
you know,
call me during my podcast.
It's Brian Webb.
Then
maybe it's called and told
me what the shows down.
Hey Boo,
you live on the air.
Okay.
His mikes out.
It's really quite well.
He keeps backing up.
That's what it is.
Yeah.
Sorry guys.
Oh really?
Yeah.
You can't be talking back.
They're all casual pitch.
Okay.
I gotta get in.
Thanks Brian.
This is technical information
delivered via telephone.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Brian Red Band on the scene.
Follow him.
Red Ban on Twitter.
All right buddy and me,
Brian Calix at Brian.
Count on Twitter.
I respond to all my twitters by the way.
What were we talking about?
Very important probably.
Um,
but this,
this idea that we were talking about
before of of community of you know,
of all influencing each
other in a positive way that
gets lost in big numbers.
And the problem is we could have a great
tribe of like 50 people and keep it
together and have the most awesome utopia.
As I've heard boulder described boulders
like a really small mountain community,
but it's so small.
It's like,
it really almost is like a
functional working utopia.
But I think that we could do that.
It's possible to do that as a country.
We just have to get more people
in tuned to thinking correctly.
And most people are just
never taught how to think.
They're never taught that they
can manage their consciousness.
They've never taught,
they've never been taught that the
mind can go down that self-destructive,
completely self destructive and also
totally unnecessary and you have to learn.
Like all the times I've blown my
cool for nothing and still do.
I mean I might be in my car retard
and hit the Horn fucking pass money.
It was just so pointless,
so stupid.
And that's near the airport and it's
almost always a sign that I'm doing too
much.
It's always a sign of some
sort of external stress.
It's affecting,
you know,
whatever it is that,
but when,
when you can see that,
if you can see that and if you
can go in the the right direction,
if we could fucking influence a giant
group of people to go in the right
direction,
then you really can change something.
Well that really can change tools.
But that starts,
that starts with individuals
really asking themselves,
starts with saying with inspiration.
Yeah.
It doesn't only start with individuals,
ask themselves what they want.
Sometimes it starts with inspiration.
Where you realize there's no,
there's no difference between them and me.
They were losers too.
I was,
I've been a lose or I have been
a fucking failure in my life.
Hardcore.
Like when people,
I've had people say like,
here's your Obama on stage.
I'm like,
Oh my Christ that I bombed.
I bombed so hard.
No one who ever watched me that day would
have ever thought that I could ever be
funny.
I had a girl send me a short film.
Um,
her name is Diana,
and she sent me a film,
uh,
and she wrote it.
She wrote a,
basically a movie,
a short film about her
experience with a guy on a date.
And the guy was me.
She never told me that.
She sent it to me and I,
and I,
and all the lines that guy was making,
saying lines.
I had said to her,
and let me tell you something,
man.
I called her up and I went,
Diana,
I go,
I'm so sorry.
I was such a fucking arrogant prick.
I was such a Dick because I didn't
even understand you are a woman.
And I had a projected notion of what,
what you were,
what you thought and I thought I was so
much smarter than you were and you were
looking at me like I was a
Guinea pig in a fucking maze.
Like a,
like a rat in a maze.
Like literally like,
look at this monkey talk
to me like I'm an idiot.
Yeah,
exactly.
And he's just hitting me with all
these things and he's just a dick.
Literally.
I looked at it,
I was just appalled.
I was appalled at who I was and it's
just cause I didn't know any better.
I just didn't.
I had preconceived notions of what women
were preconceived notions of how they
thought preconceived
notions of what a man was
supposed to be.
The all funds,
by the time you get to your
20s and you know you're,
you're having experiences with women,
these are not the very first of all
social experiences when you're involving
people that are sexually attracted
to each other are very complicated.
They're very awkward.
There's a plenty of room
for misunderstanding.
There's plenty of room
for offending people,
putting out bad vibes,
being too forward being too well,
you know,
hey,
there's,
it's,
it's a,
it's a very strange
sort of a situation way,
so we're not good at navigating it,
you know,
and we,
we,
you know,
when you're young,
especially you just say the dumbest
fucking shit and most of the time you
fucking hate yourself after
it's over and you don't,
you don't,
you didn't want to do that.
It's just,
it's like you being thrown in a major
league baseball game and someone telling
you to hit that ball,
that fucking things flying at me.
That's exactly right.
You're really not prepared
for that extreme experience.
No manual for life.
I mean,
well not only that,
how much did your fucking parent,
I don't know how much
your parents taught you,
but how much did your parents
teach you about dating?
Oh,
nothing.
I was just talking about that with my son.
I was like,
I didn't really,
I wasn't really taught the women
the complexity of the female psyche.
I'm definitely going to have to
have a talk on my son about that.
But yeah,
that's going to be that it's,
it's so important to try to actually
raise a kid that can understand what's,
what's next on the horizon.
Give them like a little
heads up of like what,
this is what I went through.
So this is probably that that
would have fucking help a lot.
So when it comes to dating,
parents didn't give me any dating advice.
Also because you have,
you also given a very weird archetypal
notion of what masculinity is too.
Like that's also like being what,
I didn't even know what a man,
what a man to find was.
It was difficult.
I had an exam.
What's to everybody?
It's different,
you know what I mean?
What did it a man is does.
This is what I believe a man is a person
who does what he wants and what makes
him happy.
As long as it's not hurting other people
and we'll actually follows through and
does what he wants as
opposed to someone who,
someone's bitch,
if,
let me tell you something.
If you're a gang guy,
okay.
And you're not out there blowing guys
because you're worried about what other
people think.
You're somebody bitch.
Right?
Whether you realize it or not.
Yeah,
you're the bitch of all the prejudice
people that want to stop people from being
gangs.
And if you are a man,
you'd go out there and suck some cock.
That's,
that's reality.
That's true.
Because that's what life is.
What I like you,
you probably don't,
but it's my right to like what I like
and being a man is going after what you
like and if you want to fucking
take the easy way out and take some,
some job that you know you can do instead
of pursue a career in writing books or
pursue a career racing horses,
whatever the fuck you're compelled to
Pressfield and going provide the best
example he said,
you may have your degree
in comparative literature,
you man a phd in comparative literature
and Teach Comparative Literature,
but guess what?
You should have written a novel.
So that's just a form of
high tech procrastination,
you know?
So you're right.
I mean,
it's really a question of
going for what you want.
And you know,
a real man can be a guy who fights in
the cage or a guy who was a nurse in a
fucking hospital,
you know?
Yes.
Whatever it is you're doing
whatever you're supposed to do,
wherever you're supposed
to place your energy,
giving,
helping and growing.
Uh,
that's,
that's what we need to teach kids.
And that's,
there's no,
there's,
there's no better or worse.
If you're supposed to be a carpenter,
that's what,
if you really enjoy it.
I have a buddy who's a carpenter
back home and he's fucking loves it.
He loves buildings,
really loves the art of
putting together a great room.
He loves it when it's done.
He loves that he can,
he'll look in this room
and it's all mapped out.
You're following the architect's plans,
you know,
laying down things.
And next thing you know,
three months later,
whatever it is,
look what the fucking awesome
kitchen you guys just build.
Totally Shit.
Like he gets a deep feeling of
satisfaction from that and he makes a good
living.
He's got a good company doing that,
but that's it's because that's
what he's passionate about.
It's because he actually enjoys his work
and it doesn't matter if it's that or
if it's been in a fucking band or if it's,
you know,
being a stand up or whatever it is.
If you don't follow that shit,
that's when you'll,
you'll,
you're,
you're fucking yourself,
man.
Our dear friend Sam Sheridan said,
he goes,
I was talking about how I want it.
I was watching UFC
every time I watched it.
A little part of me dies because I want
to be a fight or something or you don't.
I know,
but that's what he said.
He goes,
Brian,
he goes,
you are supposed to,
and I've always been supposed
to be a standup comic.
Dude,
you found what you're supposed to do.
Did you,
you were not supposed to be
a fighter or anything else.
You weren't doing comedy.
I remember you told me,
you go,
you're missing out on the
best thing in the world.
What are you,
what are you doing?
I got back into it because of you,
but I also,
I remember watching Dane Cook
back in the day and I was like,
that dude is crushing a room and I want,
I got to get back into this
because he wanted to crush.
I just loved,
I loved it.
I was like,
I'm watching him map so much.
Just stop.
I don't know cause I'm crazy.
Well,
you weren't doing real
standup when I first met you.
When I first met,
you couldn't get spots and I was like,
fuck it.
And I was trying to be an actor.
We first started hanging out.
You had this act that was like you had
taken every alternative act that you saw
and tried to duplicate it.
And I remember talking to
you about it going guys,
and even you,
man,
what are you doing?
You look you're,
you're going up there.
You're,
you're doing what these fucking Weirdo
judgmental like dorks want you to do,
like you're doing what you think
they're going to enjoy from you.
So satisfying to me now,
especially about the stuff I'm doing now
is you're being yourself this weekend
at the American comedy San Diego.
Amazing Club,
by the way,
and it's filled with great comedy.
If you're,
if you're living in San Diego,
San Diego finally has like a real
comedy club and a in Chicago,
August 23rd they have national
headlines there every weekend.
Look like the comedy store
in La Jolla is a great club,
but you could get fucked there and they
could send down one of those old school
headliners from like the 1970 [inaudible]
that has a written a joke in a hundred
years when was work anywhere
else other than the comedy store.
They'll send those down
to La Jolla on occasion.
I don't know if they're still doing that,
but back in the day you would
look at the lineup and go,
oh my God,
no,
that's the headliner.
No,
you almost wanted to like
call the people and go,
please just stay on,
because that show would be so bad.
It would,
they would never want to go
see standup comedy again.
No,
and it's true.
As you get older and if
you're trying to be a real,
trying to do something,
what happens?
I think what's supposed to happen is you
become a comic is you start stripping
away all that other stuff and more and
more of who you really are is kind of
expressed.
That's what's so satisfying to me,
you know?
Yeah,
for sure.
I mean,
it's weird,
but you're learning how to
talk on stage instead of,
you were just like you
were when I first met you,
you were doing this fake thing,
rabbits out of hats,
and then you became just
this like really silly guy.
It was like really silly,
but I was always weirded out by
the fact that you were so silly.
But then we would have these deep fucking
intense conversations and I was like,
why?
Where's that on stage?
And then I thought about it,
I'm like,
well,
you know,
that's a choice.
That's a,
an artistic thing.
Like look at Hedberg one
of my favorite comics ever.
And you know,
there's a message in that it was all
silliness and there's nothing wrong with
that.
Like I'm a silly goose.
There's a large part of me.
It's always I can't help it.
And it's funny that you're so intense.
Often it's like there's a real balance
to that and it's a good quality that you
have that it's missing in a lot of men.
Would they somehow or another
equate weakness with silly?
You know,
because I don't think,
I think the biggest mistake a man can
make his taking himself seriously.
Don't take yourself too seriously,
man.
There's always somebody faster,
stronger,
funnier,
better,
smarter.
It just,
just do only what you can do and always
don't be afraid to fucking take the
pressure off yourself,
man.
Don't be afraid to kind of
just make fun of yourself.
There's nothing wrong with it.
There's a lot of power in that you,
yeah,
you don't understand that when
you try to not take the hits,
that the,
the rebounds doubled,
tripled the effect because
you're not learning.
You're not only are
you not taking the hit,
but you're not learning from the hit
because every time you take the hint,
it makes you better.
You got to take the head emotionally.
You got to take the hit psychologically,
you got to take the hit with your ego.
You got to fucking fail in life.
It's an important ingredient to success.
The other thing that I was,
don't you agree?
I hundred percent agree with that
the a hundred percent and the other.
The other thing that that the the,
as you were talking,
I was thinking about the
other thing you get from it,
which is when,
when you take,
when you allow yourself to be a little
bit of a silly goose or you allow
yourself to be vulnerable or
whatever it is and make fun yourself,
what will happen is it people around you
feel safer and what they'll do is they
won't be on their guard because a
lot of times we come at a situation,
if you come to a situation
from a power angle or whatever,
that person's guard will go up immediately
and you won't see who they really
are.
Well,
let's think about this.
How disappointing is it when you meet
someone and you have like a level of
adulation for them?
You,
you,
you know,
you're,
they're famous.
Your,
your,
your fan and they're a dick.
The rebound is stunning.
It's stunning and hurtful.
I mean it's,
it's incredible.
Yeah.
But on the other side,
when you approach someone and
they're like really normal and nice,
what a warm feeling that is.
Like because you're coming
at them in an unfair way.
It's like we had Bert Kreischer on the
icehouse chronicles and he was talking
about his experience with Gene Simmons.
And apparently he did that show,
the expo and gene Simmons was
a fucking complete cunt to him.
And Gene Simmons like
told him not to talk.
I said yeah,
told them he wouldn't be interviewing
him and he was gonna make this grill
interview him.
And he was a huge kiss fan before this.
So when this happened,
it was completely devastating to Bert.
Yeah.
And having Burt relay this and then
having all of us share our experiences.
Like I was talking about,
I met Robin Williams last week and,
but he was like real normal,
like really nice guy.
But it was still,
it was fucking Robin Williams,
you know what I mean?
Like he didn't have to be normal.
And he didn't have to be a nice guy.
It could have been weird because
when you meet someone like that,
there's a weird imbalance.
If you're talking to Tom Cruise,
I don't care how many gay jokes you have
in the back of your head that you want,
those will pop into your
head when you meet him.
You'll be like,
Holy Shit,
I hope you'll spend an hour and a half.
I did a reading with him for three hours
and I spent an hour and a half of them
at a party and believe me,
I was like,
oh,
maybe he'll be my best friend by the way,
and by the way,
I'm a straight guy.
I think he's straight actually
shut your fucking mouth.
Oh,
I know is.
I'm looking,
looking at him going,
he's a really good looking guy.
I was like,
you know what?
He's Tom Cruise.
I mean,
weren't really,
we're talking,
we're having a good conversation.
It's all a ruse wonder.
Like he was like,
Hey,
I'll be your best friend you
make out with me for 10 minutes.
I'd be like,
I got you make out with,
I'd have to think about it because then
I can be best friends with why I think I
may go Tom Cruise 1000% as a straight man.
You know why?
Because I'd be able to tell you about it.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Are you kidding?
Watch.
Yeah.
For the record,
for the record,
open mouth.
I'd be like,
Tom,
come over here.
By the way.
He's Kinda,
he's Kinda pretty.
So yes,
I would.
Would you enforce your,
weighed on him a little bit and press
him backwards just to make them a little
bend to your will without question.
But I'd also be looking.
I did.
You'd be
phone call and make you
be the first of all.
Come back.
And I go,
dude,
I sit down for a second.
I've got some time.
I'm straight,
man.
I Bob slapped and I mean bubs slapped
for 10 minutes with Tom Cruise and his
hands were really get made
that happen with John Travolta.
We just have to put you in a proximity.
Can't do it.
He wouldn't do it with John is too gay.
He's gay.
Yeah.
Shit,
I'm not,
I'm not gonna make it.
And it's like what my agent sent me,
uh,
things violently to audition first.
Queer's folk,
you know,
which was that show
on showtime.
And,
and the first thing was I have
to be making out with this guy.
I was like,
listen,
call,
manage.
And I go,
look,
I'm not a homophobe.
I'm really not and I'm actually in
favor of gay marriage and all that.
I go,
but I'm,
you got to know who I am.
I'm Brian Callan and I'm straight guy
and it can think I'm waking up every
fucking morning at 6:00 AM and going
to set and making that with some dude.
Uh,
after,
after getting rid of my coffee breath,
you're out of your fucking mind and
there's not enough money that I would do
that with.
Here's the problem with this is one of
the reasons why I wouldn't be doing it.
It's not that I'm not open minded,
but I don't like watching gay guys kiss.
So I don't want to do a movie where guys,
kids kind of movie squeamish about it.
You wanted me to do.
I never saw,
I never saw Brokeback mountain.
Actually I saw it,
which was awesome.
I had a great five and a bit about it.
He's fucking hilarious.
I laughed through so much to that movie.
The child.
We know why because I
enjoyed it and people were,
there was a lot,
I had this conversation
with someone who like,
you know,
like well you know,
it's because of your narrow mighty
point of view that you didn't enjoy it.
I enjoyed the fuck out of it.
I bet I enjoyed it more than you.
Okay.
Cause I enjoyed it as even if,
yes,
it is a beautiful love story and
it is sad and oddly romantic.
Yeah.
It's still also hilarious.
I enjoy both aspects of it.
I'm not closed minded or homophobic,
but I enjoyed the love thing
that they had going on.
But I also enjoyed Caitlin
like a fucking school child.
Every time they were kissing each other.
I remember you were like two men
making out is in fact hilarious.
It's hilarious.
It's not,
there's nothing wrong with it being funny.
It's not like I'm
telling you not to do it.
But if you're telling me there
should be less funny in the world,
you can go fuck yourself.
And if you're telling me
that what you want to do,
if I think it's funny,
hurts you,
I think you're a bitch.
Okay?
Because if you start making
fun of having sex with girls,
ah,
I'm not going to hurt feelings,
not gonna get hurt.
Look what?
You're a majority.
There are minority.
Get the fuck over it.
If you like fucking guys,
you should laugh your ass off when
dudes talking about you fucking guys.
Cause that's what you enjoy.
Humor is the greatest fucking equalizer.
Speaking of,
speaking of which,
you'll kill me,
but I have to go.
No 10 minute podcasts,
podcasts go fuck itself too.
You know?
But I got to do it because they're waiting
for me and I gotta be there at seven.
You're going in late,
late.
You're going to be late morning.
They're going to kill me.
There'll be fun.
No they're not.
I've kind of fun.
I love it,
man.
Listen,
we have to keep the throwing
for a little while longer.
10 minutes to talk about you being an
American comedy company in San Diego's we,
yes,
I'll be at the American
comedy club comedy company.
It's for American comedy
company as soon as he goes.
What's called,
right?
Or is it the American comedy club?
You might,
it's American comedy club in San Diego.
Thursday,
Friday,
Saturday one Twitter,
Chicago Improv.
Everybody.
August 23rd 24th now you're
confusing the fuck out of people.
Do it.
Don't you don't remember
seeing more than one.
Just one.
It's American comedy company.
Oh it is?
Yes.
American comedy.
I can't wait since San Diego,
California.
So fucking awesome club.
It's one of those like really
low ceiling intimate clubs that,
you know,
like the comedy works in Denver.
Okay.
Like the old comedy.
The comedy works in Denver.
Oh yeah.
It's good.
As it gets.
Me and Doug Benson and Brendan Walsh,
we were in town in this way.
And you got to at the paramount and a,
one of the things we're saying,
we're walking by the comedy works
like there's no better club.
There's never been a better club event.
And then the comedy works in Denver.
It's perfect.
Size is the perfect height.
Shamirs don't move.
Nobody can move the chair on your foot.
The chairs are locked in place.
There's a table in between each chair.
Sit the fuck down.
Here's the show.
Everybody's packed in there.
The wage staffs.
Awesome.
The shows are fantastic.
You walked by the comedy works,
you look and you see one headliner after
another national name after national
name and she's an individual.
She's not like the Improv.
She's not a part of a giant
corporation when he is,
the shit is great.
I love that lady.
Right?
If you're listening Wendy,
you're the shit.
You are the best.
Fucking tremendous.
And she's got another one.
I had such a good time.
Well Denver is fucking awesome period.
And the paramount was awesome
too and thanks to everybody.
I've always wondered,
this is gonna sound so weird,
but I've always wondered like what?
Like with a building like that with
all that laughter over all those years,
like a wonder and then you take something
terrible like the torture chambers of
like I will gray or something that the
Saddam kept all his people and stuff.
I wonder what the composition of that,
the the walls.
I wonder if there's
anything that permeates,
I mean this hocus pocus bullshit,
but I've always wondered if if in some
ways the material like of the of the
organic material,
like the wood would be a different kind
of composition then in a torture chamber
or something is on there.
All that positive energy versus
all that negative energy.
You know the weird thing
message in the water,
a documentary is that the Japanese game
frogs all bullshit really killed me.
It was all fucking horse shit.
God Damn it.
I looked into,
I was like,
oh,
you guys were lying to me and that movie,
the whole fucking liars who made that.
I know that there's,
there's places like the ice house is a
perfect example that there's been so much
laughter in that place that
it feels good going in.
I don't know if that's my
personal association though.
And it very likely could if you led
me into that place from the outside
blindfolded and I thought I was in a
bakery and you know it's all association
cause my friend,
how about this?
My friends a surfer was
a competitive surfer.
Right.
When when she hears waves for most of us,
waves are like relaxing.
Her heart starts beating really fast.
She gets really nervous.
Yeah,
that totally makes sense.
Waves she gets,
she gets scared and competitive and she,
she can't relax.
She's like,
she's in fight mode cause she knows
that she's about to attack away.
Well you know,
when I was a kid for years I couldn't go
to fights because I didn't like the way
it felt.
That's right.
I got real nervous.
I would like,
I would think that I was supposed
to fight next and I would,
and that it was just a weird part of me.
Like I will try to enjoy it.
But there was like,
until I was like in my thirties until I
had really resolved the fact that it was
no longer going to compete.
You know,
I would get nervous first live event.
It's the first I've ever been
to where I was totally relaxed.
Really.
I would go to UFC.
I,
the reason I don't go to USC,
I can only get tickets
from you and by the way,
congrats it.
Donald Cerrone who came to my standards.
It's exciting.
That motherfucker so well.
He's so awesome.
Whoo.
What a round that.
That was 70 seconds of crazy.
One of my favorite things,
I was doing standup and I,
they came to the comedy works in Denver
and I could see Donald's Ronnie's hat
going up and down laughing at
my jokes and afterward he goes,
dude,
my fucking abs came in fucking ab workout.
Him and Nate Marquardt an underwear model
to study the girls I was with like my
friend's wife and my,
my girl,
they were like looking at,
they were looking at Donald.
They literally like,
like my friend's wives.
They were like,
that guy.
I just want to touch him.
There was an inappropriate around
him because he's a handsome fuck.
Isn't that weird?
When guys wives get creeper dudes
like right in front of them.
When you got an Alpha
male like fucking dog dad.
It's when you have such a disrespectful
relationship that a lot of people engage
in this like over relationship.
Yeah.
Well a lot of people
have that weird own salt.
You,
you'll insult me and you know you
go back and forth a little bit.
It's not,
you're not in each other's corners.
You know,
looking out for each other.
You got a bad relationship
and you're just,
you haven't worked it out
and you're not trying to,
he just stuck in this little
fucking ins and they're round,
man,
they'll grow up on you.
I will take pictures and squeeze.
My hand was coming up to me.
Go on.
I want to talk to him and say hi to him.
I want to meet him.
I'm like,
your husband is right there.
She's like,
look at his ass,
his ass.
They were like levered.
They were all over.
All those kicks that he throws
that he is,
that he is fucking ready.
That was holy Shit.
That was a crazy fight and it was right
when I had just got done saying that he
has to be very carefully,
can't get overconfident because Melvin
can fuck you up with one punch and then
oh so explosive.
Oh my God,
I left Hook.
Melvin landed too.
That could,
and Donald kept it together
cause he got find out,
you said when will you,
when were you okay after that punch.
And he goes,
yeah,
he was not okay.
And he's still through the kick.
See that's how confident
he is in his ground games.
One of the things about Serone,
I love that he'll fucking
let those kicks fly man.
Cause if you take him down,
man,
it's,
chances are he's going to
threaten you from the bottom.
He doesn't get grounded pounded now.
And he threatens dude's
when triangle arm bars.
He's not just long,
he goes for it man.
He attacks the attacks
on the ground so he,
he's not holding back.
So he's willing to throw even after
getting tagged light to that way still
throws a head kick.
But 55 is so I want to
see him fight Jose Aldo.
It's great as if to five we'll,
although is most likely going
to move to 55 eventually,
he's still young.
That's only 25 and he's having
a hard time making weight,
although he's had a less of a hard time
of it lately because he cut back on the
weightlifting [inaudible] weightlifting.
He was a bulking up in between,
you know,
uh,
fights and putting on mass and then the
cut was harder for 55 is just a division
of killers.
Well,
so it's 45,
man,
it's already five shit.
Every and every weight class is growing,
you know,
like 35 is growing now.
There's this like,
there's this Eric Perez Kid.
Therefore this weekend there's like,
it's constant.
This,
uh,
there's so many fucking good fighters,
man.
It's the,
the,
the whole like division,
like the whole UFC,
like every single division is expanding
and getting deeper and deeper and
deeper.
The heavyweight division is getting
deeper and deeper and deeper.
They're going to have Cain Velasquez
vs junior dos Santos on New Year's Eve.
Really?
Didn't they?
Fuck ass dude.
It's going to be on the 29th and the
30th day going to have a rematch.
You have to,
Cain destroyed bigfoot.
Cain just ran through big foot Silva.
Just cut them up the last
of them on the ground.
That's not,
that's such a good,
oh,
I'm glad I'm not a fighter man.
That's just every time
you step in that octagon,
you're going to war.
This is what we talked about earlier.
It's,
it has to be what you really want to do
and has to be what you're really driven
to do.
It has to be your calling
and if it's not your calling,
you better get the fuck out of there
because there's a guy like junior dos
Santos near the end of the
ring and it is his calling.
What Anderson Silva steps in that cage.
He doesn't wish she was
in a fucking Marajhi band,
no Mariachi,
whatever.
He says,
he's ready to fuck you up.
That's what he's there for.
That's what he does.
He's not supposed to
be doing anything else,
you know,
and the,
the margin for error now is
so small with these guys.
They're so good.
Some of these guys,
the level is insane and the levels
increasing constantly between,
um,
when I was watching the speed difference
between Serone and Gallard and the
fights before was astronomical.
They were both throwing hay makers,
you know,
and that is part of it is that
they were throwing the kids,
they knew each other very well.
I can't believe God went
down there and it was so,
it's such a vicious thing.
He was really bad.
Well Donald hit him absolutely perfectly.
He climbed them with the
left Shin to the head.
He likes that left high
kick with the switch.
He throws that so well to the head man.
It's such a powerful shot.
A lot of guys don't throw it that hard.
So there's dude's that
stand there and they,
and they'll take one
of those on the gloves,
you know,
they'll kind of like
recognize that it's coming,
but they'll still try to avoid it.
Instead try to try to move like
you can't do it to Anderson.
Like you try it.
Like rich Franklin tried
the high switch crack on.
I understand innocent season coming
knows what you're going to do.
And just bans and slides off his
shoulder and he looks right at me.
Your tricks,
he's the fucking matrix is incredible.
But Serone he's got so much
power in it and he's so,
he's got so,
so much dexterity with his legs.
It just calling,
it just come.
It's almost like,
it's shocking how quick it guests.
They're so confident in this phone man.
And he was very confident and
in the right hand he laughed.
It landed afterwards was just a bomb.
It was just pinpoint.
It was like boom.
It was like flying at him.
All his power directly on the jaw.
And that was the knock next.
Uh,
Nate does.
Nate Diaz does.
Oh boy.
That's going to be incredible.
I love,
yeah.
Well that was a tough fight,
man,
that a lot of people thought
Frankie Edgar won that fight.
Almost unanimously.
The professionals on Twitter thought
that he wanted that time at that.
He's the toughest small guy in the world.
Fred gaggers a motherfucker,
dude,
I,
you know,
look,
I thought he won the fight
afterwards by decision,
but it was,
it w I would have to honestly
go back and watch it again and,
and,
and score it with my mouth shut to make
an accurate assessment of whether or not
my feelings after the
fight or over or accurate.
You know,
I think I'm really careful about saying
what I think when it's real close fight
like that until I actually sit down
and watch it as if I was scoring it.
Because if you're watching
it as a commentator,
you're also involved in it.
You're trying to be entertaining,
you know,
I'm trying to like explain what's going
on and I don't have to like in order to
do that and do like a really effective
calculation of whether or not one person,
one or the other,
especially when it's close because it was,
the fight unquestionably was close.
There's no doubt about it.
It was a very close fight.
No doubt about it.
The people thought Henderson
wanted agree with that.
The people who've thought
Edgar wanted agree with that.
It was a tightly contested fight.
So to really watch that and judge it,
you got to really shut your fucking
mouth and sitting there with a pad,
another game,
and you've got to mark things down.
And if you had the best would be if the
judges had access to the information
that Goldie and I have access to,
like we have access to all the takedown,
like the end of the round [inaudible]
thing that comes up fairly recently in the
last few fights.
Who Screen?
Who Does it?
It's UFC staff.
So the production staff,
it's catching everything.
They're counting strikes and
there there's a whole like,
you know,
segment of the show where
they'll go to effective strikes,
take down attempts,
submission attempts.
So we get to look at hard numbers as well
as like our gut feeling about things.
Like there's sometimes a guy will land
like little pitty pat shots in Atlanta,
a bunch of them,
but the other dude lands one haymaker.
Well that haymaker is worth
more than those pitty pat shots.
So sometimes numbers
don't necessarily mean,
but it's good to have that information
to add in addition to your calculations
on how you feel about it.
Just watching it.
Right.
So you need almost more than
you watching it on your own.
Because I'm not just watching it,
I'm getting fed information
as I'm watching it.
That's ideal for a judge.
Not that it would really,
you know,
I just,
not that it wouldn't help to clean house
and just get people in and know what
the fuck is going on in an actual fight.
That certainly would be,
but I also think they need access
to information the way we have.
They finally gave them
monitors to get monitors now,
which is very nice surprise.
They finally gave it.
Yeah.
Not Everywhere,
but we've done it in certain places.
Emotion would strike very important.
Very important as well as
to have angles on shots.
You know,
there's sometimes it looks like a
guy landed when really the guy fell,
the guy slips.
You know,
there's,
there's all sorts of weird jobs.
No,
it's not.
It's very hard and it's not
rewarded when they're good at it.
No,
it's the only critique
when they suck at it.
You know,
I'm,
I swear to God man,
when,
when I have a weekend,
like this weekend where we did the
show at the paramount and we did the,
the comedy works in Denver,
uh,
meet all these cool people and everything.
It really does feel like this
crazy fucking dream life,
man.
It's so fun.
Everything is so fun.
You've earned it and you've created,
nobody earns this dude.
Nobody deserves this.
This is some crazy lucky shit.
It ain't just that you earned it
because it didn't even exist before.
It's not like you say you
earn being the commentator,
but you know what I'm saying.
Before it,
before I was the commentator,
the other people had done it.
But I'm saying before,
when I was a young man thinking
about this as an aspiration,
this job didn't even exist.
You know,
like that's just,
I remember when you got it,
that's like,
Hey,
I'm,
I'm going to do the UFC.
And I came down with you and
I met tank Abbott back cheese.
It's so fortunate though.
It's ridiculous.
Yeah.
Jeff,
that great guy,
great guy,
love that guy.
Olympic gold medal.
And it's so,
it's so strange to have
like that kind of a life,
you know?
It's so strange to have all these cool
friends and to like how this dream
weekend,
I remember when you were all
hanging around you and me
and Joey Diaz and Brendan
Walsh and Doug Benson,
we were eating after the show,
after the UFC.
We were last making good wine,
drinking good wine and eating sliders
in buffalo wings and just killing it.
All of us laughing at each other.
I mean that's like,
we're so fucking fortunate,
man.
That's what,
that's what that was.
So foreign message.
They're like,
we're so lucky we get to do what we do.
We're so fortunate in every aspect
in the friends that we have in our
occupations and you know,
it's,
it's completely amazing.
But to,
to do what we did to get like this,
this posse of comedians
together for that show,
like at the paramount
that is really important.
And it's one of the things that we were
talking about before you got there.
I was telling them like I was thanking
them for coming and I was like,
you guys,
like there might be 2000
people out there for this show,
but if you guys weren't with me,
it wouldn't be half as fun because you
really wouldn't even be 50% of have a
fraternity.
You can share it with.
You know,
I love watching Joey Diaz get off
stage with a giant smile on his face.
Just laughing his ass off.
I five and so authentic and original.
We had some really good talks
and he's the best listener I've,
I'd love.
But I'll say I'm going to go anywhere
at least 10 minutes to get out of the
supposed to be there and have,
they can suck it up because they're mine.
They're mine.
But it's the 10 minute podcast.
I guess that's not a good show.
I know,
but I gotta I gotta know it's actually,
you know,
wait,
they're going to buy them.
I go to go to 10 minute
podcasts and listen to drunk
Arnold that well Sasa does.
If you don't laugh your ass off.
To me,
it's the best impression of all time.
And it's the funniest
thing I've ever done.
It's a funny one because Arnold is like,
I don't,
I hardly do my own
oppression in the morning.
How many people do,
Arnold is so fucking hilarious.
We have some,
I'm really proud of some of
the things we did on that show.
I mean,
I like the idea.
It's great idea.
Great.
10 minutes.
Do some fucking characters on there.
Forget me.
I did an ostrich expert,
but that doesn't matter.
Uh,
it's,
it's some of the funny shit.
I got to go.
It's an ostrich.
Hi,
my name is,
uh,
Ooh,
she won't do the,
and the ostrich.
Uh,
my,
my specialty and the good question is,
if an ostrich is a bird,
why can he not?
And that's all I talk about.
This is what we need to work with you.
We need to get hit,
not total Alondra with you together with
your Brazilian Jujitsu character and
make something happen because
that rapist character is,
there's two of the funniest moments in
my life that I've experienced in my whole
life.
One of them is Joey Diaz on the Alex
Jones show or Joe or they fucked up and
told Joey Diaz that he didn't have to
worry about swearing because this part is
on the Internet and Joey Diaz has opened
up a can of whoop ass on the he he it
was,
he was telling a story about going
through the TSA with weed tucked under his
balls and about how
those fucking machines,
they don't scan shit and you know this
is your fucking tax dollars at work and
the Alex Jones is going crazy.
He goes check yourself
before you wreck yourself.
Big Dixon.
Yes it's bad for your help.
Joel Diaz,
Facebook,
Twitter,
stay black.
And he and he leaves when he
literally wrecked the room.
I'm crying laughing and it's,
and by the way,
we got it all on video,
it's all,
you know,
I got to see the people
that say I'm exaggerating,
it's all online.
Joey Diaz and the Alex Jones show is a
hundred versions of it on youtube cause
it's so phenomenal to see this.
There was that and there was you in the
hotel room when we were high as fuck.
And I don't even think,
I think I just got the job of the UFC and
we would all come out to the fight and
it was,
it's so fucking great guys event.
I mean so barbaric and
men to go to fucking jail.
How'd you see that fight?
Always shook.
I was crazy.
And afterwards we eat steaks and shit.
It was just such a a boy party for you.
And I actually went and looked
at Randy couture and we're like,
look at him,
look at it and be fucking animal.
He had a swollen knee.
I was like,
Gee,
you were upstairs.
And we were barbecued.
We were so high.
And you know,
we just have this group of really
funny people hanging out together.
So we're just making sure that lab and
Brian goes into this explanation like a
Jujitsu seminar and had a fuck guys
basically doing hands on because I was
training at [inaudible] says,
and of course I have nothing
but respect for hence all.
Of course he was just the character,
you know.
And come on guys.
Okay.
Like that.
You know,
when I'd take a guy,
they got a guy like that put
them into the math like that,
eh,
there was like the way the,
the all the parts of your speech
or I don't know where it is,
but any Bravo's video,
but it was like a window like you,
you had,
it was like one of those things.
He put it on his video but he put
it on there as a fortune cookie.
You know what I'm talking
about is I have been a calm,
we have to find it,
whatever.
So he put it on there I think.
Is that what's called the fortune cookie?
Whatever the fuck it's called,
when,
um,
when someone puts something
on their DVD and you,
you know,
you go and find it.
So he put on there like you had to press
like a couple of different things for
it to come up.
It was one of those stupid things that
people did before they realized that
extra content you should let people
want that people are watching.
And so Eddie had that.
He thought it would be really funny and
I also think he was worried about it was
so dirty like connecting it to his thing.
I think he would do it now because like
on a mastering the system you gotta be
careful when you're building a brand
or whatever and if you're interested in
that,
go to 10th Planet Jiu jitsu.com Cause
Eddie's got this whole web series called
mastering the system and a lot
of that is with [inaudible].
Raja,
who is this?
I don't want to tell you the whole story
because I don't want to give up the
joke.
What we'll do it but you got to get
together with him and we'll do it.
I'm coming back on a podcast
teach guys how to get this.
Guys,
I want to thank you guys.
Fuck yeah man.
You come out on the
podcast anytime you want.
I'll do extra ones for you if I'm,
if I have a full week,
we'll do one at night.
Always do it anytime you want man.
I'm sorry I have to leave early today.
It's no worries.
Thank you everybody.
You should tell those guys to
fuck themselves and stay here.
Twitter while are,
we're on the Internet now at
Brian Calley good as we do R,
B r y a.
We are doing it now.
It's a game for me.
I love you.
Don't mean I gotta get him my commercial,
but I can't.
I've got to let you out of the house,
man.
This he fucking,
I love you.
Animals out the security.
Hold on,
let me,
let me end this.
Alright,
this podcasts over.
Ladies and gentlemen,
go see Brian this weekend in San Diego
at the American comedy company and go to
the American comedy company.
Support it.
It's great that San Diego finally got a
real fucking comedy club and it is a bad
ass one.
Thank you to a Alienware MMA.
Follow them on Twitter Alienware and
then they on Twitter Alienware sponsors
through sucker punch entertainment,
a lot of fighters.
And um,
they uh,
we really appreciate the shit out of that.
So we started using Alienware computers
for all of our podcasts and if you're
into gaming,
they're fucking fantastic.
They're really awesome.
They sent us this 18 inch laptop
and it's fucking tremendous.
It's,
it's,
if you want to play games on them,
they're,
they're like the,
the graphics,
the speed.
They're really incredible.
They're pricey,
but they're,
they're really worth it there.
They're incredible gaming computers and
we thank them for supporting us because,
uh,
we,
we love the fact they
hooked us up with computers.
We loved them as a company and we love
the fact that they support MMA fighters.
We think it's a ballsy move.
And I really appreciate
the fact that Dell,
a big company has the
guts through Alienware.
They're there,
which they own to step
in and sponsor fighters.
I think that's beautiful.
And so we support people
who support him in May.
Uh,
thanks to [inaudible] dot com as well.
Go get yourself some battle
ropes and kettlebells.
So you could be manly.
Like Brian Cowlick may throw
that rope around bitch stuff,
a dancer's physique.
I love your brain.
Feed your brain with
some nutrients and uh,
get your shit together.
You dirty bitches.
Look,
we love you.
We appreciate the podcast tweets
and emails and all that Shit.
It literally,
my life would not be as rich and
interesting if it wasn't for how,
how,
how much positive energy we've
gotten back from you people,
how much that is inspirational,
how much that makes us want to
do more and make it better and,
and put out more content.
And I appreciate the fuck that all you
guys are using this podcast to make your
commute more interesting to
entertain you when you're on a plane,
you know,
whatever the fuck you're using
it for when you're at the gym.
I think it's awesome.
I love the connection that we have and uh,
thank you for all the positivity.
It's,
it,
it inspires me to no end and that's it.
You dirty freaks.
Tomorrow we will have Jamie
Kilstein on my favorite,
well not my favorite Vegan,
he's one of my favorite vegans.
He's my favorite Vegan lefty comedian.
The weighs eight pounds.
He's a great car though.
And he's a very smart guy and he
has us besides his strange ideology,
he's got his heart in the right place.
He's a good human and
he'll be here tomorrow.
And then we have Andrew
dice clay on Wednesday.
On Thursday we have,
uh,
we have two podcasts on Thursday.
You'll even,
you dirty bitch,
you can find them on Twitter.
I got to go.
All right.
Take care of people.
Big Kiss.
Love Ya.