The Joe Rogan experience
and [inaudible] was the guy,
Rick Ross was the fucking guy who is in
charge of all that shit in Los Angeles
and well, it's your audience.
So they already know. I
don't have to qualify that.
It's not the rapper who stole his
identity. Isn't that crazy? It's crazy.
Dog 50 cent did the same thing just
in his drug dealer's dead. Yeah.
50 cent is a famous famous drug dealer
in New York. No, yes, absolutely.
Yes. Yes. No Shit. Well,
Jay Z is a guy named Jasso
Wright who was a hood jazz. Oh,
I think that would be coming from him.
His partner,
like there used to be a rapper Jasso and
Jay z was his DJ way back in the day.
Oh, see, I had thought it
was that jazzed about this.
They were healing and whatnot back then.
Now W I'm not hip to that part,
but they had a hit like jazz. Oh, had
a song way back call Hawaii, Hawaiian,
Sophie Hawaiian big. At the time it was
like for the era, it was a hit for sure.
He was supposed to be a really good
rapper. He wasn't, he's still probably is.
There's a lot of guys that have
slipped through the cracks at people.
I mean Kool g rap.
I'm sure Jay even at this point
would acknowledge that, you know,
some of his beginnings come from
Jazz. Those styles of, of rap. Well,
everybody gets influenced by somebody
else. Absolutely. Everybody. I mean,
I always give up the, uh, my influences,
Boston comedians Kennison like without
all those people that I was [inaudible]
is actually,
you know,
that song ain't no Nigga like the one
I got Yazzie he's things I believe he's
the guy singing in the hook.
No one can do it better if he's not the
guy actually singing it in the video.
That's him really big. Daddy
Kane, he's still around, man.
He's doing yo big daddy Kane ain't making
records. But I'll tell you like this,
as far as rap shows go,
I guarantee you he's still putting on
one of the best rap shows around the old
classic. So as long as classic, right.
It's like he still has his dancers.
They have,
they do like a classic,
like I would call it like almost like a
Vegas if there was a hip hop Vegas act
kind of thing. It's kind of
that, but not cheesy in any way.
But like there's a classic classic
cavity and then a word to it,
like the two dancers.
It's like an era.
He represents it and it's a
great show too. How about EPMD?
That's another band you don't
hear about anymore. Yeah,
well they had a lot of internal problems
and broke up and got back together and
broke up.
Yeah.
I liked EPMD first of all because whenever
the do amazing out ass rapper and all
sides of speech impediment and
as a bad [inaudible]. Yeah,
he's got a lisp and just spitting dope
rhymes with no apologies for his list.
No, you know and, and it's good dude. Well
the first one to do that was Kool g rap.
Kool g rap is great. Kool
g rap. He had the craziest,
the craziest lists of all his,
he had a crazy list man.
Michael Blue plays lists. That's the
best because it's every single song.
He talks like this and open the Anthony
[inaudible] does all the standards and
stuff. Yeah. Yeah. Pull up a Kool g rap,
pull up, talk like sex, pull up, cock
blocking. That's one of my favorite ones.
Pull up Kool g rap,
cock blocking.
He's got a great song about trying
to bang this chicken, her son,
his cock blocking.
I'll also to remember that.
I remember dude,
Kool g rap was one of my favorites.
Something. He just fell off.
I don't know what happened. You know,
it's like one of them things. It's just,
it was an error in it, you know? Yeah.
But he was hot. It's like one of the,
it's a youth sport, you know what I
mean? That's what I try to tell me.
Why did you, why you ain't rapping
like you? So I still run my,
put it into my songs. I'm
working into what I do. My,
my version of hip hop and stuff.
It's like, but to chase the,
the adoration of the youth
that buys hip hop right now.
Is it a ridiculous for me, cause
I'm a 44 year old man. It's cool.
G rap and Dj Polo got operations to song.
It's called operations cost.
The USA operation,
CB cock blocking this action
usually results in broken friends
is this is where the SS
brings back memories.
This is great.
This is Debbie. Debbie, great song man.
This dude is like one
of the revolutionaries
style in rap,
like Kool g rap care,
one in big daddy Kane really
changed rep and Chuck d those folks.
Cause before that it was like the run
DMC thought that a pop pop, pop, pop.
My boss kind of just straight cadences
and these guys all had different,
these different styles that they started
working in and that's where a lot of
how everybody else started branching out
and realizing like there was more than
one way to rhyme and one way to rap
like Kool g rap, big Daddy Kane,
krs one and Chuck d that they,
they're the ones,
they're the forefathers of everything
that goes on lyrically. Now I,
I agree and I feel like there's,
there's something missing on a lot of
people want to do this sort of, uh, this,
this hip hop hip hop has changed and a
lot of ways today where there's a lot of
stuff that they're calling hip hop that
almost seems like dance music to me.
What it is, it's hip hop has been,
you know, it's been co opted man
by the money. You know what I mean?
The money there was,
there was money around back when
these songs were being made,
but it wasn't ridiculous money that could,
it wasn't millions and billions.
It was thousands.
You know what I mean?
Is like we were getting thousands of
dollars back in the day thinking like
bawling, man, I got a Nissan Sentra and a
gold rope. Melissa, worst shit you bought.
What's the first shit you bought
when you started getting paid?
Like a gold chain from the
Sloss and swap meet four techs.
Bong for ticks bomb. What's that? Remember
the bongs, the vortex bongs with that,
you had that, a tattoo of the vortex
clown or the graphics, I'm sorry,
graphics, graphics clown. It's
just a, I still have that.
I drew that when I was like 21 yeah,
reminded me of it. It looks like Eddie.
It's so old now. It's fleeting. Like
Eddie's face. While I'm on hat on,
I'm going to get Aaron Dellavedova to
think, finish the Musashi and fit it.
Figure out what to put at the top of that.
He's the same guy has
done both of my arms.
I just got to get this bitch lasered off.
It's dice. You can go over that. She,
I don't want it though. He prefers not
to. Aaron likes to have a clean slate.
He's a perfectionist.
He doesn't like to have to draw some
shit that he doesn't want to draw just
because there's some old ink
there. He's like, it's no big deal.
Just get it lasered a couple of
times. He's like, it's pretty old.
It'll get off pretty quick. Then you
wait three months and then get to work.
I just have to design or rather come
up with the idea and sent it to him.
Whatever my idea is and he'll design
with the top is you've got to figure out
what to do. Check out this, this, this is
what opie and Anthony was talking about.
The Michael Pupil a list.
You can keep that fucking song going on
in the background and make bublé sound
tolerable, but it's, it's ridiculous.
This is Jake's Dukes is a Debbie my man.
So I got this,
listen
[inaudible] I got that
string around [inaudible]
beautiful love youtube for this. You know
what I think probably are we going to,
because we have that
clip on there. No. Um,
it doesn't seem like, no, it does.
You know what I, I'm just thinking,
I think opie and Anthony got sent a
fake audio file cause they like broke it
down and they have an always on the
replays. It's Kinda se, but yeah, no,
the one that Kool g rap
says say puck like thick.
I don't hear that. That's weird.
You got to hear more of a song.
I'll tell you the PMD,
but he made correctly.
You got to understand he made him and Eric
sermon or comparable. Really? Wow. Yeah.
That's interesting.
I think Eric sermon put it on a little
bit more though because Kool g rap,
like I think there was Kool g rap was
before that really? You know shit.
I'm not saying he made up,
that's the thing.
I just think he let it
go a little bit more.
Whereas Kool g rap might've worked to
like try to not have it as bad when he was
recording. Kool g rap is one of my all
time favorite sermon. Just let it go.
You said I got a lift and if what's
going to be, I'm a big fan of axiom.
Maya, let your conscience be free
and get Dan to the fans of the p.
Let me hear it. Hear it. See Land,
go take a nap and watch the
show. Why? Because right now
the ICPA is my name.
It's got too much tongue
until next lips struggling.
I just get dad and I go check
one, two. That was the jam.
No there at the terminal.
[inaudible] was one of the best.
He's another one that these young
kids don't, they don't respect enough.
Rakim follow the leader.
Oh he was the gun goes off my list.
You know I actually passed it.
That's one that was missing off that list.
He was fifth. Yes. He should have
been on that, that's for sure.
I totally spaced on him.
We just did three hours.
He is like there is no Nas without rock
camp here and nods would definitely
agree to that.
He,
he is definitely one of the
fathers of remodeled lyricists.
You got me turned on and nods and rewind
and that's one of my favorite songs.
It's brilliant. Right.
The way he set it up,
going from the bullet back into the gun,
the whole thing taking the the events
and re plan one rank record, right? Yeah.
Mike and all that. It's like, Oh
man, you got some good shit man.
He knows has some good shit. Stillmatic
was that the name of that album?
It's still magic. The first
album, his album is universally,
the first album is universally recognized
as one of the great albums. Nomadic.
Yeah. He went through a period where
stuff wasn't nearly as good for a while.
It was interesting, but what
happened with him? I think the,
the feud with him and Jay z like sort
of inspired him to get better because JC
called some of his shit garbage and
like, you know, Nas was like, Whoa, wait,
you know,
they have this thing back and forth and
then they got together and they were
selling was ridiculous. Yeah. The
ether was but uh, he went after,
I just think nas was doing things and
got, you know, he made some money.
You got to remember he made that first
album when he was like 17 or something
man.
Like oh classic all time for ages
album at 17 or 18 years old tops.
When he was on his first record,
main source,
I think he was like 16 or 15 and
he like destroyed everybody on it.
Yeah. Live at the barbeque.
Huh? When I was 12,
I went to hell for snuffin Jesus.
Yeah. He has some of the greatest lyrics
of all time. Some of the greatest,
most thought provoking lyrics of all time.
That whole first album and many
albums of his sentence were great,
but that first one was just dumb.
It's like when you capture it in the can,
that lightening and you got,
you know, all of it's perfect.
Now that Alpha is damn near.
Perfect. Did you ever seen the one,
there's one album that is not universally
thought of as being one of his best,
but the one with him, with the,
uh, the Sphinx face. What does it,
what does it like some sort of
Egyptian motor, another one with a,
you could hate me know and all that on
there. I don't remember. I don't know.
Album names is wills. I know the song.
He's got a song on it called, um, there's,
there's welcome to the new world is one
of my favorite nas songs that nobody
ever talks about. And it's him talking
about, let me see. Let me find his,
um, his Wikipedia here. It's,
it's a song you never hear people talk
about, but it's him talking about the vet.
It was written. It might be, it might
be that. I think you might be right.
Let me see here. I am, see if you
can find Brian. See we'll, we'll,
we'll end with this. How much time we
got left. Seven minutes. Seven minutes.
You're on a time. There's now
three hours return to a pumpkin.
We only have three hours. Three hours.
The recordings over play a place.
Some of I can remember we went
longer than three hours. Dude,
we've crushed it today. Today we
went with, we've accelerated time.
We made three hours. Seemed like
two hours. I thought he was wrong.
I like road the road. Is that
song? No, no, no, no, no.
It's called a welcome to the new world.
Welcome to the new world.
Welcome to the new road. Do you
find it go out on some nausea? Yeah.
Listen to this shit cause this is like
back when Roy Jones Jr was the baddest
motherfucker on earth.
This is like some,
I think it was like the nineties I
want to say nineties does this nineties
but it's about technology in the future
and like where, where were the way that,
I think I know the song you're talking
about but I have to hear to be refreshed.
It's really interesting because,
um,
it's on Sanford [inaudible] is in the era
when like he was going with production
that I think more the labels and stuff
we're looking for that pop appeal.
I think he wasn't picking his beats
wisely in this little era that he got.
I think that's when only time
he got slowed down as well.
I think some long choices were made,
I don't think had anything to do
with his stuff or his lyricism. Yeah.
See this is like, I've never been a fan
of outright ripping old songs like this.
Right. I've never been a fan of it. I mean
if you do it collaboratively and like,
like there's, there's producers
like guy like DJ premier,
they would take something like that and
chop it up into smaller pieces and turn
it into something new.
I'm a fan of that.
But when you just take an entire riff
and like recreate it and kind of almost
copy the song,
but just make it into a wrap,
like versus with like even
steal their hooks. Right.
Did I think pocketed it with like Bruce
Hornsby's just the way it is? Yeah.
I've never been a fan of those things.
That's been not,
that's probably why that song wasn't
so prevalent in my mind. I, yeah,
I'm a real big fan of what he's
saying in it. It's fantastic,
but I agree with you. It's not the best
B. It's kind of annoying. Listened to,
there was a little era
his where we got to,
the production got to clean for me like
I'm not, I should be on a grimy ass.
Yeah.
I mean once he came back,
we eat there and then he came back with
the where he chopped up Apache for that
made you look at your dad's where he
should be saying, you know what I mean?
Like I think the record labels and people
got to them and radio and the success
you want when you're young and you
first get success, you want to,
you're listening to the people around you
and they're telling you you got a copy
of that to keep getting your success
and you become either one or two things.
You know,
a guy that Oban that just makes that
formulaic album every time and you'll have
some success for awhile or you
fall off the face of the planet,
you know what I mean?
Or you go back to what you know and be
the genius you are and don't trust what
everybody else was saying
and trust your guts. And Nas,
I'm sure even knew he
needed to be on to be,
he's backway CHIBE he's been there for a
minute now. Yeah, he's back completely.
His last few cds were fantastic.
Solutely yeah, he's, it's ether.
I think I've been enjoying ever since.
I think you're right about,
I think Jay z definitely sparked some
fire under his ass for sure. Yeah.
I think when someone calls you garbage,
just go,
well there's a lot more sad than that.
I don't know how close you
could pay attention you paid,
but there's a lot of things about people's
babies. Mom was getting fucked up,
like, you know, like Jay even
apologized on radio in New York.
There's a lot of like hip hop,
little folklore around that is his Jay's
mom supposedly made him go on the air
and apologize for some of these.
Oh,
there's a lot of that going around and
there was a lot more than just a wraps
going on.
But it kind of goes back to what we
were talking about earlier that you said
that you need to produce.
So you need someone to argue with
sometimes the guy as good as Nas,
she challenges me. Yeah. Like Yo, it'd
be that's not as good as it could be.
Or maybe that's not the right
choice for that song. And,
and the way I've always looked at it as
if I was passionate enough about it and
it was opposed to be in there,
I would fight for it. Right.
But if you brought it up and I even
questioned him for a thing second,
take it in and say maybe then May,
than it deserves to be
mold over and thought about
[inaudible].