We live in a sheep fucking society today.
We're all trying to be the same person.
If you look around,
we're all looking the same.
When you go to silver lake and you get
on stage and look at the people in the
80% of people look the same.
They all got the same fucking glasses,
the same tight jeans, the same
fat tool. It's the Chinese side.
Everybody's wanting to meet
up month and every bodies,
you know, you wake up in the morning,
walk into a studio for an audition.
What does everybody have in front
of them? A couple of what? Fuck.
Book Starbuck and if
you ain't got Starbucks,
you weren't invited to the
fucking party and it's not coffee.
Everybody got coffee. It's the status
of going to Starbucks. Oh my God.
Oh my God. When we were growing up
in Boston, a where you lived at,
your grandfather's in newer people have
a little fucking blue cup that's in
coffee and went to a diner and
you said, give me a, what was the,
what was it called? Regularly? Yeah,
but we didn't carry the
coffee cups like a Budweiser.
It's like when you go out and make
you take a picture with somebody,
what do they always got their head?
Let's put the bolts on.
They could tell I'm drinking. What the
fuck? What the beat down your fuck.
Same thing with coffee.
That society.
Everybody wants to fucking be cool
and drink that and fucking coffee.
You ever had someone look at your copy in
the woods at fucking coffee bean? What?
You can afford Starbucks, Bro.
Yo, step up. No Starbucks.
Why would you want doughnuts, Bro?
Why would you wait on that line?
Listen to that Brazilian bold.
We'll keep you up to three days.
That's what isis drinks. Don't be
my pocket with the cases. Drinks,
coffee. Fuck. Do they drink fucking
you ever drink resilient?
Both on fucking Dunkin donuts.
You can donuts for everybody
that pays
me by Alex and anti fungus
and get fat fucking bolt and come
back and say that's liquid slugging.
Daddy. Fuck you. Don't
let's I agree with Shit.