The joe rogan experience,
what are the other things that are of
concern to you as a congresswoman that
you're seeing not addressed or that are
somehow or another still in place when
you feel like they should have?
Then?
You know,
there's,
there's a long laundry list of issues
and I think you can go through each of
the major issues that a lot of folks are
concerned about and pick those apart and
say,
hey,
here are the things that we need to
address and improve in each of those.
But I think that the conversation that I
hope more people start having is about
how w why aren't these things being
fixed or addressed.
And that that speaks directly to,
um,
people's unwillingness to actually talk
to each other,
to stop demonizing each other because
you're from the other camp and actually
engage based on our common mission of
serving the people,
serving the people of this country.
And,
you know,
that's something I look back to during
my time,
uh,
in uniform serving the whole army
national guard.
You've got diverse people,
diverse opinions,
diverse ideas,
but ultimately,
you know,
we were the same flag on our uniform and
we are focused singularly on,
on that same purpose and mission.
And unfortunately that's what we're
missing a lot of in Congress's,
the hyper partisanship and the political
winds to often take precedence over,
um,
the reason why people in our districts
hire us to go and work there.
And a lot of that comes from not having
a basic level of respect or Aloha for
each other as people.
And instead just saying,
hey,
it's us against them.
Pick your label.
And that's where the battles are fought
and end.
Who suffers as a result of this?
The people who are suffering,
who are dealing with a lot of the
challenges that we've been talking
about.
So that's something that,
you know,
I try to bring,
I try to bring Hawaii,
zillow hot to Washington,
uh,
and try to bring that through in the
work that I'm trying to do on these
different issues in the conversations
that we're having.
Sometimes it means you talk with people
who,
who you disagree with,
or you may have different ideas,
uh,
than they have about how you solve these
problems.
But if even if you're able to come
together on one thing,
then we can start to see problems
actually being solved and,
and delivering results.
I don't know.
But he made sure I went to the place
that they broke.
You see,
Huntington was designed as the prison.
If he raped another inmate,
they sent you there.
It was the first shoe program in
America.
It was the first [inaudible].
What does shoe program?
A special housing unit or security
housing unit were level five.
Supermax,
you know,
like Pelican Bay.
And,
uh,
your punishment was that you weren't
allowed to speak in your cell.
And if you got caught speaking in
yourself,
they came in with a nurse and they,
after they beat you down,
she jabbed you in the ass with thorazine
and they knocked you off for a week and
you lost your mind.
So it was horrible.
Like I told the first two years of my
sentence,
every day I kept my mouth shut.
I didn't care what was done around Muna.
You weren't allowed to say a God damn
word and a minute and you're not allowed
to talk to other inmates.
Nothing.
I dare you to sing happy birthday to
yourself like I did.
I paid for that one.
They fucked me up too.
But I don't care about that.
Look,
I realized I was in a race.
I had to kill off the person that I was.
The person that I initially was upon
entering prison was a deceitful,
lying,
coward,
but no fortitude because no self respect
resided within me.
And in utter humbleness,
I took everything that they did to me
and I paid for every window.
I broke everything.
I stole,
rely auto,
and then I started to love myself.
I figured I ain't getting nothing out of
this but misery.
So I'm going out like the dude,
I'm a stand up and I'm gonna speak
beautifully on the daily to execute me.
I'm a walk to that walk,
man.
I'm a dude,
is I didn't kill that woman,
but I damn sure ain't no coward.
I'm going to find out everything I can
about life.
And then I'm gonna face my death.
I'm a do it.
[inaudible] like I had this beautiful,
beautiful speech ready for him to us
going to lay it out and just be at peace
because I realized there was nothing
else to do.
I could fight.
I couldn't argue.
It didn't matter because God's in
control of my life and I really believed
that I had a choice,
either be a bitter pill and get sucked
dry by all the misery of mountain me or
get my shit right and start loving
myself.
And then when I'm out of fight camp
since like,
cause sometimes when you watch a tape in
fight camp,
like you can mess with people's heads,
you know,
like the maybe maybe cal was getting too
nervous and then when he's white gives
him anxiety to watch the fight.
You know,
so you need to have a,
if that's the case,
you know,
have a coach that's willing to,
that you trust to do that for you.
That's a good point.
Now cause let me do it.
It's a mental,
this fucking sports,
a mental mind.
Fuck man.
Yeah of course.
Whatever works the best for you.
Is that what you got to figure out?
Is it better for you to fight someone
like cody that you have all this
animosity and beef towards and all the
shit talking cause you get super hyped
up and motivated every day?
Or is it better to fight someone who you
have a lot of respect for was just a
good challenge?
I think you've got to learn to live,
like to be the same person for every
fight.
I think it's like control those
emotions.
You know,
even if there was all that coming in,
like I'm nervous to fight,
you know,
like forget all the bullshit,
you know?
And I had to learn that through my
career.
I had to learn to take emotion out of
it.
I mean,
even in sparring still,
you know,
like join the,
he's telling me control my emotion,
a controlled aggression,
you know,
cause you hit me,
I want to hit you back.
I'm very competitive.
So it's something you have to learn how
to control.
And I've had to do that throughout my
career.
Um,
and I think everyone has learned to
control either to let go or to pull
back,
you know,
like really control that emotion to be
the same person every fight,
you know?
Um,
mentally,
not the same person every five and
mentally in your own head,
the same person,
but technically need to be able to
switch it up.
That the mental aspect of it is probably
the thing that holds more people back
then.
Anything like we all know of guys that
are just monsters in the gym and for
whatever it was when they would go to
compete,
they just could never be their full
self.
Yeah.
Tj does better in the cage.
Yeah,
it does.
In the gym.
Yeah.
I did better in the,
in the gym then in the cage.
What do you think it is
that makes you do better?
I love it.
I don't know.
I mean I've just taught myself to love
this shit.
Like I'm,
I'm like,
I don't know when I get out there it's
just like I want to be there,
you know?
Like I know everyone's nervous and like
they're like,
it's the highest highs.
But I used to be so nervous that I
forget like what happened in the fight,
you know?
But throughout my career,
I think after the Mike Easton fights,
when I really started to like hone in
our,
during the Mike Easton fives when I
really started to hone in and have fun
and uh,
just realize like,
fuck this shit man.
Like,
what's the worst is going to happen?
You need knocked out the rule for it.
You know,
it's so crazy subject,
right?
I mean,
uh,
you and I have known each other since
2012 when I did meat eater.
You were there filming when I shot my
first deer,
which is very important part of my life,
man.
And um,
then you went on to direct and produce
parts unknown with our late friend
Anthony Bordain and uh,
we started probably be a good thing to
come in here and just talk,
talk about them.
Yeah,
man.
And,
uh,
and I'm really grateful for it.
You know,
it's actually,
you know,
a lot of people,
um,
who have been saying to me like,
oh,
it must be really hard to talk about
that.
It must really,
it's,
I actually find it kind of the opposite.
Like I want to talk about him.
I want to talk about who he was and what
that experience was,
you know,
so,
um,
thanks ma'am.
My pleasure brother.
Did you,
did you know him before you guys started
working together?
No.
I met Tony,
uh,
10 years ago and I was called in.
Uh,
he had,
uh,
a DP on a show who at the last minute
canceled,
couldn't go to Egypt.
So,
uh,
I got a call like a week before,
you know,
it's like,
do you want to go to Egypt with Anthony?
Bordain?
I was like,
you're fucking absolutely right.
You know?
Um,
and uh,
and so I met him in Cairo,
man.
Like,
you know,
we kind of like perfect.
Yeah.
Holy Shit.
That's like Indiana Jones stuff.
Exactly.
Man.
Episode.
When you guys ate a camel.
No,
no,
we didn't need a camel.
No,
but,
um,
you know,
uh,
met him there.
You know,
we started filming were on the streets
of Cairo and like,
you know,
it's like all of a sudden is thrown in
these kitchens.
There,
it looks like we're eating pigeon,
you know,
it's like go and cover them cooking
pigeon and get an idea.
I had seen the show like maybe once
before,
but I had,
I knew who he was and I knew what that
adventure was.
Right.
You know,
and I was so amped for it.
Um,
and then there was like this seminal
moment on that show where,
uh,
we go out and weed,
we go ripping across the desert with the
Bedouin and go out and cook a goat a in
the ground,
you know.
Um,
and so as we're driving out over the
desert,
we're like,
well,
we need to,
we need some shots from car to car.
Right.
And I was like,
Oh,
get on the roof,
you know,
and uh,
and there's like this for,
for some reason there's a four post bed
tied to the roof of this land rover.
And so I get up there and kind of like,
you know,
latch my arm around it.
And these guys take off at,
I,
I swear,
80 miles an hour across the desert.
I mean,
and you're on a bed.
Absolutely.
No regard for the fact that like,
I'm on the roof,
you know,
um,
shooting and,
uh,
and when we got there,
we got to camp.
I survived it.
I'm at this big black and blue where I
was holding on to the four post bed and
I go over and I show Tony and,
um,
that was it,
man.
From that moment on,
it was,
he was like,
I like this guy.
And I started going out with him,
you know,
I started getting invited to do more
shows.
Okay.