Hi. What can I do that they're your
fellow. I see what you did there. Uh,
hey everybody. What the fuck is going
on? We're back. Uh, before we get going,
we've got to get through
our business points.
We've got to sell you on some shit that
you don't want or tell you about some
shit that you've already heard
about a hundred times before.
That's what we like to do.
We'd like to be repetitive and
then bore the fuck out of you.
That way when the podcast gets
going and you're like, God,
this is so much better than that fucking
commercial. It's the a four players. No,
it's more the blue balls. You
know, it's like, you know,
those insecure comics that would
always bring terrible opening acts.
That's what that's like.
That's what it's like.
The commercials are our version
of a terrible opening act. Uh,
one of our sponsors this week is Tang.
If you go to rogan.ting.com they will
offer you a 25 bucks off or either cell
phone service or one of
their new android phones.
Tang is a a cell phone network
that uses the sprint backbone,
but they have their own rules.
You don't have to have contracts.
They have great phones, they have great
deals, excellent international rates.
Like Brian had a great time
with them up in Canada.
It was like a fraction of what does at
and t bill was and he used it all the
time.
The service is excellent.
It's not like a Mickey mouse network
at Sprint and they just have it set up.
So they buy time on sprint and
they give you a better deal.
They also credit you for unused
minutes. Like if you, uh,
if you have a certain rate that you're
going for a certain amount of minutes,
if you use less than that, they, they, uh,
knock you down to the lower number and
then they credit you the difference when
your next bill. So super ethical
company. It just, it's really,
I liked the idea behind it.
I don't like contracts.
I liked the idea that you can get the,
some of the best high end android phones,
like the Samsung Galaxy s
four. And the the, the note,
that crazy fucking tablet phone,
they have that too.
So rogan.ting.com save yourself some
money.
Speaking of save yourself some money.
You how gross would be if that's how I
did my commercials all serious like that.
stamps.com is a,
another one of our podcast sponsors.
If you buy any of Brian's tee shirts,
you know Brian read Bam,
who's not here right now. He's doing
one of his uh, Tommy's store podcast.
He did all those desk squad tee shirts
that you see the kitty cat on them,
that's all his artwork and he prints
them up and then he sends them himself
using stamps.com and he openly says that
if it wasn't for stamps.com there's no
way you'd be able to do this because
he'd have to wait in line at the post
office and they have to measure
each box and wage box. It's,
it's annoying if you're trying to do,
if you have a small business and you're
trying to send things through the mail,
stamps.com is a fucking amazing resource.
You do all the shit on your
computer, you do all the you, you,
you enter in the addresses, you weigh
it on a digital scale that they provide.
And when you print it out,
you just stick that on your shit
and then put it out for you.
But for the post man and then you're done.
You don't have to go to the mailbox.
And I have to weigh things and measure
things in a where a bunch of people are
mad.
You have all this shit.
If you go to stamps.com there's a
microphone in the upper right hand corner,
click it,
entering the code word j,
r e and save yourself 110 bucks.
You get a $55 in free postage,
coupons,
free digital scale and
bunch of other cool shit.
So that stamps.com and the code word is j,
r e and our last but not least
sponsor for today is a new one.
It's a legal zoom.
Um,
I've never been in trouble
with the law bobcat Goldthwait
I have been on many
occasions sharing code.
If you could've used legal zoom to get
you out of trouble. I know. You know,
I sat the tonight show and firing
and I, yeah, I remember that now.
Yeah.
I don't know.
Could legal zoom helped
me tonight show it was,
it was reduced to a misdemeanor.
I think it was,
I don't know what they ended up
calling it, but yeah, we could, could,
could legal zoom.com how,
uh, a, uh, I would, uh,
I wouldn't say I was an arsonist.
That was the thing they wanted to say.
Now show exactly. I was a,
an artist, not an arsonist.
Arsonists doesn't try to hide it or a
narcissist rather. We try to hide it,
did it, they wouldn't do it on
camera in front of everybody.
And they get horny too. And I, it's
really relaxed during the whole thing.
They get horny. I bet they do. Do they
get horny or since that's the whole thing,
Jesus Christ.
Listen.
So what does legal zoom do
with legal? Zoom does, it's
not a law form, not a law firm,
but they provide self-help services,
uh,
at your specific direction that you can
also connect you with an independent
attorney if you need additional guidance.
Now if you go to legal zoom,
like everybody knows that go into a lawyer
is very expensive and it's also very
time consuming.
And what they have done is sort of set
it up so that you can go to legal zoom
and you can get businesses started.
You can incorporate form an LLC and you
could do it for a lot cheaper than it
would be to go to a lawyer. You can
legally protect your family and assets.
With legalzoom, you can write a will
on legal zoom and the past 12 years,
over 2 million Americans have used legal
zoom and they've saved a ton of money.
The online process couldn't be easier and
they'll take care of you from start to
finish. And a you go to get a special
discount from listening to this podcast.
Just make sure you enter Rogan in the
referral box at checkout for more savings.
So I remember legal zoom.
It's not a law firm.
And they will provide you with a
contact within an independent attorney.
They'll connect to if, if it gets
squirrely and you're like, oh,
I'm fucking going to jail. Don't
worry. Just keep it together, bitch.
Three great ways to save money.
You could, uh, could you tell,
could you get a divorce and then use the
amps.com and then call the person and
say, hey, did you get divorce yet? Um,
I'm in Canada right now and it's costing
me a lot less. I think you nailed it.
I got all your sponsor.
Take all her clothes and call stamps.com
and weigh it on your scale and then
send it to now. And that's
all done. I need a flashlight.
We don't use the flashlight anymore.
Now in creating creative conundrum.
Oh No,
I actually a bonafide spit.
Take Miss,
miss a lot. I didn't realize. All right,
I didn't want to bring up any sore spots.
Let's, uh, let's finish the legal zoom.
Legal Zoom for wheel. It's only 69
bucks. All right. That's, that's a great,
you can't afford not to die. These
phrases. It doesn't get any better. Kids.
I'm going to kill myself tonight cause
of these bargains. Use a code name.
You can save yourself some money and uh,
we're always brought to buy on it,
but this commercial gotten far too long.
So I'm gonna end it right there.
O n n I t is the company.
What do we sell?
Fitness equipment and supplements and
healthy food and bee pollen made from
killer bee honey and hemp protein powder
and all that good shit. If you look, uh,
at the website,
use a code name or Rogan and you will
save 10% off any and all supplements.
All right, I'm very fucking
pumped for this podcast. Please.
I tell you I'm too
tenacious beekeeper though.
That gets the honey from the killer
bees. That is a, yeah, I like his,
like his sack Cuban music.
Jamie,
the podcast begins officially
Joe Rogan podcast by night.
This is officially where the Sirius
Satellite Park starts. All right.
The other part with the commercials is
only on the Internet. Got It from here.
That's why it seems like we don't need
the music, which you could probably,
there's probably a better way to do this.
It's probably a real momentum killer to
doing the commercials as a part of the
city and wants something.
I wouldn't mind if you did them through
the show because grandpa's got appeal
lot and the last time I was on,
I didn't know I can get
up anytime or this time.
Just brick a bucket. Have you ever had
a cabinet? No. Cheese and crackers.
Those are my two biggest things is
that getting a cancer, which I got.
So I'm over that and it really, but
you, by the time you need one you,
it's sweet relief. It was the
nicest thing. Anybody that's bobcat.
Goldthwait,
bobcat.
Goldthwait tonight I'm scratching
Goldfarb. Ladies and gentlemen,
thanks for having me back on.
I have been being,
I really fucking love your big foot movie.
Watched it last night and uh,
I was really psyched to watch
it cause I'm a big foot dork.
I'm a big flower from way back, you
know, I know that. But I also was,
you're the first person that gave it
to that didn't see it with an audience.
I've been doing some screenings at film
festivals and things and I thought it,
I was worried cause I'm really happy you
liked it cause cause I didn't know if
it lose something sitting by yourself.
Oh No, no, no. Because it's fun to
watch the movie with an audience.
I was involved in more and um, it was
beautiful because it was a really, uh,
Baltimore's great and so
a really mixed crowd. Uh,
and I mean all races and all working
classes and stuff come to this festival.
So I'm sitting behind.
It was beautiful through,
through the movie I was sitting right
next to the couple of black guys who were
beautiful.
They're going crazy.
I can't tell you which part where I was
foot and they were yelling and it was
made me so happy.
I had to ask you about something before
we got on the air because it was such a
creepy movie.
There's so many moments and I didn't want
to give away any spoilers, so I knew,
I'm like,
I kind of ask him this.
Well, yeah. And the, and yeah.
So I try not to talk about some
of the things that are revealed,
but I just talk about it. A lot of them
moving out. I'm really happy. Thank you.
I mean, this is the first review.
I mean, you've got a couple,
I shouldn't say there's some nice reviews
online, but, uh, that, that's really nice.
I loved it. I loved it. And one of
the things I loved about it is you,
you are completely true to big foot lore.
Like you,
you added in all the stuff that heart,
like the knocking and the howling
sounded exactly like a real Sasquatch was
ugly.
I didn't go in
to be snarky. I mean, I think the movie's
got stuff in it. That's funny. But I,
I wasn't trying to, you know,
I wasn't trying to mock, uh,
believers in Sasquatch. I just,
because of a couple of reasons. One.
I've always saw myself as as an outsider,
so why am I going to pick on one of the
most picked upon? So cultures, you know,
I was talking to Dan Harmon and we were
breaking it down like and picked upon or
misunderstood groups.
It goes like ren fair enthusiasts,
then it goes a Taliban and then Sasquatch
enthusiasts like as far as people will
cut him some slack or, alright. Trying
to understand where they're coming.
Yeah, that's hilarious.
That's so true. Pour Sasquatch
hunters. You don't catch it.
Don't catch a break ever. Well,
you know I went to where the
Patterson Gimlin footage was shot.
That was the,
and and that was the germ of the
whole movie for me really was I, I,
it was me since I was nine years
old wanting to go to that site.
That that's really,
and then I happened to make a movie,
but, but that's the reality of it.
This show that I loved the tie,
I didn't well up, but I
did. I'm sure I went to,
I don't believe in that footage.
I think that Bobcat Patterson footage
is utter horse shit. But why? Well,
first of all, because
there was a guy that, uh,
that says he did it named Bob [inaudible]
Bob and is can't find it on a map
though. He can't find bluff creek on a
map or he couldn't, I mean, he was gone,
but yeah.
Well you just,
because I can just a lot of places I've
been and I couldn't find a map. Yeah,
that's true. I go home and
I go, I know I lived here.
I knew I lived on this street.
I know that's where Douggie tool
and I hit Danny with a shovel,
but I went back to where I went to high
school. I was like, I killed someone.
I want to clear that up. I did not. Where
did you go to high school and Newton,
South Jersey and Jersey was,
yeah,
but
uh, I lived in San Francisco.
It was a long story,
but it's age first one through seven.
I lived in New Jersey,
seven through 11 San Francisco,
11 through 13 Florida and then 13
through 25 probably in New York,
Boston, and then New York. It's a 25
New York, 27 La. And it keeps coming.
It's a, it makes for an
interesting person. Uh, the
only let your child like, yeah,
yeah, yeah. We have a new kid every
time. Everywhere, man. Really? Yeah.
That's why I learned martial arts.
I got tired of people fucking with me.
They would, they beat you up.
People always threatened to,
I got lucky that I avoided it. But you're
a funny guy. I mean, did you use that?
It wasn't very funny. You're going to be
honest. I wasn't going to head writers.
I mean even, you know, you know that
you've got good delivery. No, it wasn't
well enough to be funny.
I probably would have been funny around
people if I got to know them really well.
This class, it wasn't really quiet. Yeah.
And then getting picked on and
then you learn how to kick ass.
But how often did you actually have to use
it? Never. Yeah. That's the thing, right?
Yeah.
I've got one fight in high school. It
was really quick and uh, it was, it was,
you know, I probably could have avoided
it. Like sometimes I think about it,
I could have avoided it.
And do you regret? You didn't know a
little bit because I heard the kid.
Sure.
I didn't hurt him bad because this
stomach along with this fight,
it's pretty quick. Yeah, it was.
It was at a point where I was,
uh, I was completely like,
oh, I was competing a lot
in martial arts tournament.
So this guy hit you. I mean he, he
was going to and he took them out.
How many hits?
It was just one,
which is kind of bad ass.
But now
if you didn't know you could do that,
you wouldn't respect it. Well, it's also,
I probably did it to show off,
you know, I could have avoided it.
I could have avoided that even
though he's kind of a Dick Guy. Yeah.
He's also a young kid just like
me. We're both retarded. Great.
Now to your ears,
make mistakes sometimes just start
things you don't even want to finish,
but you're stuck in a quagmire. It
was there people around. Yeah. Yeah.
It had to be the last fight.
I mean that no one probably
messed with you after that.
Well, I mean, people are always,
if you are looking for trouble,
you're going to find Trump. Right. I was
never, I never looked for trouble. Right.
But there's, when you're in high school,
there's unavoidable situations where you,
you want to be somewhere you like.
You know what I mean? In your life,
you have control over what you choose
to do for an occupation a year with the
kind of people maybe like maybe my
shape and everything protected me from,
you know what I mean? Like if you kicked
my ass, you'd be, it's embarrassing. Oh,
you can go play tennis. Oh, big deal.
You kicked the fat doe. Hey guys. And
did you, did your fists gets stuck.
There was a section noises,
but I, I never was like, I,
I always want it to avoid,
you know, the only reason why I
ever learned martial arts at all,
it was so that I would be scary enough.
So people left me alone
like a mat. And I always, there's a
bit in my act about, you know, the,
the voice of depth and that that's,
you know, I'm going to kill you.
That guy's going to kill you.
You know a guy who was like,
I'm going to dump drunk Jack that his
buddies got to pull him off so he doesn't
get in a fight with you man.
So many scary people in my life as
far as like physically scary people,
especially all the years working
for the UFC. Right, right.
Like the idea of running around in the
same world as some of these people.
It was fucking terrifying.
You know,
cause it most like UFC fighters are very
calm and they get it all out in the gym.
But yeah,
if you zig when you should have zagged
and you run into the wrong person and the
wrong time, like many
people have your, you're,
it's like it's up to them
whether or not you stay safe,
it's up to them whether or not they
just beat the fucking shit out of you.
I've seen it happen before.
It's really just,
I saw a guy get knocked out in Denver.
I was at the comedy works in Denver.
It was a really cool place
and I saw something happened
that totally didn't need
to happen.
There was a guy who was walking down the
street and he was really fucking drunk
and there was another guy who
was sober and the guy was drunk,
said something stupid to the guy who
started it, but he wasn't a threat.
It was great. Clearly
not threatened. Right.
But then the guy who is sober
just beat the shit out. Right.
And you tell the dude was totally impaired
and the other guy was like stronger,
more athletic.
Anyway.
He was just looking for an excuse
to beat the shit out of something.
He just wanted to beat someone up.
It's like the heckler figures
out they're going to heckle.
And the guy who gets in a fight, you
know, before they even leave the house.
I mean,
I really,
I believe that some people do.
Yes.
Well, I don't know how we went
from big foot too to ask kicking,
but that's all right. I
mean it does, but you know,
it's like I'm not proud that,
that I have the ability to really,
uh, and I'm not known
for this. I mean people,
a lot of folks aren't familiar
that I understand that,
but you know that I can really decimate
someone in the audience. I can really,
really, really bad. And, and Shanker,
I truly don't usually even
my daughter and my new wife,
the o nine my ax is, they all
go, oh nine the, oh no, yeah,
she's still got the new car smell.
She's so,
so like the whole nine,
you know,
they see this like switch
go and they leave the room,
they get uncomfortable and it's just like
blah. And I'm really not proud of that,
that it's a horrible
skill, you know? Well,
it's a defense mechanism for doing
standup, but like you don't even, I mean,
when it gets going, I truly don't know.
I mean you talk about the comedy works,
man, it was just a, Oh my God, you know,
how people will yell out where they're
from and then there's this horrible
nightmare. And I love the comedy
works. I think that's probably,
if not the best club,
it's one of the best in the whole country.
But at one of those, you
know, a horrible shows.
And if people go do the
little boy, the, you know,
they want me to do this voice from the
how they know me from years ago and I'm
not doing it. And, and then there's a
woman in the back of the room, she goes,
I'm from Aurora, and I go, I know
you've learned to sit in the back.
And I truly didn't think of
that in advance, you know,
and I felt then I feel bad.
You don't want to such a weird response
that even the crowd like kind of didn't
go. Oh, they kind of just pretend they
didn't hear it because it was so weird and
horrible. But like, I really kind of,
the switch goes and I say things and I'm
not saying I don't take responsibility
for them, but I'm usually later on kind
of a surprise that I said, you know,
I berated a table full of
women this one night. And uh,
and they were very, you know, they're
acting like the show is all about them.
And I just paraded his table women.
And then one stood up sobbing and
she's like going, I, by the way,
I forgot even what I said. And it was
a couple of minutes later. By the way,
people love these kinds of
stories and they love watching it.
I mean the bars never emptied out.
You know,
two guys are getting along in
the parking lot. Let's watch.
So I'm up there and this woman
stands up crying. She goes,
I'm not a whore. It's my birthday. Oh,
these are the things I'm not proud of.
So
do you think that there comes from doing
standup and bars or ground Boston to
building the fence? My course
in Boston, that was the hardest,
hardest place to do stand up
comedy. It was, it was horrible.
It was. But, but when I got started,
it created so many unique
characters and so many, you know,
I got started and it's like, uh, you know,
who came out of that group? It was like,
you know,
Lenny Clarke and Denis leary and Steven
Wright and Barry Crimmins and you know,
just all these different, unique voices
that came out of my front, Tony V.
And so it was really tough to do comedy,
Paula Poundstone but you were forced to
have your own, your own voice, you know?
Yeah.
You guys were ahead of me.
And when I first started doing comedy
and started doing open mic night,
I was really aware because of all you
guys, like what a crazy scene it was.
It was, I mean it was released
a few places on earth.
People are hate this on my podcasts.
Well,
oh they're going to talk
about Boston comedy. Sorry,
Bill and I have had these conversations
and I'll tell one or two bucks now.
It's amazing place
on your buckets. But, and I, and I, I
really rarely talk about it, but, but I,
I am, I don't drink, I don't take
drugs, but I don't tell people about it.
But I just did. But I, I have, I
haven't since I was 19 years old.
So this story is that long ago I started
doing comedy when I was 15 I got an
alarm. I was 20, so this is
like a story when I'm 18 with a,
I'll say as Lenny Clarke
and all these guys,
and we boarded up the doors
and the windows at the
Dingo with cardboard, right.
And we're just drinking and doing
piles of blow and um, and the,
and, and, and all night.
And then the door opens and it's like
smokey and backlit cause the sunlight's
pouring it and it's,
it's a bunch of cops come walking in
and I'm just high and gacked out of my,
and I'm going,
I'm going to jail, I'm going to jail.
That's all banking. And the cops go,
Lenny, you fucking cock sucker. I sit down
and they start doing blow and I'm like,
yeah. And I'm like, there is no,
there's no god. Yeah, yeah. I was down,
it was it Chinese comedy
club and we would,
we would cut lines on the, on the
ribs, you know, the pork ribs.
We'd be in the freezer, Chapman lines
on those orange pork ribs, the ribs,
the redwoods.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
Yeah.
To be a flat surface.
And then I'm just thinking like these
families that get served up. Oh my God.
Blow covered pork groups,
juniors bouncing up.
Whenever we go to the Ding Ho,
he's so animated.
This was like in the 80s did you guys
get real coke back then or was it all
chopped up still? I think we were,
we were getting high. Yeah. No,
but you know what I'm saying, like don't
know the difference. I mean I really,
I've never done coke, so I did
it. And then, and like I said,
I stopped everything when I was
19 I know people don't believe
the folks who do it though.
We'll tell you there's like rockstar coke,
like pure code, which is
amazing. And then there's like,
you know Tom Sawyer from the, from
Cobbs. Sure. Tom will tell you,
like if you talked to them about the
old school, like rock star coach,
I've talked to some of the Boston
comics who like, you know, I didn't,
I didn't quit because I got
syllabi I could cause of the,
cause they shit got bad,
the coat got mad,
disappointed in the quality of a blow.
We'll play again fucking high anymore.
Apparently it's very different
experiences with you get
real cocaine,
a hundred percent pure cocaine.
It's a very different experience than
what a lot of people are getting.
His speed. You're getting like
coke mixed with some sort of,
no,
because I would do,
I had done speed and it didn't
affect me the way the Koch did.
So that's my Pepsi Challenge.
It's very scientific.
I don't know.
They cut it with things.
I don't know what they're cutting this
baby laxative and vitamin B's. Yeah.
One with um, uh, XTC they
cut away, cut it with speed.
Apparently speed.
Sometimes you don't get all pure x.
You get a bunch of funky
amphetamines in there. Wow.
So what we're trying to say
to the kids don't do bad code.
No. You, yeah. So you guys were doing
it with the cops, the cops. I mean,
the guy's a guy would steal some guys
joke and then somebody's arm will get
broke. I mean, it was not, I mean,
it really, that's the reality of it.
Dane Cook was on the podcast once a week.
He and I were talking about how
they're the guys who were doing comedy,
where men like Kevin Knox and
Lenny Clarke, these, these big men,
it's like manly.
And it was
a very, it was just like if
very aggressive for, yeah.
Yeah. It wasn't like on Gavin
and people are going, oh,
you're in Cambridge and there
imagine that you don't got pipes.
And we got patches on
our sweaters. Like, Hey,
you're coming out with like one of
those [inaudible] suede jackets with the
Ambien Tasseling Dang
like an overstep chair with
it. And we sitting there and
talking to him about, um,
uh, Noel coward references and
stuff, you know, but no, it was, uh,
it was pretty down and dirty
and not, but, you know,
it was the best place to train.
I mean, cause you know, you, you,
you were ready for the hackles were
insane that the violence and uh,
it really is weird to think about how
much comedy and violence was in that
scene. It was a crazy
scene. It was, uh, I,
I'll try to keep some of the
people out of this story,
but one of the guys I was with one night,
you know,
when someone's party and then they just,
the switches thrown and they become Gorgo,
you know what I mean?
Like they're just not themselves
completely, you know what I mean?
And one of our buddies insisted that
he and I were vikings and he was really
committed to this character was he was
a viking and he was holding me in a
headlock and he wouldn't
let me go. And, uh,
and to the point where it got creepy,
like he was just dragging me
around the bar, it was funny.
And then it would go for a long
time. Like I was at, you know,
and I couldn't do anything. He was much
larger than me. And then Barry Crimmins,
I remember at the time I had a, um, had a,
a cast and the guy who
had me in a headlock,
who by the way is a friend and he just
had a rough night that night. He says,
Carmen's goes, because let him
go. And he goes, and the guy goes,
hugged me or hit me.
And Cummins goes,
it was the fastest decision
I ever made in my life.
He just popped him with
the CAS broke his job.
That's a low, that was a,
that's comedy. Yeah. It was
a, it was crazy. It was ma'am.
It really was.
I uh,
I came just behind you guys and one of
my big regrets was that I never got to
perform with the Ding Ho cause
it was so legendary. Yeah.
Because the, the, the, the comics
were in charge basically, you know,
booking and the, the, all that stuff.
So it was, it was, yeah, it was crazy.
Well that's sort of how the
comedy store used to be,
except for the booking aspect of it.
You know,
the comics we were never in charge of,
but there was still,
but was no real crowd control. There
was, it was all comics working.
The booth comics would work the door,
the comedy store was like,
it's all comics working. Well, who's,
this was, yeah, this
was pretty much mayhem.
It's guy a shun Lee.
He ran the Ding Ho and a
talk to me maybe twice.
One night I go out on stage
and I'm doing my character and,
and you know I'm full board. I write
and then I stop and I say, you know, hi,
this is my real voice. I'd like to
gut and clean some fish tonight.
Does anyone have any fish?
You know, really straight.
I'm saying this in my roommate raises
his hand, he pulls out this big fish.
Now the fish would Ben in the trunk
of his car. So it's rancid. Oh No,
I just got the fish and gut end
trails and trails all over the stage.
And this woman just contact vomit
as soon as she smelled it. Just, Oh,
so I'm a professional.
I put the mic right down to her so
you could hear retching over the PA
chicks puking up. There's fish gut
vomit all over the front of this date.
And then I go,
thank you.
Gonna in the next guy was bill
Campbell around when you're this guy,
really sweet guy, but his act as you know,
talking about, you know, relationships,
you know, men go to me, you
know? Yeah. It's just gets
and fishing. And he goes, uh,
you know, so he, his act is destroyed
because overbook, this kind of stuff.
So, yeah, very nice, wholesome
kind of heck. And then I
did this and then shun Lee.
There's only time, first time
he talked to me, he goes,
he pulls me over to talk to him.
He goes, Bob, are you weird?
He said, fuck. Are you weird? Wow. What
a great boss. Yeah, yeah. That was, yeah,
it was like, I still did the second show.
Don't do the fish, you know. No more,
no more fish. It's hilarious.
But yeah, so it was,
I don't know, I was gone by the
time it, it, it met its the mice.
But when did you bail you out of Boston?
I went to San Francisco. It
was all pretty quick. You know,
I got on Letterman and then, uh, and then
I, it was in the early eighties. I can't,
you know, really, I was half in and
half out of the different cities,
San Francisco and Boston. So
it was like 82, maybe three.
I started in the 88.
Oh Wow.
So it was way after the Boston comedy
scene. When did it really start?
When was like the birth?
Yeah,
it was before I got there and I
got there at the, uh, like 80,
the end of 80 probably.
Did you see France Alameda's documentary
show? Yeah, I'm a little bit in that.
Yeah. Yeah. It tabs, some
of it, but there's still
stuff that was, uh, that, I mean,
he did a great job. Wasn't raw dog.
Well, there's just some things
in there that, you know, well,
the one thing is funny is that I watched
that movie with Lemmy clunk and part of
the story is that these guys don't like
me because I get on Letterman, you know?
And that was true. I mean. Oh yeah. And
they got really mad because, um, you know,
I don't know younger than them. I come
in from Syracuse. I again on Letterman,
like, you know, probably in a year
or so I would have been pissed too.
But you know, Lenny would be, you know,
and Leonie and I are friends actually
were going to do a project together but,
but, but at the time when he was
really pissed, he was like, you know,
he's throwing me into,
yeah,
not your 10.
It was almost like a union gig. It was
like you didn't put in your seniority.
Yeah. So, so,
um, that became part of
that movie. But you know,
I sat there and watched it with Lenny and,
and,
and we just kind of laughed
together, you know, and, and uh,
and I watched it with my daughter too.
It was really great for my daughter.
It was really cool to have
her watch that. Wow. Yeah.
I have a pretty good experience.
I'll tell a good story if you don't mind.
Can we got to go without my daughter?
So, um, my daughter is a costumer,
she works in commercials
and movies and stuff and,
and I'm very proud because she's
taken a creative life and she,
she does great work. We work
together and, uh, and, uh,
and my wife and I, we work, everybody
works. And when I'm making a movie
on my friends and family, so,
but I get this text from my daughter,
she's working on that project and it says,
Dad, maybe I shouldn't say it's the
one. Oh, I'm going to fuck it. I'm,
and so she says, she says, Dad,
I have a disaster. Uh, she
says as a text, she goes,
I have diarrhea.
And I went in Russell brand's dressing
room and I'm using his toilet. Oh,
he doesn't know I'm in here.
And he just came back in and
she's trapped in the bathroom.
I have to go back to the set.
She says, what do I do? I go,
I go make him feel uncomfortable. Just
open the door and go, hi Russell brand.
I had to change my tampon shark week.
And so,
and so my daughter texts back,
Deb, you're great. I love you. Oh,
she thinks I'm trying to help her
out of an uncomfortable situation,
but really I'm going,
what could I have her say?
So Russell brand won't try to fucker.
Ah, ah, so, uh,
because of course I'm going,
oh, this is bad, this is bad.
The bathroom being cute with the hitting
the charges are, yeah, I mean, you know,
and that's his thing, you know, and then
I'm like, and then I go, what happened?
And he goes, she was napping.
And I'm like, my feelings
are hurt too. I'm like, well,
he didn't try it yet,
which makes me a creep but weird in it.
What was the motivation for
making this big foot movie?
Cause this is like
completely for me. I mean, I,
I found out about this like three weeks
ago. Okay. And when, and also folks who,
if they are familiar, a lot of folks don't
make, I make movies but, but the, the,
it's,
it's completely different
than like world's greatest
dad and God bless him man.
It's a lot different than shakes.
Fucking great. Oh, thanks man.
So fucking great movie.
Tom Kenny and I, who,
whose name drop is now the voice of
Spongebob is binky the clown in the movie.
And he's again, cocaine. He's
doing San Francisco startup.
But I've known Tom since I was six.
We were introduced by a crying nun at St
Matthews. Well, we weren't introduced.
Tommy tells the story better,
but he says his fat kids dragged behind
this nun who's just sobbing. And she,
she dragged me into
his classroom and goes,
cause we were in two different
first grades. She's like,
I can't take him anymore.
And she left me in this class and I was
so, I felt horrible. I was so embarrassed.
I started crying too. But, but he thought
it was cool that I can make a nun cry.
So he introduced himself at lunch. So
that's Larry. We've been now, yeah,
we're both the, I'm 51 he'll be
51 in July. But uh, so I, yeah,
I've known Tom Kenny. He's binky the
clown. Him and I were watching a shake.
They showed shakes and people recently,
and people showed up as characters and
they know the dialogue and there's clown
whores. They're, these women were just as
slutty clowns. And in the middle of it,
when he leans over to me, he goes,
what the fuck were we thinking?
And the crowd was really even matter.
If it was like that Shatner sketch on Snl,
you know, we were like,
get a life, you know,
we were really wigged out by that.
But you know, if you make a movie,
you better be willing to talk about it.
Oh yeah.
Because even my small indie
films that I do under the radar,
and they play festivals,
you're going to talk about
them for the rest of your life,
so you better kind of stand by it.
And that's part of this movie was that I,
I've always been fascinated with bigfoot.
I've always been super interested in the
Patterson Gimlin, uh, footage, you know,
and, and so I, uh, it wasn't
that long ago, uh, the o nine,
she's like saying, she
knows me. She goes, go, go,
go to your big foot.
So I put about 1400 miles on
the car and just in California,
just driving around famous sites,
talking to different people until I
made it all the way up to Willow Creek,
you know? And so you did this just to
sort of form the idea in your head. Yeah.
Well, I wasn't, I didn't have a move.
I had a different movie in my head,
which I still think I'll
write because I thought it, I,
one of the things that's fascinating about
Sasquatch is, is it's a, it's a good,
everybody, I wanted to do
a thing that kind of, uh,
this isn't this movie,
but I had an idea for a movie that
kind of took on faith and religion and
everything,
and I thought maybe I'd set it in the
Sasquatch community because there's people
that just believe,
and there's people that believe and see,
there's people that are
shysters just people. I mean,
so it's a really good, uh, it,
you know, it's a good analogy for
religion, but, um, you know, uh,
I don't know where you sit on the pointy
head or less pointy headed big foot.
What I funny.
Yeah.
It's funny because I saw this guy go over
to another guy at a conference and the
guy's got a cardboard egg with a big
pointy headed bigfoot. And the guy goes,
you disgust me. And he goes,
wait. He goes, look at that head.
And so you just got, yeah.
And the other two guys
really,
I've seen big foot three times and you're
never going to see him cause you smoke.
Yeah. And I was like going,
it's pretty gangster.
Well this is beautiful. You know,
this is really amazing. It's like, so,
so subcultures are fascinating to me.
I love the fact that, that, that um,
uh,
you can get into discussions and go down
this crazy rabbit holes with everybody.
And um, and I, I, I do, I,
you know, here's the thing,
when you say you believe that means
people say you no longer impartial,
but I'm going to s but everybody has a,
you know, so I, I'm not impartial. I,
I do believe that there's, there's
a, a Sasquatch out there. Wow.
Or, or, or I should say big foot plural.
You went there, you said, I believe
is a Sasquatch. Yeah. I mean,
when I look at my career,
what it's going to happen,
you could say bobcat goes away.
It's weird that that is one of those
subjects though where it's like a Ufo woes
or psychics or something
along those lines.
As soon as you start talking about it,
you're immediately a silly person.
Yeah. But I'm already used silly
person. Yeah. I'm so far off the radar.
I do what I do. It's
completely, you know, I,
about seven, eight years ago,
I really just Kinda quit.
I stopped being in stuff that I was
embarrassed of. I stopped, you know,
I still do something if it's
nice and the breads there,
but for the most part I just quit. You
know, I stopped trying to get jobs.
I didn't want to get discovered.
I did,
I stopped writing movies for other people
that I wasn't getting paid for that I
thought they would like or I stopped.
I stopped out all of it and I just,
and I was,
and I was fortunately enough,
Jimmy Kimmel hired me to direct the show.
And that's a big deal.
That's a huge deal
because, you know, I mean,
you did dispel show a little bit.
I did a little Chapelle.
We ran into each other and that
was three. Yeah, totally random.
And, um, so I worked on Chappelle and
that, but working for Jimmy, you know,
it kind of just gave me this freedom
is nice that someone believed in me,
you know, when, when pretty much
a I'd become still and possibly,
well we talked about it before the
podcast when the, during the commercials,
the thing with the tonight show, that
was the big thing with the chair on fire,
this persona that people that had an ass
load of and, and, and, and just, you know,
and, and I didn't even,
you know, I got really yeah
frustrated because I was just being
famous for being famous and this is before
then, you know, a digital age. I
just got really tired of being like,
you have booked me on a talk show,
I go crazy and people would be happy and,
and I really was just like so over
it really destructive, you know?
Well you were like rebelling against
like the police academy movies and that
sort of box that,
but also it's,
it's, it's rebelling truly. I think
the real thing, what was that?
I was, you know, Leno was nice
enough to have me on and then,
and then I saw this pattern that
I may have become a regular and,
and I've never really discussed this,
that terrified me.
They did being successful on that level
because it's easier to be a guy who
never tried and then you're in some
dopey teen comedies and you can criticize
what everybody else does and be bitter,
but they're really put, you know,
to really put your cock on the
block and say, this is who I am.
This is going to be my material,
or this is the movies,
this is the products that say who I am.
That's terrifying because then
you're out there to be judged.
That's fascinating.
So it's almost like get a self destructive
quality because completely idea of
success was just too much pressure.
Right.
Because then I'd have to actually
pony up and actually, oh,
so you've been criticizing x, Y, and z?
Well, what, what do you do? You know? So,
so, um, I was really trying to not,
it was kind of funny because I was
trying not to be on TV anymore and I said
that the night you have a fire and then
immediately I get booked on every show.
People think like I was
banned from other shows.
I wasn't in band from the tonight show.
They actually had me on a week later. But,
but um, it's, it's, it's very fascinating.
It's funny, I was just writing this thing.
Um, you know, I toured with
Nirvana as a comedian and,
and there would be times
where, you know, I was,
it was a few nights where I was
sitting up with curtain, you know,
we were exchanging stories like,
you know,
him showing up and drag in a gown for
a headbangers ball and nobody getting
that, you know, that's pretty funny.
Especially it was funny to him cause
he's getting asked to go on a metal show.
So he thought it'd be funny to show up
and drag and everybody's like going this
guy, you know? And especially because he
wasn't running around and lipstick on.
Wow. You know, he just was comfortable
in a drag. So, uh, it was, you know,
and he's like, mom, nobody would give
him, you know, and it was really funny.
And then, and then, you know, like I'd,
I'd smashed up the Arsenio Hall show.
Did way more damage on that
show. I remember that too. Yeah,
I wrote paramount sucks on the back of
that cause they fired him basically and
they gave him a rod deal and it was
just me trying to end it, you know, I,
I really related more to rock
then comics. I just kind of, Ooh,
you know, I try to. And then
were you upset though that you were like,
you,
did you feel like you were getting
pushed into some like family box and it
wasn't representing you?
Like it was a real visionary is a
real comic that, you know, it's funny.
People,
you know,
I think the character would cloud people
from hearing anything I was saying,
you know, I love and meet Bob. I got
it when it was like a house. I mean,
when did it come out? Yeah. I don't
know. But yeah, just starting out.
That's funny because that album,
like people don't,
I don't think people understood
that I actually had material.
I think so just tell me in, in police
academy. So what I was going to say,
it was a real, it was really good comedy.
It was really good. Stand up. And uh,
I think a lot of people I remember just
thought you were like a crazy actor guy.
Like all the people didn't know.
Like you didn't just have stand up.
You had like really smart stand up.
It was really good stuff.
But it was weird because I think
I helped perpetuate it. Oh Gosh.
Ipod was possibly,
you know,
it's Kinda funny when you go on
stage and you do this persona,
even people who are rolling
their eyes start laughing.
So it's hard to jettison it.
Especially when you go on the
road and they're expecting it.
It's weird to get pigeonholed.
And I just stopped. Uh, it was,
I was on the road and I realized,
Oh, I don't dislike, stand up.
I hate this fucking care.
I did.
People try the way, expect it at all.
Yeah. And they, you know, still do,
you do the voice, you know, and they
get mad, you know, but, but it's just,
I gotta do I gotta do I gotta
be me? You know, as Corny
as that sounds, you know, I,
I feel you mean you got to
quit. You know, you got it.
Like there's this weird thing in our
society where it's like, uh, you know,
you can't quit and, and that's where you
find when you're happy, you know, he said,
oh, this isn't working for me. You know,
I thought, oh, this isn't working for me.
So you could end up in a place where you
go, oh, this is what's working for you.
Unfortunately, ended up,
they're usually about 45 well,
there's a lot of people that they,
they never abandon that act
and they hang onto it. Like,
just Judy Tenuta still do stand up. I
don't, I don't know. She had a great act.
It's funny that my wife and I brought it,
but he owed nine and I
brought Judy Tenuta today
on the plane because I did the
gathering of the Juggalos. Oh Wow. And,
and we're wondering if like, if like
they booked the wrong acts on purpose.
So we were like putting together a lineup.
Like it was going to be Paula Poundstone
and Aimee Mann at this year's
gathering of the Juggalos.
We may cause I think cause sometimes,
did you ever see,
did you ever see the
public sex wouldn't be gathering the
juggle? There's a movie called, uh,
shoot American juggle.
I think his name. No,
I've just watched clips on the Internet.
No,
they just have you sought Tila Tequila
get hit with Pooh. Did she really? Yeah,
man. Through pooler he ran
out of Phaco Cola. So they,
so they started throwing
poo and oh my God.
Like dudes were shitting and what
cops know, they knocked over,
they backed out to report upon.
Yeah.
It wasn't like GGL I may ask
someone else's pool. Yeah.
Which is, that's my point.
Look, uh, I'm going to digress
here. Ball. That's her on stage.
And that's Rowan Porter,
right? Like hypothetically.
Let's say you are, I, I give it
up. I mean, look, she, she, oh,
pull it stays in them. She,
she stays up there. Oh Jesus,
that shit just hit her legs. I love
that. She's like sitting there going,
you know what, a couple more minutes
I'm going to win her back late.
She just lay that I gotta give it up.
Grab her crotch.
Is that all shit or is it some of
the beer? No, it's Phaco Cola. They,
it's the soda. They like the throw.
But um, like if, here's my point,
if you are walking down the street and,
and you hit me with dog poop, right?
Like you saw some and threw
it, it wouldn't be a deal
breaker, but I'd be mad.
I'd be like, Joe, what the fuck
was that? And you go, I don't know.
I thought it was funny. We laugh it
off. No, but if you hit me with like,
you know, like Hobo, do you
know what I mean? Like poof,
from a person that would be the deal
breaker. I'd be like, you fucker,
I'm gonna have to see in my,
I now really swift human
shit is way more terrifying.
Did you ever see Gigi Allen? Uh, yeah.
And then he starts throwing it at people
and they get out of their way. Like,
like,
like military striping,
like when people have about
human poo is way worse.
It's terrifying. Yeah. No,
no, no, no, no. So I did that.
I just hose it off. Ah,
yeah. But I did the, yeah,
the gathering of the Juggalos
and, and um, and in, uh,
the, uh, the opening act upchuck uh,
the clown is trying to calm my nerves
now there's, there's no, you know,
they have their, their, their
own security. So there's
no security. It's just,
it's just juggle a law on this
huge piece of property. Wow.
So, and there's so, it was
just madness. Yeah. There's
fires going on and fire work.
People are always lighting
fire to like fireworks,
like the way people light
cigarettes. Like casually. I don't,
I saw a lot of that was really funny.
Like where people don't jump out the way.
It's like
some bath salts. You wandered around
amongst his be, are they freaking out?
No, because, um, I think, well,
they know that sometimes I get
recognized for the most part I don't get
recognized. But, but,
but it was, you know,
we took a golf cart through the
whole thing. And like I said,
there's fights and people,
I don't know what they're doing,
but maybe you might know what this is,
but suddenly people would drop,
like there'd be like a group of people
and then you just see him drop. Like,
like they were puppets in
someone cut their strings.
They just hit them like his own, they're
cheering graph thing like their Joan.
Oh No, no, like whatever they
had been doing, we just suddenly,
like a bunch of them would just drop.
Yeah. It'd be like three or four of them.
Obviously they just ingested or did
something. And then I'll send you Jim go,
don't get the done like dominoes and
then they get up. I don't know what that,
whatever it is is not good.
Yeah. Well, well, so, so, so, so,
you know, it's, it's, I understand
the idea of the Juggalos by the way.
I get it. You know, I get it. It's a, it's
a certain sec that's, that's pissed off.
And it's certain group of
people and I, and, and they,
and they do have the sense of
community and family. I do,
I do try to be open minded.
And they were, and by the way,
they were very nice to me,
I should say that it's a very
good way of putting that. But,
but while we were there,
you know,
up checks trying to convince me that
it's not that scary of a Gig and he's
driving me around on this golf
cart and he's like, you know,
you got to it and this huge cloud
just everybody's kind of either,
some guys are cut and clown makeup. I
is, a lot of them are, uh, or like obese,
you know, men and women. It's really like
an incest survivors convention. Like,
you know, nobody's going to
touch me anymore, you know.
So this guy just jumps out of nowhere
and starts punching up chuck on the golf
guy. He's running along and for
no reason. He's like, fuck you,
fuck you up. And he's
gutting it. And the guy said,
we lose the guy. And he's
like, ah, ah, I'm here every
year. You know, they know me,
I'm like family. And I'm like, okay.
So, so then he punched him in the face,
punched him right in the face, and then
he took it like, like in the shoulder.
And then, and then by the time we
gotten him, he got get 'em like one,
like in the kidney on the way out, like
a left. And he's hitting him hard. Yeah.
Yeah. Real punches. Real punches.
Jesus. So, so, and that was Columbia.
It was a little smudge.
He's trying to,
he's trying to convince me this can affect
the first kind of fake what comes in
and it just sprays all over
us. And uh, and he's like, uh,
he's so familiar with getting hit
with Vaco Cola. He goes, he goes, uh,
uh, it's diet. It's not going to stay.
I swear to God he really said that Larry.
And then one comes in and, and, and
uh, the o nine, he's got it on camera.
She had a sports setting on her,
on her camera set.
The shutter is like faster. So we've got
this shot. It's like the Zapruder film.
We got this can of soda.
This guy does a baseball
pitch and you see it whizzing seconds
before it hits them right in the temple,
no car rack.
And he just slumped over and he goes,
uh, lumps over the wheel
and he goes, I'm hurt.
I'm hurt bad by the way, he's mid sentence
because you know something like that,
when the soda is that going to happen
at a Dave Matthews come rack and he
slumped. So I was like, I'm hurt. I'm
hurt bad Bob. He's calling me Bob,
so I know he's really fucked up, not
five. And I think he was out for a second.
Oh my God. So he hits, he hits the gas
and now, yeah, that's up chuck. Yeah,
that's, it's Joel. And so it was like the
golf cart and I was fine. That's crazy.
So how old were you when this
was going on, by the way?
Your sold 1550 years.
50 years old.
And so upchuck now full throttle and
I'm steering spear and we're whizzing
through the crowd, like
Mr [inaudible], wild ride,
Juggalos kind of. And I, I, uh, and then,
oh, oh, do I love this? This is actually
beautiful. You know, he was concussed.
His eyes were all fucked up.
I'm like, God. And he's like,
we just went back to the trailer and
we're just gonna be really quiet.
And then he puts in ice cold
vago on his side of his head.
He's like, he's going to look,
he's like, am I bleeding? I go,
I don't know where the makeup starts.
Much blood.
I don't know what's right
fucking can of sooner to the
head that, that's hard. Ard.
And then I'm not going to,
he may or may not,
it looked like he was doing some sort of
stimulant after that too, because it's,
you know, you worried about your safety
or this was all, yeah. Yeah. I, uh,
once I got it, yeah. You know, and, and
by the way, I'm no stranger to hi-jinks,
you know, I'm this the man who lit the
tonight show couch on fire, you know,
my wife says I have good ideas and bad
ideas and I don't know the difference.
It's just ideas.
And I treat them with enthusiasm.
I may or may not have lit a quarter
stick of dynamite in my backyard.
When I lived up,
I think it was a half a stick.
It was like a for stick.
Yeah. And it blew up, um,
this watermelon that shot all the
way, like three floors up. It was,
that's the way it goes in. It gets kind of
gory. But I digress. So I'm no stranger,
so like something explodes
and, and, and, and uh,
and my wife goes to set an m 80 and
I'm like, no, that's, that's dynamite.
Wow. So I go up, hey,
where's my party people that,
no, I, I actually did a fine set there by
the way. Crowd was, you know, one o'clock.
I hit the stage. They, they, they, they,
you know, they, they liked the tenacity.
If you can actually hang
their there and I, you know,
my oldest brother was a biker,
so I'm of familiar
with a kind of outlaw behavior. It
wasn't, it's never that, um, you know,
freaky
to me it seems like it's sort of an
agreed upon thing at this sort of a place.
If you're going to hang out with a bunch
of people at a party and there call
themselves Juggalos, you know, some
sodas going to fly through the air.
It's going to be,
you can't get mad about soda,
but to the point of,
but what you see the problem is,
is if there is no,
uh, there's no law, right. It's
a little lord of the flies.
Like some dude, they thought he
was stealing so they physically,
I don't know what happened to him,
but they tore his car park, like,
just dismantled it. Whoa. Yeah. So it's
a little, little lord of the flies.
Yeah.
I mean,
I would've got paid in a plastic trash
bag full of 20s that's actually kind of
bad ass. Yeah. And then, uh, and then,
and then the cops had just at the lip,
just, just, just taking people to jail.
They had a bus. So you, so we pull
out right in the cabs are gone.
What's going on? I go, look, I got
a bag full of money. Bob. Get cold
comedian. I was big in the 80s you
know, they're like, yeah, you know,
nothing weird. You guys, whatever you
want to do, I'm completely straight.
And they were, they actually found
that really funny. That is funny.
So they were looking for people to be
drunk and then you opened up my bag of
money and they're like, I
should do comedy, you know,
and they're all busted my chops.
But yeah.
Would they looking for drunk drivers or,
oh, just raw hide out of their minds.
Anything. I mean they were just popping
everybody that pulled out of the this
street there. I love what
you said about the, uh,
about it being like community and the,
there's of positive things to that.
There. There is so, so I mean, like I
tell this story and I laugh and stuff,
but was it any different than when I
went to see the almond brothers with my
brother Tommy, and he was
tripping on acid and his brother,
his brother Biker, who is still
still alive, big bitch. Uh, we, uh,
who is a green baret and we're going to
see the almond brothers and he suddenly,
thanks everyone
ready? Going into the concert
is Charlie. Oh my God.
It was the best that,
what year was this?
Uh, probably like 78. Oh my God.
And I'm just like, oh. And you know,
sometimes when things go crazy.
That's the other thing about me
when during mayhem and chaos,
I'm actually super calm. It's pretty
cozy. You've been around it so many times,
but like everyday life we'll, we'll
flip me out. [inaudible] like we,
you're talking to her, know the line in
the post office. I can't handle correctly.
I get upset and stuff, but, but
may ham I get really calm. Really?
Yeah.
Like a deer jumped out in front of us
when we're up in willow creek and I just
said my wife, I go, just stopped the car.
I can all send Daddy. I
Dunno. It was pretty much
other than the other way. Yeah.
Yeah. But the, the, I know
what you're talking about,
about freaking out about lions
and stuff like that. If he,
if you can't just stand still and relax,
you know,
like in a line and then,
then the nicest slow.
It's probably like an ADHD thing when
people are actually really freaking out.
Well, it's the, it's
the, it's the, you know,
the whole nine caused me a,
a misanthrope and I think that is not
correct because I think what upsets me is
I actually kind of have,
I think I,
I tried to think the best.
I really do.
Even though I make movies
where I'm shooting people
and you know, and, and, and,
and all these weird things, I do kind
of give people the benefit of doubt.
I truly do. When she said that she's, she
goes, you're missing throw up. And I said,
you only say that because you're a person.
She's always afraid that I'm going off
the grid because at night she calls it
the,
at my lake porn,
she comes in and says,
what are you looking at?
And it's just me looking at
like 80 acres. How Lake? Yeah,
it's got its own at home.
It's going to creek.
Oh, you looking at like houses and
get the generator going. Oh yeah,
go off the grid, dude. You and me. I think
about that shit all, it's off the grid.
Just squash all day. Just watching.
Just set up a few gifting boxes.
Now you went swatching
lear show him doing, is it,
did you start it? Yeah,
the show started airing.
It starts airing July
16th on the Scifi channel.
It's called Joe Rogan questions
everything. And one of them is big foot.
I've had a big foot fascination since I
was a little kid when I was a little kid.
I was camping the Pacific
northwest with my Stepdad.
And there's a dude who was up there.
He was a trapper and he had like
these animal skins and shit.
He was killing animals like bobcats,
which I didn't think it was
kind of creepy at the time.
I think that's really creepy.
I was only seven. Yeah,
no, no, no. I met me. Yeah.
But, uh, and he told me
about, you know, that these,
all these people have had these big
foot like, uh, experiences up there.
And the way he was describing it,
I barely remember.
It's like a really whispery memory.
But I remember that's what
started me off on then I start,
I was always in the monsters and
shit when I was a little kid.
I loved horror movies.
So then I started like reading up on pig
foot and then I watched the Patterson
footage. Eventually I
saw, uh, in search of
and search of is the one that everybody
around and said, did you see boggy creek?
Because that was all women. So that,
that I think that had a boggy creek.
I didn't go back and revisit it,
but I think that movie probably had a
lot to do with my movie Willow Creek.
Actually,
I got addicted to that show
finding bigfoot two of you,
uh, if you want. Sure. Or
actually a cliff and Bobo showed up.
I showed the movie up,
I went back up. I went, yeah,
I showed it to the folks that are in it
because you know, a lot of actual um, uh,
folks from the big four community or in
the movie. I mean, and, and uh, and how,
how can we sell this movie?
I mean,
I'm just starting to play and
just started playing festivals.
Thing that I'm really happy is big
foot folks seem to really like it.
Like cliff said, this is the best
big foot movies ever saying, listen,
this is a great horror,
fun movie. It's a great
fun movie. Yeah. And
I don't, I try not to be cheesy
and, oh no, I didn't want,
I didn't want those guys.
Didn't talk too much about this movie
because I don't want to give any of it
away because I want people
to see it. It's, it's you or
me. It's, I think it's, Oh,
can I tell you when, when
things quickstar yeah, sure.
I'm having a blast. Thanks for
having me. Thanks for being on.
I'm having a bus too. So you've got that,
that the American Werewolf in London.
I love that movie. Yeah, me too. I,
yeah, so that blew my mind when I saw it.
Now where did you get that? Is that
from, this is a guy named Pat Mcgee.
He's a special effects guy and he does a,
he designs,
if you go to Magee [inaudible] dot com
he designs a couple different things.
Like he does an alien,
like from the movie alien,
and he just reconstructs life life size
replica. It's crazy. Yeah. He's really,
he's got a mold and he uses
Yak hair and it's incredible.
Many, I don't know if
you've ever heard this myth,
but one of the many myths about the
Patterson Gimlin footage is that it's John
Landis in the suit. Have you
ever heard that? No, I haven't
heard that. Okay. So, so,
so I've heard this and I that
and so one morning I and, and I,
and I love American Werewolf. I love John,
like animal house and all that stuff.
I mean that was John Landis is of course
brilliant. So, but I don't know him.
So I get a hair up my ass and I'm like,
Oh and I got to get to the bottom of this.
So I shoot my agent an email and I say,
I've got this idea for a TV show for John
Landis myself. It's a total lie. I said,
can you get me his email?
And so she gets me his email.
So I write him an email and I'm going to
read it to you cause it cause so he and
I had this exchange and I say,
Hi John,
I'm writing an article about
the Patterson Gimlin footage.
I'm not just lying.
So He's,
thank God he's a nice guy
and was wondering would you
be kind enough to let me
interview? Okay. So I
go on and on and I said,
I want to clear up the rumors that John
Chambers made the suit and that you were
wearing it so quickly. I get
this email back, Deere, bobcat.
I am definitely not the guy in
the big foot suit in the parish.
And Kim would footage. What publication
are you writing an article for?
How did you get my email address?
It's funny,
but I sent him back and I, and, and,
and we went back and forth and, and uh,
he was really cool actually. He, he, he,
I think he's probably tired
of answering that question,
but I'm sure one of his early, he
did a great movie. A, it's like a,
it's called schlock where he's in a
gorilla suit. You've probably seen it.
Is it like a gorilla with a
space helmet on? No, and it's,
it's a kind of famous damage and
it's him directing the movie.
I love the in the gorilla suit with
this space. So it really, yeah,
cause I got a great,
I love this.
There's a photo of me directing
shakes the clown and I,
and I'm in a clown suit and I've just,
I'll never be in
something I direct again, you know,
and I'm like fucking, you know,
I'm like dead serious and everyone's
laughing and I look like such an ass.
So no sense of humor. I'm fucking
clown suit. So it's called Schlock.
Schlock. Yeah. Never heard of it.
Yeah. Let me double check. But yeah,
it is called Schlock. Uh, but
so I'm a, I'm a big fan. I
wasn't coming from a, again,
yeah. It's like I wasn't coming
from a big snarky place. I,
I sincerely fan of land is and stuff.
But I thought there's a lot of big foot
rumors that I kind of thought, well,
maybe I can use, you know, my
connections. Not that I have connections,
but you know, I could just prove
some of the things, you know, like,
like get into the John Chambers suit.
You know,
John Chambers is the guy who was an
Argo who did the planet of the apes.
You know,
there's a rumor that he may have built
the suit and he did make a big foot,
but his big foot I've seen in a, it's
a, you know, so, so whatever it is,
a rabbit hole,
well it's a rabbit hole, but it's also a
rabbit hole where a guy says he did it.
His name's Bob Herat homeless.
He walks just like that.
He took a lie detector test and passed.
He also was a con man.
So is Robert Patterson and
Robert Patterson also went
to jail for writing a bad
check. Pay for the very camera
that found that footage.
Yes. And you go even deeper.
Excellent. Because the con men, look,
my thing about my belief in the pants
and footage, it boils down to the gate.
It really does.
It boils down to that knee in that leg.
And you've been listening
to a bunch of nuts.
Trust me. That's a guy in a monkey suit.
Let's, let's play it. Let's play it.
We'll go over it. They guy,
it's a guy with a football pad,
football shoulder pads on explaining this.
Okay.
I'm not confronting you. I know,
but why it, this is just a more,
this isn't like proof,
but this is a weird thing.
Why did they go to the trouble to get it?
Find that stabilized one.
There's a stabilized one. It's better.
Why did they, um, that was, uh,
Abraham Zapruder who shot
that too. He does one. Look,
there's a couple of things
you'd be noticed. I want to,
I want people to pay attention. When you
watching it, why does it have breasts?
That to me is the weirdest thing.
Why doesn't have that breath?
Why did they couldn't make a
suit like that in that time?
And why would they take the [inaudible]
and there wasn't for sure if the stretch
fabric that looked like for it.
I'm not sure if that's entirely
true to a lot of knuckleheads.
And I also think that it's ridiculous to
say why would they make that looks like
a [inaudible] listening
to a lot of dingbats.
That's what you'd been queer
whack a. Do you look at it? Move.
That is a man that is that
a man not compelling to me.
That looks like it's a
man. Are you serious? Yeah.
The Gate looks like a dude with a
big load and he's wearing a diaper.
I was going to football shoulder pads on.
It's all fucked up.
Stupid outfit and I think you're looking
at it from, uh, you know the problem is,
here's the problem. I
can mind. Fuck myself.
The problem is we play it back over again.
I'd go, that's fucking real. Yeah, man.
Look at the CAF. I'll look them in the
cat's ass. Back it up a little bit.
Let's watch it again. I'll try to, I'm
going to try to mind fuck myself here.
Like a mind. Fuck myself. Ready? Oh my
God. I think it's real now. See if I can,
when it goes back and forth like that,
that's the only,
you got to play Yakety Sax. Look
at that. At eight eight, eight,
eight Benny Hill goes out and
slaps, looking at walk, let's,
let's,
let's zoom and stabilize on the big foot.
That's a kind of monkey suit.
I wish I could mind fuck
myself, but I can't. I try.
I try, but it looks so
stupid. It's so funny to you.
Slightly longer hands like he's probably
got some artificial hands in the suit.
And if you watch this, look up
Bob Herana mess, but his walking,
there's some footage of canyon fascinates
split screen with Bob Herana Miss
Walking on one side of the
screen and the Sasquatch and it,
goddammit Bob [inaudible]. This was a big
gangly Sasquatch looking motherfucker.
Let's take a look. And he passed the
lie detector test, but that's not,
but I mean when the guy walks like a duck,
quacks like a duck story.
So many times he started believing it's
possible he made Oj Simpson the whole
thing.
I think you can do that too.
I believe it a hundred percent a
hundred percent I'm gonna believe what
my memory of my childhood is.
So God damn foggy, you know,
I could go one way or another way.
And start telling a story about it one
way and then by the time I get 10 years
down the line, don't even fucking
remember what really happened.
Your childhood is so bananas now to you.
Have you,
do you spend time trying to piece
it together or you move past it?
What do you mean? Well, I mean it's
pretty nuts. The moving around,
and I've heard you talk about it in
the past, but do you around was nuts.
But the really nutty thing was the
martial arts competing and going and
competing in martial arts tournaments
throughout my high school years.
That was the nuttiest thing cause I was,
I was a child and I was having martial
arts competitions against grown men.
Like my,
my,
my instructor was crazy and he made me
fight grown man when I was 15 so like
from the time when I was 15 till I was
21 all I did was full contact martial
arts tournaments.
That was way scarier than anything.
It was almost like I was so scared of
growing up and I was so scared of being an
adult and I was so scared
of just interacting with
people and fitting in in any
place. Cause I was always the
new kid and always moving.
I was so scared of fitting in that I
just decided to do something way harder
than that. So I didn't have to think about
that. I tried to do the most obscure,
crazy, scary thing to me. Well,
why did, it's really weird.
Uh, now it's, it's kind
of sad to hear this.
No, it's not sad. It
worked out great. Well,
sad is if I had to go back and be myself
as a child was often sad as a child,
but ultimately it worked
out, you know? I mean,
it's not sad to go through tough
experiences and develop character.
I don't think that's
sad, you know? I mean,
I think there's a lot of people who
came out of a lot worse than me. Like I,
it was fun at the comedy come about.
That's the part the company
came about from a gallows humor,
from going to tournaments. I used to
make my friends laugh in the locker room.
It would make my friends laugh like
on buses and planes and shit. I would
be the guy who was like trying to crack
the ice cause we were all terrified and
I wasn't insecure around them.
Like the guys that are trained with it
was the probably the first time in my
life I felt confident enough to like
talk out about things and say [inaudible]
joke about things and not to get told
to shut the fuck up or someone's gonna
kick my ass or you know,
that's what a lot of moving from town to
town when you're the new kid it's like
you always have to defend yourself. You're
always dealing with the local bully.
And it's like it was because
it's a constant thing.
So when I started doing martial arts,
like this guys all knew me so
I was comfortable around them.
So then I would make fun of Shit to
sort of lighten the tension because
everybody was scared. Cause when you
go to tournaments it was just fear.
The bus was filled with fear and
everyone's scared. Weighing in is scary.
And then every now and then one of
us would get knocked the fuck out.
You get head kicked and Ah,
and you deal with your friend.
Just got to cut cost in the thing that you
do for zero money bus, go back in the
bus and get an ice pack on his head.
I get black eyes and shows around.
Do you call the family
[inaudible]? I was the only
child. Wow. Yeah, until you know,
some kids came along when
I was like 19 and 20.
There was some kids that joined up.
There was like 17 and 18 but for
the longest time I was really young.
Have any social life? Did
you have zero zero, no party
and no drinking, no nothing.
I had a couple of friends
from high school and uh,
my best friends actually went to the
school. That was the other school.
And what about, what about women?
Did you have girlfriends at all?
I had a girlfriend,
almost ruined me,
my first girlfriend because as soon
as they're starting to having sex,
I just didn't want to train anymore.
I was like,
it was like, why would I go,
Gee, this is way more fun.
Does everybody know about this?
Yeah, it was ridiculous. I was like,
the sex is way better than martial
arts. Like getting my face. But I think,
yeah, having my nose shoved into my
brain, it was always, um, all right,
so we were talking about
Paris said before, I,
I don't suddenly became a shrink on you
if it walks like a duck and quacks like
a duck, it's a duck. Okay.
I want you to watch this.
This is Bob or autonomous walking and
then the big foot Bob looking at turning
just like the big foot.
I mean, come on man.
Put that guy in the goddamn monkey suit.
It was a mistake that the knees
aren't shown here. Honestly. I mean,
if you look at the knees and the,
the, the, the, the, the, the, the,
the way the calf goes up.
You ever walk with Ice Skates on?
Uh, yeah. Well, you know how
ice Kate's don't bend. Right?
And when you had to pick them up and
be fucking exaggerated walking motion.
What he did with the big foot looks like
to me is like a dude with like a suit
on. It's got like crazy feat on the suit
and he has to walk a certain way because
they will then, you know, it's funny,
I know I'm not giving way too much
about the movie, but there's, there's,
there is footprints in the movie.
Yeah.
So when we say that you
shouldn't have said, oh really?
Yeah. Stop. Stop right now.
Make people, because there's so much
about this movie. It's so bad ass.
If your movie sucked,
I'd let you keep talking,
but you're moving to goods from you.
Let me shoot myself. God Damn it.
Don't do it.
So
I'm just here to plug hot to trot tonight.
It would be beautiful if a guy who's a
con man just happened to be the first guy
to actually see big foot
and filming it would be,
well don't you feel that way about being
a comedian now? You went out and, and,
and where did you go? This
is the area we're not going
to fake anything. No, no, no.
But I mean, but if you find something
there, uh, Joe Rogen, you know? Yeah, no,
absolutely. Well, I feel
about it like, like, like, um,
I'm going up to Oregon with a,
and,
and talking to cliff and
we're going to go out, but,
but I also feel like I tainted, you
know, the idea that, you know, if,
if we find anything,
I don't think so. I think if you,
you're just like me and I think you're,
you're feeling about it is genuine. You
know? I think it's a fascinating subject.
It's very popular,
let's say bullshit.
But it's also very possible that it's
not all out and say it's, it's, it's,
it is fake.
Okay.
What is it about the subconscious
through thousands a year is that people
continually see these things. I
mean, why is it, you know, and,
and Teddy Roosevelt, it tells
a story of, of a, you know,
why does it keep showing up?
Okay. Finish that. Teddy Roosevelt told
his story in his book that he was unaware.
A guy killed a wild man.
Yeah.
And everything was destroyed.
But so like all these stories
that keep cars showing up.
I know I'm interested too in that,
like what?
What is it in part of our subconscious?
What part of,
why do these archetypal characters keep
showing up then it happens to be a man
in the woods going to be simply is
keep your kids away from bears or,
or is it something bigger
or is it a, is it a, is it an
800 pound wood ape? I mean,
you know, it's, it's, it's,
it's all fascinating.
There's so many different things to
consider when you say something like that.
It was like, first of
all, you have to consider,
that's probably a conglomeration of a
bunch of things and one of those things
being that everyone's
afraid of the unknown.
And when you look out into that
dark woods and you just said,
what the fuck is out there?
You said that exact getting creeped
out for the first time, by the way.
And I was in the woods a little
17 miles down a dirt road.
Ooh, you know, your 11 hours from La
North. Then we go to Willow Creek,
then you'd drive about 40 minutes to
Orleans name, you drive up this road.
Then we'd drive two and a half hours
down a 17 mile dirt road to get to the
location.
So there's no phones,
there's no planes going over
to mountain lions, whoa.
To mountain lions to,
and I put the actors in the tent and
that scene and they're going, hey man,
why are we here man?
We could do this in a parking lot.
No, because uh, it was, uh, you know,
it feels fucking real. There's nothing,
don't say more. Okay. You said some shit,
but the fucker stop talking about it.
But it is,
I am happy that people like it, that it
is scary, that there's laughs and um, uh,
it was the most fun I had
making a movie going down a
dark road and getting into the
woods or the Pacific northwest.
It will give you this,
this new appreciation of how
ridiculously wild that area is.
Like the idea that we
have an accurate account.
Did you get like a buzz when you
start the front of the tree trees?
There is right,
or am there's a female moon beam.
I mean there,
there are energy,
trees are alive,
but the oxygen that they make you get,
you get like this weird buzz.
I was not frighten.
Everybody else was kind of frightened.
Um, and uh, and I was just like, I,
I, I didn't realize this about
myself. I just like dropped my trout.
I'm walking around my
funder where the river,
is that where you want to
get a lake house? Yeah. Or
even, I'm fine with a river.
Watch him. That's what you're doing. You
want to go up there and go scratches.
Yeah, man. And, and, and uh,
I don't want to dis, I don't,
I'm not a prepper.
I don't like that attitude.
I really don't because it's like
I don't like these preppers.
It's like this weird end of
times a Christian Judeo bs
that they're buying into.
Do you know what I mean? The world, if
we've learned anything about the world,
it's not going to go out with one big
bang. You know, it's just like, you know,
things are going to fall apart,
but it's not going to be anarchy.
I don't know why so many people
in every movie is about, you know,
a scientologist saving the world.
We've been through several
of those and history.
I think we're better at understanding
it now because we have the written word
and we have history.
We have all these different stories
of the past of civilizations that have
deteriorated back when people didn't
really have access to books and knowledge,
some weird sort of hopelessness.
That's, that's, that's, that's,
and I don't buy it. I don't, I
don't, I don't, I think, I think, um,
I think human beings are
so resilient and uh, uh,
or there is the Carlin bit, you know,
maybe, maybe the earth need plastic,
you know, like as us,
that's fine as a species.
I mean, um, I think that
we probably will carry on,
but it's really easily conceivable that
some natural disaster could happen that
could wipe out most of
the population of earth.
All you need is one big you could Tom
sized media that hits true and we're done.
And there's hundreds of thousands
of those floating around.
Not like three of them,
but I'm not, I think I'm more of an
optimist I think. I think when you, you,
when you just prep and
decide to go underground,
I want to go out in the woods
because I like, I liked the quiet,
I like the smells. I like beautiful. Yeah.
But everybody else with me was just
completely flipped out of there.
But it's like this intern, there's just
a tiny crew and he's like, hey man,
what's his different suite of bobcat?
Uh, what did you see these men,
a mountain lion.
We said two of them were one and willow
creek just walking across the street and
then one car or were you
drawing a con for the one?
But the other one was right where we were
filming and, uh, and he goes, hey man, uh,
bobcat and a mountain
lion. What's the difference? I go
bobcat stocky and, um, you know,
he's got like a short tail and a mountain
lions tall and it's got a long tail.
He's like, yeah, I saw a mountain
lion that I go where? And I'm like,
I'm like, you know, this is like a, um,
Verner Herzog making Fitzcarraldo I'm
like out of my mind and I go where he goes
to the left, I go to the
right fellows, you know, just
there's a real problem with them not
allowing them to hunt mountain lines
anymore. Mountain lions I'd find
out later on our bad ass. Well,
well here's the thing,
they're cats.
So if you run your 200 pound mouse,
you know what I mean,
it's just going to take you down.
Yeah.
Well they go after people on
bikes for that very reason.
They cannot help themselves a
mouse. Yeah. And so like it's
you on a bike with a light
is a laser pointer. And so,
so I was like, how close were
you guys? About five feet
and if you've ever seen him by the
way? Um, well cause the one I did see,
and I have big balls, I was
in a car, but the one I saw
was huge.
It's a lion and they just walk.
And there he was walking with a
purpose across the road, like,
like I'm sure he's about to eat some real
problem in California's banned hunting
of them in some places have banned use
of dogs. You need dogs to Huntington's,
otherwise you'll never find what
happens to the Doug's. I mean,
the dogs bathed them,
they bark,
they get him up a tree and then the new
person comes along as the shoots him.
Sometimes dogs get attacked though.
And that was part of
that story and that's it.
I'm not so happy about that either.
But now when you went in the woods,
did you have a gun? There was a guy with
us had a gun. Yeah. Everybody kept saying,
Oh, you got a gun. And that was
gun around my nose. I know,
I know. I would never know
right now. I know. I had a,
we had a ranger with us and,
and uh, he's out. So, uh, yeah,
he, he's a, a big foot, uh,
Robert Lederman a ranger and he's,
uh, uh, I'd say big foot
enthusiasts. He's really sweet guy.
Huge help on the movie actually.
And, um, and, you know,
it's like three, four in the morning and
he's like, you know, uh, I'm a writer too.
And I go, oh, really good. What are
you? Ray Goes, we, you know, twilight,
like a Yankees.
I write tween a tween novel
set in the big foot world.
It's a coming of age story.
Twilight was too big for fall in love.
Young, young, big foot, big foot
falls in love with a person.
I know people fall in love in
the world. I go, what's the name?
He's like Yeti or not at this
point. I know. And I'm like,
I go,
this is,
this is my air hose.
You know,
like this guy is the only
thing keeping me alive tonight.
Yeah. You're not, oh God. That was very,
I was very happy that he liked the movie
again. You know, these were folks, uh,
in the community. Yeah. Steven stuff
for a up in, um, uh, bigfoot books.
If you saw that in the movie, he's, the
last thing I'm going to say about it,
that shower the house was
very authentic.
It's like I've heard the sounds that they
surrender oddly connect with the how.
That's the thing, like you
listened to that stuff too. Okay.
Let's forget the Patterson Gimlin footage.
There's so much stuff. Oh No, no, no,
I don't.
I don't think there's no evidence of big
foot exists and I don't think the big
foot doesn't exist. I think that
the Patterson gave him a hoaxer.
A guy's a bullshit artists.
I met people when I was up in the
Pacific northwest that knew the Patterson
Patterson and knew the other
dude too. Bob, give him
Herandez. Oh, oh. Herana miss.
The guy wore a suit and they said,
those guys are bullshit artists.
They're always trying to make money,
and he'd been trying to
do it for a long time.
They'd had someone else make a suit.
They had had to someone else
make a suit and it didn't work,
and so they had this city who made
that suit? Then the fuck knows.
But you know, why is it amazing suits not
that good. Here's the problem, everybody.
This is one of them. Everybody
wants to say that it's really good,
but here's what's realistic.
It's blurry as fuck,
so you're not getting a real accurate,
crisp version of what you're seeing.
You're getting this smushy version of it
and so everybody wants a tribute it to
muscles and this movement to like,
there's no design, no costume like that.
I would buy that if you would
show me a high resolution,
crystal clear video of what we're looking
at, but you're looking at blurry trees.
The trees look blurry is fuck.
You can't make out the very specific
branches or the texture of the bark.
So what you're looking at when
you're saying that the look so good,
you look into this blurry thing.
That might be tits.
That might be a flaw in the costume.
That might be his ass or it might
be he's wearing a fucking diaper.
You're a gorilla suit.
I'm leaving. No, no,
I think pull it out again.
Let's watch it one more time.
I want to get back to the
breath stabilized. I always
think that's very weird.
It's my, it's weird, but it's not,
it's not an impossible to fake charity.
It's not, maybe, well, here's the
thing. Okay, how about this? Maybe they,
they would feel like big foot
is way larger than a person.
So you just pretend to
be a female big foot.
Cause Bob Hieronymus is six foot five.
He's too small to be a Sasquatch.
So they give him tits. That's way
more likely than they filmed bigfoot.
Right. It's way more lard. But you say
that now. What big foot do you, uh,
what evidence do you buy that there's
a lot of things that are interesting.
First of all,
the footprints with the dermal ridges.
That's fascinating because that's
incredibly difficult to fake. See,
I'm looking at that man. You
know, there's, that's so blurry.
Look how blurry everything is. It's
all washed out. Look at that tree.
You don't know what the fuck that tree
really looks like. You can't see shit.
You can't see anything.
We'll get all the bad version one.
Looking at the best version you can get,
man.
It's just blown up when you're
looking at everything in the distance.
You want him shot on red?
No Laszlo Kovacs to be the DP dude.
Be Honest.
Look at the trees you're
looking at in front of,
they want to look at the
trees in front of them.
You can't even see any definition of
hazard trees there in meal penalties right
now. And, and it says beyond that,
he says, I'm out of here. Show was
that looks real to me. Jesus Christ.
You're crazy. One more time. But
look at where you're looking at.
You're looking at incredibly blurry shit.
You're looking at incredibly blurry trees
that are all washed out and everyone
trying to attribute all this
musculature and definition.
You barely know what
you're looking at here.
Why does this hold up so much?
Doesn't why foot world,
it doesn't hold up.
It's just a full,
a film that has not been authenticated
or or refuted. It just hasn't been.
Cause science hasn't really
spent any fucking time examining.
What about bigfoot that
what the Yeti in Russia,
the Russians spent a lot of time
examining. They were fucking with us.
Okay. It still limits real
let them was third time.
So we start time on this evidence that
if you're so pose ridges are fascinating.
That's fascinating. The Melba
catch DNAs fascinating on the show.
We just had a genetic but that,
yeah,
but that's the stuff that people
could be bullshit are calling bs on.
It could be.
But the dealers though,
this guy was a geneticist that overlooked
the data and it was his conclusion
based on his understanding of
genetics. There's a fame. He was a,
like an accomplished geneticist,
but
published in any real
thing other than their own.
No. That's because they couldn't get
published. And we're so far down. No snow.
It's good. It's a good thing. That's
the letter footage. This is like,
this is when, uh, the o nine checks out.
No, it's, look, it's, it's
a fascinating subject.
Wrong. This Melba catch a
women or if it's a hoax,
but when a geneticist says that he finds
the, the information to be compelling,
then I have to listen because I'm too
fucking stupid to understand who's right
or who's wrong.
Do you ever see any of the story of
Jimmy Stewart with the Yeti finger?
Jimmy Stewart? Yeah. He's,
he's muddled that what was
supposed to be a Yeti finger of,
uh, the Himalayas. Uh, and
his wife's underwear. Not,
she wasn't, it wasn't in her pants
but I mean in her underwear. Right.
Honey, you going to have to
keep this in your pussy. Yeah.
It was just important to any finger.
It's hard getting weed and
it needs to be moist.
No it wasn't.
It was in her,
in her underwear drawer and they
got it all the way to England.
Now that has been proven not to
be a Yeti thing. I can't remember,
but I remember that it had
DNA testing done to it.
Jimmy Stewart at Yeti. I,
you know, you know, um,
you know, what really works
for me is a lot of the, the,
the audio recordings will obviously,
cause you were talking
about that in the movie and,
and that is what works for me is, is,
is, you know, I love listening to them.
I think it's funny you were talking
about Ufos. I think it's funny.
It's like people will go,
where's the footage?
Well there's a ton of footage on Ufos now
that you can't wrap your brain around.
Yeah. Okay. Here's some
interest. Something interesting
about the Yeti finger.
They said the DNA tests have
found it to be a human bone. Well,
here's what's interesting.
Um, they sent me Stewart's
wife smuggled a human,
but they think
that these things are fucking human.
It doesn't mean that that's wrong.
The people that I thought
that they thought that this
was like some sort of like
a rank attack giant around a tank thing.
But no, they think it's like that,
that Hobbit,
that homofloresiensis you're aware of
that those little tiny man they found the
island.
Yeah. Well that was a human. Yeah.
Well that's, that's uh, you know,
the native Americans up in
the Pacific northwest, just,
Eh, you know, Eh, you know,
some, some, some of the tribes
just attributed to Sasquatch
as a, as another tribe.
I mean, it wasn't, yeah,
she's now how have you gone
on down this rabbit hole then?
The amount of people who go, dit
disappearing in our parks? No.
There is no federal database set up
for people who go missing in the parks.
And it's a, I can't remember
the number. It's huge.
There's an author who wrote a
book about it. It's really fast.
And do they think that these are yetis
are, he doesn't even go down that road.
He just says, why is it,
it's a, we should look it up.
I don't know what the number
is. He, he's saying, Ooh,
what is this?
Why isn't there a and where all these
people gone? I can't, oh, I feel really
well bringing up, they could
starve to death. I mean, you,
you get lost in the woods and
you could get lost easily.
But the weird part is the Fed's not
taking the time to have a database.
I actually have a friend
whose dad died in the woods.
He went hiking and then the
fog rolled in and he goes,
did they find him eventually?
Yeah. Oh yeah. Um,
I think they didn't find him for a long
time too, but you know, you can't that
now out in the woods
like, like we were, eh,
what happens to your mind when you were
out there? That's pretty funny to me.
Well, it's, it's very,
how late did you stay up?
Oh, we were all, we were, we
didn't sleep in the woods.
We decided to stay in a hotel that
was in town. It was a way. Yeah.
But just being around there at night
when you're in those woods, okay.
Even in the day when you go into
those woods, well, you're gone.
We were in Mount Rainier.
You go into those woods and
there's, it's another world,
first of all, those elk that
bound in front of you and
they're, oh, you know, five,
600 pound animal just jumped.
Yeah. That's weird. When you run into a
animal, I saw that up in Willow Creek, uh,
and uh, that, that aren't afraid
of you. That's the weird part.
I didn't know what the
fuck you are. Yeah. Yeah.
But I've never seen one of you fair.
Which was pretty fun because
a couple of the guys,
it was really funny because
we were at Laos camp, which a,
if anybody knows that's
really close to that. And
one of the guys goes,
cause we had two women,
the actress and producer, and um, uh,
I never had a woman here before.
This is around a campfire in the
middle of the night. I go, fellows,
I'm gonna stop you right there.
That's usually when the rape and started.
Yeah. You shouldn't even
say that. Even if it's true.
I keep that shit to yourself son.
And I used to get women out here,
never had women out here. So as far
as the things that they've collected,
like the, the Ufo, you know,
quote unquote evidence to me the most
interesting shit is the halls that are
really insane.
Primate Howells and the dermal
ridges that they found footprints.
Some of them was great, like, like in the
middle of the night and, and uh, it's,
it's awesome. I was once, uh, uh,
before the keynote speaker got up,
one of the guys,
he mentions there's two guys
like an opener, you know,
this is the feature that
that butter and a MC.
So basically the feature brings up Ufo
is while he's doing his big foot pitch
and about a third of the room went like,
boy,
but this group,
I'm going to take a piss.
Yes. Well there's people in the big foot
community that like make fun of would
knockers yeah. Would knock and
like they're just going to,
would not back mom.
Well I said,
you know these guys who upset if you
smoked tobacco in them and there's,
you know, there's people with crying
babies and making bacon and you know,
well the one guy saying to the other
guy that you never find big foot because
your smoke.
I've seen big foot three times.
You're never going to see big foot
because you smoke. That's fucking,
that cuts out a man.
So I was like wondering like
how's this guy feel about grass?
Does he think that big foot's down with
grass big was probably attracted to weed.
That's well I have noticed that
a few fellow Sasquatch hunters
a little could possibly be a little bit.
Yeah,
well squashing. When you're high, it's
probably way more fun than you know,
Oh God,
sober squatch much to be desired.
Really think folks can't wrap their
brains around how many millions of acres
there are still in like California and
Oregon and Portland that are completely
like a plane goes down and no one
finds it. I think you're totally right.
And I think that's one of the things
that we tried to capture on the show when
we went up into Mount Rainier. I was
like, the way I described it, trees, oh,
like it's like a box of Q tips.
You know how you get a box of cute tips
and you know they're just shoved in
there.
You're not getting through that.
You're going to get through that
going on with this one step, right.
And one step left and one step you're
going to like slowly have to see,
saw your way through all these trees.
Like this is incredibly dense rain forest
and there's thousands of square miles,
thousands and you can't just get
to the middle of it. There's no,
there's not trails through all of it.
So if something was living up there,
he could see you coming a fucking
mile away, hide from you. So easy,
especially if it had better senses than
us. Which if it lives in the woods,
it's got to have like animal
senses course probably.
It was senses like a dog does.
Sure.
Dogs would be able to hear you and see
a human being. Yeah. But dear, dear,
see you coming a mile away. They hear
you coming a mile away. Well I, uh,
so, so tell me, or you're not trying to
talk too much about the show you did.
Who did you go out with? A, I'm
not trying to talk too much better,
but women with these guys from
Wasser, the Washington state, uh,
Sasquatch research team, these guys.
Was it a black cord attached? Yeah,
they were great guys.
They were a hardcore dedicated squatters
and they took us to like some serious
spots and we saw some weird shit.
We saw some trees that were arranged in
some really peculiar positions in the
middle of the forest. We also saw some
trees that were broken in the middle,
which is really weird cause there's no,
there's no wind inside this forest.
You know, you're deep, deep in
the forest and you see trees.
They're snapped in half,
seven feet up.
Like something grabbed it and snapped it.
I don't know what the fuck it was.
I mean, I don't know what happened,
but it's weird. You know, you see that.
But to them squatch
and wanting to see your church.
There's an area in Alaska,
I don't know if you're familiar with it,
how deep you went with your big,
I have not gone to a Alaska,
Alaska,
the trees that you treat
uprooted Jamie. See if you
could find the photo. There's a,
these two trees in Alaska that
they believe bigfoot has uprooted.
Ain't got [inaudible] to
the ground. Not yet. Again,
doing a gig up there in two weeks. Which
town? I'm doing a Gig in anchorage. Yeah.
Well the anchorage is really,
uh, it's beautiful. But um, yeah,
maybe that's why I'm going off the grid.
That's great.
I'm gonna delete it too now. I mean I
did two dates in February in Anchorage.
Oh, he kind of reassess your career
choices the second time you go. Hello.
Ain't grits. How cold was it? It
was so cold, but it's, you know,
it's this weird thing.
There's guys wearing shorts and sneakers
cause they just go in and out of heated
things and it's dry. There's like
snow places that never goes away.
These are those trees.
They're picked up by the roots and driven
into the ground and no one knows how
the fuck it was done.
They know that it wasn't done with heavy
equipment because there's no, like,
apparently there's no marks in the trees
at correspond to the use of a heavy
equipment. Now what do you think
that allegedly, I don't know.
I mean, you, here's the thing,
when you hear these stories,
you're hearing about them, see if
there's any other photos of that. Jeremy,
better ones. I've seen some different
ones that are more in detail,
but the,
they don't,
you don't know how much you're dealing
with just people that are in love with
that Shit,
you know?
Sure. But I, I, uh, you know, there's,
there is,
um,
there's a cynicism that you can have
and then there's the question of, uh,
of what if, and, and, and you
could even be, say, all this stuff
is bs, but I do love the, the
what if, right, right. Yeah.
It's, Jane Goodall thinks
they're real. Yeah. Jane Goodall.
Yeah, sure. That's legit.
That's when my, that's when, that's
when the o nine gave me shark guys.
When I pulled out Jane Goodall,
she really, you know, I
mean like, you know, sharks,
you know, they wrote, they wrote back
before they bite. She's like, wow,
well people don't think it's bullshit
and you would start pulling out Jane
Goodall. That's all you know. That's,
that's again the, the, the uh,
the o nine, she likes to say
this movie, the Willow Creek.
That's what the name of this
movie is that we're talking about.
It's that I can't announce it yet.
It got into some bigger festivals that'll
happen soon. It matches in the movies.
Um, I'm, um, I think
that there's, you know,
that you can make a good trailer for
the movie and I think it could open.
I think it's different
than the other movies.
I would go see that if I was on a date.
She got such a great date night movie.
It's fucking, man. It's a fun look.
And obviously I'm very biased because
I love you and I'm a big foot Dork,
so it was a double combination. But,
uh, I enjoy the shit out of it, man.
Thanks ma'am. Thanks. You're
welcome. I am, you know, it's funny,
I just, you know, I'm starting now to make
about a movie a year, different sizes,
different budgets, different people. And
uh, and then in the meantime I do other,
I work for other folks and I do stand
up like I'm about to go do patents new,
a comedy central special. I'll
direct that. Oh, that's great.
You're getting a standup special.
Yeah. Yeah. Where's he filming that?
He's going to be a comic
con. I mean that is, yeah,
that is, that is like if like a
stack the deck. Yeah, exactly.
Like if you were in one of those giant
southern, uh, cathedrals that holds,
you know, the mega churches
and then Christ actually
just came out of the floor.
He just showed up. That's what pat
and that comicon is going to be like.
I love Patton.
His writing is fucking fun.
Yeah, he's brilliant. So,
so, uh, that kind of stuff,
like if I can work with a comic
and, and try to, and you know,
and try to make it easier when they
show up so they're not worried about,
you know what I mean? Some knuckleheads,
you know, that, that, that,
that makes me really happy.
That's just a satisfying,
believe it or not as going out and doing
a show. Oh, that's awesome. Because I,
yeah, cause I love comics
and I don't, I don't,
I don't like it when people make
it harder. You know what I mean?
Like just before you go on the,
on TV,
everybody's saying the worst
thing you could do. Good.
Making me lose. That's the worst thing
ever. You know, they're questioning,
you're going to do good. You know, my
friend Tony, like when he be, yeah.
So like he was,
I love Toby.
So I sent him flowers when he's
on Letterman and it just said,
don't fuck this up.
And then one time he was taping another
TV show and it was years ago and it's a,
I go,
Tony, I'm coming down there tonight
to watch the tape. He goes, oh,
I really don't know. I'm bringing
Robin Williams, so don't fuck this up.
He just thinks you're my friend and
he doesn't know that you're funny.
So really do good. He's like
fucking anthem. And then of course,
you know you do that to a guy and they
go up in there and they're laughing
because he's like, subconsciously he's
going, well Bob wouldn't back out.
It's not going to tell me I'm gonna
fucking blow if you, you know what I mean?
So you need a safety zone.
You need,
you need friends that are driving
you nuts before you go on.
Well it seems like what I like about
what you've done with your, you know,
I hate the word career, but I guess
that's what it is, you know? Clear. Oh,
seems so formal. What you have,
you have, you express yourself.
What I like about it is that you have
not boxed yourself into any one corner.
Like this big foot thing is
just fucking freaky hormones.
That's why I love that. It's like so
funny. It's like people like, you know,
their perception and then you make it
and it's really fun to watch for that
what you,
but what I was going to say is you,
but also like I'll run into you and
you direct and the Chappelle show,
a running a ranch. You, you're
directing Kimmel. Yeah, yeah. I mean,
you're doing all this weird shit,
but you're doing your,
you're equally competent at all of it.
And it seems like you're equally
enthusiastic about all of them, which is,
it allows you to like direct someone,
stand up and enjoy it as much as doing
your own standards, which you also enjoy.
Yeah. I, it's, it's, I'm, I'm
pretty lucky now. Now, you know,
the other side of it is, is
like, it's, it's, it's not,
um,
it's probably the least secure
I've ever been financially.
But there's something awesome every time
you, you, you jump off and you go, Hey,
what am I going to do next?
You know?
And every time it works out in some
harebrained way, you know, I mean,
I gave the commencement speech at my
daughter's school at Hampshire College,
you know, and I was, I really, well,
first I went up and I just read
an Oprah speech word for word.
I, you know, whenever I'm nervous,
I always go to Oprah and then,
and it was all about making it and as
I blah, blah, blah, dreams and hopes,
and I guess this doesn't apply
to any you kids. He got to,
you guys gotta quit as often as possible
in life until you end up someplace that
you don't want to leave, you know, and uh,
and you could smell the
parents stomach acid, you know,
they just spent all this money
on an education. It's so true.
That's an amazing advice
as many times as you can until
you find something you don't want.
You know? And, and like, there's a weird
thing for guys our age. I mean you're,
you're younger than me, but where we
were doing all different things and,
and you know, are we enjoying them or
not? And then all of a sudden this age,
we come onto our own and
it's, um, it, the, the, the,
the freaky part is like, after world's
greatest dad, I wrote five screenplays.
I mean, I just write screen plays
all the time and someone goes, well,
who are you competing with? And
I'm like, the grim fucking man.
I thought like sitting and
over at, you know, competing
with, that's not an interesting
question, that if you produce anything,
you create something. You're competing
against somebody to create it.
And what a shitty mentality, but
common, you know, it's a common thought.
Well, yeah. And as soon as you can
remove those guys and make it, you know,
yourself instead of other people and
you're not judging what you make by their
standards and stuff. It's a, it's a,
it's a pretty awesome place. Yeah.
That's a thing
now being a, you know,
a grown ass man too.
It's like you get to a point where
you're comfortable in your own life and
you're comfortable with what you do when
you know what's good and what you've
done.
You've had enough feedback by what you've
done that you enjoy and what you've
done that you did for money.
And then you get to this sort of
like place where you're like, okay,
I know what I'm doing
here. Yeah. And on the line
pink cloud,
you know when,
when you know there's gigs I take for
the bread and there's things I do,
but you know it, it does make it a
little easier when you're sitting there,
you know, and you're asking what,
what is, what is your police academy?
I'm interested in that. Like what does it
bring up your factor? Fear factor. Okay.
And you're, and you're polite, I'm
sure when people talk about it. Yeah,
I enjoy doing it. You know,
fear factor was nothing.
There's nothing artistic about
fear factor. But there was a,
I had a lot of great moments,
but there are a couple of questions that
you've heard a million times, right?
Oh yeah. What is it? What is the one,
did you ever eat any of that stuff?
Hey, Joe's fear factor for you?
Yeah, but I, I have a very healthy
attitude about it and you know,
I'm happy that people enjoy
the show, you know? And uh,
I understand what it would be like if
I enjoyed the show and I ran into me.
I might say something stupid too. I
might say it's for refractive. You Buddy.
Cause I wouldn't know what else
to say. I'm an idiot. Okay.
You,
but you don't did test it.
We do our best and smile through it.
Yes.
But this person doesn't realize they're
the third person that stopped me today
at the airport and asked me at the
end, you went to your gate. No.
You know what it is. It's always, you
know what it is. It's the security people.
When you take in your belt
with that horse,
you're mad. You did that. You did the
mood, the beer. Oh, you did that shit.
Oh, it's worse because
they go, I don't know.
They are looking at me and I
never heard of them do the voice.
It's the word Jimmy Kemble loves the bust
my balls harder than anyone about the
voices as you know,
like if we're doing the show and you know,
doing the commercial, I over
the do the voice, I guess.
That's hilarious.
Jimmy went and got a star and that was a,
I hadn't seen him in a while, so I went
and got, I went with him while he, yeah,
I was very tight. So you got a star
on the Hollywood was really sweet.
It was just a real, it was a real
[inaudible] moment where everybody,
that guys that I've seen in and
out of his life and hey, you know,
it's really sweet to
watch the, Oh Dang goes,
you know, I tried to get you a star
and uh, I go, what happened? They
said, ma'am, the pasta must
request, right? Again, it's another,
it's another thought. You were dead. And
I said, they were, I go, what did you do?
She goes, well, I, I, the guy insisted
you dad and I said, I'm your wife.
And then I was like, I would have
taken a dead star. I don't care.
You know,
they showed up in like Gore makeup,
they gave you a star Star and then you
showed up for the, and they're like,
fuck is going on
in this day and age. I mean
everyone Zombie obsessed. Yeah.
Yeah. I just come in Gore makeup with
maggots coming out of an Isiah. I get,
she killed me.
That would be
really funny man.
Especially if you, I mean,
sure you can get somebody in
Hollywood to do it up really good.
Like walking dead style.
Yeah. Real estate. Sure. Yeah, that'd be
awesome. So I have a question. What's the,
you did this one episode.
What? What's the next one?
Well, we've done, we're doing
six. We were picked up for six.
It starts July 16th so there's a,
I had a similar idea,
but what I wanted to do,
and this was after shooting Willow Creek,
I thought it'd be funny to like go,
let's say I go the Jersey
Devil. Right, right.
But I make it because I,
I'm interested in filmmaking.
So I get Kevin Smith to go with me in
a tent and we go and sleep out and look
for the Jersey down. Yeah, that would
be great. And then you just keep going.
But it's always like, you
know, John Waters is Baltimore.
And we'd go and we'd go
find that and go into this,
this haunted house in Baltimore
again. You know, it just came up.
Well, the way what I'm doing is some
of them I'm doing with Comedians,
like I did a one with Duncan Trussell.
He went with looking for big foot with me.
And uh,
Ari Shaffir is going to go
to a transhumanist con com
conference with me in New
York.
Transhumanism is no chance here.
People that want to download consciousness
into computers like Ray Kurzweil and
other, like all the people that
are into robots. And uh, so, uh,
he's going to go and do some of that
with me too. So a lot of it we're doing,
I'm doing it like with comic friends,
but it's cool to go have an open mind
and just not be snarky because here's the
thing, what people don't realize, all of
these different subcultures and stuff,
they have a sense of humor. Yeah.
You don't have to roll your eyes.
You know?
I mean like there's a lot of laughs in
willow creek from these guys and they're
just, they know they're making
jokes. They're not, you know.
Yeah.
They listen to the guys that we were
hanging out with up in Seattle and Mount
Rainier. They were great guys and one of
the guys had a great point. He goes, hey,
he's, he had never seen big fun and he
had been fascinated by it and he'd been
looking. He said, listen, if I don't ever
even see big foot, I'm still camping.
I'm enjoying the wilderness,
having a good time. He goes,
I wonder why people get
so aggressive about it.
They'll get aggressive about music. But
I mean, yeah, that's true. You know,
they get aggressive about movies. They
get aggressive about TV shows. Like,
how the fuck are you watched it?
I uh, I had a, um,
now it's actually so played out,
but I had a story when I was directing
Kimmel show about Nickelback and the
first time I tell the story I
go, I go. And I wasn't like,
I think making fun of Nickelback
is really hacky at this point.
But I really said, I go,
what's the band that sucks?
And the guy immediately Nickelback
I go, yes, they were on the show.
Now as a comic, I go, I'm going to
see if that works tomorrow night.
And it does every time. It's like, it's
really funny that these, these guys,
for some reason or the whipping boy of
music understand that, but confused.
I will tell you,
I will,
I will tell stories out of school that,
you know, uh, the, the,
the manager of Nickelback came
into the booth and he goes,
don't shoot Chad from the front. And I'm
like, I don't even know what chat is.
You know, I, I figured out
that's the lead singer. He says,
don't shoot Chad from the front. I was
like, why ain't cause cause of his nose?
Just shoot him. Don't shoot him
profile. Just shoot them in the front.
That's what I'm sorry. He said
shoot her in the front. No profile.
That's why I said, I was like, okay.
So he leaves and all the
cameramen are my best friends.
And when you're a television director,
that's who you really bond with.
And they're like, oh dude.
Hey Bob, can I drag, you know,
you're letting the manager
Nicole Vector Act, you know,
they are really busting my balls.
So if you see the cumulus show
as this show goes off the air,
the band's playing, right. And so I go,
yeah, there's, there's a profile shot.
And uh, just as a, I go to the AED, I go,
tell me when I have 10 seconds left.
She goes, okay. And she has 10 seconds.
I go shoot the nose and six cameras
go whizzing in from every direction.
And I did just, I did a montage, it
was, and I go, ready, camera five,
ready for already three ready, six ready?
Said, I just did the, did the, did it.
And we just,
we just went off the air with this
guys knows it's super quiet and in the
headsets and the guys go, hey man, what
are we going to do now? And I'm like,
uh,
I didn't
plan for that. I'm getting in my
car. I have a good weekend guys.
Did anybody yell at you?
Well,
I know that it didn't make the
west coast broadcast that, that,
that he censored the nose.
Well,
I'm sure people flipped out because I
did that something that I did something
like that to another band and I know
that's fucking knows it's not that bad,
ugly God. If someone didn't come into
the booth and tell me what to do,
I wouldn't even have done the tribute
to his nose. What do you attribute the,
um, the whole hate for
Nickelback too. It was,
it they're there to smooth I
think too polished. I don't,
I mean there's two poppy,
I don't understand why,
why just suddenly everybody gangs on
Nickelback when there's so much more crap
in the world. I don't know. It's just
this weird, well, you know what it is.
I'll tell you what it is. There's
a safety and bullying, you know,
we all decide that we're going to bullying
Nickelback then you're not bullying
or Justin Bieber. Yeah, yeah.
Whoever fill in the blank liking
him or disliking Justin Bieber,
I don't have that kind of time. You
know what I mean? I don't even know why,
you know, he's not for me right
though. He does. But then again,
50 year old men, you know?
Yeah. But here's the thing,
you know? Yeah. And I just,
you know, I, I, uh, I think of him
in terms of like Donnie Yasmine,
when I was growing up,
you know, I, I, you know,
I was threatened and weirded out and then
when I got older I was like, Hey dad,
he asked me this. Isn't that bad guy?
Nice guy. Yeah. Isn't that weird?
You end up meeting that.
He was super nice.
Did it show you the Donny and Marie show
[inaudible] that I used to bring out a
puppet and do and do so stupid and do
weird things. I do like a puppet show
with them to understand, well, you know,
I'm gutting fish.
So it wasn't that much of a stretch for
me to pull out a Donny Osmond down my
early standup. There was
no jokes. I mean I'm a,
it's nice that you like to meet
Bob because I had material then,
but it was just doing one
weird thing after another.
I was super influenced by Andy Kaufman
and Steve Martin and stuff like that. So,
so, uh, if I did well it
would kind of go well.
And then sometimes when I did bad it
she'll go off the rails. You know,
it just ruined all the other guys.
Well, you guys were, it
was such a that that comedy
environment was such a, like a,
a hot environment,
but it also,
the Boston comedy environment really
supported originality. Originality was,
it was really huge.
Yeah, it was weird. It was nice that
that like if you were derivative,
you didn't get work, you know, so, so,
and you've got shit on. Sure. Yeah.
You got shit on by all your peers.
Nobody just let that slide.
They kept a high standard,
which is difficult for people don't
want to maintain a high standard,
but for people that have like,
you know,
you realize that you're going to have to
be judged by your peers. Got this weird
court of your peers so you don't do this,
you don't do that.
You don't get other people's
actually then you go on stage,
then we're going to goose it and have the,
some of the toughest worst crowns.
Yeah. So it was a, it was a good
place. Comedy style. Sure. Animals.
Did you play it again?
Sam's, I had my own,
I had a thing called
dollar night at Sam's that,
and it'd be means Steven Wright
and we'd walk the room, you know,
I started out of the paradise
stitching, my first gig. Yeah.
I have a question for you. Do you think
anybody's going to come along and,
and as a comedian and ever
be what Steve Martin was?
Do you know what I'm saying?
Like,
or do you think we're too
fractured as a society?
Like my mother had weighed
in on Steve Martin. You know,
she thought he was funny.
Right.
You know what I'm saying?
And you did as well. So when across the
board, really that's what I'm saying.
My jag calf again is squeaky clean
and I think funded everybody.
Brian Regan.
But these guys appeal to everybody,
but they're not the phenomenon.
They're not on the cover of rolling
stone. Right. Affiliate link.
I don't think.
I don't think it could happen.
I mean there's certain things I don't
think can happen anymore because of the
digital age.
And I say it's good or bad,
but I'm just saying I don't know about
that because Dan Cook crack through
because the digital age,
and although his was like more of
like a teeny bopper sort of a crack,
that guy was doing 18,000 seat arenas
and that was very Steve Martin neck.
But when I was growing up, Steve
Martin, you had to deal with, you know,
my parents if they were alive, would
not know who Dane Cook is. Yeah.
But that's just Dane Cook.
I'm saying he broke through in this
digital age people, that'll be huge.
But I don't think there'll be people
that, that, that are so huge that,
that everybody in the family knows them
and they're a phenomenon. Wonder. I mean,
you know, they don't think it could
happen again. You might be right.
And we are definitely more
fragmented than ever before.
And in a way it's a good thing because
there's a lot more audience for more
obscure people that wouldn't have had
an outlet before. I think that's great.
I think that's great too.
Do worry about like, um, the,
our exposure to our,
our world gets minute.
Or maybe I'll just say for myself,
am I going to go to BBC and learn
today about the, uh, you know,
about the events or am I going to click on
fun site and go down a rabbit hole?
What do you think's going to happen?
I did the same thing.
There's something,
you know, when you had a newspaper
now it's like I'm an old guy yelling,
get off my lawn. But you had a
newspaper. I go through I, Oh,
I'm interested in that and I didn't know
that was going on in China and I, I,
I think the digital age makes
it a little bit too much. You,
you can find news that agrees
with your outlook, which is weird.
The news should not be,
you know, it should be,
it's never impartial, but it
should be. It should be somewhat.
Yeah, you could, if you
have confirmation bias,
you could support it really
easily on the Internet.
Just sticking to a
bubble of like whenever,
when I'm ego surfing and I see someone
called me a lip tarred and you know,
I'm like, I'm so out of
their tarred. Tired. Yeah.
When someone calls you a liberal, that's
hilarious. Self hating liberal liberals,
one of the weirdest sort of insults
ever because if you look at the like,
okay, let's look at the
official definition of it. Yeah.
Definition of liberal. Okay. Where's a,
yeah, this is Tara. Tara. All right.
Look it up and addiction.
It says to open,
open to new behavior or opinions and
willing to discard traditional values.
That's hilarious.
That sounds pretty positive.
Unprejudiced unbegged added broad minded,
open minded, enlightened,
permissive, free,
free and easy and easy going.
Those are the, now the only thing
that seems to be for me would be
to folks is uh,
disregarding a, what was it?
Disregarding traditional value. I see
that that's very threatening to people.
There's people that treat the
constitution as if it's like the 10,
the 10 commandments like that,
that, that there's no, you know,
we're checks and balances, you know,
we can change and adjust things,
but there's still people that are so
ingrained that's really scary. You know,
I think there's also the real problem
with liberalism is a lot of people know
that folks naturally are
inclined to be lazy fucks.
And if you give people an easy way out,
they'll take it.
So as soon as you start advocating giving
people aid or helping people at out or
people that I get 'em up,
get that fucker up.
It's like there's a part of people that
resent. Yeah, there's a resentment
against like the idea is that liberals
world, World War II, it's like, hey,
you're down on your luck. You know,
write a Gi loan, here's this, here's that
much, much, much harder world
that they were dealing with.
And it was only a couple of decades
after the fucking depression where people
are much more used to living together,
scraping to get by.
Your parents almost starved to death
20 years ago and they all have stories
about it. Yeah. My grandfather
had a horrible stories
about the depression. Yeah.
My Shit down man. Lived through
the depression and that'll make 'em
well, my old man is a whole
nother can of worms, but that was,
was mine there. Yeah. The um, you know,
what would we be sitting here talking?
No. Yeah, you'd never,
you'd never be a comic.
I think that's one of the
number one pieces of a comic
that didn't have a fucked
up life.
I don't think I've ever met one.
Basically. I think my act, it
was me going on stage going, mom,
do you,
do you hear me?
I think that's, that's in a
nutshell. Yeah, that's 100%.
But it's funny how that is like my
favorite art form comes out of that.
In balance.
It seems like there's the
only way to achieve it is
like to achieve it correctly,
like something, there has to be some sort
of a deficit to create this, you know,
this, this, it's a reaction
to a lack of something.
It's not just a natural progression from,
I was kind of a funny guy in
high school and I figured,
let me try other standup thing,
you know?
Well, here's the thing, it's,
it's what we're missing is that,
that those times that we
bombed, we probably should
have never got back on stage.
Right. But we, we, we eat it and then
go back up again because the, it's,
it's, it's horrible. It's so
crazy weird thing. You know,
like often the funniest guy in
the room is not the comedian.
You know what I mean? The
comedians got the, the,
the illness or the Nads to
go up there or both. Yeah.
Yeah. But you know, something that
happened in lately on stage, and this is,
this is not me lying that all of a
sudden for the first time in 30 years,
I'm sometimes having fun up there.
I was always the whole time.
Oh yeah. Something new. Like
all of a sudden a, um, I'm a,
I don't know, man. I'm on this new thing,
like sometimes with the right crowd,
I actually enjoy it. And uh, and uh,
yeah. You know, it's a new new thing.
Isn't that funny?
That something that people enjoy so
much to come see you and it looks like
you're having so much fun up there,
but for a lot of folks it's just terror
and fear and worry about bombing and
fucking try to again
when it's over, oh fuck.
Two more shows tomorrow. Yeah.
Even if you're killing every show,
it's a, it's a new thing, you know, a,
suddenly it dawned on me what was a,
a new thing that dawned
on me is like, uh, uh,
it was okay, these people have an
expectation and I'm not doing that,
but how can I warm up to them?
How can I include them?
So it's not just me saying this
is what I see the world as.
This is what I see is funny.
If you don't like a cram it,
not saying compromise what I believe in,
but suddenly I was doing like a little
bit of crowd work that wasn't like,
you know, uh, how do you know when
you're finished? You know? But you know,
to actually just sit around and poke
around and talk to folks and it's,
it's been different. It's, it made my
mom make, doing standup a lot more fun.
That's awesome man.
I love when people like refined or the
joy of performing or find it caused all
these tiny still and I'm like, oh, what is
he doing? How's he doing that? You know?
Is he funny? He doesn't have
an opening act. Yeah. Yeah.
Any speed is like an hour and a half.
I had all, everybody sits down, right?
It was actually Louis that he said to me,
he was like a c k. He's like, he's like,
go see Cosmi. It goes, wow, he's
going to do a ton of material.
You're going to think 20 minutes went by.
He's still funny. And, and Lo and behold,
yeah, go on. And I was like, this is
weird. I wanted to be bitter and uh, he,
he ruined it.
And maybe it's because he
just enjoys the art form.
As long as like stand up to me seems like
when I feel like when I'm like really
tuned into it,
I'm as much of a,
I'm like a passenger and I feel
like it's a group hypnosis thing.
Like you lock people and you
know how to do the bits ride.
He know where it's going,
you know the setup and you hold the
pause and it becomes like this big and if
you tune into that
frequency and nourish shit,
as long as you continue to nourish it,
it seems like something
that would always be there.
It seems like when people lose it is
when they take a couple of years off and
then they'd go back again or
something happens. And really
I think it just maybe the opposite.
It's like when people just, this works,
I'm going to do it and just get out of
here tonight when my life get the check.
You know what I mean? So, cause I
know I have done that, you know,
but this is different, a new phase
where I lived there and I go, all right,
um, it's not a mistake. You're
here. You know what I mean?
I slow it down,
slow it down,
and instead of blurting out those new
ideas, you know, that's usually what I do.
Like the first couple of minutes
or whatever, the new ideas,
there's this and then I do the act. I go,
I go, Geez, slow it down. It was, it's a,
it has been new, you know, maybe people
are like, and I'll see, you know,
I keep doing it and see what
we see, folks like it. But
are you more comfortable as a person now?
Yeah. Yeah. So is that it?
Yeah. I'm not like, you know,
rainbows and cramping and Unicorns
all day. I mean, I, I get, I get dark,
but I will say,
um,
the majority of the time I'm happy
and I'm happy when I'm making stuff.
So now I know that, well, okay,
no one greenlit this movie or no one did
this and that. I pick up my, you know,
I start writing know it doesn't
matter if it gets made or not.
That process is very freeing.
Yeah.
There's something about creating things
where especially if people enjoy those
things, if he could put those
things out and they can,
like people can like actually get like a,
like when you like,
so say someone goes to see Willow Creek.
If you go and see this movie,
which you're going to get is like a
feeling you're going to sit down and this
thing's going to happen in front
of you and you go, ha ha ha,
you're going to have all this
feeling attached to and you as uh,
you know the pretentious word artist,
but you as an artist,
like as someone who's created this
gets to sit there and realize that your
effort, your thought, your focus,
all this, you piece it together,
your edited up and boom and then you
deliver it and then you get to watch all
this positive reaction and
you just want to go do more.
We just want to continue that
cycle of putting out there.
Me.
I think it's kind of like,
I keep making these movies
and it's really exciting,
especially like the last four,
when,
when after the movie people are
are Chatty, they're like, rob,
I've haven't been that. Which happens.
It's really sweet. And, and, and, and, um,
and I guess basically what I'm doing
is I'm shooting out of flare saying,
[inaudible] do you, do you guys see this?
Do you guys feel this? Is this right?
Or is this going, what's going on? Or
wouldn't this be cool? You know, that's,
that's what I'm doing when I make a movie.
Well, that's the way to do it,
man. I mean, you're, you're, it's,
it's a true form of expression. Like
instead of you saying, Oh, this will sell,
you know, hey, if I box this with that
and that in a funny black guy, boom,
I'm fucking man, I do the voice. Yeah.
Instead you're like, you know what, man,
I'm fucking into big foot. Let's make
this weird fucking crazy movie about big.
Well, that's what I got to say about my
wife. That's a really funny, she says,
she says, go, you know,
go to your big foot. Like she
can't, you want me to get it?
She let me drive around for a week.
So is that what you did to, to
write it? You just drove around?
Truly. It wasn't even like writing. It
was really just just, uh, I'm going to go,
I'm going to talk to people. I'm just
going to do this with no agenda, you know?
Wow. I knew that some day
I'd probably make a movie,
but it was really more just like, do you
know how freeing that is? Like, like five,
six days,
Matt have,
you know, the, you know, I still had to
do a couple of folders, which is funny.
You know, they're going to,
where are you looking for?
That's hilarious. You're doing
phones for gigs. Like, yeah,
we'll help me in Peoria at the
Jukebox, but right now I, that's it.
You know? So, so you go out
there, you take 11 days,
you go wandering around for bigfoot.
Where did you decide to start?
Did you have a specific
no,
no.
I drove up first to Santa Cruz and the
Sierras twos and I drove around there.
Santa Cruz is amazing and never been.
It's really, it's really, really awesome.
You know,
I just went where like kind of kind of
poked around and knew certain sites where
people had seen, you know, or heard or
you know, events, you know. So and, and,
and, and that's again, I
ended up in Willow Creek. I,
I didn't go up to happy camp, which,
uh, I probably will still, I mean,
that's another pretty a, a
Sasquatch. Yeah. Yeah. It's,
it's above a Orleans. It's above
bluff creek and everything. It's,
uh, it's still another place
that there's a lot of squash. It
isn't there a bunch of different names
for those areas too that are like monkey
names and Apa. Yeah. Canyon,
yeah. In Oregon. Yeah.
Very strange. How many,
why? Yeah. And then, um, in,
in Mount Rainier, up in that area,
there's a bunch of names that are the,
one of the North American
names for bigfoot.
There's a bunch of like canyons
that are named after that. Like,
so this guy starts talking about all
these different areas and it's got this
weird North American, you know,
name in it and a, and he said,
well that's when we just, that's how
we started our big foot squashing.
We just started going to all these places
as the North American Indians had now
her affidavit that it's fucking crazy.
Like they names
bots again. Yeah. That's
makes you fucking think. Yeah.
And it's also, but when all
said and done, Eh, Eh, you know,
it's,
whenever you're a sub culture you're
going to get ridiculed and picked upon.
But like you said,
it's just camping.
It's camp and it's fun.
There's something silly about it.
I mean I went with Dunkin
trust and we ate pot candies.
Yeah. Last. Well that's what
I was wondering about the,
cause they know some of these guys,
they're high of course,
but they're very worried
about what bigfoot foot,
bigfoot likes different smells.
And I'm like, are they eating it?
They got to eat it.
Well, if they're smart, they'd eat it.
But even if they, if he eats strong,
we'd like you open up. Like,
I remember one time, uh, uh,
I won't even say his name,
but we were on a plane and uh,
he had brought a Tupperware thing and
it's fucking carry on with weed cookies
and it was an international flight.
Okay.
And this motherfucker opens the lid
and he goes, do you want one here?
You can say it wasn't him guy.
Now I'll tell you that.
He opens the lid and the smell was
so strong. I'm like, oh my God,
we're going to jail. I'm like, are you
crazy? Do know what that smells like?
He's like, can't even
smell it. And I was like,
you can't smell it because you've
been smelling it for so long.
You are in your comment.
It was so scary. It was, it
was, it was so powerful. Strong.
I would think if you had those
brownies out there in the woods,
big foot's going to fucking smell.
No.
Have I ever told the Tony Vee story
about when he was the American tourist or
gorilla? No. Okay. This is
great. I don't think so. Tony,
you won a contract to be the gorilla.
And so he had show up.
Now he told he's a big guy,
right? He's like two 50, you know,
it was maybe a little heavier sometimes,
but he's a big guy and I
think he's about three,
three bills when he was the gorilla.
So Rick Baker builds him a gorilla suit.
That's one he grant.
It's made it like real hair and
it's got this whole gorilla, uh,
it muscle structure.
Now Tony goes to like hockey games and
stuff and people get mad, you know,
like he goes out on the ice.
Fuck you really,
you know, this is bad. We're fucking
horrible. Our animals animals.
So, so Tony, the gorilla seats
got a better deal than Tony.
It's got a guy that travels with these
anvil cases in packs it up and, and, and,
and so Tony's doing standup
in the meantime with me
and hopscotching while he's
doing the gorilla dates. Now the gorilla
suit is not with us, but he's got this,
this oneZ , this big unit tired that
he wears under the gorilla suit.
And clearly he was having
some chafing problems.
So he goes and um,
so we're getting search through customs
going out of Canada and there's all this
uh, like white powder and
rocks that form from his sweat,
from the Crotch,
sweat and sweat.
The custom guy licks his finger,
he picks up one of the rocks and
he tastes it. If I'm his balls,
you know,
it was a ball.
It was a rock of baby powder from his
ball and this ball sweat and I think I'm
kind of, I think I'm witty. I
like, it was like go it is that
tiers tier can [inaudible] the
rock this big hit his tongue.
He was just immediately, he was like,
I don't know what he's thinking.
Like he could tell like
he think Paul's and old man
Dick and he's just like,
what the fuck is going on?
It was the best phase just
like hyperventilating. We,
there we are actually cause I love Tony.
Like Tony,
I love Tony and I met were
just holding each other.
We're just two guys just
wrapped around each other.
Crying is the best
thing we ever saw. Serious, furious,
furious because
we kind of stopped him by the way.
He licks the and then he's got all the
way down and we both look hook like,
all right, it's so funny. That was
the best thing. I thought it was coke.
He thought he was catching someone
who daddy got the bag, got a big case.
He's got the big collar is going to
get kicked upstairs. That is so fun.
I don't eat.
Told me one of the morning
important things that I ever learned
about driving because he was driving back
and forth from New York to Boston. It was
a long thing and he was doing it a lot.
I forget what he was working on,
but he was driving back
and forth a lot and I go,
how do you do that without going crazy?
He goes, I just goes. Then he goes,
when I'm in the car, I just say,
now this is what I'm doing. He goes,
there's don't say,
man,
I wish I wasn't doing this and I could
be doing something else. He goes,
I just say, this is what I'm doing. And
that's, I never thought about it that way.
I want, I was like,
yeah, you can do things.
You don't want to do like that and just,
just have it in your head.
This is what I'm doing.
My wife had a friend who, uh, he was, uh,
he sold ice cream and an ice cream truck
and it played a Turkey in the straw
over and over. Is that data
that, that, that, that, that,
that the, the, the day, day after
day, all day long Turkey in the straw.
And he said, you know what? I did? I said,
I'm going to make that my favorite song.
I became, became his favorite
jam. Wow. That's madness.
Yeah. Ice Cream truck. That would
be the best job. That'd be horrible.
Ah, you could deal with a
lot of shitty kids there.
Would definitely make you
want to not have kids.
Yeah.
And I'd also be like,
you're giving kids ice cream down the
side and he mostly aren't people just
selling weed out of ice cream trucks.
I don't know if you're lucky,
if you have any good in the
van Halen Song. You know,
it's funny, as you grow up,
like I grew up,
you know,
I was the first generation of like
getting, you know, the Ramones,
you know, they, they, I, I, I
got to see them live, actually
would help build the pas.
That's how I'd sneak into bars
when I was under age, Ramones,
punk rock and all this stuff.
And I rebelled against all of this stuff
as it kept coming up, like, you know,
then later on, the kids, we were in the
van Halen. I'm like, that's not punk rock,
you know,
it was an asshole.
But I was down in Baja with a bunch
of buddies and they were all surfing.
And I'm like the, uh, and, uh, I
mean, we're in the middle of nowhere,
like about about five, six hours.
Yeah. I, you know, just, just,
I don't know if you've
ever gone out and Mexico,
I think it's a little too sketchy now,
but there's nothing around there.
Any surfers with no shipwreck.
It's a famous surf site. And, uh,
you know,
and we're driving along the side of a
cliff and I'm driving this jeep and we're
playing Panama from Van
Howell fucking loud.
And everybody's fucked up except me.
I'm the designated. I'm, you know,
Joe Sober fucking but I, it was
finally, I was like, hey man,
I get van Halen.
You finally got it.
I got it was Panama, that
song, great fucking song.
I it
just loud and there's stars and these
guys are screaming and as I keep speeding
going over gigantic pot holes,
they're all thinking they're doomed.
And I was like, it's again. It's like I'm
good in chaos. I go now I get van. Now.
Isn't that a funny thing that you
do though? People do. We all do it.
Especially when you're young. Where
if someone doesn't like what you like,
you fucking angry. So angry. What
do you like it? Shit you don't like,
you hate them for liking it.
Here's an exclusive cause I,
I do tell a lot of yarns and they're
all true, but I have a lot of stories.
Here's the story. I don't, I've never told
anyone. When I was opening for Nirvana,
we were at, uh, here in la,
so I don't know which, which,
which form. I think it
was a form. I don't know.
But I'm an Eddie van Halen shows up
and he's really fucking hammered and he
wants to jam. And Kurt is totally flipped
out. Like Eddie van Halen wants to,
he's like hide me, you know, so, so
Eddie wants to go up and tread. Yeah.
And he's fucking hammered. I go, dude,
give him one of your guitars cause,
cause Kurt played lefthanded and I go,
it'll be, it'll be great. You know,
he won't be able to play it. And he's
like, he would figure it out. Like
this would be so funny.
It was really weird and it probably would,
we had David Lee Roth coming here.
He couldn't be fucking cooler.
I met him one night at the comedy store.
He was the greatest guy just hanging out.
No pretense
in the 80s they were going to cause
purple rain made money and they were going
to give him money and it was
just an insane scripty. Oh,
it was just a movie.
Yeah. I went in and read for why did they
never do that? He's so camera's Madec.
Yeah.
What did they never give him a movie?
That's what he's putting on
the busy fucking everything.
But there could be a movie there, you
know? That's the thing. It's like,
look at him. You know? Maybe they
didn't know what he's doing now.
He lives in Japan.
Okay.
He lives in an apartment with his dog
and he practiced his sword fighting all
day. I'm not kidding. No.
I believe man by himself.
He's a fascinating guy. We
had him in here. First of all,
the fucking guy wears overalls
everywhere. He goes. Okay.
He's comfortable with his nipples. I
don't let me just likes wearing overalls.
They bug your nipples.
I haven't worn in a long time.
I'd have to cut back or over overalls.
You know what they have the little things
like the farmers where they clip up
here and he, yeah, we haven't see, look,
he's wearing overalls. You see that? Oh,
he's got a shirt on it. Yeah. I thought he
wasn't wearing a shirt. No. Look overall,
it's hilarious. And, and, and so he, he
does his sword and, and this practice,
his sword fight and does, and not to be
so crass, but does he, is he set, I mean,
financially, I'm sure
he's got the side. Well,
you never know how much fucking
money David Lee Roth must have.
I by David Lee Roth is,
first of all,
he's very smart and I think
he's also a savvy guy.
I do not see him overindulging to
the point of something like that.
He likes living small.
He shows up here by himself and he's one
of the biggest rock stars of all time.
Drives himself here, shows
up by himself. Hey guys, no,
no pretense in and sit down.
How's everybody? But a
lot of, a lot of the,
the folks that have longevity do that.
Yeah.
You know what I mean? Like, like
I haven't seen him in a long time,
but there was a period where
I spent some time around,
I sound like I'm just name
dropping all my stories,
but it would take a bow and
he would do that. He was like,
well, you know, uh,
uh, I know, I know. No,
no, I'm just kidding. It is a, yeah, it's
true. If you know data, here's the thing.
You've always,
you eat
if you're in show business that
these are the folks that you, you,
you become friends with. Not all
of them, but some stories. I mean,
you just told me a David Lee Roth story,
but you also have a show maybe that,
well, he came in to promote
his show. He has a podcast.
He's going to Japan from Japan. It's
fucking great. It's great. He's fun.
He gets up and does this, does this
podcast, video podcast I think.
And then he didn't find
out what the addresses,
I don't know what the addresses and
then he, and then he sword fights.
I think it would cause it to the
Dave TV or something like that.
I remember he also, I heard
this, I don't know this is true,
but I heard that when you would know
this may be because martial arts, he,
he would, uh, sweep the
stage after the show. Really?
I heard that. I don't know if
that's true. I didn't ask him,
but I could see him doing something like
that. Just, just has a discipline. Yeah.
I could see him doing. So he's a weird
guy though. Show I also, we were at,
uh, again with the Nirvana, but this
is another funny strive that wisdom.
Uh, one of the crew guys had worked with,
uh, the new, she had worked with Dennis
and Kurt enjoyed hearing the
story because you know the nudes,
you would hit the stage with an air ramp.
Like he hit the, this air ramp, you know,
like a stunt man and he
would shoot him over the amp.
Yeah.
And so he can fly in and it with the
guitar and just go shooting over and land,
which stand on what they hit the stage.
And how far would he fall from
the top of a stack of Marshall's?
Holy shot him off like
Canon. So, um, but
apparently curtain joke,
cause I witnesses hearing
the story about when he,
he clipped the top of the speakers,
would his boot heels and just
ate shit and landed on his feet.
Oh well his knees are all fucked up.
He hobbles really bad now and he just
had some serious knee operation be that
air ramp, Jesus' side of magic, man.
We don't have to go at that way.
Flying over the fucking
probably cowboy boots on or something
stupid. Right. You know, every audience,
you know isn't red hot,
you know?
I mean there's gotta be times where
you'll feel like they're in a beer line.
I'm trying to get him to do the podcast.
He's always going to be at the Canyon
Club in July. Why wouldn't need,
or I don't know.
I shot an animal for them just to be
friends that went deer hunting just so I
could call my friend and
no, that's not why I did, but I
really would like to get them in a,
he's a fascinating character.
Of course he's and his is a hunting show.
I watched his hunting show. It's
called spirit of the wild. And He,
and is it the hunting he, does he go
around the world or is it as backyard?
The sexy part, not see the
ladder. When the Kimmel show is
Detroit,
I pitched an idea that nobody bit,
and the idea was we were going
to get the new age right.
We're going to get ted on and then we're
going to pick like Guillermo and uncle
frank and maybe someone else
in gold ball hunting. No, no,
I was going to s w I was going to give
him a paint gun and then make them,
you know, the, the, the
hardest pray, you know,
I mean and send them out in the streets
and have ted Nugent, uncle frank.
That's funny. You know, and, and it
was great cause it was a snow storm.
It would've been so fun. You know,
I would have been really fun.
These guys running away from nudes. Why
it's painful falls. I mean that would be,
and it was in Detroit
and the snow hilarious.
I was just in the eyes in
Detroit this weekend doing stamp.
And then I went to Dallas
and showed willow creek down
there to a small festival.
Couple be oak cliff.
First of all, it's food is fun. Nugen has
a son hunting show and he sets food out.
And then he climbs in a tree with a bow
and arrow and just fucks these deer up
every day is fucking up a new dear
that's going to eat his food now.
But see he
does he have to abide by? Uh, it
depends on the animation can law.
It's an he's not Michigan anymore.
He's in Texas,
fanboy of a Ted Nugent family
in Texas. Can he just, you know,
shoot. You know what I'm saying?
Like if he owns an animal,
can he kill it without having to Dubai
in Texas is one of the best places for
that,
for what they call high fence operations.
But it depends on the animal and
there's a lot of animals that they keep.
And those, uh, those high
fence places that are not, uh,
they're not native to like an African guy.
Animals like a cemetery.
So they don't have or a
season? No, no. Some other,
they shoot him whenever they want to
so he could shoot them every day if you
chose. So they come from another country?
Yup. They got, this is pretty nice.
I'm getting three squares.
Holy Shit. Is that Ted Nugent
flying stick right to my heart.
My older brother, he, he, he uh, he's,
he's no longer with us but he, he uh,
he was a poacher.
I mean he just shot things all year long.
Well that's really common in a lot of
places. Yeah. Pacific northwest, it was,
they were telling us how to poach. Yeah.
We were up there hunting for big foot.
There's a, there's a, there was a woman
that was a woman who worked at the store.
She was like, whoa. She goes, when we, we,
we see al could just shoot them with a
bow and Arrow and nobody could hear it.
They can.
Yeah.
Well my brother had everything
figured out. He had a,
I brought Tony v out to his house once
and I've given him some money to buy,
to insulate his home and I wanted to buy
some new windows and I wanted to make
sure you use the money cause I went to
visit my brother basically. And Tony,
we get out of the car and it's just corn,
like psycho corn.
It just growing up everywhere and,
and tell me what's going on with the
court because it's, you know, I mean,
there's no rows and my brother's like,
oh, that's for the deer, you know,
you know by sort of the deer and
Tony. He's like, Oh yeah, you,
you help them through the winter.
I want to blast them.
I go up to the top,
the window in the bathroom and it's
fucking sniper's perch. Yeah. I go,
when I'm in the bathroom
window, he goes, oh recoil
my brother shooting out
the window on the toilet.
He shooting deer from the toilet. By the
way, there's some guys who are going, wow,
that guy had it all,
all these missing as a qtip
lamb. He'd be like, you know,
in the end they want to go hunt
and meet me in the kitchen. Oh,
we're leaving Tony Bigos and
what does that over there?
Was it like a woodchuck came
my brother. He goes, yeah.
And then we're not even around the corner
and where Blam I just figured that.
Would Chuck,
when Chuck, what would you shoot
a woodchuck animals? He just, he,
he was,
his friends were telling me stories
were amazing stories. I hadn't heard.
Oh yeah, your brother. You know,
cause there's a swan pond. I was like,
don't tell me she'll swatch. He goes,
no, no, no. But there was some bigger,
I don't know what was in
their trout or something. So,
so they had taken acid and they were
climbed over the swap plan and we're
fishing and shooting. He would
go, dynamite fishing life is like,
you know, I had back surgery,
let's it a month and a half ago.
It was my birthday at the end of May and
I get a ladder out and the whole nine,
it's like, what are you doing? I go, well,
I think it'd be fun to jump into the
pool from the ladder because cause,
and she's like, that is a horrible, right.
I just see you slipping. Oh,
coming down the ladder. Well,
I'll give you an idea. I
was sitting at home and, um,
and because of the back surgery and
what did you get done to your back?
I had some,
a disc and bone spurs and I feel great.
And they do. They took a little bit of
my disc away and took out the bone spurs.
But I had other problems before.
I had nerves that were smashed into
two vertebraes yeah. That we're making.
So my leg just,
I couldn't walk and I have back issues.
That's all really have a disc. A
bulging disc. Oh, well I have a dude,
when you want to calculate the cut a
piece of the disc away and I got to tell
you, it hurt. Uh,
the surgery heals up and now my leg
and I don't have back pain. You know,
I lost 20 pounds. I as soon as
cause I could, I have my life back.
But what's amazing, but, so
I said that I've been sober
since I was 19, but here's,
I mean, yeah, 19 so, but the
thing was like with back surgery,
I,
I had a break. I, you know, I, I, they
put me on the lot. It was a VA based.
Yeah. So have you had the line of no, it's
in cowboy movies. Yeah. It's morphine. So,
so it's the shit that killed
Lenny Bruce. Really? Yeah. So,
so it's awesome. By the
way. It's the best day ever.
I was trying to explain it and I was like,
I said,
it's not cause like people describe
heroin as, as coming as, as like,
you know, like that and it's like,
no, it's dilaudid is like, um,
right after that and before regret,
you know what I mean?
Shame and regret, right? The
bribe second window and a,
and it lasts all day. What would you
put Nyquil? Like original Nyquil?
The real shit compared to it a lot
at like a, like a two. Whoa. Yeah.
I'm telling you man. It
was like, it was, you know,
and I'm glad I went through
this back surgery and,
and when it was over, got off the
dope, that's what we're going to.
And I gave him nervous about that. I
was terrified, terrified. And I gave it,
I gave it to the, oh no. Why did
you need it? Because of the pain.
I mean, the pain was so bad. Like they're,
you know, they go into your surgery,
pain pre and post. But, but the
problem was, is that I have, uh,
I have no sense of reality.
Like,
I don't know the difference between an
ingrown toenail and a ruptured disk.
I really don't like, it's just
pain, you know what I mean?
So I was in so much pain and, um, it was,
it was so,
but here's at one point already I have
a problem with good ideas and bad ideas.
So, so my friends are over the
house and, uh, I said to my wife,
I go, wouldn't it be funny if I
shot a hole in the roof with a 22?
She was, it wouldn't be
funny at all. I go, yeah.
It scared the cats while you
were on dilaudid in, yeah, yeah,
yeah. Well, I at least a
hundred Thompson Jr over here.
At least I read it by
while she's there for you.
It's like no that way cause
your filter. Yeah. It's amazing.
You need someone to tell you that.
Uh, well, uh, that was the lot, but,
but I will say it's always,
and I've passed this down to my daughter,
it's always the funny story that
outweighs everything else. Oh,
like later on it's the fall. That's
also what's gotten you mean as a comic?
That's what's gets you like
your life, your career. We,
your livelihood is having these stories.
It's a, it's a valuable asset. Well,
I love that my daughter has it.
Oh, that's, well that's cool.
Like she loves her daddy. She
went to a wedding, she says,
I didn't know anybody. I go,
well, what did you do? She said,
during the first song I ran
out in the hump, the bride.
Fuck is that bro? And she
really did that. Yeah,
of course. She always knows
that the, it's the stories.
You know, she's got
the photos. Look Daddy,
you know when you took this dilauded Shit,
you were 19 you quit doing everything
and then exit 19 to 50 and then there's
nothing in between.
Well, I had a back surgery before, so
that, that was funny because at one point,
like I said, I, I put it in the hands
of someone else. I give it to, to, to,
to my wife.
Give yourself a greenlight to do shit
like that because you're in pain.
Like I had, again, I had to talk
to other folks and say, look man,
and that had to explain this is
what this is for. But I've, uh,
I've had surgery before knee surgery
and I just dealt with the pain because I
don't like, like I don't like,
I don't like all that stuff.
All that stuff actually has a really
weird reaction to me and I become a big
asshole. Oh, that's interesting.
I become really nasty.
Make you cranky and just a
really an asshole. And I mean,
I'm not like punching my wife, but I
mean I would just, you know, short and
tell her what to do. And so, so
this was what worked. And, um,
and uh, you know, I was on this
and, uh, the first time and, and,
and she, did you ever try to
do it without it? Yeah, yeah,
yeah. Definitely pain and they're
going, this is crazy. You know?
And they actually just slammed morphine
into my back, cause they're going,
this is crazy that you're walking around,
you know? And then I thought, well, okay,
I can handle it. I'm sorry
they did. You know what? I did.
I just vomited immediately.
That's fine. But, but I was,
I was sitting there one day and uh,
this is the first time and, and,
and I'm watching 'em lifetime and I'm
just sobbing and my wife comes in.
She goes,
you don't get any more
pain medicine starting now.
I married a man. Oh, that's
funny. I did not marry him. Man.
Cries during mommy. May I sleep with
danger? Started Tori spelling or whatever.
I was watching.
I'm lifetime lifetime movies made you cry.
Yeah. She's like, it remind me.
She's like, that's, that's it.
Remind me not to take that stuff ever.
I didn't want to cry and I
want to watch lifetime. Yeah.
I was doing Q and A's for
the movie on dilaudid.
Wow. We went to the Boston film.
Tells the people that you on it. Yeah.
I just said I'm really high.
What else was I going to do now?
Was it painful just to like sit down?
Just like to sit up straight?
It got to the point where yes,
sitting was a pain and
walking was a pain and yeah.
And it affected my life to the point
where, I don't know if you're this way,
what you go, uh, you,
you, you measure things.
If I go to the store that's going to hurt
a lot. Can I go? You know what I mean?
It's affecting what you do to the
point where I, you know, I didn't have,
I was 50 or in my late
forties and thinking like a,
a senior citizen, so
whoa. And now I'm back.
That's amazing. Yeah. Back surgeries,
scary shit. Back surgeries.
Spooky one for people I've ever,
well
it sounds, I have a great
doctor, but it sounds like,
are you worried about the controls
surrendering it? Is that it? I mean I,
I went to a bunch of doctors. Oh really?
Yeah. I've had no surgery. Back Surgery,
knee surgery twice, three times, three
11 uni. I tore my ACL and both knees.
I had a reconstructed and
I told him I'm doing this.
Just the first one was a kickboxing.
The second one was Jujitsu.
And what happens when
it happens? You're like,
well, the first one that you broke,
I knew something was really bad.
I knew something was really wrong.
It was like a pop and just terrible,
terrible pain. The first one, uh, her a
lot more. The second one didn't even hurt.
It was really weird because it was, um,
I was in what's called a half guard,
so someone's legs are wrapped around
your legs and he extended his legs and my
leg went sideways and just went stop
like a carrot. It was really weird.
It was like this pop noise. And then, uh,
I didn't even know it was the
ACA was gone until I was walking.
I think it was in my office.
I was moving something like,
just gave out on me really weird.
And I had already had my left done,
so I knew that my right was
probably fucked. So first one,
was that during a match?
No, it was training. Both of
them were during training.
Okay. And what does, how does
the other guy feels? He's
like, know it wasn't fault.
It was totally easy. Does it feel weird?
Oh yeah. He felt bad. He felt terrible.
The Guy, will's the guy who it
happened to the second time,
it was a friend of mine.
He's a really nice guy and he was terrible
when you train. I haven't had it guys.
I had a guy's lady explode on
me a couple of times. Yeah,
two different times that I can remember
one time the guy blamed me but that was
ridiculous.
It was just weird.
It's just in the middle of scrambling
like sometimes you need just gives out.
And then the other one time was a
guy didn't tap in time in his knee,
just exploded. It went pop, pop,
pop, pop, pop. But it was like,
it was a weird situation.
It was like he didn't really have to tap
like sometimes like you can get out of
things and you're real close and then
I'll something in the middle of like
trying to get out of it. Like he was
pretty close to getting out of it.
His knee just gave out.
Like it was a weird sort of a thing
and it made this horrible, loud sound.
And that sounds to me you're, you're
thinking that I'm crazy cause I'm an,
I am a jump off the ledge. I was going
to get someone to steady it. Well it's,
it can be dangerous. Like I
said, I've had my nose opened up.
It's a little insane but it's also very
intoxicating. It's fun. It's like a,
it's a very exciting game now about
now you don't do it. Sure do. Wow.
Yeah. Well the only thing
that's stopping right now,
so I have this little disk issue but
the disc is getting a lot better.
It's pretty close. Yeah. You gotta
get it taken care of? No, it's not.
It's not like a, it was only
a few millimeters, the bulge.
So it was something that with spinal
decompression and a bunch of different
cases saw mine, the law and the
MRI and it was like a comedic,
it looked like a, a bicycle tire with
a bloop. Oh Wow. It was that big.
And I remember how many millimeters
or poked out like they put on
the Mri and the two doctors go,
oh you like, you're like slow.
Yeah. It was like, okay, mine is
actually asymptomatic right now.
It's a stiff and it just does
getting things out of the things.
This is the problem.
The problem,
the problem is by the time you figure
out how to do it, what makes you happy?
The wheels start falling off.
They were just telling me you might need
to get glasses. I mean it's, yeah, no,
I definitely should get reading glass.
What have actually reading classes.
Like when I look at things like anything
that close is, is kind of blurry.
Like right there that's blurry.
But like, my computer's fine.
I can read everything on the computer.
I need it. It's things are close.
Well my phone sometimes,
sometimes our wake up,
I can't read a number and I'm like,
fuck you,
look if I have to actually dial it on
my home phone, I'm just looking at like,
what the fuck is that? It's weird.
Then I have to go. Like I said,
it's the cruel, cruel joke at time.
Yeah. Time as mother fucker. It.
Uh, you know, I, I hate to be so cliche,
but as you get older it's, you know, like,
you know, that's, that's like I said,
that's who I compete with now. Yeah.
Well that's one of the reasons why, um,
I think like going, I'm not like going,
wait a second, did the grim reaper get
a comedy central special mother fucker?
What do I got to do? A competing? Yeah.
You do rewind up thinking you got
to get out more ship before you go.
I want to be behind.
Conflict is what builds everything
is what creates everything.
It's why anything's interesting.
Conflict or pure enjoyment of whatever.
You're doing that too. That's
true. Conflict kind of,
there's a bunch of things that can move
along. Right. Well the cool thing is,
is if you,
if you stop making the conflict being
other people and you use your own demons
as the conflict and then you don't
have to create, you know, you know,
yeah. I can sit there and
write a screenplay and,
and not go down and not go to
a terrible place. Yeah. Go,
yeah,
go back and forth with myself.
When you create something like a, like
this movie or anything that you write it,
do you sometimes like get out of
it and go, who the fuck wrote that?
Like it just almost like it
comes from somewhere else. I uh,
I think that it's almost like,
this sounds really trippy.
Um,
but I think a lot of this stuff,
and well here you're on stage and you
say something that he never said before
and it's not even derivative.
It's not something, you know,
I mean your buddies and you are, you
guys discuss, it's a brand new thought.
You kind of feel like it's just there
already and it's like this, this,
this stream and then you
reach up and you grab it.
And the big part of it is trying to,
I can't believe I'm not not dilauded
right now, but the big part of it is,
is getting yourself out of the way
so you can just grab that stuff.
That's a great way to describe it, you
know, because cause cause you know, I'm,
I'm terrible, I'm a failure. I'm a
hack. This has all been done before.
Nobody likes me.
You know.
It's so exhausting excel and that
stuff's just having a big ego in reverse.
You know?
It's still a big ego.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You're thinking about yourself instead
of thinking about what you're doing or
going zen and focusing on, yeah. It just
makes stuff that's, it should be a shirt,
you know,
make stuff or just make stuff,
you know, the other cliche, it's true.
You know, you're feeling bad, you know,
you do something good.
Yeah. This, uh, this, did you ever read
a, any, uh, Pressfield's the war of art?
He talks about the Muse,
you know,
and he talks about and treats it like
it's a real thing and it's a kind of an
interesting idea because what know, people
think of the Muse, you know, that like,
and the idea is that there's something
that gives you these ideas for something
that you pay tribute to and then
it, it gives you ideas. Right.
He actually asked sort of
actively courts it like,
he actively like says like a, you
know, I'm going to respect the muse.
I'm going to show up at work every day,
you know,
and I'm going to put in the hours and
when I put in the hours, the musical come.
Yeah.
And like he sort of,
his philosophy on it was very enlightening
and it, and it's also very, um, the,
it's, it's, it's, it's inspiring
because it makes you want to write,
it makes you want to create
and it makes you want it.
Like that attitude is a very
beneficial attitude to have.
It's sort of spiritual and Mumbo jumbo
and kinda crazy. No, that's not right.
I say the nicest compliment I've ever
received, uh, as this friend of mine who,
who, uh, Tom Link I think, and he, he, he,
he saw a movie of mine and he, and he
said, I want to go. Right. Ah, yeah.
That's great. And I was
like, oh, that's nice.
I always feel that way when we're
cynical me. He's like, what? He thought
better now,
dirty prick again though.
No, I was like, that was the
nicest thing anyone's ever said,
I think after a movie.
Yeah. Yeah. That is, uh,
one of the coolest things about
other artists to create more of it.
I truly don't know when I'm
making these movies, uh,
what they're about later on I'll
say, oh, that's this character,
that's this person in my life and I have
no idea until after they're done and
I'm watching him, like my wife was like,
you didn't get that. This is just pretty,
or people playing you and me.
Yeah.
Well listen man, you move.
He's fucking bad ass.
I really wish you all the
best in the world. I will
cherish these big foot socks.
That's a big the in my life
and that posters are really rad
that my friend, uh, Alex, uh,
yeah.
Where do you might get one frame and
we'll put it up on the hall of fame here
please. And it's called Willow Creek and
Willow Creek. If anybody wants to see it,
what will be the availability?
It will in some festivals and as soon
as I get a distribution of some level,
I'd love to come back.
Probably. I'd like to come back
before that. Fuck yeah.
Dude. Any time. And please,
if there's anybody out there that has
anything to do with the movie business,
just check this out.
It's fucking great.
You're gonna enjoy the shit out of it
and it's, it's, we need fun movies.
It's a fun movie. Yeah,
it's exciting. Thanks.
I'm not going to say any
more about it. Don't, and you
don't either, man. It's one of those
movies where you can't say, Oh,
I love that scene.
Yeah.
I can't even say it. I enjoy the
shit out of it. Ladies and gentlemen.
It's called Willow Creek and we'll
keep you updated as far as, uh, what,
whatever Bob gets,
whatever distribution we'll tweet it will,
we'll put it out there for you.
I know people are gonna want to check
this out and if people want to get in
touch with you or see any,
or should you have a weapon?
Do you have any names on Instagram?
That's about it, but what's the Instagram?
It's just bobcat. Goldthwait all one
word. It's hard to spell, but you know,
he can figure it out. It, yeah,
I'm on Instagram and I'm pretty close
to pulling the trigger on the Twitter.
Maybe
do it. Please. Come on, man.
Do it. We'll will pump you up.
We'll have a contest to see.
How many Twitter followers were you?
Do you have like a million? Yeah, I
thinks it's a little more than that,
so it's like, hey man, who's in the
numbers? It's over a million. Okay,
scratch. I don't know what
it is. I don't know. I, I,
all I know is that I'm pretty close
to 9,000 Instagram, whatever, nine,
9,000 people looking at
pictures of my cats. Yeah.
There's a lot of pictures of my cat.
A squeaky frown in my underpants.
We'll tell about that in
that quickie from, yeah. Got
a dog named squeaky Fromme.
Yes. Yes. Girl. Did you read head? Oh,
female pit bull because he was red and
I found her wandering the streets of
Hollywood, just like Manson.
Well, my dog killed two dogs.
That's a pretty bad as well. I kind
of crazy dogs. Killed a boy dog.
She's not really, she's not around
anymore. She's not really squeaky.
Fromme then we had to take her out
of the blue. She was awesome though.
She had loved me anyway. Squeaky.
Fromme is my best friend.
I used to love squeaky Fromme my dark too,
so it's all good.
She gets troubled childhood. I got
her after I got her a little too late.
Wish she was already a year old
and already crazy. That cat.
I actually found while we will wrap it up,
we'll talk about my cats next time.
I got a lot of I could go on for hours.
Wait Ladies and gentlemen,
I know we asked a piece so we're going
to wrap this motherfucker up nice and
tidy. He's going to be a, you can see
me on comics unleashed with Byron Allen.
Don't do it.
Thanks to stamps.com use
the code word j. R. E n save
yourself some money thanks to teen.
Go to rogan.ting.com to save
yourself some cash as well.
Something's wrong with my Microsoft
word. Fork is happening here. Um,
and thanks to who else was on this one?
stamps.com oh, legal zoom.
Yeah. Legal Zoom bitches.
That's the newest one. A legal
zoom is a, our newest sponsor.
And if you go to legal zoom.com
and use the code word J,
r e you'll save yourself so much.
No, it's Rogan. That's it. Yeah.
Legal Zoom to get a special discount for
listening to the podcast and have the
code name Brogan in the referral
box for checkout. For more savings,
thanks to [inaudible] dot com as well go
to o n n I t and use the code named rug
and we'll be back tomorrow
with my pal Aubrey Marcus. And
uh, and that'll be it for the week
because I've got to go out squatch him.
I'm not done. I'm still, I'm looking for,
oh, I got a lot of crazy shit going on.
I know. Going in in the fall. Are
you really? Yeah. How dare you.
Bobcat Goldthwait thank you. See
you guys. We love you. Big Kiss.
Okay.