Oh Shit, you dirty bitches internationally
known and locally recognized.
Just recently escaped from
the government of Canada,
snuck across the border
back to the United States.
You must be so tired back
to the belly of the beast.
Back to the inside of the balls of
the Dick. That's fucking the world.
America. I fucking love Montreal
dude. I'm a little tired,
but we'll talk more.
The Joe Rogan experience is
brought to you by several things,
but before that full even
bring them the sponsors.
I want to thank Green Mountain grills
for hooking me up with this fucking bad
ass grill hooked me up with one of these
pellet grills. It's hardwood pellets.
They essentially take saw dust and they,
they,
they make these pellets out of it and
they use it to power your grill and it all
goes through.
It's all electrically fed.
So it keeps the temperature exactly
the same. Apparently all these, um,
this dude Eric who set it up gave
me the four, the four one one,
all these grills that they use
for these barbecue competitions,
they all use pellet grills now.
And the way these pellet grills work
is you don't have to light anything.
You don't have to fucking use
lighter fluid, but it's still wood.
And what it does is it all gets done in
cities like I hot coil and slowly but
surely the pellets get fed
through a machine to the hot coil.
It stays the same temperature.
Do I made some of the best fucking steaks
I've ever made on this thing? How long,
how long did it appellate's last?
Are they like one time user? I do,
you know [inaudible] he turns
to dust and vacuum it out.
It just like it just like charcoal dust
and then just buy new bags of pellets.
And it's amazing how efficient it is.
It's like one like little,
like you could take a couple of cups
full of pellets and you can cook a couple
of steaks.
Whereas if you think about how much
charcoal it takes because it's not that
efficient, you know when you
throw on the charcoal in there,
a lot of the heats lost to this
works in a convection of and way.
So as you close the lid on it and all
my God, it's so juicy and delicious. Oh,
what's the, what's the website I want to
look? That's a good question. It's uh,
they're called green mountain grills.
Oh, it's green mountain grills.com. Um,
I got the one called the Daniel Boone.
There's a,
there's a couple of different models,
but you can cook like
shoulders on these things.
Like you could do like crazy shit
like cook, like briskets and stuff,
like stuff that you would never do because
you're not going to be the smart guy
who's out there like knowing exactly
how much fire wood to put in the thing.
Cause you know,
if you,
if you're like smoking something that
traditional way you like have a box and
you've got to keep throwing wood
in it, that shit's wack. Okay.
You've got to get up in the middle of
the night and go put some wood in there
because you're fucking, your meats are
going to get cold. That's stupid as fuck.
You don't have to do that anymore.
Although there is something
pretty bad ass about that.
There's something like very
a craftsmen about that,
about getting up in the middle of
the night and stoking the fire.
Apparently there's this place in Austin,
Texas that has barbecue.
That's fucking insane are you should fear
went there and I saw it on the Anthony
Bourdain show too. It started off as a
food truck and this guy developed this,
this way of making brisket
that's fucking insane.
And he does it totally old school.
He gets up in the middle of the night,
throws wood in the fire, he knows the
right amount of shit to spray on the meat.
You're like,
it's all just simple salt and pepper
and like a little vinegar or something,
I don't know,
water or whatever the fuck is using,
but apparently it's unbelievable.
But let's be realistic folks.
You're not that fucking guy.
Okay.
And if you get one of these green mountain
grills, you can make like some ribs.
You could actually do this.
Can I tell you what my grill is like now?
I have a thermos grail.
It's five years old from
target 100 buckets from therm,
the thermos company. And,
uh,
I had some on steak and the insight paint
that black paint has started to come.
Oh, at the time. Yeah. It started, it
has started to come onto my meat now.
So I think it's, uh, it's probably
very toxic. What I'm eating now. Fun.
I just kind of,
you scratch it off,
but it's so gross because
every team you're me. Yeah.
And I think it's like not,
it's this kind of paint that
it's used to like, you know,
in four inside of grills.
So it's probably like heavy duty
baking, paint banking. Yeah. Yeah.
It's probably designed by the
government to keep idiots in check. Yes.
I might have to figure out a way to
get that paint chip, those nettle,
nettle fibers getting into your head.
That's the government man that I've never
even heard of that happening before.
That sounds terrible. That should
not happen. Right know, have, look,
if you're on a budget, man, just get
yourself one of those kettle grill.
So it was like Weber Kettle Grill.
Those are fucking bad ass and they're
not that expensive, relatively speaking.
That's a great, yeah. I'm one of those.
I have a Kamado which is very similar to
the egg. It's just a little bit bigger,
a little prettier. They make them
like artistic. But uh, I like,
I like cooking steaks on that
too. But there's this, this,
the beautiful thing about one of these a
pellet grills is that you can't fuck it
up. It tells you what
temperature it is. 500 degrees,
you know exactly how long to
cook it at 500 degrees. It's a,
it's pretty bad ass and you can, like I
said, he can do all kinds of shit within.
They're very nice.
Folks were also brought to you by Ting
Tang is a mobile company that we've been
uh,
representing on this podcast for a while.
Apparently there was some apprehension
about going with us. Brian,
a lot of people didn't believe
in the Joe Rogan experience.
I thought that maybe were a tad fringe,
maybe were half baked as it were.
Uh,
not that tech. Well, we were
slightly technically oriented.
You're far more technically oriented
oriented than I am. But, uh,
the reality is, um, it's
a, it's a great fit for us.
This tank company,
the reason being that it's
a company that's not trying
to rip anybody off there,
they're trying to make a
respectable profit, but they're not,
they're not offering you all the like
sneaky shit that exists and regular cell
phone contracts, like first of
all, the contract itself, you know,
you can't just get a phone,
you have to get a contract with
someone to get that phone activated.
And in most cases with them means is
if you want to cancel your service,
you have to pay, you know,
a, what they do is a,
apparently they sort of
move the numbers around.
When you buy a phone's like say if you
want to buy like an iPhone and if you go
to any big name, store,
whatever, you know, big name,
cell phone company and the,
and the name though,
when you're paying x amount of money,
it's normally more than that.
So they take that money away from the
price to sort of entice you into it.
But the deal is if you,
if you try to like take that phone and
then just cancel in a month and take your,
you know, x amount of dollars
savings, they'll, they'll,
they would lose a lot of money that way.
So the way they do it as they make
you pay that back, if you cancel ting,
doesn't fuck with that Tang.
Makes it very simple. They,
they offer you the best android phones.
You can get really cool ones. Like A,
I have the Samsung Galaxy s three,
and that's the one that's
coming to Brian to um, and a,
if you go to a brogan.ting.com fuck,
I think that's it.
Yeah. rogan.ting.com they'll
give you 50 bucks off of, uh,
any android phone when you start up.
They have a mobile hotspot,
four g mobile hotspot for 125 bucks.
Yeah. Dude, it's a fucking
great company, man. No,
no joke there on the sprint backbone.
So you don't have to worry about
any wonky fucking backwoods service.
It's an actual, real top
flight, cellular backbone.
And, um, because of that, they can,
they can offer you what a big name
company can offer you as well as offer you
what this ethical, small company
is, is trying to provide,
look, they have the cell phone tower
things that you put in your house.
So if you have bad service in your house,
it broadcast Internet.
Yeah. Juices it up. It says
something. What does it do? Let's,
let's read what it does.
So we don't give out into information
connects to the Internet and it
broadcasts a four g signal in your house.
So if you have like a live in a place
that has a sketchy neighborhood,
but you have great internet, you can
make your own Forgy tower pretty much in.
Really? Yeah. That's
incredible. That is good.
And it's using sprint's network and
because it's connected to your Internet,
I think that,
I think that's even better.
Sweet. Jesus. No, no. Does it get any
better than this? Ladies and gentlemen,
go to rogan.ting.com and save
yourself some money. And, uh,
Tim has been saying that they're getting
a lot of customers from this campaign
and a, we appreciate you guys supporting
the people that support us on the show.
And one of the things
that we will promise you,
100% always is said anything
we say on this show,
we're never going to bullshit you.
Anything we say is what we believe.
And if I'm wrong,
if I find out I'm wrong,
I'm going to fucking tell you
right away and apologize. Um,
everyone needs a whole phone.
Everyone needs a hoe phone. If a,
especially gay dudes, let's be honest,
you're not going to keep it together.
You're all guys. You're going to
get wacky. It's beautiful thing.
Celebrate it. Get yourself a tig
or if you're really gangster,
get when a virgin mobile fucking flip
phones and pretend to use that shift for
anything other than Dick.
Anybody sees you enter in their
number into that knows all this.
One of the fucker doesn't care about me.
This motherfucker's not hear from me.
rogan.ting.com excellent company.
They have a couple of things going him.
That's great. Besides the fact
that you don't have contracts.
One of them is that if you,
they have certain tiers like you know,
use x amount of minutes. I don't
know the exact system they have but,
or the plans that they have.
But what I do know is if you use
like what a lower plan would be,
they credit you on your next bill.
So no one's trying to rip you off.
They're trying to offer you the best
cell phone service available in a way
that's very ethical in a way that I
think is very generous and it makes it,
it makes you feel better about what
you're dealing with because you know what
else is out there, you know, you know,
if you can deal with a company like this,
like I would, I would, I like
to vote with my money, you know?
And when there's a company
like this that comes around,
it's doing something cool like this.
I like to support it.
And so that's why they're a,
that's why they're a part of the podcast.
We're also brought to you by [inaudible]
dot com and if you ever been on it
before, we got a whole
bunch of new shit, man.
Like fucking Buffalo Jerky is this
Tonka Buffalo Jerky that's made with
cranberries. We got killer bee honey.
Why do we have killer bee honey?
Because it's gangster as fuck.
That's why it's gangster as fuck to have
killer bee honey. Man. I don't even,
I tried it the other day. It tastes
like honey. I don't give a fuck.
I felt special. You don't have
grocery stores in my tea. Gotcha.
She had grocery stores will have like
problem with like lettuce, like Eh,
you know,
making people sick or something like that.
That seems like the least
dangerous thing ever.
But you're having killer bee
honey. Yeah, it's gangster.
That seems like you need that bigger
insurance costs are sexy. Dude. Seem sexy.
You want to rub that shit on your Dick.
I bet your deck would
just get hard and silly.
That killer events almost venomous.
It's probably delicious.
It's very good for you. Official
jellies are the new things that we have.
We have those for kids. Um, you know,
give kids a good dose of
Omega Threes v Fatty Acids,
which are very important for brain
function development. And uh,
a lot of people don't get them in their
diet so they make them in almost like a
candy. It's pretty cool. I just
started feeding it to my kids.
Hopefully it's not a science project.
My sister's daughter can't read my
fucking mind cause no kids from the past,
I forgot like fish oil pills.
What if the kid started their brains
start developing and control and it's the
next stage of evolution or not.
We also sell battle ropes and kettle
bells. We sell a fitness equipment.
That type of the type of shit that we
sale sell rather is all type of shit that
I would use. We also have, um, DVDs.
Now for a while people were saying like,
what's the best workout you can do online?
Well,
there's one that I always talked up,
so we just decided to start selling it.
It's called the extreme
kettle bell cardio,
a DVD and um,
it's,
this guy is a fucking animal.
My God's Keith Webber.
Fuck what a what a what a workout. This
is, it's so brutal. I do this shit.
We get to that. I do this, uh,
this thing with just 35 pounds
and you feel like such a,
it's amazing how tired you
can get with just 35 pounds.
You'd be amazed at,
like,
everybody thinks that it's like hard
to go to the gym and lift some weights.
Lifting weights is easy.
It's really easy.
You know what's really hard?
Lifting something that's not that heavy
all lot of times and doing it with your
whole body over and over and over
and over and over again. It's you,
you're breaking.
Everything just breaks down and it's
pretty safe because of the fact it's
unbelievable workout in
a short amount of time.
But you're not doing the type of things
that you do when you blow out discs and
it really fuck yourself up,
which is what a lot of people do when
they start lifting heavy weights.
Like everybody wants to be like super big.
And the way to get super big is you gotta
do like dead lifts and squats and all
that shit with heavyweights so
that your body goes, oh Jesus,
we got to get bigger.
Well, with kettle bells,
the beautiful thing is
you just get stronger.
It just makes your body acclimated to
doing a lot of like physical work that
will really manifest itself in real life
situations because you're using your
body all is one unit two, it'll help
you with picking up stuff. It'll,
it'll help you, you know, if you do any
sort of sport it'll help you. But I'm a,
I'm a huge, huge fan of kettle bells
both in, um, there's a, you know,
a bunch of schools of thought. Steve
Maxwell believes in like lower weight,
higher repetition, you know,
extreme, uh, you know, clean form.
And he's one of the masters of it as,
as Mike Mahler,
who's more of like a really heavyweight,
shorter,
smaller reps guy and he's fucking, that
guy's yoked as fuck. And he's a Vegan too,
which is incredible. Um,
I'm rambling. It's official.
Listen folks, go to [inaudible] dot com
get yourself some hemp protein powder.
You will not test positive.
Don't worry.
People need to have that explained
to them over and over again.
Hemp protein powder is one of the best,
most efficient protein powder for
your body to process. Um, but it's,
there's no THC in it so you can eat it
and it does not come up in your system.
Whereas like poppy seeds will come up
as morphine or heroin. This does not,
you don't have to worry about that there.
Hemp is completely non psychoactive,
but unfortunately we live in retarded
times and we cannot grow this plant in
America. We have to actually, it's
legal to have, you can even buy it.
You could bring it over here. You can
import it. Nobody has a problem with that,
but you cannot grow it. How
much sense does that make? Zero.
So they grow it in Canada. So, uh, they
grown in Canada and we have to buy it.
We can't even employ American farmers
on it. We wanted to start a farm.
We were like, it would be
beautiful because we know
that Vermont has a legal hemp
manufacturing and now I believe
because of what happened,
the the law that got passed and
cal in Colorado and Washington,
I think at least in one of those states,
you're supposed to be
allowed to grow hemp now too,
but the government will arrest you.
That's the bottom line on it. It's, it's,
it's all based on ignorance.
It's a completely non
psychoactive version of uh, the,
the cat,
the cannabis plant.
It's not the same thing as marijuana
and it's illegal all because of it as a
commodity and it's, it
stay there, hold it down,
and they keep it from farmers because
it could take away a lot of different
things.
Take them out of the market.
A lot of different things that
we consider standard, like ropes,
nylon ropes will actually, hemp is a
better fucking rope. You know, clothes,
cold clothes are made out of cotton.
Actually, if they were made it a hamp,
they'd be better. They're
more durable. Paper. It's, it
makes way better paper. It,
it makes so many things better and it's
illegal. And it doesn't get you high.
It's the whole thing is fucking crazy.
If it looked completely different than
pot and had a completely different name
and was not related, but it was
going through the same circumstances,
people would be up in
arms as they should be.
Farmers should be up in arms about this
because it's an incredibly good plant to
have on your soil. You can replenish
your crops in a short amount of time.
It grows very fast. It's very
healthy. You don't need pesticides.
It's an incredibly strong plant. It's
good for so many different fucking things,
and if you try to grow it,
they'll put you in a cage.
They will take all your money.
They will separate you from your family.
They will lock you in a cage if
you try to grow this awesome plant.
So that's why hemp protein
powder cost so much, folks.
It's fucking stupid and
it's fucking ridiculous.
In 2012 wake up, you
freaks. Wake the fuck up.
Go get yourself some Alpha brain
and think this shit through.
Go get yourself a blender.
We can no longer offer the BLENDTEC
blenders with a free hemp force.
They have ra, they have Lou rules as to
how you sell shit because it doesn't,
it just makes it too desirable.
Maybe you should have a thing like every
time you sell over $300 you get a free
him force.
Can't do it. Oh like anything
from this from that's a good idea.
Like anything from the whole store.
Yeah, we'll put that into play.
We'll speak to Aubrey about that.
Get that shit in motion. All right.
This fucking commercials really long and
Tim Ferriss is here so let's get this
party started.
You dirty anything to add?
Anything promote isn't
going on and he shows,
oh, I'll be with Doug Benson Wednesday
and San Diego at the American Comedy Co.
Jesus Christ son, comedy co.com. It's
a good club down there too. Very,
very perfect little comedy club and
we'll have a desk squad show there.
The 12 1212 also and I think there's a,
the other place is really good too.
That Matt House. Yeah, that place is
good. I want you to go, there you go.
Make a comeback. Bitches. All right
folks. That's it. It's fucking,
let's get a girl hit that. Hit
that button. Let's talk. Yeah.
Crazy.
The Joe Rogan experience.
Try it my day.
Joe Rogan podcast by night all day.
Boom.
Bitches back with new
knowledge and information.
Tim Ferriss joins the podcast. My brother,
thank you for coming back, man. Oh,
it's great to be back. I've been looking
forward to this one for months. Dude.
I've been looking forward
to how you want to.
I'm a glad we were able to work this out
time wise. You're very busy character.
You too. Do you have a four day
marriage? Is that out yet? You know,
people have asked for the floor
for our marriage and I'm like,
you know, that'd be easy to
write given the rate of divorce.
It's like I can find it.
I can do those interviews for our
Presidency Ninja until I figure it out.
It's not going to read a book for
our CEO. Yeah. A lot of those too.
There's a lot of those too.
Yeah. Um, your, uh, your new
book is, what is it called?
The four hour commercial. That's
me, man. I'm the master. That shit.
The four hour chef,
four hour chef.
Simple path to cooking like a pro
learning anything in living the good life.
It's a very narrow scope that's
not announced scope at all.
How dare you confusing me. I'm not
as smart as you settle down. Well,
this is the second. This is probably the
first time I've actually had some TAC,
my system since the last podcast. Well
that's ridiculous. What a coincidence.
Attribute that to Tim Ferriss is pure
knowing that the government is listening
and all. So we always like to
hydrogen like the government.
Know you guys are talking about trying
to pretend like the government is spying
on us. But meanwhile we broadcast
his shit on our Internet show.
That's how you know you're
a stoner. You're like, dude,
what if the governments listen
to his podcast right now? Dude,
thousands of people who listen to
this fucking thing right now. Oh yeah.
Fuck the government. Why are
they listening? Why do they care?
Um, for our government, is that
possible? Maybe that we form government.
We might be past that point. You could
have a four hour countdown clock.
Do you think that's happening? Well,
you worried? Yeah, I'm worried.
Are you worried about, uh, what's going
on in Israel and the Gaza Strip on board?
Not only about that but also honestly,
but just the financial integrity this
entire country. Yeah. And it seems fake.
All right. I know exactly. And you
know, the financial integrity. So yeah,
there's a really,
there's a really good book called the
biography of a dollar which talks about
just the development of the currency
of the US dollar and where it is today.
And the conclusion of all of those books
is basically like buy shotguns by food.
We'll get something in a
different currency. And um,
what was kind of wild is,
so what I was looking at the uh,
doing research for the four hour chef and
we've got into this the wild stuff and
we can talk about that,
but like the foraging and tufting
and all these things that never done.
And I went a little bit off the rails and
started meeting all these survivalists
and preppers and whatnot.
And so I ended up writing like 150
pages that to cut because I just went
ballistic in more ways than one just
to researching all this shit. But, uh,
and I had a number of close
friends in San Francisco, New York,
thought I was fucking nuts. And then
hurricane sandy comes along. Whoa.
So they thought that you were taking this
way too far and you had lost your mind
and you were proposing and probable
scenarios and then hurricane sandy and now
everybody has to think it's
amazing how fragile our,
our life is here on this
planet. We essentially, you
know, live without a roof.
Most of the time the world is
a convertible. Yeah. You know,
and above us is all this shit
is flying around. There's,
there's like thousands of times every day
a piece of rock from outer space comes
into the atmosphere and burns up.
Yeah. Like people need to wrap
their heads around that. All right.
This is crazy.
This does not have to,
just because this has been here as a
city for a hundred years doesn't mean it
has to stay like this.
Yeah.
Well, no, exactly. And um,
so Nassim Taleb who wrote the
Black Swan fooled by randomness,
he's a really good example,
which is, you know,
the Turkey thinks that things
are going great all the,
all the way up until thanksgiving,
you know,
like just the fact that he's had 364
days of live in pretty doesn't mean three
65 is going to be very brilliant.
I always use if my,
my analogy is the ant hill analogy that
there could be an ant hill that exists
in a field and it's a big ant hill and
these ants have been working in this ant
hill for God knows how long and they only
live for like a short amount of time.
So it's been there long
before they were ever born.
This ant hills existed in its
many fucking complicated caverns.
And then one day this little kid comes
along and stops the fucking shit out of
that hill and no one saw it coming.
It never happened before.
So they never even considered it.
They just fucking go about their day.
And this little kid comes along and
stomped the shit out of that anthill.
And that's exactly what
happened with Hurricane Katrina.
That's exactly what happened with Sandy.
That's what could happen with
Yellowstone Jeliboo. Yeah.
Or any sort of an earthquake. I mean,
I have a friend who has a house.
He has a vacation house on the
beach in Malibu. It is so bad ass.
You sit there and be like, you're
on the ocean. And it's like,
it's such a humbling experience to
have an, it's like something like very,
it just connects you.
It's some weird way to nature
when you're staring at that water.
I think that's why beach
communities are so chill. You know,
beach communities are like,
every day you're confronted with this
reality that you ain't shit. Okay.
You stop and look out there,
do it.
As far as you can see is
water and you die out there.
You can't make it.
And if for some reason it just
switches back and forth a little,
it's going to wipe out everything for
a hundred miles in like it's nothing.
Okay. So settle the fuck down and
stop taking yourself so seriously.
Like that's the feeling that you
get when you're right next to water.
I think that's important for people.
I think
it is. I think it's also the, the sort of
meditative aspect of the, of the waves.
I think
I have,
it gives you a feeling,
it gives you like a peaceful feeling
when you're like sitting around and like,
you're in Hawaii and you look
at it that water, you know,
you're on top of a volcano,
you know the shit is temporary as fuck,
but you're like, I didn't. Yeah, right now
it's beautiful right now. It's amazing,
you know,
or to, you know, I grew up on long
island way out at the end and apart.
What does that like mes at Montauk.
So I grew up as a townie,
like a rat rat tail
wearing townie Hamptons.
And you start thinking
about, let's just say, uh,
you know, climate change.
And then you look at the,
the wealth concentration in the first
10 to 20 miles of every coastline.
It's like 80% of the world's wealth
would just be wiped out if there's a
dramatic temperature change.
And with Hurricane Sandy,
what's, what's not amused,
it's depressingly amusing to me is when
people are like, oh, that's a one in 100,
one in 1,000,001. And if you look at,
uh, there was a piece in nature magazine,
this is just in the last,
I think few months where they said if
climate change continues as predicted,
100 year storms will have
to happen every three years.
I took a,
uh,
a training course in San Francisco
that was done by the police department,
the fire department,
which was the northern California
emergency response training nerd.
And in the first class, this
is the police. This isn't
some Wacko like paranoid,
uh, dooms doomsday a predictor. He
said, all right, let's do an exercise.
How many people are there
in San Francisco? Something
like, wow, I don't know,
whatever, 800,000. Right,
okay. If everyone's commuting
in like a couple of million,
whatever it might be.
Okay.
How many fire engines do you
think there are in San Francisco?
And everyone's like 102
hundred 50 whatever it was.
It was something like 19 and he said,
what that means is if you look at like
the Loma Prieta earthquake in 1989 it
could be seven to 10 days
before anybody gets to, like,
you cannot rely on the existing
structure and that kind of blew my mind.
I was like, even though it's amazing, 10
days, it's amazing. Get it done that fast.
I after Sandy, I'm like,
well, there's look,
they don't have a backup plan for
something massive. You know what?
They have coffins. Yeah, right.
They have those plastic coffins.
They save up in case a
fucking asteroid hits us.
They don't have like some
crazy plan to feed everybody.
They have a plan to go overseas
and Jack people and take their oil.
No plan to take care of the people in
case if there's some sort of an earthquake
or something. Oh yeah, no, there's,
there's no possible response
that would cover it.
And so would you know what I figured out
is I started doing the math and I was
like, well, I spend, because I've
broken myself like a thousand times,
I spend 500 $600 a month
in health insurance and I
don't even have 20 gallons of
water and food and a
shotgun and a few things,
which would cost what,
500,000 bucks total onetime cost.
I have a friend who has a solar powered
house. That's cool. That's cool.
That's gotta be the way to go.
Especially out here and just
even a cheap generator. Like, uh,
I had the power go out on my block in
San Francisco for 24 hours and I realized
all my food is going bad. I had like
80 pounds of meat, no power supplies.
So I got a,
I think it's a Honda.
I like to EU 2009 I
generator that's popular,
popular burning man and then a bunch of
extra gasoline and I would not buy it
just for that. Well, I can
get a burning smell every,
I can go to burning man with the rest
of San Francisco to see all my friends.
Why don't I smelled like petroleum?
Listen burning man. People relax.
I'm just joking. I don't what you
getting angry at me? Fuck you dude.
Why is it aggro problem with burning man?
I don't really,
I'm just completely joking.
Can you just say shit just to say shit
sometimes everybody's going to take
everything so fucking seriously. Um, yeah,
I think that generators
are an awesome idea. Yeah,
that's a good idea to have around.
It's far though.
If live in an apartment
with the fuck do you do,
then you could actually pull it off and
the owners and I thought I figured this
out.
Open the window or something.
And then you just have to have an exhaust
exhaust pipe going out the window.
So you get some coil up thing. In
that case. How long does it stay on?
It depends on the gasoline.
You have a,
I mean I have maybe 10 gallons of
gasoline and this, this generator. What's,
what's great about it is it looks like
an old school like desktops server or
really? Yeah, it's tiny. It looks like one
of those towers. It's not heavy at all.
It probably weighs 30 pounds.
And how does the gas tank connect to it?
What does it look like?
Cause it like you pour the gasoline right
right into the generator itself. Yeah.
It's really well done. How old? How many
gowns? I don't know. Off Hand. Yeah,
I found I had it.
So how long does it stay with like
one fill up and you turn it on?
How long does it stay on? I honestly am
not sure I have everything ready to go,
but I couldn't fit more than a 10
gallons of gasoline in my apartment.
Isn't it fucked up.
Thinking about that.
Like thinking about alternative
ways to keep the power on.
That's fucking terrifying.
Yeah.
Everyone should at least get a Red Cross
endorsed hand wind up powered radio,
which also doubles as a charger. You can
get these for like 40 bucks on Amazon.
Power's out. Won't the radio
be out too? Well it can. Uh,
you can actually use
different frequencies.
So I mean like the ham
radio is crazy as it seems,
is actually a pretty good to have
a pretty good skill to pick up.
Like that's what the fire
department police department,
they're like all those wines are the catch
patos right. It could be one of them.
Or Dungeons and dragons players
again,
which I was not slamming Ralph.
That's what you are gray alf has a grail.
Wow. Yeah. Um, you had 80
pounds of meat in your house.
I'll have more now. I have about 120
pounds. Three charters. Are you eating?
Are you eating homeless? Cleaning up
the streets, gentrify your neighborhood.
Try it. And so we have a, we have a
mutual friend now. Steve Rinella. Yeah.
And uh, I, so just to give some
context. So growing up on long island,
Steve Rinella,
for folks who don't know a meat mediator,
he's an author actually as well.
It's got a book called [inaudible],
which is fantastic. Brilliant. Right?
It's a very good, brighter man. Yeah,
I'm really good. Very
bright guy. So I met,
I met Steve when I was investigating how
to reconnect with ingredients as part
of this book.
And I think above and beyond that how
to correct like manual illiteracy,
right?
So one of the things that really started
to bother me in the last few years is I
looked at like what my dad could do,
my granddad could do,
I can't fix half the things on my car.
I can't do basic like woodwork.
I can't do any of that shit.
And I realized it was really causing
me a lot of anxiety not to build things
with my hands. So food and foraging
and all this stuff became another way,
are one way to try to reclaim that.
And then Steve,
I met through a bunch of different
random circumstances. Uh,
and what he countered was my image of a
hunter because growing up on long island,
I had a lot of injured deer come across
my property from people who didn't know
how to bow hunt beer cans
on the side of my, on this,
on like my side of my driveway.
And I just developed this real hatred.
It was that strong for hunters and
just saw them as really responsible,
wasteful kind of jerk offs. And then I
met Steve and uh, so I'll give a little,
you've probably heard this story, but what
blew me away about Steve is he'll say,
look,
there are a lot of better hunters than me,
although he's a really good hunter.
And I said,
there are a lot of better cooks than me,
but I'm a decent cook.
But they're very few people
who can put them together.
And so he took for one of his
books, I guess was the, uh,
scavengers guide to Haute cuisine.
He,
he took this 1906, uh, scoffed a banquet.
SCAF he's like the grandfather of
French cuisine, three day banquet,
like 40 different dishes with all this
weird shit, sting rays and you know,
quail stuffed with steer
Chin or who the fuck
no was he served people raccoon that
he found on the side of the road. Yeah.
And he would,
he didn't.
Particular three day banquet is,
he killed and forged everything.
He got every ingredient then read and
then recreated the entire three day thing
himself. Guy's a stud. Yeah. He's
an amazing dude. Oh, so for the,
he took me on my first ever hunt,
which was a white tail deer hunt.
And then most recently we went to
Alaska for about a week in the middle of
nowhere to hunt Caribou.
So we are successful both times I was,
yeah,
that was so the whitetail deer was your
first experience the first time and
where did you go there?
That was South Carolina
because in California you
have to fill out like a phone
books worth of paperwork to get anything
done with hunting in South Carolina,
you just buy the hunting license
online and you're done. Beautiful
people of South Carolina.
God bless you.
God bless you for fucking keeping the
bureaucracy and check. Um, so you,
your idea about wanting to hunt was
probably similar to what my idea was.
It was like, I eat meat. I
have no connection to it.
I'm just buying it as to,
I know this isn't healthy. It's a kid. I,
I likened it to the
idea of being born rich.
It's like I didn't really understand
what it was like to earn it.
I didn't in any way,
shape or form.
And there's a lot of people that have a
lot of misunderstandings about hunting
too. And I shared those when I was young.
I, I had a very ignorant appearance, uh,
opinion on hunting too. I just
thought it was just people who like,
why would you kill an animal and you
can just go to the store and get it for
free or you know,
buy it without to have to deal with that.
Like these people probably
want to kill animals. Like,
well why don't you
leave the animals alone?
Then one day I was driving from a Gig,
I was in Boston or in New York rather
and I was an upper western Massachusetts
and I had to drive down and I got to go
like 30 fucking miles an hour cause he's
dear just kept jumping in front of my car.
It was crazy.
I just kept seeing them over
and over and over again.
They were all over the road. So I had
to drive really slow on the way home.
And it was a really common thing on this
one parkway where deer would get hit by
cars.
Yeah.
I mean it was an infestation because
if you're looking at that much on the
actual road, off to the right and off
to the left, there's fucking woods,
man. So who knows how many
God damn deer there. Those
deer, first of all, they're
going to get hit by cars.
They're going to starve because
they're going to run out of food.
And if they don't have hunters
managing that population,
there's only one other option.
And that option is predators.
So you have two options.
You have something that can kill a fucking
deer with its face and you're going
to have a good population of
those motherfuckers running
around and you're just
going to trust that they're not going
to get you and your dog and your kids,
or you're going to,
you're going to manage that population
by shooting them and eating them. Yeah.
And it's a,
it's a really fascinating
sort of a situation when
you really understand it for
what it is.
Like it's wildlife management.
They have to do this because we
are at the top of the food chain.
So we have to take responsibility
for that situation.
We have game and it's everywhere.
And if you don't eat it slowly but surely
that mountain lion population is going
to start creeping up. That's just
how nature deals with shit or that,
or the human population's going to start
dropping because they become disease
vectors for things like lymes disease.
And my brothers had lives these,
my dad's had Lyme disease, upstate
New York. It's a real issue. Yeah,
I've heard quite a few people get it.
Yeah, it's too, there's only one issue.
There's a, there's a lot and
the fucking, it's great meat.
It's like really good for you.
It's better for you than cows you buy in
a store that had been fed corn and uh,
other, an unnatural things for cows.
It's way healthier for you. Um, my,
my experience was a, my whole
life. I'd thought about it one way.
And then that one trip home I started
reconsidering like, this is fucking crazy.
And then I started looking at, but there
was no internet back then, you know,
so I'd have to like read a book,
which is really annoying.
I've sat down there and I mean,
I don't mind reading a book now,
but when I was 20 or whenever the
fuck this was, you know, like why,
why the fuck are so many deers?
And then as I looked into all this shit,
I realized like, oh, they'd like, they,
there's arguments about managing them
and they're just like, get the game,
the fish and game and the hunters and
like everyone has to come to an agreement
of how many there are. And I go, what?
This is crazy. You've got these fucking,
they're like rats.
They're like giant rats.
Giant rats are run in front of your car
and commit suicide. It's fucking bananas.
Um,
and they,
they taste delicious and then you could
shoot that with this and it's free.
You just have to pay for the license
and then hit him in the right spot.
They get this stressed than
meat's no good. Oh, is that true?
It can make it really a distasteful
if you get what's called a red cutter.
So for instance, if you fuck it up and
you injure it and then you chase it,
what you shouldn't do,
number one,
if you get a good shot and then you
finally kill the thing, um, the, the, uh,
the access of adrenaline and whatnot
can really can, is that true?
Because my deer, I shot it and went down
and it was, uh, it was going to die,
but it was still alive in the next shot.
It again, I had to shoot it again. Yeah.
I think it depends a lot on the
duration of that sort of that stress.
So what happens a lot, for
instance, of novice bow hunters,
and I'm not above a hundred.
Like they'll go in the woods for hours
with a bow and then instead of waiting
for it to dial, chase it and we'll
run and run around, run around,
run for like an hour.
Right. And that, and then drop. But that's
flooded with adrenaline. Yeah. I mean,
and again, I'm super nervous,
but based on what Steve told me,
also like depending on what gender dear
you hit and if it's during mating season
or not. So if you hit like a ruddy
buck is just pumped full of hormones,
naturally occurring hormones,
then I can end up being pretty.
And what if that's an aphrodisiac when
the deer is like super horny and you eat
it's meat but seems kind of homosexual.
I gotta be honest with you. I don't
think there's anything wrong with that.
But if it works,
it works.
I mean like what you're eating tiger
dicks or whatever the fuck it is.
A Chinese people. Yeah, you're kind
of not tasty. It's very, I mean it's,
it's Inter Inter species, you
know, you're mixing species up,
but it's also sort of homosexual anyway.
Yeah. I have the whole penis in China.
Not Tasty.
I don't recommend it.
We serve that shit on fear factor and
served a water buffalo dicks. I saw that.
I saw that upset when you had all the
different variations. That was just one,
one time where I was like,
this is the most ridiculous job on earth.
The other time was when we served
them. Um, donkey seaman. Ugh, that's,
that's what canceled the show. They got
so crazy. They serve donkey seating.
The producers lost their fucking minds
and soda at NBC because NBC said Yes to
it. That's the dirty secret about
the last season of fear factor.
They approved NBC approved,
sucking down a big golf of
donkey come. They're like, Yup,
that seems like good thing to put on
TV. Let her rip as disgusting. Dude.
It was the only time.
There's only been two times when I
disagreed with the producers. I said,
you really shouldn't do this. One time
when we made them ride bowls, I was like,
this is crazy. This is, you can't
control this. This is, this is not good.
I didn't like it. And then the other
time when we made them drink calm,
I just never thought I'd have to say that.
I'd never thought I'd have to say,
I don't think he should serve those
people at donkey coffee. It's just,
it just doesn't see,
it just seems like we're crossing a line.
If you'd like this job
and you want to keep it,
and then TMZ got ahold of it,
they put the pictures of it online and
then NBC said Polish Owl Polish out.
They pulled the episode.
What response did they expect?
They were thinking,
man,
if I'm the guy who's telling you
you're crossing the line. Yeah,
you're already there.
You know I'm a pothead cage fighting
commentator and I'm telling you,
you're going to far,
everything in my life is fucked up.
Every everything I do, whether it's
standup comedy or this podcast,
everything could be considered fucked
up. And I'm like, you're going crazy.
I'm like, you get it. You get
into chicky over here. You gotta,
you gotta let that one go.
You can't, they can't drink.
Come and pissed by the way we serve them.
Pissed too.
Nobody seem to care as
much about the piss.
I wouldn't care as much about the past.
The past is they just drank it and
nobody complained about the pit.
So it was always the donkey come
and it always was like, again,
it was like some sort of beastiality thing
in people's minds because it's a body
fluid and we know where it came from.
Like milk.
Yeah, but it's not like we're
asking them to have sex.
It's so funny a week people connect,
flex sex with the fluids at sex creates,
you know,
it's like drinking the like,
you know you're no where near that
donkey when it comes, but drinking,
it's come somehow or another
is a sex with that donkey.
I'm not sure I could rationalize myself.
The drinking donkey come like as hard
as I tried to make it into the like and
thought exercise.
Well what's fucked up is two people
had a drink and they didn't want shit.
That's what's fucked up cause
everybody drank it. Yeah.
One guy and two girls drank
it and they were nice people.
That's what's even more fucked
up than there were very nice.
Always the nice quiet time drank the
donkey semen for all of them. They were,
I mean it was like he took,
occasionally you have a show where
someone will try too hard or they're build
noxious.
We didn't have any of that.
This last season of fear
factor was they were,
everyone was like really there a knife.
Nice folks.
So I felt bad sitting down
there drinking talky come.
I'd hate to see it digested like the
next morning shit sitting on the toilet
blowing out. Quite honestly.
It's very similar to phlegm.
So it's like drinking almost like
drinking a big glass of phlegm.
You know it's really very similar. It's
very similar in its texture. And you know,
I dunno about taste cause you
know I never tried phlegm.
Ha wonder if you get the job,
where the fuck is his podcast?
What have you flagged when you
flush the toilet after digesting,
if it's like a super fast,
like a flesh is really,
really fast because it's slippery
because of all the phlegm, right? Hmm.
I don't know what kind of,
Oh what the fuck you're saying
you need to go to a doctor.
Frill need to go to a doctor and just
tell him that you propose that and he'll
sit you down and go,
something's wrong with your brain.
Um, so, uh, your first deer hunting
experience was in North Carolina,
was it South Carolina? Which
is the gun. Oh, would you?
It was gone.
I didn't want to,
my biggest fear going into all
of that was fucking up the shot.
It was really worried about just maiming
the deer and then it takes away like
hitting of the leg or something. I was
really worried about that. So I took,
I really got into the
marksmanship super serious.
It was actually just down here a couple
of weeks ago doing sniper training with
some of the La Swat team members.
Oh yeah. There's a great,
a company called itts that does
trainings are fucking, they were great.
But prior to that,
so that the deer,
I used a seven millimeter Remington
mag that I actually use Steve's gun,
which is a lefthanded too. It's
a nice gun. It's great gun.
I have since had a right handed version
of that made with a couple of changes.
So it's like a his and hers, soon
millimeter of Steve Vernella now. Nice.
But I used, I used his gun and a man, he's
a great teacher. I mean that's part of,
there's, I want to put them in the
book. He is a fucking outstanding,
outstanding teacher.
Well he knows what he's doing.
All aspects of uh,
the whole a hunting thing cause it's his,
his attachment to it isn't
just hunting. It's also to, um,
just the,
the history of the United States and,
and the people that lived
in the land of the, the uh,
American Indian hitter
heritage and the stories.
He had some amazing American
Indian stories. Like really, uh,
I should say native American stories.
Really,
really interesting stuff about that
whole area where we went to Montana,
to the Missouri River.
The rosary breaks. Yeah.
And he had just incredible stories,
story after story.
So he's a guy that like really embraces
the history of a region two and the,
the history of the wildlife there as well.
How the uh,
migrate with the numbers used to be like,
and you know, we, we occasionally would,
uh,
look for buffalo bones cause they're
like really common in the sides of hills.
You know, you see like the, when
the Strada wears away you'll,
you'll find like these old ass
fucking buffalo bolts. Krill. Yeah,
that's super cool. It's
pretty bad ass. And Steve,
I mean he grew up hunting with his
brothers. Obviously this dad as well.
And I think his brothers,
they're both in the sciences,
but I believe they're Bostick both
ecologists and it's just such,
it's a fascinating family.
And I mean Steve,
I guess he's been writing for money
for whatever it is, a decade maybe.
But he started trapping
in from honey in Rome,
Michigan and he was like 10. Yeah. Yeah.
He was talking about how his dad pulled
him out of school for a first day of
trap and, and first day of hunting
season. That's like how he grew up.
I think that's fucking awesome.
But it's,
it's fascinating because
everybody immediately, if
you think of a guy like that,
you think of a dumb guy. You think of
an uneducated guy and unworldly guy,
he's the exact opposite of total opposite.
Brilliant guy, brilliant guy. Very,
very well read and a really
fun to talk to. You know,
he's inquisitive is intelligent,
you know,
he's on the ball but he's the
real fucking deal, you know?
And he expects that from other
people as well. You know,
you go on a hunt with them, you're
going on. I mean you're, you're going,
it's legit. Yeah. When we were in
Alaska where we got dropped off,
I was like five hours in
north of Fairbanks flight
time and we got dropped off
on the side of a lake by a Bush plan.
And I like seeing awake pace.
I'll get eaten by bears.
And then Lo and behold,
it never got dark because we were,
we were above the Arctic circle and we
had two huge grizzly bears repeatedly
tried to come into our camp because the
people before us would let the fucking
gut pile of Caribou like 200 yards upwind.
So we had these two huge
bears come in and uh,
Steve was so funny cause everyone's like,
oh fuck grizzly bear like 10 o'clock.
And it's like, I dunno, ETA three minutes.
And then Steve found that his found
out his cell phone had been like in the
bottom of his bag and was
soaked with deet. And he's like,
fuck my fucking cell phone.
Everyone's like Steve,
a grizzly bear ETA three minutes.
He's like my fucking cell phone.
She's like so unconcerned about this
grizzly bear. And then he's just like,
all right, fine, fuck it.
And he picks up a shotgun,
like walks over with birdshot like starts
firing it off and waving his arms and
scaring it off from like,
that's all you need to do a hundred yards.
But here's the thing, a hundred yards to
a bear, that's not a slow animal. Right?
So he's got some big balls.
I scared it off the thing that
running back like two hours later,
but to say about him after he gets
fucking eaten, you know exactly.
He big balls and the
bear ultimately eight.
So they set about grizzly
man until the very end.
He really knows those bears
stay safe. Yeah. I think Steve,
Steve is fine to be within a hundred yards
of the bear as long as he has a good,
a good a firearm. Yeah.
You got to really, um,
when you straw inspecting
the fucking Grizzly,
that's when the grizzly takes
care of you to shoot a grizzly.
Like you can't shoot it with
like a little pistol. No.
You need to hit it with like a slug
because you're not going to stop them.
It's going to take years for them to die.
Like if you shoot it,
if you shoot a big grizzly with a
fucking nine millimeter, you know,
he tried to go gangster rapper style on
them. That's not going to kill a bear.
Keep running at you and you're going
to be so scared when it eats your head.
Yeah.
If people underestimate how hard
it is to kill an animal like that,
depending on the circumstances.
I was talking to a friend of mine who's
a navy seal and he sees still enlisted,
I mean he does deployments and everything,
but he was at one point in Africa and
these villagers in sort of the downtime
knew these guys were with the
military and they said, hey,
could you help us call this herd of water
buffalo because they're destroying all
our property and blah blah blah.
We can make food out of the boat,
the buffalo that you
kill you. I'm like, sure.
So they had these long range sniping
rifles and he said that and he's a damn
good shot.
I've done some training with them and he,
and he said that he shot a water buffalo
right in the corner of the eye and the
thing like shook his head and then looked
straight back at him and just kept on
eating. Like what? Yeah, the
fucking skulls like that thick.
And it had like gone halfway in the
skull and just lodged with a high power
rifle.
And the thing just kept on eating.
And so like that is what would happen if
you didn't place your shot with a bear.
And forget it.
Like if the grizzly powered rifle and it
couldn't get through his fucking head,
they had to aim the,
ended up having to aim at the base of
the skull from the side of the bag.
It's don't shoot him in the head.
Became the, became the rule.
That's a big fucking animal.
Yeah. Well when I was, uh,
I was in Africa doing research for this
book too. I went on to India, Japan,
all over the place.
Then in the one lunar in South Africa.
What a buffalo kill everybody. I mean,
people are afraid of that. The lions,
but you, if you meet,
let's say the Masai Mara,
these warriors who are like jump up
and down, the famous for the red robes,
they're not free to lines at all.
They will,
they'll walk off into the darkness with
their big walking stick going from one
village to the next. They're like, Eh,
like big house cats will scare him off
water, Buffalo, hippo and elephants.
Those are the ones that are all afraid
of because they'll just charge you and
kill you.
Yeah.
Water buffaloes are big fuck and
tourists get out of their cars on safari.
They're like, oh, let's take a
picture with the, and then the cows
are like cow Lamborghini
bowls and then they get,
I've talked about this a
bunch lately, so I can't, uh,
I can't really go into it again, but yeah.
Have you seen relentless enemies? No.
This was what I'm talking about.
I've talked about it so many times
in the podcast. You have to watch it.
It's a documentary.
I'll just give you the brief documentary
about a part of Africa where the rivers
changed courses and it's isolated.
These lions with water buffalo,
that's their only prey.
So the lines of grown enormous.
The female lions are the size of male
lions. It's an amazing documentary.
There's a couple different prides in the
silent, but one of them is fucking huge.
They're like hulk lions. That's awesome.
They just jack and water buffaloes, man.
That's how they have to do it now.
And you see how big a fucking water
buffalo is when you see five lions
struggling to take it to stay down
there. No joke. Fuck that man.
If you see when those things in
the wild do not fuck with it. Yeah.
Apparently back in the day,
like that was a big deal with buffalo too.
Like if you, if you got near at
Buffalo and the buffalo charged you,
I saw a video of a guy getting charged
by a buffalo on youtube. You know,
you don't think for whatever reason
that you're gonna die by Buffalo.
But that moment when that thing is going
through and you realize how fucking big
it is and you go,
what am I doing here?
I'm in fun of this crazy fucking
star wars looking animal. Yeah.
You're going to get hit by something
always weighs more than a Volkswagen Golf
with, with skull plates on the its
head, not gonna end well at all.
It must have been amazing back in the
day when the native Americans would run
into these Kurds that was far as the eye
could see of these things because they
really didn't have many natural
predators. No, not at all. I mean wolves,
but it takes a lot fricking wolves
to take down a buffalo. Yeah,
they probably were fine.
It must have been so many wolves.
The wolves Musta ate great
because there was so many buffalo.
What other being after the saber tooth
tiger, which was what? The place to scene,
what was that like 14,000 years ago?
Was that what it was when the,
the wooly mammoths and saber tooth
tigers also she goes to what other animal
would eat them?
It will only be wolves and mountain lions
where I could a mountain lion even I
take out,
I don't think so because I think mount
line more as a stock and pounds type of
animals opposed to the
endurance running like,
I don't know if you've seen planet earth,
the series where they have an
aerial shot of wolves hunting.
I think it was a Caribou may have been
an elk and how they basically the wolves
would run, this is trippiest thing.
When you see it from the air, they'll,
they're almost like a Peloton
and the Tour de France,
so they have like the wolf in the front
who is tiring out the Caribou and then
like the replacement runner will come
from the back and fill in and that guy
will drop back and say they just run
this relay race where they, they,
they tag in and tag out on running this
animal until it drops and then then they
take it out. Holy Shit. Like persistence
hunting sort of. Exactly. Yeah. Yeah,
exactly.
Which they still do and certain
parts of Africa they,
they'll chase over. Yeah.
Gazelle or whatever the fuck it is down
until it just runs out of gas. Yeah,
pretty wild. And then they stab
it. Fuck. How long does that take?
I guess that could only be done in a
place like Africa where you need the heat
and you'd also need the higher heat. Oh,
right, right, right. Animal to overheat.
You right, right, right.
That makes sense because that was
the weirdest thing about a deer.
When you open them up, how hot they
are and the only side it's like,
it's really kind of like, whoa.
It's a real eye opener. Yeah.
What was really trippy. So the
field dressing, right. So I was,
I was much more interested in what happens
after pulling the trigger then before
you stock this dear.
How'd you do it this year?
The first year this was done from blind,
so it was really,
didn't have to work as hard on the hunt.
Certainly compared to Caribou with
the Caribou, we did have to stock.
So you did both with Rinella?
We did both. Which is an ally.
And the first one when,
how long ago was it first one that had
to be a year and a half ago or maybe even
a slightly less because he had
the other show the wild within?
Uh, no, no, I don't think
so. It was a new show.
So the deer hunt was not filmed for
mediator. The caribou hunt was a,
for me to hit her.
So the deer hunt was just you guys?
The deer hunt was just because I, I
met Steve and I said, you're my guy.
If I am ever going to hunt,
like you're the guy who's good,
who is the best option for
guiding this and got along and uh,
both have pretty fucking strange senses
of humor and went to South Carolina and
you think he has a strange sense of humor?
I think he has a,
he can depends on how much wine we've had.
Uh,
when we were camping,
what was great is we had these fucking
bags of wine because they were from the
boxes, but they had been taken out
and they looked just like an ivy bag.
So I've been like fantasizing about
getting these like rolling carts from the
hospital,
like supply store and just get any
fucking ivy bags of wine that people can
drink for like a camel back at dinner,
just to creep the shit out of everybody.
Those camelbaks or fun.
Either you, you, um,
you were in a warm weather area.
Was it a warm weather time
south in South Carolina? It was.
So we had to be really careful
about keeping all the meat cool.
That's part of the
reasons that you need to,
one of the reasons you need to remove the
internal organs so quickly so that the
meat doesn't spoil. Right. And uh,
what was super trippy for me because I've
just never experienced anything quite
like it was when I was
doing the field dressing,
maybe a minute or two into the process.
Like I just felt like I had done it
before and I had this like hard wiring
moment where, uh, I was just
really good at it and it's done.
That doesn't happen with many things.
And I was starting to ice and made me
think about like how to orphan cats,
know how to hunt, how to orphan
to anything, fill in the blank.
I see no more specific than
knowing how to hunt. But I mean,
it just like to take it apart and it
felt so natural going through it. Well,
how'd she has been with obviously this,
you're a very smart guy,
so this had been something you had
considered for quite a while before you
actually went hunting. But I never read
about the field dressing because I want
it to have an intellectually honest
first experience for my readers and to be
able to convey that to them. So I did
not study butchering field dressing,
anything. The only thing I
studied was the marksmanship,
so it didn't want to fuck it up.
One of the things I liked about his show
as opposed to a lot of other hunting
shows was the fact that he did do a
lot of the field dressing on the air,
did show you what was going on.
So I had a better sense of it.
I'd seen a lot of hunting shows before.
Like I'd watch Ted Nugent's show a lot,
but um, he doesn't clean them as
much and it doesn't like do it.
You'll do it occasionally, but Steve did
it quite a bit and it was very, you know,
you get to see like that's, that's
realistic shit man. Like that's,
you really see what an animals like when
you get a steak, you know, okay, this is,
let's back it up. Here's the
animal, now it's dropped.
Now you open it and then you
turn it to stake, like, Whoa,
that's a completely different
experience. And uh, it was,
it was fascinating to go
through it for the first time,
but also document the whole thing in
terms of photos and videos and everything
else all the way until that night
when we had some backstraps.
She kind of like the spinal erectors.
Dude. You're talking like a hunter? Yeah,
well I'm using Stevie,
Steve Rainelda's Vocab,
a Yolo, the backstraps. It was
trippy about that because I'm,
I think about anatomy just in terms
of training and weightlifting,
deadlifts and blah, blah, blah. And so
thinking like a back strap since then,
I went back to,
uh,
where we were staying with a guy named
Dave amick who builds custom rifles.
And they had this little
labradoodle that came around,
was play with a labradoodle. And I
started like feeling it's back and it's,
anatomy was so weird and I was like,
is it weird that I'm like
looking for backstraps on
this labradoodle? No, no, no,
no, no. And Steve's like,
don't worry. Like I, when I
give my wife a back massage,
I think the same thing.
So weird.
But it's like when you're actually taking
an animal part and thinking about the
anatomy,
you start seeing those cuts in that
anatomy and like everything that moves,
it's really fucking weird.
Well,
when you see an animal for a purveyor
of meat and now you see it as a meat
container. Yeah, new experience.
Yeah. It's weird. I went to Chrysler
Birthday party last night and
they had one of those things.
It was like a box where you put a pig
inside and then you put like coals on top
of the box a bit and they buried
underground or something. But again,
I guess it cooks faster
than burying it underground.
It only takes like three to four
hours or something like that. But uh,
it was amazing watching them take
the pig out and then like Burt,
which is digging in their like taking
out parts of the pig and then like,
then cutting out the meat. This is
Burt's birthday cards, birthday party.
It made me feel like such a pussy
watching like all these men. Just,
I'd taken this pig apart like,
like they all knew exactly what to do.
Like I would be like disgusted by it,
but eh
really?
So you look at like the whole pig,
you were like this is too much seeing
the whole pig. It was really creepy.
It was creepy.
I thought it was creepy to watch because
it's an actual body instead of like cut
of box.
Makes it creepier though.
Cause it's like a coffin
for a instead of just being
in the ground. Yeah. You think? Yeah.
I, I think um, the,
that never really bothered me but maybe
I looked at things differently. I Dunno.
Maybe if I wasn't, it snuck up on me.
I've been thinking about it for so long,
but by the time I went hunting I'd
been thinking about it for at least 10
near, so I wanted to do it for
at least 10 years. I'd always,
I'd always wanted to feel
more conscious and aware,
just like responsible for the food that
I eat, including the meat. And I just,
I didn't know that someone like
Steve existed, you know what I mean?
It's like men. And then I'm like, yeah,
well I don't think there's many like him.
Maybe his brothers. Yeah, there's
the pig laying in that. Oh,
that's wild. That's Kinda
creepy. Looking at that pig.
Looks like it looks like a refrigerator
that looks like a Peta advertisement.
Yeah. Right. And then, then
there's a, that's sorry.
Then like the pig head. Oh, chimney
Burt's body. Like a photo of Bert.
Oh, the head is certainly
weird. That's cool though.
The pig cooking like a pig on a spit,
essentially a whole pig.
And they did it at his place.
It was pretty sweet and
his man cave. And uh, I,
I completely understand by the way,
where everyone's coming from, Vegan
everyone was coming from,
was a complete animal lover and doesn't
want to have anything to do with eating
meat.
I fucking here.
And I think it's a very
noble way of thinking.
If you really look at what they're doing,
they're essentially trying to be a part
of the next stage of evolution when it's
done through the right or the most
moral for the more, most moral reasons.
They're trying to exist with the
very minimal Karma with no death, no,
no damage to the planet.
But the reality of this
environment that we live in now,
this world is this existence,
this of this dimension that we live in
now and said these animals, everyone,
these are all temporary, everyone's and
some of them are, they're dumb as fuck.
Okay, this is, this is this
whole system going on here.
Like you've got to recognize this
system where we're attaching morals to
something that's just natural everyday
process of animals consuming animals.
And in order for you to,
you must recognize you are an animal.
And in order for this animal body to
work at its best really achieved eat
animals. You know, that's the, I mean
you can live and exist as a Vegan.
There's a lot of top vegan
athletes like Mac Danzig.
He's a high level Vegan athlete.
But maybe he'd be better if he ate meat.
It's possible, you know, if you
listen to guys like Dave Asprey,
they'd tell you the science behind,
you know,
eating actual animal matter and
what that does to your nerves,
the way your body performs.
The way your body can move.
I don't know if he's right.
I'm too stupid. Too stupid
to really know who's right.
But it sounds to me like the,
the,
the people that are trying to be vegans.
I like what I liked,
what that stands for.
I like what that stands for.
That stands for people that recognize that
like fan. So I'm them doing something,
I'm effecting something.
I don't want to be a part of it,
but if you want to live in a society,
the reality is if you like, you know,
we've sort of like distanced ourself
from what we're doing by not having most
people involved with the actual
taking of the animal's life.
So even though you're a part of the chain
of command or the chain of evidence or
the chain of matter from, from a
living animal to stake you, you're not,
you've got nothing connected to it.
So there's a lot of people
that are wearing leather.
There's a lot of people that are
eating cheeseburgers and they're like,
I could never go hunting. And you're
like, well that's kind of crazy. Yeah,
that seems like,
that seems like it's Kinda crazy.
No, I, yeah, I totally agree. Number
one. And uh, I would also say, you know,
what a lot of people don't realize
is the industrially farmed meat,
and I'll use the term farmed very loosely,
but he's extremely damaging to the
ecosystem and ecological sustainability,
the US. But what they miss is
like monocrop, like wheat, soy,
corn are arguable,
arguably equally or more damaging.
And I think that what a,
so one of the things that made me want
to actually explore food more is that in
the next 10 years or so,
I met with a lot of really
interesting people like Sam Kass,
who's the private chef for
the Obamas at the White House,
also does a lot of food politics. And we
know the chef of the White House. I, yeah,
I've met him before.
He says Obama like to eat a weld.
The meals he told me about where fish.
So he would like go out and catch the
fish and then bring them in and cook them
in a bottle. We catch them. That's not
what I was dancing. The Sam Kass who, uh,
orange chicken and watermelon,
you son of a son of a bitch,
but something like 50% or more of the
current small farm owners in the u s are
set to retire in the
next five to 10 years.
And what that means is you have
these last of the Mohicans,
like small family run farms. In many
cases they're going to be up for grabs,
whether that turns into strip malls or
is handed over to Monsanto or some big
industrial food court or third,
which is really the only
sustainable option that I see is uh,
moving from a few really big producers,
too many smaller producers. Uh,
otherwise there's just too much politics
involved with like subsidies for corn.
Yeah.
Things of that type.
Explain to people who don't understand
that because there's a weird thing going
on with corn there just when you have
a handful of very large industrial food
producers and you have basically a sort
of exchange program between let's say
the,
the governmental bodies that regulate
food and the Monsanto's and the kind of
aggressive the world.
Uh,
you end up in a really fucked up situation
where there are certain crops that do
a lot of damage that are forced into the
food supply in everything that you can
imagine, like corn, she'll be
in everything from certain,
like every condiment you use
to bread that you eat because,
uh,
the growth of corn and distribution corn
is subsidized by the u s government,
which makes it possible for farmers to
make money by producing excesses of corn.
And if you look at, let's say the, uh,
if you look at the top soil
in many of the most, uh,
agriculturally productive states,
they've been reduced from 10,
15 feet in some cases,
the less than a foot by constantly
producing the same one or two crops.
Uh, so in any case, I think
that there's, there's a,
when you were saying vote with
your dollars, I think it's,
it's really important to realize that
people are voting for the future of this
country in many, many ways.
Financial and otherwise,
certainly from an ecological standpoint,
every time they eat a meal,
like you're voting three times a day for
what you want in the next 10, 15 years.
Uh, and it's not, I, it's not
going to be reversible. Like once,
like once that farmland goes away, we're
kind of fucked. I mean, in a lot of ways.
So anyway,
how did it get to that point?
How did corn w people that produce corn,
how did the,
they influence the government to
get them to give him subsidies?
Was the benefit of them getting subsidies?
They don't know all the historical
context to be perfectly honest.
What is the benefit? Like what is, how do
they sell it? Like giving, well you could,
they export a lot of corn as well.
Know what I mean? Like how does,
how does a bill like that get past?
How's,
how's laws like that get put in the place
where they're subsidizing people for
growing excess? So hard to say. I
mean there's so many lobbying groups,
there's so much backdoor dealing.
If you look at,
let's just say the labeling or non
labeling of GMO food as an example,
like that was a big issue in
California recently. What did lose?
I can get lost in the state of California.
It's, which is crazy, which is crazy.
Uh,
sometimes they can word things
where it's confusing as fuck.
I mean ultimately I think the most direct
path of making a statement is using
your dollars on the right things,
right? So this is a free market.
People respond to money.
So it's like if you can,
if you can buy food whenever possible
from smaller producers as opposed to
bigger producers and closer producers
as opposed to those really far away, uh,
the healthier you will be,
the better your performance will be.
And ultimately the less you'll be shackled
to some company that can do it every
once. It's so hard for people to do that.
So, and it costs a lot of money. Like,
even if you want to eat organic,
that shit so expensive.
If you want to eat like
really healthy foods,
if you want to go to the
supermarket and you know,
go to like a whole foods or something
and get like all grass fed this and it's
amazing how much more expensive it is
than to go into a market and you get some
weird looking semi gray steak, take
that pitch home. You know, it's,
it can be expensive.
There are a ways out there for people
to make tactical choices for health at
least about which produce to spend
more money on like their, their,
their annual lists. For instance,
the clean 15, the dirty dozen
and what all that means is there
are the dirty dozen are the 12 most
contaminated, uh, produce items,
vegetables and fruits that exists on
the market in the US and they're stuck
there.
They're studied every year and chemical
analysis is done and those are the,
those are the,
the fruits and veggies that you'll want
to get organically if you can afford it.
The clean 15 on the other hand,
are foods that even when
produced conventionally with
pesticides, antibiotics,
et Cetera,
have the lowest levels of contamination.
So those you can actually feel pretty safe
buying at lower prices conventionally.
Um,
and a good way for people
to tell if you're getting
screwed by your local grocer
or not, or tricked is a on
most fruits and vegetables,
you'll find a label or sticker,
right? If it starts with nine,
it's probably organic.
If it isn't,
if that number doesn't start with a nine
and then you might be getting beaten,
switched if they say it's organic.
So really there, what are the,
what is the standard for organic?
What does exactly organic does that
mean to science? What does it mean?
It's a very, so this is a label
that's been very abused. Uh,
my loads are organic. They're a hundred
percent donkeys, seaman, organic, chatty.
When you're broadcasting over there
on your channels, while you freak,
uh,
organic is,
it means a lot of things to a
lot of people been in general.
It's supposed to mean without or as
it's intended by a lot of people without
additional pesticides,
antibiotics, et Cetera,
as it would have been grown
102 hundred years ago. But, uh,
it's a, it's a, it's a battle for
dollars. So a lot of these labels,
if they're not regulated,
get misused.
And what is the feasibility of like,
say if you had a community of people,
say if you got together with a
10, 20 people, whatever, and you,
you all wanted to get in on some farm
land and figure out how to grow your own
vegetables. Have you like ever thought
about like how much land it takes,
how many animals you need,
how many looked at it super closely.
Is that in the book? It's a,
I talk about a lot of the,
the survivalist and self-reliant stuff.
I don't talk about like homestead
homesteading or animal husbandry as much.
Um, I pretty much talks
about a weird way to put it.
Homesteading and animal husbandry.
That's my next book.
Those are two strange terms that
you very rarely hear people use. No.
So I looked at this really close to
it in my, uh, my girlfriend actually,
she's from Vancouver,
Victoria and her family has created
in the last year of farm that produces
almost all of their foods.
So they have a handful of sheep.
They have a garden that's probably 150
by 150 feet and nothing produces so much
vegetation.
They have to give it away like,
and that's a family of four plus two dogs,
one 50 by one 50 feet and signing off.
It feels like it may be maybe 200 by 200,
but it is a very manageable amount of
acreage and it produces an astonishing
amount of food.
Now you have to know what you're
doing from a gardening standpoint.
I think raising animals and a lot of
ways it's a hundred times simpler than
keeping track of like 20 species and
keeping them alive of clients of plants,
they have more, they had
more, they use greenhouses.
They did have a greenhouse for certain
plants, like tomatoes for instance,
but outside just like
these huge stalks of Kale,
like four or five feet tall.
It amazing. I mean it's just,
it was so true.
It was the,
it was trippy for me in the same way
that going on my hunt was trippy where
you're like, wow, huh. So
that's what a, you know,
a Ribeye that's the part of the body
that are revise from a in the same way,
just seeing,
you know,
Kale for the first time growing out of
the ground or asparagus or whatever.
It was really wild. How much effort would
it take to do that for like a family?
Like to run like it, to grow enough
food and to have it like it's, it's,
that's an interesting thing to think
about. How much land do you need?
How much water do you
need? You know, how much,
how much acreage do you need for four
people? Five people can need much. I mean,
my uncle had a farm. I have two
uncles who had a one very small farm,
another with a much larger farm.
And uh, I mean if you have,
you want chickens for
protein and not for the meat,
for the eggs because they give out eggs
every day. Just kicked those eggs out.
You know, I didn't even know
that till I was in my thirties.
I'm so fucking stupid.
I thought that a,
every time a chicken gave an egg that
it could have been a baby chickie who
could have grown to be a baby.
Chicky but you ate it before it could.
That's what I really thought. I thought
like when you had fried eggs, the,
you were having baby chickies that just,
you caught him in time and you killed
them before they became little.
But that's not what an egg is. Folks.
Chickens lay eggs every day. Yeah.
The ones that we make at least,
I don't know if it's normal in the
wild for them to run. They still,
they still do. There's
a lot of eggs. I mean,
they're not like Franken chickens where
they're like, breast meat is so big,
they can't stand up.
Right.
Like the freak ones that you see like
in those weird documentaries that scare
the shit out of here. Yeah.
There's a great, uh, there was, uh,
there was a great TV
show or series in the UK,
I think it was BBC produced called,
I think it was escaped to river cottage.
And it was about a chef from London
who decided to go to the country and
basically try to do all
this stuff from ground zero.
So raising animals, raising all of his
food on this property. And it goes,
you remember the guy's
name? Uh, should know this.
He wrote the river cottage cookbook and
as well as a river cottage meet book,
which is the same guy that
bought Dane had on his show,
got longish hair glasses. Maybe,
uh, you know, the show's over now.
He's got a new one on CNN now. Oh,
really? Yeah, they moved it over to CNN.
That's what, uh, the,
uh, one of the guys, Moe,
who's the director of a meat eater is
also one of the guys who works for a port
Dane. He works for both. That's
right. That's right. 0.0. Yeah.
So I remember it's Hugh
fairly weddings hall,
some very British sounding
aristocratic name that's very British.
So clearly winning his hall,
something like that.
But the show is awesome and it goes
through a lot of this stuff. Shows
him fucking it up and getting it
right, which is really cool. Yeah.
I would imagine it would take some effort
and planning for sure. Yeah. But I mean,
Brian Cowen and I who, uh, Walsall went
on the hunt with me, with Steve Rinella.
We've talked many times about getting
a plot of land for our family and like
figuring out how to do
something like that. It will
require a lot of work though.
I eat. It would, and it's
probably a good idea.
Part of what I thought about
when I was, uh, you know,
doing all this research over the last
fuck two years since we last saw each
other, whatever is creating a, a,
a small group of like
modern hunter gatherers.
So you have five friends and instead
of trying to do it all yourself,
you're like, all right, you're in charge
of Caribou. Go get us some Caribou.
You're in charge of fucking tomatoes,
tomato guy.
Make sure you get the
tomatoes you're in charge of.
Who the fuck knows Kombucha you made, that
would be a great thing to make. Uh, uh,
isn't it crazy though that that
might be a rat reality some day?
It's impossible for people to imagine
anything bigger than sandy or Katrina.
Katrina was bigger than Sandy. Yeah,
but something along those lines.
So a massive disaster.
Massive loss of property and life.
But that's nothing compared
to like what used to be here.
Just the ice that used to be over
North America just to, you know,
some guy we're in Canada
and he was talking about how
they found beaver can just
brought it up.
Someone was talking about growth,
global warming and he was saying how
they found beaver dense like a under
hundreds of feet of ice in Greenland
and that at one point in time that I saw
wasn't there. You know, this is
like real simples real recent.
Some shit happened and we cling
to the idea of staying in a spot.
We claim to the idea, this is
my land. I've sticked to claim.
Well I have a property line.
I even have a fence up.
But that's ridiculous because this
earth is a constantly shifting organism.
You know, it's a, it's a thing and
it moves around and things change.
The atmosphere changes. Yeah.
They used to be dinosaurs here.
Stupid Shit.
That shit is a Volvo volatile, you
know, and we don't want to believe that.
We want to believe that,
oh,
I shut my little cardboard door and the
co La Loche my little brass lock and I'm
in, I am completely shut off
from the environment. You know,
it's just having,
fuck,
I mean people like spend
three hours on a Saturday,
spend a few hundred bucks,
go get,
go to Costco because they have all this
disaster preparedness stuff and get two
weeks of food, get like a week
or two a water. Just have it.
What's the downside?
It's definitely not a bad thing to have.
It's definitely not a bad
thing to be prepared. Um, if
you could do solar power, I,
I definitely want to try to do that.
And a lot of people go with, um, uh,
they have, um, they have both.
They have like a generator or they'll
have like solar power. They have propane,
you can have like propane
generators that will kick on
that we'll kick on automatically
when your power goes out.
I had that in Colorado because
when I was living in the mountains,
apparently the power,
the power goes out up there all the time
and sometimes it takes a long time for
them to turn it back on.
So as soon as the power would go on,
you would hear like a second and then
you hear the generator kick on is a big
ass generator that was
set up for this property.
But I'm windmills.
That's another option.
I have my friend and Oregon has windmills
and he actually sells power back to
the grid. However, the fuck
that works. How does that work?
Uh, well yeah, I mean they will
meet her, goes the opposite way.
That's crazy. They don't get
you a credit. That's what, uh,
that's what some actually many schools
in California and elsewhere are doing to
generate extra revenue.
Is there actually, uh,
having solar power companies
that are partnered with,
whether it's different power companies
that were local government will install
solar panels on the top of
all the gymnasiums and all
the school buildings and
everything like that.
And then they will receive either an
upfront payment or some type of monthly
stipend or they get a percentage of the
energy that is paid that is then sold
back to the grid basically.
Yeah.
Yeah. There was a school, uh, in boulder
that had like a whole farm set up there.
It was pretty bad ass kids were growing
their own food at school. I was like,
yeah, that, that'd be a really smart
thing to teach kids how to do, you know,
instead you're teaching them some shit
there. Almost likely to never use yeah.
You know,
teach them how to actually grow some food.
That would be a great thing to teach.
Like as a standard class in high school
farming to search simple farming.
This is, hey, grow vegetables. That's
why isn't that like a or a requirement?
Math is acquiring English as a
requirement. We were like, listen,
we've got the natural world lockdown.
Okay,
we don't have to think about
that anymore. But that, that law,
that lost connection, you really
do feel this, uh, this connection.
When you grow something, when you
actually grow something and then eat it,
it's like it awakened something inside
you. This weird primal satisfaction.
And also just the,
the therapeutic aspect of having to care
for something besides yourself I think
is really, I certainly underestimated
it. I mean, I kill plants.
Like it's my job. I just,
I, I have a brown thumb or I
don't pay attention. Oh care,
whatever it is.
But I,
I ended up experimenting again with
growing plants and I just got rosemary,
it's a really tough planet,
pretty hard to kill and you can use
it for just about any type of food.
So I started with just
a little rosemary plant,
like cut to kind of look like a fucking
Christmas tree that I got a whole foods
or something.
And that thing will produce enough herbs,
enough herbs for tea and herbs for
food for like weeks and weeks on end.
And it's hard to kill.
So I thought,
I found that to be a really low stakes
way to have an early success with growing
a plant that would hopefully then
encourage you to do more of it because it
sucks when you try to get into something
like that and then immediately fail
because everything dies
and you're like, ah, yeah,
don't want to jump right into the deep
end of pool and learn how to grow a plant.
Right. For thinking about starting a
farm. Yeah, exactly. Yeah, exactly.
Geez. If you have like your
everyday life and then on the side,
do you want to run a farm? Like,
bitch, you ain't got time for that.
You get the full, the full timers have
enough trouble with that, like, yeah,
I mean you would,
you would have to,
if you were going to feed yourself
completely with the animals in the food,
that would require a tremendous
amount of work. You know, the,
the people that sell vegetables and
actually run a farmer at dairy farm or
something along those lines,
that's an incredible amount of work.
People who actually know folks
that actually have a family farm.
That's an incredible amount
of work that's even more.
But to just to feed
yourself and your family,
it's going to require several hours
every day, many hours every day.
Taking care of the animals, feeding them,
cleaning up animals. Definitely. Yeah.
Dealing with,
you know,
setting up whatever the fuck you have
around your vegetables with its fences
that are keeping your irrigation
going and keeping him watering, gone,
dealing with fucking pestos little fucking
things that start eating your food.
You can, uh, you can actually purchase
a pretty cool, uh, think they're,
think they're hydroponic.
I might be using the wrong word
hanging gardens.
So they have these plastic containers
that hold the various plants and it
actually hangs down the side of a door,
almost like a shoe holder.
And then there's an
automated water system, uh,
that you can time so you can leave
and go away for a day or two.
And it just grows these plants effectively
vertically, which is super, super cool.
And then they get to a certain size.
You have to plant them,
get to a certain size and
you can eat them. Really,
you don't even need to plant them.
That's super cool.
Do they run on a power like we're going
to power is, yeah. You would plug in.
If you have the time than
automated watering system,
then you'd plug it in. See,
that seems to me like it's
at least slightly defeating
the whole purpose of the
whole thing. If you need the fucking
electricity to be on. All right. Yeah.
Think this is more for the aesthetic
of having plants on your door. Yeah.
Well it's pretty dope if you power on,
but if you don't keep the power and then
all that means is you have to water the
plants, which means you better
have some goddamn water. If, uh,
if your water system, if you, if your
municipal water goes out, no shit man.
You have to have it like a well system
or just go by, I mean, for instance,
in the basement of my
apartment right now I have,
I don't know what it was like 40
gallons of water. Don't tell people do.
They'll come look and I five guns.
Shoot, shoot him for your water. Wow.
Tim Fellows,
first murder starts to guy.
I have like seven of those
arrowhead water thing. If people,
if after three days of no water, people
will start looking for water. Oh yeah.
It's not like I'm saying I expect that,
but here's the thing,
I like target practice. I have
ranges near my house. It's fun to do.
Having a firearm is worst case scenario
insurance in a location where a seven
point or higher Richter scale earthquake
is 80 plus percent probable in the next
15 years.
Is that real?
80% so seven 70% plus a few years ago,
and I think that has since gone up
because on the ring of fire we had Japan,
New Zealand,
and I think the odds just improved.
What's the deal with those dudes who
find wells with a divining rod down?
What's called, yeah, yeah, yeah. What's a
divining rod then? What the Hell's that?
Defining Rod,
I believe is where it's,
you hold onto the fork of a stick
that looks almost like a slingshot.
So you hold onto the top of either end
of the why and then you're supposed to
get you supposed to get
steered by the end of it. Oh,
it's so dowsing is the use of a divining
Rod. That's what I believe. So, yeah.
And there's an also,
there's another method where they have
two sticks that are shaped like Ellis and
they hold them in either hand upside
down and then when they cross that's
supposed to indicate how the fuck
could that be real? I don't know.
It's like that game where you played
like you're with card Mani. No.
Where you have your, the spirits
where you're bored. So I will,
I will say this much.
I do think there are things like that
that are not unexplainable but are yet to
have been explained.
And uh,
I say that partially because I've seen
some pretty weird shit even at a lot of
people don't realize this at
Princeton University before.
I think this ended 2000 2001,
but one of the reasons I went there
as an Undergrad is because they had
something called the scientific
anomalies laboratory.
And this is where among
other organizations,
several branches of the military
funded research into things like remote
viewing, which is basically scientifically
controlled clairvoyants where you have
transmitter and a receiver and they use
like double blind protocols to see if it
is possible to report images back from
one location, from one person to another.
And uh,
they had some.
And then to validate whatever, uh, or to,
to design the studies and
then analyze the data.
They had some of the world's top
mathematicians and statisticians, uh,
supervising this stuff.
And Professor John J, O,
h n who ran, I believe that was
his name, who ran this laboratory.
And I went down and I was a test subject.
I didn't have any x men like power,
sadly, um, who supervise this,
did this closing presentation when the
lab was being wound down due to lack of
funding. And he presented some of
his findings and he basically said,
if you look at the statistics,
like all of this stuff has been validated,
but it will never be accepted
because of a, B, and c. And, um,
what was really trippy about
the remote viewing, right?
So in the remote viewing protocol,
one of them,
they would have let's say
three or four envelopes.
The transmitter would choose one,
they would leave,
get into a car with the
supervisors, uh, the experimenters,
and then open the envelope, find gps
coordinates and go to that location.
And that's where they would transmit from.
And what they found was
for one of the locations,
the drawings that came
back and they were better,
some people were better at
receiving than others. Uh,
the drawings all looked very,
very similar,
but they didn't resemble the gas
station where people were going.
And then they did research on the
location and they found out that they were
drawing barracks that had been there
like a 120 years earlier. Whoa.
Trippy. Really, really,
really trippy shit. So,
I don't know,
like say if you wanted to set up an
experiment today with a remote viewing,
are there experts that you would
go to that are, that are the,
that are the bad motherfuckers are remote
viewing that you really think could
replicate something scientifically like
for a television show or something like
that if they were under the gun?
That's a good question.
I don't know. I think,
I honestly think that these types of
abilities are at some point going to be as
analyzable is like shooting three pointers
or looking at the top of UFC fighters
and like,
okay,
we're going to look at the
fiber composition of like
a GSP and Anderson silver.
I think at some point's gonna be like,
oh,
like Johnny's really good
at remote viewing because
he has the blah, blah, blah.
And his like substantial. Yeah.
He's got like some fucking,
the th three 74 gene is
turned on. Oh, of course.
And so there are some people who appear
to be better than this than others,
but just to touch on like
the weegee board and uh, uh,
fucking Taro cards and all that shit.
I think that there,
I don't place any power
in the tools themselves.
I think there are people
who have abilities who then
use those tools to explain
their abilities. It is an
outlet for their abilities. Uh,
I've just seen way too much weird shit,
man.
What have you seen that's verifiable?
What have you seen? Nothing.
No, no, I know,
but like the want this to all be real
verifiable stuff I would say is look at
research that's been done by,
I think it's Sarnoff international there
bunch of defense contractors who have
funded this kind of
stuff. And uh, also, uh,
look at the, uh, try to
find stuff on the, um,
scientific anomalies laboratory.
Should I watch the men who stare at goats?
I, you know, I've wanted to see that.
I haven't seen it. I would see
it anyway. It sounds great.
It was very face it a Cohen
brothers, is it Cohen brothers? Yeah,
I've heard it's very funny.
Clooney, right? Yeah. Yeah,
I've heard it's very funny actually.
I can't believe I haven't seen it now.
Now that I think about it.
Um,
so there's nothing that you can like
no studies that you can point to that
definitively have proven it,
but you do you mean that it's
possible or are you a believer?
No, no, no. I'm not operating on
faith. I think that if you like
nice and what I meant, I mean you've
seen enough that you believe enough
that I what I'm comfortable saying,
it's not that like telekinesis
exists or this exists,
but there are odd phenomena that
I have seen that that's how,
I mean I don't think science has a limit
sciences and method of thinking and a
method of testing hypotheses.
The method of measuring
and a method of measuring.
I think that with some unique is you can't
really measure them if they don't happen
again. If they're unique. Right, exactly.
So they have to be good
sciences replicable. Right.
And I do believe that there are enough
demonstrations of like measurements of
metrics that should correlate like Ci,
right?
Like energy that's emitted from
poems by people in China and shit.
There've been a lot of studies
like mailing stuff where they say,
well the they have, I don't know
what they measure, photons I,
it's probably not futons heat from
a distance. I don't know what it is.
But like I've seen enough stuff that I
think many of these anomalies that are
seen as like a super powers,
they're not super powers is they're
manifestations of some type of biological,
a variable that will be
explainable at some point in time.
And I'm not saying all of them exists,
but like I've seen,
and again this is going to sound like
it's straight out of Crackville but it's
stuff that I fucking scene is like
I lived in China for six months,
I was an exchange student there and saw
this like you know Chigong master from
a, and I think a lot of that's pure
bullshit and just like cultish behavior,
but it's particularly guy,
old guy.
And he was sitting there in a park and
he was doing his exercise and shit and he
had dry leaves in between his hands and
that he was just like kind of shuffling
them back and forth between his hands.
The weirdest,
like one of the weirdest things I've
ever seen was that it wasn't a con,
I don't know. You mean they
were like flying through
the air, but they were like,
she was sliding across this tabletop
in the park between his hands.
His hands are like 18 inches apart.
And I mean,
I don't have any explanation for it,
but I know what I saw.
So it's not like I'm a proponent,
I'm not on the, you know, the, uh,
our, uh, lobby or anything. It's just you
find that guy and get a video of that,
that seems like simple. Okay, dude. Yeah,
you can get white leaf thing. Well, there,
there are videos of all sorts of weird
shit and most of it's bs. But anyway, I,
you saw a guy really do it. They believe
that God can really do that with, well,
I, I know what I saw. And to me, I mean,
that's just that one. I know.
And here's the thing, right?
Like there's some really brilliant
ways to con, so it's like,
that could have been a con God knows that
China's full cons. I mean it was like,
Oh yeah, oh sure. I mean
if you're in Beijing,
like you'll have art students come up
to you like every 10 minutes to sell you
their unique pieces of artwork and
they're poor and they could really bubble
lights, horn. No, no, no
artwork. Poor said their porn.
I'm going out there selling you their
porn in Beijing. Them No, no, it's good.
They're poor. I mean, there are tons
of scams and China, so who knows.
But what I would say is,
you know,
in the research for let's
say the four hour chef,
because it's kind of a book on learning.
It's a book on accelerated learning,
not just on food,
but I met people who could memorize a
shuffled deck of cards in like 43 seconds.
Right?
Or somebody you can learn a language like
Icelandic well enough in seven days to
go on TV and be interviewed. So to me,
if that is within their own possibility,
remember I was like training
yourself to memorize 10,000 numbers.
Like moving something like moving at
least two in your hands is not like beyond
belief. For me it's just, it's, I, I,
I don't see any reason why it
should be impossible. I don't know.
The,
you'd be able to push some energy from
your hand that would make light things
move back and forth. Very, very sure.
I mean, I don't, I haven't, again,
it's like there,
there's been no physiological evidence
to demonstrate that is possible up to
this point. But there are lots of
things that seem impossible that, that,
that had been certainly observed.
Whether it's through looking at, uh,
like theoretical physics or looking
at applied physics for that matter.
I mean there are plenty of things that
were thought impossible that are just not.
Um,
so you think that it's you or,
or rather you,
you believe that there has been studies
that have shown that people can generate
certain amounts of energy
with their hands. What styles
there? No, no, no. I like,
I'm not saying any of this stuff
and measurable, Measurable.
There have been studies done in
China and elsewhere looking at she,
so the potential measurement of cheese
specifically, how would they do that?
And I remember, I don't know
the exact tools are using
for measurement. And again,
I'm not saying like I am
standing for, I know. No,
I know what you're saying. You're
saying there are people world's weird,
the weirdest world and the problem
in this world. I said, yeah,
this is nice. I wonder what's in
my way. I need some adapalene.
I need some pro vigil. Um, the uh,
what did I say? The weird his world.
Yeah, the word is, we're weird.
His world world is weird. That's
what I'm saying. You're not, you're,
you're not saying
necessarily that you believe,
you're saying that there's so
much weird shit that is real,
that you leave open the possibility
that a guy could have some strange
telekinetic control over matter
for instance. I mean I'm a,
you need for something to
be scientifically verified
with let's say statistical
validity,
whether it's through this
number of subjects that a
number of n or you just have
such a magnitude of change that like the,
the p value mean the probability of it
being random event is less than 5%. Uh,
to do that you need tools for measurement.
And it's naive to think that we have
created all the tools for measuring all
things we haven't. Right? Right.
That's why, that's why for instance,
people try to isolate
nutrients, get themselves into
trouble because they'll say,
okay, Beta carotenes good for you.
This is true like 15 years ago.
And then people use a ton of Beta
carotene. They get sick. Why?
Because they're not consuming.
It would naturally current cofactors
that they couldn't isolate and see.
You have to be science among other
things is a game of measurement.
So I think that as the tools
get better. For instance, uh,
right now I'm actually involved with
and partially funding studies at a Ucla
University of California at San Francisco
in their neuroimaging lab where for
the first time they're able to do a couple
of very interesting things like take
a functional Mri machine and use it in
the same room at the same time as an Eeg,
which is actually a really tough problem
because these fucking magnets will like,
you know, pull shrapnel out of your skull.
I mean they're really strong magnets.
You have to be careful and they're,
they're able now using like even retail
products like the connect and whatnot to
look at how you can reverse
symptoms of dementia potentially.
Like how do you train someone's brain
to go from resembling that of a 60 year
old to that of a 20 year old.
And the better the tools for measurement,
the more precise you can be,
the more specific the protocol is that
you can use and it's fucking amazing.
Like there's stuff going on right now
that is going to just turn things tight
upside down when it
comes to like training,
mental performance and reversing the
symptoms of of age from a cognitive
standpoint. So for me it's
just like God, like as,
as we follow Moore's law and
technology gets smaller and faster,
exponentially and the certain heat
issues when you get to a certain size,
but the tools we're going to have for
measurement five years are going to be
like Ray Kurzweil land.
We're going to be able to isolate all
cofactors involving in new nutrition,
cellular development, the,
the evolution of the genetics.
We're going to have all of
that mapped out a lot. It,
I mean I think the rate of
progress is going to increase.
How could it not really dramatically
so we won't have it all figured out,
but do you think we'll get to the point
where we create an artificial person I
think will absolutely get to the point
where we get where we're able to create
an artificial person
that tricks most people.
I think that's going to happen
sooner than people expect.
That's going to be so fucking weird. Yeah,
I mean it's like the Turing test, right?
So, and somebody could call me
on this if I'm fucking it up,
but I believe the Turing test was having
a base effectively a chat communication
between a real human and a computer and
having that computer trick the human
into believing that it is another human.
And I think the,
the more interesting Turing test is when
you get an artificial humans sitting
across from you who tricks you fools you
into believing that it's another human.
And I don't think,
I mean maybe I'm in my own sort of
echo chamber living in silicon valley,
but just seeing how quickly
things are moving and how,
how quickly things are getting quicker.
I just,
I think I'd be surprised if we don't
hit that point in five to 10 years.
I'd be super surprised.
It's amazing when you really stop
and think about what lies ahead.
We are so far away from the reality that
existed when I was just in high school,
which is 20 years ago.
It to look at the future and look at
what lies 20 years ahead from now.
It's almost unrecognizable.
Things are gonna get so strange.
Yeah. Well if you think about in
the movie minority report, right?
So minority report was made what,
like 10 years ago and like all of that
technology and I think that was supposed
to take place like 20 years
from now or whatever it is,
that stuff's going to exist.
All of the screens that you can
move with your hands in everything,
I mean that's, that's going
to be widespread in the
next two years probably. Uh,
and you know, yeah, that's not even,
that's like that Microsoft surface thing.
It's very similar to that. We're
running ahead of schedule, you know,
like where things are, things are running
ahead of schedule and people give us a,
Ray Kurzweil is, um, I'm not sure if you
know who that is, but he, oh yeah, sure.
All right.
So people because of some of his beliefs,
and I think there are few
of the ice conclusions are
clouded by the fact that he
fears mortality and wants to bring his
dad back to life, things like this.
But he's a brilliant guy with an
excellent track record of prediction.
So when he says like,
we're going to have nanobots
that you swallow it and be like,
we're able to diagnose all your
issues and fix all these problems.
I don't think he's that far
off with most of it. Um,
I really don't think he's that far off.
Are we going to be able to make people
immortal in the next 20 years and have it
very conveniently coincide with his
sort of expert projected median death
sentence? Uh, probably not, but uh,
but he's sort of opening
people's ideas or ah,
mine's up rather to the
possibility that these,
there's like there's sort
of an extrapolation that he
has made that maybe other
people would just not be qualified
or have the vision to see.
And when he lays it out,
it really sort of changes the entire
game because when it becomes a mainstream
idea, like transcendent man has
documentary all of a sudden, amazing,
fascinating insight into him as a
human being too. But it all, it that,
that all of a sudden that becomes
like a alive meme, you know,
and that idea sort of grows,
you know,
because of the fact that he's
talking about it on this hill.
The hill accelerate it unquestionably.
Unquestionably.
And uh, I actually saw the, uh, it
was the debut of transcendent man, uh,
or trends at dental,
one of the two at Tribeca film festival.
And Ray was literally right here.
He was sitting in front of me watching it,
which was pretty cool to sort of watch
him watching this movie. Was it weird?
Like what wasn't that
weird? I'm a, uh, so I'm,
well I guess starting few years ago and
for a number of years was a visiting
faculty member for the Finance and
entrepreneurship track of Singularity
University, which ray started
along with Peter Diamandis,
chairman of the x prize based at Ames,
NASA location in mountain view,
California.
So I've had a chance to
interact with a lot of, of,
of Ray's cohorts and colleagues as well
as Ram self and Peter Diamandis who's a
really impressive guy in
his own right and, uh,
raises smart guy. I mean he's, he's,
I like that he doesn't back down.
So I think when,
when a lot of people who are very,
very smart have extremely bold ideas,
they sorta get brow beaten into,
into curtailing their belief really
well.
I think that ray has,
has stood up to critics so many times
and gone on TV so many times despite the
fact that he's, he's
given, people tend to,
to completely dismiss a lot of his stuff
out of hand. And I just like that he is,
he has so much intestinal fortitude
to stick to his guns like his,
his level of conviction, um, based
on everything that he has seen.
Uh, I think it's warranted. Number one.
I just find it very add
admirable that he doesn't,
he doesn't hedge or try
to like concede or, uh,
in any way to negotiate.
See I'm so out of the loop and I hang
out with such a bunch of Weirdos that no
one that I hang out with even remotely
thinks that it's crazy. You know,
I hang out with this great, great chem
trails and shit and left and right.
So this like coming singularity is like,
oh yeah, that's happened. Yeah. I mean,
and
I'm also living, I live in San
Francisco and it's sick. Yeah.
And people who want to colonize
Mars and shit. So it's like,
it's not that out of reach for,
for people that I spend time with.
Uh,
in any case, some people don't see
it. They see it differently than him.
And they're also brilliant men.
Like a Hugo de Garis who was
in that documentary as well,
who believes that he calls them our
deluxe, the artificial intellect.
And he doesn't think it's a rosy
scenario for the human race at all.
He doesn't get the I robot. Yeah.
He's got that scenario going on.
He thinks that some shit,
you know,
is going to get completely away from
us and just going, I think it's,
it's extremely light.
I mean, humans are constantly
creating things that can destroy it.
Yeah. Everything. So who
our best accomplishments
are all destructive. I mean,
that that would be, people would say
that's really an ignorant thing to say.
But I would say that the most impressive
things that people have figured out how
to do is to create nuclear bombs and
to, uh, make the large Hadron collider,
which is not, you know, not
necessarily destructive thing.
The large Hadron collider
is not a destructive thing,
but it does make microscopic
black holes. You know, you,
you really have to realize
that, that you're, you're doing,
you're creating some
incredible amount of energy.
Some you releasing some in amazing amount
of energy to make these Adam's collide
at the speed of light or just
slightly under the speed of light.
It's not destructive, don't get me wrong,
but it's bordering on it. It's like,
what are you doing? You know,
you're, you're figuring out
a way to fuck with Matt.
What's going to happen from
that? I mean it's, well,
it's eventually going to get to
something that you can use to like make a
country turn into a hole. You
know, you'll just have a whole,
where this one country used to be a void.
Yeah.
You'll have like the no matter the
nothing in the never ending story.
Imagine I'm going to be that first
person and try to fuck a black hole.
You probably already have you. Um,
if you,
um,
if you can conceive of the idea of
someone dropping an atomic bomb on a city
full of people that had
nothing to do with the,
the conflict and really had no choice
whatsoever and where they were born,
which is exactly what we did in the
1940s and then Nagasaki and Hiroshima.
If you can conceive of that,
the next step is literally you show up
where this town used to be and there's a
giant black hole.
It just sitting there and you can't get
too to it and it's just no matter and
you can't see through it and just sits
there and that's where the town used to
be and someone just decided to erase it.
That's not outside the
realm of possibility.
A nuclear bomb itself is fucking bananas.
That idea is crazy that you could figure
out a way to harness the very power of
the sun itself and drop it on a city and
instantly make a half a million people
just disappear. The, you could do that.
You can come up with the next slide,
the next level shit's
going to be even nuttier.
And that's the forefront
of our capabilities.
And of course he's like distribution of
information and beautiful things that
have come from, you know,
medical innovation and, you
know, the, the scientific, uh,
understanding of the world,
the universe we live in.
It's beautiful and it helps
the growth of the human being.
But at the end of the day,
what we really like doing is figuring
out a way to fuck things up with like
extreme efficiency.
Yet a lot of that is the,
uh, to the potential of like
an accidental black swan.
Like, oops, like we thought
we were going to do this,
but now we have a black hole over Toledo.
Oh yeah. And then there's the, uh,
all of the stuff behind the scenes that
people don't see where there are very
competent people who are very
deliberately trying to destroy the thing.
So you think, oh, I don't think,
I mean I have friends who
were on deployments to
different places and they're
like,
oh yeah,
we just got a bio like biotech terrorist
with a phd from like Brand Name
University in the u s and Yemen who's
trying to build a dirty bomb to like
explode over the Great Lakes using a blah,
blah, blah. And we're just like, whoa,
huck,
like the number of times.
So do you think,
do you subscribe to the idea that that's
what's going on with the United States
government? That's why he's
trying to clamp down on, on,
on personal liberties and freedoms.
It's really is to protect people because
there's so much shit going on that we
don't know about.
I would love if that was true,
but there's so much shit going on that
we don't know about that they have to.
It's not like they want to read your
email and find out who you're sending Dick
Pictures to.
What they want to do is make sure that
no one's making a fucking dirty bomb and
there's only one way to really do that
is to monitor everybody's email and look
for certain words.
But then you're going to arrest Bryan
because he'll call a girl. I'm like,
I'm going to leave a dirty bomb
in your mouth and then boom,
next thing you know you're in jail.
I think there's a fine line
between the two. I mean,
I think that once you sort of set the
juggernaut and motion for like constant
surveillance and warrant free
wire tapping and whatnot,
that yeah,
it's a fun,
I think it's very hard to have to
not have the, to go lockstep, uh,
hand in hand.
The other issue is human beings,
whenever they have power over
other human beings, they abuse it.
You could go back to the Sanford prison
studies that they did where they were
trying to,
Stanford was they got as students to
pretend to be jail house guards and
prisoners and they had a stop.
The experiments really quickly because
people are all immediately started
abusing each other and
that was supposed to go on
for something like a week or two weeks.
I cancelled it I think after 48 hours
and you're in the problem.
One of the big with the idea
of warrantless surveillance
is that you're allowing
people that are just regular folks to
decide whether or not they should spy on
people and whether or not they should
take their information or whether or not
they should fuck with their lives.
You're regular foot,
you have no evidence whatsoever. They
are enlightened, no evidence whatsoever.
They're operating on a higher frequency.
We'll all with the good of mankind.
There's no evidence whatsoever that
government people are any different than
regular people and regular
people are fucking crazy.
Regular people are on antidepressants
taking sleeping pills and drinking every
weekend and they're doing drugs and
they're all fucked up in the head and who
knows on what Ssri is there on.
That's everybody.
That's a huge percentage
of our population,
including people in government and we've
seen with his general Patraeus thing,
okay. That the people at the
highest level of government,
the guy who's the head of the fucking CNA
still can't keep his pitches in check.
He's still got regular people problems.
The guy's still got like affairs.
He's still got, you know, this hot woman
who's married and this is going on a site
and these people,
that's the CIA,
they're allowed what an
I were ironically enough.
What I think is fascinating about this
is this must allow the people at the
highest levels of government to understand
how dangerous it says because the
whole thing came about.
Like his exposure came about because
the FBI was investigating the CIA,
FBI and a CIA don't like each other.
All it's so, I didn't know that.
Did you know that?
Did you ever think that the FBI and
the CIA didn't like each other? No.
I have a friend who explained to me that
the navy seals and the marines do not
like
each other. There's a lot of
infighting. That shit is ridiculous.
Ton of infighting and you know what?
What mildly don't like each other or
like want to kick each other's asses.
Well, the, yeah, maybe, maybe it's,
that's an unfair question to ask cause
you generalizing and lumping everybody
into one group. But I mean if you
look at let's say the Pfizer Bill,
which Obama passed a couple of years ago,
which effectively allows
warrantless wiretapping uh,
the response that people have,
which I understand in which was the
response I had for a long time is I don't
have anything to hide if it keeps
everyone safer, go for it. Right.
The problem with that is when you have
people in power like to stay in power,
obviously enough, when you have that
type of warrantless wiretapping,
who do you think are going to be the
first people who get wired that every
member of Congress. Sure. How all
your opposition, how many people have,
so what percentage of congressman
or congresswoman have dirty laundry?
100% everybody has fucking dirty laundry.
I mean it's easy enough to, you know,
especially the old school people
that have been around long a long
time. They were, they were rocking it
like pre-internet, you know, if you want,
you know, like Teddy Kennedy, like you
want to go to like to his past like that,
you know the, those guys like that, the
fucking Newt Gingrich's of the world,
that they rocked it that way long
before the distribution of information.
So now that all this stuff is out and
everybody's tapping everything like, whoa.
Yeah.
You see with the portrayal scandal
clearly mapped out the problem with this
whole situation because there is
fucking no reason this should be news.
There's no reason this should be
investigated by anybody that's in any
organization that's trying to stop
crime because there was no crime being
committed other than I guess morals
violations by the guy who supposed to be
exemplary of the military,
his highest honors. Yeah.
I guess you can look at it that way,
but the reality is there's no,
no one's in danger.
Like why are you wasting resources on
his fucking national enquirer shit. Yeah.
And the attitude you go about doing
it well, it's all so obvious. Like,
you can't allow people to just
check shit out because the woman,
she was just like some crazy bitch that's
like this socialite flirts with guys.
And then there's this other one who's
the author whose email and that girl
saying, get away from my man.
And she calls the FBI says,
this bitch is threatening me. She turned
the FBI honor. And then they're like,
why is this?
What's going on here?
And then the guy who's investigating it
sends shirtless pictures of himself to
the chick. So then they stopped
the investigation. They go,
what the fuck are you doing?
You can't send to,
so they investigate him and find out
that he's doing creepy shit while he's
investigating. Portray us
and this girl, oh my God,
it's so clear.
Just that as a map should be stop,
stop looking in each other's fucking
emails. Jesus Christ, you women,
the FBI shouldn't be a
bunch of fucking women.
The FBI should be one of
the most distinguished group
of people in the position
of power in this fucking country.
You're not supposed to be investigating
who's blowing who. That's ridiculous.
There's shit to be done. Yeah,
we're in two wars. You fucks.
You can't send shirtless pictures of
yourself just chilling at the barbecue.
Thinking about our case, flexing
your six pack. You fucking asshole.
We're sick.
We're a God damn sick nation.
What we need is legalized
prostitution and no more snooping.
Those are two things we need to calm
everybody the fuck down those those
gentlemen in this position
of power clearly need some
sort of an extracurricular
release. Yeah. I'm not saying everybody
needs it. I'm not saying I'm, I'm happy,
I'm good,
but what I'm saying is you need to figure
out a way to calm these motherfuckers
down. Yeah, and that's the
only one that makes sense.
Stop reading their emails
and let them get blowjobs.
We're trying to fucking keep the
country safe. Yeah, I think that's it.
I think that's a pretty good concession.
You can't just go digging
into people's shit like that.
These guys are portraying
is 60 fucking years old.
That means for 40 whatever it
was years he operated with.
No,
he lived his life without a
fucking whisper of the Internet.
And he lived his life as a fucking
guy who's a professional killer.
Okay. And all of a sudden
introduce the internet,
this guy's life and to start snooping
on his email. I think that's rude. Yeah,
I think it's not fair. Those fucking
guys, they better stop this gear.
Stop this NSA thing that they're trying
to do when they're trying to make a
database of every phone call you've
ever made, every email you ever take,
every text message you ever make,
they're building some crazy facility
in Utah where they can just record
everything that gets done.
Well,
just in case they need to
investigate Tim Ferriss,
he's making terrorist threats
against the president.
Let's see what he's been doing online.
He doesn't even build,
the scarier thing is he's
not making terrorist threats,
but like Tim Ferriss propagating
a message that the, that the, uh,
the powers that be disagree with,
I mean you get to like a West Berlin
point pretty fucking quickly. Exactly.
And you know,
and people that think that's impossible
because America doesn't stay. That's not,
you're not dealing with America. You're
dealing with people. Yeah, exactly.
America is just an idea and I
love America. I love the idea,
but I just don't trust people to be in
a position of power and neither did the
people that fucking founded this country.
That was the whole point,
the whole point.
And we have slipped away from that to
the point where now we operate under this
semi democratic situation where you kind
of have a say, but not really. Yeah,
that's not cool. We're all
adults. That's not cool.
You don't have to do it that way.
There's really good a movie I'm going
to spell. I'm going to fuck up the name.
I think it's other people or
other people's lives about
West Berlin and there's
surveillance done in west Berlin.
It's a Ooh fucking great movie.
It's fascinating. But if people look
back to, not to dwell on this point,
but it's like people should
keep that potential in mind.
It's not that long ago that
we had McCarthyism. Right?
And if you want to put McCarthyism on
steroids, like have every phone call,
every email that anyone
has ever sent. Um, my Lord,
I used to think that, that we, we learn,
but I think we learn and then we
forget and then we have to learn again.
I think we have these like cycles.
It's like the,
the coming and going of the
tides. I, cause when I was a kid,
I remember that the Vietnam
War ended when I was,
I think it was like seven or
eight or something like that.
And I remember it because I
remember very clearly thing,
I was really terrified of the
idea of war because, uh, my,
my stepfather had avoided the draft.
He got lucky.
He didn't get drafted,
but we knew people that did.
And it was really scary that these
people would go and they would have to go
someplace where they might get
shot and nobody wanted to do it.
And everybody seemed to not believe in it,
but yet it was still going on.
So when that war was over, I had
this real tangible sense of, okay,
we figured out that that
sucks. That's, we're not doing
that anymore. Like that is,
we figured out that war
is a terrible thing.
It's unnecessary now that the war is over,
we can relax.
And that was the case all through my life
through high school and into my early,
I guess I was maybe 21 when the first
Gulf War happened and I was living with my
friend Jimmy did Telia. We're
living in Waltham, Massachusetts,
and we're sitting in the middle of the
living room watching the shit on TV
because it was the first time they would
show you these like night vision shots
of these rockets flying through the air
in this Eerie Green Hue and you've seen
all these explosions and he just
looks at me, goes, well buddy,
looks like we're at war. That
Boston accent. I was like,
Holy Shit. Like we were
back to this. Yeah.
That one went nice and quick and then
post September 11th it's like the entire
lessons of generations that had
to go through World War II, Korea,
Vietnam,
those lessons were that whatever
the society learned from that,
at least elusive was temporary
last temporarily temporarily.
We lost our fucking minds and now people
are starting to starting to come around
to it again and I'm hoping
that the evolution that we
make from this version of
it will be more lasting because of the
freedom of information rather than the
the free ability to distribute information
with the Internet that we can get it
out a little bit easier this time and then
we could say, listen ladies, gentlemen,
we're not saying we don't need government.
We certainly do.
We're not saying people shouldn't
have laws that they abide by.
They certainly should.
We should have a nice peaceful,
not saying you shouldn't make profit.
You certainly should.
What we're saying is you can't get crazy.
You can't go nutty and not look at humans
and not look at the human race as the
most important thing. Instead consonant
training on money, concentrating on,
you know,
the extraction of resources from strange
parts of the land that people aren't
really paying attention to
because it's not close by.
So it's okay to kill people with
robots that fly in the air. You know,
all of that is bananas and it doesn't
mean we can't keep a nice order in the
world. We can but we can't get
too fucking crazy. Yeah. And I'm,
I'm hoping that, I don't know if you
agree with this, but that there's a, uh,
a sort of a wrestling match
going on between the idea
of an apocalyptic scenario
that's human created and the idea of
technology and understanding meeting
somewhere in the middle
and working it out.
Yeah. No, I think that you
have technology that's,
I would like to thank, you know, human
sort of self interested rationality,
but I don't know,
you have the technology to solve problems
which is developing really quickly.
And then you also have problems
that are compounding, right?
Just like money in a bank account.
You have these problems compounding,
whether it's climate change,
populate,
explosive population growth in certain
areas. And so it is a bit of a,
it's, it's a race in a sense. Um, and I,
I don't know which side is going to
come out in front. I mean, I'm very,
very curious about population growth and
how that population density and global
travel and how that compounds the impact
of something like avian flu or SARS or
whatever.
And it's like,
at what point do we reach a population
density where it is like the deer jumping
in front of your car,
where you just have such a high density
of people that the inevitability of a
disease and rapid spread globally through
air travel effectively just wipes out.
It isn't that the sort of the natural
cycle of things is that when there's an
overpopulation is correction,
there's a correction. God,
it fucking terrifying to think of the
plague as a correction, you know, wild.
Uh, in any case, I mean,
so I'm actually probably going to
be getting a little bit of land in,
uh, you tell him, tell people Tim
Ferriss to come into your house.
Brian and I have been talking about
Columbus. His mom's got a compound.
We're gonna move in with Mrs Red Band.
I actually ended up visiting a couple
of, uh, from the last book, um,
for our body. Had a number of
hedge fund managers who were,
who basically want to be the
guy from limitless a pro.
We got to talk about this.
I gotta take a Piss talk to Brian.
He's really all about limitless.
I will talk to Brian about limitless
and then I will piss off. It also
had like a gallon of water together boys.
We could do that.
Why, why is your were we were talking
about this earlier, a what you're,
your book is banned from bookstores.
Yeah. What's the, what's,
what's going on with that?
So the four hour,
the four hour chef is the first major
book out of Amazon publishing as Amazon,
about a year and a half ago announced
the launch of Amazon publishing in New
York City,
which would be competing against all of
the major publishers to recruit authors.
Right.
Uh,
and that's really making everyone in the
book industry extremely uncomfortable
because Amazon super ambitious and hyper,
hyper confident and competent also.
So the book is being banned as a result.
The first time I'm aware of that,
a book had been banned by
all of Barnes and noble,
tons of tons of indies. Uh, so they
even matter anymore because to me,
I barely even see bookstores anymore.
I mean, no, I'll tell you what the,
I think the play is. Um, so there,
what they want to do is kill Amazon
publishing so that they aren't able to
recruit good authors.
And so they want to make an example
out of me as this guy who's had two to
number one New York Times best is very
fortunately they want to say they want to
basically crippled me.
So I don't hit the New York Times list
and then point to that. And in effect,
say if that guy can't do
it with Amazon publishing,
don't sign with on publishing.
And uh, oh, is this,
you're talking about you're being banned
from Ben wanted to bring that up? Yeah,
yeah, yeah. I think it's the
most, uh, band boycotted,
whichever were 1100 bookstores more
than that now. So yeah, in the airport,
even the airport bookstores
or is that he's nothing. No,
the airport bookstores
are are interesting. Those
are basically, not always,
but effectively pay for play,
so that's like buying advertising almost.
You pay for placement
with a lot of people.
Fail to realize is let's
say at a Barnes and noble,
it's just like a Walmart like you have.
Coca Cola owns the first
20 feet of Walmart,
like they legitimately pay for that space.
Similarly,
if you walk into Barnes and noble
and you see like the the whatever,
whatever rack or the the new
note note worthy or whatever,
the store owners have
some decision over that,
but a lot of it is paid op advertiser.
That's why it's so hard.
If you're a self published to get books
into Barnes and all works, they're like,
you know what are you going to pass
for an end cap that's not free.
They also have to stay open. Man. Barnes
and nobles closed lefts and rights.
Hard to get people to
buy books these days.
I always said that if you want
to really starve to death,
open a bookstore in Miami, you know,
it's hard. It's hard. It's tough.
It's a tough business. And
either, I think that what, uh,
I'm curious to see what happens. So
they've banned you. Yeah, I'm out zero.
And actually if he was like
discussion, no. Well, what's,
what's really funny about
the whole situation?
There are a lot of things that are
amusing to me about it, but they,
at first they said,
well,
we're not going to carry Amazon published
books because you're not on the hook.
Like you won't let us put like the
four hour chef on that does look bad.
I have a nook. No, it looks not bad. No.
What I'm saying is they were saying, hey,
Amazon, you're not letting us put these
books on the Nook so we're not gonna,
we're not going to
carry you in the stores.
And then Amazon came back
and they're like, okay, fine.
Put It on the neck and principles.
Like I always still don't like you.
And so they, uh, yeah, they're not.
Yeah, they're not carrying it. In fact,
some of the Barnes and noble store owners
wanted to carry this book and they got
severe slapped down from corporate
because corporate got word that they were
ordering copies of the book and
they just gave them the iron fist.
Have you thought about organizing an
email campaign or something against Barnes
and nobles? Unfair practicing. I
said unfair. I think it's unfair.
Yeah,
it's deep feelings.
I feel like you know who it's unfair to
and this is the children, the children,
the poor refugees. No, it's, it's an,
it's unfair to their customers and
ultimately this is where I think they're,
they're,
they're missing the mark.
Number one is if even if
Amazon publishing fails,
that will not stop the move from print to
digital. That will not stop that trend.
It will not.
It will not even register.
Secondly is Vic only competition is
for loyal customers and bookstores.
Certainly more than ever
need loyal customers.
If someone comes until
it's at Barnes and noble,
browses around and then goes home
to buy the book on Amazon for price,
that person was never a
customer to begin with. If,
on the other hand somebody walks
into Barnes and noble and says,
I really want to buy copy, I want to buy
three copies of the four hour chef for,
you know, as Christmas presents and
for myself, and then they kick it.
It all that accomplishes is there
driving that loyal customer to Amazon to
become a customer of there. So I don't,
I don't quite understand the logic I,
but again it's, it's humans are
emotional, right? That's why it's,
it's so concerning among other reasons
about all the stuff we were talking about.
So I'm not sure if it's a
completely rational decision.
Amazon's a big scary company
to go to a lot of book sellers,
but I think that for instance,
the only way to keep print relevant for,
for the foreseeable,
let's say 10 15 years,
is to create a tactile experience like
works of art through publishers like
Faden, p, h, a I, d, d o,
and they make beautiful books that that
is next to impossible to replicate on
digital or to have a very unique
experience in a relationship with your
customers, like omnivore books in San
Francisco, which is all cookbooks.
It's all they sell.
He's like,
you want to know anything about
cookbooks by something at a print,
get a recommendation, meet one of the top
chefs in the world. That's where you go.
Really? That's a specialized sort
of corner store. It's cool. Yeah.
There's one called, uh, I think
it's Slotnick, Slo, t n, I,
C K cookbooks in New York City.
Same Story.
It's like the Mecca of cookbooks and
you want to know something about that.
That's where you go. And those
businesses will continue to thrive.
But it's like if you're competing against
digital for price and convenience,
it's going to be a pretty tough road.
And uh, but there are ways to counter it.
So I mean the only reason if I wanted
to just make more off of the book,
I would have stayed with other
publishers quite frankly. Um,
but Amazon was interesting because I
want to try new things and I want to be
allowed to try new things.
Like I'm doing a partner,
a content partnership with bit torrent.
I'm putting out like tons and tons.
I probably well over a gig
of free material and videos
and all this shit on bit
torrent because they have 160 million
users and that's the kind of thing that
Amazon will let me do. Whereas
others may not be so keen to let me.
The other thing that people are
talking about the distribution,
the distribution and they're like,
oh well what's Amazon going to do with
first thing, no publisher out there.
I don't think any publisher except for
Amazon in my case would let me do a 672
full color book with thousands of photos.
That is a fucking expensive book to make.
I don't think anyone else would have,
let me do it. Why is that? I understand.
Because the margin suck. It's a really,
really tremendously expensive book.
And you just, the way the photographs,
the print that it has
to be on. Yeah, exactly.
Like to create a really physical book,
a really beautiful physical book,
like a tactile experience.
There just aren't many publishers
will do that anymore. And, uh,
so, uh, you know, distribution aside, if
you, what's, what's really p seven assets,
um,
what makes Amazon interesting from the
standpoint of a content creator is that
if you look at almost any other
publisher, Simon and Schuster, whoever,
it doesn't matter,
they do not have any direct connection
to their readers. They sell to the head
buyer in a category of Barnes and noble.
They sell to the head
buyer category at books,
a million in the middle of the
country. Uh, but whereas Amazon,
I mean I use Amazon prime.
Amazon probably knows me better than I
know myself and a lot of ways like they
have such direct access to
tens of millions of customers.
It just makes it really
attractive as an experiment.
Whether it'll turn out like who the fuck
knows? Well no at the end of next week,
but that's a
really interesting scenario.
The Amazon has a couple of
good things going for it.
Besides the fact that people already know
it as a great place to buy things with
one click and buy books.
They have this new thing that
they're doing with audible,
which is one of the sponsors of this show.
Oh look,
we're doing whisper sync. Yeah. This is
the fucking coolest thing. Would whisper.
See I was going to save it for the
commercial, the next audible commercial,
which is this week.
But what whisper sync is essentially
is you read a book and say if you fall
asleep where wherever that it pages,
you can have it on your smart
phone where you get in your car,
you plug it in,
you have an app that plays through your
audio Jack and it picks up where you
left off and starts reading the book
to you while you're in traffic. Yeah,
exactly. We'll go from text to voice. It's
fucking beautiful. It's really amazing.
He said going from tax to an
actor's voice, right. So it'll sink.
Like if you're reading a book in bed
and then you get in your car to go to
working and you have
the audio book version,
then you'll pick up where
you left off reading it.
So do you have to sync it from
your, um, cure your kindle to it?
Does it as long as you're connected to
Wifi or three g it syncs automatically
and it syncs to your phone and your phone
knows what Scott, what's up in the car,
whatever that's predicted.
The government's got to know,
got to know what page of 50 shades of
grey exactly. Hawes and masturbated on
who is, it's it, um, it's so it's actors,
a reader or as a computer that reads it.
Do you know that? Uh, I built,
my understanding is that it syncs
with the point in the book that Oh,
they have this act to come to
hand. Ian Audio, audio book.
You buy an audio book on audible and then
because it's owned by Amazon and then
you're reading on your kindle,
let's say the next chapter,
you get in your car to listen to it and
it will continue where you left off in
the book reading. It's pretty
credible. That's wild. Yeah.
Here's the answer. It's a,
it's a, it's only on the kindle fire HD
and the kindle fire. That's two of them.
The 8.9 inches, the seven inch, the
second generation ones, they, um,
it's a professionally narrated
audio book. Amazing. Yeah.
It's pretty cool.
Yeah.
That might actually get people to start
like reading books for and learning some
shit. Yeah. That's,
that's, that's the future.
But it sucks that Barnes and noble
a is trying to keep you out. Yeah.
I mean, they really need me to
fail, so if I succeed next week,
they're going to have a big world to
trouble. So silly. Just sell the fucking,
yeah. I don't see, be in
bullies. Yeah. I mean they're,
they're really being bullies.
It, another thing is the, I mean, I've
had the prior, the prior two books,
very stupid. They're picking the
wrong guy to make an example of, yeah.
Like your your books or New York
Times bestseller, number one,
New York Times best sellers socket,
Amazon or Barnes and noble
talking to Amazon to suck.
I'll suck Amazon for you. Suck Barnes
and noble. Come on. Barnes and noble.
Get it together.
That's ridiculous.
It's silly. So, uh, yeah, it's going to
be a dog fight though. So we got some,
I could actually give you a give you a
scoop on some stuff that's happening next
week. But so for instance, uh,
nobody knows this yet. Oh, I know.
Yeah, yeah. No. This Doo Doo Doo
Doo Doo. Get new sound. Yeah.
So do you really? Yeah. You have
a breaking news. So ready? Go. Uh,
I have to find it. Oh, come on.
Semi break.
This was one of those fucking morning zoos
that's not Britain. Oh, that was
good. Definitely good. Damn good.
That was worth the wait.
Uh,
so you know,
what do you do when you get banned
by bookstores while you open your own
bookstores is what you do. So I am
actually going to be taking an outlet.
I'm partnering with a Panera Bread. Oh
Wow. Which a lot of people don't realize.
Pinera has like what, 2000 locations in
the u s and I was doing a pilot starting,
uh, what's tomorrow? Monday.
Tomorrow in New York City,
people will be able to buy the four hour
chef at retail at all of the pioneer
look, the four main penny or
locations in New York City.
Interesting. So like how
Starbucks sell cds now. Exactly.
And that's a,
that's a new thing.
Dang man, I think that's the way
to go. That's a perfect place.
Starbucks and Panera bread.
Yeah,
and they're also going to be at the
same time piloting. So Panera, right?
Bread Pan Pawn, right? They're going
to be piloting a slow carb diet,
hidden menu, which is from
like the four hour body stuff.
So if you want to actually effectively
eat paleo or eat slow carbon loose fat,
now you can go to this place that's known
for bread and actually get a slow carb
meal, which is pretty cool. It's going to
do both the simultaneous simultaneously.
That's amazing. How do you feel
about like seeing now there's,
there's so much awareness
for the content of food now.
You mean you see grass fed meat everywhere
now. It's part of the vernacular now.
This is what just didn't exist as
five, six years ago. I think. Great
thing,
as long as it's,
the labels are policed to some extent
so that assholes don't come along and
start mislabeling things purposefully,
which happens all the time.
But I think it's a great thing. And
I mean, one of the goals that, um,
that I have is to sort of create a, a, a,
a super trend of about 20 million
people who simply think about let's say
purchasing food from breakfast
differently or dinner differently.
And if you can create a super trend by
getting roughly that number of people to
change certain buying habit,
then I think we,
I think that this country
can really it towards
more of this,
a smaller producer,
many suppliers versus, you know,
monolithic industrial producers.
And once you do that, I mean,
once the money is there,
the supply will generate
itself. I mean, you'll have,
it'll be commercially viable for people
to do more of this grass fed stuff,
which we already see coming.
It's just I want to stick kind of a
Archimedes lever in the whole thing and
fucking blow it up, which is part of,
uh, what I hope to do in the next,
I don't know,
12 months or so.
How much different would communities be
if every neighborhood had a little mini
farm? Yeah, yeah, exactly.
Like a shared gardener garden.
And we all sort of chipped in
and everybody had responsibility,
Neighborhood Watch type thing, and
it's not that farfetched. I mean,
it's not that far fetched at all.
Well,
the problem with cars is that now
we don't have communities anymore.
Like I don't live near any of my friends.
I've been trying to get everybody
to move near me. That's not working.
We're going to have to buy land somewhere.
But I thought,
how great would it be
if I lived in the same.