Hello Freak bitches. That's
right. We're back. Oh, oh.
I'm mixing it up.
Prompts a dom Irrera whenever you say Ooh.
Ah, Ooh. You got to give
props to the Godfather. I'm,
this episode is brought to you by
[inaudible] Dot Com uh, on it is,
if you've never heard it before about
it before a human performance website.
It's all supplements and strength and
conditioning equipment dedicated to human
performance,
including the new primal bells,
the new kettlebells that come in the
form of gorillas and chimpanzees.
These are just the beginning. We have a
bunch of different designs coming out.
The new gorilla one just came out and
it's fucking Badass. It's 72 pounds.
It's a a bad ass workout.
It's got a big fat handle on it.
And if you've never worked
out with kettlebells and
you buy something like this,
let it be a goal. Don't have it be
your main piece of exercise equipment.
Because if you have never
lifted kettlebells before
and you don't understand it,
70 pounds is a lot of weight
to swing around. So, uh,
start with, I would start with light
and do it correctly. And if you can,
if you can afford to get a trainer or
get someone who knows how to do it,
to show you the movements, just film
it on your phone and then watch it.
You don't want to hurt yourself.
And so if you're doing anything that is
involving a strength and conditioning,
my main,
the main piece of advice that I always
give people is learn what you're doing.
Do it correctly, learn from someone
and then pay attention to your form.
It's the most important thing.
If you get sloppy,
that's when people get hurt and you
don't want to get hurt when you swing it
around a 72 pound kettle bell bitch.
All right.
Especially one that looks like a gorilla,
you'll feel so weakened, fleshy already.
Um, we have all kinds of shit,
battle ropes, maces and club bells,
and there's a fantastic series of
strength and conditioning DVDs,
especially the ones that I can recommend.
The extreme kettle kettle, excuse me,
extreme extreme. Do I know how to talk?
Extreme kettlebell cardio workout,
DVD one and two,
they're these fucking incredible workouts
by this maniac named Keith Weber's
guy's a nut.
He's on the beach doing this workout that
literally makes you want to just stop
breathing. It's incredible. And you can,
it'll kick your ass with a 45
pounder or 35 pound or even a,
he uses a 45 pounder though in the video.
Fantastic shit.
Go to [inaudible] dot com
any of the supplements,
if you use the code named Brogan,
you save 10% off any of the groovy shit.
All right, any of the
supplements broken. Use the code.
We're also brought to
you by death squad.tv.
If you don't know what death squad.tv is,
that's where a little dry and Ben has his,
Keith is a tee.
Shirts for sale including desk
squad tee shirt number three,
which you can preorder today. Um,
this the, the, I like it the best.
It's the coolest one
to the last two though.
There are definitely like getting more
complex and weird and this is a weird
fucking shirt that Brian makes a also.
He uh,
has a podcast death squad
podcast network that uh, has, uh,
my pal Tony Hinchcliffe was
here. Boom. Hello. He's on kill.
Tony is a that podcast along with
Kevin Perreira is a amazing podcast.
Pointless and a, a couple of
other podcasts that Brian does,
but you can catch them all.
And all the information on does squad.tv
including the presale order of those t
shirts. My tee shirts higher
primate.com are restocked.
So go to higher primate.com k cells
from psychedelic chimpanzee shirts.
Everybody wants one a and Tony
mother function hands cliff.
Don't you have something going on
do when there, that's you marriage.
Is that Tony hinchcliffe.com? Yeah, that
is, oh my goodness. She's sexy. Bench.
Look at you staring down the camera.
Confidence. You're not trying to be wacky.
You just dangerous. You're radical. What
is your shirt? What are you selling?
It's the new uh, equation. Tee shirts.
My first tee shirt and I got together
with a designer and gave him some wild
notes about different things about me
and he had this idea to make it look like
a chalkboard and it's really cool and
they're selling and it's exciting. Oh,
that's cool dude. Get me one
of those. Definitely will do.
What size XL you got it or large.
If you think I'm sexy,
if you want it to be tight, I'm saying
probably be a good one. A good tight with
woo girls would be like, he's
not the edge cliff equation.
Oh my God. The way he stares
down the camera and his website.
He is so gangster.
Look at how he looks at you.
Give zero fucks. Yeah, look at him.
He's just so confident and that's
on the back between the shoulder.
So anybody that's behind you
sees me looking right at them.
So that's a for those paying attention.
Just squad.tv higher primate.com Tony
hinchcliffe.com boom Sherlock lock.
Boom. All right, Brian. Keith
music. Let's get this party rolling
experience. Joe Rogan podcast. My name,
sweet baby Jesus.
Tony Hinchcliffe is in the house
today. Oh yeah. Tony Hinchcliffe.
How's your life? Great man.
Having Fun and kicking butt. It's,
but I hardly believe people when they
say kicking Butt Sam kicking ass.
I'll take you seriously. Say
kicking butt and like, who are you?
What are you doing? Partying was all
ladies and beating them at things.
How are you kicking?
But just having them just staying busy.
It's my favorite thing to do is to
stay busy. What about kicking butt?
Uh, well, you know what, I, I'm going
to rephrase it. I've been kicking ass.
There you go. Thank you very much.
Thank you very much. I appreciate that.
I appreciate, appreciate it. Also,
all the people that, uh, have, uh,
sent comments pro and negative about a,
the new Scifi TV show
appreciate all your input.
I think this is a rare time
where people get to, uh,
give input about things they see online,
whether it's a standup comedy show or a,
um,
a TV show like this show or anything.
It's important that people get
to talk about stuff and telling,
tell me what sucks. I want
to know, you know, and it's,
it's not perfect. There's no,
no, none. No shows are
perfect, man. It's hard.
It's hard to do a television
show that's perfect.
It's also hard to do a terrible television
show like this where you squeezing
hours of information and hours of
conversations until like 40 plus minutes.
But one of the things that I've found is
that people are so fucking attached to
this shit.
They believe they're so attached.
And one the big one that people are
mad at me now is chem trails because a,
we had an episode of that kind of debunk
chem trails and it didn't debunk all
chem trails.
This is what people need to understand it,
and this is a really important, first
of all, I don't work for the government,
but if I did work for the government, I
probably wouldn't tell you, but I don't.
I don't. I'm the fucking, I give up,
come on pot smoking fucking
cage fighting commentator.
I'm not working for the government.
All right, stop it. Don't be silly.
You would be the perfect person.
She'll what?
What people are seeing for the most
part when you see these con trails,
these trails behind jet that
become artificial clouds.
The way it's been explained to me by
not just one but numerous scientists is
that when jet engines pass through
various levels of condensation,
it creates different effects.
And if a jet engine passes through
sky that has enough condensation,
it will literally change
the temperature of the sky,
stir it up and create a cloud and it's
a lingering cloud behind the jet and if
you're looking at it,
it looks like someone's
spraying artificial clouds
and you get this feeling like,
oh my God,
they're spraying clap like I when I,
I've saw them and I saw
some of the documentaries on
and there was a quite a bit
of time before I was, I was looking at
it, I was like, that doesn't make sense,
but is it possible that they're really
spraying artificial clouds out of all
these planes?
And then you talk to people to tell you
that these are military planes and this
is a constant geothermal
engineering exercise.
But then when you find out that it is
possible to put a jet engine through
various levels of condensation and create
these clubs like scientifically proven
hundred percent you got to go,
okay,
well that's 100% if that's 100% is there
a way to tell when they're going to
leave contrary and when they're not,
it turns out the risk.
There's a NASA website and
you go to the NASA website,
it shows you where there's condensation,
where there'll be contracts and it's
for pilots so they could see better.
It's for people that are like
trying to observe the sky.
It's like a bunch of reasons
why they monitor this shit.
They know when contracts are going to
exist and when they're not. In fact,
in 1942,
the government was trying to figure out
what the fuck was going on cause they
just like first started having planes
involved in world war two and they were
um,
they put out a paper on what they called
persistent condensation trails and that
is these lines that were behind these,
these planes.
And their conclusion was that it's a
natural part of what happens to the
atmosphere when a plane flies by and it's
sometimes they last and sometimes they
don't based on how much
moisture is in the atmosphere.
19 fucking 42 they did this,
so this is something that has been
scientifically able to be explained for a
long time. That set, now this
is where everybody gets crazy.
The I'm sure the government or
let's just say people that are evil,
let's not just say the government
because they're probably not even the
government now is probably
the government of the past,
which you can't blame the people now.
You can blame them on a lot of shit.
You can't blame him for shit that
happened in the 50s for sure.
People have sprayed things out of planes.
Hundred percent yeah,
it's definitely happened for sure.
You're dealing with a power structure
that values money over a certain aspects
of humanity for sure.
100% but we've gotta be honest about
what's happening and what's not happening.
Southwest is not spraying
artificial clouds.
They're accidentally making them in a
natural byproduct of a jet engine passing
through condensation.
But it doesn't mean that people
haven't done evil shit in the past.
It just means that's what that is.
And people are getting so fucking mad
at me on Twitter and calling me a shill
and a government agent and thinking
that somehow or another, um, um,
I'm changing the truth because I want to
protect myself or something. It's just,
I think people are looking for like a
reason, something to blame, you know,
the lack of health and feeling good and
you know, on, and I think that they,
they do that and then they roll in,
they blame it on the chem trails and they
roll into Mcdonald's and eat five big
macs and wonder why
they're feeling shitty.
They think they're just
spraying stuff down on that.
Have you ever seen the one,
the video with prince on the prince
sitting with Dick Gregory, pull it up.
Prince talks about chem trails.
Prints is talking about chem trails
in the hood and friends, for instance,
one of the banners,
rock and rollers of all the tile.
And he's talking about chem trails,
um, in the hood when he was growing up.
And it's, it sounds like he's singing
a song. Like it's like almost lyrical.
Like the way he looks at it.
It's like sometimes no
clothes in a thought.
It was purple rain.
Yeah. The, the video is,
the video is really quite fascinating.
It's, did you find it? Yeah. Okay.
I play this bitch
like Jackson, like Jack. Yeah. Oh,
it's not that great. I'm sorry. Well,
because I knew I was right.
You know,
we talked about this in our very first
interview and conversation together.
Um,
it's obvious now that artists are supposed
to own their master recordings. Okay.
This isn't the part will be,
there's a part where he talks about
chemistry takes them bodies. Oh, it's,
it's Prince Dick Gregory. You started to
see a whole bunch of, Huh, here we go.
Phenomena of chem trails.
Okay.
And you know,
when I was a kid,
I used to see these trails
in the sky all the time.
And so that's cool.
A jet just went over and then you
started to see a whole bunch of,
and next thing you know,
everybody in your neighborhood was
fighting and arguing and you did know why.
Okay. And, and you really didn't
know why. I mean, everybody was fine.
So he,
he started riffing about
the chem trails and
he started to say things
that, uh, hit home so hard.
And I would recommend that everybody try
to get what he said online or wherever
and try to get a copy of
it and just listen to it.
I'm so moved that I had to write the song.
He wrote a song about chem
trails. Really, when you lean,
what?
All the half,
what is this?
That's just ancillary video.
That's actually Dick Gregory.
That's the guy who brought these approved
or filmed of the Geraldo Rivera show.
Dick Gregory, the older guy. He, uh, was a
standup comedian, like an activist and he,
he bought this approved or film to a
Geraldo Rivera show and showed it on
television. President Kennedy
getting shot for the first time.
It's actually in the 1970s long after his
death, he died in [inaudible] 63 they,
they showed it on TV, I think I'm
like 72 or something like that.
72 73 it might have been, you would have
done that. Yeah. They showed the actual,
it might've been 75. The uh, um, yeah,
they showed the actual gunshot to
the head on national television.
Even showed a close up on it and Geraldo
Rivera was the conspiracy theorist back
then. Geraldo Rivera who now
works for Fox News back then.
He was saying the clot shot clearly
comes from the front as you see his head
snapped back into the left. Like
wow. It's interesting. Really.
It is tough to argue that. I mean, I'd
love to, I'd love to see that broken down.
Like how do you explain his
head going in front to back,
but how crazy his prints on KemTrace.
Oh my goodness.
It's like you listen to
that and you're like, wow.
And all of a sudden everyone's fighting.
And I couldn't figure
when I was a kid,
there was only a few airplanes.
And then as the airplane business
got bigger, there was more airplanes.
Well, when he's saying actually kind of
flies in the face of the traditional camp
trail fears,
they believe that these,
these long lines in the sky didn't exist
in the past and that they are fairly
recent.
But there's like photos from like the 80s
and shit and people took where there's
these lines in the sky and it looks
like artificial clouds and it's just,
it's just part of the process of
flying a jet and mean it's, it,
it does create a cloud though.
And people will likely,
these clouds are blanking up. The Sky was,
it was really clear until they flew by.
That is true. It does happen.
Is that, that is real.
Yeah. And it goes along with
what you're saying about it,
the planes making it because,
uh,
planes have gotten bigger and
bigger as the years have gone on.
They didn't always have a seven
40 centers, seven 57 you know,
so as these are getting bigger, of course
the uh, the chem trails will be too,
it seems at least,
well there's,
you know,
the other thing that's real is that it
changes the temperature of the earth.
That is a fact, in fact,
that the temperature change
quite a bit after nine 11.
Do you remember what it was like when
nine 11 happened and then also no one was
flying for like two weeks? Yeah. What
changed the temperature of the earth?
But I forget if it heated up
or it down. Let's see, uh,
temperature changed nine one, one, let's
say. Cool. Dan, what would you say? Yeah,
I would say that. Yeah, I think so
too. Opposite reaction. Right, right.
Okay.
Let's say temperature change after nine
one one air traffic affects the climate.
Yeah, yeah. Let's do this.
Oh yeah. And then that seems
like the piece that I know,
the purity of the air definitely changes
temperature and then everybody's tears
even says it in here.
Listen to this.
During the three day commercial flight
hiatus when artificial clouds known as
con trails all but disappeared.
So they're like admitting on CNN that
these planes create artificial clouds.
Like no one's tried to hide it.
This isn't like some crazy conspiracy
that people wondering about.
But artificial clouds known
as has all but disappeared.
The variations in high and low
temperatures increased by 1.1 degrees.
Interesting each day.
Said meteorology,
meteorological researchers. That's
interesting. I don't know if that's,
I don't know if that
means anything though.
It's so hard to tell cause
like the temperature fluctuates
by more than a degree
every day anyway. And if it goes up, I
mean it could be, I mean I'm an idiot,
but I'm reading this and I'm
gonna go on. Are you sure? Anyway,
the point is in this,
even in this CNN paper from 2002 it says
artificial clouds known as con trails,
I think.
But people are looking at them,
they think it's something that didn't
happen before. They're like they, oh,
I didn't,
these weren't there before.
It doesn't mean that people
haven't sprayed shit out of planes.
But what it does mean is that what
you're seeing is not what you think is
happening.
Most of the time when you see this spray,
what you're seeing is a fucking cloud.
That's what happens when it goes
through the jet. But if it was a spray,
it wouldn't look like that.
If it was aluminum and Barium,
which is like what they're claiming the
government for some reason to spraying
in the sky, it would be more
like smoke signals or like a, um,
those things behind a plane to smoke
writer. It would linger in the sky.
But those are, those are heavy
metals. Those are particles.
Even if they're nanoparticles, they're
going to fall, they waste something.
It's not going to be
like moisture in the air,
which just lingers like a cloud was.
We know about clouds,
we don't know about shit that
like sits up in the clouds,
but it's actually aluminum. It just
floats up there. Well, that's not even,
that's not even possible. It would
fall, would fall out of the sky.
It's not the same thing.
So I understand people's
mistrust of the government.
I understand that people
are, but you can't, when,
when something's explainable, you got
to explain it. You know, and it doesn't,
doesn't remove all the other
possibilities than the fairies doings.
But it does explain one thing that
people are trying to point in the wrong
direction.
And the problem is if you,
if you pointing that direction and then
people can prove that that's not what's
going on,
but you won't let it go,
then they're not going to listen to you
when it comes to other shitty either.
You know, they're gonna,
they're gonna Think,
oh you're that guy that believes this
shit that's kind of wacky and this is one
of those things. It's a tricky
one man. It's really tricky. Yeah.
Cause it looks like they're fucking
spraying artificial clouds. Right.
And in effect, they are making
artificial clouds. That is a fact.
The guy in the show that one of the
craziest moments was that he, um,
had this a test that he did this water
test and he showed that there's aluminum
in the water,
but you look at the test results,
the t like the from the lab and it
says sludge. So like, and I go, well,
so, so it's got dirt
in it, not just water,
but it says sludge like to test results,
say sludge.
And all sludge has aluminum in it
because all dirt has aluminum in it.
So it's not testing water from
aluminum that fell from the sky.
You're testing water
for having dirt in it,
which also is always has aluminum in it.
Yeah.
So that was a good owning
by the way. I didn't want to
own them. I look, I'll, I'll,
you know,
I just,
I wish these guys had approached some of
these things with a little bit more of
an open mind and you know,
and not just go one way or the other,
but that's one, one of the things we're
seeing over and over again on this show,
so people just,
they get an idea in their head and they
just fucking and run with it. Right.
I thought that that little
town or whatever city that,
that the sound was coming from,
I thought that was the one in the most
interesting things about the episode from
yesterday.
But did they even,
did you even figure out if it was
coming from that? No one can tell.
No one can tell. Did you hear
it? No, I didn't hear it. The,
the people that experienced it,
they said it was really bad a
couple of years ago. It got better,
but occasionally it still happens.
It's like this weird hum
that's in this town and they,
no one knows what the hell is
causing it. Whoa. Yeah. It's like,
it's like we lost,
like rattles your windows and stuff and,
and it's in this area of Canada
called Windsor, Ontario. It's like,
well documented. There's, there's
terabytes of this hum online.
Nobody could figure out what the hell
it is. And some people believe it's, uh,
there's a lot of like crazy conspiracies.
One of them being that it's a harp
repeater station harp is this gigantic
antenna array that's in Alaska that
they send radio signals up into the
ionosphere. But you know, who
knows what the hell it is.
There's another thing to take into
consideration that nobody was willing to
consider, but it is
possible that they, uh,
they dig under the ground around there
for salt, you know, and they're, uh,
their salt mining and they say it wasn't,
you know,
that wasn't happening while the sound
was going on, but, you know, I don't,
I don't know how the fuck do, you
know, it's a weird thing though.
There's all these people experiences.
It's not just like a couple
of cuckoo heads see dragons.
There's like a lot of people and
they record it, you know? Wow. Yeah.
That's pretty freaky.
That one guy said he had seven terabytes
that I wish you had challenged him on
that. No, no. He does. He does. He record
that shit for like the entire night.
He likes, he'll set it up. He has like
a recorder and you're like seven MP,
three recorder up and tape
through the night. Yeah.
I really believe him because he has,
he's been following this and being
an activist on this shit for you.
Imagine if you lived there man,
and all sudden you fucking windows are
rattling in the middle of the night. Well,
yeah, I would move. Fuck, well
they don't have any money.
I wouldn't move to if you had some money,
but if you don't have any money, man,
oh shit.
And you're stuck there and you can't go
to sleep and then you have to get to go
to work in the morning and you're fucking
exhausted because your house has been
humming.
Windsor is a pretty interesting tags.
That's where everybody from Ohio and
Michigan goes to get drunk when they're 18
because you cannot drink there before
you're 21 oh really good example clubs.
Yeah,
Jamie [inaudible].
It's like you go there and
you fast forward three years
of your life and you can
do anything you want at
18 if you just go over it.
Bridge. Yeah. Well Detroit
is fucking crazy, man.
If you never been to Detroit before,
I recommend going just
to see the $39 houses,
house houses for sale for $39 dude,
you could buy a house for $39 they told
us we could buy a house for $500 and I
thought they were fucking crazy.
And then someone from the Rogan
board found a house for $39 wow.
Jesus do. They just went bankrupt.
The entire city went bankrupt.
It almost seems like it's almost like
an apple stock at the very beginning.
Like we should buy all these $39 houses.
You know, like, like while they're this,
you know what, man, it might not come
back in your lifetime. It might be.
What we're seeing might be when people
find the ruins of ancient cities in the
past. Sometimes cities just go so
far down. They never come back.
Sometimes cities stick around forever.
Like Rome.
You could drive by the fucking
coliseum today. Somehow or another,
they managed to keep some form of a
society around in that area for all these
years. It changed. It morphed, but there's
still people there. They still a society,
but fucking Detroit is
close. It's close, man.
It's 47% illiteracy rate.
47 47% illiteracy rate.
Yeah. It's crazy. I mean, it is,
it is one of the craziest places
in the world and it's in America.
It's a place that used to thrive.
Think about like the fifties
and sixties like the,
the roaring times for the auto industry.
They're making fucking 69 Chevy's and
everybody's making money and his union
workers and everyone's getting paid well,
and then all of a sudden somewhere along
the line jams like, we're out of here,
dog. We're going to take our shit to
Mexico. We're going to make cars in China.
We're going to, you guys cost too
much money. We're tired of this shit.
And they pull out and it's catastrophic.
Oh yeah. I mean, you seem Roger and me,
uh, the Michael Moore. Yeah. Yeah, I
think so. Yeah. It's all about that.
It's all about Flint,
Michigan.
It's all about the watching these towns
implode when the jobs aren't there
anymore. The Luda jobs literally pull
out of the community and Poof, that's it.
They're gone. And then everybody's
like, oh my God, how do I eat?
And then it's fucking crazy
that's going on, right.
The city where I'm from, uh, just
got ranked. I, there was an article,
I tweeted the number one most
dilapidated city or something like that,
and it used to be the number one steel
producing city for the entire world.
And they built it there because it was
so cloudy that back in the day satellites
couldn't see through clouds. Oh my God.
So they built it all in Youngstown, Ohio,
which has the weird lake effect.
So there's always clouds over
where I'm from pretty much. And uh,
and um, so the whole steel
industry was there and then it, uh,
it's nothing. I mean, it, there is
nothing there now. That's incredible.
It's really wild. It was a big, big,
big steel producing city and uh,
and Mafia town. And they got rid of
the mafia and the nineties and steel,
like the seventies super mafia
town. Yeah, that's actually a
what my parents, uh, my parents
were in that business before.
Um, they did some shady
stuff. Family things. Yeah,
they were, they were almost, almost
everybody that my parents knew as well.
They knew them from being, you
know, in some kind of business.
Like my mom for example, ran
numbers, you know, number running.
It's like a form of racketeering
and the illegal lottery.
So she would be the center
person of this entire thing.
All the people that would call in
their numbers would call her and uh,
and that's what just what she did.
Wow. That's incredible. Yeah. My uh,
grandmother went to jail for
numbers running. Really? Yeah.
She apparently got caught.
You know,
what she would do was she'd be
like the go between or something.
She would like move things, you
know, I was like a job I guess.
And they arrested her and she
didn't want to rat anybody out.
So she spent like six
months in jail. Wow. Yeah.
I didn't even know about it until
I was like in my twenties you know,
my mom never told us about it.
Yeah, it's interesting. Yeah.
She had no choice but to tell
me because when I was a kid,
you know how when you're a kid and the
phone rings, you try to pick it up. Hello.
Well people would ask for a,
for Gina and my mom's name, joy.
So when they're like, hello
is Gina, is Gina, is Gina
available? No, Gina lives here.
Sorry. And I remember one
day I told my mom, I go, mom,
people keep calling asking for Gina.
She goes,
what are you doing with these phone calls?
What do you mean? And like, you know,
cause she obviously she
was missing business.
I was just being a little
kid being helpful. No, Gina
here. Sorry. Oh Wow. But uh,
and so very young,
I had to realize what she
was doing because also she
was on the phone a lot and
she would be repeating back
these numbers to people.
And there's like all this terminology
and stuff like Po and box and all these
different things like that.
Straight or boxed,
which means like straight means you're
picking three numbers in a row, like four,
six, seven and box means you
could have four, six, seven
but if it comes out seven,
four, six or six, four, seven
or whatever you win either way.
So there's all this terminology. So
you'd hear on the phone three, three,
four force it cause she would repeat back
the numbers that they just gave her to
confirm. So it's like
unbelievable. Wow. Yeah.
So that's who you grew up in
that environment. Did you,
did you ever see anything like dangerous
or was it just like gambling type stuff?
Nothing dangerous ever.
The closest thing that, uh,
the closest thing that I had
a weird feeling about when
I was a kid was one time
my dad came to visit
cause I lived with my mom.
So my dad would just come
in and visit sometimes.
And the weirdest thing was he came
in, came over when the day with a, uh,
with a cast on, with a cast on his hand.
And I'm like, how'd you break hand?
And I remember
my mom looking at him weird and
him looking at her, we, I don't,
I still don't know exactly what happened
with the, with a broken hand. But I mean,
I don't know. It could be
like a punishment. He could've
beat somebody up. He was,
he owned a restaurant, uh, at
the time. So it's not like he,
he didn't do, he didn't and he wasn't
the hands on guy at the restaurant.
I don't know how he broke his hand.
Yeah.
We're going to have to leave that one
to yeah, yeah, yeah. Suspicions. Yeah.
It'd be nice to,
Alicia didn't like make something up like
to fill in the blank to make the story
better. Right. No, exactly.
I keep it real. Yeah.
Isn't it weird when you really stop and
think about how little our parents knew
about the world?
Like now that we live in this really
strange place where we're finding out like
pretty, you mean you just ask your
phone and it's in a lancer, you almost,
any question you can come up with and you
just think about growing up and having
kids and living your whole life
without that and you're like, my God.
Like is that even society?
Was that even civilization?
Wow. Our poor fucking parents.
It's unbelievable. They
were lucky they had phones.
Oh yeah. They really, where there's apes.
I know the evolution of everything's
crazy. I just found out there's a,
a high school district in La in which
all the kids are getting iPads now.
So they upload all their information on
the IPAD and that's their only book send
out.
They're done with books.
And think about how many tons of pounds
of books we carried on our shoulders.
His kids for no reason.
There's a jet,
there's generations to come that
will never know that feeling.
They're going to look at us like,
what do you mean you were
carrying books around?
It doesn't make any p tons of
paper stacked on top. What is that?
Why would you do that? I don't get
it as they scan through nothingness.
You know what I mean?
It's thinking about that the other
day about how paper and books,
it's just going to be this and take well
how are you starting to see like some
of these different phones that are
coming out that allow you to answer and
scroll and do things without actually
touching the phone and that when you look
away from the phone like it
changes the way the phone behave.
Look at it. Yeah. Yes for does that. Yeah.
I think three also where you could just
wave your hand over to like answer our
phone call as well. I don't
know. The four does though.
There's a lot of like weird
shit's happening was like
the ability to like just
conjure things up out of the air with
your hands and your, your you'll looks,
it just doesn't seem like a
good idea because he's like,
give me like laying in bed,
like phone ringing and you like with wave
over it now you just have a video call
and your Dick's just like
in the, you know, like,
it just seems like a problem
for Brian, right? Yeah.
If you sleep with your
Dick next to your phone,
you'd have pull your dick out every time
the phone rings just on instinct. Oh,
we doing this? Okay, we're doing
this. You want to do this? Yeah. No,
I think that what I was getting
at is that, uh, it's, it's,
it's going to get weird
and to live the human
computer, human information interface
is going to get weirder and weirder.
It's the, who knows what the
limit is way. This is going to be
a bit something implant or
something. Oh yeah, totally.
Something you see,
you scrolling through things,
there's going to be a point to even wear
wearing a lens or something is going to
be like, oh look, that's peppers
and still wearing the lens.
No balls to get a fucking operation buddy.
Right?
You're afraid of neural implant starts,
they'll do something to your
eye and then they realize no,
you really got to get to their
cerebral cortex itself. Right.
So it'd be like it'd be looking at
people like they pierce their ears.
Did you get your brain peers?
Yeah,
just going right down the
factory line in the baby ward,
whatever those are called.
Duncan and I were talking about this and
we both agree that there's gonna come a
time where you're probably not gonna
use your regular memory anymore,
that you regularly memory will be
replaced by some sort of internal digital
storage,
which can record everything you
see in total real time HD. Right?
I mean that's pretty pretty likely to
be what we're dealing with in the future
and then we're going to swap hard drives
and shit and I'm going to be able to
watch 20 inch clamp. It
really is. It's going to be,
it's going to be like the Matrix, how
they just upload information. Yeah.
It seems like it's inevitable. They've
already figured out a way to um, uh,
put artificial memories in a mouse.
Have you heard of that? Yeah.
Yeah.
They figured out a way to do that to mice.
They figured out a way to somehow or
another install and artificial memory in a
mouse and they also figured out how
to make a cat's tail move without a,
actually like a man with a brain thing
on can make a cat's tail move wirelessly
somehow or another. I need
to do that. Man. That sounds
awesome. It's fucking nuts.
I put it up on Twitter. If you could find
it. It was within the last day or two.
Maybe Jamie can help you. The, uh, the
story is a, it's pretty fucking freaky.
The ability to control another thing.
Me Even it's just a cat with your brain.
What the fuck is going
to happen in the future?
People are going to force people to
walk into their houses and blow them and
having your pet will be a
totally different experience.
Like that would be like your warrior.
Like all right Kat,
go in the kitchen and see if
there's anybody there like your,
cause if you could make the cat tail move
totally in 20 years you'll be able to
control your cat.
So your animal,
your dog or pit bull or whatever would
now be like your weapon or like your Hawk
as a needle, like a pirate. Especially
when you could kind of do that enough.
You train your dog really well,
but you might be able to control it
with your mind and see through its eyes,
eyes and feel. It's, it's some game of
Thrones anyway. Yeah. That would be crazy.
When you imagine if you killed somebody
with your dog and then there'd be like
some crazy legal thing. Like it wasn't my
idea. The dog went fucking crazy. Okay.
I'm trying to control the dog with the
brain. I'm just not that good at it yet.
The dog went crazy and killed the burglar.
Okay,
I'm not a murderer or we're having like
an eagle or having some kind of huge
bird or a gorilla. Like you
can control animals that, yeah,
well they, you can control a few animals
to do a few things, you know, like they,
have you ever seen those videos of
Mongols? This is the, uh, the brain.
Harvard creates brain to brain interface,
allowing humans to control other
animals with thoughts alone. Wow.
Hitting these Zale entails hooked up to
this thing and he figured out a way to
make the tail move so we can already
have the cat's tail answer, uh,
galaxy three phone.
So it's,
it seems like it's just a matter of
time before you're able to control
everything the cat does.
And then that'll be like version one.
And then eventually virgin too will be,
you'll be able to see what the cat sees.
Wow. It's crazy. It's fucked up wild.
That's what it's turning
into human beings. Uh,
just wanting to be cats and stuff just
because they may like the cats. Like, Hey,
where's this guy? Can I be a
human? It's so crazy, so crazy.
It's all so crazy. It's weird. It's so
crazy. It's weird because you wonder like,
where is this going and there's no
way to know or else we would. Well,
it seems like it is not going to stop.
It's just going to get more and
more invasive. More and more.
You're going to be able to do all kinds
of really strange things within the next
few years or they're going to someone,
whoever has that kind of technology
controlling a fucking cat's tail. Jay's.
Dot.
This is awesome.
Have you ever seen those videos of the
Mongols that hunt wolves with the eagles?
Holy Shit, dude. Golden Wool.
Golden Eagles might be the most gangster
animal on the planet because they do
not give two fucks about a wolf and
they swooped down and kill a wolf.
What their out their talents. I showed
it to Steve Vanilla. He's a hunter.
He's just got that show of meat eater.
He's unimpressed.
He said they were more
coyote looking wolves.
There weren't the biggest
wolves in the world,
which I'll give you that there's
still fucking wolves, right bird.
Think about that. You weigh about
140 pounds. Tony Hinchcliffe.
Could you imagine if you had to kill a
60 pound wolf with your fucking teeth?
Now you have to tackle wolf and
then kill it with your face.
You know how the w, you know an
eagle weighs 25 pounds and it does.
That swoops in and Jack's a
fucking wolf with its face,
clings onto the back of this
thing, attacks it and, and
takes it out cold quick.
Watch this shit. Watch this shit.
You got it. No, no. Pull it up.
Mongols hunt with eagles. It's
going to trip you out, man.
I watched this once a month. The Eagle
comes back to the Mongol. Yup. Kills the,
he kills the wolf and then they
use the wolf. Are they buy them?
They take their first. Wow. They
make like hats out of them and shit.
I don't understand why the Eagle
does that. Cause they're gangster.
They don't give a fuck. Watch this
shit. This is really trippy, man.
Look at this fucking bird.
This is agent of death
soaring dinosaur of death.
Watch this.
Bam Bitch.
Just that wolf knows it's coming to.
It fucks him up so quick.
It just gets those claws around its
neck and it's a wrap within seconds.
[inaudible]
look at that heartless motherfucker.
Watch this shit.
The wolves running is poor wolf was like,
oh, you gotta be fucking kidding me.
This guy just let's this
monster loose off of his arm.
Okay.
And it knows exactly what to do.
The Wolf is running and the Eagle
just count. The Wolf was like, oh,
fuck my life.
Fuck my life.
Look at that thing, man. Ego Sung this
song. I wish that Eagle Sung the song.
I love the eagles.
Welcome to the the phone.
Watch this.
Bam Bitch,
man.
It just takes them out within seconds.
It's incredible how lethal these things
are. That's why I look at those dudes.
What a dumb way to dress
Lilly.
I can train an eagle to kill a wolf,
still wearing a toilet.
Paper rolls on their
heads and it's straight.
I guess it's cold as fuck there though.
You know they probably need all that
stupid shit on just to stay alive. Yeah.
Just think of how much time it must take
to train a fucking eagle to kill a wolf.
Like how many eagles did you let go
and they never came back. How many,
how many eagles did you let go and
be like, bitch, I'm not killing.
I won't even know that. Well Fuck you man.
Right? Flying South. It's cold up here.
I wonder if the eagles just can't help
themselves and when something is running
they just go get it. You know, I wonder
if it's that this is terrifying animals.
I saw one the other day in Seattle,
so fucking Eagle,
they have eagles up there and
it had something in his hands.
That one got something,
some sort of fish or something.
I've been noticing a lot of
parrots lately in Burbank,
just like real mobs of parrots
like flying over my like,
like for 20 the other day and
they're all green with like the red.
It's like how Florida has pythons lose
cause people let them go right in Burbank.
It's parents. I fucking hate my bird
opened the window, get out pitch right.
There was a friend who lives up
here in Calabasas and he, he has,
he lives on like the place where they
film true blood. Like, it's, it's huge,
huge mansion type thing.
But he was talking about the other day
how a tarantula somehow God was in him.
Like he has the crazy,
he lives on this crazy like
humongous thing in the mountain.
So you know the caliber or Santa Monica
Mountains and there's all these weird
things like, like, like lizards
and snakes. But when he got,
had a tranche let in his, in his bedroom
the other day and he's like, well,
I don't know how the fuck it got.
Yeah, there's Tarantulas in
California. It's creating,
get him anywhere in the La area. I like
people that live in the Hollywood hills,
you know when they have a problem with
the Hollywood hills rats. Yeah, I see.
I see tons of Burbank. I know a
story. I don't know if it's true,
but I'll tell it anyway
about Sylvester Stallone,
apparently that someone went to
a Sylvester Stallone's house.
He had a house in the Hollywood
hills and when they were,
he had a movie theater and he told them,
he goes,
put your feet up when you watch the
movie because we have rats. Like what?
Like they couldn't get rid of the rats.
The rats were just like so infested in
the hills up there that you would have,
I'm like running through your house.
Sometimes
they ran on the power lines outside.
Like I'll sit out back and you just see
rats running on it and then one time a
rat came up and stepped on my
foot or something like that.
And I will you barefoot? Yeah.
Oh my. I uh, through my laptop.
It was like the first time I had bought
a new Mac book and I opened it up for
the first time and I'm looking at like,
oh, look how nice and sexy this is.
Rat right on foot throws laptop
up in the air, falls down. No,
it fell down to break. No, luckily
just landed fine. Build quality.
Yeah. Powerful IPOD,
iPhone, apple product pitch.
Yeah. Um, rats were fucking gross.
They've carried disgusting disease
is to have those fucks. Oh, they,
the black plague came from a rats
carrying a tick, I think, I think,
or a flea or something like that.
I think that's what it was. Right.
Something like that.
I think it was some sort of a parasitic
thing that rats were carrying bugs gave
them,
well it's so gross and I'm one
of those people where like if I,
if I were to see a rat or a cockroach
where I live, I would just move. Well
that's one of the realities of
living in New York City. You know,
if you want to live in New York City,
you're going to see roaches and you're
going to see rats if you're paying
attention. When I lived in New York, there
was one time I never lived in the city.
I lived in new Rochelle,
which is like just outside the city,
like outside of the Bronx,
little suburb, Westchester. Um,
I parked my car at this gas station and
it was back when there was payphones.
I didn't have a car phone. I had to make
a call. I had to like get out of the car.
So I'm making a call on this payphone.
As my car is parked,
I'm watching rats jump on top of
the tires and climb up into the car.
I'm watching them and I'm like,
what the fuck? I mean, not one,
like three, four, five. They just
kept doing it, looking for food,
like the car parked.
So they jumped on the back tire that run
over the top of the tire to run under
the car.
They ran up into the engine compartment
and sometimes they just stay in the
engine department.
You're fucking fan tears them apart cause
they're stupid heads are in there and
you start the car up
and fucking you open up the hood and just
splatter everywhere because I'm stupid
rat got inside of your fan. Yeah
man. They look for food everywhere.
They'll burrow the themselves and the
little tiny holes to try to search for
something that might be food. That's
Yonkers. Yeah, well it was actually,
that was in Manhattan. It was in New
York City. Uh, I'll never forget it.
I was just like, what? What the fuck?
And then when you find out that there's
this many rats in New York City as there
are people,
there's this,
there's 7 million people in New York City.
So there's 7 million rats in New York
City. Imagine controlling those rats.
They really have a hard time.
I think a lot of them drowned in Sandy.
I think a lot of, uh, those underground
layers and shit drown because, uh,
Shane Smith did a video once read af
after sandy a video about the possibility
superstorms increasing and
like a river of dead rats,
like flowed by him as he was a, as you're
standing there talking, I was like,
Holy Shit, you thing,
the thing that scared
me when I moved here was a,
I lived in Burbank when I first got
here and the Black Widows, oh yeah.
First it's like almost a normal spider
until you really look at that belly and
you see that red diamond thing.
Yeah.
That's the part where you're just
like this fucking thing. And it's,
it's interesting how nature
sort of a warns you about like,
I like I've read things about snakes.
If you see like red, yellow, black,
and that spider, that red diamond,
I mean if you look at it, it really,
it's like a warning sign, right?
Yeah. You're totally right.
It's incredible how nature,
uh, does that stuff.
You know what else I saw recently
is a thing about how butterflies,
if you look at a,
if you look at butterflies that
are around area where snakes are,
when their wings are up and they're just
chilling, most of them look like snakes.
Like if you look up a
butterfly snake, uh, Eh,
I mean it's unbelievable.
Wow. That makes sense. So
then any intruder that comes
by, it's like, oh shit.
A snake instead of a look at this pussy
butterfly I'm about to eat. You know?
That's interesting. It's
really incredible. Yeah. It's,
it's weird when you see animals that
have figured out how to mimic their
environment, you know, like,
have you ever seen octopus or Octopi
that change their shape and their look to
look exactly like the environment?
Well,
look at these crazy looking butterflies
that totally looks like a snake. Right?
That's incredible. Yup. Oh
my God. That's what they do.
That's amazing. Yeah. Wow.
Folks who view of, you're not,
obviously you don't watch most people
listening. There's a, what is the,
the Google that you go let her
fly snake butterflies. Snake.
There's one that looks like
these two fucking syrup.
It actually several that looked like it,
but they look like these two serpent
heads right next to each other. I mean,
exactly under the underside.
It's all looks that corner
one. Oh my God. That's amazing.
That's incredible.
Seen this by the way. You'll notice
that in actually a lot of butterflies.
It's not,
it's not necessarily a rare thing at all.
I'm pretty sure if they ever see a snake,
they're pretty much like,
well that's what I want.
That's amazing. That is really
amazing. It looks just like it.
Now look up. Um, octopus
camouflage, octopus camouflage.
He's really weird man,
because they also think that they
don't just look at that fucking,
it looks like a butterfly. We're looking
at the tip of the butterflies wound.
That looks like a snake. I mean it has
an eyeball and even has a nose. Yup.
It's like Steve Harvey
has a mouth immediately.
It's a beautiful tattoo of a
snake. Yeah. And it's the softest,
most precious,
easy to kill animal in the world.
Butterfly of all the things. Yeah.
They're like, they're like man, a mush.
I mean they're softer than a fly there.
A butterfly.
Like they were like a tissue flies,
right?
Octopus or Octopi can blend in with their
surroundings and they also think that
they,
their
ability to change shape on the
outside of the camouflage. Look,
they think they use that also to
communicate that it's not just,
um, that, that is
incredible. It's incredible.
We're looking at this octopus
that's completely blended
in with this white floor
and there's also been ones
that have eaten sharks.
They had a problem at this aquarium
where they're sharks started missing and
they would find like shark carcasses. So
they're like, what the fuck is going on?
What's eating at shark? And so they
watched this video, they set up a camera,
see there's a video of it. Brian's
even go watch it if you could find it.
But it's,
they do it on a regular basis.
Like apparently octopus are
smart as fuck or Octopi.
And they set up this camera and um,
they watched this octopus just sit there
completely camouflaged and as his shock
flies by him over the years.
But when the keepers here
decided to move one into a larger
tank with sharks and other big fish,
they assumed that the octopuses strength
and camouflage would keep it safe.
Is it turned out they
went tragically mistaken.
Watch the sharks got a gun.
It's Chardonnay though.
So you see this thing swimming.
Watch this shit
like the shark has no idea that
octopus is there dies in evil looking
motherfucker, white eyes, wide eyes,
completely camouflages
with his environment.
You're waiting for that motherfucker
to get clothes. Watch this.
It's like bitch, I got you. My God.
So bad ass.
And you know they have like teeth,
like little beaks on the end of their,
of their check suction cups. Yeah.
It's like sharp, like little cat. Yeah.
They found giant ones in a
fossil and that they believe it.
It could possibly be evidence for a
cracking the idea of a crack and it's like
an ancient mythology idea of
a chai and octopus that would
take out ships and kill people.
And they always thought
it was just mythology and
horseshit until they recently
found these giant fucking
suction cups and fossils.
And then they realize, oh
yeah, if the, if octopus die,
they don't live behind anything.
It's not like they're not like
a person leaves behind a skull.
The octopus are mollusks this movable,
you know,
sort of weird flexible material
and all they have is like a beak.
And that gets eaten by things like
really quickly. So if they die,
like you don't find shit,
but somehow or another someone died and
the imprint of it's suction cups left a
mark on the floor and they're enormous.
And so in looking at these,
they were like, oh my God. Like
this was a massive octopus.
Like something that was just
impossibly large. Oh Wow. Look at this.
The octopus got this cat's face.
The cat got gangster and the,
the octopus locked on its face and
it's fucking this cat up. Look at this.
Oh my God. It's like alien, like an alien
face hugger. Octopussy is that a, um,
a vine? So what that is? Give a gift.
That's hilarious. Yeah. The cat
cat. You think you're clever?
Octopuses are so smart.
They've,
they've had videos that they've taken
of them on security cameras where they
climb out of a fish tank and go across
the floor and climb into another fish
tank and then eat the
fish and then climb back.
Like guy was missing like these expensive,
efficient as fish tank. He's like,
what the fuck is going on?
So he set up his camera to look his fish
tank and he watched his octopus climb
out of his fucking fish tank, walk across
the floor, climb up the other fish,
stand the tank, stand climbing into
the tank, lift the lid off of it.
Jackfish kill it,
walk across the street how back into
his tank and go to sleep. I mean,
Jesus Christ, it's what the fuck
are those things believable?
What are those things? Have you
seen this? What is this? A bear
bear, uh, getting into a
dumpster behind a restaurant,
walking up to the back of the restaurant
and there's this big humongous green
dumpster, you know, full of
old meats and stuff like that.
Probably smart ass bear
goes around the side of it.
Let me see if I can fast forward
it. Where did this take place? Um,
I forget it.
He starts going through it and then he
does something amazing coming up right
here. He's taking the whole entire
dumpster and walking with it.
The Fuck Gotti.
Wow.
And uh, yeah, if you keep on going,
he actually starts pulling it, uh,
around the corner.
Oh my God.
Tom Credible.
And that's like a humongous dumsor.
That's like a double wide dumpster.
Bears are so swollen. Then he comes back
for the strong, I should say what? Um,
then he comes back.
Where does it say this is a,
let's see. Uh, do you do, do,
it doesn't say it's just, Oh, Denver.
Denver totally makes sense.
You know what's interesting is that they
have a real problem when bears find out
they can do that. They always come back.
Like once a bear eats your garbage,
you got to call somebody,
you got a real problem.
They either have to shoot it or they have
to figure out a way to put it in a zoo
or do something because once it knows it,
can he get garbage.
It just keeps eating your garbage.
So if you live in a community that has
bears and you have that asshole neighbor
that leaves pizza boxes and is fucking
garbage is sitting out there and a bear
finds out about it,
you're Foxville.
I'm so glad I don't live near big animals.
When I was in Texas,
they introduced me to the goats
and these fucking things are crazy.
He's a little goats that I thought were
all cute and just like adorable or head
butting each other at full. They're like,
Tony, get on it and there goes, hey,
these goats get on in there and I am just,
I'm just not,
not the guy to be in
there with goats like,
oh look at the little La
Pussy boy with the goats.
Look how scared he charge
things or animals. Yeah,
absolutely. Who wants to have it
fist fight with a kid?
A house cat.
Do you want to have a fist fight
with a house cat? No. Fuck No.
I'm a lot bigger than a house cat, but
I wouldn't want to fuck with one. Right?
Yeah. That cat was jumping
off the furniture trying to
claw your eyes out. Yeah.
It gets scary animals. It's
just so different than people.
You don't want to fuck.
I got a little goat. I got home late
the other night, even little Twix.
He scared me. You know Brian's little
dog, little white, perfect little baby.
But I can,
but I know I came home late.
It's all dark and my living room and I
see something on the couch like looking
at me. I'm like, what the fuck is that?
Because normally Trixie's blocked
him probably about a 9.9 and uh,
but uh,
but normally she's blocked off upstairs
and stays up there throughout the night.
So this thing was on the couch and
I could see it just standing out.
I got really concerned.
I'm like,
what kind of fucking and am I know
that's an animal looking at me.
I flipped on the light and it's
the cutest dog in the world,
but I was really scared. I'm
like, what kind of white is that?
Like an all an albino raccoon that
somehow climb through a window?
I S my brain just started flying.
Well, somebody left their door open.
It was a photo that was taken. Um,
where was that? Was that you, Jamie?
Did you find that there a photo taken
of a coyote that was in someone's house?
No, somebody showed it to
me in an email. A coyote,
a snuck into someone's house and I
think it was in boulder and just,
it was like in their house.
So they opened up the front door and they
see a coyote is sitting in their house
and they're like, oh Jesus Christ. How
do you get this fucking thing out? Right.
Did you see the mountain lion that
was a in the guy's garage? No. Yeah.
Look up mountain lion and garage and
in Colorado these guys had like a
confrontation with the
Mountain Lion Mountain Lion,
like ran right past this guy and into a
corner and the guy goes into the corner,
try to chase a mountain lion out and
the mount line runs past him again.
And you watch this,
you on what the fuck
things are happening in Colorado.
They in and they just legalized pot.
It sounds like the last thing you'd
want after getting really stone,
I'm going to go to the garage, grabbed a
soda. I'm high as fuck. Oh, this is it.
Yeah.
This
is exactly it. So these guys, they
saw the cat. There it is. Look
in the yelling at it like,
oh Jesus.
They're going after it and then look,
he steps in there.
She's not back yet and it's going
to run past it. Look at this.
Whoa. And he kicked it as it ran. Pastor.
That is nuts, man. Look at that thing. Go.
Wow. That's so crazy, man.
They weren't scared of that shit
at all. Yeah, those are hunters.
They were all wearing cammo does see
that there are hunters probably. Yeah,
but still you should be scared.
So thing decides to jump you.
You have problems with mine.
Totally. You've got problems.
I don't get that leverage.
You can't choke out a mountain lion
quite as easily as you can a human.
The thing about mountain lions, those,
there's so much food in Colorado,
there's so many animals for them to eat
so many rabbits and deer to so much for
them.
To Jack.
They don't really care.
You could just probably have a
spray bottle with those guys.
Just sit back and chill.
Puppy. Come here, puppy.
Did you see the clip of
Steve Harvey? Uh, uh,
bringing up marijuana on family feud?
Oh No.
Well, yeah, it's pretty
funny. Check this out. Hi.
We got them top success named
something that gets passed around.
Oh,
Chris,
a joint.
Joel [inaudible] look at Steve
Harvey's in questioning closes.
I'm off. Oh, I am so wacky.
The man says I've seen this
before, haven't you? Yeah.
Let's see what he says though.
I don't remember.
No,
Chris.
I don't know 100 people you thought we
were talking to at some nice little mall
across Goodall America, but I'm pretty
sure that people didn't tell the survey.
People Hae an illegal drug that's turned
around and see how many we'd hands are
out there with Chris hot joint.
I believe it. He was talking shit
against it. That's hilarious.
But this is the best part.
[inaudible]
when you're know we're going
to hear why it's weird. Okay,
Tracy,
see only four else's topic.
So
the collection played at Church
[inaudible] he clapped cause
he felt bad about saying joint.
Yeah, the halo and I got no knowledge.
So I'm like, I like the way you tried
to stop us from going there. Hey,
you missed you evil boy passing around.
The little thing with this funny
smell with can flush some saving here.
Charge
less than two weeks.
That's created then the joint.
This is not good. I'm
just going to do, did
you just go over that? They're
going to play this? Yes. Yeah. Wow.
Similarities though. That is pretty, it's
funny to me that you know,
if you said a beer, you know,
no one gives a shit. Right.
You know. But you say a
joint like, oh my goodness,
it really is such children. It's so
bizarre. Such children pairing it to hell.
Even he's a real like hardcore Christian.
That guy.
This is his audience is very,
very Christian. He does like a,
these big stadium church
shows here. She knows. Yeah.
You see one of those things that like
makes the women in wheelchairs or walking?
No, no, no, no.
He just does stand up
comedy and big church shows.
He does. Uh, he has like radio show. He
does a lot of different shit. That guy.
These, yeah. I admire his hustle.
Totally. Scott. A lot of things going on.
He's got his own radio show. He
does that show. He does stand up.
He does these big church stand up shows.
It's not my style. I don't, you know,
not my kind of comedy, but I
admire the dude's hustle. I get,
I enjoy when people are hustle.
What are you guys laughing at?
My God jam band just showed me this,
this video and it's when it was fucked up.
But you know Kevin Rose of
Digg. Oh, with the rack. Yeah.
She'll show that I at one time and
rose found a raccoon attacking his dog.
Yeah. He grabbed it and threw
it off. Kevin Rose like he
founded what? What did he,
he found dig. He was on the screen savers,
you know? Yeah. On g four and stuff,
it says at 1:00 AM I heard my dog
toaster crying and yelping and Panna
discovered a raccoon and attack him.
I do not encourage animal violence.
I want to get the wild animals far away
from us as possible. Toasters. Okay.
Would have some claw and bite marks.
So that's what it says at the beginning
of the video and the video. You see this,
this raccoon and the dog
are fucking going at it.
And so Kevin Rose runs down
there, grabs a raccoon, slams it,
and then kicks it. Holy Shit.
He's gangster grabbed that thing.
He didn't kick it first.
He just reached out and grabbed
his hands and then hulk slammed it.
Wow. Oh Nelly. Oh Shit.
Down a staircase isn't and yeah.
Whoa.
Now where is that a security camera that
caught that? Yeah. Is that his house?
Yeah. Wow. That's so crazy state.
He grabbed that thing and hurled it like
a, like a pillow. Yeah. Body-Slammed it.
Hey, that's how you do it when you
loved ones are in danger. You know?
It's like when a woman picks up a
truck to save her baby, you know,
that kind of shit. Yeah.
I hit that freak strength.
Think I would have just kicked it. I
don't think I would touch it with my hand.
I think I would just like, it's hard
as I could. Yeah, I think you're right.
I think I probably would've too.
Who knows?
Now you hear that yelping or your
favorite little pet little wiki has uh,
you might just,
I would grab a raccoon off of your dog.
You don't just go read eyed. You might
just get crazy. But God, I was scary.
Would it be that thing
locked on your face? Sorry, I
took my dog due to the vet and he had
these canines I guess like puppy teeth,
like they're supposed to fall out,
but a lot of times their normal teeth
will grow around their baby teeth. Yeah.
You told me about this shit had
to pull out all these man at poor
dog is just sitting there like
looking at walls crying. Yeah.
That's fucked up man. It's weird.
Lincoln's he's a little breeds to,
because you got to think like,
what are those things like, I mean,
how healthy is it to make an animal
that weighs a pound, you know? Well,
what's involved in that process? Is
that like normal? It's a normal salary,
something like that. It's not, it's not
a tea cup or anything, it's just a shit.
So yeah, it's a, yeah. A lot of
people think it's like a tea cup,
but I think it's just the, a rent
or whatever it's called, you know,
like that the baby of the litter
is small one at the litter. Hm.
That's called a ranch.
Yeah. I did some research on a twic
sees a thing in the peak and knees dog.
You know, they used to, uh,
the how they came was they would have
like Samurai warriors would just leave
these beautiful little puppies
in the bottom of their sleeves,
so they'd walk around and be all the,
you know, intimidating and stuff.
So to offset that,
they'd have these adorable little dogs
as they would just walk around with them.
Yeah. Speaking of animals, Brian,
I want you to go to this store.
It's on the daily cause. Chaos.
You ever go to that website?
Go to daily cars.com
and there's a story on,
I'll tweet it because it's
so fucking crazy. You're not
going to believe it. This,
these armed agents came into a no
kill shelter. I just tweeted it.
Um,
you can find the link.
These armed agents when they had a no
kill shelter for like dogs, you know,
so like if you don't want,
you could,
you could donate money
and it's like a nonprofit.
So like for a dog that goes to a pound,
a lot of times they're in danger of being
killed. So there's a few of these, no,
no kill shelters that people set up to
make sure that these animals don't die.
Well,
someone put a deer in one
of these no kill shelters.
So aerial photos were taken.
They saw the deer.
A warrant was issued in a raid
in sued by heavily armed agents.
The staff was corralled,
not permitted to make calls and cell
phones were confiscated to delete pictures
of the raid.
And a baby deer named giggles by the
staff was seized and stuffed into a body
bag and then promptly
killed by the agents.
The presiding warden compared it
to a drug raid to justify the Swat,
like tactics.
They compared it to a drug raid that
having an illegal deer on the premise of
baby deer that they've been taken
care of was like having drugs.
So they, this is, they came in
there and this is in Wisconsin,
the Wisconsin Department
of natural resources agents
and the Sheriff's deputies
rated this nonprofit,
no kill shelter,
put this fucking baby deer
in a bag and then killed it.
This is insane. This, uh, the article
says yes to your civilized world,
heavily armed agents of a state government
and the u s of a have raided a no
kill animal shelter to execute with
extreme prejudice and recognized
symbol for the gentleness,
helplessness, and innocence. Yes, world.
This is America.
Today we're a militarized assault has
become the answer to even the most minimal
threat. It's really, um, I don't,
I mean that's a really interesting,
it's a really interesting article that,
I mean, the way he just said that it's,
it's really weird that they did that.
They went in for this,
dear specifically the word. Yeah, the
word interesting is the wrong word.
Obviously, I'm, I'm, I'm
still kind of stunned by this,
but that agents would want to do this,
that they would want to
go in armed like that.
Like why are they so armed for a deer?
Have they,
have they given a reason why or have they
made any comments? I don't know, man.
I just read this. It's kind of crazy
though. That is, I mean it's, it's a,
it's a new story. Um, it says 6:21 PM,
and right now it's 7:57 PM where we are.
Um,
I don't know if this is Pacific
time. Yes. It's specific times.
So they is only a couple of hours
old. Yeah. Today's August 1st buddy,
isn't it a second? Second say the
second already. Yeah. Oh my God.
Where's this fucking life going?
Slight flying by any way.
The story's gone viral now. It's
saying, did daily causes daily.
KPOS excellent website. There's always
like really interesting stories there.
So go there and, uh, and
check that out. And it's,
if you're looking for the link to the
story itself, it's on my Twitter feed,
which is Joe Rogan.
Um,
it's also has a beautiful picture of
Michelle Bachmann and on the front page,
I'm that crazy conservative lady. Yeah.
I love those crazy conservatives ladies.
Maybe that Deere was like some kind of
a government experiment and it got away.
Oh, right. Maybe there's
like 28 days later, dear,
has to be something crazy for them. I
mean, killing the deer is one thing.
Maybe they just board
and then they wanted to,
something to do and that
was like a big deal.
Just went in there and
fucking deleting the pictures.
That seems like a whole
nother illegal move.
It seems like you should be able to
take whatever pictures you want your
property. Yeah. They want,
but they want to minimize any kind of
political situation that would come up
from killing the deer.
And they probably thought the best way
to do that is to stop any photos that are
being taken, you know? Wow. Yeah.
Kind of crazy. Really. Yeah.
Just,
it seems a little bit overkill.
Maybe Wisconsin's just trying to act
gangster so they get some attention. Uh,
I don't know, man. It's, uh, it's
just, it's hurts your feelings. Like,
and this is coming from someone who's
killed a deer. I killed a deer to eat it.
I didn't just, someone has a baby pet
deer and then send to a no kill rate.
Just so crazy. I mean
the, I mean the people,
that would be the biggest animal lovers
probably you could find with the ones
that will be working there. So to do
that to them it's like extra cruel.
Another thing that's really bizarre.
Did you say that they put them in a body
bag and then kill them? Yeah. Like um,
yeah, they, they just grabbed
it and stuffed into a body
bag and then probably either club that
are shot at and Kevin Rose throw down
some stairs. Yeah. I mean, I
knows, man, who knows what it is.
Normally you put things in a body bag
after that. Seems like a lot of hard work.
Yeah.
Flailing leg.
It's horrible. It's really, it's weird.
You know, you stop and think about it.
It's like that someone could just just
do that in front of me screaming, crying,
people stuffed in a bag. And I
said, right, of all the things,
it just seems like it's not necessary.
I mean,
the only thing that you could say though,
and this is true,
is that they contain ticks and
those ticks contained Lyme disease.
That is possible.
And if they were worried about Lyme
disease spreading into these other animals
and they were justifiably upset that
these people brought it possibly
contaminated dear,
it does make sense that they would take
the deer away and examine it. At least,
you know, examining but thrown
in a body bag and killing it.
It's pretty fucking pretty cruel.
It's like, why not? Why not be nice?
Well, I do that. Pour a little deer. Yeah,
they're so cute. Really bad. Way To die.
They're so cute,
but they're so fucking delicious.
It's like there's a battle
going on with us, you know?
You know what else is delicious? Rabbits
delicious. And for a while people just,
they had to eat them.
There was no debate.
And it's just like recently where people,
you know,
in the last few hundred years or so,
people gotten to a point where you
don't have to kill everything to eat it.
So everything near us that's moving to
get hit with a rock and fucking thrown
into a fire. We don't have to do
that anymore. So we have pets,
we have pets that used to be our
food. Yeah. You know, cute. Did Rapid.
They're so fluffy. They are like, please
don't eat us. We're not aggressive.
We just hang out. Sometimes
you got to eat them. Yeah.
I uh, I actually, uh, I don't
think you know this about me,
but I thought I just tarian I'm a
Vegan. Total Vegan, right? Yeah.
I knew there were some rollers. Yeah.
I've known this for a long time.
I'd always thought it was funny cause I
love you're a secret Vegan bit that you
do. And the first time I heard it was when
I was working with you in Indianapolis
and I'm back there cracking up and
I said to myself, you know what?
I'm going to keep this. I'm going to see
how long I could be the opposite Vegan.
I knew you were at least a vegetarian
for a long time. Yeah. Yeah.
I think he came up maybe
when we're hanging out. Yeah.
Maybe till we go to dinner or something.
We eat something. Yeah, I think so. Yeah.
That's gotta be weird, man.
When you're on the road,
know, annoying. So hard
on the road. It really is.
What do you do when you like on the road
to do stand up? Luckily, you know, the,
the main thing that I avoid is
dairy. Um, I still eat fish,
Sushi, salmon, all that.
Oh, you do? Wait a minute.
What the fuck are you talking about?
You're not a Vegan. I'm a pescatarian.
That doesn't eat dairy food. That
is not being a Vegan. Oh yeah. Fish.
But it's the butter and milk.
That's the bad stuff. Yeah.
But your vegans, most part, they're,
they're doing it more as an,
well,
I would just say more,
but one of the major considerations is
that they don't want to hurt animals.
Yeah. That's not my consideration
on mine is so selfish.
I just wanted to be happy all the time.
That's what I was like.
It has nothing to do with the animals.
And you found that altering your
diet has a big change on how you,
uh,
how you feel
big time. In what way? Creativity.
Creatively and really, absolutely. I mean,
we'll see what used to happen was that
down that I would get after eating.
I mean, that's just exhausting
and I'm very reactive to that.
I like coffee and I like being able to
be in position to do something. You know,
I'm so used to really bother me in,
first I cut out meat, I'm like, Jay,
it's something with my eating because I
would just crashed so hard after every
meal I'd want to take a nap.
So then I went a few months and I've
done it before and both times it's been
this way. But this time I've kept
it for a year and a half. And,
but once I cut out the dairy,
sour cream, the cheese, it's,
it's hard in the beginning,
but it's not really,
once you just go round at once you
have vegan cheese in your house.
It's pretty much straight cause then you
can make a pizza or whatever, you know,
you could throw something together if you
really are craving it and uh, but yeah,
that,
that uh,
that edge and the negativity and sort
of depression like symptoms that I was
feeling pretty much throughout my
whole life up until the point really
dissipated after the dairy Wiscon
almost instantly by the way,
like to the meal once I
started eliminating cheese
was really the main thing
cause I'd have cheese on every
sandwich. So delicious though, right?
I think we can choose,
you can use to it and there's,
there's great ways around it.
You know, Avocados. Great.
For me, it's one month now
with no gluten. Oh Wow.
One month where I haven't had any,
it's a completely changed my diet.
I only eat vegetables and meats and
chicken and fish and things along those
lines. Occasionally I have
rice, but not very often.
But I've completely cut out all pasta,
completely cut out all bread and I know
a loan us a lot of differences. The,
the, I don't feel when I eat, even if
I'm full, I don't need to eat anymore.
I don't feel bloated. I don't have the,
uh, there's a feeling that she eat. Dude,
I can put away some fucking food,
right?
I would eat a giant whole pizza by myself,
like with all sorts of shit on it,
Pepperoni and sausage. And I will fuck
up a big pizza to the point where I just,
I the, the last couple of slices, I'm just
trying to prove a point, right? I'm just,
just, just showing what a fat fucking pig
I can be in stuff this down my throat.
But the feeling after that,
when that cement is
digesting in my stomach,
that paste when it's all smashed up with
my teeth in and packed into a ball of
just barely digestible, fart fuel. I mean,
that's what it is.
I'm just cutting horrible farts and
listen to my stomach rumble and it just
stretched out in ageing.
That's gone.
I all by one of the reasons why I did
it because I talked to someone about my
back, um, which has gotten
a lot better. Um, and,
and thank you everybody who's had back
injuries and given me tips whether it's
on Twitter,
on the message board.
A lot of people gave me some great
suggestions of different shit to do.
[inaudible] um,
including Dave Asprey told me
about ozone prolozone therapy.
It's prolotherapy with ozone, which
helped me quite a bit. Really interesting,
interesting stuff. But this tea, this lady
told me cut out gluten. She said she, um,
she,
she's a therapist,
a physical therapist and her and her
husband both work with like high level
athletes and one of the
things they said is like,
we've had really good results in getting
people to stop eating gluten and a lot
of inflammation goes down and people
that have had like back issues just in
cutting out the gluten,
the inflammation from their disc swelling
and stuff has gone down considerably
to the point where it
becomes asymptomatic. And I
thought that was so crazy.
I was like, how could gluten like have
that much of an effect on yeah, but man,
it fucking does. I'm only been a
month. It's a, it's about, you know,
roughly a month now. But I have
much less aches and pains in joints.
My face looks thinner like my
face is like and I'm, I'm not,
I'm still eating like as much as I
want. I'm not like a, I'm not like,
I wouldn't say I'm limiting my calories
or dieting but I'm losing body fat and
my stomach is going down. I know this is
book wheat belly, I haven't read it yet,
but apparently when
they talk about is like,
like how many people have like belly fat
from eating gluten and wheat and like
that. It just just packs it on you.
But I noticed my stomach on television,
I was like my God,
it's kind of sticking out a little bit
cause I haven't been able to work out as
much because of my back. All
that shit's gone. I'll let you,
it's gone as soon as I cut out
gluten. I can tell in your face. Yeah,
it's my favorite skin. Pretty fat man
that's, I carry weight in my face.
It's one of the first places I carry
it for whatever reason in my Dick.
So fortunately,
fortunately and unfortunately my
is my Dick is looking like a runner
but dick looks like a jogger.
Shocker.
I was want my dick was
like a bulldog instead.
It looks like a like a
jogger with a headband.
But I would recommend anybody trying it,
you know,
but some people say it's
nonsense. Um, but uh,
one of the things I found
out about the Internet,
the Internet is a beautiful
resource but no matter what,
there's going to be a certain amount of
people that think something sucks, right?
It could be the most awesome
shit that's ever existed.
I've seen people say the
black keys fucking suck.
I've seen people say Louis C K fucking
songs I've seen believe you'll say Dave
Chappelle fucking socks.
Everything that is awesome in the world.
Someone out there is saying it sucks.
Just search the keywords on Twitter and
you'll find people saying the dumbest
stuff in the world is so much of it is
people not talking in person to other
people and not like having to
like have like a sort of like a,
an cooperative interactive exchange
with people instead of that like
communicating with people and seeing them
in a full three dimensional to person,
to person sort of a way. Just
the ability to like, yeah,
Eh, right. Flagging. Just get online.
Me fucking Tony Hinchcliffe you could
get funny. A fucking queen. Yeah.
Yeah.
They just throw it out there and just,
just unleash from the
bowels of their soul.
They hide in their apartment
from the fucking bill collector
[inaudible]
from their parents who live
on the floor above them.
It's a weird thing,
you know,
if I can give any advice to anybody
that finds themselves caught doing that,
sometimes people think they can do it to
celebrities because celebrities aren't
really people. You know,
I've seen people that like,
they seem like normal folks and then,
you know,
they'll tell you look good or were you on?
He's less blocked me from Twitter like,
why'd you do that?
I was fucking given her some shit about
something. She blocked me on. Like,
why are you doing that dude? Do you
even know her? Like, what do you,
what do you know? Why are you having this
exchange with her? What are you doing?
Why you being so mean? Why do you mean
focus on yourself motherfucker? It's just,
yeah,
it's weird when you meet
those people in person too.
Like there was a guy the other day that
came to the comedy club and he was just
like, wow, you remember that guy that came
up? He was kind of drunk. And he goes,
he goes, he was talking to our friend
Benji and he was just like, you know, man,
you suck. You're set was
this stupid? Like, like,
and we're just like, like interrupting
our conversation. Right. And a good,
it got me to the point where I was like,
I almost just want to beat this guy's ass.
I'm not even a fighter,
but I just want to smash this dude's face.
And because I've already gone through
the, uh, the police, you know,
just get away from iceman and
leave us alone type thing.
And the whole night he wouldn't leave.
He kept on getting kicked out and he
would come sneak his way back and start
talking shit that p, uh, comics and then
like, wow. It's like he just needed,
so he's like a, like a human
in real life troll. Yes. Yeah.
He was set up like an internet.
She was really bad at it too because he
would come up with, come up to the group.
He would say somebody sucked and
we're just like, okay, what else?
What else do you got? Oh,
that's it. I just want to
tell you, you suck. It's like,
okay, well then that's it. Right? So you
can go like, why you gotta be like that?
You just told,
told me I suck.
What am I supposed to do?
Hang out with you?
It's as,
as time goes on,
more of those people are being exposed
and they're starting to feel that,
you know, they're starting to feel
the sting of being mean to be black.
That like have you seen
what happened with um,
that guy that was on who's a
reddit guy who was like, he,
he was a posting you post like really
mean evil shit on reddit and they found
out who he was in real life. So they
contacted his employer and he got fired.
He got fired for his
written and he's got like,
he was talking about it like he's
like, look, this is just a persona.
I just do this to blow off steam. Like
actually a nice guy. I've got a family.
Like he just was entertaining
himself by just doing this on online,
you know,
it gets weird,
man gets weird because it's like I
don't agree with that guy getting fired.
I'll tell you that I don't agree with
the guy getting fired for something that
has nothing to do with this work.
Right.
Because you find out that he posts mean
shit on Twitter, on Twitter or on reddit.
Well he didn't know that he was
going to get caught. Like, you know,
you have to show, you have
to show that bar. You know,
like most people think that
the rules are pretty simple.
Like it's a game to a lot of folks
like try to say something mean,
try to get people to react and try to get
people to freak out because you put up
some horrifying image and that game,
the,
the parameters of that game had
been pre pretty clearly established.
No one was losing any jobs because
of that. You had an anonymous name,
nobody lost any jobs.
Well somewhere along the line people
decided that that wasn't good enough.
So they had to go after the people
that were posting this fucked up shit.
And the way they went after is they find
out who you are as a real human being
and then they go after you and that's
where it's just shit gets weird because it
was like, who are you? Are you your
online guy or are you the real God,
the real,
you know,
Tony Hinchcliffe that I see out there in
the street or are you Tony Hinchcliffe
that pretends to be a woman
and a goes on cougar life
and tries to tries to
get guys to fall in love.
Have you been looking at my
browser history? How many women?
I mean like how many dudes out there
that are online talking and they think to
women are actually just other dudes that
are pretending to be women. Oh yeah,
that happened. No, that didn't
happen to me. People are getting,
well one of the things that
we did on this, uh, is uh,
Scifi show is a, we went to a motion
capture studio, um, that does a,
they do the same stuff. They
do Avatar and all. They did a,
a lot of other movies and they have all
these different frames that they can put
you into.
Like they put you in this motion capture
suit and they make an image of your
face and then they can put your face
like on a body and then you're running
around this area. And you're, you're
running around actually like in this game,
you know, you like, you could see
this character and you can have,
you can be a woman,
you could be like a monster.
You can be all these different
characters in the game.
How long is it until we have like a world
of Warcraft type three d game and do
is just decided to be a
check, you know? Yeah.
Just because, just because it's
just for fun. Why not? You know,
I'm always grow up video game characters.
Yeah.
You would be a girl if you
were a superhero, right?
Didn't you say you'd be
superwoman? Superwoman. And
if you had the choice, if it,
you know,
it's,
you would bother the other players more
by killing them being a woman anyway.
Like, Oh man, I just got killed by it.
She let me give you a, for instance.
So let me give you what
if, okay. Let's say, uh,
I don't know anything about your
personal situation, but it's,
let's say you're in love. You found the
girl, this is the one you want to marry.
Okay.
And you have the opportunity
for one day or one hour,
let's say an hour to feel what it's
like for you to fuck her and she gets to
feel what it's like to be you
having sex with her so you,
you feel what it's like to be her getting
fucked by you and she feels what it's
like for you to fuck her.
Do you think you could do that?
Do you think you could lie there
and get fucked by yourself?
I don't think I could handle an hour.
I don't think I could handle our,
of what I'm dealing with.
I think you could do that.
Do you think you could
deal with like kissing you
and do you think you'd love her enough
to let her be you for an hour and you'd
be here?
I really,
really love myself,
so I'm pretty sure that if I got fucked
to buy me and if I was a check for an
hour, I'd, I'd probably really enjoy it.
I'd probably be,
if I was, if I was a chick,
I'd probably be a squirter.
Do you think you'd give up the
booty? What'd you go? Anal.
Would I give it if you would check taking
the ass from yourself? Well, for me.
Yeah. I mean from yourself. Yeah.
Just spit on your head right around.
Now it's you back and
open it up wide for you.
I don't know if I should go ask them out
for yourself. That's the real question.
How much do you really love yourself?
Because you probably don't love yourself
enough to go aft asked him mouth and
yourself.
But if you watch porn,
girls who don't even love guys are willing
to go ass to mouth, right? So consider,
well, the [inaudible] are
getting like 2000 bucks.
So do I go for two thousand
five thousand to fuck myself?
If that's all it takes for you to go
ask the mouth, we can have that arranged
the way it has to be fucking himself.
We'll just make a mask.
We'll
just make a mass. It looks just like
you. It's not gay if it's yourself,
but we make them bass looks just like
you and we put it on a girl with a strap
on.
So it is like you're fucking yourself.
Not Enough now.
Definitely not.
We need to actually be a girl because then
you'd say, yeah, I'm, I'm not even me.
I'm hurting that. You look down, you
see your penis and you go, oh no, no,
I'm still good
guy.
Fuck on a game with my plane.
I know I'm so confused.
I don't know whether I would
fuck this thing or I wouldn't.
I don't know what you mean. What
did they both have? Penises.
Does one have a vagina? I mean I've
wondered, have you ever wondered what it,
well, I mean, what it must
be like to be a woman,
to be attracted to men and to be a woman.
Like how a man inside of you and
to like throw the whole experience.
It's so radically different. It would
be really trippy if they offered up.
Like say if one day your,
your mind literally can be recorded.
Like say if one day the memory that
you experienced now is like old school,
they're going to have digital memory.
They're going to plug it into the
cerebral cortex or wherever the fuck your
memories are stored. And you're going
to be able to have it on a hard drive.
You're going to have to be able to
have your memory in a hard drive.
And I'm going to be able to take a copy
of your memory or borrow your chip or
whatever and sticking in my head and
experience what you're experiencing.
So the question becomes,
if that is possible,
if you can like literally one day
experienced someone's memories,
will you experience you
getting fucked by you?
That's interesting because it's like,
you know, people that are born wine,
people that are born blind
don't dream in color.
I wonder if you could feel a
vagina if you don't have one.
That's a very good point. That's a very
good point. That's really interesting.
I never even thought of that.
But uh, but you in the wife
would just swap hard drives.
They,
it seems like they're getting,
it seems like they're getting a more
enjoyable and I mean the noises that they
make the whole time. And compared to,
I mean, I don't know how you guys are,
but I'm brown. I'm not that loud. It's
not like, ah, I should try it. Practice.
It really can go crazy.
Pretend I can't wait till this is
life changing advice I'm about to get.
Just pretend when you
pretend, when you're fucking
that year an animal in a movie,
that's what you should do.
Not even a real animal because real
animals or family quiet like a squirrel.
Yeah,
like just a crazy wild,
undiscovered ape that lives in Africa.
It's one killer fucking screaming Ayp
and Claude older brother neck and try it.
Let's get crazy.
I make sea lion noises the other time
that are drying up on the beach cause they
have a broken
good flipper.
Is that how you, is that how you get
the fuck dolphins by making that noise.
By the way, sea lions are the most
funniest sounding animal, I think.
Just hanging out. I wonder
what they're doing. They're
communicating. I don't know.
They sound so depressed and dom and
you ain't lying. Yeah. It's
not like the best sound. Yeah.
I if you ever heard an elk elk,
yeah. They have this weird,
we have like a bugle. It's called an elk
bugle pull. Pull it up. Littler guys,
a sound.
It's the weirdest noise.
Like animal animals have
weird fucking noises,
but male elks would they call bull elks
when they're calling out the bitches,
letting him know what's up. It's time
to get some Dick Conduct. Get some deck.
Listen to this sound.
You hear that? That's an elk. Hmm.
Awesome. Sounds like Tony. That's a female
RGT to,
how weird is that
elk when you look at them with their
giant fucking horns? Listen to that.
Is that the guy that's an elk? That's an
elk making noise. Yeah, that's of male.
The males have horns.
How crazy is that? That animals right
out of Lord of the rings. Oh yeah.
It looks like a boar with antlers.
They're weird because they're
closer related apparently
to cows than they are to
deer.
It looks like
good,
really thick necks. Well,
weird fucking, yeah,
I'd suck off that elk up
that's made in calls or working on me.
I mean,
what a animal man.
I mean, think about that
reality. Living in the woods,
just trekking around in snow,
looking for grass to eat.
And then once a year it's time
to fuck. Wow. Once a year.
It's time to get your fuck
on. How exciting that must
be when that comes around.
Woo.
I wish I was here for the the other day
that the car guy on. Oh, Matt Farah. Yeah.
How was that? Oh, he'll be back again.
He was awesome. He was awesome fun.
We got hammered too. Oh Geez. We
should about Volkswagen with them. Why?
What's wrong with your Volkswagen?
It's, it's the most dumbest thing ever.
I've haven't had my car for a month.
What's wrong? Well, when I first got it,
they had this thing where the windows,
you try to roll up the windows and it
would roll up all the way and then it
would roll down all the way and
then you're like, God dammit,
you have to do like four times in a row.
So finally I was like,
what the fuck's going on? They're like,
oh, there's there, there's a recall.
So they take out the windows and they
scratch up. Uh, I had tenting on him.
They scratched up all the tinting on it.
And so then I had to take it back.
And then like this, uh,
like a couple months later,
the sun roof thing broke the trunk thing,
which had like string
holding up the trunk broke.
Like all these little things keep,
keep on breaking like the car. Awesome.
But all these little stupid thing. Okay.
So then I'm, I take it back. They, they,
they have it for two weeks.
They give it back to me.
They didn't fix half the shit. So then
I had to take it back out of this shit.
Like, like they, they were supposed
to fix this headlight thing and,
and they didn't fix the
headlight. And then, uh,
when they were fixing the sun roof thing,
they scratched up the top of the,
the interiors that they have to replace
the interior. And I ha, it's not like the,
the general manager and the service
managers won't even call me back anymore.
They're just this like, cause they don't
have an answer. They like, they like,
every time I call, I'm like, how
about now? And they're like, oh,
it'd be beginning of next week. Then next
week comes in, they're like, Eh, it's,
it's going to be the
following week. And, and I,
they just don't even answer my phone
calls anymore. It's gotten to that point.
You've got to, don't answer
your phone. No, no, they
won't return my calls. Like I,
there was like three days that they
didn't return, like return my call.
And this is the dealership, this is
the dealership. But I just contacted,
cause I went crazy on, on Twitter. And
then of course, you know Volkswagen,
Twitter fit page, you know, just send
me a message and what'd they say?
So I called up and I made this happen
to make up this whole like, you know,
thing where they said the district
managers just going to figure out what the
fuck's going on. So they had opened
up a case and but still no car.
And like I like they gave me,
they gave me up Assad,
which is I guess is a nice car at 2013 to,
to use for the last two days.
But it's like one of those ones where
it's been stripped of everything where you
don't even have like a map, you know,
gene, I have like a four cylinder,
like I have no pickup at all.
So I'm like on the La freeway trying to
like speed or do something and it's just
like I have a little go cart.
That's bullshit.
That's crazy that they've had it for a
month. Yeah. Um, what was the major issue?
What the fuck was it that made the
major issue? It's just that like,
I mean there's been so many little things
I've been broke breaking on it like
the windows and stuff, but like, uh,
they have net that it was over
the sunroof and you pull the net.
What are they saying? They're
giving you a reason why they can't?
Well,
no,
what they do is they fix it and they
will break something else and then they
break something. Yeah. Like
when they fixed the roof thing,
they scratched up my whole interior
and so they had to replace it.
They're replacing the interior
now when they replaced my windows,
they scratched up. But like all the tent,
all my windows, when they put it back in,
like it's, it's been just nonstop and
then they're like all these little tiny,
like, people warned me about this.
I already knew this about folks on,
but all these little tiny,
like the cigarette lighter thing when you,
where you plug in your iPhone charger,
when you pull it out,
the whole thing came out. So I had to
get that fixed. So it's a build quality.
It's a,
yeah.
And what's weird is if he looked back
at like I get consumer reports and stuff
with Volkswagen,
they,
they've had this problem for so long that
that it's always an electrical issue.
It's always, it's always, you
know, like the little things break.
It's never the engine. Like I usually,
usually like everything runs fine.
It's just like your car will fall apart
and uh, it's, it's, it's like to the t
there and I would verbally
abuse every month.
Yeah, it was fall. Who knows what the
fuck is going on. You know, it's, I mean,
it's not the every employee, well, no
[inaudible] the one that, the one
that they put in front of you though,
that's respond,
whoever's responsible for that location.
There was also a point where apart part
of this Volkswagen experience where I
ordered a part, this headlight, like
they were like, you know, uh, uh,
something on the freeway snapped up
and hit this one of the fog lights.
And it was like, all right, so I
have to pay for that. I understand.
And they were like, well, it's going to
be $200 but the labor is going to be $100.
I'm like, that's fine. Just need to need
it fixed. And then they didn't fix that.
And then I was like,
why didn't you fix this?
And I had to take my car
back and they're like, uh,
I went to the service manager
and I was like, well, you know,
why didn't you fix this? And then, oh,
this service guys said that you said not
to fix it. That was too expensive. Okay.
Well this sounds like, yeah, personal.
Oh yeah. Yeah. I'm just saying it. Yeah,
it's just on for everybody.
Yeah. The um, yeah, that sucks.
Do you want to say the name of the place?
New Century Volkswagen Glendale.
You can eat my dick.
Oh my goodness.
How dare you.
That's not what I was
hoping you were going to do.
I was hoping you were going to say
do century Volkswagen Glendale.
Let's work this out. Eat My dick. They
have your car still. I don't care anymore.
Like they say, my parents ate my
deck so they might see your deck.
You're going to get there. They're going
to lock the doors. I'm going to go.
Oh yeah, we'll talk some shit. Huh? Hey,
our phone's been ringing off
the hook for the past two days,
so we are going to eat you. They come out
with a fucking pair of hedge clippers.
Chase you around the Volkswagen
shop. Okay. That's in Glendale, man.
Glendale's Oh, I'm fucked. I'm
fucked. Don't play. You don't fuck.
It does sound like a pain in the
Dick though. Tony Hinchcliffe.
Any car problems you want to
throw into the bed? No car
problems. I did a, I did have
some bad customer service. Uh,
two weeks ago though I was at the airport.
I had just gotten done with this gig.
I was by myself in Corpus Christi,
Texas for a weekend. I'm at the airport.
I get there half hour
early about to board.
I mean this is the
Corpus Christi airports,
so there's just me and the other people
that are on my flight there and I'm
sitting right next to the door where
they pull the gate up to you and I'm
sitting right there.
I have about a half hour though to wait
before they load up the plane and my
eyes start getting a little heavy
because I have a five o'clock flight.
I've been up all night.
I did stand up that night so I stay up
to get the flights so I can get back to
la early and sleep in my bed,
you know, and sleep on the plane.
Anyway, my eyes get heavy, I fall asleep.
All their boarding this plane, I wake up,
it's 15 minutes after it took off and
I opened my eyes and there's still that
lady that works for the airline there
and I go, so that plane took off,
Huh? And she's like, oh, you
must be hinge cliff. I go,
yeah. How do you know that? She goes,
because I just paid you twice. I go,
I'm sitting right here. I
mean, sure I fell asleep.
But you would think that this lady,
there's nobody else in the airport now.
She didn't.
So you think this was to wake you up
because that what the fuck you're saying?
Jesus Christ, she's
blazing bitch. She's paid.
They're going to fly you through
the sky and a fucking metal too.
You want them to wake you up to,
there's,
this is like 150 fucking people on this
plane and enough time to wake you up.
I wasn't even,
it was like 35 whatever it is,
34 other people to think about why
the fuck should they wake you up?
There's only one guy sitting nice and
wake up bench that they probably were
like, Hello Sir sir. You right
there? Yeah. All right. Last call.
Like they're not going to come up to you
and like shaking like just in case if
you're not Tony Edgecliff Tony, you're
a mess. That's what the fuck happened.
You're a goddamn mess.
Wow.
You couldn't even stay awake
long enough to catch your flight.
What are you on Ambien taking drugs on?
Nice Ohio boy come over here.
Phones to those La ways.
Is that what happened?
No Man that was sitting in an airport.
Yeah, son of a bitch, son of a bitch.
Did you see this article on a magic
mushrooms repairing brain damage caused by
extreme trauma? It's
a, it's on my Twitter.
It's a study from the University of South
Florida that found that low doses of
the active ingredient in magic mushrooms
repairs brain damage caused by extreme
trauma,
offering renewed hope to millions of
sufferers of PTSD or post traumatic stress
disorder.
And that this study confirms previous
research by the Imperial College London
that silicide at a naturally
occurring compound present in shrooms,
stimulates new brain cell growth
and a races, frightening memories,
mice condition to fear electric shock
when hearing a noise associated with the
shock simply lost their fear says Dr.
Juan Sanchez Ramos who coauthored the
study,
a low dose of psilocybin led to overcoming
fear conditioning and the freeze
response associated with it faster than
the group of mice on Catacid run Catan,
Catan,
sarin,
which is a drug that counteracts the
receptors that bind siliciden in the brain
and a control group on amazing.
It's amazing Shit, man.
Yeah, they, they've linked it to curing
depression and, uh, other, uh, um,
mental health issues as well.
Well, they're saying, yeah.
This, this article also goes
on to talk about how, um,
PTSD is not just psychological,
that common symptoms. It says such as
hypervigilance, memory, fragmentation,
flashbacks,
this association,
nightmares and flight or flight responses
to triggers are generally thought to
be psychological and therefore treatable
by learning to change thought processes.
But new research suggests that they
may in fact be the result of longterm
physiological mutations to the brain.
That's interesting that it actually
changes the brain and that silicide and
repairs those changes. That's
amazing, man. I totally believe it.
I believe it too, but that's an
extreme, extreme statement, you know?
That's really incredible. It's really
incredible that they can do that.
It feels like it when you're on them.
Yeah.
It feels like there's
renewal brain growing.
Well, I always can see my cell.
I can see life better. Yeah.
I can see like, uh, I get uh,
a nice path. Like, oh, there's
a nice path. You go down,
you know,
like sometimes you get,
especially if you're overwhelmed
with life and busy and stressed out,
you can get a little cloudy
on what the path is. Totally.
Then sometimes just one psychedelic
experience and then you see the path like,
oh, this is what's right.
This is what's good. Yeah.
This is my first one in a, in a while. Uh,
just a few weeks ago with Ari,
we went out to Joshua tree. Oh,
you were on that little journey and we
had him a last and ever since then it was
just like, I knew I needed, I
mean, it's just like clock work.
It gets rid of all that, uh, this a,
I was having regularly maybe once a
day for maybe only 20, 30 seconds.
These feelings of, Oh, I'm dying. You know
what I mean? Like this natural anxiety,
like how, how am I, you know, whatever.
Yeah, interested in those. It's just gone.
It's just a different it cleanse.
It's like giving your brain a
shower is how it feels like to me.
It just feels scrubbed.
I think it's amazing that you had that
incredible experience from just dropping
dairy that you had this
experience of no depression.
Feeling better and happier just from
dropping dairy. No doubt about it.
And z immediately like that
day and so delicious though.
But it's so delicious.
Do you?
It is, but you'll lose the, you lose the
thing for it after you don't have it.
And once you see, once you feel
the results directly or like Ah,
I mean I love sour cream but I don't
love it that much and it's easy to switch
over to almond milk and uh, you
know, or any kind of those things.
They make so many different kinds on.
I love almond milk and I never really
was a big fan of regular cow's milk.
Yeah. Almond milks. Pretty bad ass
actually. Yeah. Almond, almond milk.
It tastes good and it doesn't give
you that weird feeling when it's over.
But it does like tastes
like when you drinking
it and sounds like you're drinking milk
but no, I can't even have fucking cereal.
So it's a point Tony Hinchcliffe there's
no cereals that are no non gluten per
day.
Probably tastes like ass.
I'm sure someone's going to
tell me about ones that good.
I found out there's a lot of beer that
you can drink. You can drink Budweiser.
Budweiser has less than 20 parts per
million. That's how you do judge.
Whether or not something is gluten free.
Budweiser and Heineken,
apparently Hanukkah. So little gluten
in it. The Corona, Sapporo, um,
the rice beers of Japan, those, those
beers are all rice beers and not, um,
they're not a wheat based. Some good
options. Yeah. There's some options.
I'm like Heineken's always been a
fan of Heinekens so, uh, that's nice.
But I can't drink fucking Sam Adams
and I can't drink black Butte porter.
Like a thick Guinness type beer.
I love,
I love like those stouts about wines.
You can drink wine. Sweet. Yeah. Um,
I think some, some blah. I don't
think, I don't know about vodka. Yeah.
What about whiskeys thinking
you drink whiskey? Yeah.
I think you're allowed to drink whiskey
because whiskey whiskey me that awry.
Is that what it is? Yeah.
Hmm. I don't know. Corn.
I think probably Tequila.
That's my scowl. Right.
That's made out of like a cactus or
some shit. Right? Think so. Really?
That's what's killing me though.
That's a great question.
I never thought about it.
It's clear, clear, clear for something
that fucks you up. That money.
It seems like it should be rainbow kind
of made some of the worst decisions of
my life on Tequila. Ah,
it's so much fun. I see.
I've been doing this thing
lately where I'm, I'm uh,
I rotate what I drink regularly and I
noticed that there's different kind of
buzzes and stuff that come along
with it. Totally. And, uh, now my,
one of my new favorite things is just
popping a shot at to Kiel and having a
beer and rock in the night
away where before I was very,
very hung up on a,
you know,
a crown royal and coke
like whiskey and coke was,
was originally so bad for you.
It's made out of a Ga Bay.
And uh,
the blue a Gavi plant is,
uh, the one where they, uh,
they extract a goddess and eating man.
That's fascinating.
Shit.
Blew a Gavi primarily in the area
surrounding the city of Tequila,
uh,
which is west of northwest of Guadalajara
in the highlands of Los Altos of the
Mexican western state is of Jelly.
Sko
does not sound safe around that.
Not The place to take
your family on vacation.
Excellent place to be if you're a key low
man. It's just weird that that
has become the reality of,
of Mexico and just a few
short decades. I mean, nobody,
we didn't associate Mexico with
that when I was in high school.
Mexico wasn't drug war and people cutting
off people's heads and the nutty shit
that you see down there, it's just, it's
so quick help that that's happened. Yeah.
We would like to think that that could
never happen us. And for the most part
I think you can never happen to us,
but Goddamn, how's it happened?
There hasn't happened right there.
They have the control of the, you know,
when the, when the, when the mob gets big,
they can, they can control the
government. That's why, uh, you know,
they got good, you know, good
fellows and the Godfather, they did,
uh,
they're the ones that really pretty much
ended the mob because they made it look
cool and it was all about that take
off. I mean, that whole, Eh, we were,
I don't think we were too far
away from the same type of thing.
I think a difference is that the mob was,
you know,
it's called organized crime for a reason.
They're very strategic.
I'm not sure if that these
drug wars going down in Mexico,
they seem to be a little
bit more unorthodox.
They're very eager to send a message
that seems to be their main thing.
They will cut off heads and put
them on your mailbox, you know?
If you fuck with them
and you know the mob,
they would just put a horses head in your
bed or something like that. You know?
They wouldn't put up a human head on your,
you're romanticizing the mob. The mob,
they were nice. My mom was a nice person,
so she ran a few numbers,
but everybody was fine.
We killed the horse every now
and then to keep you in line.
It's really interesting. They
really were. They, I mean,
you really think so that in a lot of ways.
Yeah.
I mean the city of Youngstown was
booming when the mob was still,
I mean, not booming, booming. The
steel industry was dilapidating it,
but it's better to have organized
crime than disorganized crime.
And what happened when the FBI raided,
uh, Youngstown for example. And then,
I mean that's a small,
not too small,
but it's a pretty small scale of what
obviously would be like in New York,
in Chicago.
But what happened in Youngstown was a
black gangs took over the bloods and the
crips in, in a very, very big way.
And then all of a sudden there's drive
bys and there's bullets going through
your window and leaving a mark on the
other side of your living room wall.
And it all becomes a reality.
Whereas when the mob was there
controlling the streets, other gangs,
there was no other gangs. But as soon
as they got rid of the mob, they let,
they don't mind disorganized crime
as much as they mind organized.
It's very bizarre.
Yeah. That is pretty crazy.
You know, that's what people
say about Vegas. You know,
people,
they're always talking about the good
old days when Vegas was run by the mob,
you know, the mom just ran Vegas. Right.
Everyone was polite. Everywhere you go,
you've got a nice lobster. People love
to talk about that. Yeah. My Brand Vegas.
Yeah,
they did.
Did you see the, uh, speaking of Vegas,
the, um, uh, the video with our, the,
the film rather with, um, Michael Douglas
and Matt Damon, or they played Liberace.
Liberace slower.
Yeah.
Watching it. How was it? Was it
like on a, on a Brokeback mountain
scale is amazing. It's, it
buries Brokeback mountain.
Really? Yeah. Barry. Barry's it.
Brokeback mountain is Brokeback mountain,
first of all.
I don't remember who said it.
I think it was Ricky Gervais'
said something really funny.
I think it was him that
was quoted this saying,
it's surreal watching Gordon
Gecko get fucked by, um,
uh, Jason Bourne because, you know,
Matt Damon is Jason Bourne and Gordon
Gekko was Michael Douglas and you know,
my 15 minutes fucking, you know,
Michael Douglas show that? Yes.
First of all,
Michael Douglas is one of the baddest
motherfuckers that ever lived.
He is Liberace. I mean,
he fucking is him. Wow.
It's amazing. I mean, if you watch
Liberace and watch the films and watch,
like how he talked and behaved,
I mean, he literally is him.
It's amazing.
The transformation is spectacular.
He makes you realize what a
great actor he really is. Yeah.
And Matt Damon to you fucking buy it.
You buy it, hook, line and sinker.
You know, he's Jason Bourne.
Okay. You know, he was the
guy from goodwill hunting,
you know all those things. And
yet you still buy it. Hook,
line and sinker. They are too
bad motherfuckers. And I went,
before I saw it, I was like, how
good could this bay to Jesus Christ,
you're shooting your balls and waxing
and oiling it up. No. Before that,
in preparation for that, I
don't, I don't, you know,
I don't watch gay films
naked anyway. The, um,
the, the, the, the act again, it was
incredible. The story though is really,
it's kind of a weird story because all
it is essentially is one guy who got
pissed at Liberace,
didn't want to fuck him anymore.
So he told the Liberace story,
you know,
and the Liberace story to be told in
this film is basically the Liberace liked
to fuck. He was really super
talented. He liked to play music.
Most of the old ladies came to the show,
didn't know he was gay and
after the show was over,
he wanted to get guys and fuck
them. You know, and like that's it.
Like that's he and you know, painted
out to be this like horrible, horrible,
horrible person.
But in reality,
he was just a guy who had $500 million
and like to fuck. Yeah. You know, I mean,
it really didn't hurt anybody in the mill,
kicked the guy out when the guy got crazy.
But it also is interesting because
the guy who Matt Damon is playing,
like his character in the movie is hooked
on pills and all these amphetamines
and you watch like Matt Damon's
character changes personality and stuff.
It's fucking great, man. I love it.
It's amazing to see how some actors,
you know,
a lot of great actors and play some of
the same types of characters through
movies or the most impressive
to me is a Walter White, um,
uh, Krantz, Bryan
Cranston, Bryan Cranston,
because I didn't realize until like
season four or five of breaking bad.
I don't know if you
watch it. Yeah. But he,
but he also plays the dad in
Malcolm in the middle. Oh yeah.
Like this is positive,
happy. Like who who do that?
And Walter White is the complete
opposite about he these.
So he's got so much to him and he's not
just a something that's just a little
bleak character like the
Malcolm in the middle of dad.
He is so developed and it's so deep and
sell emotional and you see so much of it
that agility that
he could play that guy and that
guy. Yeah. Andy plays that guy.
So while you want me wins like
every year, pretty much, uh,
or at least a few now for his work on
that and to think that he can play that
guy too. Just a Malcolm
in the Middle Dad. He's,
his portrayal of a teacher
is so goddamn good.
I mean he,
he sets the parameters of like the way
a teacher would behave so perfectly and
precisely. It's masterful.
It really is masterful.
He's incredible. They ever really
is. Yeah. The guys who can do that.
Like you gotta really admire that,
that, that, that's just such a very,
it's such a very specific level of acting.
You know,
like this like Daniel Day Lewis,
which I harp on too much,
but so that level of acting,
it's so much different than most of the
Douche bags you see at Starbucks going
to their scripts. Totally in
Cranston. Such a cool guy too.
I don't know if you saw this,
but it comicon. Oh yeah, yeah.
I just saw the thing with
the mask and then uh,
they brought him up for the panel and
he took off the mask place went crazy.
Why do I feel like we played Liberace
music on this podcast before?
Have we know this is
what I want to pull up.
Then I want to pull up the
song when Liberace winks at me.
Cause this is like, this was like some
real shit. This is in 19, you know,
fifties ish. When Liberace
was like, you know,
I guess this was like a scene in a movie
and a woman is singing a song about how
enthralled she is by
Liberace. And it's, it's,
it's amazing.
First of all,
it's amazing when you stop and think
about how much our culture's changed since
then because this is like, you know,
whatever the hell it is. 19 we'll pull it.
What does it say? What year is it? Say,
uh,
1955. 1955. Watch this
shit. This is incredible.
It's like strange time machine.
Oh,
it's just the watch this
Liberace and Libby Morris,
she's sitting in front of her TV and
she's on her knees in front of a little
desk writing a letter and she's
staring wistfully into the TV.
Oh, Liberace plays
piano. He's so handsome.
And he winks at you.
And when he winks clinks
[inaudible]
like it.
so are
[inaudible] [inaudible] [inaudible]
my says Clinton that's allowed to
that loud clink his, his, his eyeball.
No.
How many fucking weird listening to it.
I'll tell you what, man, after that movie,
I went on the Liberace
kicked for several days. Wow.
I resisted it at first because I was
like, what am I Liberace fam. Um,
but, and then, but so somewhere along
the line, somewhere along the line,
I embrace it. And, uh,
I just started just googling Liberace
and listening to interviews or watched to
him give a tour of his house. He had
like a, it was weird. He had like,
his house is like real regularly
looking on the outside,
but then when you went inside of it,
it's like a fucking palace and he,
he had like a normal front to the
house but then he had like, he goes,
I had two houses built inside of it.
Like inside the house it just
says like this fucking massive,
huge place. And apparently,
um, one of his houses,
one of his big houses is for sale
right now. I think it's palm springs.
I think that's where it is. But it's
for sale real cheap, like 500 grand.
Like you could buy Liberace's house and
it still has like the painting over the
see if he could find it.
Liberace's house for sale.
I bet his house had a giant
closet that he would say.
Well he sued,
um,
he sued a newspaper in England because
they claimed that he was gay and he sued
them in one apparently. Wow.
Yeah, there were different times,
but for reporting the reporting of that,
he was a homosexual. Well today. Yeah,
his mansion for sale for $529,000 which
is a lot of money for that fucking house
cause you never going to get it back.
It probably smells like shit,
dicks and shit.
When he died,
apparently he had like a half a billion
dollars or something close to that.
He was just so gangster.
What he did was so crazy.
He made his boyfriend get
plastic surgery to look like him.
So it goes back to like what
we were talking about earlier.
He wanted to fuck himself. Yeah.
That's what he wanted. Yeah. He,
he made his boyfriend's handsome guy get
a chin implant to look like Liberace.
Wow.
Handsome phrase I read that is
going deep with the crazy. Yeah.
That's going really,
really deep with the crazy fucking a man.
Yeah. A Chin implant here. Hey, get a chin
implant and learn how to play the piano.
Like a fucking genius dude.
He didn't give a fuck. Wow.
He didn't give a fuck.
And he was a brilliant,
brilliant fucking penis. Man. I mean,
he was like a fantastic pianist.
It was really,
I mean, it's really amazing to watch.
Did he ever date Leno and how dare you?
How dare you. I'll get it to
Linda has a big chin too. Oh,
they're around him for years.
I see how this crazy fuck works.
Um, did you guys hear about the unmarked
graves in Florida at the reform school?
Oh my God. Go back to July
31st on my Twitter. Brian,
you find this story in Florida,
a clash over at zooming
bodies out of reform school.
There's this reform school in
Florida and it's called the,
they're called the White House boys.
And there were a group of men and
many of them now in their sixties and
seventies who were sent to this
reform school when they were children.
And they remember beatings where
people were beaten to death.
Where were students there were
beaten to death like they had,
like they ran the place with an iron
fist and when kids got out of line,
they gave them frightening beatings and
say they knew children who died from the
beating.
So a few years ago,
the state investigator said that they
found no evidence that anyone at the staff
at the school had been responsible for
any student deaths. But then these people,
with the state's permission,
they've got a team of researchers and
they use ground penetrating radar to
locate nearly 100 unmarked graves
at the school more than a hunt.
Oh yeah. So they thought it was 50 at
first and then people were freaking out.
And then they found,
they kept finding more the state reports
of the 50 boards or believed buried in
unmarked graves,
but said that it would not be possible
to identify and zoom the remains from
individual grade sites.
So then they started like admitting it.
And that's when forensic
anthropologists, uh, Aaron,
Kimberly Kimery and Aaron Kimery got
invested interested in the story.
So He's ground penetrating radar,
found a hundred fucking bodies.
And now what's interesting is that
the governor does not want them fun.
They don't want them
zooming all these bodies.
They're trying to like keep the lid on
this shit. They're like, Jesus Christ.
So the government, the governor
Scott is a fighting exhumation.
But Kim Marie and her team are supported
by Florida's attorney general members
of the legislature and by Senator
Bill Nelson. This is incredible, man.
The state of Florida has the
worst publicist in the world.
Everything out of Florida. It's
never like great, like, uh, hey, uh,
great stuff discovered in Florida. No,
it's either sinking into the ground,
people killing each other.
100 bodies,
hundred a hundred bodies,
an unmarked graves. Well,
they're dead. The, these people are,
this is all from like the 1930s and shit.
No, but like when it happened, like, like,
Hey, my son never came home from school.
I don't know. Hey, my, my other son
didn't come home from school. I mean,
I think there you're dealing with,
you know,
I'll probably decades of,
you know, one a year missing,
you know, and they've hundred
fucking bodies, you know. I mean,
I guess it's more than that. It means
it needs to be more than one a year.
One every few months. I mean,
how many of they kill him?
And I wonder how long they were open
for. That's a good question. Actually.
Let's say this. Yeah, you would think
somebody would be like, wait a second.
There's been a hundred missing
students in the last 10 years.
Just what they call them, the White
House boys. Ooh, this is so creepy.
Just think about this group of men,
many now in their sixties and seventies
who were sent to this school who when
they were children who knew boys
that had been beaten to death.
Jesus Christ. That's what,
that's insane. Yeah man.
Brutal,
brutal beatings.
Florida has a website or a Twitter
account called Florida man.
It's underscore Florida man at Twitter.
It is maybe the best Twitter account ever.
It's all shit. That dude's who live
in Florida have been arrested for.
I mean,
and it's updated all fucking
day every day and it's awesome.
It's awesome.
Florida man tells police he has a gun
so they respond to is nine one one call
quicker Florida man,
the cops,
I'm not going anywhere until I
get my weed. It's humidity, man.
Humidity drives people crazy.
Florida man arrested twice in
one week for sex with dogs.
Florida man taken to police station
for driving without a license.
Urinates on x ray machine.
And detention officer.
Florida man stops to help woman after
a motorcycle crash steals her purse.
Oh, I heard about that. Yeah, no, this,
this woman was in a car accident.
She was trapped in her SUV and uh,
this guy came up and just store
purse and then left her in there.
Florida man leaves six year old son
and crashed car because he thought his
driver's license was
suspended. It wasn't. Wow.
Florida man crashes car three
times in one night of drunk driving
three times.
Oh Man.
People are awesome.
But Florida is just so strange.
It's just so strange. It's so, there's
a whole weird thing going on over there,
man. That all swamp land. That's like
the, it's like the devil's Gooch. Yeah,
just swamp lands and fucking, they
put Disney world there, but it's like,
it doesn't seem like Disney world should
be in the middle of that state. Well,
you don't, they said about Florida
is that within this decade,
within the next 10 years, they believe
that Miami's going to be underwater.
It's like they're the most
recent estimates. They're there.
They're worried that Miami
and a lot of Florida,
the ground is apparently very porous and
so it's not like New Orleans where you
could set up a levy though. Like
once that water rises, it's a wrap.
Yeah. You know, so I don't know if
this is right, but if that's right,
think about all those giant ass
condos that are like on the,
on the beach in Miami. Those were all
what it's going to be like Venice.
There'll be like Venice,
Italy.
It'd be way great carries in that
because it's going to be no one in those
things. Like what are they going to do
if all that's under the ocean? Like,
do you know how freaky would be if you
could drive a boat through Miami and see
all these,
these giant buildings in 10 years?
Do you think people wake up
then and realize what the
fuck is going on out there?
They're going to have to at single,
like people are gonna be like, hey man,
I think maybe we should fucking
stop building right on the water.
What do you think? Right. I think
think this water's coming up on us.
Oh, it's happening. Do you see the,
uh, the videos of the North Pole?
That looks like a swimming
pool? No, you haven't seen that?
[inaudible] is fucking crazy. See if
it pulled that up. North Pole melting.
Wait, what do you see this? Just like,
they have videos of Greenland and like
these Manhattan size chunks of ice are
fallen off glaciers into, into
the ocean. Oh my God. It's like,
it's all happening like right there.
It's like you watch it every day.
I wonder how long I am.
Hey, I just don't even know.
I wonder,
I wonder when like common sense and
technology are going to just buttheads.
Yeah. And people are just
going to, they'll no longer be,
eventually there's going to be no longer
debates about things. You know, like, hey,
is there global warming? Well here
you go. Boop, boop, boop, boop, boop,
and just diagrams and stuff and yeah,
there's a, you know, I mean it's got,
it's going to get realer as technology
keeps getting better at the arguments are
all,
yeah.
Hg Wells had a great quote that
history is a race between education and
catastrophe. Wow. A great quote. Yeah.
He wrote that shit in
the 18 hundreds you know,
it's just shows you people saw trends.
We're have crazy shit is a long time ago.
It's just like we're hoping that one day
it's going to get to a point where it
doesn't happen anymore. It's like it's,
but it seems like that's not how it goes.
How it goes is just you manage the chaos
as must chew as much as you can while
it's around you.
What is,
this is supposedly a a Webcam.
The melt pool.
Yeah.
Just slowly starts turning into a
lake and this area of the North Pole.
Oh Wow.
Oh boy. Oh Wow. That's crazy.
That is so strange.
While you're watching something that was
completely covered in ice and then all
of a sudden that melts, but we don't know
if that happens every year. Right? Yeah.
If it just went back to being
frozen like two days later. Yeah.
Maybe that was their summer. Yeah. Because
you remember in March of the penguins,
there's that whole thing about it thaws
out and then they fuck and then they,
then they go and have babies and shit
and then it was freezing cold out.
They have to hide the eggs. Did you
ever see that now? I didn't catch that.
Maybe for a great, maybe
it's an interesting movie,
but it's a brutal existence.
These poor penguins,
they have to huddle up together.
The block each other from the wind.
They just get together and stand up
and the wind just whips them fucking 50
below zero and just, and then just trying
to cover their eggs with their feet.
It's so primal.
Wow.
It's amazing when you stop and think about
what kind of environment that life is
not just living in but thriving
year after year, year after year.
These things keep fucking in that
same spot. Keep making babies,
keep walking miles across
the ice to get to the ocean.
Keeps surviving and you can plan
when your Internet goes down. Yeah.
Penguins. I mean they're just
born in negative temperatures.
This is the suckiest spot on the
planet. Right? Is there a suckier spot?
Would you rather live in the North Pole
or in the jungle or South Pole or South
Pole jungle. I live in the jungle. I don't
know. It does the same shit. Both frozen.
I think South poles frozen like Argentina.
Like this is glaciers in Argentina.
Why don't we hear anything
about the South Pole?
It's always the north pole
because that's where Santa lives.
South Santa lives in the North Pole
with the fuck lives in the South Pole.
Is it that one article as the south
port, right? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's creepy down there. Yeah. It's tricky.
They don't even say they. Is that true?
They don't even really know.
Let's see. Map of the world.
Was that true that the NRA,
I don't know if you say to me people,
Antarctica is down there. People say, um,
like I've got a lot of criticism
when we did the Dan Carlin podcasts.
You're so ignorant for me.
Is 40 years old up out some shit.
Yeah. But you know what? I'm
fucking honest about what
I know what I don't know,
man. Yeah, there's a lot of
shit. I don't know, but there's
a lot of shit. I do know.
There's no room for all of
it. Okay. God dammit, you,
you can only know so
many things in this life.
It doesn't make you stupid because
you don't know things. Okay. You know,
and it makes you,
you're interested in other shit folks.
People have to get that into your head
just because there's certain data that
you should have probably accumulated.
But if you haven't,
it doesn't mean you're stupid right now.
And people are so quick
to call stupid on people,
but there's plenty of shit that
I've done that makes me stupid.
That's not one of them. Yeah. South
America, it's below South America.
Antarctica is essentially the South Pole.
And I just signed the other day that a,
we're still in the ice age. We are.
Yeah. If you look up ice age, uh,
it's, uh, it's, that's what we're,
we're still in that cause it's a huge,
you know,
tens of thousands or whatever of years.
And because Antarctica and the North Pole
and Greenland or something like that,
there's another one or Iceland or
Greenland, because these things exist.
We're still in the ice age until they
melt that we're still in that. Whoa.
That's crazy. Wow. I never
even thought of that.
So until these frozen areas melt,
yep. We're still in the ice age.
So when the dinosaurs were around,
there were no, no, icebergs are shut.
I'm not sure about that.
I don't know.
I don't know whether that was in that
period or not of tens of thousands of
years. That's the hardest thing
to wrap your head around. Yeah.
That this thing changes so often.
It's just constantly the,
the oceans moving and changing. When I
was in Montana, when we were hunting, um,
one of the things that was so weird seeing
seashells there, he would climb these,
these tall hills, and as you're climbing
up the ground is actually like silt.
It's silt because that
used to be the ocean.
They used to be the great western inland
seas. So as you're walking around,
you're walking in this real mucky
sort of clay ish, muddy thing,
and as you're walking out, but you'll
find seashells. It's such a mind,
fuck Joshua tree.
You're looking at these rocks.
Sometimes it's like a movie set because
you're like, how's that a perfect circle?
How's that rock perfect half. Who
rolled that here? How did this get here?
Will you ever see those
rocks that they found? Um, I,
I want to say Billy's Billy's stones.
Let me say bullies.
I loved that picture you in salmon that
you caught that giant hug of a salmon.
Your smile was ear to ear. I Laurie
and I caught a bunch of them, man. Oh,
you were up there with him? I didn't,
yeah, Ari and I, we did a, the bear tooth,
I think it's called the bear tooth lodge.
It's bad ass place in Anchorage.
And we uh,
went salmon fishing and put those bad
boys or is it we didn't need those. Yeah,
because um,
we,
when we went it was a catch
and release time, but they,
they base it on how many salmon come
through the we're, the weird is like a,
like a salmon to have to come into this
box area and they count them then they
let them through.
But right before we got there,
we couldn't have asked for a
better day before we got there.
There was like hundreds of salmon came
through, so it was like a crazy amount.
We're in the river while we were there.
It was so fun.
They're so big that it's weird though.
Being up there and seeing moose
everywhere, seeing Musen Eagles and shit.
Alaska's amazing. Have you
been up there yet? Not yet.
You guys gotta to do a show up there.
We're in talks right now about four. Five.
It's supposed to be a wet two days for
shows. I don't know if two days, what?
Two days, four shows in our where and
remember where it was now. I don't know.
Fairbanks or anchorage? Anchorage. Were
you going to go? Do you know the place?
I don't know the place. Two days of shows.
That'd be fun. You'll have a great time.
The people up there, coolest
shit. The girl said that, uh,
the girl that's booking it said that
it's one of those places that they never
had anybody come out there.
So like if anybody comes out,
everybody just goes to the show.
Like no matter if they're a fan or not,
they just want, you know, they find out
about it because that's it. Yeah. Yeah.
Well it's uh, it's an
awesome town, man. There's,
there's something really cool about those
people up there and I think part of it
is because they just, uh,
it's like they're real bonded.
It's a real interesting
kind of a community and
they're very progressive too.
We saw um, uh, Christians free quality,
this big group of Christians for quality.
They were standing on the corner with
like the gay flag, the rainbow flag,
and they were,
you know,
like waving these signs and like waving
to people and people like honk at them
when they drove by like
agreeing with them. It was
kind of interesting, you know,
I didn't expect that in Alaska. I
mean, I don't know prejudice word,
I've never heard of that group of four.
That says a lot about Alaska
Christians for equality.
Normally Christians are very
Christian. Yeah, no, not up there, man.
It was really cool. I it the,
the f the shows were cool.
Everything about it was
cool and it's just, it just,
you feel weird being up
there. The fact is, any trend,
how much Canada loves comedy,
the farther north you go,
then it must be like heaven,
comedy heaven up there.
Because I love the few times I've
been in Canada to do comedy shows,
it's always been some of the highlights.
And so I can't imagine what it's like
farther north. Did you Seattle? Yeah,
I've done Seattle. Seattle's
on fucking awesome. Yeah,
they got a cool comedy scene there too.
You know,
they have a couple of comedy
clubs now. They got that, um,
the parlor live to that place.
It's connected to a pool
hall. I just did, uh, the,
uh, the Moore theater up there with
Thompson girl last weekend. Oh,
it's fucking so fun. Yeah.
Seattle's a great place.
I did that venue, I think with
Jeff. Does it have like church,
like a things on the walls?
Like those big, yeah. Yeah.
They actually just shut down to do some
renovations, I think to clean it up,
but it's, uh, it's amazing. Man is so
fucking funny. Yeah. He's very funny.
You guys gotta show tonight, right? Where
are you at tonight? What time? 10 o'clock.
10 o'clock. If you listen to
this shit right now, folks,
you can get in your car and make it
there and use coupon code RSS and you get
two for one tickets. Who's
there tonight? Uh, we've got me,
we've got Tony powerful judge cliff,
Jason Tivo.
Jesus Cringila calling. Oh
my goodness. Uh, Matt Edgar.
He couldn't make it in this too
much comedy. Is Tiana Sarah Tiana?
I think maybe. Excellent. Do you gotta do
an icehouse chronicles as well? Uh, no.
Yeah. Too much, right? Yeah.
We, I'm over saturated. I know.
If you don't like me folks, I don't like
me either. I'm going to have about that.
How about that?
I'm tired of hearing me talk as well.
If you're like Joe Rogan's everywhere.
I don't even like being everywhere.
All right, how about that? Yeah,
like the opposite of Liberace.
Who want her to go fuck themselves?
Yeah. I don't want to fuck myself.
Uh, but you can go fuck yourself. How
about that? That's it. Show's over.
Let's get out of here. You guys
got to go do your show. Um,
order Brian's new t shirts folks.
They're bad ass death squad. Dot TV. Um,
go in and check them out. Thank you
to a on it.com for sponsoring us.
Thanks to Tony hinchcliffe.com
and you can get his new,
you're going to get me one of the shirts.
Definitely.
I'm going to make it a large, I want
you to, yeah, I want the muscle.
Be Sexy at the new gluten free Rogan.
Then um, higher primate.com
is my tee shirt company.
Go to a higher primate.com and
just all sorts of tee shirts.
Most of them done my maximum.
Mike Maxwell, Max, Mike Maxwell,
art.com Badass Dude, good friend of
mine and an excellent artist, uh,
on a.com. Use the code
name, Rogan save 10% off.
We will be back on Monday with a the
lovely and intelligent Abby Martin from a
r. T we'll try not to
get too conspiratorial on
you, ladies and gentlemen.
We're trying not to be too doom and
gloom when Abby Martin comes on.
All these people that come
on that are, uh, journalists,
they scare the shit out of me
with, with reality. So, uh,
we're just gonna try to have
fun with Abby. You know,
everybody wants it to be
serious and fucking tried to
bring down the government,
man. No one's going down. Let's
just have some fun to hang out.
So that's a Abby Martin on Monday,
and we got a Jim Norton on August 12th.
So Jimmy was supposed to be here today,
but he had a reschedule.
We got a lot of shit coming up and a,
so thank you everybody.
Thanks for all the Twitter messages and
all the love and thanks for everybody
who came out to the Moore Theater in
Seattle. We had a great fucking time.
We appreciate the shit out of people
and, uh, we'll see you next week.
[inaudible] wow.
[inaudible]
[inaudible].