Four,
three.
Welcome back man.
Hey,
thank you.
Good to be here.
Great to see you again.
Yeah,
I like your new spot.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Ma'Am.
You have a real flip phone.
I do have a real foot said that you.
You didn't go back to it.
You've never left.
I never left her.
So you never went like iphone,
android?
Never.
No.
Never,
never even thought about it.
Never even thought about it.
No.
You see people taking pictures and using
apps?
Nothing.
Uh,
I,
I don't need the APP so I'm good.
There's no draw at all.
Nothing that using the internet to
answering email.
I have a laptop,
I have a laptop at home and I do access
the Internet,
but when you're out you don't want to
mess with it.
No one of them out.
I want to be out in the world.
You know,
if you're,
if you're looking at your phone,
you're not in the world.
And so you don't get either.
You don't get either thing.
He would get along very well.
My friend Ari,
he went back to a flip phone and he
looks disdainfully sort of like a former
alcoholics look it at everybody with a
drink.
Like there's no way you could just enjoy
one drink you loser,
right?
Yeah.
No,
I,
um,
I just look around at this.
I mean I'm an anthropologist and I am
interested in human behavior and I look
at the behavior like literally the
physical behavior of people with,
with smartphones and it doesn't,
it looks I'm antisocial and unhappy and
anxious and I don't want to be.
I don't want to look like that and I
don't want to feel like.
I think those people feel,
wow,
that's deep.
I'm a junkie,
you know?
Uh,
it's really interesting because,
uh,
I was at a restaurant the other day and
I was looking around and literally
everyone in the restaurant was looking
at their phone.
No one was talking to,
to anybody.
And I was thinking,
what if there was a drug that did that?
What if there was a drug that didn't
kill you,
but it just sucked up all your time and
you just stared blankly at your hand.
And did everything that you do while
you're using a phone,
people would be terrified,
like you're staring at your hand and
crashed into cars.
You're staring at your hand and walking
into Poles.
Yeah,
I mean,
I mean there is a drug.
It's that social media.
I mean,
I think the big lie of our generation is
the phrase social media.
It really isn't.
It's antisocial media and it has a lot
of uses and know whatever.
But it's not social in any human sense.
And,
and if you look at suicide rates,
depression rates,
ptsd rates,
anxiety rates,
they're doing nothing but going up in
our society,
mass shootings,
you know,
just something tragic just happened
yesterday.
I'm all those things.
There are indicators of something and
they're all going up in our society
despite the fact that we're a very
wealthy,
powerful,
relatively peaceful society.
Like something's going on.
I can't prove that it's,
you know,
the internet or social media,
what I mean obviously,
but,
but the fact that those things are
happening at the same time does make me
wonder that these new devices certainly
don't bring happiness because the
numbers are going in the wrong
direction.
Well,
I don't think they're designed to bring
happiness,
but there's certainly designed to give
you access to information go perhaps,
maybe
with some discipline they can be used in
some sort of a way that that benefit
not.
Well,
yeah.
I mean all of that information is
available in your laptop at your desk at
home.
I think the problem is when,
when people want to be socially,
socially connected constantly,
no matter what they're doing and that I
think keeps people from actually fully
experiencing whatever they're actually
doing.
I think there's definitely some truth to
that,
but I do like the fact that I can ask my
phone questions like if I don't know
anything and I can add a new feature on
this Google Pixel,
we squeezed the side of it and the
Google assistant comes up and you can
ask it questions.
You squeeze it and ask a question.
I mean,
that's some space age shit,
man,
or it's downright creepy.
I mean,
you look at it,
I,
you know,
I get it.
I mean,
you have all of human knowledge in your
front pocket.
Yeah.
Accessible at every moment.
Like I do understand the power of it and
the appeal of it.
I'm not saying there aren't great things
about.
Of course there are.
Um,
it's just,
for me the downside outweighs the upside
for other people.
I guess it doesn't.
But if you look again,
if you look at mental health statistics
in this country,
we're doing something wrong because
they're all going in the wrong
direction.
I agree with you.
I just wonder if the mental health
statistics are indicative of other
issues.
You know,
I think lifestyle,
what you do with your time during the
day,
and I know a lot of people live a very
deeply unsatisfying lives and I don't
know if the phone accentuates that
problem.
I mean we were talking the other day
about we were at the airport,
we're waiting to fly home and there was
some girl and she was talking,
we were just ease dropping and she was
talking about like the amazing race and
how she,
you know,
this show so boring now and I can't wait
to,
I'm going to eat this and then I'm going
to eat that and I,
I'm supposed to get a raise at work.
It's like all nonsense,
non engaging,
not interesting.
There's no real life to anything she's
talking about.
And like this is most of our country or
a large part of our country.
Oh absolutely.
I mean the thing about social media is
that it sort of weaponizes blend this,
it allows,
it gives people a platform for the most
mundane,
uninteresting aspects of their lives
because they have to constantly,
constantly be producing some kind of
output of communication.
Well and if not,
producing it certainly absorbing it all
right.
Yeah.
We were both feeling good
mining when I'm on twitter,
like nothin,
nothin,
nothin.
Oh right.
Oh murder.
Oh look at this little monkey found.
Oh,
I mean there,
no,
I mean there's other people you could
have on the show that could speak more
intelligently to this,
but I know that,
I mean,
I've heard that um,
risk of suicide and face facebook are
correlated.
In other words,
people that are are on facebook and in
social media,
they are at an increased risk of
depression and thoughts of suicide and
that and that.
That's
terrifying.
Do you think that that's correlation
equals causation though?
You know what I mean?
Like,
do you think that people on facebook all
the time are doing that because they're
already depressed?
Right?
I mean,
that's the question and what the
correlation means.
We have to look at something more
closely.
Yeah.
Anxiety rates and teenagers have
skyrocketed.
Um,
anxiety partly comes from a sort of a
painful self awareness.
And of course that's amplified by social
media because you can never escape the
opinions of your peers.
I mean,
that's crippling to people.
we're not,
you know,
I wasn't the most popular kid in class
by a long shot.
And when,
when I came home,
whatever my whatever my issues were,
were on hold until,
you know,
when I was a kid in high school,
there was issues around hold till 8:00
AM the next morning.
Right.
You got a 12 hour break from your
problems,
now you don't.
And it's really tough on kids.
Yeah.
I can only imagine growing up today,
I,
you know,
I think we got very lucky that the,
we experienced the Internet in
adulthood,
you know,
for me,
I was,
think I was 27 the first time I ever
gone online and that's a nice,
you know,
and no one knew what online was back
then.
You weren't leaving any traces,
you were just going out and looking at
stuff.
Yeah,
that's right.
That's right.
Yeah.
I was.
How old was I?
I was about 36.
I remember.
I remember a girl asked me,
do you ever logged on?
And I say,
well,
Donald,
what?
She had to explain to me what that
meant.
And then I literally said to all,
that's never going to catch on.
Come on.
That's like a really.
Yeah.
Wow.
Yeah,
isn't that what they said about the
first computers,
like that was one of IBM's a initial
reactions to the idea of the personal
computer?
I think that's the reaction to the first
of everything except maybe the bow and
arrow.
I mean like when they invented the bone
Arrow,
everyone was like,
no,
that is going to catch on.
That is cool.
Right?
But everything else,
I think that's
skepticism.
Like we don't,
we don't need anything more.
We're good.
And then you realize,
I mean that's the amazing thing about
the human mind is that we invent this
stuff and it doesn't mean that it's
good.
I mean we evolved over hundreds of
thousands of years to live a very
different environment that we live now.
So these things that we invent,
it doesn't mean that they're sort of
psychologically good for us,
but they definitely are incredible.
I mean there are definitely amazing
things.
Yeah.
I don't think that necessarily they're
good for us,
but I don't think this is kind of sound
weird,
but I don't even think they're
necessarily designed for us.
I think they're designed for the future,
I think,
and I don't even think it's a design.
I just think that all things move in an
ever more complex direction and whatever
a person is now is not going to be the
same thing a thousand years from now or
100 years from now even.
I think there's going to be some sort of
symbiotic can actually train us in
electronics like we're going to have it
installed in our body.
Well that gets to a kind of profound
question like what is the point of
existence of human existence?
What's the point of it?
Is the point for as many humans as
possible to leafs to lead safe human
fulfilled lives?
Or is it for the human race as an entity
to produce the highest technological
achievements and insights,
you know?
And,
and I don't have a vote either way,
um,
but that it does sort of seem to be the
question and that technology.
I mean,
we know does not lead to fulfillment and
happiness,
but it does lead design,
topic,
insight and to,
you know,
incredible.
Um,
under profound understanding of how the
universe works in a physical sense.
Yeah.
I wonder if what we're doing is just
being caught up in the momentum of all
this innovation and instead of like low
using discipline or using some sort of a
rational objective analysis of what it
takes to be happy and then maybe
pushing,
pushing some of that stuff aside and
engaging and actually physical
activities,
going out and doing things and making
that almost like a prescription.
Like,
Hey,
you know,
look,
let's look at your daily chart.
Hey,
you don't even get enough vitamins,
buddy.
Hey,
you didn't get enough activity like you
need.
You need that in order to be in order to
feel right,
to feel,
feel balanced.
Right.
And it feeling right is the point of
existence.
Then iphone are probably not a good
development.
No.
If the exchange of data,
if the exchange of information is the
point,
then,
then they're a great innovation.
So it really depends on what we're all
here for.
I W I was in San Francisco with my wife
and I were walking behind these two kids
who were talking about about robots and
one was they were sort of kids that were
sort of sort of in the know about all
this stuff and one guy was saying,
you know,
they're taking over,
in 50 years,
you know,
we're,
we're going to be,
humans are going to be completely
unnecessary,
but I said to my wife,
you know,
we always were unnecessary,
like none of this had to happen.
It's not like the world needs.
Human beings do exist and for some
purpose,
right?
We just,
we are here,
but we didn't have to be here.
And so if robots replace us,
we go right back to where we would have
been if we hadn't.
If we hadn't evolved.
And it was,
it was just a funny way of thinking
about it.
Like none of this is actually necessary.
It doesn't have to be happening.
No,
it certainly doesn't.
I mean,
look,
if we are finite life forms,
if you're only going to be lived to be,
if you're lucky,
90 years and when your health is going
to fail and you're going to die,
what was the,
what should be our goal is to feel good,
right?
To have community in relation.
That's a big part of that book.
Tribe.
Your,
your book's fantastic by the way.
I've read it twice and I read it again.
I read it before.
Then I read it again since,
uh,
since our first podcast.
You very much.
Yeah,
I've been getting a lot of.
I keep getting a lot of good responses
to it.
And,
and I think partly,
I mean,
whether you're a Democrat or Republican,
this was a pretty unsettling time in
this country.
And um,
and I,
I think people are coming to the book a
little bit just partly because they're
wondering what is the glue that holds us
all together and is there,
it exists still.
Like,
I mean,
I think there's a real question in
people's minds about what is it that
binds us together?
Well,
there certainly is.
And you really covered a lot of the sort
of just not commonly discussed aspects
of it,
like the need for real community,
the need to really,
and the need to have something on the
line now,
the need to be in situations where
there's real consequences and that it
seems that this is part of the glue that
holds us together.
I mean,
the thing about technology is it buffers
us from real consequences in the
physical world,
which is what's great about it,
right?
And uh,
but the downside is that as you,
as humans get buffered from consequences
they need,
they need each other less and less in
order to survive.
So now it's sort of modern modern homo
sapiens in a suburban house with an
iphone and a garage door opener and all
that stuff.
You know,
you get a paycheck at work and you don't
need your neighbors,
you know,
to,
to get help.
You gather food or hunt food or defend
yourself from the gang,
from the other neighborhood.
I mean,
it all kind of gets taken care of,
which is a great liberation from your
neighbors,
from your community.
But it deprives you of that essential
human reliance on other people around
you.
That's what makes people feel good and
safe and like they're leading meaningful
lives.
And so that transition to having a life
that's not part of any community,
um,
that is a really tough one for people.
And I think that's part of the reason
for high depression rates and such in
high ptsd rates in our society.
Yeah.
I think that lack of community is a very
confusing thing when you see most people
just sliding into their garage and
shutting the door,
going into their house and they don't
even know their neighbors.
How that's really highlighted in your
book how alien that is to the human
experience until fairly recently.
This idea of like living in these.
Like I was in New York City this past
weekend and there's enormous apartment,
like my friend Jim was talking about
this,
he lived,
Jim Norton lives in this enormous
apartment building.
Those,
I don't know anybody there.
And he goes,
I live in a house,
a building essentially a house with a
thousand people.
I don't know any of them.
Yeah.
And listen,
I mean I live in a little tenement
building,
but it's the same,
same idea.
There's a little cubby holes we all live
in,
but I,
you know,
I got to say,
and I grew up in a suburb,
but I got to say,
at least in the building I live in,
I'm in the lower east side,
at least in the building I live in.
I run into people in the landing and the
staircase.
There's no elevator in the staircase and
you get to know them a little bit.
The problem with the suburbs is that
everything's a stone.
You know,
everyone's a stone's throw away behind a
big hedge and you and you don't,
you don't have to share an elevator with
anyone.
You can be totally isolated.
And I grew up in that environment.
It was crushing and,
and I,
you know,
I was in a material sense,
I was lucky we were affluent family,
but I was not lucky in any human sets.
That's so fascinating.
He say it was crushing to live the
American dream.
I mean,
a lot of people's ideas.
The American dream is living in a nice
quiet suburb.
Yeah.
I listen to.
There's a lot that stream,
like about it,
but,
but um,
the,
the data will tell you that people in
those situations are not happy.
I mean in,
by the,
the,
the metrics by which we measure human
fulfillment and human happiness,
mental health,
they suck in the suburbs.
Um,
and uh,
and,
and generally modern society is,
as affluence goes up in society,
the suicide rate goes up to the
depression rate,
ptsd,
ptsd rate,
all that stuff goes up with,
with,
without fluids.
Yeah.
I've noticed that in some of the circles
that I am hanging around with now
because of Nice people,
but the children of my children,
my children's friends,
parents,
sorry,
I am interacting with these people that
I don't know from work,
I don't know from social circles and
just.
And most of them are great,
but a lot of them are on pills.
Like a lot of like,
like half of them are on pills.
Pills,
yeah.
Yeah.
They're,
they're taking the adderall and then
taking anxiety medication and they're
taking antidepressants and they're
mixing it all together with alcohol and
some new freak out every week and
there's literally no physical fear for
anything.
Everyone's driving a Mercedes.
Everyone's living in a gated community.
Everybody's.
It's all smooth edges and corners.
Everything is a very soft and easy and
the.
The big appeal seems to be the newest
objects chase the newest objects.
It ends a really well known phenomenon
that if you introduce a disaster into
that environment,
if you introduced the blitz in London or
an earthquake or what have you,
have flood tidal wave of war.
People wake up out of their dream.
I mean they're in a kind of dream state.
I'm a part and for some people that's
in,
you know,
induced by pills and some people it's
just induced by isolation,
but they're in a kind of dream state
where they're not part of society in a
meaningful way and a catastrophe wakes
them up out of that.
And,
and people,
I mean over and over again you can hear
testimony of people saying,
well,
I really miss those days.
The days after the earthquake,
during the blitz,
I mean,
you,
you from generation after generation
that goes through there,
there their things,
right,
there are tough things those days are
missed and they're missed because
people,
the thing they actually like most is
being an essential part of a small group
that is struggling to survive.
Like that is the human experience for
hundreds of thousands of years.
We're wired for it.
We're wired to like it.
Uh,
the people that responded to that
challenge tended to pass on their DNA
that people that didn't respond well
didn't pass on their DNA were the
descendants of the people that sort of
took some thrill and from that challenge
and,
and acted well and with vigor and with
community in the face of hardship and
danger were the descendants of those
people inevitably.
And uh,
uh,
because the people that didn't act well
didn't survive is as well,
right?
They didn't pass on their genes.
And,
uh,
so that's one of the things we're
missing in the big.
The big trick is,
I mean I'm not saying we're now in the
suburbs band the car and live in a lean
to,
I mean no one would say that huge to
this society too,
but the trick is how can we have that
close communal connection that buffers
us from our,
from mental health problems that makes
us feel meaningful and fulfilled?
How can we have that and have the
benefits of modern society,
you know,
like,
can we do,
can we do both?
And I think that's the big challenge
because what I see in America,
I love this country,
but what I see in my lifetime,
I mean when I grew up,
we didn't have mass shootings.
I mean,
you know,
like that,
that didn't happen.
You go into a church with a machine gun
and kill as many people as you can.
Let's just didn't happen.
What is going on?
I mean to me it's a country in kind of.
I mean those things are all a symptom of
a country that's in the kind of psychic
pain,
you know,
all the people on their iphones.
I sort of get it but it.
But also it makes me think you're
anxious,
like you're so anxious that you can't
bear not to look at your feed for more
than 20 seconds.
It's an,
it's an addiction for sure.
I mean,
you're literally getting dopamine shots
every time you check your feed and
they're very small.
It's a trickle.
It's not like a real,
like it's not really worth it.
You don't get any real good feeling.
Very rarely.
It's like fast food.
Like the end of the end of it,
you know,
you go to the drive in,
get,
get your cheeseburger and fries and a
shake or whatever.
Afterwards you're full,
but you,
you didn't get any nutrients.
And,
and social media is the same way.
You're sort of socially full.
But actually it's all calories that no
nutrition.
I mean there's nothing,
nothing to sustain you.
Well,
I've found for me personally that people
get a lot of fulfillment out of tribes,
for lack of a better word,
of likeminded people doing similar
things that are difficult.
Absolutely.
I see it amongst like rock climbers,
a lot of rock climbers.
They,
they find like real community in other
rock climbers and runners get it.
Jujitsu.
It's huge.
And the Jiu Jitsu community horse,
you know,
um,
and uh,
I experienced it in a deep way.
The first time I ever went hunting
because hunting was almost like,
like I had a wall that I didn't know.
There was a door on it and I opened up
the door and oh,
there's a whole new area back here.
Like your,
your DNA like goes up.
We know what to do with this.
We're hunting now and you feel like,
wow,
this is crazy.
Like this is lighting up parts of my
brain or parts of my,
my genetics.
Yeah.
Listen,
I went through that same door when I
started boxing.
I started late in life.
I was 50.
I go through a big life change.
My first marriage ended and I needed
something.
I needed something a little different.
And I think one of the things that
really works for people is a situation
where they're evaluated for their
behavior rather than for how and where
they were born.
Yes.
Right.
So or how much money they have,
which is a fun,
you know,
it is a function of a to some degree of
how,
how you were born,
where you were born.
Uh,
and yeah,
but so,
you know,
in high school you evaluated for the
family,
you come from,
how you look for all that stuff.
You don't have control over any of that
stuff.
But in the boxing ring out hunting,
you know,
whatever,
there's a million things like this,
you're evaluated by your peers for your
conduct and that you have complete
control over soldiers the same way,
you know,
and I was with this platoon in combat
for non,
for a year in eastern Afghanistan.
Those guys didn't care if you're a good
luck with your bad looking if your dad
was in prison or not really give a shit
right?
That what they cared is how you acted in
that situation.
And would you,
would you,
would you put the group,
the welfare of the group ahead of your
own welfare?
And that was his basic human basic human
question.
Is the group more important to you than
you are to you?
And if we all answered that question
with a yes,
then we're good.
And so you know,
when you're in situations,
hunting in the gym,
Jujitsu,
whatever it is,
where you're not bringing your street
identity in there,
you're just,
you're just a human being trying to act
as well as possible with dignity and
respect for others.
You're good and it doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter if you suck at
Jujitsu,
right?
As long as you have that basic respect
and hard work ethic and being freed from
those things you're not responsible for
and so and are not judged for it.
That is a huge liberation and it really
makes people feel close to each other.
Yeah,
so people need mom and it's also.
Do you think that a lot of what's going
on today is just the fact that I don't
think people are supposed to work in an
office all day.
I think it's probably bad for your
biology.
I think it's sitting in a chair all day
is terrible for you.
I think staring at a computer all day is
terrible for you.
All these things that people do or just
counter to their contrary to what your
body was designed for and that must
cause a lot of depression and anxiety in
people.
Yeah,
I mean,
if you,
if you want to know what we were evolved
for,
you can look at current modern day
hunter gatherers who more or less
anthropologists agree represent our
evolutionary past and you'll find that
there's at least two hours of pretty
vigorous movement everyday.
You know,
fast walking basically two hours a day
by virtually everyone in the community.
Um,
you are almost never out of contact
with,
uh,
I mean out of physical products,
proximity with other people that you
know extremely well.
There's about four or five hours a day
devoted to survival,
food gathering,
that kind of thing.
We work eight,
10 hours a day,
right?
The most,
quote primitive hunter gatherers and
some of the harshest environments in the
world spend around four hours a day
surviving.
But it survival is a group endeavor.
It brings everyone together.
Everyone's needed high protein,
low no processed foods obviously.
Um,
uh,
I mean,
the Diet,
obviously it's a very pure diet.
Um,
and people who live like that have
extraordinarily good health,
um,
and if they survive childbirth and those
first early years,
I'm often live into their,
into their seventies,
eighties to 90.
I mean,
you know,
West Bay basically live as long as
westerners do with no medical
intervention.
I mean,
it's pretty extraordinary.
That is externally
when you think about it.
I mean,
what I saw an article and I didn't,
I didn't read the article,
but the headline was something along the
lines of I was talking about artificial
intelligence and it was a,
whether or not the rise of artificial
intelligence will,
uh,
will even out inequality.
And I remember looking at that and one
boy that's like giving into the hive
mind,
like artificial intelligence is going to
cure all the woes of the world.
Like we'll let the computer thing for
you and everything's going to be even.
And you know,
now that I'm thinking about it,
the two guys,
we were walking behind San Francisco,
it wasn't robots,
it was artificial intelligence they were
talking about.
I mean obviously they're connected.
But yeah,
it was,
it was ai and,
and um,
you know,
it's,
I mean it's either ai is either the
final blossoming of the human mind or
it's the end.
I don't think anyone knows which it is.
It could easily
be the end.
I've been thinking for the last few
years that it's,
we're some sort of electronic
caterpillar is giving birth to some new
butterfly.
What we're doing is we're,
we're the biological thing that makes
the electronic thing and that the
electronic thing is going to go,
thanks,
we got it now.
And then we assume that the things that
we hold dear,
like emotions and comradery and this
feeling that we have community,
that that's important.
But
if we live and we die,
it's important to us while we're alive.
But what if we didn't exist?
Is it important in air quotes to the
universe?
Is it important to the planet?
Not necessarily just important as a
human
understanding of physics,
is that it was incalculably unlikely
that the universe would exist and that
life would start on this particular
planet or on any planet.
That it was extremely unlikely that even
the universe would exist and um,
so it's hard to say that anything would
be important to add to it,
to a system that,
that,
uh,
statistically shouldn't have happened
and that doesn't have a conscious and
moral mind behind it.
Like,
I mean,
no,
of course we're not important.
I mean if we were sitting on the moon
and you watched a nuclear exchange
between Russia and the United States
that obliterated civilization,
if you were sitting on the moon,
you'd barely be able to see it.
You would barely notice anything
happened.
Right?
That's the moon.
And that's pretty close.
Of course it doesn't matter.
So keep in mind that all those emotions,
everything we are had survival value in
our past or we,
that we wouldn't have those things,
right?
We're,
we're,
we're the legacy of an evolutionary
process that went on for 2 million
years.
So if we feel sadness,
if we feel anger,
if we feel shame,
all of those things had survival,
survival,
value for humans.
And the individuals that had the
capacity for those emotions made better
citizens within their little community.
We're better hunters were better,
whatever,
and so those emotions,
we find them meaningful,
but actually what they are is they
helped us survive and now we have so
altered our circumstances that survival
is no longer a question.
And so what do we do with those
feelings?
What did we do with those capacities?
The ability to hunt that the dopamine
that you get from hitting a target.
I mean,
teenage boys will sit in a basement for
hours,
days,
years playing video games to practice
their training for hunting right there,
turning for hunting and war and they're
getting rewarded with dopamine,
which is exactly what should have been
happening for 500,000
years.
And now there's nothing to hunt,
nothing to fight.
They're still doing the behavior as they
should because they're wired for it,
but there's no useful purpose for it and
they're making themselves irrelevant.
They're human casualties of this
technology and it's,
I find it really tragic.
Are they more irrelevant than someone
who plays sports?
I mean,
I think our relevance comes from our,
um,
our relationship with our community and
our society.
And I mean,
at least if you play sports,
you're part of,
you're part of the human community.
And,
and when you're in,
when you're playing a video game by
yourself,
you're really not
by yourself.
But a lot of kids,
what they're doing now is they're
playing these online games at playing
against other people.
They talk to each other online.
They have headsets and they get,
I mean,
east sports is a big growing thing and
it's,
um,
I mean it's,
it's a fascinating thing because it's
also sort of based on your ability to
perform,
you know,
the ones who are the heroes are the ones
who are like,
um,
when I was playing quake,
there was this dude named fatality was,
uh,
his name.
He just killed everybody was awesome,
but it was,
you know,
he was the,
he was the king because he was just the
best at the game.
So in the community of people that were
only judged by their performance,
he had risen to this very high level,
but it was a community.
Well,
you know,
if you look at humans,
you look at chimpanzees,
we clearly need the proximity of others,
like the physical proximity about it.
So yeah,
I mean the only way I can evaluate that
is to say that's an that's awesome
training for hunting and war and the
military does use those games to train
their soldiers and so I get it.
It's effective.
What I would do is look at suicide and
depression rates and gamers and see are
they above or below the national average
for that age group and if they're above
then there's a problem.
Either depressive people are seeking
that as a refuge or that activity makes
people withdrawn and depressed and you
know like either way it's a problem that
needs to be solved that I have no idea
what the data is,
but that's where I would look.
Now,
when you're researching all this data
and you're putting together a book like
tribe in your,
you're putting it out,
are you thinking to yourself that you
have know that it's
not just an interesting study on human
behavior,
but it's also probably important for
people to read,
to kind of get an understanding and
these,
uh,
to get an understanding of what it is
it's causing people to have all this
depression and anxiety that it may be.
This is,
this is something that needs to be said.
I mean,
any categories,
category statement I shouldn't make,
but a lot of authors when they write
books,
it's their firm conviction that their
book needs to be read by the public and
that will help the public in some way,
right?
It will eliminate life illuminated
America,
luminate the world in some way.
That's important.
I mean,
that's just a starting point for the two
years of work that a book takes,
right?
You have a child.
Your assumption is the child is going to
be a good person in the world.
Not a terrible person winds up shooting
up a church,
right?
It's just a starting basic assumption.
So for me,
when I was writing tribe,
I was trying to make sense of a number
of different number of different things.
I mean,
one was that what the soldiers I was
with in Afghanistan,
I was really struck some months later
that a lot of them wanted to go back to
this sort of flea,
bitten godforsaken outpost where they
got shot at it every day and didn't want
to come home to the US.
It's like that needs explaining.
Yeah.
Right.
Um,
and it made me think of this uncle that
I had sort of surrogate uncle named
Ellis Ellis settle.
He was,
um,
he was Lakota Sioux and Apache is born
in 19,
29 out west.
And um,
he had a very rough,
interesting life and he's very well.
Right?
And I remember him telling me he was a
sort of mentor figure for me and I
remember him telling me when I was in my
twenties,
said,
you know,
all throughout the history of the United
States,
along the frontier,
and this is how he put it.
He said white people were always running
off to join the Indians and the Indians
never ran off to join the white people.
And so here was this fact again,
like,
oh no one wants to go,
go back to or go to the sort of modern
world.
This wasn't even the modern world.
This is the modern world in 18,
65,
right,
or eight or 17,
55 or whatever.
I mean at the,
at the,
the,
um,
right at the time it was the modern
world,
right?
Uh,
but so no one,
no,
it's basically the post agricultural,
really a revolution world,
the industrial world,
the world of organized religion,
organized government of,
of uh,
an industrial economy and an agriculture
based system where people had jobs and
you got up at dawn and plowed the fields
all day and went to bed and your
minister and your king told you what to
do and you know,
whatever.
That's the modern world.
And that's what nobody wants to be part
of,
including the soldiers I was with at
Restrepo.
Right.
And so it just made me think maybe what
the soldiers are missing isn't war,
although that certainly has its charms
for some people,
but it's community is that they were
with each other community with
consequences.
That's right.
Exactly.
Community with consequences.
Likewise for the native Americans were
the tribal societies in North America,
maybe with the young men,
young men and some young women along the
were looking for was an escape from the
sort of oppressiveness of the
congregation on Sunday mornings,
the oppressiveness of the society that
they were toiling in the regimented
nature of an agric agrarian society.
Maybe what they longed for was the
closeness and freedom of a,
of a tribal society.
And indeed,
I mean,
there was this incredible sort of
hemorrhaging of people from the frontier
to the,
to the tribes and some and even when
people were kidnapped on rates,
uh,
by the Indians kidnapped from their log
homes along the frontier and,
and abducted and forcibly adopted into
these tribal societies.
Um,
when,
when given the chance to come home to be
repatriated some years later,
very often these people refuse to go.
They didn't want to go back,
they wanted to stay with their adopted,
tried their adopted community.
That,
that is,
that's amazing to me.
And it says a lot about what the way
humans are wired to
wanted to live,
you know,
that's,
that was one of the craziest aspects of
your book that I'd never heard that
before.
And how many people had done that.
They were,
they,
they were kidnapped and then they said
we like it here better.
Yeah,
that's right.
And again,
we're talking about more than 100 years
ago.
So we think of as modern society today
is the only escalated those anxieties
and woes and all the things that
separated them from the tribal world.
That's right.
And one of the things about tribes is
there,
there are sort of inherently
egalitarian.
It very hard to pass on pass on wealth
and a non capitalist society in a mobile
nomadic society is impossible to pass on
wealth because you can't carry it.
I mean,
there's no way to carry wealth when,
uh,
when you're in a nomadic hunter gatherer
society.
So,
so they're very,
very egalitarian and they also guard
against the sort of abuses of power,
sort of one alpha male trying to sort of
like bully people and take more than his
share or for that matter,
people sort of freeloading and not
contributing to the group survival
effort and sort of scamming a little bit
of food here,
a little bit of whatever they're.
Both of those sins against the community
are really harshly punished.
So it's very galitary.
Ian and I got a Galitary aneurysm is
something we are all wired for it.
Right?
And I think one of the distresses of a
modern capitalist society is that it
can't be a Galitary and um,
and,
and that's,
that's painful for people.
But then if you introduce a crisis,
um,
the blitz in London,
for example,
uh,
an earthquake in Italy that I studied,
um,
what happens is that money doesn't
matter anymore when the floodwaters are
rising,
when the bombs are falling,
social class doesn't matter at all in
it.
It's like being in the,
in the boxing gym,
how you conduct yourself with respect to
the others around you is actually what
gets evaluated in a,
you know,
a poor man can be brave and generous
just as easily as a rich man.
There's no advantage to being wealthy or
powerful when it comes to those basic
human qualities.
And that is a huge liberation.
And so I'm,
you know,
I live in New York City and after nine
slash 11,
there was a bit of that in New York
City.
I mean,
you know,
there's a lot of more people in New
York,
a lot of rich people,
you know,
whatever.
Obviously we all know that,
but after nine slash 11,
no one was rich or poor or anything.
We were all New Yorkers wondering if
there was going to be another bomb
dropped on us.
Basically another attack on the city.
So what happened in New York,
the suicide rate went down.
The,
the violent crime rate went down.
Vietnam vets in New York said,
who had pete,
who suffered from Ptsd said that their
symptoms disappeared after nine slash
11.
Everyone was needed and people and
everyone for awhile,
everyone was equal because we were all
facing some danger that terrified us and
that for all of its tragedy,
that is an intoxicating social state to
be in for human beings.
That's so bizarre.
It's so bizarre,
but it's also so make sense.
One of the things that I also thought
was fascinating in your book where you
were talking about ptsd,
Ptsd sufferers and how people in these
veterans hospitals would be absolutely
furious if they thought someone was
faking their symptoms and that,
that they,
they had to be physically restrained to
keep from attacking people that they
thought were just joking the system and
how many people are on ptsd benefits.
Yeah.
I mean the numbers are really elusive,
but.
Well,
you know what I have sort of anecdotally
from veterans as well as people within
the va,
the Va administration who were acting as
therapists or whatever a group
counselors is that there's certain
number of people and I,
you know,
I don't know what the fraction is,
but there's a certain number of people
who were not traumatized in war and ptsd
is hard to prove or disprove and it's,
you know,
so obviously wide open for um,
either an unintentional misdiagnosis or
an intentional misrepresentation,
whatever.
And so I mean,
of course,
and any bureaucratic system gets scammed
and pts deep benefits are no different.
And,
but it really is traumatizing.
I mean seriously angering and
traumatizing to soldiers who really were
traumatized because they really were in
combat.
And keep in mind only about 10 percent
of the US military experiences direct
combat.
How would they know if someone was
seriously traumatized?
And the other thing that's fascinating
is that as you were talking about in
these small societies,
free loaders are looked down upon as are
the greedy Alpha males and try to
dominate the wealth like that.
The in these societies like egalitarian
ideas are a much more,
much more openly expressed.
It's much more important that this is
represented by these people that are
legitimately suffering.
Seeing someone was scamming the system
and angry.
Whereas say if you had a hurt knee or
something like that and you were going
to a doctor and you saw someone who was
faking a back injury,
you wouldn't be upset right where they
were just robbing money from the
insurance company and getting free.
Well yeah,
there's a hurt knee doesn't have a sort
of emotional cargo to it.
Right.
But combat does.
I mean if you're in combat and you lost
your best buddy and you got trauma from
that as well,
you should.
Um,
and then you're in some group therapy
thing at the va with some guy who was in
a rear base the whole time and is
claiming 100 percent ptsd disability for
some that never happened.
Like,
yeah,
that would make you angry.
It makes me angry because combat,
this is extremely emotional and he get,
I don't know,
is it one in a million?
One in 100,
100,000.
I have no idea what the rates are and
I'm not even sure what the va does and
there's,
you know,
in some ways incentivized not to find
out,
but,
but it's,
I am,
I can tell you from like the real deal
combat vets that happens,
they smell it instantly and one way it
gets sorted out is that those guys who
are misrepresenting themselves get
questioned by the combat vets.
Holy.
So what unit were you with?
Like he said,
what happened exactly.
Oh,
a mortar hit the other side of the base.
That's a pretty big base.
I've been there,
you know,
it was a mile away and you're
traumatized.
Are you kidding?
Like,
you know what I mean?
They'll get questioned.
Right,
right.
Um,
so I mean,
like you,
my question,
someone who's bullshitting you about how
much you know,
how much a fighting's done with MMA or
whatever.
I mean,
wherever your area of expertise is,
I'm sure you can smell a fraud
instantly.
Right?
Well everyone can.
That's one of the things is one of the
characteristics of humans because it,
because we live in collective societies
where we have to sort of trust one
another.
We're extremely good at smelling out
misrepresentation and fraud were really,
really good at it and it's one of the
things that feels intolerable is to have
someone who was unfairly gaining,
gaining from the hard work of the rest
of us.
And,
and,
and I should just say,
when I say a Galitary aneurysm,
I don't mean that there's no hierarchy.
Right,
right.
I mean it's complicated.
Systems need hierarch need to order,
right?
Need Heart.
I mean groups need hierarchy so that not
everyone's a general.
Not everyone's a private.
I mean you need organization within the
group,
but I'm Galitary Ian means that nobody
gets extra rights,
you know,
like all have the basically the same
rights in the group.
That's what that means.
It
meaning,
it all completely makes sense.
It particularly makes sense.
The idea that these people who were real
combat vets who saw real action would be
instantaneously able to discern whether
or not someone was faking it.
Yeah.
And that this.
But that,
this sort of mirrors what you were
saying about these small tribes that in
these small tribes,
someone who's a freeloader is a
extremely dangerous to the group.
You'll look at it as a liability he
looked at as someone who just can't be
trusted and you need trust.
You need community.
And this is,
this is what you're saying about a
combat troops that what they want to
know is that you're going to be willing
to put your own safety secondary to the
safety,
the troop.
Right?
And if everyone does that,
everyone is safer.
But if
no one,
if some one person doesn't do that,
I mean,
that's always in the movies,
right?
It's always the one guy who runs away or
the one guy who sells out or.
Yeah,
that's right.
And you know,
those,
those human themes are enduring and very
powerful.
So sometimes speak to a lot of liberal
audiences,
right?
And,
uh,
and so I,
I love doing this to them.
Like,
Oh,
I'm a Democrat,
so I sort of know those people pretty
well,
right?
I grew up in Massachusetts and I get it,
you know,
and so,
uh,
it all,
I'll say to them,
okay,
who hears it gets war and doesn't want
to know anything or have anything to do
with war and Dah,
Dah,
Dah.
And of course everyone raises their
hand,
right?
And um,
and then I say,
okay,
who here has paid money to go be
entertained by a Hollywood war movie?
And everyone raises their hand.
It seems like a contradiction.
But when I go onto say to them is,
look,
if,
if work and get a room full of passivist
to go pay money to watch it,
it's,
there's something important going on in
that narrative.
It's not a,
you're not going to the movies to watch
people get killed,
right?
You're not a sociopath.
You're going to the movies to see these
very ancient human concerns of who's
loyal to the group,
who's a coward,
who's brave,
who's willing to risk their life for
someone else.
I mean,
these are,
these are things that have kept humans
alive or endangered them as the case may
be for a million years.
Of course they're compelling narratives.
And in war you see those things happen,
like in a sort of accelerated intense
rate.
I mean,
you know,
I grew up in a suburb.
You almost never see someone have to
choose between their own safety and the
community.
It never happens.
That's the problem with the suburbs in
war that happens every moment,
every day.
Right?
So,
so it gives you this sort of like human
narrative in this incredibly compressed
intense form which reconfirms the value,
the human values we all have about,
okay,
if you're in a group,
you have to love that group.
Even if you're,
if you disliked some of the people in
it,
like that's what it means to be part of
a group.
And that's what has kept humans alive
for a very long time.
Even see that narrative in science
fiction,
futuristic movies like the Matrix right
there,
the one guy who sells out the other
humans to the,
to the Matrix and just says,
look,
I want,
I want to be in the matrix.
I want to have a great life and eat good
food.
And
yeah,
I mean,
listen,
once you,
once you are aware of this narrative,
you see it everywhere and I mean,
one part,
there was some research that I did that
didn't actually make it into the book.
I couldn't quite fit it in,
but I,
I,
I interviewed someone who had a
consulting firm in Hollywood that did
basically sort of like market research
for the big studios and they would,
they would screen films for audiences
and then ask the audience's questions
about the ending,
about the characters,
about how to construct the plot.
They would sort of trying to figure out
what's the public one is c,
right?
So what they found was that in disaster
films,
very typically,
um,
we're a community was facing a,
a disaster,
right?
A plague or uh,
you,
uh,
um,
you know,
a flood or a war or whatever when,
when the community had to rally to
survive,
right?
An alien invasion.
But what does a million scenarios.
But it's all the same basic story.
You have these different characters.
There's usually a,
a male figure that takes the lead to
difficulty defend the space.
Right.
There is often a female figure that's
connected to him that sort of takes
place of the,
of the community that's being defended,
take,
takes care of the dresses,
the wounds,
dresses,
the emotional wounds,
I mean turn takes care of all that stuff
while the man or the men are sort of
physically defending the place there's.
And then there's a guy who offered was
really wealthy or well off before the
catastrophe,
who's continuing to act in a self
serving way even during the catastrophe,
when everyone's needed and everybody
gets mad at that guy.
That guy always dies,
always dies.
And then there's another character.
And again,
this is just very common in these
narratives and easily Beta male.
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly.
Yeah,
No,
but keep in mind that these narratives
of Ford by public opinion or this isn't
the studio,
is trying to make the public,
um,
force,
feed the public like gender roles and
you know,
whatever this is the public saying.
I like that.
I don't like that.
So the studios are responding to the
questionnaires that these researchers
give out.
So one of the really interesting things,
and this is totally inflammatory,
but the role of the person defending
like fizzle,
you physically defending the community
when they try to put a woman in that
role,
people have a problem with it and,
and,
and frankly often women have a problem
with it.
Like it's really,
it's really,
really interesting and women are just as
important as men in a crisis or in
anything,
right?
But the,
what the public seems to want is the guy
with the sword and the woman with the
bandage,
you know,
or,
or with the sort of reassuring,
you know,
like it gets divided like that and it's
not,
again,
it's not the studio's forcing something
on people as the people watching these
films saying just voting on what the
narrative that they like best.
But the,
the other characters that I thought was
really hilarious.
There's often that,
there is a,
an estranged husband who's betrayed his
wife and family in some way.
He's on the outs,
right?
Uh,
with his family and his,
with his wife.
And then the crisis happens.
The martians invade the floodwaters
rise,
whatever it is.
And he comes to the rescue and does the
right thing and saves his wife and
family and maybe even the wife's new
boyfriend.
I mean he even could have gotten to that
stage.
Right.
And because he does the right thing,
she takes him back.
God,
it's funny,
man.
It's really just playing out these
ancient archetypes to exactly what it's
doing.
I mean they read,
I mean,
those storylines resonate because
they're ancient and because those,
those roles in society helped us
survive.
And there's always the woman who in
absence of the strong male figure rises
to the occasion herself when some of the
research I did with tribe,
what I found,
I studied this coal mine disaster in
Canada.
So it was all men trapped a two O,
two miles down in these collapsed
passageways in the miles.
Two miles down,
two miles down a,
an angled shaft down.
Yeah.
So they had an explosion.
Some gases ignited and the passageways
collapsed.
So they're two miles in their gaslight.
Their,
their,
their batteries.
Last,
you know,
24 hours.
Their water last 48 hours.
Pretty soon they're just sitting in
darkness.
Not Knowing,
not only if they'll survive,
not knowing if their bodies will ever
even be recovered,
they no way waveness sitting in darkness
trying.
So whoa,
this is what happened.
I mean obviously a situation like that
takes needs leadership.
So in the first minutes and hours there
were these sort of Alpha males that
weren't necessarily crew bosses,
right?
They didn't,
they weren't within the traditional
hierarchy.
They were just guys who grabbed a pick
ax and a shovel and said,
come on guys,
we're going to try to dig our way out.
And they basically,
I mean literally attacked the problem of
these collapsed mine shafts.
It,
there was too much rubble to dig
through.
There were two miles down.
So.
So they,
they,
they dig,
dug and dug and dug and it required
these,
these guys.
And again,
it was all men down there,
but there was one sort of leader.
Was this very aggressive.
He didn't care what anyone else felt.
Oh,
you're scared.
I don't give a shit.
Grab a shovel.
We got to solve this problem.
Like totally unempathic.
Right?
When they realized they couldn't dig
their way out and they ran out of
batteries and they're sitting in
darkness,
a new kind of leader was required and
that was someone who was able to keep
people's spirits up.
Who is empathic,
who listened to.
The guy was really scared,
was able to say,
hey listen man,
it's gonna be all right.
It's okay to be scared.
We're all scared,
you know,
that kind of voice.
It's a different kind of leadership.
Now.
Typically in society,
the male role would be the guy with the
pickax attacking the problem.
The female role would be the person sort
of like trying to keep the group
emotionally together and,
and um,
and functioning.
And,
but what happens in a,
in a situation where there's all of one
sex,
those gender roles will be filled no
matter what.
It would just be filled by people of the
same sex.
So if it was all women down there,
someone,
one woman would have grabbed the pickax
and taken on what would be typically
considered a quote male role.
But she's female.
So the gender roles that society needs
to survive in adversity,
in war,
in nature,
in a collapsed coal mine.
It needs both gender roles,
but either sex can fill those roles.
It's amazing.
And we will sort it out.
So it doesn't matter who's male and
female.
What matters to that?
Those two basic kinds of leadership and
caretaking get taken care of.
Wow.
So how did those guys get out?
They eventually.
The rescuers eventually got to them.
How long were they down there for?
Over a week.
I might even been two weeks.
I mean,
they,
oh,
eight days.
So I can't remember.
Actually.
It's something,
it's something like a week.
Uh,
how did they survive?
I mean barely.
I mean,
you know,
they,
I mean,
they ran out of water.
They were,
they were eating the bark off the
timbers.
Uh,
the,
you know,
the support structures,
they were eating coal.
I mean,
you can call.
We're trying to.
Yeah,
they were drinking their own urine.
I mean,
you know.
Yeah.
And they,
the guys died.
I mean,
not everyone survived.
I'm one guy was trapped.
His arms trapped between two collapse
timbers and they were,
you know,
it was a pretty lively conversation
about and he was begging them to cut his
arm off so that he could at least be
free and there was a pretty lively
conversation with the other men in the
group.
Like did we do that or not?
Right.
And they decided not to do that.
If they,
all they had was an acs.
They're like,
we chopped his arm off and free him.
He might die from that.
Right.
And he was removed from where those guys
were.
So he was lonely.
That was the thing.
He was lonely.
He was like,
cut my arm off.
I want to join you guys.
And they didn't any,
any died.
Oh,
amazing.
Amazing sentence.
Yeah.
And so,
you know what I mean?
Not to whatever to steer this
conversation too much,
but I mean that's a,
that's a microcosm in some ways for
America,
right?
I mean every country is potentially
trapped in a coal mine trying to figure
out how to survive.
We don't know.
I mean the day before nine slash 11,
we didn't know like 9:11
was coming,
right?
We don't know what's coming.
Right,
and the only way for any group of
people,
whether you it's $330,
million or 18 people as it was in the
coal mine,
the only way for any group of people
that to survive is to act collectively.
Right?
Humans don't survive in nature by
themselves and so in that coal mine,
both kinds of people were needed.
They happen to be all men but it didn't
need it.
Whatever.
It doesn't matter.
Gender doesn't matter.
I mean sex doesn't matter.
They need to both kinds of people.
They needed aggressive Alphas that
attack the problem and didn't care how
people felt and were interested in like
strict law and order and the group,
you do this,
you do that.
You do what I say is a survival.
You needed those kinds of people and you
needed the other kind like,
hey,
we're going to be all right.
Are you feeling okay?
Yeah,
we're,
you know,
like that kind of collaborative,
empathic person.
You needed that also.
So when you look at the politics in this
country,
you need both conservatism and
liberalism,
right?
You cannot,
I mean a completely conservative America
will be well defended,
right?
No one's going to mess with us,
America first,
like no one will mess with us,
but what will let,
what will be left unaddressed is some of
the internal dynamics of this country,
um,
which is frankly not at the foremost of
conservative thought.
I mean sort of racial disparity,
economic disparity and all that stuff.
Like,
you know,
I mean,
that's not at the foremost of the
conservative agenda and it shouldn't be.
It doesn't need to be,
it doesn't need to be because it's the
forefront of the liberal agenda.
And God forbid you have a country that's
completely run by liberals.
It'll get overrun immediately by the
nearest armed neighbor.
Right?
What'd you.
Liberals just aren't wired that way to
be suspicious of the world.
But what it,
what liberals do quite well is to try to
figure out a sort of system of fairness
within the group that gets it.
Know it's just tries to equalize things
and get everyone to sort of participate
in to be valued and taken care of.
Like I mean that it's all lovely,
right?
I mean that's needed also and so that
every country is at its best when you
have both of those dynamics going on and
they're in a kind of dynamic tension
with each other,
but neither completely takes over.
One of the things that breaks my heart
watching this country is,
is there's this idea on both sides,
on the liberal side and on the
conservative side that the other not
only is totally wrong,
but it's totally immoral and shouldn't
exist,
right?
It's just not true in this country is
not going to find peace until both sides
of the political equation sort of reach
across and shake the other person's hand
and say,
look,
I disagree with you on almost
everything,
but I'm glad you're with us.
I need you and I need to because I don't
think like you do.
I need you to think like you do and
until this country figures out how to do
that,
we're going to be in this sort of awful
partisans strife that eventually will
destroy us.
I bullets are not going to take down
this country words well and they're
going to be our words and it just breaks
my heart to see this dynamic not only
going on and on,
but getting
worse,
worse.
It does seem to be getting worse and
And what's seems to be new is the idea
from the liberals to silence people on
the right and to,
to think that free speech is important.
What's important is their ideas and that
their ideas are especially.
I think now that trump is president and
I think people feel even more emboldened
locked up in this.
I mean,
listen,
I think it will.
I mean honestly,
I think it's equally both sides,
but I.
But I agree with you.
I mean,
the problem with the right with the left
for me,
and again,
I'm a Democrat,
so I,
you know,
I love evaluating my own size problems
because they drive me.
They make me more upset than the right
wing's problems,
right?
Because because they're my people.
Right.
And I'm like,
come on,
can you,
can you act a little better?
Pleased to see the irony though,
that you've chosen a tribe and that
tribe of people that you don't even know
that these people are just.
It's a political tribe.
Well,
I mean,
listen,
I,
I share those political,
some of those political ideals and the
conservative ideals I don't,
I don't share,
but I would hate to live in a country
that didn't have conservatives in it
even though I disagree because I
disagree with them.
I don't want to be surrounded by people
I agree with.
Right.
And there are conservatives to do not
want liberals in this country.
Right.
Shame on them.
Sure.
And likewise for liberals come in here
and on both sides.
So I think both sides tried to silence
the voices of the other side.
Frankly,
I don't,
you know,
that's,
that's a sin.
I think that's committed equally on both
sides.
But one thing I wanted to bring up,
because I actually made mistake last
time I was on your on your show,
I mentioned a book and I got the name
wrong and it's such a good book and I
wanted to,
I just saw on twitter that people trying
to find it and they couldn't because I
got the name rock,
it's called our political,
our political nature,
and by a guy named Avi Tushman and he
collected an awful lot of data about the
fact that political opinion is about 50
percent determined by genetics.
In other words,
you inherit about half of your political
opinion and the other half is acquired
through experience,
through exposure.
So if you grew up in a liberal family,
yeah,
you're getting you probably you're,
you're about 50 percent likely to wind
up being a liberal because you absorb
though that way of seeing the world.
If I'm a Democrat,
if I had.
I grown up in a conservative family,
I think I'd be a conservative.
And I actually think having read this
book,
I think I'm actually a genetic
conservative that adopted liberal values
because of my environment.
I think there's a lot of people who are
genetic liberals who have adopted
conservative values.
I mean it.
It's about 50 slash 50,
but the point is,
so it's Avi Tishman our political
nature.
That's the name of the book.
I got it wrong.
I just wanted to correct that,
but the point of this to me is that,
and he knows this,
I mean scientists know this because when
they look at identical twins that share
almost all of their DNA,
identical twins later in life are far
more likely to have the same political
opinion than fraternal twins,
which don't share all their DNA.
You understand what I'm saying?
Yeah,
so that's how they know this.
When they looked at identical twins,
there's a much higher concordance of a
political opinion later in life than for
fraternal twins.
That's how they know that it's around 50
percent of your political view is
determined by genetics.
If it's determined by genetics,
that means it had survival value.
That means that liberalism and
conservatism both had survival value in
our evolutionary past and is as a
result,
has become encoded in our DNA.
Like other behaviors like generosity,
other character traits like generosity,
courage,
things like that,
those are all encoded in our DNA because
they had survival value will likewise
conservatism and liberalism,
which means that in the argument,
the discussion in this country about
politics,
you can disagree with people,
go for it,
democracy comes out of disagreement and
compromise is great,
but what you cannot do is point your
finger across the aisle and say,
not only are you wrong but you shouldn't
exist,
like go away,
disappear.
You're not part of what America is.
It's that assertion is completely
contradictory to evolution and if and if
it's contradicted your evolution,
it won't work well.
It seems to me that people have a really
difficult time managing conflict,
even managing verbal conflict,
that when someone disagrees with them,
they want to silence that person.
They want to yell at that person,
they want to scream and they they think
about their own thoughts rather than
putting themselves in the position of
the other person or objectively
recognizing that there is an important
factor,
they'd both.
It's important to have both sides.
It's important to even be challenged on
your ideas so you can solidify what's
the root cause of your ideas.
What is,
where were they coming from?
What,
what,
how,
how much have you examined these ideas?
Are you just married to them because
they were given to you?
Are these things you've adopted or are
these really well considered thoughts
that you've put through the mill?
Right.
I mean,
the thing is there were rules to
contests,
right?
I mean,
there are rules and MMA,
right?
There are rules and boxing.
There were rules in marriages,
right?
I mean if you,
you would never stay in a marriage where
your spouse treated you the way the
political parties treat each other right
now.
You would never stay.
I mean,
there's incredibly contemptuous,
mocking,
disparaging tone that both sides have.
Like you,
you were like,
I'm Outta here.
You know,
my wife clearly just thinks I'm a
complete dirt bag,
or no one had talked.
You know,
you don't talk to someone like that that
you have any respect for.
Right?
I'm Outta here.
I think no one would stay in a marriage
like that and what's happened,
and this is new,
right?
This,
I,
we didn't grow up with this.
Like this is a new thing where the
political parties talk to each other.
I mean,
disagreement is great,
right?
Come from,
you know,
we want eventually you compromise and
you figure something out where nobody's
happy,
but that,
you know,
the machine goes on,
right?
The ship sails on.
What's new now is this content and it
toxic in marriage and it's toxic in a
country too.
And this is a new thing.
And I think,
and I think,
um,
if you really,
if you really take in the reality that
this truth,
that half of our political opinions are
genetically wired,
you got to get rid of the contempt,
you know,
I mean,
it's part of what we are as most people
are aware of that.
No,
they're not right.
That's what I'm talking about it.
I mean,
you know,
um,
and Congress plays on this,
right?
It's a great campaign strategy to like
say things that are hateful things about
the other side and consolidate your
base.
And if you consult in both sides,
do this right,
and if you consolidate your base,
then you're more likely to win the
election you have,
you're in a more solid political
position so they can.
And we know behavior,
behavioral psychologists will tell you
that one way to,
to,
um,
make a group cohere,
make it a closed ranks and strengthened
its group commitment to itself.
One way to do that is to introduce an
enemy,
and when there's no enemy groups
naturally disperse because people just
go off to do their individual thing.
Of course,
you know,
you have the freedom to do that.
There's no threat anywhere.
Introduce a threat,
boom,
everyone's in a group.
So what politicians do is they,
they,
they create a threat where there is
none.
You know,
they say that other political party,
they're actually trying to destroy
democracy.
They're not part of the democracy.
They're actually trying to destroy it.
They're trying to destroy this country.
Um,
the same thing happened at the beginning
of the Spanish civil war.
My father grew up in Spain and I studied
this matter,
civil war quite a lot.
The democratic reforms that were,
that were coming in the thirties,
you know,
just land things like,
the vote for women,
you have a,
you know,
pretty normal things,
but there were a threat to the power
structure in Spain and the military and
the,
um,
so far right in Spain,
the fascist basically said that those
democratic reforms where people who were
trying to destroy Spain.
So you create an enemy that consolidates
your power and you go on to win the
election.
It's great campaign strategy.
It's just terrible for the nation.
Yeah.
This,
lock her up,
lock her up.
When,
when trump was running,
that was the big thing,
right?
The enemy that yet this was the enemy
that was Hillary Clinton.
She represented the evil Democrats who
had been stealing and robbing and
right.
And I,
you know,
I listen,
I totally understand being in
disagreement with Democrats.
Right?
But it's a different matters say that
they're actually antithetical.
The Democrats are antithetical to free
democratic ideals,
but just seems to meet to.
There's not a good party right now that
the Republicans are mass,
that Democrats are a mess.
You know,
they both suck,
so reform them,
right?
I mean,
or creative work,
isn't there also an issue with just
having two sides,
right?
Having the Yankees versus the red sox
every year in the world series.
Well those two sides,
I just
do represent the sort of,
the genetic strains in our liberal and
conservative.
I mean,
it's good.
It's going to break down one way or
another in that direction.
Right.
And so,
I mean,
it is sort of a binary.
I mean our brains are sort of binary in
that way.
Um,
I mean as humans surviving the wild,
you have to defend your group and you
need fairness within the group.
The,
the two things you have to do to survive
and remain a group.
Right?
Right.
And,
and so those tasks have been sort of
like subcontracted out to conservatives
into liberals and it's been that way for
a very long time and you can even see
some of those same behaviors like
insearch in chimpanzee society.
Right?
So this is very,
very ancient behavior.
So like it,
and I think you have to grips with it
doesn't mean that the two groups have to
act so a bismal with each other.
And,
and I really think that if you want to
save the,
if you want to sort of save this country
morally,
politically,
nationally,
maybe,
um,
you know,
really what you need is a bipartisan
committee in Congress that calls people
out and calls them out for doing and
saying things that undermine our sense
of unity as a nation.
So when Democrats say he's not my
president,
that undermines the understanding of
what democracy is easier,
president.
Like he got voted in man.
Like that's what happens in a democracy
is the guy you didn't vote for ends up
being your president.
That's what a democracy is.
So just deal with it,
right?
I hate that.
I hate that I'm a democrat.
I didn't vote for him.
But I hate when people say that.
And likewise,
when Donald trump sit,
when citizen trump was accusing Barack
Obama.
And I understand not liking Obama,
I don't really care if you don't like
them or don't like him,
but when citizen trump accused Barack
Obama of not being a citizen and gop
didn't repudiate that,
I mean,
think about it.
Citizen trump was telling every veteran
and soldier fighting overseas that their
commander in chief was an imposter,
was a fraud,
was not an American citizen,
and has usurped the White House,
right?
That's a terribly destructive thing to
tell men and women in uniform or in a
trench getting shot at,
right?
And the gop like the DNC with this
stupid.
He's not my president thing,
that the DNC is not rejecting that idea.
They let people say it,
they don't denounce it,
right?
The gop never repudiated that stupid
idea that trump came along with and for
the good of the nation.
They both had to write.
And this isn't a free speech issue.
Everyone has the right legal right to
make a fool of themselves.
Go for it.
But that doesn't mean the two political
parties have to stay silent in the face
of things that are completely toxic to
our democracy.
And they really should have spoken out
and I think some kind of bipartisan
commission in Congress that would call
out those are the worst outrageous and
calling the political parties to
denounce them that that would be
enormously positive thing in this
country.
I agree with you,
but I think it would take a truly
exceptional person to look at the other
side's faults and,
and not capitalize on it,
you know,
and,
and especially even if it's a false
thing like the Obama thing with,
with trump or any,
any number of things you could find in
that regard.
But it seems to me like this is like the
perfect time.
If there was ever going to be a time
where a third party with some sort of
centrist type party would come around,
this would be the perfect time where
people are so.
And we also,
I think people recognize that what we're
seeing on the right and the left in
regards to Hillary Clinton or Donald
Trump is you're seeing people that are
pretending to be this thing right?
With Donald Trump.
He's a lifelong Democrat.
And then all of a sudden he's a
Republican.
He's talking about God and I mean,
this is just like,
it's a show,
it's a little dog and pony show on the
right.
And on the left you've got this woman
who was part of the Clinton Foundation.
They were essentially,
it was a pay to play scheme.
They were making millions of dollars and
hundreds of thousand dollars for
bullshit speeches that they would give
to the banks.
And this is not some sort of a,
a real liberal.
This is not a that the ideas that you
were embracing about liberal values.
I
mean,
no,
I mean the two parties basically have
become sort of cartels to keep
themselves in power.
Yes.
That's a great way to pray.
And,
and um,
and you know,
he'll,
hillary was absolutely part of that on
the,
on the,
on the left and you know,
it,
uh,
all of it's antithetical to the highest
ideals of the framers of the
constitution and the people that
established this country.
And in and I,
I mean,
I hear you about the centrist party.
That would be great.
But there's,
you know,
I mean,
the way the power structure works,
the way the cartels work is they got
all,
they have access to all the funds,
right?
All the money,
Where you,
where do you,
where do you get the money for something
like that.
You need to build something from scratch
and get to speed and in
time to win an election,
that's very,
very hard to do.
But at the very least,
I mean,
a centrist party could fall prey to that
kind of toxic rhetoric as well.
I mean,
but I feel like there should be norms
where freedom of speech is an absolute.
I mean,
we get it,
but that the parties don't.
They have a moral obligation to denounce
things that they know undermine than
unity of this country.
I don't mean people in disagreement with
one another.
I mean a basic level of respect for the
other person's personhood,
for their citizenship,
for their right to participate in the
democratic process.
And when somebody accuses the president
of not being a citizen of the US,
they're basically saying,
I don't respect the system.
Uh,
like I,
I,
I think the entire system is a lie and,
and,
and I don't even think Donald Trump
thought it was true.
I think it was a tactic and that the gop
never called that out is really
shameful.
You don't think he thought it was true
that the Obama was actually born in
Kenya because I think he did because I
know that he's really good friends with
Alex Jones and talks to him all the
time.
I think he believes a lot of very wacky
conspiracy,
you know,
I think he starts out believing that,
but I,
by the end,
I mean,
does he,
did he,
did,
he did it for seven years.
So many people did believe it though.
I know,
but he.
But the thing is he was doing something
that worked.
He's a pragmatist.
One of the things I really like about
him in a way,
I mean I hate,
I find him sort of a moral in the way
that it gives me the chills,
but he's also a pragmatist,
right?
So I think he's completely capable of
advocating a position that he doesn't
believe in,
but I don't think he needs to believe
in.
He's like,
enough people believe in this,
that this is working for me.
What was the benefit for him even
chasing that idea down?
I mean,
he wasn't running for president back
then,
do you think he was thinking?
I think he's been on it.
I think he was considering it for a long
time.
So he was doing it to sort of
deteriorate to Democratic Party.
Yeah.
And Yeah.
And to see,
see if this immigration stuff also,
man,
I,
I mean maybe he believes in that stuff,
maybe he doesn't,
but it doesn't,
it doesn't matter what he figured out
very astutely as he identified a
democratic demographic that feels like
the country's getting overrun by
immigrants.
Right.
And you know,
statistics don't bear that out,
but people feel that way and people feel
that way.
They vote that way and he figured that
out.
Right.
And so,
I mean,
more power to it,
right?
Like,
I mean I'm,
I'm not questioning his.
I mean it worked for him.
Right.
But the only thing that I would say is
like,
please don't say anything,
that I'm undermines the nation's sense
of unity.
Right.
You know,
that's the crucial thing.
That's the thing that's keeping us safe
in the world is that we're a unified
country.
And when you disparage the courts,
for example,
you're splitting the country apart,
then the intelligence agencies don't do
it.
Right.
I think you're drilling holes in your
own boat,
man.
Are you astonished that all that works,
that he can do that,
that he can disparage the intelligence
communities,
that he could disparage the courts and
that no one calls him out.
No one says this is fucking outrageous.
This is stupid.
Especially knowing all of his campaigns
ties to Russia that are coming out
now.
Even more so.
Well,
listen,
I mean,
I,
some processes happening that will
eventually catch up with him.
Like,
I mean I,
I mean,
I don't know how it's gonna turn out.
Am I surprised?
Yes,
of course.
I'm surprised.
I'm also surprised that the Democrats
that,
you know,
within my lifetime went from being a
party that was deeply concerned with the
poor,
with the working poor,
uh,
with,
with people working in factories.
You know what I mean?
Those are at least the highest ideals,
right?
In my lifetime they went to,
they became a completely elitist
organization.
They didn't give a shit about those
people.
Right.
So,
like that surprises me too.
Right?
So along comes Bernie Sanders who,
whatever,
you know,
whatever his issues,
he's,
he's least sincere,
you know what I mean?
At least you trust the guy like that guy
speaking his mind.
And the thing about Donald Trump,
he's speaking his mind like he's not
trying to,
he's not,
doesn't have these awful poll tested
opinions like Hillary did and Jeb did.
And all those guys like,
he's like,
no,
no.
This is what I think.
I don't care how people,
you know,
how people react on this is as Martin
Luther said,
here I stand for,
I can do no other.
You know,
a lot of places that trump stands,
I don't agree with,
but I actually,
I'm actually impressed by his ability to
say something no matter what the
repercussions.
This is kind of cool.
Well,
it is definitely a first,
you know,
I mean he's,
I mean at the debate when he was talking
to Hillary Clinton and I forget what
exactly what you said,
you know,
uh,
and he said because you'd be in jail and
the whole place went crazy.
Like who the fuck has ever done that?
It doesn't central debate.
It's amazing in a work that I,
you know,
like my house kind of off to.
Although I disagree with him.
I'm almost every political point that he
says he holds.
But I,
but I got to say like,
like it worked and he,
I wrote an essay and I was talking about
different kinds of courage and you know,
this sort of physical courage,
right?
And,
and I mean lives are literally being
courageous in the face of harm to your
body.
And I feel like trump is,
you know,
he's a bit of a bully and I think that
to me,
bullies and cowards are sort of the same
thing,
right?
They're just two different sides of the
same character trait.
And I said,
but that's not all trump is.
He's actually morally,
he's actually very courageous.
Like he's not a moral coward.
He will say exactly what he thinks,
no matter what the opinion's going to
be.
He has extreme confidence in who he is
or he doesn't give a shit,
you know?
I mean,
that's moral courage.
It like this is what I believe and I'm
going to say it.
I don't care if I don't win,
I don't care if I go to jail,
here I stand for,
I can do no other Martin simply could
have is elitist mentality because he
does believe that he's above a lot of
the repercussions for saying these
things.
But a lot of people who are elitists are
cowards and this thing.
And I disagree with trump on just about
all of his policies,
right?
But the thing I do kind of have to tip
my hat to his head.
He's not a moral coward.
He works.
He will say thing that every political
pundit in the world will say,
no,
that's going to get,
that's going to destroy you.
You're going to attack John Mccain and
you're gonna hope to win the Republican
nomination and you're fucking crazy.
And he did it and it works.
But he attacked him for being captured.
I know,
which is insane.
And I think trump truly feels that way
and I don't agree with them.
But I do respect the fact that he said
it in the face of all political advice.
He didn't give a shit.
He said it because he believed it.
That's moral courage.
I just disagree with his opinions.
But I that moral courage,
very few people have it.
He has it and I just,
I wish he used it to unify the country
and he's still splitting the country.
And that thing has any desire to unify
the country.
Very self serving.
I agree.
And I,
you know,
I don't think hilary did either,
and none.
You know what I mean,
and that's the problem with our pool
parties right now is that they're
serving themselves before they serve the
country.
Well,
I think it speaks to what you're talking
about in your book that no one is
looking at this like a real tribe and
uh,
an enormous tribe of 350 million people,
but there's no one person that's
standing out as a real leader and at
least what Obama was,
I mean,
whether you agree with his policies and
there's a lot that I don't agree with is
particularly in where the way flip
flopped about whistleblowers and freedom
of the press,
those things disturb me greatly because
I know how intelligent he is.
I know he's a lawyer.
He was a statesman though.
I mean,
he really came across as a guy who you
go,
oh,
well that,
that guy should be the fucking
president.
He sounds like the president.
He's,
he's,
he has a fantastic vocabulary.
He speaks clearly.
He,
he's a very,
he's a highly honed human being.
That's right.
No,
no,
I agree.
And I,
you know,
there are things I didn't like whatever
that about him,
but,
but absolutely as a,
as a person,
I mean he brought a huge,
I thought he brought a huge sort of
gravitas and dignity to the office.
Dignity.
Yes,
definitely without a doubt.
He mean he was probably one of the best
ever at that.
But I think that what we need now,
um,
is someone who genuinely wants to help
the country be unified.
Someone who genuinely wants to help the
country,
not help their party,
not,
not help themselves,
not just think,
well,
hey,
when this is all done,
I'm going to make a fucking million
dollars a year doing speaking fees or
whatever,
however much they make when they do
that.
Well,
yeah,
and you're going to,
I mean we're,
I mean we need that to stay to remain a
country.
Yeah,
right.
I mean like,
I mean,
it really is headed towards a bad place
I think.
And so that person is going to have to
overcome the sort of reflexive reaction
of the left wing.
You know,
he's not my president.
And the reflexive reaction of the right
wing,
the right wing hated Obama in ways that
were completely out of proportion to
Obama's actual policies.
And you know,
what Mitch Mcconnell said,
you know,
the Republicans job in Congress,
their foremost job is to make sure that
Barack Obama is a complete failure as a
president like it that's not serving the
country,
not at all.
Right?
So,
so you need a leader who is actually
able to overcome that toxic thinking
in both parties,
right?
Right.
I mean,
who is Jesus coming back like,
I know who's going to do this,
who is going to do this?
But I think the start is a bipartisan
commission that starts to call people
out.
Right?
So you,
you have Republicans calling Republicans
out because they're on this commission.
Do you have Democrats Calling Democrats
out?
You need it.
You got the free speech to make a fool
of yourself,
go for it.
But you're not going to undermine this
country without being called out by this
commission.
And um,
and I was talking with someone in
government pretty high up about this and
I said,
you know,
I had sent my thing,
you'll bullets aren't going to destroy
this country,
okay,
is never going to destroy this country,
um,
but our own words we'll can destroy our
democracy like that actually could do it
if we play this hand drawn.
And I said,
that makes partisan rhetoric actually a
matter of national security.
And when you can think about as an think
about it as a national security concern,
then you actually have a sort of
political and legal basis for forming a
commission that addresses it.
And I really truly think that should
happen.
And if it doesn't,
hopefully something else will happen.
That works.
But it's the only thing I can think of
that will begin to address that,
that can,
that can rise up above the partisan
interest of both parties because those,
the parties clearly don't seem capable
of doing it on their own.
Now when you write a book,
like try,
when you outline all these issues that
people have and all these issues
historically that people have had,
do you try to consider a solution?
I mean,
do you,
do you have a solution?
Are you just examining all the various
problems that we have?
So I mean tribe was me trying to make
sense of sort of what ails us,
starting with,
you know,
people hemorrhaging off the frontier to
the American Indians and on up to the
soldiers.
I was with mass shootings,
you know,
something's,
something's not working for us.
Right?
What?
So it was foremost in analysis.
Um,
and towards the end,
um,
I talked a little bit about solutions
and one of the solutions I talked about
was making a concerted effort to get rid
of contemptuous partisan rhetoric in
government.
And I really felt that that trickles
down and pollutes,
it pollutes the water stream down,
like downstream.
It pollutes everything so that everyone
all as citizens are drinking toxic
water.
Um,
from,
from that rhetoric and wondering if the
unity can survive,
like will this will the center hold?
Um,
you know,
you hear your parents screaming at each
other in the bedroom and saying
unforgivable things to each other as a
child,
you might rightly think,
wow,
this marriage isn't lasting in this
family is not lasting.
That's how it feels to be a citizen of
the United States right now.
Like mom and dad are screaming at each
other.
And so I talked about contempt,
disagree.
If you want,
don't speak with contempt about someone
you share a combat outpost width and
that's what this country potentially as
don't you think also
with the mom and dad analogy that it
also shows you how to behave in your own
life.
And I think that's one of the things
that's really important about the
president is the president does sort of
represent the best example of what we
can be.
When we were kids growing up,
that was the thing,
like he asked the kid what they want to
be.
If someone said,
I want to be president,
and were like,
Holy Shit,
you're really going for a kid.
You want to be the biggest job.
That's the number one position.
So you're supposed to be the best person
ever,
which is why we hold someone to such an
incredible microscope,
which is almost even more impressive
that trump won after that,
grab the pussy audio recording and that
he could just brush that off as locker
room talk.
It's right in a way.
He's kind of right.
I mean,
it really is kind of fucked up that they
did try to use that on them and pull it
out the last minute.
But it does give you also an
understanding of how he thinks and
behaves when no one's around.
Right?
I mean,
you know,
my problem with him was that I like if I
look at the worst of his behavior,
um,
I mean people sent society says people
to jail for the worst thing that they
did.
So it is actually legitimate to judge
people's worst behavior and evaluate
them on that basis.
So if I look at the wharf,
look at the worst of his behavior,
even if I was a diehard Republican who,
who adhere to all of the things he says
he believes it.
If I looked at the worst of his
behavior,
a mocking a gold star family,
like mocking a disabled person that
wasn't real though,
you know that mocking a disabled person
was sort of trumped up.
He does hate to use that word trump cup.
He does that when he's talking about
anyone.
Like when you asked flustered like,
oh,
what are you going to do here?
Like that they tried to say that he was
mocking a reporter that it was disabled,
but it's pretty clear that that's not
right.
Well,
I mean maybe so,
but with a,
with a question from someone who's
visibly disabled,
maybe you just don't do that.
You know what I mean?
Like each pattern it does.
Well maybe,
but maybe I'm giving him more of the
benefit of the doubt that I should.
But if it was the only example that I
wouldn't be thinking about it,
but there is a sort of pattern that,
that,
that model from Mexico who gained some
weight that he was walking.
I mean like the mockery of less powerful
people is sort of endless.
And so to me,
I wouldn't,
I wouldn't have that person at my dinner
table,
you know what I mean?
Like I just with my close friends,
like someone who was acting like that,
he started acting,
started doing that and my dinner table,
I'd walk around,
I get up and walk around the table,
put them in a headlock,
I think drag him out of my house.
Right,
right.
I don't want to think that about my
president.
I want my president to be someone I'd be
like glad to have at my dinner table.
I would,
would've.
I didn't vote for George Bush by love to
have that guy.
I had dinner table,
Ronald Reagan.
Did you know what I mean?
Like he's the first president and be
like,
no man,
I don't want to subject my bi friends
too that you ever read rudy errol woody
Harrelson's account of a dinner that he
had with trump.
He said literally had to get up in the
middle and go outside and smoke a joint
just to just
relax himself.
Yeah.
I was talking about,
I think you said early 2000.
He had a dinner with trump.
And he said he never met someone so
narcissistic,
so self obsessed.
Yeah.
And you know,
the,
you know,
my worry like in this conversation is
that it will somehow seem partisan and
like I will be saying the same things if
trump were a democrat,
something about George Bush that you'd
be happy to have him over.
And I just think,
I hope that what comes out of this is
that a hero will rise and that someone
will.
Someone who's really legitimately good
person will say,
look,
this is a,
this is a fucking travis day.
Like someone who actually could assume
the role correctly will step into place.
And it was see that very clearly in
comparison.
Right.
Well what I mean,
do you get back to your question?
One of the solutions that I talk about
it,
it's not in my book,
I talk about this.
This is national compulsory national
service with a,
with a military option.
And in the your question was how do we
make this nation feel like a nation?
Right.
And the problem psychologist will tell
you that the more you sacrifice for
something,
the more you value it.
And if you're part of something that
doesn't require any sacrifice at all,
you just don't value it very highly.
Right.
The advantage of national service it,
and I don't mean the draft,
I think I don't mean military service.
I mean national service with a military
option.
I don't think it's moral to force
someone to fight a war that they don't
believe it.
But what sort of service which,
you know,
whatever,
whatever it is,
the nation needs a lot of stuff done
right.
And whatever that may be.
But the point of it is,
so if you had a military option,
but otherwise you could teach in schools
otherwise you could dig ditches.
I don't whatever the nation needs done
this work,
this core of workers at 22,
23 years old does it for a year.
My first wife was from,
from the eastern,
from eastern Europe and the young people
formed work brigades in the summer and
help harvest like harvest wheat and
stuff like that was what she did when
she was a teenage girl.
And it was incredibly good for the kids
over there and it made them feel like
they're part of something.
Right.
And so what I would say,
there's a downside to national service,
which is the government's telling people
what to do.
Of course there's also an upside,
which is it makes everyone feel like
they're part of this thing called the
United States and it puts white people
and black people enrich and poured.
Everyone,
puts them all in one big pot and stirs
them up just like the military does.
And they get to know each other.
And so everything's is an upside and a
downside to everything.
Right?
So national service has a very obvious
downside,
but the upside isn't discussed much,
which is that it creates an American
identity,
a shared experience that all Americans
have that like in Israel is compulsory
service and that that is a common ground
that every single Israeli has,
whatever,
wherever they fall in the political
spectrum,
they all have that shared experience and
it's an enormously potent thing in that
country.
Keeping it bound together.
And this country I
think needs something like that.
I think it would be very,
very helpful.
Well,
it'd be nice if people did have some.
I mean if you,
if you use some sort of connection to
what it takes to keep things running,
whether it's help fix the streets,
whether it's,
you know,
help do something.
But the problem that I would have it
probably I would have with it is the
idea that someone from the government
would be able to require you to do
something and that if you didn't do it,
they could treat you the same way the
irs treats you.
If you don't pay your taxes,
I just lock you in a cage,
which is.
Well,
I mean one made,
one way to do it might be to incentivize
it by sort of making it mandatory,
incentivizing it by giving people really
large tax breaks for doing it.
Yeah,
but young people aren't going to think
about tax breaks.
They're going to think about,
fuck that man,
I want to skateboard or I don't want to
go,
all right.
Then they have to listen to me.
Listen,
for most of this nation's history,
we've had a draft as the government
telling people what to do.
Right?
And likewise with taxes,
you don't pay your taxes,
you go to jail.
Like I mean the government does,
the government puts red lights and
intersections and you have to fucking
stop.
I agree.
But to try to do that today,
it'd be extremely difficult.
The distrust of the government is so
high and if the government comes along
and says,
you have to do all these things and then
we go,
wait a minute,
are you doing these things?
Are you going to join the military?
You're 55 years old,
your senator,
are you going to go pick wheat or
fucking fix the roads?
It definitely has to start.
I mean,
yeah,
you can't.
You're not going to get 60 year olds and
in national service,
right?
They're already involved their lives.
The great thing about 18,
19,
20 year olds,
22 year olds,
is that their lives haven't really
started yet.
I mean that's why it works in Israel.
Yeah.
So are people gonna object you?
Of course they are,
but the question is how do we unify this
country that the truth is like if we
wanted to unify communities,
you'd been in the car,
right?
People can,
you know they are living there spending
their whole lives within walking
distance of their home that will,
that will unify communities.
We're just not willing to do that.
What will unify the country's national
service?
We may not be willing to do it,
but that's a different conversation from
would it work or not?
My opinion is,
is that it would help.
It's a good opinion.
I mean,
I,
I definitely see merit in it.
I definitely think that would be
something that would be a fascinating
debate to have back and forth.
I just wonder if people at any point in
their lives today who would be willing
to give up freedom for the government.
I think people are used to this kind of
like free ride.
I pay my taxes and that's all you got
from me.
I don't have to vote.
I don't have to do anything.
You know,
in Australia you have to vote and if you
don't vote you get fined.
Well that,
you know,
that's what you said it right there.
That's the misconception.
It's not for the government,
it's for your neighbor,
it's for your fellow citizens.
Everything you pay your taxes,
not for the government.
You pay your taxes for the country,
but you pay him to the Gulf,
to the government.
There's no auditing of your taxes.
And I think that's one of the things
that freaks people out today.
Like you don't know where that money is
going.
They don't have to tell you and if you
don't give it to them,
they'll lock you up.
Right.
And that's the problem with a large
scale society is that collective effort.
It's not clear that that collective
effort is going to the whole entity.
It looks like it's going to the tax man.
Right?
It's not.
I mean that's an illusion,
right.
But I mean the check is to the irs,
the irs handed over to the government
that that's then spends it on the
country.
I mean,
that's the reality,
but it looks like the irs is oppressing
you.
Yeah,
but that's actually not what's
happening,
right?
The irs is an arm of government that you
elected in.
Right.
And it's been charged with getting,
getting money from people like that's
just the irs isn't doing anything.
It was just like,
it's like Tsa ever.
I was standing in line at Tsa and
someone was complaining about how long
it was taking and,
and,
and the guy next to her,
they didn't even know each other and the
guy next to her who said,
look,
they're not doing it for them.
They're doing it for us.
Brian.
They're searching all our stuff.
They don't care.
Right.
They're not on the damn plane.
They're searching our stuff for us.
Likewise with the government,
the government isn't doing it for itself
is still new for us.
Right.
We like to think of it as one entity,
right.
We like to think of the irs as the
government,
you know,
they are collecting the money.
We almost think of it as them spending
the money as well.
We don't think of it.
It was distributing it to the rest of
the government.
That's right.
Yeah,
that's right.
So if you want to gin up as sort of like
antigovernment screed,
like it's easy to play on that
misperception because it's an easy
misperception to,
to have,
I mean you get a $200 parking ticket in
New York and he definitely feels like
the parking bureau is like,
is,
is vengeful,
you know what I mean,
has targeted you personally as you're
going to take your $200 and spend it on
itself.
That's what it feels like.
The truth is that that $200 paves the
fills in the potholes that you're going
to be driving across next year.
That's the truth of it,
right?
You know what we're talking about
solutions for the woes of society in the
end,
particularly the individual.
You have sort of found your own solution
in journalism and,
and embedded journalism in these very
dangerous environments that this is how
you have sort of reinforced your tribe.
And you talk about that in the book
about how,
you know,
uh,
how well you slept in this very tight
confines in these bases with all these,
like very loud snoring men.
But the fact that you guys were all
together in this very hostile
environment,
but that was your solution.
Well,
I mean,
there wasn't a solution in this
instance.
I mean,
it wasn't a longterm solution,
but it did give me these experience of
sort of,
um,
sort of shared a shared fate,
right?
I mean,
it's sort of collective effort,
right?
I was part of this group,
um,
and my,
my,
my welfare was tied to the welfare of
the group.
My actions could help or hinder the
group.
I was judged by how I behaved in the
Right.
And that's,
that's our evolutionary past.
And it felt great.
Right.
And,
um,
so the,
you know,
the trick is we,
we live in a dispersed,
modern society where that's just not
going to be the 20 hour a day reality
for most people throughout their lives.
But it may not need to be,
you may just need a little bit of it,
you know,
maybe you get a little bit of that sort
of collective,
the collective norm at the boxing gym,
you know,
maybe you get it in the military,
maybe you get it hunting,
you know,
whatever,
like there are ways to experience it and
maybe you just don't,
you maybe you get it a church in a.
I mean,
I'm not religious,
but I,
I,
I understand church to be a profoundly
communal activity and so I'm not saying
burn down that suburbs and bend the car,
although that would work pretty well.
Um,
maybe for your own personal sense of
meaning and fulfillment in life.
Find,
find that collective experience in
little bits and pieces and the little
goes a long way.
Yeah.
And doing something and doing something
difficult.
I think it's also very important.
Absolutely.
I mean getting together,
shoot pool with your buddies every
Thursday night.
That's great.
But it's not quite.
We're talking about difficult things and
things that test you physically and
mentally for some reason there.
Those seem to be a requirement for
people and when people don't,
don't fulfill that requirement.
It seems to me those are the people that
are most unhappy.
Yeah,
I mean the state there have to be stakes
involved.
Yes.
There are no stakes to pool to golf
right there.
Pleasure gambling.
Right.
But that,
but that's not a collective,
you know what I mean?
That's not a collective state and um,
they're pleasant activities,
but what,
you know,
what,
what reproduces our evolutionary past as
being in a small group where the stakes
are for the stakes are serious,
if not life and death,
but even,
even if it's not life and death,
at least they're real physical
consequences.
And that collective action makes you
more,
makes the group more able to navigate
those adversities successfully.
And when you do that,
um,
it is,
it's an intoxicating feeling is what
we're wired for.
It's what we're missing in our sort of
modern lives.
And you,
you don't need,
you don't need a huge amount of it to
feel better.
Another thing that seems to make people
feel very fulfilled as creating things,
working with their hands,
creating anything,
whether it's furniture,
art,
just making something,
doing something where your mind is
involved in natural task of bringing
forth something into existence that
didn't exist before.
What we'll think about it.
I mean,
again,
in terms of evolution,
if doing something successfully produces
a chemical reaction that feels good,
a little bit of dopamine or in terms of
communal connection,
a little bit of Oxytocin,
the,
the trained monkey that we are,
we'll continue doing that.
Good thing.
So,
so basically the tasks that helped with
survival get rewarded with
neurochemicals that feel good.
Yeah.
And the things that are dangerous to us,
uh,
and,
and less than our chance for survival
don't feel good.
So being isolated,
being alienated from your group,
being an outcast feels bad and your
survival chances go down,
right?
You don't want to stay in that place.
You want to join the group again.
And so there's these neurochemical
reward incentives and punishments that
get heard.
People towards behaviors that help
survival build,
doing things,
accomplishing things,
building things that all feels good.
It's clearly what we needed to do in our
evolutionary past and is reinforced and
creativity factors onto that.
How that like say like art,
like painting or something like that.
Like there's something deeply satisfying
to people that are painters.
Well,
uh,
yeah,
and what they're.
I mean art,
um,
they know from the,
from the incredible paintings on the
caves and in the caves in France and
Spain,
Lesko and the other caves that art is
one of the things that's used to bind
communities together in ceremonies.
I mean,
you can see you in church.
there is no,
there is no church in the land that
doesn't have art on the walls,
right?
Um,
the depictions of Christ or whatever or
what are the visual aids that helps bind
people into a group like,
oh,
we all believe in the same thing,
right?
So art is a great binding force.
Music is an incredible binding force.
So rhythmic like rhythm and heavy
drumming rhythm.
We'll get a whole group of people sort
of moving in unison.
And I'm,
Jonathan Haidt has talked about,
he talked about that sort of hive
behavior and how it works and very,
very powerful.
So what I would say,
and I'm just guessing here,
but I would say is that the arch that
are so intoxicating to be engaged in
their survival value is that it makes
the group cohere around a unified idea.
And that music does that.
I'm the visual arts do that.
Um,
the spoken word poetry song,
all those do that as well.
And so the,
you have a group of people that are
there are unified on these all,
all these different levels.
So what happens when the enemy comes,
I mean the music starts the sort of like
visual pageantry starts like you get,
you know,
like the,
the war time posters showing heroic
soldiers with rifle and bayonet or you
get the,
the war art,
right?
You get the martial music,
all of that galvanizes the public spirit
to face the enemy and it works extremely
well.
Wow.
So you think that that's one of the
reasons why art is so satisfying.
I mean,
I just assume that our evolution has
produced that anything that feels good
to us had survival value in our past,
so of creating art feels good.
That's because we are genetically
predisposed towards doing things that
bind the group together.
Generosity feels good,
right?
If you walk down the street and you give
someone $5,
you just a random dude,
you just give them five bucks and you
measure the.
The neurochemicals in his brain and your
brain,
you get more of a high than he does.
Right?
So generosity feels good.
It's clearly adaptive and helps groups
go here,
right?
Yeah.
And Art as well,
so that art,
when you create something amazing,
what you're realizing is that someone's
going to see that and go,
wow,
that's incredible.
Like they're going to get a great
feeling off of seeing your art.
Yeah.
You have the same vision,
oh,
I painted that tree and this other
person or that antelope or that bison or
whatever you find in the walls of the
and this other person comes to like,
oh my God,
that's an incredible bison.
There's no,
like you did something the other person
connected to now you the two of you are
joined in your understanding of what
that painting means.
Right.
And that's a very powerful thing.
So if you drew that bison and no one
else in the world ever saw it,
I'm guessing that the chemical rewards
for that creativity would be let will be
lower.
Yeah.
I,
you know,
I noticed that in my children,
my kids love to draw and one of the
things that they love is showing their
drawings.
I mean they love to draw but like not
yet.
Not yet,
not yet.
And then when they're done like look,
try and I'm just like boom.
They did getting that little rush
themselves and you get the rush and I
mean look,
I mean just do it.
It's easy to test like taking musician,
measure their neurochemicals while
they're practicing in a room by
themselves and then put them in a,
in a,
in a stadium filled with 10,000
people and see what happens.
Well,
I'm guessing that the guy in the stadium
with the Bruce Springsteen in front of
10,000
people is experiencing a neurochemical
reality that he's not getting in his
living room.
Not only that'll probably a
neurochemical reality that very few
human beings will ever experience.
That's right.
Some sort of a strange.
But think about the power of that.
I mean,
you know,
any musician on stage is basically
acting sort of in the role of the
Shaman,
right?
To like,
I'm going to act.
I'm going to act as a conduit between
you all and the divine right and my
music is going to do it.
My words,
you're going to do it by dances going to
whatever it is,
but I'm the conduit,
right?
I don't matter.
I'm connecting you with a,
with a divine feeling and that feeling
is going to unify all of you and I'm
going to play these chords.
I'm going to sing this song and like
magic.
You are going to be tapping your feet in
unison.
Like how do you get 10,000
people do the same thing at the same
time.
You sing them a song is the only way to
do it.
That's an incredibly powerful thing and
that's the uh,
I mean that's the power of the Shaman.
I mean bruce springsteen isn't a shaman
literally,
but he occupies that space in a modern,
secular,
secular society doesn't have shebeens
but,
but in the old days,
that's what he would be.
Do you feel that way when you put a book
out?
Like when you put the book out,
when you know it's done,
you read it,
it's done and he sent it out there and
do what kind of weird feeling that you
get.
Are People going to read that?
It's an interesting thing about a book
because you actually never observe in
real time people's reaction to it.
I mean,
I'm not perched in someone's arm chair
watching them read in bed.
You know what I mean?
Like the general public about like
reviews.
Yeah,
but that's also very.
It's very distant.
But when I started making documentaries
for the first time,
I had the experience or the experiencing
of watching other people's experience
when I'd done
right.
I'm not watching the audience,
I'm in the audience and I'm watching
people react to ristreppo.
Yes.
I never got to see people react to the
books I read because I'm not in there
damn bedroom.
Right?
Right.
But I am in the movie theater.
I'm watching people react to the things
that the films I made.
And I wouldn't say it's apples.
Oranges under know,
which is one better was what,
you know,
whatever.
But it's a very different experience in.
It's incredibly powerful.
Which do you like one better?
I mean,
movies just can't.
They don't have enough bits of
information.
I mean a book.
You can really communicate information,
right?
Very sophisticated ideas and they're
permanent,
right there.
They are in the person's bookshelf and
the person could underline that
paragraph and go back to it.
You know,
you've actually affected sort of
communal thinking.
You've affected the way people
understand the world of film is an
experience more than it is a sort of
data dump and um,
or a philosophical argument.
And that experience is very,
very powerful.
It acts on a different part of the brain
than a book does.
It's much more emotional.
Um,
I mean,
I've,
you know,
I've choked up,
I've teared up watching my own films
because they're personal to me,
you know,
I've never done that reading my own
book,
rereading a book that I've written,
so it's a different experience and I
would never say this is different parts
of the human mind like you need,
you certainly need boats.
So no long answer.
I don't have a preference.
I feel like I,
I need both now.
This documentary on Syria,
um,
when is this available?
Well,
it,
we may,
it's called Hell on earth.
Um,
our website is hell on earth.com.
It's,
um,
how'd you get that?
It seems like that would have already
been taken,
right?
The different websites that are
available.
And that's true.
That's true.
I thought about that.
I didn't,
I wasn't in charge of getting it by the
wizard.
Right.
I'm going to have to pay for that one.
So it was called Hell on earth.
It's about the Syrian civil war.
Um,
we made it for National Geographic.
I made it with Nick quested,
my partner and all the films that I've
made.
Um,
and it,
it brought it broadcast last June.
It's gonna,
you know,
nat Geo rebroadcasts,
everything that they do,
obviously you can also go to their
website and stream it.
It's about this treatment today.
Yeah,
absolutely.
It's about the Syrian civil war,
how it started.
Um,
and particularly how isis,
why isis arose up out of that.
And we all know what Isis is.
This is grotesquely violent radical
jihadist movement.
Um,
and,
and that,
um,
we have all seen,
seen their video,
heard of their videos where they're
beheading people and you know,
in front of a video camera and a
ghastly,
ghastly things.
He said,
why did that,
why did that happen in Syria?
How did that,
that mutation occur at this point in
history in that place.
And so the,
the,
the film examines that.
And um,
were you there?
Did you go to Syria?
No,
you know,
after my friend Tim Hetherington was
killed,
uh,
Tim,
obviously I made restrepo with an,
he was a brother and a good friend and a
colleague and he was killed in Libya in
2011,
uh,
on an assignment that I was supposed to
be on with him at the last minute.
I couldn't go and he got killed.
And so I stopped war reporting after
that front line reporting.
Syria was so dangerous that you couldn't
think of going in there.
I mean,
in numerous kidnappings and beheadings,
um,
it was basically a suicide by the time
we started working on the story.
It was a suicide mission.
So we actually worked with Syrians in
Syria who are documenting their own war.
Wow.
I'm a including an incredible family
that was living under a,
in territory under isis control and
surviving.
They were trying to figure out like,
do we try to escape or not?
And of course if you try to escape and
you're caught,
you're dead.
They will drag your family out of a
pickup truck in line.
You open a wall,
a machine gun you.
But they were worried that if they
stayed,
they also die and they decided to
escape.
We got a camera to them at a very
nondescript little cell phone camera and
they self documented life under isis and
the decision to leave and the um,
their flight through the isis
checkpoints through the front lines all
the way to Turkey and they self
documented and it's part of,
it's the sort of through line in the
movie.
Absolutely extraordinary family.
Wow.
And so then they're in Turkey,
now you're in Turkey.
Then they tried to get to Greece on a
rubber raft on a Zodiac.
They returned again.
This is also documented by them.
It's in the film.
They returned back at the last moment by
the,
by the Turkish coast guard sent back and
now they're increasing their actually
doing really well.
They started a small business.
They're incredibly hard working,
resourceful,
beautiful people.
I mean,
they're,
you know,
like I wish they could come to this
country.
We'd be lucky to have them and they'd be
lucky to have us.
There are an incredible family and if
you see the film,
you'll see what I'm talking about.
That's a,
that's a big point that a lot of people
felt was missed at all the criticisms of
immigrants coming over to this country,
you know,
the stock closed the border,
stop allowing Muslims stop allowing all
these people to come over from these
dangerous areas that somehow know that
these people would be agents of these
dangerous areas coming to destroy our
democracy.
But these people are trapped.
A lot of these people are,
are people that are experiencing these
horrible conditions,
much like many of the people that
originally made it to America and the.
Yeah.
I mean,
our country is immigrants.
This country is.
My father is a two time or refugee,
right?
I mean,
he fled Spain during the civil war.
he's passed away.
He was born in Nineteen,
29,
19,
23.
He fled Spain during the civil war.
Then he fled France because of the Nazis
rolled in.
He came to this country.
He was a brilliant physicist and we were
lucky to have him and he was eternally
lucky to be part of this country as
well.
Um,
so what was odd about trump's try not to
get political again,
but I got to say what was odd about
trump's travel ban did.
There were countries that we'd never
been attacked by.
No one from those countries had ever
attacked this country.
Like,
I don't want to go.
Like what are those countries doing on
the travel ban?
This lunatic that killed people in New
York.
It was Becca.
Stan like that wasn't on the travel ban.
Like the,
I mean,
I understand trying to create a filter
that keeps bad people out.
Of course,
every country does that just didn't
understand this specific logic of those
countries on the list.
That made no sense to me.
No.
It made no sense to anybody.
And it's also,
you're assuming that everybody in these
areas is bad,
including the people that try and escape
that sounds.
That sounds insane.
And that sounds.
It's just,
it's cruel and anti human to not want
people to have a chance.
I'm not saying don't vet these people
out.
Don't interview them and communicate
with them and find out what their
backgrounds are.
As much information as you can get you,
of course you are you concerned because
this is something that has been
bothering me.
I was concerned about my own reaction to
yesterday's mass shooting that I was
almost nonchalant about it.
I was like,
well,
there's another one like that.
We're getting numb
to mass shooting.
You know,
I ask myself two questions and it didn't
mean to ask them and I'm just being
honest and telling people this.
I asked myself,
I wonder if it was a white church or a
black church.
And I asked myself,
I wonder if the attacker wasn't Islamic
radical and a foreigner or was he a
homegrown American?
I assumed it was a.
He obviously.
Yeah.
Um,
and I don't even know what that says,
what those questions say about me or
about the country.
But it's really interesting.
Those are the first things I asked and I
didn't like.
I didn't like that.
Those questions came to my mind so
quickly.
There was something about it that didn't
feel good and they're very obvious
questions to ask.
I mean,
you know,
it's clear that those are very important
things to know.
But I didn't like that it came to me so
quickly.
Yeah,
I am.
It's the exact same questions,
but I also felt like it's just,
these are patterns.
They're inescapable patterns,
whether it's the Vegas massacre or this
one or the Orlando shootings.
It's always a man and a.
is it a Muslim or is it a crazy white
guy?
Well,
you know,
in tribe I write about mass shootings
are a very particular thing.
I mean there's gang shootings in Chicago
or whatever that may have a kind of
logic to them.
Right?
Like you're controlling turf.
There's money involved.
Drugs would.
Yeah,
it makes sense.
So,
so you,
a bunch of innocent people get shot.
That's the price you pay for gang wars.
There's a logic to it.
There is mass shootings are completely
nihilistic,
right?
It's someone killing as many people that
he doesn't know right as possible before
he dies.
It's totally nihilistic.
And what I found,
and I did a lot of research into it,
that,
that those kinds of mass shootings
typically happen in middle class
communities like otherwise safe middle
class communities or small low crime
Christian communities,
they have never happened in the inner
city even literally never happened.
Um,
they,
they happen in communities that are
otherwise very safe,
very Christian,
very,
um,
boring frankly.
Um,
and it really made me wonder like,
is there,
I mean,
lots of countries have as many guns as
we do.
Every country has crazy people in it,
in them,
right?
We are the only that does this to
ourselves.
And we do it only in a certain kind of
community,
right?
We're doesn't happen in high crime,
low income communities,
right?
It happens in the most sort of like
small,
quiet,
Christian,
low crime,
bland,
suburban or rural communities.
That's where it happens.
Uh,
what does it say?
Why is it that these communities are not
producing crazy people?
But somehow those people come to a place
where they think this is a good thing to
do.
Like,
why is that happening?
My theory is that the deep alienation of
the suburbs of sort of small town
America,
the law,
the lack of real community effort,
um,
and the lack of national unity and the
Pa,
I mean the,
the mass killings have risen abruptly in
the last 15 years and I,
you know,
it's hard for me,
it's,
you don't murder people in your own
community when that happens.
It means the community doesn't exist,
at least for the murderer.
And
do you see any connection or do you
consider any connection between psych
drugs?
I mean,
I don't know how many of these people
are on psych drug
a tremendous amount.
Like there was a study that,
uh,
that see if you could find it,
Jamie.
They connected all the mass shootings
that have happened over the last two
decades with all the different
medications that people are on and every
single one of them was on something or
was withdrawing from.
Okay.
So there's,
here's the question,
where are the drugs creating the
behavior or the drugs?
Treating a mental disorder that is self
is tied to the behavior.
Very good question,
right?
I mean there's,
there's no way to know mass shootings of
the nihilistic sort that I'm referring
to started abrupt abruptly rose in the
eighties.
Okay.
Um,
and then doubled since 2006 and I think
they're increasing even more since that.
So
mass shooting over the last 20 years has
one thing in common and isn't guns.
Yeah.
This is
right.
But that's not,
that's not just positive.
Right.
You know what I mean?
Like it's,
you're right.
It's not.
Correlation doesn't mean it couldn't be
dishing.
It could be the depression is rising in
alienated communities and the depression
is getting treated,
unsuccessfully treated with drugs.
All these people were on drugs.
But really what's happening is that,
and this is true suicide,
depression,
ptsd,
anxiety,
alienation,
all of these things are going up in
society and that's just statistically
unquestionably.
The question that I would have about
this though is that when I've talked to
psyche,
a psychiatrist about it,
they say that the dissociative aspect of
the psychiatric medications that are
part of the problems that people do not
feel,
they don't feel the connection even to
their actions,
that they can do something horrific like
shoot people and they might be even
doing that to try to get some feeling.
Listen,
that's totally possible.
I would also offer this idea
that the massive national addiction to
violent video games is a dissociated
experience.
You're shooting people,
they're not real people.
That doesn't happen.
You know?
I mean,
I'm just are connected somehow.
I don't know,
but I'm just saying what you just
described happening in the streets of
America is exactly duplicated digitally
in video games.
Right?
But the video games doesn't.
It doesn't keep you from feeling things
in the real world where the psych
medications do.
Right,
but did the experience of shooting at
human targets that aren't real.
Right?
If you incorporate that into how you
feel about shooting and then you go out
into the real world,
it may not be that hard to particularly
with the age of eight of psych drugs,
drugs and whatever.
Depression is sort of endemic in this
society right now.
It might not be hard to.
To transpose that dissociated experience
in a video game with digital images
transpose it onto actual humans in the
real world if you're sufficiently
disturbed.
That's a very good connection and an
interesting question because I haven't
heard it a discussed when they're
talking about war and how kids that grow
up playing call of duty and things along
those lines,
they get really good at.
It would be actually better in combat.
They would have the tactics mapped out
in their mind better.
Yeah,
yeah,
absolutely.
Absolutely.
I mean,
look,
there's a TV program called active
shooter,
right?
Like and they go back.
I've just heard about it.
I haven't seen it.
I would never watch it,
but it's,
it's they go back and recreate.
They re interview everyone who's
survived active shooting incident and
recreate it and now people watch for.
I mean,
in some sense,
entertainment,
right?
TV is entertainment.
They watch for entertainment,
recreations of acting,
shooting incidents that are,
I think partly the result of the kind of
deep alienation that happens in a,
an immediate obsessed society that
we're,
no one's talking to each other.
You know what I mean?
It's a perfect circle,
right?
Like,
well,
they're definitely escalating,
right?
I mean we had the event in New York
where the guy runs over all those people
and then a couple of days later or
having the one in taxes.
So this is,
this is happening over the scale of one
of the year,
one every few years.
We're getting a once a week.
Well,
yeah,
and what's interesting,
I mean in New York there was an ideology
behind it,
so it wasn't nihilistic.
I mean it felt nihilistic to us,
but to that guy,
he actually believed in what he was
doing,
but the real mass shooters that they're
just out there to kill as many people as
possible.
It's hard to know what the ideology is.
Well,
this guy was dishonorably discharged
from the military for something.
I forget what it was.
So he was in a position,
what's up?
It was a abuse on his spouse and child.
Right.
And he didn't have a license to own a
gun,
but you know,
he owns whatever guns did he had.
He got them illegally in Colorado where
he drove to Colorado.
That's what I heard.
He got,
it was in Texas.
I think he got them into Colorado.
Did he get them at a gun show or
something like that?
I don't know where I go,
but yeah,
I mean we're looking at little tiny
details.
The real question is how the fuck does a
person do something like that?
I mean shot babies,
you know what I mean?
Shot five-year-olds and
the whole thing is just.
It doesn't even make sense.
And I don't know if he was on a psych
medication or if they know he was,
but you know,
just the staggering numbers of broken
individuals that are committing these
crimes.
It's just very,
very confusing.
And you think that it's tied to what was
what you were saying too,
about communities about inner cities
where you have impoverished high crime
areas,
but they're not seeing these things.
Do you think because in these high crime
communities are dealing with much more
life and death and the struggles much
more real,
that they feel more connected?
I.
This is totally a theory.
I mean I have no idea.
It's just the truth is that those awful
sort of school shootings and mass
shootings in the streets have never
happened in a high crime,
high crime neighborhood,
and so one has to wonder what is it?
It's possible that for all their very
real stresses and traumas of poverty,
that for all of those things,
there is also more face to face communal
connection in poor neighborhoods than in
wealthy neighborhoods or in middle class
neighborhoods and that,
that communal connection.
I mean literally meeting people in the
landing of your apartment building,
right?
Meaning people in the door,
stoop on the street,
you know,
with that,
those kinds of human interactions even
at even in a,
in an economically stressed
neighborhood,
that those create enough of a sense of
community that people who might
otherwise go crazy and turn their guns
in this nihilistic weigh on people,
on innocent people that they just don't
do it.
Because why would I do that to my own
people?
That's the and what I fear in this
country is that we're losing the sense
of what our own people are,
what are our own people and if you're
doing that in the streets of the
neighboring town,
like,
you know,
clearly there's been some loss of like
some idea of what,
what we belong to and that's where,
you know,
national service or a congressional
commission that really calls out
rhetoric that that undermines our sense
of who we are as a nation.
Like you know,
it might start at the top changing.
That might start at the top.
It might help.
Do you think there's any
incentive that the,
these people experience to be someone
who creates this big event where
everybody has to
get them?
I mean,
I,
I don't,
I mean I'm guessing,
but I'm a,
I'm imagining that someone like that
feels powerless and insignificant and
abused by society and at least there'll
be famous in their last acts and their
death.
They're going to cause a lot of
reaction.
They're going to.
They're like,
oh you,
you messed with me my whole life.
At least for the last five minutes about
my life.
You guys are the ones that are going to
be scared.
You're going to be begging me for mercy.
No,
I begged you for mercy my whole life.
Now you're going to be begging me for
mercy.
I mean,
I'm totally guessing,
right?
I'm just riffing here,
but I,
I wouldn't be surprised if there was
something of that to it.
It's a good gas.
I mean this has been a very common
conversation lately as to whether or not
you discussed these people and even
bring up their names.
I know in some places and some even
media outlets,
they don't want to report on the person.
Individual is creating this chaos.
Well,
you know,
one of the things I think is a problem
is that if you love this country,
there is a certain pressure to think
it's the best possible country ever.
Right?
Yeah.
And I think it's very painful for
Americans to actually look at the actual
statistics and say,
you know,
for example,
with mass shootings,
we were the only country that does this
to ourselves.
The only one.
There's not another country that has not
at the rate that we do in China.
They were,
you know,
there's a rash of knife attacks.
Right.
I mean,
I'm just not that it doesn't happen at
all,
but if you really look over the last 20
years is more than that.
Since the eighties when this shit
started.
Like we're the only country that does
this regularly to ourselves.
It regularly to the point where it's
like every month practically.
Right,
right.
So it's,
it's a sign.
I mean,
if your child was acting out in a
violent way and punching kids in the
playground,
you think,
okay,
he's in pain.
Right?
He's acting out like,
what's wrong with this kid?
Like he's clearly in pain and some kind
of pain and he's lashing out.
Well the society is in some kind of
pain,
like,
what is it you know,
and you,
you know,
you can just miss me as a bleeding heart
liberal,
you know,
whatever.
I don't mean you.
But one could dismiss me as a bleeding
heart liberal.
Like,
okay,
well then what's your,
what's your question?
That my question is what,
what,
why are we in so much pain?
Right.
That's the question that I think might
begin to lead to an answer of why
there's such high suicide rates in such
a wealthy society.
Why there's mass killing,
you know,
that would begin to answer those
questions.
If you don't like that question.
What's your question?
To answer those terrible tragedies.
Well,
what you're saying is very compelling.
Uh,
and it's,
it's an aspect of this that I don't
think is being considered.
And I think your book is very important
when it comes to that.
I think the questions that you raise and
the,
all the,
the various examples that you give
there,
it's really food for thought and I don't
think it's being discussed in very many
other circles.
It's everyone's looking at the
psychiatric drugs.
Everyone's looking at the white men with
guns and the gun problem,
the NRA and all these various aspects.
They're not looking at the root cause of
this depression,
anxiety and this detachment that we have
from our neighbors and our community.
Look,
I mean Somalia has got a lot more guns
than we do,
right?
And there's plenty of violence in
Somalia,
but no one's walking down the streets of
their own neighborhood,
massacring their own people.
Only we do that.
And what is,
you know,
in a,
in a sense,
it's a call to a cry for help by our
society,
like,
uh,
not by that person.
I'm saying generally the phenomenon
within our society is I kind of cry for
help.
Like we are.
Something is wrong psychically,
spiritually wrong.
Christians will say we're not a
Christian enough country,
but,
uh,
you know,
like,
that's,
uh,
that's not true.
That's not the problem right there.
There are um,
peaceful Muslim societies and very
violent Christian woods and you can
correlate it with Christianity.
Um,
I think the one thing you can,
there are democracy.
There were their oppressive societies
are very low violence and their full
democracies like us,
we lots of violence.
So it's not the democratic system,
right?
Like what is it in my guests and it's
only a guest.
My guest is that a certain amount of the
high suicide rates,
high depression,
anxiety,
drug addiction,
porn addiction,
child abuse,
mass shootings and shootings in the
streets.
My guess is that the common denominator
in all those things is the true
catastrophic lack of communal connection
that many Americans experience.
Well,
it's,
it's a very compelling argument.
It's a very compelling point that again,
I don't see being discussed in very many
other areas and I really appreciate it,
man.
I really appreciate your book.
I think it's great and,
uh,
I really suggest anybody's interested in
the subject.
Please go read it.
Tribe Sebastian younger.
Thank you brother.
Appreciate it man.
I really enjoyed it.
Thank you very much.
Anytime.
Come by.
Alright,
thanks everybody.
Awesome.