Three,
two,
one.
I'm gonna.
Do what you're doing.
What are you doing over there,
man?
What is this?
Well,
actually I was thinking about making
sure that I'm in a position mentally and
spiritually to talk openly and clearly
connect,
but you're doing it with fists on
interest.
You're going to talk openly,
but you're going to be strong about it.
It's not like this.
There's this thing that the meditation
thing where you're just gently touching
your fingers together.
Yeah,
right.
I suppose then I'm looking to be
embodied as well.
Tense.
You're like a hybrid.
Yeah,
that's right.
That's what we've got become these days.
A little bit of both.
A little bit of spiritual,
a little bit of warrior,
the whole thing.
We've got to survive in this world,
so you can't be all the theories.
Can't be.
It can't all be in the consciousness.
Yeah.
Otherwise you'll never get anything
done.
Right.
You'll just be constantly dealing with
other people's wants and wishes and no.
Unless you going to make the decision to
be one of those cave people unless you.
Because last time I was thinking about
that,
like this,
put on robes,
meditate.
I that I only live in the consciousness,
but given my extreme levels of
attachment that I've experienced over
the years to physical things,
I don't think that's my path.
You know,
I'm here,
I'm in the world,
I'm sending books,
I'm having a baby or caring about what
people think about me.
I'm wondering if I'm going to be in a
film.
I'm dealing with the world,
being a man in the world,
being the type of man I am.
It's not like,
oh,
you know,
I'll just real life myself off in a
cave.
Well,
there's a certain amount of attraction
that I think we all have this idea like,
hey man,
I'm just going to get away from it all.
But the problem is you,
it's going on whether you like it or
not,
it's happening.
Even if you're not there.
So you should probably be there just to
go,
what is this?
Yeah,
Even in Christianity,
Christ says in the world,
but not of it.
So trying not to be defined and
determined by other people's opinions of
you,
the systems and structures that are set
up around you,
particularly if you question those
systems and structures and think,
well,
I don't trust that system.
I agree with that,
you know,
just having how you don't want to be
defined by that.
But the fact is we are here and I think
there are certain people you know,
but do have a monastic tendency that
should be meditating,
that aren't equipped for the material
world.
And one of the great things that make me
sad about at times is if you don't have
economic and productive value,
then you are nobody.
You know?
And there were some people that don't
know how to resource themselves.
You've found a way of turning yourself
into an economy of creating a kingdom.
I found my own way.
If I can make my mental illness work for
me,
people me money,
it'd be this crazy,
you know,
but not everyone gets those kinds of
breaks or has that kind of skillset.
Yeah,
I mean obviously there's some people
that really do thrive on that monastic
lifestyle does.
Have you ever seen
this,
a vice documentary on this guy?
His name is [inaudible].
He lives in the believers that eastern
part of the,
uh,
of Alaska.
He's in this,
uh,
this Arctic region.
It's a,
there's a,
a vice piece called Heimos Arctic
adventure.
That's it.
Arctic refuge.
Hi Mo.
H e I,
m o heimos high malkuth is his name and
this guy is a very.
HE lIves in the elastic arctic national
wildlife refuge,
100 miles from tHe nearest human and he
lives there with his wife and he lives
in this little log house that he's sort
of built himself and he thrives up
there.
It's very strange because we're,
we're attracted to these people like to
just go,
okay,
wHat do you do all day,
man,
like,
what's,
what's your life like and what do you
do?
Do you miss people?
And he has like a vcr and he plays old
movies and it's a fascinating thing
because I think when you watch soMeone
like that,
you always run it through your head.
Like,
could I live like that?
is this,
got happier?
And he says he is.
I mean,
he says that the,
the hunter gatherer lifestyle that he
lives is a uniquely attractive to people
and,
and uniquely satisfying and it's
something that we don't get in our
everyday world,
so we're never like completely even.
Whereas he is just running around
fishing and hunting caribou and stuff,
we're fitting in with someone's else's
idea of what life should be.
The system within which most of us
operate is not this.
What I would do if,
if I had to free star,
you know,
I don't mean just personally me,
russell,
I mean anthropologically yeah.
We're designed to be nabad nomadic
tribes people.
When my podcast,
as I said gestion by you,
I had on as a guest,
yuval noah harari,
he wrote that book sapiens and he does a
lot of anthropology stuff and says about
like that,
you know,
look,
we're designed to live in tribes of
about 75 to 100 people,
or at least that's what chimpanzees do
when they get bigger.
THere's normally a conflict and a
separation and a split in that nomadic
tribes would follow the food sources
that were available to them.
so in a way,
if you can replicate that or get close
to that in some way of your own,
in your own life,
it would make sense that it would make
you happy.
And we're like,
when you were saying that about the guy
is a hundred miles away from the nearest
person I fought people,
there's people that live in suburbia
that mentally or 100 miles away from the
nearest person that you're just really.
Your life is.
You sit in front of a screen,
you don't connect with.
People hAve not spoke to people for
days.
You know,
I think about this when people make
these desperate attempts to connect
through dog in his finger in my country
where people meet up in labels and just
having anonymous sex masturbating in
public dogging.
It's a uniquely british for nominal
dogging.
That's where I heard of this.
Well welcome,
welcome to britain docking is people go
la bise quite buyers and it still could
be sort of suburban is a bit like
swinging,
you know,
but it's like you pull up in a car with
this isn't.
This is.
I've never done this.
I'm just clarifying.
You put up in a car with a partner,
it could be,
you know,
I think it's kind of heterosexual thing
or home that you can do it wherever you
know,
wherever your persuasion is.
This particular place of particular
people and you know the lights go on and
people jerk off and you know you can
have sex and so thinking these are
desperate attempt to find some
connection to nature to sort of drop
anchor and hit your prime or self to get
into who you are because you wake up and
you've got to do your job and you've got
a screen in front of you and you're a
consumer and you're not living in the
world anymore.
You want some visceral experience.
One of the things I get from these New
York guys,
he's like,
oh,
your person.
That's questing after with the whether
it's the artery or the dmt,
looking for what is it that we're meant
to be as humans and I'm doing that in my
own way.
Having unfortunately written off
substances because my stupid stupid
mistakes in my twenties.
I can't go into the dmt iowaska world's
much as I would like to and like I want
to find how is it that I be me in this
world and yeah,
I don't think it is through isolation
isn't.
I don't think it's like,
right,
I'm going to try and get an island and
I'm not going to participate.
I think it's like write what you know.
We are nature.
We created this.
This is a form of nature.
Our civilizations are manifestations,
but is it the best we can do?
Can we change it?
Can we pull back from what seems more
than ever like some kind of apocalypse
with your current president?
No disrespect them with our country
breakfast of sort of like a weird time
of fracture and the manifestation of
ugliness stuff bubbling up.
Affiliate like dark unconscious matter.
Bubbling up,
man.
I was in the airport traveling to here
and I was in New York and like just the
people that are working the lines.
When you put your cases through that
people felt seem heavy and low and like,
because if you're british Donald Trump,
just something that you know,
you kind of make jokes about,
you hope that there isn't going to be a
nuclear war,
but he seems like a sort of a comic
figure,
but here I sort of sent,
oh,
there's pain now.
I know there's a lot of people that
obviously liked him enough to have made
him president of United States,
but I think even in those cases he
speaks to a particular rage.
Something that wasn't being addressed.
The failure of neoliberalism that lies
of the last 30 years of a kind of
politics that was just about management
and not about giving people truth.
I don't know joe.
I like,
you know,
like our individual journeys.
How can our individual journeys,
informal social and tribal journeys now
national journeys and he's ever even
hope anymore for such a thing as United
States of America or great britain.
Or should we start looking at smaller
projects?
Because you know,
if the United States of America and
great britain leads the colonialism,
mass capitalism,
consumerism,
ecological meltdown.
If that's what you believe in,
then maybe we need to look at breaking
down some of these great institutions.
I wonder if what's going on is that our
biology and what we've been sort of
programmed to for the thousands of years
of living these tribal existences where
in these travel existence where you had
the small groups of 50 to 60 or 100
people plus that this is the new thing
and that part of our chaos is are trying
to adapt to the new thing.
It's almost inevitable.
We've created this incredible way where
we can get food to people so more people
had babies,
more people stayed in these areas where
they're not growing food and then you
have.
You're dealing with these massive
numbers of people you know,
in la 20 plus million and we're trying
to figure out like how do we get along?
Like how do all these different
ideologies coincide?
How do,
how do we,
how do we cooperate?
How do we,
how do we figure out what to do with all
our waste?
I don't figure out what to do with what
we're doing to the environment.
You know,
how do we figure out who's right,
you know,
is it is a the doom and gloom people
correct or that we're going to be okay
people correct.
You know,
and what's,
what's the right attitude to take about
this?
Many of those significant movements that
you're talking about,
agriculture and industrialization and
urbanization,
agriculture obviously meaning food
available on mass industrialization,
products available on mass urbanization,
people living together en masse.
None of these things are good for the
people on mass.
They're good for a select straw of
people that primarily benefit.
You know,
like the app,
they say that the average diet of human
being got worse after agriculture before
that varied diet.
People with loads of stuff after I coach
her urine,
potatoes,
now peasant,
you're on rice now,
peasants,
I think each of these movements are to
benefit a particular aspect of the
system of particular class,
a particular structure,
a particular economic class,
and you know me and you ain't doing bad.
We have relatively near the top,
but we're not the engineers.
It.
There are corporations and elites to use
that very popular word these days that
benefit from things being like this.
I don't.
When you're saying is there a way that
we can all coalesce and get along in
urban conurbations are 20 million
people?
No,
because the power is to centralized.
Don't break down.
Mostly we are getting along maybe
mostly.
Mostly.
Mostly we are getting along in these
weird groups and even with our whatever
static that we have with each other.
Even with the weird weirdness of it all
the diffusion of responsibility that
comes with these gigantic groups and you
see things happening,
you just get away from them.
We still for the most part of getting
along in this weird new world,
I think you'll write it in a sense,
joe,
like I'm not.
I'm not a demon,
clean guy.
I think human beings really,
really beautiful and brilliant and like
I don't feel like,
oh god,
this is such a mess.
what I think is is that we're trying to
inhabit systems that are not designed
for us to live within and I think that
yeah,
people are getting on,
but I also think that there's a lot of
tension in cities that everyone's one
right turn or one traffic light away
from getting out of their car and
smashing someone in the face.
You could like feel it bubbling under in
that,
in that the feeling I had in the airport
is that the people that were working
there were under undue stress.
Now,
this is just one anecdote,
but I feel that we're being forced to
live on a particular aspect of our
consciousness,
a particular bandwidth of where we kind
of a bit fry in the foot a little bit.
Too much desire and I'm talking about
most people.
We're again,
I'm not poor no more so I'm able to
create money.
Creates distance.
Isn't it?
Money's like you can fuck off problems.
I'm getting in a nice car and I'm out of
here,
but like I remember the feeling and a
lot of people are living like that where
the tensions up in their face and so
yes,
I agree that people do muddle along and
that's I think shows you that we're not
as in a darwinistic model or or or some
of the ideas derived from darwinism
rather like the selfish gene and the
richard dawkins idea that people just
want to survive and we just want to kill
him.
Fucking with.
This is what propels us forward.
I think.
No,
we're coke.
We're cooperative,
collaborative,
artistic,
imaginative,
beautiful people,
but we've created systems around the
worst aspects of our nature.
Greed,
selfishness.
This is what capitalism and consumerism
on and this is so all encompassing.
Our cultures are domed by them and we
can't see beyond them.
We exist within them and I feel like if
we were to break down those kinds of
systems,
live in smaller assemblies,
smaller groups where power is as close
to the people that affects as possible,
where people would vote on,
well,
this is how we want to use our
resources.
This is where we want to run our street,
our hospital,
our prisons,
our schools,
our systems.
This is how we want them to run.
Then things which really,
really slow down,
but man,
what's the rush into things would slow
down and get a lot slower,
but I think that people would be
empowered and you wouldn't have
resources and power filtered to a small
group of people.
No,
I think you're definitely right and I
think you should probably start a cult
idea about how to run it and how to keep
so the resources in the community,
but I think that also this discontent
that we have is a sign that people being
upset with how this is and the momentum
of the way things have sort of
established themselves today.
That we is what we need.
This is the momentum and the motivation
that we need to try to improve upon
things.
I think we're uniquely qualified to do
that today because we're.
We're talking about it so you can be the
doom and gloom guy today.
I'll be rose colored glasses,
so I think that this tension that we
have in this,
even like a guy like Donald Trump or
brexit,
I think the good thing about those
things is that people are looking at
what they don't like about the way we
were running the world,
what they don't like about our culture
and they're getting upset about it and
hopefully we'll sort it out that way and
that being completely content with
everything and everybody just sitting on
the couch and smiling all day.
It doesn't lead to necessarily lead to
progress.
I think we're more informed now than
we've ever been before,
so I would hope that with our ability to
communicate and being more informed now
that we have the potential to move
towards a better society.
I agree with that,
but I also think that that was important
in the world is who has power,
power being the ability to affect
change.
I,
I'm not one of those people that are
like,
I'm not like baffled by what happened
with trump.
I feel,
oh,
there's an indication that a good many
people feel extremely angry and
disenfranchised the same as brexit and
our country and I recognize and
understand it similarly.
I don't think,
oh,
wouldn't everything be zippity doo dah.
If hillary clinton was president of the
United States,
that was where the way stuff was going.
That's what the previous 30 years has
been like in your country.
My country,
managerial politicians with no vision.
We've seen the failure of recent sort of
that they've kind of promises that were
offered by an administrations recently.
I think that what trump is,
what brexit is,
is a big fuck you to the system like we
want something different,
but for me,
in a way these things are good because I
believe that people that fill those
things are right and I would like to see
more power delivered to ordinary people.
Genuine change happening now,
but I think it won't happen unless you
sort of look at,
well,
what,
where is the power?
Really the power really is with people
that this system works for a sort of a
particular corporate elite,
a particular straw.
I Don't know.
Politicians and bureaucrats and I hope
that what the sort of cataclysms of
recent recent news lead to is devolution
of power new systems because even in the
time that I've been in the country on
this trip,
joe,
you know,
there'd been that mad sort of massacre
that it sort of for me is it,
and this tells me that this is a sick
society,
not,
not.
Oh,
and britain's wonderful of course,
you know,
we went round plundering the world
crazy,
crazy.
We've got enough problems with our own,
but like for me,
what is causing this?
Why is this hAppening?
You know,
for me,
I don't see it in isolation.
I don't believe in lone wolf.
I think the system is coughing up these
events and there are patterns and
there's things that we can read and
there are things that we can change to
improve it.
Certainly a part of the guy that was
that shooter was certainly a part of our
society.
Right?
So if we have a set culture,
you know,
I mean there's,
there's eVidenCe of it.
I mean,
is it not,
it's not a completely set cultuRe.
I mean,
we don't.
We're not all dying,
right?
We're not all,
we don't have all have this disease,
but some of us most certainly do.
So this thing that you're saying like
that people looked at Donald Trump as a
big fuck you to system the tipping over
the apple cart.
I think that's absolutely what people
were hoping for.
And then there's a bunch of people that
just love saying,
fuck you.
There's a bunch of people that went,
fuck you is flying around.
Yeah,
fuck you.
They just get in it.
Fuck you.
And then you're seeing a lot of that
with Donald Trump supporters as well.
You're seeing people that they're
looking for some excitement,
they're looking for some fun.
You're looking,
you're seeing people that enjoy chaos.
You know,
maybe they're trapped in cubicles and
they're just completely frustrated by
this fucking grind day to day grind.
Like literally being their soul,
being ground down a cheese grater every
day,
being forced to stay under these
fluorescent lights and it was fucking
small little box dealing with human
resources in the corporate environment
and they're going fucking crazy and
anything that happens that,
that tips that over.
It's all fight club,
right?
They're just going to get punched in the
face.
They're looking to go crazy.
Then there's a lot of that as well,
you know,
but I think this chaos,
the worst parts about it,
there's no good too,
right?
There's no good to mass
shootings,
but what comes out of all these things
is the discussions and the intense
realization that we have real problems
with real problems with the way we're
communicating with each other and I
don't necessarily know if the solution.
I mean it would certainly be a solution
for those Involved.
If you get 100 amazing people and
everybody just starts a co op and Maine
somewhere.
I mean,
yeah,
it'd be great for those involved.
But for,
for all of us,
I mean even while that,
I mean it's almost like the monastic
lifestyle we're talking about.
If everybody just isolates,
it's all going on around you.
If you put your phone in a drawer and
never use it again and you stay off the
grid and you get your water from a
spring,
all those people out there still
drinking water with antidepressants in
it and there's a bunch of fucking small
and the people have to deal with.
There's a bunch of problems with
hurricanes now because the water's
warmer.
It's inevitable.
it's inevitable that this is all you can
decide,
hey man,
I only have 100 years in this planet
fund this.
I'm just going to ride this out.
But if you do make a kid and you have,
and I've got a bunch of them.
I mean you would see what's gonna happen
to them.
You know what?
We have to think about what happens with
them as well were we're all this global
community.
Really?
Yes,
we are,
and that's why I don't go for the head
dominique lifestyle of our fucking.
I've got a century.
let's line up some blowjobs.
I tried that route and that fellow john,
let's get a century worth of pillow
tops.
Line up some blow jobs,
ice cream here,
brother Joe Cook because I like you
believe in the possibility of change and
I've been like,
again,
I mentioned it again.
I started a podcast because you said,
you know,
cost and he's.
He's good fun.
Now.
What I do on mine is I get like a
because I'm doing a university degree,
religion and global politics.
In fact this thing happened.
What happened to me really is I hit full
on a full right now I know a bunch of
things on it.
Gonna work,
the ice cream,
the blow jobs,
the attention,
the privilege,
heroin,
crack,
all these things.
I control.
Cough is not working.
I can't control them.
I've got to find a way through this.
Oddly peculiarly it's a sort of a
personal version of spirituality.
Yeah,
that's what I've found.
William blake,
the great english poet says each artist
must find his own religion.
We have to find our own way.
What works for you is not going to be
the same as what works for me.
You know,
there are ways that we're coLlective,
but there are ways where we are
individually.
So fulbright are going to have to
educate myself,
I'm going to have to do things that mean
something to me.
A big part of that was like write me and
doing,
you know,
in my own small,
fragile,
brittle way brazilian jujitsu go,
I've never done stuff like that before.
So go and live in your body being there
and go genesis,
jimmy marlow and giving them a drop
because all these guys are such big fans
of your show,
you know,
and I go there and I do sessions with
chris,
that titanium skeleton of a man that
twists me up and can cause paIn in ways.
That's what,
how was he even doing that?
And like when I try to do this stuff
back,
it doesn't work or it puts me in my body
in a different way.
Learning the history of the ideas that
we're in in religion.
The way that the,
the,
the distinction between politics and
religion is an sort of an imaginary
distinction.
When people talk about religious
violence versus secular violence,
they're saying their violence is a
rational and our violence is okay.
I've learned some amazing stuff in the
last few years.
I'm the and as a result of that,
the kind of guests I get on my podcast
like this guy,
can ross mate,
you'd love him on yours.
Actually,
he was a diplomat in the foreign service
around the time of the weapons of mass
destruction and nine slash 11.
He believed in the system.
He's like,
all he wanted was to work in the foreign
service.
He knew they were lying while it was
going on,
so he's like,
oh no.
This thing I believed in is not true.
Like he's being asked to participate in
it.
He come out of a foreign office and
believes that no centralized power can
ever work.
We have to have devolved power
assemblies.
Anarchism is the word,
and a key doesn't mean chaos.
Anarchy means devolve power to the
smallest possible groups that there's no
power between you and I and jamie,
that we're equal in here and we should
run the space according to what all of
us think is a group that hospitals,
schools,
or institutions,
community should be run on a democratic
basis.
You don't need to minimize the amount of
centralized or eight.
We need roads to be running,
needs to be some security and all those
kinds of things based will be minimized
where possible.
That's what this guy came away with and
he explained it real well to me and what
I liked the increasingly.
What I think is that when you talk about
that make the cheese grater on the soul,
that's the.
That's the phenomenon of the west,
you know,
that's what people in our countries are
going through is alienation is talked
about like in one of the things that
navigates taught me about marxism,
that marxist theory of the way that he
criticized and broke down capitalism,
how operates it weren't just talking
about the economics,
so mark's was a great economist.
He goes,
capitalism will lead to individuals
feeling worthless and meaningless
because they'll just be cogs in the
machine.
It will break people's spirits and that
is what's happened because people sell.
Not the only thing that's happened go
on.
It's also created incredible technology
and medical innovation,
all sorts of different ways that we can
make the world easier.
Do you think we could keep those things
without the cheese grater soulmate?
Because I think we couLd think we could
call the stuff now.
We could progress with it.
We could have different fare or ways of
doing that and people were like,
I think people sort of kill that
conversation too early because there's,
you know,
because it's working for the enough
people.
Yeah.
The throwing out the baby with the
bathwater.
I think so,
yeah.
That's what the whole thing of marxism
is the abandonment of capitalism and so
let's go this way,
but you know,
you look at what happened when people
adopted marxism and left the lead to the
death of millions and millions of people
as,
as capitalism and a lot of places we've
been all f's but it's not reported in
the same way,
but I'm not saying that we will want to
live in communist Russia or the soviet
union or China.
Terrible,
terrible things happened there,
but that's what we always.
We always revert to say,
well,
is there not?
Is it not possible thAt we could for
start?
They didn't do it properly.
They ignored it.
That's what everybody says,
but no one's ever done it properly.
I mean,
we have more freedom today.
Human beings have more freedom,
more freedom to behave,
more freedom to communicate,
more freedom to excel with this
capitalist society that we're
criticizing today than any human beings
that have ever lived,
ever.
There's a lot of negatIve about it.
One hundred percent,
but it's also.
There's a lot of benefits and positive
about it.
There were a lot of soulless people that
are just counting numbers and throwing
them on a hard drive somewhere and
buying yachts.
That's true too,
but that doesn't mean we shouldn't
continue to evolve and inspiring.
I don't think evolution is finished.
I know there's loads of good things
about capitalism buffing.
Let's carry on.
Let's see.
What we can do is could we be doing this
better or I believe that we could.
I believe that this has taken us about
as far as it could go because of certain
ecological imperatives in this spiritual
thing that you definitely mentioned that
it's destroying the souls of a lot of
people and it's not necessary.
When is that?
You know,
the war we were promised in the fifties
and the technological revolution will
mean you'll work.
I have an hour a day.
You know,
like they know when delivered on that
and people just went,
no,
actually you carry on fucking work in
and we'll siphon the profit up hill and
we could have leisure by societies buy.
I think that as long as there is a form
of centralized power,
people at the center of that power will
not share it.
I think you have to go,
all right,
this community is going to be run by
those people.
This community is going to be run by
those people and that also solves a lot
of the other problems that are defining
our times of people seem to want
different things.
Some people want to say absolutely no
homosexuality.
Some people say,
we want total sexual freedom.
Some people want,
we want to live in what would be called
a religious extreme way.
Some people say atheist,
well that can't exist under one banner.
I don't think any more problem with
people saying no.
Homosexuality is that they're deciding
about freedom.
The other people's freedoms to exist for
other people's freedoms to behave and to
express themselves the way they want to,
and the real problem with that is a lot
of the people that want to control other
people's freedom,
they really.
The reason why they're doing is they're
trying to suppress their own urges and
me.
Right.
One of the things I'm most interested in
is how much of our activity is
unconscious activity so much with doing
things.
We don't know why we're doing it.
The book here that I'm promoting
recovery,
I written this book is my version of the
12 steps,
but some of it last night we were in it.
Yeah.
The 12 steps is a is a journey from
unconsciousness to consciousness.
That's what essentially is unconsciously
pursue pleasure.
You unconsciously pursue patterns
because you don't know you're doing it
if you're a smack it or a crack head
like me.
Eventually it gets you into such
trouble.
You have to address it,
but most people hover along on the
cheese grater level lives of quiet
desperation,
never realizing,
wait a minute.
It is possible to be happy.
It is possible to be contented,
move towards nature,
you while yourself doing it,
you can run.
This is what I'm good at,
this is why I'm doing a note.
The way you run your life,
I know they will know and telling you
what to do.
You don't want to compromise.
You want to learn all of this
fascinating staff and fulfill yourself.
You don't want to be like,
so you've created a road for yourself to
do that,
but not everybody can and more people
could and I think there'll always be
resistance.
They'll always be corrupting because
it's in me like I don't,
I shouldn't spend another second
condemning Donald Trump because I've got
an arsenal in me.
I'm a greedy person that wants attention
and wants people to love me and buy my
book and take care of my interests.
You're introspective thinking has led
you to stop that path.
I mean that's,
that's essentially
you.
You saw the flaws and hedonistic
behavior and you hit the pause button
you thinking about and that's very
attractive to people because we all see
that in ourselves.
You know?
And when you talk about like what what I
do and what I've done,
the most important thing that I've ever
done is surround myself with people that
I love.
Like I've a really good group of friends
and interesting people and that that
leads to more like they find more
interesting people.
It branches out and spreads out and then
people listening to this,
they become like minded.
They pursue their happiness,
they pursue their,
their actual desires,
what,
what interests them,
like what,
what,
what they would like to do for their,
for their career,
for their life,
for their,
their craft.
Like what do you enjoy?
Like find that thing.
Surround yourself with likeminded
people.
And I think we all get fuel from the
people that were around and it's one of
the most underrated aspects of being a
person in a community is if you're
around a bunch of ambitious people who
are creative,
who are open minded and honest,
you are inspired by that and you seek to
have like likeminded thought.
Yeah,
you're right about that.
I think that's another one in the
column,
the against column for disappearing into
the cave.
And being an hmi or a monkey or
whatever,
because I heard someone say,
we exist in dialectic,
which means we exist in relationship and
conversation with one another.
Who are you without other people?
You'll nobody in it in an aluminium
capsule floating through space.
What does your personality match?
You know,
so you're right about that,
you know,
that we exist in these relationships
with one another.
And I suppose what I have sought out is
to connect with people on the level of
the damage,
on the level of the wound,
on the level of the vulnerability.
Knowing a pessimistic that's,
you know,
ring ourselves out into the gut away.
No,
that's recognized that we're flawed,
but that together we can create
supportive,
compassionate,
loving communities.
And for me,
the,
the stein point for that is a life that
is predicated on spirituality as opposed
to materialism predicated on what my
consciousness does.
When I stopped thinking what my
consciousness does when I meditate,
now I don't have the advantage of the
dmt experiences in the ios got
fascinated by it,
listened to it.
She tried kundalini because you do that
well.
Have you ever had any sort of
psychedelic experience through doing
kundalini because the people that I know
that are really into it,
they say that they can achieve people
that I know that I've done dmt.
I'll say they can achieve the same sort
of states.
Wow.
With kundalini.
Well,
they're doing it well.
Kundalini is one of the things I believe
in this particular toe at my finger by
mark mahoney of shamrock tattoos,
los angeles.
He's the kundalini serpent as drawn by
called young one of the great early
figures of psychoanalysis,
but the fire in the belly,
the animal energy of survival,
the energy of creativity,
the serpent energy,
the reptile energy that's deep in our
dna.
When we were listened to,
when we were creatures that crawled on
our belly and lives in a still can be
the serpent,
the snake within can become crowned.
It can become royal.
Your animal desires can become royal,
and I think that the kundalini as I
understand it,
is about harnessing those energies,
bringing it up.
I'd do like a yoga and I have.
I do have pretty tripped how experiences
where I feel like,
oh my god,
I'm awake,
but I am not me.
I am not my thoughts.
I feel this sense of transcendence 90
fold them retrospectively.
You know,
in the moment there's no me to register
it.
It's only afterwards went,
wow,
I lost myself there.
Do you feel weird when you finger people
with that finger?
Because it does.
I know.
Don't send that snake in,
but to be honest,
fingerings are less significant.
My life finger is a very weird.
It seems so rude in the expression
fingering.
It's a dirty business.
It's not functional.
No,
there's no need for it in the adult
world,
but like it,
it's not for a lot of people love it.
People ask for it.
I say,
do not give them the snake combat
reptile.
Right over open.
The shark was,
is this the right moment to tell you?
I dreamt about you last night knowing
it's a risk always to tell someone that
you dreamt about them because once it's
out there,
it's out there.
So and particularly,
you know,
check it out.
So we were in this dream.
We're in some sort of semi organic
forest type world,
but they had an industrial component,
somewhat labyrinthian makers that
component like that as if you know,
like the,
he walks how they've made the most of
the woods,
you know,
to build little huts and stuff and maybe
they'll have a little.
I don't know if the walks have another
couple of thousand years,
maybe a little.
He was trained.
I don't know what they would have done.
Who knows?
They were lovely,
cuddly little guys.
So anyway,
there was a solvent.
It is small industrial component to it.
We were somewhere within that world and
we were doing brazilian jujitsu.
That's used the word rolling.
Now there was a sort of,
this is how we know is a dream cause
there was a moment where I had you
inside control.
Now from that moment I moved towards
choke and you did something where you
arched and flipped over.
Very acrobatic and very elegantly don't
even know if it's an actual move or not.
It was very,
very beautiful and a for ah,
right there.
This spa,
we're going quite well this rolling,
but it seems that joe rogan is better at
brazilian jujitsu than me,
but that even in the dream world that
seemed like something kaiden
understanding of,
well,
there's
so what's brilliant about it and what's
interesting about it is that the more
time you put into it,
the more you understand the moves,
the more moves you require,
the more moves you drill,
the better you get at it,
the more it's literally like a language
and that as your vocabulary increases
and your ability to like.
Even if your vocabulary is very broad,
if you don't talk a lot,
he'd probably have stumbling
conversations.
Right?
But if you get used to talking all the
time and you're having a conversation
with someone and the words kind of flow,
but if you're talking to someone and
they're weird and they bark out things
and they talk over you,
it's,
it's awkward.
And herky jerky,
much like jujitsu.
Jujitsu is almost like a Connecticut
language,
but there is a puzzle that's solved,
right?
And there's a problem,
And this person's.
the problem is this person is trying to
apply all these different techniques,
whether they're chokes or joint locks on
you and you are trying to both defend
that and then put it on.
You put yours on them.
It's beautiful.
I've heard you say before,
high pressure problem solving or mma.
I always describe as high level problem
solving with dire physical consequences.
Physical clickers,
mma is the most,
the most high level of all the problem
solving because there's the consequences
are so grave getting kicked in the head,
getting elbowed and kneed like those
things are so.
Jujitsu I think is better for you for
sure physically because the consequences
are not nearly as grave.
You get choked out,
you're fine.
You get your arm,
you know,
you tap out.
If your lungs,
you're,
you have.
As long as you're willing to tap out,
you have to be willing to tap.
Now you'll,
you'll get through it.
Okay,
and if you get injured,
you just get it fixed and take six
months off,
she'll be back.
I like that connect language thing you
said.
That really makes sense to me because I
feel like when I'm doing it,
I'm not going.
Hello?
Yeah.
Show me the way to the train door door.
People that are like punch me in the
right direction.
You go thousand ways.
Why exactly do you watch jujitsu?
It all online?
No,
I don't watch those,
but sometimes I look at videos of named
grace.
He's or something and they're effortless
capacities and charisma.
You should watch just because you're
enjoying it.
Watch like current top of the food
chain,
jujitsu guys like hoffa mendez,
you know,
watch some.
Marcello garcia watched some,
you know,
some of the young guys coming up.
Gary tone and it's fascinating to watch
them apply these new strategies to this
old language,
you know,
because that's really essentially what
it is.
I mean what you're seeing is these new
approaches.
Jujitsu is this never ending thing.
I mean it really just doesn't.
It doesn't.
The the like boxing,
although it's very complex and it
doesn't seem as complex to someone on
the outside,
but When you watch like a guy like floyd
mayweather or sugar ray leonard or
someone who's just a master at their
craft,
which you use see how complex it truly
is.
You see all the different,
the all the different nuances to it,
but it's still punching,
right?
There's just still too punching.
Whereas jujitsu is this fucking tangle
of bodies and possibilities and
potential.
There's so many different ways to
approach it.
There's people that are chokers.
There's people that are armed lock guys.
There's people that are.
They like to get you with their legs,
their triangle people,
and they all have their own little way
of approaching this conversation,
so you've learned a few sort of
grammatical pathways,
fruit that kinetic language and think,
right,
I'm going to mf that.
That particular area,
so watching videos online,
it's like watching a video of Alan Watts
talking.
You go,
oh,
okay.
TerenCe mckenna or timothy leary or
whoever it is that you think is
fascinating when you hear them talk and
it develops new pathways and
possibilities for your own thinking.
and it was one of the things I was gonna
say earlier though,
we,
when,
what I was thinking while we were having
this conversation about the future and
about possibilities and about
civilization that you,
with all due respect what you and I are
doing,
both of us were.
This is a very rudimentary way of trying
to figure this out.
I think were,
were,
were clubbing at it,
you know,
and I think people are listening to this
that will do a far better job than us in
the future.
Yeah.
And I think that that's important and I
think that we're doing our best,
you know,
we're taking our tests,
but when Henry Ford created the model t,
he didn't intend it to race against the
la ferrari.
You know,
he didn't know what the fuck a la
ferrari was,
but if he didn't make that model t the
la ferrari and wouldn't have been
possible.
But you can't go back and go,
Henry Ford fucking suck,
dude,
ride this piece of shit with its leaf
springs at stupid tires,
you know,
and then get into 2017 corvette zr one.
You go,
whoa,
okay,
this is where it's at now.
It's like all these things have to be in
place for the next evolution of it to
advance,
and I think we're,
we're looking at today with our society
is we're hoping that there's a solution
out there were the,
there is a solution,
but it's god damn slow.
Just like all evolution.
It's god damn slow.
It's faster than single celled organisms
to a giraffe,
but it's still fucking slow and we're a
part of it.
All of us,
not just you and I,
but the people that are listening to
this and the people that are having
their own podcasts,
their own conversations and doing ted
talks and writing books.
We're all apart of thinking this out and
these little pieces all fit together
slowly but surely and create this mosaic
of ideas and potential.
And what we're experiencing now is just
what we can experience in this realm.
Like in this world with this life that
we're currently stuck in and then
someone 50 years from now we'll be
looking back at our stumbling
conversation,
trying to figure out a way to engineer
society correctly and they'll have a
much better way of doing it.
I Think that's a very beautiful
progressive argument.
I agree with much of what you've said
except some adequate joe.
Even things I've heard on this podcast
say when you have graham hancock or a
particularly intuitive when you got them
more sanctioned academic guy on there
and they felt like,
you know,
you bastard.
You're the people that I love that
such a rebel,
you know,
it's,
it's fascinating to see these people
know,
attacking him for his ideas and his
research,
but now having less and less ground
stand on.
Graham's ideas had been more proven in
the last 10,
20 years than ever before the case.
Finding these new civilizations and
finding these new evidence that human
beings have existed on this continent
far longer and that they're traveling
all over the world for far longer and
the civilization,
it's probably quite a bit.
Okay.
Than we thought that's right,
and so we don't therefore know that this
idea of continual progression,
linear progression is the only one.
It is possible that when it comes to the
realm of consciousness,
ancient people knew something that we
are struggling to understand that and I,
I
recognize that your model t to ferrari
metaphor is a good one and actually
speaking to young people now,
I do feel that they're kind of more
switched on.
Geez,
look at a baby With an ipad.
It seems lIke they know already and,
and,
but what I feel is,
and this might just be my personal
narcissism,
but I like to think of myself as the
pinnacle of consciousness.
That there isn't some other realm.
Even though god,
I want that dmt so bad.
Like,
why are you afraid of that?
Because it's not.
It's not a like,
it's not an intoxicant because I'm a 12
step guy and I'm a sobriety shit.
Stop other 12 step that you're not going
to fuckIng book about that fucking
promote.
You're not going to fall slip addiction.
It's not this idea that you're going to
fall apart and become a junkie again.
It's not going to happen.
That part of her is that you can say
that joe,
but also a in an integral part of my
recovery is the idea of surrender and I
think that's an integral part of a lot
of spiritual beliefs and internal part
of dmt.
Yeah,
I feel you,
man,
but like to bypass the idea of my egoic
offer ship my egoic or flurry of I'm
russell and this is what I believe and
this is what I'm going to do.
I've surrendered to a way of life.
I've surrendered.
If I can find some people with 25,
thIrty years in recovery,
clean time that go.
You're allowed to take the empty.
I'm like fucking hammered a pipe.
You don't need there.
There isn't a face or they're
sanctioning.
Well,
in a way I learned by the way,
you don't even need dmt.
No.
You don't need it,
but you seem like you want it.
Yeah,
because I love the transcendent.
I love it because I've know and I've
always known that this experience of
being in a body,
in the conscious,
individualistic mind,
and remember I've taken loads of acid
when I was a kid as well.
I know that this is not all of it.
This is just we're just reading one
bandwidth of data with our century
instruments that there is limitless
consciousness and limitless reality.
Do you miss that asked experience?
Yes,
I do.
I.
I love it.
Is the concern that if you fell into it
like whether it was mushrooms or
whatever it is,
that if you fell into that experience
again,
that it would lead you in a downward
spiral of addiction in a sense.
It's that in a sense,
it's that and the fact is as well,
I've turned my life around or my life
has been turned around by this program,
by this system and like,
you know,
the,
the 12 seven,
it does have something in it.
That's quite what I want to say.
Like I said,
little bit.
Ascetic is a little thing like it's
about the nile,
Right?
Because,
but the reason that I've written this
book was an interpretation to 12 steps,
excuse me,
it's because I think it's a masterpiece
I think is a masterpiece at a time when
people are struggling with ideologies,
a tIme when people are struggling with
religion because the bad things about
religion is so obvious,
the bigotry and the violence,
those things are so clear to us even
though there are many,
many beautiful things about islam and
many beautiful things about christianity
are focused,
tends to turn on the bigotry and the
hatred that is present it or used out of
those ideologies.
The 12 steps is accessible to anybody
and can be used
as a code to unravel your connection to
your own individual experience,
your own self centerdness,
your own self obsession.
Now this might not be a problem that you
have that this might be the line that
separates us.
Me,
I'm self obsessed and I have the first
league like this is hoW it works.
One,
you admit there's something that you
want to change and like that could be
I'm a smack head,
pretty obvious then,
or you're a sex addict and that's a
harder thing to admit because it can be
rewarding if you're into adult human
females in a culture like I was,
but if he ultimately leaves you lonely
and unable to have a family and you feel
like you're having a negative emotional
effect on others and yourself,
then you need to admit it's a problem.
The secoNd thing is could your life be
better and the of course it could,
and the third thing is being willing to
accept help from others and whether
that's a community or from your
understanding of a higher power.
Now I happen to have,
I believe in god in the sense that I
believe that there's limitless
consciousness that my individual
consciousness is connected to something
that I can't understand,
that no one can ever understand.
And again,
as I've heard on one of my own podcast,
as a matter of fact,
yanis varoufakis who lived this
political movement in Greece.
He said,
we will never know whether consciousness
proceeded matter or matter,
proceeded consciousness and in a way
it's irrelevant now because spirit,
this quality is here.
It's here and it's a big pile of what
human beings are and it isn't dealt with
by consumerism and it isn't dealt with
by contemporary politics.
People don't talk about love,
kindness,
togetherness there,
but these are the dominant things in our
lives.
That's What's most important to me.
The people that I love,
like you said,
the connections with the people.
You have to become your reality,
but a political system that reduces you
to a component of an economic machine is
never going to fulfill you.
So what I now believe is that by what I
think this book and do is give people a
guide to reach in their own spiritual
truth because it's completely non
prescriptive.
It's like your version of god is going
to be different from mine.
Your personal inventory that you draw
up,
we will reveal the truths of the way you
see the world and the problems you've
made.
The communIties that you belong to will
support you and you can change your
patterns,
you can make amends for your past,
you can continue to stay present,
and a vital part of this program is
prayer and meditation,
continued connection to the moments you
don't lose yourself in your past or the
projections of your future.
Now,
whether or not that prohibits me from
experimenting with psychedelics in the
long term.
you know,
for me the jury's out because I do want
to.
And bill wilson,
the guy who founded these fellowships
was fascinated by asset and subsequent
like even when he was so bad,
it took a lot of acid and I think that
guy was a prophet.
He was on a mission.
He was trying to discover what is truth,
what is reality?
We discussed much in the 12 step program
though is because I think it's like most
things,
it becomes orthodox.
You know,
like most religions,
most systems in the end they become
orthodox and it does such a good job at
helping with its primary purpose of
stopping people,
being alcoholic,
being drug addicts.
That's such an amazing job and it's
doing that job and it should continue to
do that job well.
I feel like I wanted to do is extract
the thing that I think is amazing about
it and say,
oh my god,
anyone could use this.
Do you hear this again and again from
people that have got long time pro clean
in these programs,
everyone should work this program.
EveryoNe should know what is the impact
cause your mom treated you tHat way or
your dad,
they saw associate at intuit score.
You were abused.
You are still carrying it in your
consciousness.
We've touched on it a moment ago,
joe,
if you're like I say this,
you don't choose between having a
program and not having a program.
You choose between having a conscious
program and an unconscious program.
If you're not working in a conscious
program,
you are being worked by your unconscious
program.
This is what I do.
If a man makes me feel intimidated,
this is what I do.
If a woman makes me feel like I'm
important,
this is what I do.
If I have a bad day program,
program,
the program of your class,
the program of your school,
your family,
your culture,
your time,
and this 12 step system can be buggy
from it and it's not anybody else
telling you what to do because it's your
own version of a higher power.
It's your own version of a truth,
except it's guided by the idea,
become free,
connect to who you really are,
and become benevolent and loving to
others.
You know what I'm thing?
Is it really important that you said
earlier about there's no political
system or no,
no politicians that are talking about
love and values and caring and a sense
of community.
I think that's the solution to what
we're fearing about brexit and Donald
Trump and the rise of,
you know,
the just this attorney of the apple
card,
this,
this thing that people are seeing right
now that they don't like and this,
this,
the hateful rhetoric that people are
most disturbed about,
particularly with brexit.
Right?
That's like the big thing that people
are really disturbed about is that it
was fueled by this fear of the other.
Yes.
That's right,
but isn't it possible that the when if
people decided that that didn't work
out,
whether it's brexit or trump,
that the response to that would be the
rise of this ideology,
the rise of someone who's going to talk
about love and community and someone
who's going to be genuine.
I mean we don't have that person now,
but it doesn't mean that that person can
exist and we've only had 45 different
presidents we had.
We haven't had any,
every single version of what's possible
for a human being to be interfacing with
the entire civilization of the United
States of America.
I think it's pretty clear that what that
system delivers.
I think that those power systems are
evolving in this direction.
I think that this is,
if not the pinnacle,
I think it's possible that there are
better versions of a president,
but I think that systems that at that
centralized will always deliver
inequality.
I think it's impossible for them not to
and I think that they should be evolved,
altered,
devolved in a in a sense,
but I do agree.
One of the things that in the I think is
positive about cataclysm in politics,
if something like brexit,
when brexit happened,
when trump happened,
I felt this sort of.
I'm a bit,
I'm eric know I'm a dharma mccormick.
I live in mischief,
I live in the madness.
That's just behind reality and I've been
away.
This is good.
Not for the people's lives will be
negatively effective when we've seen the
rise of divisive politics and like kinda
softened quite old fashioned ideas about
sort of ethno nationalism and that kind
of stuff.
But the good thing is it precisely as
you say,
joe,
that it does open the conversation up
for someone to say,
oh,
hold on a minute.
I think we've just left out love
kindness,
unity,
togetherness,
like these things perhaps people will be
open to.
Whereas I think if,
you know,
if we'd stayed in the european union,
if we'd had hillary clinton as
president,
things is a bit more business as usual.
We're not forced with.
We're not staring into the face of
madness.
We're not forced to address.
Things are going wrong.
You know,
I talked to my friends sturgeon,
a dental sturgill simpson,
the musician.
He a brilliant musician and he sent me
this text message of a conversation that
he had with dr rick strassman.
Dr rick strassman as the guy out of the
university of New Mexico ran those
clinical tests on dmt,
wrote the book,
dmt,
the spirit molecule,
but he was quoting when he was talking
about the times that we live in and how
fucked up everything is.
He was quoting this,
I forget,
I think it was a monk who said this,
that we are constantly in a fight
between 49 point nine percent and 50
point one percent good and evil and that
they fluctuate back and forth and that
we feel like we are just like a speck of
dust because we are both a speck of dust
and the most important thing in the
world.
Because the.
The actions of one individual literally
can influence the course of the human
race.
The course of our civilization and that
this period of flux is what creates
growth and change and that the tipping
of the apple cart and the.
The,
the positive thing about having someone
like Donald Trump,
and I don't like Donald Trump more than
I like hillary clinton,
I didn't like either one of them,
hillary clinton represented to me was
this lifelong politician who didn't
support gay marriage until 2013,
which she was to me.
What she represented to me was an
obvious magician,
someone who I could see them pulling the
cards out on their sleeve and I'm
supposed to not pay attention.
It's bullshit and what he represents is
the ego unfettered in figuring out with
crazy hair and a family in the middle
sands and the whole deal.
It's just this chaos ego putting his
name on buildings and then we're
realizing that both of these are
terrible options.
System is a terrible system.
This way.
When we have what's essentially a
popularity contest to see who controls
nuclear weapons,
it's insane.
It's literally insane and that the only
way this is going to change is by having
this incredibly upsetting moment for
everybody where they're looking around
going,
what the fuck is going on?
And then new ideas get introduced and I
don't know what those new ideas are
going to be or who's going to introduce
them or how someone is gonna come along
within the next three years and
challenge this current system in a way
that's appealing,
not just to the right and to the left,
but maybe in some way to just human
beings.
Maybe in some way human beings,
They realize like what's what's we're
not going to get by in this world by
enforcing right wing politics and ideas
and and,
and this sort of ideology or left wing
ideas and politics ideology,
but freedom and love and community and
to be free to practice your own level of
conservatism on your own.
But the idea that I don't want any gays
and want to have a little tribe were no
gays are allowed.
That seems to me to be counterproductive
and that seems to be the counter
revolutionary.
All of that idea.
Any suppressing of people's individual
right to express themselves.
Sure.
I agree with almost everything you said
there and I've got a sense of been
involved in academia.
Do you know one of the main changes or
make notes?
Oh,
well,
yeah.
Notes now.
I never would have dreamt to that when I
was a younger man.
Excellent.
Native beginning.
You talked about this idea of the
fitbit,
the percent aisle,
you know,
good and evil that couldn't even now
there's a great quote by the rational
for sultanates and the line between good
and evil runs not between creeds,
religions and empires,
but through every human heart.
So nice quote for that quote now,
and he's a personal theory that the
reason that I dollar tree is bad,
like they becomes like an in most
religions say don't worship individuals
is precisely because they understand
that don't make one individual have too
much power.
Even now,
historically we know that gandy had
skeletons in the closet.
Great.
Great gandy,
wonderful.
Great hero of bringing down the british
empire,
bringing it about freedom and love.
Interestingly,
gandy said there's no point ass kicking
the british out of India and then
replicate in their systems.
This is a country of 70,000
villages.
These 70,000
visitors villages are or should be
autonomous run on their own craft or
craft economies,
trade with one another only in access,
so like he was trying to get like
important ideas out there,
but like,
like your great civil rights leaders,
malcolm x,
martin luther king,
these are men that had flow.
Malcolm x did prison time for unusual
shit,
but Dr.
King,
you know,
extra marrow of stuff.
People are not perfect.
They're great hero.
Pioneer people are people.
So we have to change this.
What I think is is that we can't have a
popularity contest to decide who's in
charge of nuclear weapons.
These kinds of systems need to be
devolved because it's mental.
We know that.
Exactly.
I agree with your analysis of hillary
clinton and Donald Trump entirely.
I think that the reason that you have a
mad option like Donald Trump being
successful,
it's when people had had enough of those
cheap tricks and cards up sleeves and
financial corruption.
So yeah,
the apple carts going over chaos too.
I agree,
is an important part of evolution.
We rest on chaos.
These patterns that we observe,
just temporary or show their sort of a
cult leader and sort of poetic figure
leader said,
we talk about civilization as if it's
this great thing.
What is civilization a clearing in the
forest?
You know,
for a moment we create our cities in the
forest closes in and has it again.
We're all theSe ancient civilization.
Graham hancock talked about,
so lucidly,
where are they now?
It up by the amazon
and I think great quote in a herman
melville's moby dick that says,
you know,
noah's flood is still happening.
We are.
The majority of the earth is still
flooded in war.
These,
we are connected to these events.
We are out there in that chaos.
So I suppose,
gosh,
what I'm trying to say here,
joe,
is that when we recognize that we're all
flawed,
that we're all fallible,
we have to sort of thing.
We have to think,
how can we build systems that tend
towards the better aspects of our
nature,
not the worst aspects of our nature.
Can we recognize that any politician in
a position of power for too long we will
make mistakes,
will be floored.
That power has to be spread out as much
as possible and as close to the people
that it affects as as is feasible.
Yeah.
There's always going to be an issue with
someone being able to acquire
$100,000,000,000
like the amazon,
Jeff Bezos guy like that,
that is going to corrupt people.
It was like,
why would you?
First of all,
why would you keep working?
Why would you want that amount of money
and what's your plan?
What's your end game?
You're trying to make the world a better
place.
You're going to try to acquire more
brown boxes with your logo on them.
I mean,
what do you.
What are you doing?
Where's,
where's it going?
And it seems to me that there's a game,
right?
Everybody plays this game.
Some people play it for $10 an hour.
Some people play it for $10,000,000,000
a year and that once you make
$10,000,000,000
a year,
you want infinite growth.
You want 11 next year?
I would like to tell my stockholders
that we have caused to celebrate and we
have 20 percent increase in our,
uh,
bottom line this year and everybody's
looking good.
Let's go to tahiti.
Right?
And then like where,
what are you doing?
You can't,
this is not going to last.
You're not going to live forever.
Like what?
What is the end game?
Well,
there's no end game.
You're caught up in the current game,
in the current game.
They are literally,
capitalists are literally living in the
moment because you have to just
stockpiling shit that they're not
thinking about the overall objective,
you know,
a sky down looking from the,
looking from the heavens
down on earth like what the fuck are we
doing?
They're not thinking about that.
Nor are they accepting that limitless
growth is literally impossible.
That we have finite resources on a
finite planet,
not for me.
It's also you get caught up in the
momentum of whatever you're doing,
you know,
whatever you're doing,
you just get caught up in it and you
know,
you.
If you're doing something and you're
trying to get better at it,
whether it's make a better paintings or
acquire more wealth like you these
requests and you try to get better at
these quests,
you know,
and that's,
that's,
that's a real issue with human beings
and I think it has evolutionary roots.
I think it has roots in our,
our,
our need and desire to make better
structures and shelters to make better
weapons,
to make a better civilization so that we
can stay alive longer so that we can
ensure that our children will be alive
longer.
I think there's roots in that that are
sort of just sort of bastardized and
twisted in this world of ideas where,
where you're talking about like money
and and and,
and stocks and bonds and mutual funds
and hedge funds and it's like jesus,
like it's,
it's almost like we have these ancient
instincts for,
for constant improvement that just,
they,
these human reward systems get.
They just get corrupt.
Did.
My theory on this idea is that we have
biochemical drives,
as you've just described,
that compel us to move forward and to
survive.
But we also have a culture that's
continually stimulate in fear and desire
in order to cost us in a particular
economic role that have consumer.
And the reason that I believe that this
program and indeed this book are
important,
is because it is a code to awakening a
code to becoming conscious and once you
are conscious you aren't beholden to the
same systems.
So much of our behAvior is a result of
what we don't know about ourselves.
We are motivated.
we're trying to fulfill ourselves
because there is that biochemical
imperative to get more to survive.
Which as an addict I experienced and
have experienced an extreme sex,
sex,
sex till.
There's no more getting out of my head
till it's inconceivable that I could do
that anymore without killing myself a
one in status and power and prestige.
And see.
The reason that I think this system
works outside of addiction in it's as
it's currently recognized is I've had to
work in all sorts of ways.
Once I got rid of drugs,
I got obsessed with sex.
Once I get,
once I get a handle on sex,
I've stopped being obsessed with what
other people think of me.
Power,
fame and money,
and what I'm continually recognizing is
none of these things can be fulfilling.
If you're not connected to who you
really are,
that can give you a moment.
Then you're free to pursue your art or
your creation of structures in a
conscious way.
You're not doing it because you feel
unconsciously a bit worthless or a bit
crap or like it might fulfill you.
It becomes pragmatic.
Eric,
do you also feel that like less
concentrating on yourself and less being
self obsessed is allowed you to have
more open communication with other
people and more healthy like back and
forth,
fulfilling communication with other
people,
which literally makes you happier.
Whereas you thought that being obsessed
with yourself and being obsessed with
success and adulation and or sex or
whatever those other things were that
you were obsessed with was going to
fulfill those needs and they weren't,
but that community and bonding and
that's a big part of jujitsu as well,
man.
So I think part of it,
yeah,
big,
big part of jujitsu.
It's like we're a family when you're in
there choking each other,
as weird as that sounds like there's a.
There's a bond between those people that
are in those classes all over the world
that are.
They're going to.
They they,
they recognize this community in that as
well as it being an extreme pursuit and
as well as it being something that is
developing your human potential,
you're also.
You're also creating this really intense
community of likeminded people.
Comedians feel that.
I definitely feel that with you.
I feel that with most comedians that
come in here and I know what you.
We are the same thing in a lot of ways.
Yes.
I think that's very important and in a
way it's a return to what you were
saying at the beginning of our
conversation that there are certain
anthropology core requirements that you
need to feel lIke you're part of a
tribe.
You need to feel connected to one
another and in my very limited pop in
there once a week experiences of bjj
when I've done classes with other people
instead of just the one on one with the
instructor because he looks after me,
you know,
I mean he's delicate because he's
brilliant,
but when it's with like other people
that are similar beginner level,
there's moments of real intensity within
it,
but afterwards,
a sense of fraternity and love and
closeness and like some stuff that I'm
not familiar with have not used to being
close to men in that kind of way and
it's amazing and beautiful and probably
very,
very natural and impute important side
of my life that I didn't explore because
I did download the myth of our time that
you are an individual and you carve your
own way in this world and what's
important is your power,
your ability to affect change on others.
Your ability to sleep with women,
the adulation of others.
And as I've got older and having
experience a degree of it,
I recognize,
oh,
it's not real.
It doesn't work.
And symbol things.
Connection and community have become
more and more valuable to me,
but it's an ongoing thing because if you
set,
the percentage is so close,
you know,
we're not getting involved.
Recently in a campaign that it was.
I got involved in a campaign to save a
house in the state a couple of years
back about these women asked me to tell
them our state's going to get turned
into commercial flats were all getting
evicted.
We live here with our families.
I back their campaign,
I've got them on the tv,
this corporate power back down and it
was amazing because like ordinary
people,
ordinary family be,
you know,
it was like the rebels be in the empire.
It's like an amazing achievement of
those people.
But my ego,
like there I am,
the power,
I am the power fed back into it.
You know,
so like I,
I see it as an ongoing thing,
but that my life now is how can I convey
ideas that I think will help people in a
way that is accessible?
How can I be useful?
And knowing that my,
my role in this is to make sure that I
don't slip into the yoga egomania again
because I would love to be a cult leader
on some days.
Thinking,
thinking about it though and being aware
of it is one of the most important steps
because we're all,
we're all a work in progress.
I mean,
there's no perfect person out there.
They don't exist.
And we've already discussed this kind of
ad nauseum,
right?
I mean,
I'm a work in progress.
You're a work in progress.
I don't,
I've never met anybody who wasn't.
And I never met anybody who doesn't
vacillate at least a little bit,
larry.
There were some days you're better than
other days and those days where you're
not as good,
you feel uncomfortable about it.
And those are the lid would lead to
better days.
When you find yourself slipping,
those slipping moments are actually
critical because they give you some self
awareness.
You realize why I fucked up,
you know,
I yelled,
fuck you at my car window when I
shouldn't have or whatever it was,
you know.
Well,
again,
this system is what provides
you a way out at like the,
you know,
the recovery system,
this 12 step system is that you like,
you would not rely on one person to be
perfect.
You recognize everyone is fallible,
but together as a community we can start
to have better objectives and in an
instance like I fuck up all the time,
but this step nine,
step 10 or about making amends when you
make a mistake.
So I would like now I literally do this.
If there's a moment where I shout fuck
you,
but somebody or it isn't.
I go shuffling back a day later
listening to this thing where I said
fuck you.
That was wrong with me.
That must have affected your feelings to
find someone in traffic there you to
fuck you.
Yeah.
I'll try and do it real quick.
You've got,
you've got fast and a lot of my fuck
you's.
Maybe it's on a phone call or maybe it's
in a shop or whatever.
The air like,
I mean in a way is about,
I suppose becoming a benevolent force in
this world.
If I tend towards that better,
50 point one percent as opposed to the
49,
then I'm becoming an a progressive agent
or a bird benevolent agent as opposed to
another person intoxicated.
I think it's a microcosm of what we were
talking about earlier about society
itself is that one day in the future,
look what the way we behave today is
light years past the way they behaved in
during the inquisition.
I mean in,
in,
in the future.
I imagine especially today because
people have so much access to the way
other people have behaved.
We have so much data on just written
words,
listening to people talk and podcasts
and speeches and watching videos.
There's so much more data than there
ever was available.
One hundred,
200 a thousand years ago,
that in the future we're going to have a
much better way of communicating based
on the learning and growth if we
survive.
Right,
and I think that's the same thing with
You and I and everybody listening to
this as a human being.
If you continue to grow and you don't
fall into all these traps as time goes
on,
you will be a better version.
It's slow and it's fucking brutal and
it's painful sometimes because it's
just,
You feel like,
god,
why don't I have my shit together?
You know?
I mean there's,
I was saying this about Donald Trump,
like someone was writing off Donald
Trump,
like he's never going to learn.
You know,
he's who he is.
I'm like,
did you just stop learning when you're
70,
like,
70?
That's it.
It's over.
There's no more data's getting in there.
Well,
I don't know.
I don't.
I mean,
maybe Donald Trump could have a
revelation one day,
you know,
maybe Donald Trump could realize the
error of his ways and the way he
communicates is his,
you know,
he's causing more problems and he's
fixing,
you know,
maybe he'll be not even to point him out
because it's just,
he's just one of us,
right?
To all of us that I think we're,
we're all slowly,
brutally piecing this thing together and
hopefully we're better at it than we
were a week ago and hopefully we're
better at it than we were six months ago
and that it's going to continue.
Well,
that feels like the general tendency in
my own life to put out the general
tendency in your life.
Absolutely.
And you know,
one of the things that's helped
tremendously as this podcast,
being able to have these long three hour
conversations with people,
you sit down and talk to them with no
distractions.
It doesn't exist anywhere else.
It doesn't exist in nature.
Someone.
Someone said this to me,
they said,
you know,
you always say on your Podcast that you
just try to have a conversation.
He goes,
but who the fuck has these kinds of
conversations?
We just sit down and stare at each other
and talk for hours at a time.
I'm like,
get your right.
I mean,
it is just a conversation still,
but you're right.
Is that,
it's sort of an accelerated form of it.
It's like a.
If you,
you know,
you could kind of apply it to everything
else.
If you spent enough time doing it,
you know,
you're just,
you're,
you're going to get better at it and
you're going to.
A lot of the podcasts is thinking right
and it's an examining your own behavior
and examining the way you interface with
other people and I do more of that than
I ever have before.
What do you want to change about
yourself?
Just keep going the same way.
I'm going to get better at being nice,
get better at being honest,
get better at being in loving.
I mean,
it sounds hokey,
hippie bullshit.
He says,
yeah,
I want to.
I want to be nicer.
To me.
I want to have better relationships with
my friends,
better relationships with my family,
better relationships with people that I
don't even know that.
I mean I just want to interface with the
world in a more positive way.
I think one of the most important things
to realize is all the interactions that
we have with each other,
a dependent upon to individuals or more.
Right,
but it's You and whoever you encounter
and the way you encountered them is
going to change the way they behave to
you and everybody always wants to put it
off on the person who behaved a certain
way to them and in some ways you're
right,
but in other ways your reaction is
completely dependent on your own way of
approaching it and your reaction may
change the way they react and you'll
complete the right like any.
Like if the,
you know,
throwIng a pool against that brick wall,
it will bounce back a certain way,
but if that became a softer surface or
indeed a furry wall to quote one of my
own films,
that it will bounce back in a different
way so that they did another thing
that's in the program than necessity for
forgiveness.
If you.
If you instead of blaming your past and
blaming other people,
you come to a point of forgiveness.
This creates the silver,
the nexus for change.
As long as you're like,
ah,
that person felt me out when I was a kid
or my bad wasn't a loving figure in my
life.
As long as I hold onto that belief,
I'm trapped by it.
I mean,
I say I relinquished that now.
It's not happening anymore.
I'm willing to move forward.
That's another human being.
They were doing the best they could.
Suddenly you're liberate it in your path
changes.
Now,
joe,
when you were saying just then mate,
about like wanting to help people,
do you have any particular projects are
specifically about that?
Obviously this podcast is a tool for
education,
but do you have anything that
specifically about right,
I'm going to do this thing like,
I don't know,
take in martial arts in the community
type stuff?
No,
no.
You think it'd be really good at that if
I had more time.
I just don't.
I don't have enough time to do what I'm
already doing,
you know what I mean?
In terms of just sheer numbers of hours
in the day and I think
I can't just work because if I just
worked,
my work won't be any good.
I mean you have to live.
It's one of the most important things
about standup comedy is you can't just
do comedy.
You have to do other things and this is
something that took me a long time to
figure out like you can't,
like you ever see a lot of comics,
they just started talking about airline
travel and hotel rooms and your life is
your life and they can relate to it,
so that's what they talk about.
What?
That to me is a failure of gathering
research.
I mean it's all.
It's life,
right?
But your life has to.
I think in order to have a continual
body of work again,
he can't just constantly talk about
airline travel.
You have input.
My thing in the beginning of this was
about airline travel and the low level,
low frequency anxiety I experienced in
airline workers.
It certainly wasn't a comedic bit,
but it was cultural analysis and did to
a degree revealed that I'm in the middle
of a press junket and that's my life at
the moment.
I could just as easily have told you
about bees.
I'm a bee keeper.
I've bees.
All right.
Do you swim in the river?
you have experiences,
you have said for we sort of one be,
I'm not keeping one b,
one b,
one one doesn't work.
You're like,
be.
I'm afraid.
I said responsibility to have now.
Sixty thousand pounds.
I'm not taking them on the or anything
like that,
but he doesn't.
Yeah,
you're right.
It's given me and said,
what's your standard,
your standup comedy then what is it
currently?
What are you covering?
What your sections,
your bolts.
See what I'm doing right now is working
towards the new netflix special that I'm
going to do in either march or april.
I have to figure it out.
Uh,
want to do it in boston and I don't want
to do when it's too cold because that
1000 seat place in boston.
I think wilbur.
Yeah,
they will.
Yeah.
It's awesome little theater because it's
really 900 seats and it's really three,
300 seat comedy clubs.
Yeah.
It's three stacked on top of each other.
It's a great venue.
Well,
you'll say,
so you're going to do an hour of free
nights.
Boy,
you'll see.
What if you got to a free 20 minute
average?
Do you know what your pit.
So yeah.
Anyways,
if you don't mind me,
it's difficult to talk about it on the
podcast because without going into
actual.
But can you tell about the area or I'll
tell you about my arrows to show you
this.
So I think I talked about like when I
got heavily involved in politics and I
found myself on tv shows and doing rants
on telly and getting into arguments.
Those are great,
but otherwise thank you.
I love doing those.
Love the one you did.
Was it fox news that you did one with
it?
Breaking down like what are we doing
here?
I love doing that.
I liked that love,
ridicule available.
Once you get into the analysis,
you're,
you're a fucking runaway train and once
you start a sentence and you start going
very fast and powerful and they'll be
like,
whoa,
whoa.
And there's not a lot of ums or uhs to
interject and they're sitting there.
They're all,
you know,
first of all,
the little starry eyed in the first
place.
Second of all though,
the runaway trains happened like,
uh,
under the ride's over five minutes
later,
like tin cans or rolling down the aisle
and they're like,
okay,
it's a good technique because see that
what we were saying about bjj,
that,
that language don't know the language,
the language comedy,
it's a language I've worked on.
So one of my techniques is never create
space.
Give them no space,
no space,
no space smush.
See if you take the actual jujitsu out
of it.
I'm brilliant.
Or jujitsu,
it's just the actual physical contact.
Hold locks and chokes judges who shows
itself in all forms.
Yeah,
that is true.
Transcendence to find one universal
language,
one universal myth,
one mind one consciousness,
one,
yes,
no,
the way broadly.
And you'll see it in all things.
So Ryan Hamilton,
masashi,
that was pretty good for five rings.
Just drop that in there.
Chinese philosophy or something like
that to my arm.
What is he?
Some sort of master?
He was a samurai that was a,
he was a ronan.
He was,
uh,
during the time where samurais roamed
the earth and got into these one-on-one
sword fights.
And he killed 62 men in one-on-one sword
fights.
I said,
life in a bad motherfucker.
He wrote an amazing book on strategy in
life.
And one of the things that he emphasized
in that book is that a real warrior must
be balanced.
You must be good at art and calligraphy
and poetry.
Good.
Can't have any holes in your game that
you have a balanced person in order to
survive in these intense moments of
sorts,
flying at your face.
I had never teach a man to fight who
doesn't know how to dance.
It's quite good in it.
I don't know how to dance set paycheck
they like.
But what I sort of like,
what I've done is I've found things like
the approach from a different angle of
like pointing out the things that I did
wrong in my political campaigning where
I floored and fed into my ego.
I do a good long bit about the birth of
my daughter,
like purely from the perspective of a
watching a birth,
like,
uh,
commentary,
sports commentary on the baby coming
out.
I don't use the beat,
uh,
the rhythms of sports commentary,
but just actually describing what
happened and what it did to my mind to
be present at the birth of my daughter
to experience something that's so
defined,
but so animal tearing,
flesh roaring and all that stuff.
But It's like god is in their house,
you know?
So it did it beyond that.
But in every time I building up into a
point of divinity,
I undercut it with like,
you know,
how sort of mad it looks and the obvious
stuff I guess you'd call it.
So like I do that so.
And the whole show rebif,
which I'm doing from a netflix,
I believe at some point soon it's like a
is about,
it's called rebirth.
And the point of it is how having the
babies,
men,
I've been reborn to myself,
but a lot of it's about recognizing the
limits because I think I got very
narcissistically involved in politics
the same way and possibly getting
narcissistically involved in
spirituality right now because I still
have this yearning,
this thing that wants to change other
people's lives,
changed the world in inverted commas.
You know,
but like the comedy comes from
recognizing my own flaws within you.
Do you do any sort of like really
difficult to exercise outside of a
jujitsu?
Do you ever do ever get involved in,
you know,
any like yoga,
like intense yoga,
like long periods of time,
like 90 minute hot yoga classes
or running or anything where you really
have to push yourself physically,
really push a run and then listen to
your podcasts and sam harris' podcast
sometimes or wherever and I'm like,
and I do.
I do do yoga,
but not like.
It's interesting that you specifically
say push yourself to the limit.
Why do you think that's an important
part?
I think there's a freeing aspect and
pushing boundaries and physical
boundaries because it's exhausting and
not just exhausting physically,
but mentally too because there's a
strain on your.
Your body's desire to quit,
like your,
your,
your mind's desire to seek comfort and
that in pushing past that you find this
freedom and you also find a
vulnerability and who you are as a
person.
It's very difficult to think greatly of
yourself and to Be egos autistic when
you know that you're so fucking tired,
you have to put your hands on your knees
and your,
you're heaving and you know,
and then you have to keep going and then
don't,
don't be opposed to you.
Come on,
keep going.
And so you,
you don't,
you realize who you are.
You feel yourself for who you really are
as opposed to like adulation and looking
at yourself as this,
uh,
this thing that's above it all.
Like you realize the flaws in your
mental process,
the flaws in your,
your physical abilities.
And I think it's very humbling you.
Yeah,
right.
I can see that doing that in a bodily
way,
it will be useful.
But like I tell you the truth,
the trouble for me,
and I think a lot of addicts,
he's not the like of course they self
obsession,
but self obsession isn't usually about
fucking great.
IT's normally I'm worthless.
That's why he comes mostly from that
position,
but it's also you're thInking about
yourself all the time,
right?
That is the problem that needs to be
decoded.
And I think you're right,
that physical exercise is really,
really important.
The level to the level to which I think
I always feel better.
It's not my,
like I have to work even to bloody do
that.
I'd rather spend a ton of time thinking
or doing something thinking I'm fucking
coming is thinking that's what's,
what's confusing about it to people.
It's thinking,
but it's thinking in a very different
Way.
Like there's,
there's thinking when your body's at
rest and you're just using your mind
whether there's also thinking when your
mind is trying to manage your body under
extreme stress.
And that is also a mental exercise and
that's where people get it wrong.
When people look at people that exercise
and especially people that work out
really hard and they think of them as
meatheads or as like someone who's based
or primal and unevolved.
But I feel like there's a high level of
mental evolution involved and being able
to push yourself like,
like I,
I really admire people that,
you know,
like you'll see like a lot of old people
that are,
uh,
I see him in yoga class all the time
that just never fucking stop in there.
And they don't have extreme physical
abilities at all.
They're not,
there's nothing athletic aBout them.
They're not strong,
but they're in there grinding.
and in doing so you have to,
I mean,
it can't possibly be comfortable for
them.
Right?
I look at their saggy arms and their old
legs.
This is not like some graceful person is
able to do this easily.
This is a person who's really struggling
and in real struggle,
like that is a mental
energy that's involved in forcing your
body to go through these uncomfortable
emotions.
That I think is very freeing.
Yeah.
I think you're right.
What you said as well about balance and
possibly what you're saying is that I'm
a person who will benefit from more of
that.
I see a guy in the gym once and he said,
don't stop exercising.
He was old,
he was like in his seventies.
He goes,
don't stop exercising,
don't let your body find out these
dying.
I just keep going.
Don't let your body find out.
It's dying.
That's great.
Yeah,
that's pretty cool.
Isn't it?
So,
yeah.
but like I think that in any form of,
uh,
I think that some variety of it.
I know you do the yoga,
you do the brazilian jujitsu,
you do the running.
I think it's very important of different
forms of exercise,
different forms of mental activity,
different forms of stimulation to live
like good because this is what this
machine is designed to do.
And again,
I returned to the problem of capitalism
is that it reduces you to your role
within an economic system as opposed to
why not gap.
Go for a run through a bit of fishing.
Could wander around,
shoot some arrows,
do whatever it is you're into.
I spend some time,
meditate in,
spend some time exercising,
spent a time in loving physical combat.
Well,
the reason you can't,
there's no fucking time because he's.
Your job is to stand on the line or in
that cheese grater.
Great.
It just get your soul ground down.
Yeah,
that's necessary anymore.
It's not necessarily.
It's certainly isn't necessarily enough
to justify spending eight hours plus a
day,
five days a week inside some sort of a
box.
I know a while ago you said we are both
a speck of dust and limitless
consciousness and this I agree with to
limitless expansion,
limitless contraction,
possible within consciousness and what
you said,
if that one idea can change the world
very quickly and that's why they'd be
systems regulate the kind of information
that's available and the way that it's
transmitted and also the fact that it
exists within the same economic model.
You can,
as long as you're making money,
as long as the money's getting directed
in the right way.
People will let us talk about real
radical stuff.
They're quite comfortable for us to say,
hey,
you should break down the system.
You should devolve at twilight,
this conversation.
Whereas with geico,
p attachable,
he's an australian gay rights activist
who lives in the uk and he said,
it's like when you're talking like this
with no disrespect,
disrespect for the great civil rights
heroes in the people that have had civil
rights struggles,
but he said,
and he's experienced as a gay rights
activist.
He goes,
in the end they will yield when it's to
do with those things,
your race,
sexuality.
People sort of know you guys,
but when you,
you know,
the system will use,
they will you.
All right?
Gay marriage,
of course.
All right.
Yeah.
We,
you know,
we can't fucking have slavery in the
end.
And of course these monumental human
struggles.
I'm not diminishing them because.
But if you go near people's financial
interest,
you are fucked either they'll get you
there when you start saying,
hey,
why don't we not pay our mortgages?
Hey everyone,
let's not pay tax to stop using oil.
Right?
You fucking your out.
Uh,
I see it so straight away.
So it's sort of like,
this is what's interesting to me,
like was like these are the,
these are the access points,
these are the points where
there is vulnerability.
I'm not suggesting that we will organize
ourself into a radical crew of tax
avoiders or mortgage renegades or
wherever,
but even though
are both doing well,
we're in,
like you said before,
we're not in that weird,
you know,
upper stratosphere where you're living
on the hamptons and some fucking hundred
acre ridiculous seaside mansion you
where your helicopter and private jet
everywhere and you're worth
$100,000,000.
And that's a weird world.
That's a weird world that very few
people exist in.
Once they get there,
they don't want to leave.
Once you start flying private
everywhere,
you don't want to leave.
Once you have a match and you don't want
a department,
once you have a bentley,
you don't want to,
you go,
you know,
it's like nobody wants to go down.
You want to keep moving up.
Yeah.
And it's weird because those things
happened.
They tend to happen in.
So if they haven't been in,
if you've got that money for
entertainment,
maybe you're still sort of,
you've got some connection to your roots
and your entertainment and not maybe
you'll still connected to the source.
But when it's in tech and finance,
yeah,
you've got a vested interest.
My friend jason segel,
the brilliant actor goes,
um,
you know,
you guys,
you think all that stuff's about you,
the jets and the billboards and stuff.
But it's just the symptoms of other
people making money out of you.
It's not that you have a tool in your
parlor machine,
you'll be processed to be kicked out.
It's not a carousel,
it's a train.
It will run out of energy and as soon as
you're not providing your route.
and I was doing some promo for this
book.
I'm still trying to.
Sally occasionally promote in this free
willing conversation at facebook and I
family,
man,
this place didn't exist 15 years ago.
We've looking at now it is a monolift
like these other kingdom lives.
Now google started all these little
ideas that will make phones.
Fuck
the newest google pixel.
Two phones.
I mean,
they make,
they make these incredible devices that
you can interface into the google world
and they're optimized for their whole
system.
Amazing,
amazing.
You know,
david fosTer wallace,
your great american author in his book,
infinite jest,
postulated a world where all stadiums
were named after brands were countries
and regions were named after brands,
and it's sort of happening.
It's happening.
The flags of our nations are merely a
veil over the true corporate interests.
The british empire was always about east
India trade and all that kind of crap
and this country.
Now it's just a veil over true power.
I'm going to the t mobile arena in las
vegas this weekend for the ufc.
Oh yeah.
The team over in the mobile arena,
that's what it's called.
Now you know,
you're sort of at fIrst when they start
to name football stadiums in our
country,
you still remembered the name of what it
used to be before sponsorship,
but we start to forget that it was ever
anything else.
You start to forget.
We were once warriors.
We were once connected to the earth.
We are gods were ones,
eagles and stags.
Now our gods are the timo,
pilar,
rena,
take back your freedom.
Not the coliseum.
It's the sony center,
right?
The christians are been flown to the
lines at the same 3:00
PM.
Wow.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean,
you know,
they want people to use t mobile.
I get it.
Would you mind to use it?
We'll just ask me.
Give me a deal.
Oh,
use it.
I my liquid.
You're saying keep talking unlimited
data.
It's nice.
Yeah.
One.
Hey.
So like,
I learned an important lesson of you and
this was it when I was a light came on
last time you were doing sort of a very
big a ufc event in I think vegas and my
mates,
like from the gym that I go to,
genesis theme,
I've already mentioned that they were
coming over for a stack though they
didn't ask me,
but I sort of thought,
oh listen,
I could further inveigle myself into
this little crew of martial artist by
hooking them up with joe rogan tickets.
And I thought,
Yeah,
I'll do that.
Like every,
the politician,
so forth.
So I text you a joe who hook up my mates
with this thing and he went,
oh,
okay,
who are these people is important to
you?
And I took a moment,
a form.
They are important and like them,
but was my motivations here.
They're like,
this is a good thing.
I took a moment to reflect on it for
shayla do this will come up with
tickets,
you know,
maybe I'm doing this for the wrong
reasons.
I took a moment of rest are reflected.
I didn't do it well it was a little less
than.
It was a little less than because you
gave me pause for rest by.
I think you were doing a standup show
actually.
And I was to and they were already had
tickets for your standup.
That's what it was.
And I was like,
how could you give them backstage
passes?
And your answer wasn't an immediate ben
dover.
Yes,
of course I'll do what you want mr.
Brand.
It was a bit more questioning like,
well who are these guys?
The reason why I ask,
I always ask is because sometimes people
say,
look,
you don't have to do this,
but they've been bothering me about it.
It's a guy I work with,
or people have said,
hey,
would you do this?
It's my best friend.
I love this guy.
And then I go,
okay,
yeah,
ah,
so you give people little junction
because sometimes those people are
paying now because somebody might be a
pain in the ass to you and you might
just be getting in line and I didn't
know you as well,
you know,
so I'm like,
well,
and I really admired the way you handled
it.
Like I said,
do you want to give my number?
And that was the thing,
and you went,
no,
I don't think I'll give him your number.
It seemed like I might be overcome me
and made me look at my own motivations
and I suppose that's it.
Anything that is called the great Carl
Young,
the mystic,
and one of the pioneers of
psychoanalysis said anything that
crosses your path that you didn't intend
for,
that is god in inverted commerce and
opportunity to learn.
So this is how I try to approach my life
now.
I was like,
hmm,
I didn't plan for that to happen.
What's the lesson here?
What can I learn from this situation?
So like,
you know,
anyway,
I'm sure damn guys would have been
fantastic.
I though they did later show me videos
of what went on.
I think it was just stack them and they
were carrying on like idiots called up
and down corridors drunk at their mind.
So perhaps it was for the best,
but generally I'm sure that nothing
would have gone wrong.
But when I look at my own motivation,
ah,
what are you doing here?
Why do you want to do this?
You're doing it a little bit because you
want to look cool.
Don't bother doing that.
Then you know,
that's a little small in the way that I
walked the path for a small amendment
down a line.
Maybe I will ask again.
Yeah,
actually joe,
could you sort these guys out with
tickets for this or that?
But I'll do it with the right
motivation,
the right connection.
Now,
this again,
as I keep saying this journey from
unconsciousness to consciousness is what
has been the myth of my own life.
I think we have to.
Whether or not we're in just limitless
chaos in an ever expanding universe
without meaning,
without point,
without love,
you know,
it may be.
That is the way you know that a lot of
people see the world that way.
It's not how I see the world.
I see there as being meaning in
everything,
poetry and everything,
beauty in everything,
and certainly in my own life.
I like to find the story.
What am I meant to learn here?
What am I meant to do here?
What did I learn from being ahead in the
story that I learned from being
promiscuous,
from being a drug addict and it all
seemed to make a kind of sense.
It all seems to be guiding me towards
something and that thing does seem to be
love,
service,
kindness,
awareness.
Not trying to manipulate people and not
trying to get shit off people.
Time is a good journey and I feel like
it's sad if people don't get to do their
own version of that journey because
they're on the cheese grater or because
they're pursuing some myths,
some code from their childhood that
they're not good enough or that they
don't deserve to be happy or they can't
achieve anything where whatever rung
their call on,
whether it's the wrong of booze or drugs
or the wrong of staring at social media
the whole time with the rung of hatred
of others or the wrong of being caught
in bad relationships and a crap job.
For me,
I think that we can accelerate that
evolution.
I think that there are codes that can
slip through and the same way that an
amazon can spring up in 15 years and be
this great economic monolift,
new ideas,
new faith's new ideologies can slip into
the net.
Particularly now we have this access to
technology.
You've slipped past the gatekeepers.
you have your own media empire out of
nothing.
You know,
and you've limited it because it's too
you built around you as an individual in
your perspective,
et cetera.
But these are,
there are ways now of getting
information out there that excites me.
Yeah.
And They should,
you know,
and what we were talking about too,
about being a hedonist and doing things
wrong and fucking up.
and what can you learn from them?
I think every time you fuck something up
and every time you do something badly
you,
there's a lesson that you get out of the
weird feelings of failure,
of discontent.
And those lessons are extremely
valuable.
You know,
a person who doesn't make mistakes and a
person who doesn't do anything wrong,
they never learned shit.
You don't learn anything from doing
everything perfectly.
every time it doesn't happen.
No one knew no one and the more bold and
brash you are and the more you take
chances and the more you put yourself
into these weird positions.
Even in these like,
you know,
I'm sure when you're,
you were a sex addict and you're in this
hedonistic whirlwind experience,
you're still,
you're taking in all this data and
you're taking all this in,
in the hollow feeling that you had that
you didn't like.
It is what propelled you to your new
stage of once you
emerge from it.
Yeah,
that's right.
Every so often because it's like
pleasure laden an orgy.
I mean that's the point of view.
I mean this flesh everywhere.
It's this bits of it.
They're brilliant.
I was no in,
hold on a minute.
This isn't working and this is a thing
that I thought would really,
really work,
you know,
like sometimes the,
the great gift of promiscuity is you get
to experience the intimacy with all of
these strangers and it seemed exciting
and the type of sexuality that I've
always had is more about worship than
any kind of domination I adore.
I adore,
you know,
so it's not about like,
I want to control you,
so by like all these wonderful
experiences and encounters,
but within it,
this kind of ongoing seem of loneliness
and ignorable and also this is the
thing,
when you get the things your culture
tells you you should be doing and you
experience them now you know,
now you know you can stop chasing the
carrot because you've had a bite out of
it.
And he's like,
oh,
mini bullshit,
like you know,
not an,
it's a hard one to learn because
anything that's got an orgasm at the end
of it,
you know,
there's a degree of pleasure to be had,
but it takes,
it takes a while to recognize what this,
the emotional cost or made a spiritual
cost on other people.
The fact that it's prevented me from
becoming a father,
from becoming a husband,
from berlin,
from becoming rooted from becoming
actually whole,
from becoming a man,
from becoming connected.
It takes a while to spot that.
I think a lot of people don't get the
opportunity to break out that pattern.
I would never have spotted it.
Had a not first being a heroin addict
and got,
hold on a minute.
You're doing that thing again.
Same with fame and celebrity.
Well toxic,
well toxic,
exciting and brilliant and loads of
lovely people in there.
And I still like,
you know,
I might make another film,
I don't know what happened,
but like it's because I'd had the
template and the experiences of awe,
this is addiction.
You're expecting this thing to make you
feel better.
Now what's happened is I am as a
baseline disabused of the idea that the
material world will give me anything
that it will ever fulfill me,
that I am responsible for my own
connection and that my role here is to
serve other people and help them in if
my objective in life is or what can I do
to augment myself to make myself better.
And I,
you know,
even self improvement.
I agree with all of that.
I agree with entirely.
It's brilliant,
brilliant thing and it's necessary I
think,
but like in order that I may be of
service to others rather than.
Because then I'll just look great in
this arm chair ranking.
Self improvement is about being better
at what fulfills you the most,
which is almost always establishing
community.
So don't you think then joe,
that we could do something that's a bit
more explicitly that from the.
You already have this huge community
there around the joe rogan experience.
Is there something in it bother you?
Like couldn't there be something that
wouldn't cost you that much?
That might be sort of wonderful.
Didn't do these things,
not float into your world,
and people go,
you know,
you're an influential figure.
You're unusual.
You have this strong male energy.
Be very open to learning and very open
to it and you're like,
you know,
I agree with you.
A left wing categories right when
categories,
that shit's all got to go,
but I think that there's a real
opportunity for you to have a huge
impact on communities.
They're very neglected.
Young males,
for example,
not knowing how to use their bodies,
young males are that violence is
becoming a problem for.
there's not that many people that are in
as powerful position as you to sort of
the wrecks to them in a different way.
Is that something that you know about?
Is that something that's come into your
orbit?
Well,
you're doing it right now.
I mean,
you're doing it right now about
communicating in a way that you're going
to get to way more people than you're
going to do it in a physical sense.
You know,
by spreading these ideas and
communicating online in a podcast and
allowing people to download it for free.
Getting into your phone and your head
and you know you're jogging and you're
driving your car,
you're getting ideas and the way more
people's heads and you ever would by
physically being there physically being
there.
It's very retro.
It really is.
I mean,
you can only be there for so many people
and what are you going to do?
I mean,
I could.
I do comedy shows for a lot of people,
but I mean physically being there and
doing something and organizing some sort
of thing.
That's what you venture into some weird
cult thing that's for the culture.
Shit gets slippery.
Everybody's covered in baby oil and you
just fucking trying to grip nothing.
Right?
We're in a jungle now.
Massively side may be a right job.
I think it's an interesting thing to
observe.
I do think that's right and it made a
lot of people in england like the go.
Yeah.
I heard you on joe rogan.
I listen to joe rogan.
People talk about it and it's
interesting because it's different,
like it's accessing information that
people would not have always been.
People come for the fight stuff or come
for the entertainers,
but then they're getting hit with graham
hancock or some neurologist or wherever
the behavioralist or wherever is a good
thing.
Well,
I think
the wide variety of guests is very
important too,
for me personally because otherwise I'd
get bored if I only talk to comedians
are only talked to mma fighters or
whatever,
or even only cocked to scientist.
I'd get bored.
You know,
I like,
I like talking to a bunch of different
people.
You know what I mean?
I didn't plan any of this.
So the way that sort of an an folded is,
is been pretty organic to use an
overused.
tell me please just briefly,
is there something about the phenomena
of conor mcgregor that is unique?
what is it that is happening?
What has happened with him?
What does he mean?
What does he mean into ufc?
What happens to him now that I'll post
mayweather fight?
What is he an example of sort of an
outlier,
a pioneer?
How will he be regarded?
What does he represent?
Is he an entertainment product?
Easy.
A great athlete is a combination of all
those things.
What does he mean for the sport of ufc
and what do you think will happen in
mixed martial arts and boxing?
Do you think we'll see more of those
kinds of events?
Well,
you never going to see another one like
him,
right?
Because he's a unique
person.
He's.
He's literally being himself.
You're going see a bunch of people try
to mimic that and in a sense he sort of
mimicked the people that came before
him,
like the chill sonance and the muhammad
ali's and the people that were really
good at talking shit.
The difference is that what connor's
been able to do,
he's the first guy in the ufc that's
been able to do that,
that's had spectacular results and also
showed his real character in losing and
then coming back and winning very
quickly afterwards at the same guy like
the nate diaz fight.
I think that was a very important
character exposing fight because he lost
a fight.
He got humbled and then he jumped right
back on the horse and then wound up
winning and then he comes back and blows
eddie alvarez out of the water to become
the first two division concurrent
champion in the sport.
I think he's a unique guy in a very.
It's almost like we don't have a word
strong enough.
Unique is not really a strong enough
word.
So he is founded on a belief in a very
basic way.
He's got brilliant,
brilliant ability,
massive.
He's incredibly smart and a very.
He's very innovative in his techniques
and his approaches.
And um,
I think he has phenomenal coaching as
well.
And animal movements.
The fuck is that walk well,
he's just getting that thing that he
does.
He throws his name doesn't mean anything
loose.
He's doing.
He cocking okay.
When I come out and stay sometimes it
says just an amazing thing to do with
the body heat cooking.
You say cocky.
I was like,
oh my god,
these guys fucking out and look what
he's doing.
He's letting the other guy know that he
so loose.
You can kind of struck with his arms
like rubber bands flying around,
but I mean he's a combination of a lot
of things.
He has a brilliant team.
John kavanagh is coach is a brilliant
coach.
She's got,
you know,
amazing jujitsu,
coaching and striking coaching in his
mind.
He just,
he understands how to apply these things
and his ability to perform under
pressure.
This is fantastic.
You saw that in the mayweather fight.
I mean even though he lost that fight,
he hit me with some pretty good shots
and he won the first three rounds
against the greatest boxer of all time.
So then the extraordinary,
extraordinary.
I mean you can say easily that made
whether it was taking those rounds off
and I agree he was,
and you could say that may,
whether it was bringing them to deep
water because he knew it would exhaust
him because he didn't give him enough
time to train for it because you really
only gave them two months.
It was very brilliant.
I made with his part.
He knew that he wouldn't be efficient.
He would tire.
Although as a kinetic,
big explosive movements at conor likes
to do their very taxing and he knew that
he was not going to have the efficiency
to go 12 hard rounds with a master
defensive fighter like mayweather and
made whether it was right,
but he didn't want to get hit with that
upper cut that he got cracked within the
first round.
He didn't want to to to like connor's
movement was very unusual.
It took floyd a while to decipher.
It has been way better for him if he
just blew connor out of the water from
one round on and just completely
outclassed him.
But he didn't.
And one of the reasons why I didn't is
because connor's an extraordinary person
and he has greatness.
Greatness.
I mean he didn't really have the proper
opportunity in only being able to
prepare for two months and only having
this one professional boxing match.
There was a lot of things stacked
against him and yet I feel,
although he clearly lost,
he performed admirably.
I don't think it hurts his stock in any
way.
I think it elevates them and I think his
next fight in the ufc,
a whoever it would will be will be
probably the biggest fight in ufc
history if they can do it correctly,
depending upon who it is,
especially if it's nate diaz.
Nate diaz is a huge name and if nate
diaz and him decided to do it one more
time,
I think that would be the biggest fight
ever in the historY of the sport because
I think connor has eclipsed the sport
largely,
you know,
and,
and maybe for now maybe someone else
will come along in the next year or two
that,
that does it.
I mean look has only been around for a
few years.
I tweeted to him in 2013 or 14,
I forget what it was when he had won a
big fight in the uk and I said,
congratulations on an amazing
performance.
I really hope to see in the ufc someday.
That was like four years ago.
Oh my god.
The most.
So in four years he's gone from being
this unknown fighter that only like the
really hardcore fanatics,
like myself knew about to him being this
worldwide phenomena.
He's the biggest combat sport athlete,
not just of today,
ever.
There's no one like him.
No one like him,
no one that has the kind of popularity
that he has.
I mean,
this fucking guy has thousands and
thousands of people fly from Ireland to
vegas.
Every time he fights the weigh ins.
It seems like you're in dublin.
I mean,
it's fucking crazy,
man.
When you look out,
when I,
when I interview him at the weigh ins in
the ufc in vegas,
you look out,
you see nothing but irish flags.
You see people screaming and cheering
and singing.
Mandalay bay during the floyd mayweather
fight,
which is not even the venue where the
fight was being held.
Mandalay bay was packed.
Bumper to bumper with irishman walking
down the hallway,
cheering and singing songs in sync.
It was insane.
Brilliant.
There's no one like him.
Is that.
First of all,
you have to have the greatness.
Like we've had the greatest.
Who gives a fuck?
He's just another person because like I
said about van gough,
you know,
like,
it gives a fuck if you cut your ear off,
if you paint paintings,
have god be good,
game is good,
but then like the law,
there are often great geniuses in sport,
but to have that,
like you say,
this fall that he used like that
romantic ideas of Ireland and he's an
irish ness,
that became an important part of his
perception,
but it's obviously resonating in a very,
very powerful way to have that kind of
devotion or Ireland.
Ireland's
very important.
Ireland's a very important part of the
equation as well because their
appreciation and love and support of
him.
It's unprecedented.
I mean,
I've seen brazilian fans that love josie
aldo and I've seen brazilian fans that
love anderson silva and you know,
the worshiped by their countrymen,
but it pales in comparison to the amount
of love that conor mcgregor gatz.
I understand.
Then then myth aligns with his myth,
the myth of the irish people as being
oppressed by british colonialism and
having to fight for their freedom.
It resonates with what this man
represents and perhaps this is always
what happens with figures of greatness,
whether it's within the realm of sport
or within the realm of politics,
temporarily a person sort of captures a
particular mood,
a particular energy,
and this is what I think again,
is to do with unconsciousness.
I don't think people are go like a con,
like are aware of these kinds of
feelings.
I think it's stimulated on a level
that's not about for.
This is one of the things I'm very
interested in what lies beyond the
rational.
You know,
what lexia,
we can equate,
we can work out,
we can just.
But there seems to be some ingredient
even in conor mcgregor that you can't
quite pin down.
Yes,
there's the greatness as a boxer.
Yes.
The irish people,
you know,
but there's also some flavor is being
caught and I wonder if you can ever
preempt or understand these things.
I wOnder if you can ever drill down,
but like the sort of the work of Joseph
Campbell,
the work of Carl Young,
the worker bees people to say,
oh,
they are unconscious archetypes.
There are unconscious themes,
there were stories that are running
below the surface,
patterns,
coordInates that can be connected to.
Some people will not believe the
profession of in know how to harness
these energies.
If you have enough people feeling not
good enough,
they will spend money trying to feel
better,
whether it's the purchase of a car or a
coffee or whatever it is.
One of the key ingredient is make people
feel not good enough.
If you can rehab and redirect people's
sexual eNergy so that their sexual
energy is directed at products and
consumerism,
then you will sell Your product.
But for me it seems like such a shame to
waste this force,
to waste this knowledge,
to waste his energy just to turn people
into consumers just to turn everything
on this planet into a commodity when
what we could be doing is using these
energy to imagine new worlds,
to imagine new systems,
to use our greatness,
to use our greatness to.
I don't know,
Joe Love one another to create new
tribes.
I mean,
I don't know if he.
You.
Boy,
you tied a lot of things together.
There was.
It was pretty,
pretty good rent that coffee's really
kicked in and actually that's no joke.
That's serious.
I think I could do another one.
I think I won't fucking handling 250
milligrams.
I'll mainland this shit.
I'll pour mii you want another one?
I do like it.
You do have a terrible drug problem.
It is a drug.
I mean,
what were you saying about connor's?
I think undeniable.
He's a hero and he dares to be great.
I mean he dares to be great in a way
that very few people do and he stands in
front of the opponent and looks at the
entire crowd and goes and goes like that
and puts his hands up like that.
I mean literally is like some
archetypical fixture figure from the
past.
I mean beautiful.
I mean what he's also doing by doing
that,
he's like,
he's letting the opponent realize like
you're in there with greatness.
You're in there with someone who's
incredibly comfortable in the moment and
someone who truly believes that he's
great and the results that he's had,
like you can't deny that they have a
factor in,
in his future success and in the way
people love them,
the way knocked out.
Although with one punch to win the
title,
I mean this giant buildup over this long
period of time and then he just fucking
starches them with one shot,
13 seconds of the fight and the
deafening roar.
The irish in that arena,
when that happened was it was fucking
insane.
He's like a hero,
like a mythical creature.
I suppose the role of the hero is to
embody and represent some inspire to
inspire,
inspire the crowd to put me right.
Those people,
those 15,000
plus people that saw that fight,
who knows how much energy that gave them
to then go forth and pursue their own
dreams because that's a big part of what
heroes represent.
What a what a big part of someone who's
accomplishing anything spectacular.
It's not just that people get to watch
it and get this thrill of watching this
experience,
but also that you get energized to go
and pursue your own ideas.
Yes,
yes.
This is true.
I agree.
But,
uh,
I think an integral component of the
mythic figure of the hero is sacrificing
fucking credit.
I'm in the bloody world judge conor
mcgregor and any stage from any angle
because people that are brave enough to
do that,
it's fucking unbelievable.
But like the,
what I've felt it while it resonates,
we've asked when somebody is willing to
sacrifice themselves is because it
temporarily makes us recognize when
someone's willing to die for what they
believe in.
Whether that is,
you know,
these civil rights leaders and miserable
for malcolm x knew he was going to die
for doing that.
And he did it anyway.
Gandy had a good sense that he was going
to die.
He did it anyway because what he
believed in was more important than what
he was as an individual.
And I think that when that happens,
it reminds us,
oh,
there's something like you say,
inspire.
It puts breath into us.
It reminds us we have the capacity for
greatness and we are not just contained
by our body.
We all these streams of energy in that
moment,
perhaps there is no disconnection
between conor mcgregor in that crowd.
There is a oneness of purpose in that
single punch punching for all of them in
that moment.
The only thing that saddens me is that
is ultimately not ultimately,
but at least seemingly housed by an
economic idea.
That's the old thing that prisons are
the sort of contains it.
Do you know what I mean?
You got to pay money to go there.
Ultimately,
it's a commodified thing.
Conor mcgregor is a commodity that all
that makes people aware of the stakes
that are at hand,
that makes people aware of the magnitude
of the event.
If you can get pack 22,000
people into an arena like that,
it makes people aware of the magnitude
of it all.
If it just happens on a soccer field,
no one's watching.
It's not the same.
No,
you're quite right.
I'm not criticizing the crowd because
they're or because the crowd is
important and that's what it's doing.
It's representing something bigger,
but I feel like it's a shame and I feel
I say when you take it like we've taken
into the arts because there's more
sensitivity,
it's more cerebral and it's less
embodied,
so ca qubein.
He's like someone like,
you know,
like someone in the matrix waking up in
their pod.
He woke up in the pot of fuck,
you know,
he knew he was a genius.
He knew that he was connecting with
people.
He knew it was representing something
and we also use mentally ill and a drug
addict and he killed himself and it.
But I think that there is a sort of a
comparison there that he knew that he
was becoming commodified.
He was being reduced to a commodity.
He woke up in the pod and for our fuck,
all of these things that are coming from
my heart,
this truth,
I isolation,
alienation,
the kinds of things that he was singing
about,
that in itself became a product.
The machine can handle it.
The machine can take people talking
about that connecting to people's
deepest fears of India that inadequacy
and worthlessness and it can turn that
into a product and sell it to them.
I think you're getting caught up in
money as always being a negative anD I
think connor is actually eMbrace The
money as a part of the narrative and I
think you know another person who's done
that without bragging about that as
manny pacquiao,
manny pacquiao was made hundreds of
millions of dollars in the same form,
has actually used that to spread well
throughout the Philippines and hands out
money to people and he's famously.
I'm generous in that regard and I think
with connor's done is it's part of his
hero mythologies and he's sitting on a.
He's sitting on a throne on a pile of
gold.
It's really a part of it all.
He's a king.
He is a hero.
Now the heart of the story,
I'm not criticizing him as an individual
and saying,
conor mcgregor the money.
Yes,
but I'm criticizing the seed.
Money is a part of the story.
It's not necessarily negative and I
don't think it is negative at all,
but joe money is literally a symbol.
It is nothing but that represent
something.
I promised to pay the bearer.
we believe this is one up in semantics
because he could definitely go out and
buy a house with that.
Money is real as fuck.
Like he can go out and buy mansions and
cars.
It's real as fuck.
The idea that it represents like,
I promise to give you this.
Yes,
it's a promissory note,
but it's fucking real.
You know,
he has all that.
He has 100 million dollars.
It is a part of the store.
He is sitting on a throne on a pile of
gold.
He does have a crown,
is a crown on his fucking neck.
I mean it's real.
I'm not like,
like I don't see conor mcgregor is the
terminus of this point.
I see.
This is an opportunity to critique what
the culture is telling us and what the
culture is doing to us.
They're,
you know,
I understand that,
with money you can acquire goods and
services,
but what I'm saying is,
is that our system for evaluate in worth
has become about commodities instead of
perhaps about beauty or about love.
Not like,
you know,
I'm not saying that conor mcgregor
should give away all this money and
start marchIng around a be the new jesus
of Ireland.
Then that will be fucking fascinating to
watch unfold.
I'm saying that isn't
it discussed question,
is it not a little unfortunate,
but greatness is ultimately given to us
as a product that that is how it is
received.
That's how it's understood.
Is it possible that there will be other
ways of demonstrating greatness as he
does?
you know when he's fighting?
Yes,
kurt cobain did when he was playing,
but ultimately the dominant thing,
that dominant puppet here,
the thing pulling the strings is the
dollar.
I don't tHink it is.
I think it's a part of the story.
Much like you know,
your clothes are a part of,
you know,
what you look like.
I don't think it's the dominant thing.
I think it's a big part of how you sell
it,
like this is going to be the biggest
fight ever.
He's going to make x million dollars and
the way condamine,
but connor uses that as a part of his
narrative.
He drives around in a drop top bentley
and he's,
you know,
he's got beautiful watches and suits and
say fuck you,
and pin striping.
I mean it's part of what he's done by.
By creating this incredible mythology
mean.
I don't think it's necessarily in any
way,
shape or form negative.
I think it's a part of the story.
Say with hip hop,
right?
This is possibly a similar way of
looking at the same idea and this isn't
saying I know the answer to.
Do you know what I mean?
Sure.
I'm not.
The kind of work is being out and I want
to teach you there.
I'm not going.
I'm trying to fucking work out myself.
Say with hip hop,
hip hop first.
When it comes out,
it comes out as this angry raw.
No,
not really pay.
Originally it came out as like a happy
ron,
a hip hop hibbett to the hippity hip hop
activity beat.
Don't stop this bit with
for combat or at the beginning and then
like it becomes a social whole.
Yeah,
sure.
Heal and bambara and yesterday early hip
hop pioneers and then we go through this
sort of that phase of.
Yeah,
you're right.
It goes through the early part of it.
Jolly
alliance to rap,
gangster rap,
like anger of we are going to have a
voice straight outta compton.
Amazing.
And then that in itself becomes about
like what is the subsequent mutations of
hip hop as it becomes sort of claimed by
a dominant system.
It becomes about jewelry,
bling,
particular attitudes and lou,
do you not see what I'm saying that
there's sort of almost like a trend.
Things get pulled into a certain strand,
a certain way of being.
It
does,
but it doesn't have to look.
It didn't with some guys like the really
like here's a perfect example,
one of the best rappers ever,
nas,
nas never fell into that.
Nas remains one of the best lyricists of
all time remains brilliant.
All of his rap has meaning.
It's creative,
it's interesting.
He doesn't fall into all the bullshit
and the bling,
although he has plenty of money and he
has all the trappings.
He's got this sort of style about him
where I believe his father was a jazz
musician and he grew up with,
you know,
with art in his family and he's an
artist first and foremost,
and although he's a brilliant rapper,
he's my favorite rapper.
I think that he's never really fallen
into all the bullshit blang,
mansions,
all that stuff.
Like the display of it all.
I mean he has these things but it's not
the primary display when you're talking
about nas,
like as an artist,
as a musician and because again,
like I suppose what I'm interested in is
how like sort of cultural movements
start off.
It seems by saying something that's
important and powerful,
whether it's punk or hip hop like
becomes a voice to the disembodied or a
way of conveying a embodied
disenfranchised comes a voice for them.
Or like in a similar thing with punk
punk.
Very observable because it was
relatively short term movement.
The bands like the pistols and the clash
and all these stuff,
these bands come out of england and it
quickly became sort of commodified and
sold back to people.
What I'm saying is is like that,
and this could be resolved,
this.
I'm now during the second candidate
caveman coffee in his skin deep.
the pimps in my mind.
This is too much for one man.
I think it's 5:40
for the two kiDs as well.
Do the dMT now.
I'm almost there.
So like um,
what I'm saying is,
is that things start with this original
germ greatness,
a glory heroism,
but there's anger and there's an
external system though joe,
that can turn into a product and sell it
to people.
And I think that that does strip it of
its,
of its real value and you all saying,
I suppose no,
it doesn't matter.
It doesn't have.
That can just be the architecture of it
or the,
the aspects of it.
And I'm just saying as long as we have a
system that is ultimately about making
money and turning everything into
profit.
And that's what I'm not saying this
about any of the individualized.
In fact that's the point I'm making.
He is great now as this great,
great,
great.
But ultimately you great me great.
We're like,
please god like a pool.
But everyone's pulled in the direction
of prophets of like is a thing you've
got to swIm for.
Like now as we become free,
is there something different that could
be done here?
Can something truly glorious?
Be down here.
Like when you describe that moment of
vegas temporarily being overwhelmed
noise.
It has been in recent days by tragedy,
death and blood,
but it a glorious spirit of Ireland and
a hero that isn't the unfortunate that
that energy can't be literally used to
create better worlds,
better systems,
better lives or that really happens is a
load of people make bunch of money and
probably.
And I don't necessarily mean the fucking
protagonists,
you know what I mean?
Like people talk a lot about our
athletes and too much money I don't
agree with.
That's one of the few ways that fucking
ordinary working class people can make a
lot of money.
But there are people at the top of that
chain is siphoning significant amount of
money.
I've all of those little industries,
you know,
so.
But that's my question.
Responsible for making it happen in the
first place.
I mean you can't leave It up to the
athletes to put something like that
together.
You need a dana,
why you need a floyd mayweather and
money.
The money team productions.
You need people to promote it.
You need people to put together a press
junket and a world tour and then you
need people to organize the paper view
and then ben.
Then the real ultimate result is the
inspiration that all the people that
watch it get the inspiration,
the entertainment,
and it's completely up to the individual
whether or not they pursue greatness or
whether they just pursue money and it's
a trap if there's trappings in both ways
is the trappings of greatness with no
money.
There's the sadness of someone who dies
great,
but penniless and homeless.
and then there's the guy who just threw
it all away from money and that never
ever realized its full potential.
Which is equally sad.
But I think the in that is that we are
showing a particular aspect of our own
conditioning there in believing in the
myth of the individual,
but the Individual will always try and
if you have greatness,
you know.
But like now you did say like the great
person that dies penniless know it's a
kind of a shame that we don't create
benevolent systems that are helpful to
the vulnerable.
Wherever you're talking about sport,
right?
If you're talking about is completely.
I mean,
look,
there has to be some sort of a support
team behind the individual,
but it's deplete completely dependent
upon the individual.
If you don't have john cavanagh,
you don't have a straight blast gym,
you don't have ido portal and then dylan
dannis and all the different people that
train connor.
You don't have connor.
But if you have all those things,
it's entirely dependent upon the one
individual that takes that knowledge and
goes in there and performs.
That's what's so scary about It and
that's what's so rewarding to people
that watch it because they know it's so
dangerous.
It's so crazy.
It's so fraught with peril to be the one
that's so much lies upon the the one
that the weight on his shoulders is
massive and that's one of the most
substantial things and the most
impressive things about connor is the
way it handles the weight of the
pressure that it goes in there and does
this in in the giant big moment that he
stands there in front of everybody and
throws his arms out like he's the king
and then everybody goes fucking crazy.
That he's glorious.
Yes.
It's nothing to do with money.
It seems like it does,
but money is a part of it all its
greatness.
Greatness is the thing.
The money is a side effect of greatness.
That shit when he does that,
I don't mean come on man.
Beautiful case that because I don't ever
want conor mcgregor to listen to this
and things like brian's criticized.
We didn't make like fucking shoulders on
that son of a bitch.
Especially that left.
No wonder why knocked people dead easy.
It's hard to tell from the angle,
but big fucks people up at that left
hand.
Boy,
this is not a critique of any
individual.
This is my.
I'm trying to understand how systems
work and that's why I'm trying to
understand and I'm suggesting that
they're all favorite ways of doing
things.
Even they let me say this,
this system doesn't mean jack shit.
If someone can't rise,
this guy is dIfferent.
Okay?
It's the system exists all day long,
24 slash seven,
three 65.
The systems going on this weekend in
vegas,
there's going to be to world title
fights.
It's not nearly the amount of attention
being paid to these two world title
fights this weekend is conor mcgregor
pulling his dick out and taking a piss
in a punch bowl.
He could do that on paper view and more
people would watch it.
Why?
Because he's done so much In the past as
an individual.
The greatness that he is shown,
it's.
It's more than just money.
It's more than just the system.
The system exists.
It's a matter of one person figuring out
the frequency that this system operates
on and showing this unbelievable
performance inside that system and
that's the individual and that
individual is.
When you talk about his past,
when he,
you know,
he was,
he was working as a construction worker
or as a plumber or some shit and you
know,
he'd done some amateur boxing and some
mma fights.
He was a regular guy.
He grew up in a working class
neighborhood.
He wasn't rich.
He wasn't.
There's nothing substantial about him.
He even his own parents say they never
thought that he was going to be this
guy.
He figured out a way through it.
He wasn't born the king.
He wasn't some,
some person who,
you know what,
for whatever reason was gifted with this
existence,
you know,
he worked his way through it,
figured it out,
and once he got to the greatest stage in
the world when the pressure was at its
highest,
he shown like the brightest star in the
universe.
And that's What's so exciting about him.
Yes,
I think he's beautiful and fascinating,
but my question is about
commodification.
Money freak.
You're free.
You're not free to amend that,
hold them,
but when you say you take a look at the
empty right or take a lot,
I've taken a few taking it 99 times.
When you have them experiences,
what does it,
when you come back from it,
what is it that you feel about the way
that systems are organized?
Do you know?
Do you come back from it quite
fatalistic?
Like,
oh yeah,
that's just the way the world is.
Do you Think?
Hold on a minute.
It's fucking mental.
There's so much stuff going on.
Things could be different,
but I don't think about the way that you
think about.
I don't think about these systems.
I think you spent a lot of time thinking
about the elites in the one percent and
the systems.
Um,
I don't,
I don't think about that stuff very
much.
nor do I think mostly about why I'm
interested in is god and oneness.
And I think that greatness is a
representation of god.
I think that is coming through conor
mcgregor or kurt cobain or jimi hendrix
or Dorothy Parker is some kind of the
beauty that that person is the perfect
vessel for iconography is the
realization of greatness or the
realization of god in inverted commerce.
Given them this is the singing,
the stO playing the star spangled banner
at woodstock.
unbelievable.
Here is some,
some moment that pulls us all together.
Now what my curiosity is about the empty
is that does dmt make you experience
that oneness or that loss of self in a
way that's kind of religious or
spiritual?
What does it do to your tense loss of
self?
I mean as intense as any thing,
but it's.
It's
not even.
I shouldn't say as there's no
comparison.
I shouldn't say as intense as anything
because there's not a word
that I could say that's going to come
out of my mouth.
It's going to do it justice.
The words haven't been invented.
They don't exist because it does all
words that we have created.
They represent things that we can
reference in the material world.
When you.
When you have a dmt experience,
you're literally having a conversation
with god.
You're experiencing something that's
everything and something that's
infinitely powerful infinitely wise.
The way I've described it,
as you're seeing this insane,
infinite world of complex geometric
patterns that are made out of love and
understanding,
right?
Right.
But there's things in there that might
have these entities.
He feels something in there that knows
you and I don't know if it's you that
knows you.
It's like you that gets your bullshit
separations.
Dissolve is my,
is my.
My suspicion is that there is no
separate.
There is no subject object.
There is only oneness.
Now you yourself just said,
it's about starts to feel like it's
about loving and one show.
So that level of consciousness exists.
So my belief is that our systems we
have,
our athletic systems are in attainment
systems and certainly our economic,
political and social systems should be
as close to as possible to that feeling,
but that feeling should be our guiding
light.
So I'm not criticizing conor mcgregor,
the great genius who like I'm fascinated
by and door all kumbaya know anyone.
I'm just saying,
isn't it odd that you have personally
experienced in your way through dmt and
I have free yoga and meditation and she,
I'm,
when I was a kid,
they sense of oneness,
this love that seems to transcend my
personal form and everything I believe
in and yet when it comes to our systems
for organizing this plane that we live
on,
the material plane,
the choices we make are not about that
love and understanding there about the
kind of a,
about resources and elitism,
you know,
so he's interested in the one percent
and all that stuff.
I'm a bit interested,
but what more interested in is why are
our systems not more representative of
the divine puba truth that we can access
through spirituality?
Well,
I think our systems are based on the
monkey need for survival and this sort
of.
That's not good is it?
We should get beyond that.
Well,
I think we will,
but I think it takes a long fuCking
time.
Just like we were talking about before.
I mean,
unless you want to get the world to do
dmt tomorrow.
I mean,
if we had a dmt day,
boy,
that would change a lot of shit.
I'm very interested in that.
I think that's the role of the role of
the shame and the role of the artist I
think is the role of the comic and even
the role of the shaman.
I mean that's important point that gets.
That gets distorted.
There's a lot of people that go down to
south America because they have this
romantic vision of what a shaman is
going to do to them and that they're
going to go and experience and then
they.
They encounter some shyster who really
just learned how to make iowasca to prey
on gringos.
I mean that's.
That's a big,
big part of the narrative that a lot of
people experience when they go down and
do that with the wrong people or.
Yeah,
I'm not happens mainly thing because of
systems of commodification.
Materialism and profiteering does,
but it also.
It happens because people are just like
looking at an opportunity there.
They're opportunistic.
They're.
They're desperate.
Maybe they had been mistreated,
maybe they,
they don't.
They don't have a particularly healthy
view of human beings.
Well,
I recognize this.
I'm standing for men in my mind just
over the course of this conversation.
It's like,
like you said earlier,
there's the potential for good and the
potential for bad in all of us.
Sure.
But I see our culture as a magnet and
the magnet is pulling out the worst
stuff and what I think is it would be
possible to have a magnet that was
pulling out the best stuff,
but it has some
the best of to like what happened in
houston.
Okay.
They have this giant hurricane that
comes down in houston and I have put my
friend John Dudley went down down there
and brought supplies and was feeding
people and organized a bunch of other
people to help and do the same thing and
there was a ton of people that were
doing the same ton of people that were
donating their time and their money and
they were using their boats to help get
people out of their homes.
And there's a video that I saw.
There was an amazing video.
These two guys talking after they didn't
even know each other and they were,
they were,
they were being interviewed and they
were saying that the love that they
experienced helping all these people
pull,
pulling them out of the wreckage of this
horrible natural disaster that was.
It was like nothing they'd ever felt
that this love was amazing,
that all these people were being
completely altruistic.
They being completely generous and just
helping and just the I think in times of
crisis.
Are you familiar with sebastian younger?
No.
Sebastian younger is an amazing war
journalist and he wrote a great book
Called tribe and his.
His book is essentially all about how
human beings really only feel at their
best and they're happiest when they are
coming together to overcome something
and so that in this,
in this moment of overcoming this
incredible natural disaster that you
blame it on industrial capitalism and
global warming,
blame all that on the fucking the
hurricane.
At the end of the day,
it's a force of nature that no one saw
coming.
No one can.
There's no one that pulled that trigger.
Right?
There's a guy in vegas that pulled that
trigger,
but there's no one that pulled the
trigger on that hurricane.
It was collective.
It was,
it was.
It was a thing of nature.
I don't do that together.
That is beautiful.
What a coffee.
Agree that anything we're human beings
come together like that is glorious.
But both of those examples that you're
using as you yourself alluded to,
you know,
you can look at what conditions create
hurricane maybe,
possibly.
Yeah.
No.
We don't know.
They could have that hurricane.
Has hurricanes have happened forever,
but that's my point.
That's only 50 percent.
The other 50 percent of my point is that
that guy pulling the trigger isn't just
an individual.
He is,
like you said when I was touching you on
the fucking shaming thing,
they all,
maybe that shaman had a bad day and
that's why it's become a slippery
shaman.
Well,
no,
that's a great band.
Slippery shaman like so,
like,
so this guy,
the shoot,
like of course we all have individual
culpability,
but similarly he is a product of our
culture is a product of this again,
system.
So like,
you know,
there is one form of analysis
that says a meteorological disasters.
They're detached from reality and of
course meteorology is its own fucking
thing and individual freewill near.
There are some newer,
I'm sure you know,
say that doesn't even fucking exists for
out in nature out in a meteorology.
The biochemistry of our system is
governing everything.
But certainly there are connections
between each of us that create the way
that we behave.
You know,
if like if,
if I haven't experienced in here where I
walk out feeling intimidated,
maybe I'll be less kind to the people I
work with,
a less extreme example of a brutal
murders and the more obvious example
aware of it,
we're aware of it,
which is one of the reasons why
altruistic behavior kind behavior,
loving community,
these,
all these things are rewarded because we
do understand that those do enforce a
better way of people behaving.
And that real determinism.
Like people like if you,
if you really truly don't have freewill,
well we know that we would like people
to behave kinder because whatever
factors that play into people going out
and behaving in a nicer,
kinder way,
there are part of that that we know that
that's the fuel of that
so isn't then the role of us as
individuals finding our own conor
mcgregor,
our own greatness,
out own heroism to create as much as
possible a spice for the altruism,
a spice for that philanthropy,
a space for that togetherness to create
those moments,
like you said,
without hurricane web and we've all
experienced there.
I know when I do something nice for
other people,
I start to feel,
oh,
this is what I'm meant to be.
This is what I'm meant to be doing.
But I in my own personal life gets
sidetracked by our fuck.
I've got these economic imperatives on
want to fucking feel great about myself
because of other people's applause or
you know,
verification like it like because we are
all flawed because we are continually
going to battle between the monkey in
us.
The primary little creature in us.
And the great angel within us,
what if we have an agreement on a social
level that what we're aiming towards is
the most benevolent,
the most beautiful,
and on an individual level we try and do
it,
and communally we encourage each other
towards it knowing that we're going to
fuck up and fail all the time,
but that we're heading in that direction
together instead of what we have,
which is a system that is about make as
much money as you can and get out.
You only have 100 years line up the blow
jobs.
That is the system that we have that is
capitalist consumers and that's what
it's based on.
This is a machine.
The machine makes money.
It's got to have infinite expanse and
infinite growth.
That is,
that is the system.
I'm not saying that it's very fatalistic
way.
It look fantastic.
I think we can change the world
doing it.
And you're not.
You're not living that way.
So the system that you're talking about,
it's escapable you've escaped.
Yes.
And we.
We're talking about it and it's just no,
there's no like willy wonka golden
ticket that's going to get you out of
the system.
I don't trust him.
Shady fucking on polymers.
Where do you get them?
I doN't think I should even be working
there.
Too much chocolate loss in that truck
though.
That poor boy drowning.
And there was johnny depp behaving like
a young girl.
I've been lucky.
A fucking movie man.
He's a weird way of talking.
A lot of questions.
I think it was about Michael Jackson,
chocolate chocolates,
the peter pan type deal that clean.
I don't want to grow up you.
I think you need to go back to it.
There is.
It's chocolate factory.
Johnny.
Look at my.
And I think,
uh,
this fatalistic thing that it's just
designed to.
It's.
I don't think it's designed to do
anything.
I just think it is,
it just,
it is an agree with that.
I even agree with that.
I think.
I think that what we live in is the
manifestation of our most primal
desires.
Greed or not even necessarily great
survival.
And I think that if you extrapolate on
that system,
you end up with what we've got,
but I think an alternative way of being
something that might be a corrective
path for us is to look at those.
This feelings that you described of the
altruism in that hurricane,
the feeling of greatness in an
individual and the way that an
individual can pull communities together
is sort of like a.
It's not a binary choice.
I know the world's more complicated than
that joe.
But like I suppose my quest and indeed
fuck me,
my book is about how I individually have
got my head and I wrenched myself away
from selfishness and greed and pride on
a daily basis and pull myself towards
our tourism and love and self betterment
apart of it.
Keep myself fit mentally,
spiritually.
So I can be a better part of this.
Excuse me,
system and perhaps through myself,
improvement create better systems
because there is all this energy.
There's all this power.
And I think it's a shame that it gets
siphoned in a particular direction.
Well that,
that feeling you express and as you
express it and express it,
honestly,
that resonates with people and I think
this,
what we're talking about is the 49 point
nine percent and 50 point one percent
that rick strassman was describing.
It was this constant battle and it is
not an easy path.
I don't think the system operates it.
The 50,
49,
therefore I think the system's way way
towards the negative system like a
cultural system and the economic system,
human beings in this world is a
capitalist country or where they say I
don't know enough about what goes down
in China.
So I'll say like sort of global
capitalism.
Say and again I'm not a fucking
economist.
I'm just picking up shit from listening
to your podcast and have a podcast,
you know?
I mean that's where I'm getting
educated.
I've luckily turned up at university of
lately.
I'm tripping on that fucking coffee,
man.
Man.
Deep.
Can I go to the toilet and maybe the
poor hell have I been in here?
Do you feel like I've done enough about
my book?
We've done two hours and 20 minutes.
We could wrap this fucking got a clock
there.
You've got these advantages.
There's buddhas in every direction and
only one clock I didn't know at the time
is a clock there.
There's a clock there.
There's.
They're all facing you.
Facing anybody who was a guest to think
about time.
This is a tune one.
This system.
Yeah.
I'm just some johnny come lately.
Kid from england with a dream weaver a
I'll come
over here to the layer,
a dream to sell books.
I'm just a kid.
He wants to fuck the system,
but by my book out of that,
obviously polk.
Chrissy,
how dAre you point out.
That obviously puts it.
Cannot do a wait.
No.
Yeah,
yeah.
You're bad.
You're good.
Typically we're open that door and the
first one.
Yeah.
Nah man.
It's beautiful.
Don't worry about it.
No,
no,
no.
You're good man.
Don't worry.
You're good.
Told you that caveman coffee.
Who's going to get them?
You were gonna.
Pull something up about nas.
I think I had something I didn't know if
you knew he was a venture capitalist.
Um,
I mean like I know you opens up a
restaurant up that sweet chick place
potentially if there's companies sell
soon,
I don't know how that happens.
Or if it comes public,
he could be what they're saying is hip
hop's first true billionaire.
Yeah,
no worries.
Says it's only like if that slipper
network,
there's like $17 million.
That doesn't include all the companies
he owns and has been investing in for a
long time.
No,
I didn't know about that.
I knew
about his restaurant because I'm friends
with everlast and everlast goes to that
sweet chick.
I think everlast was a piece of that
too.
I don't know,
maybe he doesn't,
but he took me to it in New York and
took me to an la once we went there.
But if they were playing music that was
so loud,
it was literally hurting my ears.
Nas is like half man,
half venture capitalists look at that
beautiful suit.
He's gone on.
He's got a pocket square and like a
little small chain.
Have you ever seen the small chain?
I don't know now with the.
I don't know.
Interesting.
Yeah,
there's a lot of those motherfuckers
make a shit ton of money.
Smart.
Why not?
You know,
I mean it shows you that they could
figure out a way through just their art
to get to this weird position where I
mean if not really does make a Billion
dollars.
Like fuck still makes amazing music
though.
That's my point.
My point is that his music never went
commercial smoothies.
It's fucking fantastic.
Someone was saying I was reading some
stuff that he supposedly tried.
Remember he had a rap battle up beef had
a couple of beats jz with like puff
daddy the hate me now thing.
Oh that he like,
he also wrote,
ghost wrote for wilson myth.
I don't know what that really means.
He's sold out,
but that's not selling out.
That's just writing for a friend.
But the rap battles I think is more just
an ego thing.
Someone talk shit about him.
He talks shit about them.
Yeah,
you know,
you all right brother.
You got a copy of your book.
You're not fucking around.
You brought a copy back.
Now if you want to show everybody here,
give it to me.
I'll hold it up so you don't feel bad.
Vanna white.
I like joe rogan.
I'm wanting to experience freedom from
our addictions,
russell brand.
Ladies and gentlemen,
let's wrap this thing up man.
We've talked for two hours and 20
minutes.
That's good.
Beautiful.
You kicked it,
kicked it into the fucking orbit.
I didn't change the bit that I wrote
about you as a matter of fact because I
didn't know you wrote about me in there.
Yeah,
yeah.
Now you fucking interested.
Oh man.
I'm feeling
good.
It was slightly because what it was I
realized I asked them to put in the word
seemingly because I thought that I'd
been to reductive and you know me like
I'm having this experience like is part
of the book is about trying to explain
how in the addict's mind you're trapped
in this constant cycle,
own self obsessive for an outside world
seems so massIve distance and you can't
connect to it.
Right?
So as well as explain Now to go through
the steps.
I talk through like this is what it's
like to be in mY fucking head.
So I'm like,
this is me out with my dog,
I'm a dog,
causes all these problems all the time,
and I run into these people and say,
all I know,
I've run into them and I start,
I don't want to go and talk to them
because I feel so self conscious because
I've looked kind of like cool.
And I think,
oh no,
I've got these people.
I'm going to feel inadequate.
All I know is how I feel and that's all
I'll ever know unless I learn.
I can learn a new system for being bill.
This guy comes over and says hello while
I stand now on the goose.
Shit,
we're on this sort of riverbank.
Vaguely embarrassed by bear.
My dog bears looping enthusiasm.
I heard you on joe rogan.
He says,
joe rogan,
the former mixed martial artist
commentate a comedian and host of the
world's most downloaded podcast is
himself an interesting example of new
emerging models of masculinity,
a fusion of right wing individualism,
a new age tolerance,
a fierce auto didact.
he has become a champion of american
libertarianism is to me,
fascinating because he's clever and a
good fighter.
There you go.
There's me mentioning you in passing
now.
I went over whenever he wrote here.
I said,
you better put in seemingly because I
think a footnote in reductive.
They're saying miksang,
right wing individualism and newark,
but what do you think about that,
joe?
They are.
I don't know how much right wing I have
in me.
I'm exactly libertarian libertarian
right wing stuff is probably,
if you talk to a real bright winger,
they'd go,
what the fuck you're talking about?
Yeah,
I think you're right.
I mean,
I think a lot of libertarianism would
have sort of covered it better,
but this was written a point where I
didn't.
I hadn't listened to as much stuff,
so I've changed in this amount.
You can come on here anytime you Want.
I love talking to you.
You're awesome.
Do you think so?
We have a great time.
We did have a great time there.
We.
I'm looking forward to going back to
your new studio.
That sounds like your own version of a
willy wonka podcast.
Land be crazy.
The thing is,
you know,
like this is why I don't take drugs is
because I've drank caffeine there and
I'm sort of slightly scared of going
back to like my normal life in a
parachute in,
back into that fucking brand.
Ladies and gentlemen,
joe rogan ebook.
Download your podcast.
What is it?
Go under the skin with russell brand
under the skin with russell brand.
Goodbye everybody.