Do Do, do,
do Cho motherfucking d a sub
brother on the drive up here.
I was thinking about all the busted ass
holes that are in the hospital today
from the Gay Pride Parade.
Can you imagine how many guys went down
there just to say I ended up getting
fucked in the ass by the same time,
Bro. Let me tell you something.
That was one of the biggest turnouts my
friend went and he said he had a fucking
blast. One of my guerrilla buddies said
he had a blast. Blast gay people. Great.
And fucking New York all over. Everywhere.
Everywhere they're celebrating,
they can be free. But anybody who's
got a problem with them, it's crazy.
But on the dark side, let's
talk about the facts here.
A couple of confused little young white
dudes went down there yesterday. Sure.
I'll go have a drink. Oh yeah. Some
guys who just wanted to be an ally.
Ally to the gay folks. I just want
you to know I'm not gay, but uh,
I am your ally. Next thing
you know, Chad's millionaire.
What's up brother? That's what guys
have to remember. Gay dudes are dudes.
They're all same rules apply all same
rules of scumbag Uri that apply to men
apply to gay men. Yeah.
There's like three types of gay is this
gay guys that aren't interested? Yeah,
there's gay guys or the semi interested
and the gay guys that live the converge.
It hurts my feelings as a 51 year old
man that that's still a big deal that
anyone cares at all. It
really does. It does.
It hurts my feelings because I thought
that by the time I was at fucking middle
aged 51 year old father that we'd be done
with that people wouldn't care for the
people who are gay. Like
I've all this shit to worry about of
all the shit in the world to worry about
you worrying about guys who like
guys like what do you give a fuck?
And they always go biblical.
They always go biblical.
Like it's always a, if God
wanted the be in the Bible,
all that is. That shit drives me crazy.
Where I lived in my old
house in North Hollywood,
there was a gay couple
across the street, two dudes.
One was the pilot for a major airline
and he was in the process and the other
guy got fired from target
for being a transgender.
This goes back to 2010 and they
had cats, you know, made dog.
I talked to the guys about cats.
There was an old guy down the block
that would come home and talk to him.
Like you can't talk them old white
dudes like you can't talk to them.
Can't encourage that in that neighborhood.
I don't want to do more of those
fucking assholes moving in. And I go,
they're out here feeding fucking
homeless cats. What's the
plan? Right?
So this day whenever I go to my old
neighborhood and I see him outside of that
pull over, I talked to him,
say hello. It just too sweet.
People trying to be fucking just
being who they are. Trying to be.
Who the fuck they are. I
don't. We make jokes, hey,
I make jokes and the whole
thing. But at the end of the day,
I learned the hard way. And I
talked about on stage here at night,
you were there when I said that
my daughter invited me to a party,
that she went to school with a kid and
his parents should train agenda and I
kind of weird. And
I went and on the way
out, I looked at the kid,
I seen 60 transgender people
that could come from a community.
And I saw this little kid
smiling. I'm like, Oh,
I'm adopted that kids are adopted.
Look what they're doing for that kid
that they're making them a life like,
and I closed the door and I went
in and like I said in the joke,
I hugged the lead tranny just and
now we're fucking tight. That's it.
I eat the food. Yes.
Yeah. It doesn't matter.
It does matter. The only time it
matters with me is with sports.
Just stop with that. Just stop with that.
And we're going to be fine with this.
I look, there's some statistic,
see if this is true, um,
that someone sent me that out
of the 14 states that allow, uh,
high school kids to compete
as the gender that they,
they identify with rather
than their biological gender.
In those 14 states,
transgender students are just
dominating transgender male to female.
They're just dominating,
just winning everything.
It's crazy. I know you
have problems with the box.
I have a problem between
the sports, all of it. When,
when it comes to like power sports,
like I'm not sure they've
done the work here.
I don't like this idea that every trend,
like they use the excuse of outliers and
the outliers are there some like super
athletes, right?
Like you can get a regular girl who
weighs 145 pounds or you can get,
you know, a Ronda Rousey weighs
145 pounds. You know, there's like,
there's extreme athletes that are
people that are different, right?
Like Serena Williams is clearly a
different level of athlete than a regular
person. Right. If regular girl who's
like her weight, she's just superior.
And I think that that is what you see
with some of these transgender athletes
that come over to become women. They
say, well they're no different than a,
like an an Wolfe who was like a
superior athlete. Female boxer.
You ever see in Wolf knock
girls out? No Dude Dude,
she haymakers is chick with a right
hand and say one of the most brutal one
punch knock outs you've ever seen.
Men or women, perfect technique. Boom.
She has way lays this girl Tim Bell,
she falls out cold and there's not a
whole lot of women other than maybe Amanda
noon has been. Amanda Nunez is doing
it with them. Little gloves on.
I wonder if she would be able to do
it like that with those big gloves.
I think she probably could cause she
hits that God damn hard. But you know,
you gotta judge each sport by, you know
the, the like we see Pauline Manoj,
she goes over to bare knuckle boxing.
He doesn't do that well in comparison
to say like if somebody's like,
you know,
like a really good high level striker
with knockout power with the big gloves
on. Would you put like, if you put
Deontay wilder and little gloves,
I w I don't imagine anybody
being able to take that.
He's fucking people up at like a
heavyweight with those big gloves.
So it's a different thing, you
know? So who the fuck knows?
But the idea is the outlier,
the outlier, like the, the,
if you get one superior athlete and then
you have them sort of commensurate with
a transgender athlete,
a good guy who was an athlete
who became a woman that you know,
in his thirties and they identify
as it goes through the surgery.
But how much benefit does he take of
having testosterone flow through his body
for 30 plus years? We really don't know.
It doesn't mean you
hate transgender people.
It doesn't mean you don't love everyone.
It doesn't mean you don't want everyone
to live their life and be whoever they
want to be with total freedom.
I don't think we have,
we have males compete against males for
a reason cause we feel like it's more
fair.
Even though it's not like it's not more
fair if I'm playing basketball against
Michael Jordan, that's not fair.
He's better, he's better athlete.
There's just people that are going to be
way better than you no matter what you
do.
Like if I had trained all my life to be
a better basketball player than Michael
Jordan, it's not even physically possible.
Right? So there's outliers in males,
but when the outliers, when
there's so many, you have to,
when you see so many transgender athletes
that are dominating and sports and
then when you add combat sports,
which is how I got involved in this,
when a woman was doing that,
who was a transgender woman,
just not telling anybody and
saying it was a medical issue.
Like that's fucking
crazy. We all, we know,
we want to pretend that
everyone's equal. You know,
we want inclusiveness and we want
peace. We want everyone to get along.
We want in quality one gender
equality. Okay, I get it.
I see where you're going. But
we also have to look at reality.
The reality is there's this
fucking giant physical differences.
These transgender athletes are dominating
against women who are born a woman.
They have to be a woman their whole life.
They never have 30 years of testosterone
through the throne flowing through
their veins. It's like doing steroids
for 30 years and then stopping.
It's crazy. That's what I think.
You freaking me out. You know,
I just smoked some reef. Me Too, man.
How did you get me on this subject?
I don't even know how the Fuck Oh,
transgender people, but as human beings,
I love them all. I love
everybody. Dude. I,
Eddie Izzard is one of my favorite
guests of all time. He's so interesting.
He's been transgender since
85 I believe. He said, um,
prefers women likes women
is not, not a gay fellow,
just likes dressing up as a woman
and a extremely intelligent,
very interest. I fuck event
special on me. There you go.
15 years ago was mind bock. Yeah.
Say what you want to say. It was my,
it was up there with the great specials
because it had more of a one man show
tone to it. Yeah, you didn't
qualify that as a special,
but when you look at it as a whole,
it was a great fucking performance.
He's a special person and a,
um,
you just happens to be transgender.
That it kind of makes him
even more interesting.
Big Mouse special people.
I got to apologize to you for sound
for me because I've always had this
discrepancy. Last night I went out
for a little while. I got home,
I had a couple of numbers in
me. I grabbed the fucking apple.
I sat on a constant unwind and I put the
TV on and in front of me was the blues
brothers. Ooh. When was the last
time I watched the blues brothers?
I don't know.
So the scene that opens up is them at
the restaurant when he's trying to talk
the Maitre d and the join the band
and there's a family next to him,
a husband or wife and three
daughters. And the guy's telling them,
I'm not going to join the
band. So he goes, really,
you're not going to join the band.
He takes a bottle of champagne and he
goes over to the table and he goes,
so how much was that little goes,
I wasn't ready for that. I just
lost it. Right? He's like, I said,
[inaudible] goes, and the guy's like,
what? And he goes, for the women,
I want to pay you for the women. And
the guys like, you know Sara, sir,
he turns around, the guy comes
over, breaks his balls again,
he fucking turns over to the guy
again. He goes so much further. Wife,
wife, I remember this day,
this is Claire. This is crazy.
This is craziness.
This would never have mouth full of food.
And Dan Akroyd continues eating
in that background. And Dan,
we got to talk about Dannatt quick,
cause he's been like a hemorrhoid.
He's the silent, he don't make a
bull and make guy's phenomenal.
He's still around. And
if you don't believe me,
watch a movie named my girl and
then watch this and then watch him.
The fucking Liberace movie. He's
outlasted everybody. You know,
he's a serious believer in you. LFOs well,
what are you going to do with everything's
got problems right here. Right here.
When he threatens him right here. How
much for the wife? Okay, look at the guy.
Just joking. Just shit like it.
Them Champagne and then watch fucking
then Akroyd watch what he does.
He goes, if you don't fucking,
if you don't join the band,
we will be in here every
day for breakfast, lunch,
and fucking dinner and watch it. Dan
Akroyd does at this fancy restaurant,
but Joe, it doesn't stop that. They get
in the car. They drive off. Look at him,
look at him. That's craziness.
This is the last of real comedic.
If you're going to get into
comedy or you want to be,
this is comedy one oh one they
walk out, they get into a car.
That black fucking car, this is nonstop.
Joe Rogan. There's not like a hug,
like there's no swath. They get
into a car, they get into traffic.
The cop comes up to him, he goes, there's
Nazis, the having parade, and he goes,
the blue. She goes, Illinois and
Nazis. I hate them more than anything.
He looks at Ackroyd,
they fucking pull over and they take
the car and go right for the Nazis.
The Nazis have to jump off the bridge.
White people are clapping and
shit that they knocked them off.
Then they pull into a black neighborhood.
Who's playing the fucking guitar?
Your boy, John Lee Hooker down the middle
of the street. Don't quit. Don't quit.
Don't quit. Just playing the fucking
guitar. Then after he sang the song,
brothers fucking everywhere doing
that business. John Lee Hooker,
Belushi and Aykroyd, they just
stare at them down. Then from there,
they walk into a diner to get the
fucking guitar play and it's a reap the
Franklin and Aretha Franklin
to get at the fucking ambush.
That led to midnight. I got to go to bed.
I gotta get up at six 15 with the baby.
I don't give a fuck. I'm watching this.
Aretha Franklin goes off. They do a dance.
The black dude leaves with a white guitar
player. Then what the fuck would I go?
A pawn shop with the
fucking black piano player,
Ray Charles. He's the pawn shop owner.
He opens up the day. He's blind.
He owns a punch shop. Look at him. He
owns a points yet this doesn't stop.
Wow. I had a fucking finally got to bed
and then I felt bad about going to bed.
They will never make a movie
like this ever, ever again.
Then they start dancing like it's Greece.
This little dance. Let it go. Jail.
This got dancing. I'm like, look
at this like it is fucking Greece.
Look at this. This will
never happen again.
Joe Rogan layer black people flipping
in the air. This one, Calgary,
I'm the cut. This will never happen
again. These were these old shit.
This the WHO direct. Isn't this part
liberal? Look at these two. You take.
Belushi gave a fuck. Wow.
Look how free people were in movies.
There was no superhero more later.
Yeah.
It costs millions to make this
movie. Look at me. Look at,
they're dancing it out that you know
I forgot. Oh, goddamn fun. This movie,
this movie is fun. And then the
chick that died on the airplane. Oh,
what's the chick that
died on the airplane?
That was a star wars chick that died
on the airplane that was at Star Wars.
The chick last year might be the
best description of anybody ever.
The reefer I had that killed the,
what's that chicken down on the plane?
She has sleep apnea. She was
doing pills on the plane. Who?
She played the actress and
Star Wars. Carrie Fisher.
Carrie Fisher is chasing him throughout
the whole movie because he dumped her.
Oh, that's right. Throwing
missiles and grenades. Right.
And then they go into the bar and
they tell the fucking dude that they,
the good old boys. Oh my God,
this is don't stop. Oh my God.
Whoever wrote this directed this
shot this. So this whole movie,
they have the Nazis.
A looking from John Candy is
looking from with the state police.
Wow. That's all Chicago.
This is wild man. It's just what
the folks who are just listening,
she says the blues brothers,
1980 shake tail feather,
seen four of nine on movie clips.
How does that work with like
a year? Are they allowed
to show these? Yeah.
They made a deal with them
because this links also to the,
if you want to watch it, you can pay
right here to rent it and all that stuff.
Oh, look at this stuff. It just means
you fully support buying this movie.
You're looking at me going, Joey, it's
a Cami. Why they dead? Look at the,
it just took a brilliance. They look
at you, they're having a good time.
All of that. If they're not snorting
blow, they're not doing anything. Okay.
Now what's is this movie where he would
walk off the set and just knock on
people's door? One of those
movies, Bro. This fucking nuts.
When they would say, cut, you
got, you know, 18 go sit down.
Belushi was so fucked
up in the night before.
He would just wander
off into a neighborhood.
I'm not consuming these dong go you
mind if I crash on your couch? Yeah,
Bro. They had to go looking for
them in neighborhoods and shit.
He would just find people and
ask to sleep on that couch.
What duel could you knock on?
Look, the blues brothers may have,
John Belushi fell asleep
in a stranger's house.
Dan Akroyd proposed to Carrie's faces
crazy like this was this caddy shack.
You know when they shot caddy shack,
they shot it in Florida. I hit one.
Paramount went down there and they
fucking went nuts. They were like dog.
They found everybody snorting coke. Rodney
was throwing a party. They couldn't,
you know, this is a different type
of movie. These people having fun.
That's a different stab and fun on
that set. That's probably alcohol.
The director's drinking, you know,
he's keeping her bill. How many extras?
We're dancing fucking
hundreds. They're all in tune.
And it was like everybody
loved that movement.
That's one of the rare movies with a
musical scene that fucking everybody loved
the Blues Brothers Right now
the blues brothers started.
I'm saying that live like that was a
sketch, I guess. So Yak right. Wrote it.
John Landis directed it.
They covered it together.
Ackroyd's crazy in the you LFOs he's like
one of the main celebrities they pull
up when people start talking
about, uh, like UFO real believers.
He's done like little clips where he
narrates things, UFO shows and shit.
He fucking believes what
didn't. They just released that.
There's even more belief now
about foes. I, yeah, it's fun.
I don't know if it's real but
a, it's fun. That's how I feel.
Doug,
I did a podcast with Jim Florentine and
I explained to Jim Florentine that what
people don't know is that
Hudson county, New Jersey,
northern New Jersey is the number one
place in the country where they have the
most UFO sightings. Really?
Northern New Jersey. Look it up,
Jeremy, if you've got a
minute please. Not to be rude,
but isn't that like near
a couple of airports? No,
it's closer to like you don't like when
you live in New York City and then you
look at the Hudson River,
they say that people go on their
balconies to drinking coffee,
they talk on the phone and they'll
see a little flying social go by.
And I know for a fact
that in 1976 little one,
whatever the fuck they are,
I know for a fact that in 1975 and
1976 you could check me out on this.
Are you a full Landon
in Hudson County Park?
I was a kid and the next day the feds
locked off the park. That yellow tape.
They had samples. Go look it up dog.
They say you at fault. There's a, that's,
you see that? That, that, that, that's
called the north burglars where I'm from,
that's called, I forget what it's
called, but it was, so there was,
it's a circular building.
So they did so much coke in there
in the 80s they called it the grind.
That's the thing called it cause it was
shaped like the stone edge. Stonehedge.
I have a couple of
friends that lived there.
People that lived in that building have
seen UFO for fucking years and if you go
to youtube, there's an
actual north Hudson Park UFO.
They dug up, they even,
they came out the Mar,
there's a liquor store and the liquor
store guy says, you seen the lights,
you heard like the organ music
that they play. They landed,
a couple of Martians got out and took
samples and got back in the thing and took
off.
There's a youtube thing is a history
channel special about it and I still
remember being a young kid.
Did you find anything Jeremy?
Not Given that that was
what's pop pop popping up,
all that stuff about that
building and oh yeah, no, no, no.
It's anything that says a UFO landed that,
that's the story I'm reading right
now is what he's saying and witnesses,
you know, it's not just one
guy that says, oh no UFO.
It's people who got knocked in the
door and said, do you see anything,
anything at 1110 at night?
And I said, you know what?
There were lights flashing outside.
They contacted police departments
to see if there was any,
they went full to and the FBI
came in, circled the park closed.
It was by the little league field and
Hudson county, but it's, you know,
like you'd think it was area 51 you think
it was close with northern Las Vegas.
The number one place to see you
in foes is northern New Jersey.
They even made a reference to it.
The Sopranos when he said something and
he goes, what are you talking about?
Last week you said you were saying that
you were following Hackensack because
that's where they're at.
Hackensack Monache throw those,
you'll go to Monaca in New
Jersey. A lot of ugly apples.
A lot of people were big heads.
The only good thing in New Jersey is
fucking Segovia Spanish restaurant.
It's been, this is 19
fucking [inaudible]. I Dunno,
but that's the only good
thing about Murdoch.
I think those people in
Munafiki had been abducted.
They stuff and they put them back
as big Heather motherfuckers.
I did a Gig there a couple times.
Oh yeah. They used to be like a bar.
There's a bar that did
something. Pop Gonzo Gig. Yes.
Outside the C club was it?
Yeah, it's outside. No, no, no.
I think Bob is more down the shore
and stuff, but, well he had gigs all,
he had gigs all over.
Bob, how I met Bob was,
he did a Gig in Romanos Italian restaurant
in my hometown and my buddy's like,
hey, aren't you a comedian?
Let's take you up there.
And we went up there and Bob was like, I
don't know, you know, he said I'm known
and next to him Bob came up and
I was like, no gotta put you out.
Cause my friends threatened me.
So Bob put me up and we become a
friends ever since. That's awesome.
I think I follow him on Facebook. We have
a chat from time to time on Facebook,
but yeah, for you UFO motherfuckers
look into northern New Jersey.
That's the fucking mother load
of them. That's interesting.
I had read that before
but I kind of let you go.
51 51 UFO sightings in 2018 I as a,
you get biased because the, the,
the story is always some person in
the woods and they get abducted.
They say UFO and some strange
town in the middle of nowhere.
The aliens land of duck people. You
always think about it being a rural thing,
but if I was an alien, of
course I'd go to New York City.
Of course I go to New Jersey.
What the fuck? Why wouldn't you?
You want to go see the craziest
thing we have. You got like
7 million people stuffed together on a
fucking tiny island and in comparison to
the rest of the planet, if stuff's
stacked on top of each other, awesome,
amazing buildings in all
these lights at times square.
Look at all these people mulling around,
traveling over these bridges to get to
this one hub is one hive of humanity.
Of course, if I was an alien,
I would check that out.
Why would I look at a
barn? You know what I mean?
They used to have a joke that w w
the United States is the Tijuana.
If outer spray by the space like that,
like where are we doing this weekend?
We're going to fucking,
they'd come down when they're fucked
up and they want to see a show
that was the whole bed. Is that, I think
aliens come here when they're high.
I did. They just get fucked up.
They're like, come on, let's go.
Let's go check out the monkeys. This
go dude. Come on. What's up? Duck Duck.
A couple of them have a good time.
Let's go see those monkey people.
I never saw a fucking UFO or I
want to, I never have though.
I want to see it Atlanta and I want to
see one of those green dudes get out.
Sorry. I thought I saw
some shit when I was a kid,
but as I got older I thought that
was like a fighter jet or something.
That's what that was like.
There was something that of,
it's a real sketchy memory.
It's one of those memories
that's like barely active,
but I remember thinking for like a
day or two when I was a little kid.
Maybe I saw UFL, but I think I was trying
to convince myself of it. You know,
I was bored, but I think it was a jet.
I think it was something
something fast and unusual.
Have you ever seen one of those stealth
bombers that looks like a fucking UFO?
You're seeing one of those
things in the sky? No. Yes.
It looks like a star wars. When you go
to like a, a blue angel fucking thing.
Those plants know that those are
like, I think those are f a teens.
That's what I think it is. I think that's
what that is. I flew in one of those.
I had a bit about that too. Yeah.
You gotta do you hold onto the hand.
You gotta do it. You Hook. Either
you either hold on to your handle.
If you're steering the plane or you hold
onto your straps. If you're a pastor.
I was a strong, I was in the pastor seats.
I grabbed ahold of my straps and
you have to go like go to school
and you have to force blood
in your brain. Stay awake.
That's how much g force
you're going through.
It's insane for blood and your
brain to stay awake. See that's,
that's one of those stealth bombers. I
saw one of those in the air over. Uh,
I guess it's Edwards Air Force Base. Is
that what the one it is? That's Edwards,
the one that's out near
Palmdale. I think that's it.
Cause we used to film fear factor in
Palmdale and we saw that they fly overhead
like that. Look at that thing.
Tell me that doesn't look
like it's from another planet.
When you're on the ground and you
see that fly overhead, you're like,
what the fuck is that?
So I think that's responsible for a
bunch of the things that people saw.
I think it's military craft. Can
I should question that article.
You pulled up to 51 sightings. What
type of sightings do you look at?
This fucking thing. What
is consider this side?
Well the thing is like you just
see shit, but how do you know?
What are you doing? You know,
these are the sidings. Okay.
But go back to that video, look
at that thing. I mean come on.
If you're just sitting on the ground,
you saw that you're like their combat
aliens are coming that does not look like
it's from this world.
That thing is madness,
especially with those two guys next to
him. God, it's fucking beautiful though.
It's like what a amazing design.
That thing flying through.
It looks like something
on a keyboard. You know?
It looks like a symbol on a keyboard and
it's just flying perfectly through the
air. That looks like the future.
I mean that really does look
like it's from another world.
I would imagine like little blue dudes
have black eyes talking to each other in
that thing, but
going through fucking
wormholes and shit. I mean,
that's what that thing
looks like. And what's the,
what's the thing that they're going
to have a hundred years from now?
Just imagine that. Just
want to know what the,
what the logistics is for it
to be consumed. Oh, agenda.
Eligible sighting. Legitimate
siding should have been said.
It just means that someone saw it.
You know why you don't like
if you're a lawyer, okay,
and you see something and then you
convince yourself that what you saw was
something extraordinary and you need to
have the feeling that you're looking at
something from another world.
But if it's just some drone
or some military vehicle
and then you look at it and
then you convince yourself,
then it becomes a bigger and
bigger deal in your head.
That's a problem with people.
It doesn't mean that everybody that
sees something and seeing that,
but people are kind of full of
shit. Well, let's say you see,
let's say there's a one 800 call
Martian, right? I see a fucking thing.
I call that one 800 call mark. Call. I'm
washing. Okay. Whatever the fuck. Okay,
1-800-MARTIAN though the phone
won't stop ringing. Okay.
The phone won't stop ringing.
It will never stop ringing.
It'd be people talking to Martians.
My concern is when do they
consider it a credible?
What does it take for it to be
credible? For me for it to be credible,
I got to see the motherfucker
land get out. My a,
my take usually military guys. Um, when,
when you have a military fighter
pilots, that's an extraordinary human.
Those that's a, you know,
if you can be one of those guys that
flies one of those [inaudible] to,
for them to trust you with that
billion dollar fucking spaceship dude,
you gotta be, uh, an exceptional human.
There's no room for
someone who's full of Shit.
You're going to be a top
flight fighter pilot.
You're going to fly around with gunfights
in the sky because that's what they
do. They have gun fights
in the fucking sky.
Those guys are exceptional human beings.
So when they see something,
that's when I listen for sure
everybody else, I'm not that.
Not that I wouldn't listen, but I don't
know. You know, you might be crazy,
but if someone then you might be
crazy. Even if you're in the military,
you might be crazy. If
you're a fighter pilot,
it's 100% possible fighter pilots and
all those air force pilots that do test
runs or whatever they, they see,
they say that they see things,
there's a bunch of signings. None of them.
They a bunch of sightings is a bunch
of sightings from these really credible
guys. What does it say?
Fleet of UFOs followed us.
Aircraft Navy pilot says May 29th call
about these guys that are talking about
these things. These aren't uh,
guys with histories of
embellishing things. There's a,
I mean they have this whatever that is
that radar, what are they looking at?
Is that infrared? Like what, what is the,
that screen that they're looking for?
Does it say what kind of image it
is? Cause it's like a weird look.
It's not like a photograph,
right? It's like a weird
computer image because it's, um, it's,
it's detecting it right with
some piece of equipment. Right?
Isn't it like tracking it on
radar or something like that?
I know what you're saying cause I feel
like I've heard that description of it
too. But this, this article just says
it's a video of two aerial encounters,
but that video doesn't look
very clear. Why isn't it clear?
My phone does a better job in that
shit and I'm very good cameras on those
cameras. They have good candidates.
I mean, they don't have good ones,
but like in order to catch movement at
that high speed up there, Yada, Yada,
all that stuff. Oh, so it would
require some exceptional gear, I think.
And it could've also been at night.
I don't know what time of day.
It was so convenient,
so convenient that they never have a clear
picture that drives me fucking crazy.
It drives me fucking crazy because
if it is real, I am. I love,
I want it to be real. Honestly. I
really do. But when I look at it like,
Oh God damn.
So many people are so crazy and told
me the people were so full of shit.
You personally believe
in soda. Why don't done,
there's other galaxies out
there. There has to be. Well,
it definitely the galaxies, other
civilizations, civilizations. Yeah.
Some form somewhere. I live nine
planets. It's gotta be, Dude,
there was a song thing, but
I don't know what I didn't,
I'm not going to sit here and tell
you what that called or whatever,
but there has to be
something at this point.
You have to believe that
the universe too big.
It's just too big to discount
and say nope or doubt it.
Like that's so crazy to say
this is because we haven't
seen it yet. It's so big.
Okay. It's 40th caught. And
what he said that though,
tracking equipment radar and infrared
cameras on his aircraft detected ufs both
times. He was unable to capture
them on his helmet camera. Okay,
so maybe you couldn't look at it.
Hmm. Get it in good vision or whatever
or that's a good,
excellent reason why I would imagine as
fast as those goddamn things are going,
it must be really hard to get a candidate
to be able to constantly focus in and
out. And that's interesting.
He says that Luke Tyler and Ryan
Grimes put heaves, graves', whatever,
a squadron of UFO Fall,
his navy strike group up and down the
eastern coast of the U S for months.
That's, I'm telling you
that little fucking,
I read something about the Hudson River
that all those people that live across
the Hudson River,
whether on the Weehawken Edgewater
side or the west side of Manhattan,
those are where the people on
their balconies see all that shit.
Look at this shit. We did have issues
with them and we went to the Middle East.
Lieutenant Graves said, Ooh,
imagine them following the war.
Imagine if you were there were aliens
and they came down to follow the war.
So they see the war going
on and they were how crazy.
Afghanistan come down and
they're checking it out.
Just to did go on the
cynical side of this,
they're not necessarily
saying they are an alien ship,
they're saying it's a UFO, so it's
something they're not sure of.
What if it's some sort of awesome drone
that some Middle Eastern company has an
they can just follow shit
or fast or something?
Sure. That would be the more
likely explanation. Right?
Terrestrial would be more likely
that someone has advanced shit.
We know they have advanced shit. I mean
we know they have incredible drones.
You know what I mean? The stuff
that they can do, they got a drone
that green berets, the seals,
you put razor blades on them and they
slit your fucking throat when you're
driving. Whoa.
That's how good the technology
is on those drones. Jesus Christ.
I wouldn't be shocked if they
can do all kinds of things.
We can be standing there and they could
take the drone to just come down fucking
they put razor blades
on them or some shit.
Well you could totally see someone
having a small drone, like a small thing,
like the size of a cheeseburger that has
poison in it and you just slamming into
somebody. You could see, I
could see that this though,
what you're seeing when you're seeing
stuff that's flying around the sky,
most likely it's made by a person because
people make stuff and people know how
to make stuff that
flies around in the sky.
But then when you get this
shit like defies physics,
like some of the things he's
fighter pilots say that's
when you got to go wait a
minute. He,
you see these extraordinary
feats of traversing distances.
Like they can get from one
place to another place so fast.
It looks like they disappear. This
is something they all talk about.
They all talk about insane speed
at which these things can go.
They can just change angles.
They can just go and then take a tarred
right angle turn and they can do stuff
that nothing that we know how to make
can do. That's where it gets to be like,
whoa. Like nothing sounded like it's
like, oh, that's like a fighter jet,
but like really fast. You know what
I'm saying? It's like an alien car. Oh,
it's like a car, but it's way faster.
Like you know it's an alien car,
but this is not like anything
that we make these fucking things.
They fly this way. They say flat like a,
like a plate hovering over the
ground or, but when they go to fly,
when they go to take off,
they flip up sideways and they have like
the bottom of the spaceship is pointing
towards where it wants to go and it
does something to space and time.
Make some sort of fucking
magnetic gravity connection.
Insert big spooky words,
whatever, then no,
they don't know how the
fuck it does it. Right.
This thing can go like insane distances
and insanely small amounts of time.
Then when they all report the same
kind of behavior of these things,
so many of these reports are like that.
They're talking about this thing that
goes insanely fast turns on its side.
It looked like a tick tack.
It looks like a saucer.
It looks like they're trying to figure
out what the fuck the shape is because
it's moving so goddamn fast,
but it's doing stuff that nothing we
know how to make and do. I thought,
I don't know if it's from another
planet, it might be from here,
but it's exciting. It's exciting shit.
I want it to be from another planet.
That's what I want. Like unbiased.
Like what my honest, what I would,
I would love it. Just be completely
honest. I would love it if it was aliens,
but it was people. I'd be even
more scared because, hey god damn,
people can do that. People
can do that and no one knew.
Like some kid.
If you can imagine a person who can
make a spaceship that defies all of the
rules that we know about
travel, about air travel,
they can make something that defies all
that shit and somehow now they're keep
the whole development and production of
it a secret and then have this thing and
take it off and no one knows
how the fuck they did it.
That's almost more impressive than aliens
because that's what these things are
doing is so if these pilots are accurately
reading what's happening and they're
telling the truth,
the thing that's remarkable is
their stories are very consistent.
There's a lot of very similar stories
from different people that they're make a
living flying super fast warships,
you know, they see things,
they know what the fuck they're looking
at. They see something they don't know.
They're like, what in the fuck is that?
When they see something like that,
that freaks me out.
That's when it gets me,
because when some fucking kids riding
his bike to school and he looks up and he
sees a UFO, okay, maybe it did
happen. Maybe it did happen.
Maybe the kids being a hundred
percent honest or maybe he was bored.
Maybe he was bored and decided to
make up a store and, and stuck with
it. And then after a while telling
it, maybe he believed in himself.
That happens to people see things,
they don't know what they're seeing and
they decide that it's a different thing.
I've said this before, but it's a
true story. When I was in, in Alberta,
there's wolves there and I thought I
saw a wolf for like a whole second.
It was a squirrel fucking squirrel,
but I saw grey for
movement. Wolf Squirrel.
Like if you're dumb or if
you're compromised or if you're,
you get a little drunk, maybe
a little tired, you know,
maybe just saw something that looked
really weird because of, you know,
whatever weather conditions that are
affecting some part of the world you live
in, there's things called ball. Lightning,
flies through the air, you know,
it's a, it looks like a
UFO. You ever see that shit?
It's like a real natural phenomenon.
Somebody might see something like that
and then add a bunch of other shit to it.
And that's where you get a lot of these
stories yet like natural phenomenon and
then people adding a
bunch of shit to things,
but then on top of that you have credible
stories and you can't throw out any of
them like you gotta you. It's
when you look at all these things,
you can't decide just cause there's a
bunch of crackpot stories about UFOs that
the ones by legitimate fighter
pilots that those aren't real.
Can't look at it that way.
It's crazy to look at it that way because
it's more likely there's something out
there. Then there isn't something
out there. It's way more likely.
When I was a kid that happened to
Hudson county park, I wrote it off.
I didn't pay attention. I
remember riding my bike up there,
seeing the Fed tape and seeing people
with those, a orange protective suits,
huh? Yeah. I was like, these
people are fucking out of my mind.
Then one night I got high five or six
years ago and I saw it if somebody had
posted on Facebook or youtube,
and I read more and more into it and I
discounted it until I read the accounts
of the 28 people, you
know, in that building,
the liquor store,
there was a guy who had just got dropped
off a bus from New York because buses
drop you off there from New York. The
bus driver said there was a flash.
He couldn't, you know,
there were just so many people
with stories that, you know,
they didn't see a fucking guy get out.
Only three people saw
people get out [inaudible].
Everybody else discounted the lights and
the noise and the other bullshit that
went with it. I would've shipped my
fucking pants. If I live in that building,
it's all three little Martians get
out or it could just be fucking hold.
Hold on. Who knows who
gives a fuck? Yeah, man.
You just want me to tell you that that's
where he can get freaked out and they
can, you know, they can think all kinds
of things. That didn't really happen.
They, one night I was on acid,
I thought it wasn't fucking,
I put the FBI was out there with dogs and
I, the next day it was fucking a fire.
All right. I dumped the ounce of
coke down the toilet. Oh my God.
Because I hallucinated
because when you doing the coke
more than fucking 10 hours,
you start hallucinating.
I started hallucinating.
It was fucking dogs and
it was a fire hydrant.
You know how stupid I felt the next
day. Pretty fucking stupid. Ugh.
Pretty fucking stupid. I sat
there and I went over and pet it.
Dihydrate you fuck you. Fuck.
This is a problem with any story.
Like all these fucking UFO
stories is people's memory.
Memory's not that good.
It's just not that good.
It's too hard to figure out what it
actually looked like after you saw it.
Like you see something crazy like a year
ago and then you try to describe it.
It's too hard to describe.
Like you barely remember it.
You're your version of it is a rehashed
version that you keep repeating to
yourself. You know,
if you saw something like say if you're
hiking and you saw a wolf, right?
If you saw that wolf, when you
try to describe that that moment,
you saw that Wolff years later, like what?
What are you actually seeing
when you go in into your memory?
How much do you help?
Accurate as it were always lying
about how accurate our memory is.
It's not that good. Like if you,
if you did see a wolf, I think,
which is an extraordinary moment,
right? You're in the fucking forest.
It's a fucking wall. It's off, and you
see a real wolf looking down on you,
a wild motherfucker in the woods
of Canada. Just looking at you,
staring at you on a trail.
That's an extraordinary moment.
But if you try to recount that
in your mind 10 years later,
what do you actually see?
How much do you actually see?
You see this blurry,
weird fucking misty version and you got
some words that fall into place that can
describe it, but how accurate is
your fucking memory? It's terrible.
How accurate is your memory?
It's good with statistics.
Like I can tell you about fights. I can,
I can tell you what year someone fought.
I can tell you how this guy
won and how he beat, you know,
this many guys or the triangle
and I remember things.
But if I actually have to remember that
what it actually looked like in my head,
I can't really pull that up. I
barely can pull it up by seeing,
I'll recognize it again. You know,
I just show me Joe Schilling knocking
out Melvin Manhoef and Bella Tor aside.
I said, watch that chaos
so many times. The wild,
crazy slugfest and if I see it, I'll,
I'm watching it happen in a video. I
remember it. Yep. This is how it goes.
Here it goes. Boom. He kaos him.
But if I had to just pull that out
of my brain right now, it's not good.
You know what I'm
saying? Like if I had it,
like if I have to like close my eyes
and pretend I saw Mike Tyson knockout
Michael Spanx, I kind
of can see blue flashes.
I can kinda remember weird
little parts of it, you know,
I remember the final right hand, boom,
we just sends him flying
through the ropes. It was chaos.
It was just like he's the best ever.
But if I had to like
play it back in my head,
it wouldn't be nearly as
good as a video of it.
How has the memory in your life,
how have the memories of your life,
do you remember being
three, your being five? Like
I was fucking suffering, not suffering,
but I was like trying to think of my dad.
My Dad died when I was three and
I have two memories with him.
I have two memories that
I can look you in the eye.
I don't remember what he was wearing
or what shoes he was worrying,
but I still remember driving from the
Lincoln Tunnel from New York to Jersey and
then put me on my lap, no seatbelt,
and me holding onto the
steering wheel while,
and I still remember him and my mom having
a discussion and taking me with him.
That's it. I don't remember
nothing else. Wow. You know,
you try to go back on your memory,
then you start to write a little bit,
your memory gets better.
Hello Devon. Even when your memory gets
better. The problem is with my memory,
I'm always wondering how much
of this is accurate? You know,
how much of what am I mean?
How much of it was I really
paying attention during
the moment and really be in
a like do it.
Like if you have a bias perspective of
something that's happening and then you
have a memory of it. How much does
your memory of the bias perspective,
how much does your memory and the
bias perspective shape what you think
happened?
You could actually kind of twist the
past in your head if you're not careful.
And you start thinking about things that
didn't really necessarily happen the
way they like. If you got a get
fucked over at work, you know,
I had gum in my fucking pension
all of a sudden, and then you,
you look at it from that way. Wow,
this guy worked for an evil
company that fucked him over.
Or you go to the employers and some of
the other people that you work with go,
no, no, no, no, no. That guy was a fucking
asshole. He made life at work. Hell,
nobody wanted him around. He didn't
get fucked over. He was so negative.
Nobody wanted to be with
him in the office. We had to
get rid of them. Like you,
you'd have to look at it from
their point too. You don't know.
So the actual memory of it for that guy
might be that he got fucked over by this
evil company,
but the memory of the other people
is a completely different experience.
The memory of the other people is,
this guy was annoying to work with. Oh,
and they're both, you
know, it's both. I mean,
who the fuck knows who's who's right,
but my memory is good at some
places and completely bad in others.
Like right now, my memory of
30 years ago, just spot on.
I could take conversations we had
last night where we did a year ago.
Like I'll sit here and go, what
did I do last for the July?
I have no fucking idea. But I went
home when I went home for three weeks,
I went to dinner with a friend of mine
and then the way back I had him in tears
telling them about the night
his arm got broken. You know,
he looked me legitimately in
the face and he goes, Joey,
I forgot I broke my arm. It's
amazing. Remember how the,
do you remember
that go? That was just one of
the best nights of my life.
I never laughed so hard. My friend,
he drove his car up. My friend,
you know how people go on a
coming and they drive at? Yes.
He didn't stop in time and he tapped
my friend. My friend went down.
It was hilarious as it is. He got up,
he went to take a swing at this guy and
the guy put his arm up and when he hit
it, he broke his arm with the punch,
the punch, and he had to wear a cast.
And we torture them when my friend kept
threatening to sue him and it was just a
he and he, when I was telling
him this, his face was red.
He had to take his napkin down and he
was banging the table. He goes, cokes,
I just remembered the broken fucking arm,
you know, he's my age. He goes, I forgot
all about my fucking arm. You know,
before you came in, Jamie and I
were talking about Achilles tendons.
And I remember the time
ripping, pulling a hamstring,
like having to go to the hospital when I
was 15 and having the fucking doctor do
or something and it was bruised.
Blood was running from my
ass to the top of my leg.
It was fucking horrible. I just ripped
the hamstring. We were talking about, uh,
uh, you know, like just that
you know, and then this,
there's a theory that there's times
like you'll go back to Newark like you,
I don't know if there's a fire.
You're going to Newark that fight. No,
I'm not going to, I'm
not working that one.
But let's pretend you went back to Newark
and you went to see where your grandpa
lived and you saw a corner
store that was still there.
This is interesting and you go into that
corner store and maybe you get a bag of
wise potato chips. Maybe you get
a bun that you went there and got,
they say by tasting that button and it
takes you back and opens up all those
fucking memories. Why, why
eating something from the
area, something something.
It's like sometimes a song will
trigger something fucking songs.
Really true for sure.
That's why it's important.
Sometimes when you watch a movie or a
TV shut the habit soundtrack because we
have a soundtrack. We all have
a soundtrack of our lives.
I had a couple of years ago,
I was on a podcast and we were talking
about something Bon Jovi and you're like,
aw, I remember giving some chicken
stab and listening to [inaudible],
something like that. You know
what I'm saying? Like you'll see,
you won't even say I fucked Mary Lou
Smith in the ass. Listen to the songs.
You know, it just brings you
back. It just brings you back.
But they say that examples
to bring it back. Yeah,
it was me and my best friends were
by the lake. Nope, banging some.
That's what you got, man. Listen,
most guys, most guys will hear a song,
they'll be by themselves, they'll be
by your wife and your kids. You know,
you'll hear never say goodbye to Bon
Jovi and you're thinking of night that
drunk midget chicken, the decline
in church and you never told nobody.
It just comes back.
It comes back to haunt you for a minute.
You know like shit like that always call.
That was the song I sit in some prison
to like whatever. I don't fucking know.
Like when I got locked up, the big
album was appetite for destruction.
The Big [inaudible], the
big, when I got locked up,
the big albums for the regular people,
appetite for destruction for the brothers.
It was don't be cruel by Bobby Brown.
That album, he made solo when
he slipped from new edition.
So every time I hear don't be cruel.
The other one, every time I hear it,
especially that fucking Mr Brownstone,
every time I hit Mr Brownstone I want
to crash the car because all the bike is
the shoot heroin to that.
So you know what I'm saying?
Like it's time for Mr. Brown style.
That's all they would talk about.
So every time I hear those two albums,
I fucking think about being
locked up and what's on them.
Ever since guns and roses went on tour.
That's all you hear on the radio now.
But the radio on for five minutes
everyday you're in November.
Rain walking through the jungle.
Cause that's it. That's it. Right.
Every time I hear those jams, I think
about that stupidity. That's fun.
Welcome to the jungle was mine.
But there's a lot of people who
will say to you like, Oh, you know,
I make love. I used to make love to
my girlfriend, listen to that album,
you know, whatever. But
there's some people animals
and say, you know the truth.
I used to get my dick sided.
Listen for that when I was 14 yeah,
music more than anything. It's
like an imprint of the time of the,
of your life when you saw it. Like
if you go back and think about,
like for me it was stripes with
Bill Marine, I think I was,
I had to be a teenager. What
year did stripes come out?
What year was that?
81 perfect. So I was 14
years old that that was,
I was a in ninth grade, I was
a freshman in high school.
So that when I think about
that movie, like that was the,
the epic movie of our time when I
was a kid. It was like, that was,
I think about that time of the
year or that time of my life.
You think about who you
were, you know what you,
it brings you back to a weird place like
it's, it helps. It enhances the memory.
Fucking tremendous. That
was a great movie, man. When
he was such a funny movie.
Think about the Lyme.
He asked the fat dude why he joined
the service and the guy goes,
I want to lose a couple pounds. Look at
him. Candy was amazing. Amazing in this.
It's a fucking great movie, man.
It was just so good at the time.
You know, it's just, you had a smile
on your face through the whole movie.
Like even the moment moments of the
movie that weren't like hilarious when
they're setting things up. You just,
it was so well done. You just smiled.
All you guys looking at this cast, you
got the guy from Beverly Hills cop,
you got Zito from Miami Vice.
You got fucking Harold Ramis
who was a blessing in my life.
He legitimize me when I did this
movie. The movie was terrible,
but he was phenomenal
comedy wise. That's awesome.
I don't know what this brother
went on to do, but you know,
this is fucking great calm. But look
at Bill Murray. This is dumb now man.
This is the height of Bill Mary.
Now you guys gotta remember we were
just talking about another great movie a
couple of minutes ago. Then these both
come out the same year. Did they? Yeah.
Any one 80 this is the
shit we were going through.
This is why we talk
about movies and music.
It's not that we're old men
fucking being nostalgic.
I'm telling you the truth. They were
making great movies at this time.
There was a few great movies, a
few. There was a few. Yeah, I mean,
I mean quite a few, I
should say. This planes,
trains and on them bills that
come out in 83 82 84 you know,
you gotta the comedy lessons we were
getting those years 87 well let's think of
this like just cinematically. Look.
What Year did the godfather come out?
73 73 72 exorcist.
73 the mechanic 73 it was just too much.
Just those three movies
right there, the Godfather,
the mechanic and the exorcist.
And if you look at who was up for an
academy award in 73 you'll fucking die.
You'll die. You'll go out. Fuck fucking,
they pick a winner there. It's also,
imagine the stark contrast between
that in 53 1952 the movies were kind of
Corny. You know, even if they were
good, they were kind of corny. You know,
if you go any earlier than that, like
y'all try to watch them. Kong ever watch,
I watched it with my kids and a wife
wasn't home and they were scared.
They were like, I don't want to watch
a scary movie. I'm, I go, we're going,
we're going to, we'll laugh at a silly
scary movie. And they're like, really?
I go, you got to trust me.
This movie was from so long ago
that what they thought, it's scary.
You're going to think it's silly. And
they're like, are you serious? Cause they,
they go, okay, but if we get too
scared, just shut it off, right. I go,
definitely shut it off. They were like,
I think seven and five at
the time fucking movie.
It's so fake looking when the gorilla
comes out, they thought it was hilarious.
And then because we talked about it being
fun and then they were just laughing
hysterically and cracking all these
jokes about what that thing luck looked
like,
that it looked like my youngest daughter
said it looked like someone was moving
poop around that it looked like
just like it was made out of poop.
Cause it's all clay. It
looks so dumb. But you know,
back then that was as good as it
got. Won't look at the new Godzilla.
The new Godzilla has got off of people
leaving with a fucking headache.
Are they yet? Look at the old
Godzilla. It's a comedy. It is.
Oh my God. You see those
poor little Japanese people.
Look at this though. Yeah,
I'll take this looks.
But it just always been huge back
at these guys like, yeah buddy,
you're not in a plane. It's
like so fake looking. You know
like these guys flying around
and look how bad the gorilla
looks. It's so crazy.
But at the time this was
unbelievable. This was amazing.
So if you go from this
to like apocalypse now,
the jump in terms of like how impactful
it is and how much they nailed it.
Like this is, it's a fun
movie, man. Don't get me wrong.
I have a King Kong poster on my
wall at my house. I love the moon.
I love the smoke. I live movie
poster from the nightclub.
I'd much rather see the old gods
Zos Godzilla vs Mortara [inaudible]
versus the smog in lunch.
The Godzillas are fun just to
see what Japanese people doing.
Yeah, they had the string on
them. They would zoom wide shot.
So they would show the Chinese people
running and then they would just have a
single shot and Godzilla moving through
the air. You see, look at the Japanese.
I'm Japanese. Look out dopey
looks like even when it's lit up.
That is fucking fun, man. That's
fun. Look, he's gone through.
They fucking electric. Godzilla
doesn't give a fuck. They're shooting.
I'm fuck you. Yeah. See No,
they can't show you a behind shot of
the Japanese shooting Godzilla cause
there's really no gun. They just shoot
into a wall. It's completely separate.
This is like a, a real claim model. If
you look at it, he's really not 60 feet.
It's maybe fucking eight inches or
something. No, this is not a model.
These are men in suits. This is the
difference between King Kong and no shit.
Yes, these are men in suits.
And it was really complicated and these
guys had to be really strong because
they're carrying around this
gigantic rubber suit and it's heavy.
It's fucking hot as fuck.
So the reason why it moves so fluid with
the Japanese did that was brilliant,
was they had men and they put
men in these monster suits.
The fucking stuff up his
mouth. Yeah, go in a Google.
The men who wore the Godzilla suit,
it's actually a pretty fucking cool.
It's not easy to do.
These guys had a walk around and have
these fight scenes and shit and these big
giant suits. There was an
animation. That's a dude in there.
Isn't that crazy? And that's a,
that's what it really looked
like in terms of a height wise.
It was like the size of the person
seat. That guy go back a bit.
You see that guy getting
out of it? That right there.
That's what the dude looked
like. He was inside of it.
He was wearing them [inaudible]
it was like a claim model. No,
King Kong is clay model.
King Kong was a claymation
from Ray Harry Usan.
That's how um, I got onto
the subject with them.
I was telling them about um,
they love that monsters inc show and Hara
Hughes in is one of the characters or
something about Harry. He was in
his, in the movie. I said, Huh, I go,
do you guys know that is
and they go, no. I said,
that is the guy who of course they didn't
know who this fuck am I talking about?
I said,
that's the guy who was one of the
original monster animators for,
for movies like King Kong. He did all
that claymation stuff and back then,
I mean that was the state of the art.
You got to think 19 fucking 30 something
and I was like King Kong was what,
33 yeah, Godzilla. That was later.
That was post World War II. Yeah.
So you got 54 54 post post
World War Two was Godzilla.
Godzilla was after we,
we, I shouldn't say we,
somebody from the United States drop
bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki when they
use nuclear weapons. The idea was that,
and all the nuclear tests that
they had done in the water,
there was no real understanding of
what the fuck was going to happen.
And so the science fiction version of
that would be that all that radiation
would create some super monster.
Okay, brilliant. Yeah, the man,
the Japanese give it to them.
They were dealing with radiation
poisoning and death on unbelievable,
on an unbelievable scale.
I mean hundreds of thousands of people
wiped out instantly from atomic bombs.
I mean, and so the, just the sheer
force of the power of those things,
you couldn't even imagine that there
could be anything that could do that.
It's one thing that falls out of
an airplane that can do that. Well,
what else can it do? You know what,
what happens if it gets in the water?
What does, how does this chicken
affect fish? How's it going to affect,
you know, who knows? So the, the science
fiction version was always awesome.
It would be like a Godzilla would come.
That's what the new ones about to write.
The new one is the same kind of thing.
Like a dinosaur got zapped and now the,
I believe the new one was all the other
dinosaurs came back and they had to
reawaken God until it, uh, cause he
was the only thing that can fight him.
Oh God. Oh God. So it's a
superhero monster movie.
He's a superhero superhero then bring
him back. He's a good guy. And this one,
oh no, he's not a good guy.
At the end of the last and everyone
complaining cause there's like this weird
winky scene where like Godzilla and the
main guy like looked at each other in
the eye or like same team grow,
you know, the real Godzillas man.
The Real Godzilla is services are not
Searcy. That what the fuck's her name?
The Dragon Mother of dragons,
dragon in the game of Thrones.
That fucked up that city at the end.
Like that's, that's what a like a real,
that's a real horrific idea
of a fire-breathing lizard.
Godzilla was always adorable. Didn't
really go after people. Even the early,
even the early Superman's the first like
six episodes. You could see the strain.
Really check it out. That's liberal.
Black and white. This is violet.
Maybe the pilot my first three episodes.
So they figured out how he could do it.
You could see us train. It's a weird,
the Godzilla story is a weird story,
right? Cause it's not like God's will,
it goes on a killing spree.
It just goes through Tokyo and just
starts lighting every building on fire.
He doesn't do that. He's like, almost
like he has almost like a good guy lizard.
And in the new movie it's more accentuated
then. So he has to help help us.
And Mold cloud was the fucking bird.
Martha was a moth. Multiple moth.
Yeah. And what was the smog
monster like? I wrote Dan, I wrote,
Dan wrote, Dan was, that was
awesome. Dan looked like,
I'm trying to remember like wings and
Shit, right? Didn't Rodin have wings.
You gotta get out of watch.
At least got to get still.
Dad looks like this is crazy.
This shit. Oh, that's right. Look,
Rodin could fly. Look at that one.
The Blue Sky below on three. Oh,
this is a three headed one. Yeah,
but this is new monsters, right?
These are the new ones. What the
fuck out of here with this new shit?
Give me the blue sky right there
with that. Yeah. Right there.
That's kind of TV show wish
was the smuggling loves to had laser
beams coming out of his fucking eyes like
Medusa. Yes, he did. Yes he did.
One of them had fucking laser beam.
Did he really? I was like, oh
my God. The three headed things.
What was that called again? I forgot
about that three minute thing.
Get door. I don't want to
say that. Oh, Guidara Rodin.
It was Gita rough. Yeah.
Just pull up a video of
a Godzilla vs Guidara
it was so silly, but man, when we
were a little kids in this shit
Saturday morning. Yeah. Lose your
mind. I used to love dishes the best.
When you found out Godzilla
was going to be on TV,
you were so pumped from
the actual new movie. Oh,
there's a new movie with Kitura once
out. Not this movies out right now.
It is God's looking at the
monsters. Yeah, that's fine.
Brought all three of these
are, let me see these bitches.
Whoa. Special Effects Today. Oh God.
Holy Shit. This is amazing. Oh my God,
Dude. The special effects
they can do today are insane.
So we're looking at, it says king g,
H I d o r a h king. Guidara. Oh my God.
To ood. The fucking
special effects are insane.
There's Mothra. Wow.
Is this supposed to be a good movie
though? The things with these movies is,
and I really hate to say this,
how come they can't do both?
How come they can't have an amazing,
amazing special 40% on rotten tomatoes?
How can they can't have amazing special
effects and a fucking killer story. No,
I can't. They do that. That's one of the
last of the great 1009 is 10 years ago.
Yeah. Which one was that one? Avatar.
Avatar was a great story with great
special effects like it was at the end of
it. People are Gootz Pocahontas
in space. Get over it. Okay. Yeah,
it is. It's a classic story. Like James
Campbell always talks about classic
structure of these heroes journeys.
There's a lot of that in there.
It's very similar to a lot of
the stories. It's still great.
Don't let that get in the way
of the fact that it's great.
That movie was fucking awesome.
That movie was awesome just to special
effects and the way it all went together
and yeah, that fucking the bad
military guy was cartoonish. Yeah,
of course he was. So what, why let
that get in the way with your fun?
Think of it as like when a movie
like that I think of it is like,
it's like a lot of the hyper
violent Tarantino movies.
Like you know what you're signing up
for, you know, you know what it is.
It's not supposed to be some detailed
analysis of the human psyche.
You know where a guy takes his strange
slow transformation over the course of
two hours? No, it's a fucking bad guy.
This is the bad guy. Here's a good guy.
Good guy. Can't use his legs.
Wouldn't it be awesome if you
could be one of those blue things?
Papao I live in a solid fucking
fucking movies. Great. I never saw it.
I remember one of the saying that
they put too much money into it to my,
but you make a movie. If I give
you $600 million, it's not anybody.
Any of you can make a movie. If I
give you 600 Mil. Joey's James Canton.
James Camera's a monster. I love James
Snakes. So many amazing movies, mates,
great movies. It's like building an ego.
It was like fucking building a
team to put a movie together,
which I understand, but 600 million,
you know Casca nominated, but
I love him. They shunned them.
They shunned them that,
Oh, Shanda at the Oscars.
He walked in and he thought
he was bad to the bone.
He was sitting there with his little new
girlfriend and his ex wife directed her
locker. Whoa. So they both
got the same thing. Oh.
And he's sitting there looking at
Spielberg like winking at him and went,
got all the other white people like what's
happening and all of a sudden they go
to announce the winner of the best movie
and they showed up with Robert Craig
Fan. Oh, once you pay her feed, you know.
And her number is just to walk out of
the house. What's the number? Big. Big,
big [inaudible] when
she does the theaters,
like tickets are more expensive
than the fucking Laker ticket.
When she did the staple center,
cheapest ticket to rebills by the
refrigerator thousand to just sit on the
floor. Barbara Streisand don't
fuck around somewhere. They call.
It's cause she's lightened
somebody's asshole lot.
Even James Cameron knew what he saw.
He put his head up, look at the tape,
he knew what he was done and
she came out and gave it to him.
He lost that to his
wife. Hurt locker though,
was that was a like a culturally
significant movie at the time of a war.
That was super well done. There was no
bullshit in that movie like that was a,
that is a good fucking movie. Her locker
is one. Those moves at the end of it.
You go, Jesus speak of a hurt locker.
Did you see what happened in New
Jersey yesterday? What happened?
Ice went to New Jersey to go into some
Jewish place and Jews got together and
held hands and 36 of them got arrested.
I've always said those Jersey Jews
don't fuck around thug, those Jews,
all of them calling New York, Brooklyn.
They held hands and went up against
eyes. Good for that little young kids.
They don't fuck around those jurors. I
was telling Lee last night, the lady,
you know, they sell more like braces in
Jersey and they do it across the country
because there's a lot of Jews in
Jersey. It just wear neck braces.
Did you know that? Why?
Because then they're on the
lawsuit. Oh, well I grew up,
I grew up here and all this.
Every time I go to the Meadowlands that
be eight guys with neck braces on at the
metal lands and I asked
around and what goes on you,
you don't know what that is down
the, they have somebody on the paper,
like they have a court case
going, oh that's so fun.
So they got to wear fucking neck braces.
So they call them the Jewish gold
chains. You didn't know that.
They call a Jewish gold chain.
When you go get a fucking neck brace,
you got the back order them in Jersey.
Like they fucking Jewish folks are
interesting in that it's a religion and a
race. It's a religion and a both
kind of cause. A lot like Jewish,
ours, Jewish. But ours is not
religious anymore at all. No.
He went over and did the whole fucking
buddies. Jewish. He's Jewish. Yeah,
it's a different animal. There's a lot
of Jewish atheist, you know like how,
how the fuck, how can you do that?
How does that work? They just do it.
They identify with that tribe. They'll,
it's part of a tribe. It's like a tribe,
right? Like a tribe and a religion.
And a race. It's like three things dog.
When I was a kid, I knew what
Jersey Jew in attorney's name was.
Coach this motherfucker, the smile. Wow.
People going to them because
they call them guaranteed 30.
If I can get you 30,000 for anything,
like people would cut that
thumb and just go down there,
get already Jersey 30 gs and
then you take an advance from,
you get hurt and you're taking an
advanced coach. Let me get 10 g's.
When we been Brooklyn last time
when we were going to um, uh,
Peter Luger's and so we drove through
these Hasidic neighborhoods and these were
the ones like Ra, there's orthodox Jews,
there's a big comedian, Orthodox kids,
but in, in New New York
and Brooklyn particularly,
and the Ra was explaining how
they don't leave this community.
This is where they stay.
These are all their people.
They don't give a fuck about what's
happening in the outside world. I'm like,
wow. They just,
you just see this interesting subculture
that it's one of the more cool things
about New York as he get to be in that
car. That's how it like a genuine man.
Even though they're isolated,
they have their own neighborhood.
It's a genuine melting pot in that
regard. Like you could go to a Chinatown,
like a real Chinatown. You've
got to Chinatown New York City.
That's a different animal man.
I mean do you might as well be in some
part of Asia fucking blow hot matrix in
this. It's what? What's the name
of it? Whoa hop. Where's that?
It's in Mont Street
and it's open 24 hours.
[inaudible] real 24 Jason, New York.
Just put the fucking menu up per Mohab.
When I was in New York shooting that
movie, the one that I was starving,
I got stoned and at one
30 I go, I can't do it.
I called wall up. I go, what time
do you open though? They go home,
we will open. I hung up
the phone. I went on Uber,
it was a $10 cab ride and I go, I'm going
to go to wall hub and I chickened out.
Joe Rogan haunted attack. He goes
to low hop at two in the morning.
You're getting a heart attack. All that
sodium fucking killed me and doing them.
I'll be up to fucking,
I'll be up for two days.
We often went to Chinatown after playing
pool cause it was like the best thing
you know back in my early standup
days when I didn't have obligations,
we'd stay up playing pool until two three
in the morning and go and you have a
real meal, like a really good meal.
I think I'd have odd attack that.
Yeah.
They get us meal at night with egg rolls
and steak on a stick and fucking just a
pork fried rice along.
Set you off. What's there?
Even diet coke back then when
did diet coke get invented now?
There's always been, we always had,
yeah, we always had foster kids.
My mother had a Trashcan Tab.
I drank tad. My mother had tab.
People got Super Sad on taboo in a way.
I remember like a people would
be all bummed out like wow,
can I ain't love tat battalion girl's
drink tab. That was a grocery. Yeah, tab.
FRESCA FRESCA was more of a girls drink,
but Todd was a girl's drink
because he had a pink can, wasn't,
didn't tab of like a pink gas. Yes.
1982, that's when tab went away.
Coke. Oh Wow. I thought it was
older than that. Hm. Me Too.
Yeah. I still remember in 85
when they changed the recipe,
that was 85 and motherfuckers
went nuts. Crazy. And they really,
they went crazy. New Coke
like what? You're on coke.
Why would you fuck with the taste
of the best soda of all time?
Coca-Cola was the best
tasting soda of all time.
And this other stuff that's really
good. Like root beer is really good.
It's interesting,
but there's a reason why that shit sold
a billion fucking trillion gallons over
the past.
So tap had Sacramento and led to
bladder cancer and found that out.
And then the popularity declined.
Exactly. One Diet coke came out 1982. Oh,
they got set up. Put on
your pink or your uh, yeah.
Your pink tinfoil. Um, let me see a
picture of it with a tab can look like,
was it pink? I'm trying to remember
it. See Again, memories. Okay.
Like I was talking about, I know
that registers with me. Okay.
I know that that makes sense.
Yeah. That's what tab looked like.
That makes sense.
But that looks like going to call
the company also so I think Coca-Cola
discontinued tab put more
fucking cancer in it.
Sold in this diet coke. What
I was going to say is I can't,
I could never draw that. Like if you asked
me to draw what a tab can looks like,
okay look I wouldn't be able to do it.
Who was in that realm of that
red but it wasn't Coca Cola red.
That's what I'm talking about with memory.
You know memories is a weird thing.
It's very weird because my memory
with numbers is pretty good.
I remember a lot of important dates
and times and things and statistics.
I can remember a lot of statistics and
I remember a lot of fights pretty pretty
much tell you what the outcome was, but
how much do I remember of seeing it?
How much can I pull up and watch
again? How accurate is that?
I don't know.
Like I was more of a sporting guy when I
was growing up and yesterday I was on a
plane and they had the direct TV on there
and they was showing the best time I
was looking at the iPad. Anyway, I
was watching something on the iPad,
but the screen was on and it was showing
the best 10 football players and they
showed a Joe Montana claw to Dwight Clark
in 81 and away my memories like wait a
second, I want 800 on that game.
Cause I had the ova and I had San
Francisco getting the point man,
fucking Dallas and into San Francisco.
Give it a point in those days, Jeez,
my clock that slowly
Joey was throwing him.
That's what snowy Joey was up this
coat throwing the fucking touchdowns up
there. Joe Montana, I have all
like high school. Who fucked?
Look at Jesus Christ.
Although there was a cat's at
some giant made with one hand.
I Dunno what the fuck. Oh my God,
they showed the best 10 catches.
I was sitting there and I
just was looking at them,
but the actual just one
catch. I don't know what the,
I think this is the kid they traded.
He just reaches up the defendant.
He fucking pulls it in. All My, I don't
know if it's old delt back on him.
I thought it was all go back. It's
like a special is doing those catches.
Did you see Francis and got him
knockout junior dos Santos? Yeah.
I didn't even think it was a real
knockout. He just blushed him. Look up.
He hit him and he went down and helped
his head. Let them fight it out with,
listen, that fight was over.
You got to listen to me.
That fight was over cause he
hit them now. It doesn't matter.
The scary thing is he just clipped
him. He clipped him, he clipped him,
rocked him, put him down,
pounded on his head and jr
just couldn't even move.
He just laid there and take
it and they stopped it quick.
That was a hundred percent legitimate
hundred percent legitimate.
Between you and I that this
would go a little long.
I thought that he was a seasoned veteran.
I thought that he would go at least
take it into the third round and try to
nullify his power by the third round.
You can't keep throwing
those fucking ain't makers.
I told he was with the wrestling a little
bit. It was not what I anticipated.
It was not the game plan.
I thought I got off stage and
it was starting because I got,
as I walked into the green room fucking
they were gone and I was so fucking
happy. I'm like, let me
watch this. I go here.
I think Judy has a shot at him fucking
as I thought that he was already on the
floor holding his fucking boy.
Junior had a good start
where was kicking the leg,
especially the lower part of the leg.
You could really fuck someone up,
knocked him off balance and
that can really fuck you up man.
Like really mess up your movement.
And, uh, if that was the case,
if we was able to mess up his moving
and get them to miss a little bit,
you know,
make get him so that he was having a hard
time moving correctly and keep chewing
on that leg, then maybe there
would be openings for him to,
to jump in with some punches. The problem
is when their balls on the outside,
Frances is bigger and the
consequences are way more grave.
If Francis clips you, it's
99. I don't care who you are.
He's so confident in it too.
He moves forward and he's going
to throw everything full speed.
The first round with him is extremely
dangerous because he's just trying to take
you the fuck out. It takes
a guy like Steve Bay.
Steve [inaudible] saw what he was doing
and what he did was just ride with it.
Just moved away from it,
kept his hands up when
Francis was coming after me.
Use good defense and he kept moving
and kept pitch picking away at him,
picking away at him, picking away at him,
taking his shots when they were there
and then started wearing Frances down,
taking him down, beating him up, and
then just dominated him. Clear cut,
unanimous decision for five
rounds. It takes a guy like that,
a guy like Steve a that has the mental
fortitude to stick to a game plan,
not panic in the firefight cause that's
what happens with in Ghana. You're like,
Jesus Christ, I'm going
to see lights any second.
Now I'm going to see a big flash and
I'm going to be out cold any second.
Now it's calming and you see
the reaction they have to them.
It's they fight different.
They fight different with him than
they do with anybody else because the
consequences are so great.
If you watch the way he
knocked out Allister over him,
the consequences are so grave, so
everyone's scared. No matter it's normal.
Everyone's scared to fight, you know,
there's at least there's going to be
some anxiety or fear or you're going to,
your heart rate's going to get checked,
your adrenaline's going to be pumping,
but it's even more so if the
consequences are more grave, right?
Like if you're going to fucking
take a skateboard down a small hill,
you're not freaking out, right?
But if you take it a skateboard
down like four Mile Canyon,
what does that four mile in boulder,
what does that w one of those crazy
roads that goes sunshine canyon, right?
If you're taking a skateboard
down that go on 50 miles an hour,
you're going to shit your fucking pants.
You're going to try to land this thing,
right?
Try to figure out how not to die here
because the consequences are so much
graver you're going to be more jacked.
And that's what happens to these guys.
And they fight Frances. The consequences
are so grave. They make mistakes.
And then with junior, he reached for
uh, an overhand right. He just really,
really extended himself. You can't do
that with Francis. You just go there.
The scary thing is true with cro courses.
Everybody has a game plan and they get
punched in the face. That's my Tyson,
Mike Tyson offense.
It's some guy all that.
Once you get that first part,
the fight, I only saw two fights.
The funniest one was the first one
against the kid from Dallas. Props to him.
He went
up against like a lieutenant, the KKK.
The guy drew blue on his face at the
way in and they almost got into a little
scuffle in the way and then he
had no fucking love in his face.
He didn't smile.
One time he was definitely a member of
the KKK and there's a little black dude
from Dallas came in and he threw the
spinning back kick and that dude,
it was all over. He hit first
fight on the column, the main card,
which fucking defeated from, he's not
from the miss this plan. This series.
Yeah. I didn't see that fight. First
fight on the card. He's eight. No,
now out of Dallas. Strong guy.
Really good. He still has to,
he's just got to grow a little bit. He's
going to get knocked out once before.
He really makes that big
jump, but once he gets it,
the guy kept doing spinning back
kicks on him and the second one,
he was writing his back. This
guy just hates black people.
Who's the guy that's right. No,
that's Paul Craig. Yeah. Yeah.
That guy that Paul Craig is great now.
He's probably great. It's a fucking joke.
Joke roll. But then he went in
with a tough phase, you know,
like fucking the guy from a, he went
in there like fucking Wa Braveheart.
He's a tough guy called Craig. He's a
good boy. You see the fucking fight.
I'll see it. No, he was great. He just,
the guy waited for the second one and
when the foot land that he was right
behind them, not be new,
new time. Click oof.
I turned around and he hit him
with a fucking dropping right hand.
You could see his feet just go like,
you know when you come at your feet,
just pointing. Same thing. It looked like
he came. He just went, Jamie's got it.
Oh Geez. Jesus. It was [inaudible].
Well that's the first one.
So he said right away he timed it,
but the doc bopping got bought
by. That's it. Look at a man.
The last, the last one he did while the
guy would amend this, look it up for,
he was saying boom, boom.
There you go. Boom, boom.
There you go. He's probably right now
reading fucking Malcolm x's biography.
Freezers. Yeah, that was ferocious.
I'm glad people wonder why
people want to spend that much.
You know those like that. I hate
all that shit. Spinning punches.
Why are you giving your back to
a killer? I never understood it.
Well that's not what I'm saying. I'm
saying if you're not that good at it,
he doesn't have like a really fast,
we didn't commit to it. Barboza okay.
Edson Barboza wheel kicks people and
puts them on Pluto. He spin back,
kicks you to the body. He
mean he's a, his kicks,
his spinning kicks are fucking insane.
But these guys are not that good.
Like what I'm saying is like Paul
Craig, that's not his specialty.
He's more of a grappler. I mean he can
strike, obviously he's a good striker,
but I wouldn't think that he
would want to throw a spin kicks.
He's not like a taekwondo guy. I don't
if you don't do taekwondo for 10 years,
why you spending kicking in the UFC
against? I laugh. Full Attic Guy,
you know all those things.
I hate when they even that reverse punch
when the guy keeps doing it and doing
it. I'm like, you know what, Yo
come bust him in the fucking ear.
See when you're talking about
like Edson Barboza though,
like [inaudible] on the Dan Hangman
kept fucking kicking his body though.
Spinning back. Kick.
Just fucking in gotta commit to that
spitting back and getting my commitment.
Oh, I'm Max Holloway spilling a little
fucking cow bottle and then they got the
guitar played. Did it?
Yeah. What's his name?
John did so did Max Holloway invented it.
I don't know how I just saw it on. Is
he the first person I saw it? Yeah.
Like that's amazing. That's amazing.
Max Holloway's. He's such a fucking
cool guy. I love that guy. One place.
He's a champion. He'll
go, he'll come back like,
who the fuck comes as better than him?
The way he draws to Dustin Poirier
excuses all above all happiness.
He's amazing with Jason Stadium.
What's he doing? What's going on? No,
let me see it. Oh, he's a real
karate guy. Jason. Stay them.
Has real striking skills.
Like, well look, look,
you can tell even the way he's standing
here, like the way he's moving. No, no,
no. He's going to spin it. But you
see, even the way he's doing it,
like this guy's got real
skill. Look at that.
Okay.
Kapow he um,
he achieved a very high
level of a skill in karate.
I don't know exactly what it
was, but from people that, um,
I know that have done martial arts
with him and trained with him and said,
that guy's a bad motherfucker.
Like a legit bad-ass,
like really knows martial
arts. I believe it. Right?
You see him like, I believe it. Seaman,
like snatch one of those movies. Like,
yeah, he fucked people up.
Hey, did the mechanic, oh,
I know. Bothers you. But Hey, it's a good,
I don't want to look at your
fucking face and it tastes good.
It's hard to shame them, but you
really should just say to them, hey,
let's not do that. Let's just write a
movie that's similar and homage to it.
I know they didn't even do it on March.
That's what really pissed me off.
There was no respect at any
level for Charles Brunch.
Not even a fucking out.
Why? Why did he say that?
What do you mean if the, if you watch
the mechanic and study the mechanic,
it just wasn't a white guy shooting
people. He was very calculated.
There was no very calculated.
Everything was made to look like it
was an accident. A very much accent.
One of the best beginnings in it.
The only movie that starts better than
the mechanic, it's scarf. Like no,
there's something that has
a better opening. I forget.
There's no fucking dialogue
for 11 minutes, 12 minutes.
It's him setting up a guy to make it
look like the fucking heater blew up.
Like those type of guys.
Like I had a friend that he used to say
is the best way to kill somebody who's
breaking their house.
Take the fucking pipe,
the gas thing out of the stove,
pointed down and light a camera on
the refrigerator and then leave.
Well give it 1520 minutes and it's late
night. Irene, what does this, Jamie,
this is the of the whole movie actually.
It's on you. This is the
beginning of the mechanics.
This is the beginning of the
original one. Original? Yeah. Okay.
When you know Jan Michael
Vinson, his father in the movie,
Charles Bronson kills. He
gets a contract to kill him.
That's how Jim Michael drips to him.
When he killed him and made him
look like he had a heart attack,
he wanted his medical file and he saw
he had a weak heart and he went to meet
them and then he shot at the
road and he goes, run, run.
So was the guy who was
running, he had on a tie,
Jason straight them and whoever the fuck
made the movie make it look like he was
just shooting my child. But
you're saying to me, joy,
what did it take so much
offense? Because it's, you know,
it's the fucking mechanic. It was
that good of a God damn movie.
You know that we did death
wish. No, no, no. You know,
you can't Redo death wish. One of the
most disturbing movies you'll ever say.
Bruce Willis. Yeah. He should be
shot and then shot again. Okay.
I mean, he did fucking listen. You
know what? That's the wish has,
and nobody remembers
what I saw when I was 10.
This is why I don't play that shit as
one of the most disturbing rape scenes
you'll ever see. And Jeff
Goldbloom Senate members,
they knocked this daughter right,
raped us, spray painted, harass.
I left that movie being 11,
like fearing for my mom. Now,
like I left that and I became
tied with my mom at the bar.
I tried to get a stick, a knife
like that could happen to women.
Like that happens to women. Like
guys just ripped their pants off.
I didn't know. I didn't know what
that shit was. So I watched the uh,
whatever the fuck is this. That's the
way it's a different world for women.
Yeah. I couldn't even believe
it when I watched that.
Doesn't that ever talk about
how disturbing that scene?
Is that something that most men never
have to think about unless you're in jail?
Most men, most men don't have to think
about that with women have to say no.
What happened, right? He goes to Arizona,
they sell him tires on it to build
the building and it becomes run to the
redneck and the redness like, man,
that can't happen to you. He goes,
I put a little something in your bag.
Either take back up to those big city
folks with Charles Bronson got back to his
house, was a fucking
white canon from Texas
Walk Kurzy he was an architect.
He gave him a fucking cannon.
So Charles Bronson said, let me go on
and have some fun and see what happens.
First night, first night, some guy's
like, hey, old time to give me 20 bucks.
And you could see the panic in his
face. He was an old man. He stole it.
He stole it. He didn't take it out and
say, fuck you. No. He was panicked.
He shot the guy in the subway
scene. You could see he scared. You.
Remember when that fucking looking at
him looking at him. Oh, this is great.
That's right. Right here.
Look, he's just an old man dog.
53 years old. Fucking
killing it in America.
Giving men like you and me hope he
was giving the men hope. This fucking
guy, right? Yeah.
I think he was at least 50
years old when he was lunch.
Wow. Look what kind of
skinny is by out by pain.
Got Right that you Bob, look at him.
He's just get better suit on shooting
these guys. Yeah. This is cute.
Brilliant film.
They'll never do that again because
they won't take these little fucking
details. He was petrified. I took crazy
in hard times. I think he
was 50 years old by then.
I remember when he played the, that
boxer a mechanic. He was 51 I think.
Hard tie. Yeah, Bro. He was,
I think he was 51 and there was no
TRT back then son. That dude was doing
things.
He was going to fall Moesha I forgot what
was Formosa that for most of the cafe,
that little bar down there, that's where
he would go like to eat or some shit.
I heard he lived down there. I don't
know what the deal, where does he live?
Well, when he came down like that's
where he took the name Bronson from.
Was that street in Hollywood?
Really? What was his real name?
He's a Polak Radensky something.
Just that they'd told him like,
you can ski. Yeah, you can't,
but it have that name. So he probably
looked around Hollywood. Perfect.
I said Bronson, you fucking believe
that when you hear that shit like wait,
whoa, whoa. Wait a second.
You were walking down the street and
it's like when you had Jamie Fox on it,
he made his name Jamie Fox because
people would think he was a hot chick.
That is the most bullying thing
I've ever heard in my life.
Jamie Fox was a bad mother. Brilliant
man. Brilliant man. Brilliant.
That's the fact that he figured
that out. Yeah. Chicken Shit.
Pick your name on the lineup.
They see that Jamie Fox,
you get a chance to get up
there. So smart. You're re,
you know like if a guy
sees that fox, whatever,
Jamie with an especially with
an eye. You supposed to j I. M.
I does. He doesn't he James
basic, my regular Jamie.
That makes you think it's a broad
right off the fucking back is Jamie j.
A. Y. M. I. E. I would
say it's girl. Yeah.
You said the I before the M is a girl
spelling us a lot of those weird words
like Shawn, but there's a lot of
hot Shawn's that are girls. Right?
What else? What are the ones, it's a
guarantee. They used to be like Stacey,
like these didn't name dude.
Stacey like Stacy Keach. They said,
you know there's a lot of dudes,
they're like in their sixties they to
name guys. Stacey, there's something,
there's a name that a friend of mine had.
There was a guy that can't
remember it now, wasn't there?
One of the weird guys in
airplane. Leslie, Leslie, Leslie.
These name guys. Leslie. How weird.
That's a weird one. What's his name?
Linsley the hilarious dude. Listen
hilarious. The guy was hilarious.
Wasn't he in creep show too?
Was he one of the people in
creep show that got killed?
I feel like he was one of those people
that got buried on the beach or some shit
like that. Yeah. Yeah. He's
a husband. Yeah, he, he uh,
did something to some, some rich guy.
It got buried him up to his head.
I forget those fucking scary
horror movies like creep show,
fun horror movies. They don't make
enough of those anymore either.
Those are my favorite
moves. Anything else?
Scream wasn't bad. Right? It wasn't
bad at all. And what year was that?
87 97 six yeah.
Those are the six 97 fun ass
movie. I think the Latin,
that's the last one I watch.
But the last movie, the scare,
the living fuck out of me was the first
nightmare on elm street with the tongue
coming out of the fall. Before
that, you know the people I go,
you don't watch walking dead. You
know why? Again, I'm loyal to fucking,
when I was a kid, those
dawn of the dead movies,
what was the guy that wrote those?
George Romero. George Romero.
I'm loyal to him. My loyalty is with him.
I took acid and went to George Romero,
that one dorm, the dead.
When the helicopter chops,
a black guy's head off when he doesn't
even know the helicopter lands.
And he says, I'm B. Yeah. And
I think he chops his head off.
I remember tripping on the ass. I
almost had a fucking heart attack.
Walking dead was awesome for the
first few episodes. They just lost.
They just each can't keep something like
that up forever. It just becomes too,
too hard to keep the story going. And
it's just a good story. Got Too weird.
But the best hard movie, Zombie horror
movie of all time. It's 28 days later.
That's the best one. That's
that British movie. So, uh, it,
we didn't get until like way
after it came out in this,
in the theater over there. Most
people have seen it. They've seen it.
They've seen it on cable
or DVD. Right. People.
That's what it was 28 days later.
Even in the theaters out here.
Was it the depth, the depth, the
one after that was a big deal,
but it was a British movie.
Right. Goddamn that movies good.
I remember I bought a
version of it on VHS,
on the number of European VHS was
a different format. He was like,
yeah, I have a different player.
Or you had to have a player that was a
universal player that could play both.
I had one of those just so I could get
some cool documentaries and shit that
you'd get from Europe.
Just just to remind them.
Want to give props to American
Airlines for returning my luggage. Oh,
after the whole weekend.
And they missed that fucking half
ounce of weed in my boxing glove.
So you're the delivery driver.
You are dumb. Fuck. That was,
they lost my movie tie bag. They did.
I was going to Columbus to go to the short
movie thigh and I brought in the, uh,
you know, my little fucking Shin
pads and my gloves. This man raps.
He'd been doing that a lot lately. Huh?
More done. Of it. That's great. Right?
I go twice a week. Well, I've had a,
I'm 56 the targets that thing, and I
take the class with everybody else.
I do everything else I
die. They're like, well,
we don't want the boxing
because Tuesday and Wednesday,
Tuesday and Thursdays boxing. Then when
you do the class, do they have you spar?
I'm 56 I light no headgear.
None of that shit. Chopping pop.
Yeah, working in a combination. Shit
like that. Saturday, Sundays I go in,
there's an open mat. If I'm home,
I go in and there's a chick that's
like an ice cop, an ice cop.
Oh No, she's, she's a
tough chick. Yeah. Yeah.
She trains for Brett and the whole thing,
so I go down and just let her beat
me up to death. Let me ask you this.
As someone who is born in another country,
how do you think that they should
handle the immigrations that are here?
Because this is the big question. A
lot of people know people that are,
I mean probably a lot of people listening
know someone who they love that's
illegal.
Whether they're illegal from Canada or
they're illegal from Europe or they're
illegal from Mexico.
Where the fuck there's a lot of people
that get over here and stay over here
that aren't supposed to be.
Some of them turn out turned out to be
amazing people. So how do you decide,
how do you decide who gets to say and to
someone coming over here trying to make
their life better? A better thing,
but just doing it illegally.
Does that automatically discount them
from staying here? That seems crazy.
What if their great?
There's a lot of people come over here
because they were super unfortunate and
where they were born and they,
they grew up in a shitty place
and they wanted to make it better,
but they didn't know how to do it.
So they came over to
America by Hook or by Crook.
They figured out how to get here. They
got here and now they're kicking ass.
Why? Why would you want to get rid of
them? As long as they're not criminals,
as long as I'm not hurting anybody, why
would you want to get rid of them? Well,
start is, let's do this. Let's
what's going on right now.
Just points the finger
at a certain realm of,
Oh, you're pointing the finger south
of the border. Yeah, it's Canadian.
A lot of Canadian. Which, and I'm
not saying nothing bad about anybody.
This is the United States of America.
People come here to fucking have
a dream and whatever happens, bro,
sometimes the dream goes, could put,
you know, when I went to New York,
I spent three weeks in New York and I
ubered and I did a little thing in my
mind, you know, I took 20 Ubers. In fact,
I became Uber planning because I was
doing, you know, all these rides.
Not One white person picked
me up. Not one time, one time.
And guess what? I asked questions.
I asked everybody questions.
And the most inspiring person I
met was one, not at work though.
I rapped at six 30 in the morning.
There was no way I was getting in the
van to go home. But I just called Uber.
I was in Ridgewood, Brooklyn and
this Indian girl picked me up.
Very cute, you know, six
in the fucking morning.
It's still kind of dark out, you
know, five 30 whatever it was.
And this little girl that
weighed 90 pounds picked me
up, got in the car, hello.
We have charger in the back if you
want to charge your car and this little
caramels in the front, you know?
And I said, where are you from?
And she told me India and I go,
how long have you been a year and
a half spoke perfect English. Wow.
I go, why do you, why did you
become an Uber driver? She goes,
I became Uber driver because I was a
waitress in an Indian restaurant and the
guy abused
me and he would only pay me eight
bucks an hour and take half my tips.
So me and my cousins got together,
we put away money and we rent
the car. We leased a car,
my s she drives in the daytime
and I drive with at night. Wow.
And I drag on, why are you, aren't you
scared to go out at night? She's like,
no. She's like, I love it
because there's no traffic in it.
I go, what do you walk with? I just
asked her creepy questions. Not Sad,
you know? I just watched her and it was,
I went, I gave her an extra tip like,
can you be illegal and do that?
I don't know what the status
was with her. I didn't ask her.
I didn't know [inaudible]
but what do you think?
Do you think that you could do that?
Do you think like if you
came from another country,
you came from Guatemala illegally,
you were came over here though and became
an Uber driver. Could you do that? Me?
No. Can anybody do that or do
they check your citizenship?
What do you think Jamie?
There's yes they can do that.
So someone definitely can come over
here and start working for Uber or or
another or a similar,
I'm not saying that I'm
doing that necessarily like
through the proper ways that
you can get,
if you have a legal friend you can use
their license to be that like the Uber
thing and they don't know who's behind
the car. So it happens all the time.
When I'm ordering food, you definitely
have to have a valid driver's license.
Right? So you get a valid driver's
license if you're illegal.
Oh that's the part like
so I'm saying so like, no,
but that doesn't stop someone from
getting behind a car if you don't have a
license any day. That's
sort of where I'm going,
want to get in trouble right now is on
we on the shit list because we agreed and
somebody else to give illegals licenses.
That's why I was asking does there was
a thought that popped a memory popped in
my head about some story like that,
that they were going to give a
illegal aliens the a right to drive.
I'm sort of saying like it does happen,
but not above the board basically
because it's, yeah. But are you
sure? Could you see if they're,
they're trying to give illegal aliens
driver's licenses because I remember a
story like this too as well.
People are super upset about it.
It's a weird thing. Mash
13 states that allow it.
There you go baby. Where do you
have to move one of those states
in d c uh,
California was the first one as
of 2013. Colorado, Connecticut,
Delaware, everywhere. There's suite,
Hawaii, Illinois, Maryland, Nevada,
New Mexico, New York. Just everywhere.
Their sweet Hawaiian doesn't
necessarily have wheat. Vermont
medicals is very close.
Well, what business standpoint, they
work for cheaper and work harder than,
you know, I mean, there's so many benefits
to as a business owner in different,
I mean, when was the last time you
saw a white laborer? You see them,
you go in the kitchen and at any
restaurant it's all, you know,
I mean, and so now you,
now you questioning what
rights you have as an American.
You come here, you get a job, you're
working hard, you stay out of trouble,
you stay out of trouble. Your mind, your
business, you know, I mean I grew up,
you and I grew up in the east coast where
you'd go to a Chinese restaurant and
you'd see them though the husband and
wife working and the kids would be doing
homework at the back table and
if you came in the daytime,
it was a different couple, which is
telling me that two couples got together,
they buy a home and they opened a
business together and they work together.
That's what those immigrant in groups do.
And then from there they bring a cousin
and they open the open and next thing
you know they got three houses on the
block and now he just had a fucking
immigrant family move into your
neighborhood. Not necessarily good or bad.
You know what I'm saying? That that Nice.
We all had them in our neighborhoods.
Sure. I remember 70 years ago,
this was your grandparents,
so you have to think
about your grandparents.
How would you want them to treat it?
I'm sure your grandpa father got a job,
lame Rick way before he
got his immigration papers.
I don't know how they did it right.
I think they got it pretty quick.
You get through Ellis island and
they pushed it. Boy, shoot drew.
I mean the illegal situation, it
was a different world back then.
You could immigrate pretty
easily. Like my grandparents did.
Weren't rocket scientists when they came
over here. No, they were kids. Their,
their, their parents weren't geniuses.
You know what's going on? Farmers.
Do you know what's going on in South
America right now? Nicaragua and Doris,
all those places. Pure hell, pure. Hell.
You know, I can't be mad at you for
wanting to get the fuck out of that,
but this other places on earth right
now will this Po fucking hell going on?
Yeah, there's trying to come over
to, let's point everybody out.
Let's lock all the fucking borders.
Don't make it seem like it's just
Mexico. That's the fucking problem.
You know, we're getting
bombarded from everywhere.
We're getting new people in here every
day from everywhere. I ain't mad at it.
That come in here to make better lives,
but don't just keep pointing the fucking
water that you know offers coming
through that Mexican border that
nobody's talked about. Jamie,
when you get a minute, if you'd
love to check it, just to verify me.
You know how many Cubans and getting
sent back to Cuba on a daily basis from
Mexico? Real getting back to get a shot.
But Cubans want to come to Miami
Doma, why they're not coming through.
They're closed, all that type of shit.
So right now you can't come through my,
it's easier to come go from Cuba
to Mexico and just join the walk
and walk up. But once slides
here in America, we give
them asylum. Right? Right.
The tag. But then it's still going.
I think robot Emma removed it.
Did he really? Yes. Trump made
it so we can't go over there.
You go pack Mexican shelters.
Hope the Mexican people are going
through Mexico. And that's crazy.
So I think I, the number
of couple of weeks ago,
I think 900 Cubans getting sent back
weekly to get shot. Does
you think that more people,
more people are make it towards
the border since Trump was like,
build that wall, build that wall.
Do you think more people are headed
towards the border now because it's just
like it's a popular thing to
do. It's a part of our culture.
Like a part of the conversation
is the border wall, right?
Like do you want a border wall or do you
not want to go build that wall and make
it a fucking million feet high, bring
it right to that top of the earth.
Or are you one of those people that
thinks anybody should be able to come over
here and have a better
life? You know, and this,
that those two ideas of fucking
clashing left and right.
Some people think that people
should be able to try to do better,
try to better themselves.
They should have the opportunity and
then some people think, fuck them.
You're born somewhere else. You don't
ever get a chance to come over here,
go in through proper channels,
which is almost impossible.
Do something that's very valuable to us
over here. See, that's the thing. Like,
if you are a person who has some
extraordinary skill, you know,
you could probably get American
citizenship easier. You know, unusual.
If you're contributing to the physics
department at Harvard or something like
that and your, you know, you
were born in Germany or wherever,
you probably get citizenship a
little bit quicker than you have.
Just a guy who like lives in Guatemalan,
wants to come to America because
he thinks he can advance his life.
You think he can get better
words where he lives? There's no,
you can't go anywhere. You're
stuck. The, the poverty is extreme.
The is extreme and he wants none
of that. He wants to do better.
So he makes it over here.
I'm like [inaudible] when
you talk about immigration,
you going to get good and bad
from every shelter. You know,
Castro with 79 opened up this prisons
in the Mario and you got 100,000 Cubans
and I'm like a thousand fucking spoiled
rotten savages from Cuban prisons where
they would no clothes in this.
They have to shit in a hole in the
middle of the floor. This averages,
they're animals.
They got no problem taking your
life from a piece of toilet paper,
but the same one's true
from other countries.
You get the good and the bad
from other country, you know,
let's not beat around the bush
before Russians come here.
They going to course they go to a school
and to take a 12 week course and to
come here and get money right off the
bat. How to go to the social security.
Check that out, Jamie.
That's a very weird one.
They get taught how to come
here and scam the system.
Whether you want to call, scan,
I'm not putting nobody down.
I have a tons of Russian friends. I
love him. I'm not saying them bad,
but I've heard that's a fact.
I've heard them from them.
I have a friend who was married and she
told me one day that before they come
here, they take a course to prep them on
how to get money. As soon as they land,
three days after they get them, they land.
They get caching and Dola
paperwork. What to say. They coach.
That's hilarious. This is like a service
that they offer. Some type of class,
the system works. But if you want to,
some of the systems still tell you
how to do that. How many Armenians
come over, come over and get
citizenship? Guess what they do?
They get social security and they moved
back to our meeting and they get the
check sent back to Armenia. They
have a system on how to do that.
They got a thousand loopholes now
brother. And if you learn those loopholes,
you get caved the fucking system.
There's nothing wrong with having a
group of people that all agree on certain
rules, right? Which is what
the United States should be.
But the problem with having
a group of people is you,
you don't get to pick
like who's in that group.
So you just deciding instead of being
admitted by your merit or how how good a
neighbor you are or how
nice of a person you are.
Now you just whether or not you
were born on the dirt like that,
we born on this dirt or that dirt
cause you're born on that dirt.
You can't stay. But if
you're born on this dirt,
even if you're a shit human
being, you get to hang out,
you get to ruin other people's
lives while you're here.
As long as you don't do enough
that we need to put you in a cage.
And then if we do,
we keep you for a couple years and let
you out and you do more. I mean, this is,
we have no problem with that.
I Dunno what the fuck,
what the percentage is. What the
fuck was I going to tell you?
I don't know what it was.
Thought it was what you said.
People versus bad people that come
in across the border. The thing is,
every time there's a bad one
that comes across the border,
it's highlighted as an example of why
we've got gotta keep the border closed and
they have a point. They all
have a point. Absolutely.
When you see someone who was
talking about illegal gang members,
they're sneaking across the
border and murdering people.
It absolutely has happened. It's
100% of a real thing. This is not,
not fiction questions. How
much does it happen? And, uh,
how much better is it for those
people's lives that make it across?
Is there a way to screen better to make
sure that the bad people don't come in
and all of these questions
are legitimate? You know,
you don't want a bunch of fucking evil
vicious people from another country in
your neighborhood. That's
how everybody feels.
You don't want your children in your
family to be in danger because someone's
snuck across the border and they have a
long history of working for the cartel,
murdering people. That's a real
thing. It's a real possibility.
So all the people that are vigilant, all
the people that are scared, you know,
they're probably smart to be scared.
Look at fucking human history.
People are capable of doing some awful
shit. No one's saying like, I'm not,
I don't think there should
be no, no wall at all.
Nothing stopping people
from coming across.
You definitely don't want pieces
of shit coming over here. Well,
let me ask you, this
was how they find out.
Did you ever notice that maybe
we're full. Yeah, we're probably,
maybe we're full. Did you
notice that when you go on,
there's homeless people on Ventura
fucking boulevard on Lankershim Boulevard
under bridges everywhere.
Has that ever come to your
mind that anywhere way you go,
there's cars everywhere and the between
Uber and Lyft in cabs now there's
trafficking. Every major fucking
city. There's that lock or whatever.
Did you ever notice that?
Maybe it's not that I hate Cubans and
Mexicans or Puerto Ricans or blacks with
Germans, Irish maybe
that will fucking fall.
Have you ever come to that conclusion
that we're just full, right? Yeah.
We have to take five years off. Like I
would accept that. I would accept that.
I would accept special circumstances.
Like why are you have family or so,
but at this point right now we're
fucking full bro. Yeah. Yeah. We'll fall.
We don't have nowhere else to put anymore.
We really don't look at no eddies unless
we pack them all to Iowa and send them
all, you know, send them all into my,
where's the highest population
of Mexicans in the country?
I would probably say southern California.
Wrong. Indiana. Chicago. Chicago.
Yeah. Hi. They farm a ton of shit up
in Chicago. I'm going to make sense.
Illinois, you know, where's the highest
population of Puerto Ricans? The Bronx.
You're wrong. Cleveland Clinic,
because in the 50s they shipped,
they all the dealers were with, uh,
taking Puerto Rican is putting
them into the Cleveland,
Ohio area to work in the fucking Ford
plants and all those type of plants.
And after all those places, sat down,
all those people sitting
there holding on to that Dick.
When you go to certain parts of Ohio,
there's a suburb outside of Cleveland.
12 fucking Puerto Rican. Wow.
You know, interesting. But it's,
I don't think of it as we hate
Russians or Germans or anything.
I look at it from a different sprint
back to the times and maybe will fall.
You know,
it's for me to send my daughter to
the date cam cost rebills a week.
I'm not complaining. That's a
great day. Kids a science camp,
they make potions than learn about light
bulbs and electricity. My point is,
I did the same thing for free when I
was a kid. All I do is walk to my park.
There's no funds left. There's
nothing left for these kids. You know?
I don't know. When I walk into
a dodger game or an event,
I go,
I always think of the family of four in
America today that both parents have to
work and everybody has to work.
If you go by my office with a
podcast in the middle of the,
say 24 hours a day camp, and we tell
him to leave my office at midnight,
I see parents picking
up their kids, you know,
carrying them out over their
shoulders into that car. You know,
it costs a lot to control the American
family. There's not a lot of jobs. Wait,
you see everybody's driving Uber. If you
take all this, Uber's is interesting.
I'm thinking of doing a documentary.
I'm just going Uber's and talking to
these people and ask them why they Woburn.
Yesterday I had an engineer
engineer lost his job.
58 years old, got to work Asian fellow.
Very nice. I tipped him extra. He
offered me to plug the phone. I mean,
you know, you have to
look at that and go, wow,
there's a lot of people in
this country without work.
There's a lot of fucking homeless people
and we're running out of money to take
care of what we got here.
It's true. Like there's,
La has an epidemic of homeless people
right now where there's so many tents on
the street and at the fucking dammit,
they're everywhere. I mean it's
definitely, it's fucking Lankershim. Yeah.
You know what they're, when
they're in Sherman oaks. Yeah.
The streets on Heidi on the underpasses
on their passes are stuffed with them
now. Something else. I mean, we have
to, what are you going to do with,
you can't walk through those
underwear. You know what the answer is?
You know what they
usually do with them? Wow.
They give them 100 bucks and they give
them a bus pass to Vegas and now Vegas
has stuck with them. We talked
about that on the pocket tools.
Every city's done that.
Every city keeps doing you
just kidding around like shit.
It's time to get fucking some apart
and put a 10 city and make him be
resourceful.
We'll give them more than 110,000
empty rental units in Los Angeles.
Filling those spaces won't solve the
housing or the homeless horizon. Yeah,
but the problem is if these fucking
things are for rent and you have these
homeless people that are drug addicts
and probably mentally insane and you let
them stay in those rental
apartment, they're going to
destroy your rental place.
Well, let's be honest, there's
110,000 on. Whoa, Whoa, whoa.
Because all depends on what kind of
homeless person you're talking about.
You're talking about a person
who's down on his luck.
Are you talking about a mental
illness, mental illness,
drug addiction that stuck violently.
When I see 60 when I see a hundred when
I see 10,000 homeless people and I'm
like,
I got to assume 4,000 of them are
people are down that look at me.
The slip, they got four
flat tires and it just get,
you know this time people go
through shit for periods of time.
It could be a year. It could be.
It's like these fucking icos.
Every fucking three days. A
hike against lost. Okay. Yeah.
These hikers gets lost and they
stroll off when they get saved,
they're all happy. You see
on my witness news happy.
Wait till they get the bill. They get
hit with a bill. Oh yeah. Every time.
Most went through those
helicopters calls. So they,
there's talks and teach
groups that's volunteer.
If every fucking Hika got paid
for, for a fucking taxpayer,
we'd be broke. So like in Colorado,
so if you're one of those hikers that
goes and snaps her ankle and you're on on
a ridge somewhere, they come and
get you. That costs somebody money.
You gotta pay somebody. There's no
fucking tax funds. Just that cost. Well,
it's going to cost a lot of
money. You get hip listening.
If you like lady who got
stuck in Hawaii for a week,
wherever the fuck she was a month ago,
those helicopters caught something.
She got stuck in Hawaii. Oh,
I lady, the lady teacher,
you know they found her, right?
Yeah. They found them. I assume.
I'm just saying this story just because
what happens if something like that
happened to see it and you get hit? You
ever get involved in a lawsuit? Okay,
and the lawsuit I rear end Joe
Rogan, Joe Rogan's neck and the,
God forbid his neck and his back
hurt. You can't do God's right.
You file a claim against me while
you're going to the doctor, right?
All those months. What is
the doctor usually Rick Bell,
yet everything's payable
30 days. That dirty is it?
[inaudible].
When you start getting those 1100 a
dollar bills from when they look in your
knee and then your neck, when you get 10
of those, how are you going to pay him?
Because you can't pay it. You get the
settlement from the fucking attorney.
A lot of times people go broke
by the time they get the money.
The ship has sailed. It takes
seven years to get that money.
You've been going to the doctor for three
days waiting to concurrence covers all
this one insurance. We'll tell
everybody with the net collars,
is this more complicated? What's that?
Tell everybody with the neck collars.
Oh yeah. It's more complicated.
Yeah. So all those bills add up.
You get hit with a bunch of bills.
Joe, you're homeless, you're homeless,
it's you and your wife,
whatever. It's homeless.
Unless you have parents and you know
you're homeless and you're in there.
So when I look at the homeless situation,
when you hit me with a 50,000 number,
which is a lie, if you go around that way,
it's a lie.
I land at the airport and hooked that
fucking thing onto the four or five north
and look under that. There's a
hundred people just under that.
So whatever number they tell you,
what do you think they'd tell you as
far as like homeless population in la?
I don't know. I know God said he was
under fire. Like I know that fuck. Yeah,
like the people are pissed because they
gave $2 million. They gave $2 million.
They gave him money and they
didn't do Dick. Oh really? Yeah,
they gave me some type of money.
You got to put up some shelters.
I saw that up in North Hollywood studio
is a church that on Thursdays they go
and take showers there. You know,
there was a place in
Maine that was a offering.
They were offering young couples.
They wanted young people and young
families to move up there because uh,
it's tough to get people to live
and some of those parts of Maine,
so they offered incentives for young
people to move up there and a lot of
African folks started
moving up there. You know,
they found out that that
was a good place to be.
And so they like filled up a lot of
their shelters up there. There was a,
an article about that. See if you could
find that interesting. It's like, hey,
they'll, they're like, look,
I know it's cold as fuck,
but we'll take a chance there from
a war war torn part of the world.
And if they could just be
cold in Maine and be at peace,
they beggars can't be choosers. That's
why Marcus Davis lived up there.
I asked him, remember UFC fighter?
I asked him like, why do you,
why do you like it in Maine? He's like,
there's no fucking crime. He goes,
it's none. He's like, there's
none. He goes, everybody's nice.
It's cold as fuck. But everybody's
nice. There was a comedy club up there.
Where was it? Comedy Club was on a
wharf and it floated. No, where's,
where's that came from man of a month.
A Marley, Bob Marley's from Maine.
It was a man came up to the club.
Ones that more asylum
seekers arrive in Portland,
Maine from southern border
is city debates assistance.
Portland's human resources
director criticizes comments
by Mayor Ethan Strimling
welcoming the arrival of more immigrants.
It say that they're all from Africa,
isn't to say specifically Africa,
but they're buying them bus tickets to
go from like San Antonio and tech other
parts in Texas. Oh, I think this is a
different one. This is a different thing.
Yeah. Um, just, just
Google it from Africa.
Did digital main African shelter.
Damn. And this shit popped up.
This gym, this one, this,
that's just one person.
A new migrant surge from the board
of this one from Central Africa. Wow.
Interesting. Uh, but you know,
for other people in other parts of the
world going, I'll take it. I get it.
Maine is, it is cold as fuck for
a good stretch of the winter,
but you know, they just stay in doors
and keep the fucking heat on. Whoa.
La Population, La county
homeless population jumps.
So from 2011 it was 39,414 and in 2019,
it's 58,936.
So it jumped up a fucking
ton to almost 20,000.
And that's a just over a period
of eight years. That's crazy.
That's a lot of people cause a couple
of dudes by my house I take care of,
there's a couple of dudes
that live in shopping cards.
I always drop a little food.
There's one dude that was like,
he's like a soldier with PTSD
and he lives in the park.
He's gotta be six, four, two 80
big black. What do you want to do?
Every time I see him, I pull over.
I give him a 20 I introduced him
to my wife and my daughter. I go,
you see anything used to just attack,
he's just attack. You rip them apart.
When my daughter started
going to Grandpa's school,
I saw them when they walk walking by
the grandmas who I pulled right up,
I go that you see that grandma's go right
there. Go. My daughter goes to school.
You shouldn't be suspicious. White people,
you just rip them apart or whatever.
Lay there. He has a Rambo knife, Rambo,
bigger than ramble. I love
him. I love him. Took that.
You could see where the PTSD and
mental health, he won't take showers,
but he's got a heart of gold.
Whenever he sees me, he smiles.
It gives me a thumbs up. I never said
I believed that neighborhood tag he is.
I seen him in that park. Maybe
six. Never violent behavior.
He doesn't drink alcohol, so I
know he's not just a fucking drunk.
He just can't get a job. He just mental
health. No, it's a mental health issue.
It's, he's a veteran. I asked him,
how you doing? What's going on?
They told me his whole like a little
story as much as he could without being
embarrassed.
So I just do every time I seen him I just
put money in his pan and he's as happy
as a pig in shit, but he's
a fucking stone killer.
They ain't going to be no bleed,
no shootings at that kid's schools cause
I got them checking it out three times
a day. You think I'm kidding. I don't
think you think I'm kidding you.
I love him. I love him. Did
that. My wife waves at them.
We beat by them mercy waves at them.
Everybody's happy with it just
so there's no misunderstandings.
I got a little piece
of mind. Is there ever
going to be a time when there's no
bad neighborhoods? Is that possible?
Is it possible to have a
place where there's no crime
at all? What do you think?
Does that ever really going
to be possible? I mean,
it's definitely better now
than it ever has been before.
And you could think that if, if things
move in the same general direction,
there'd be less crime 100 years
from now than a hundred years ago.
But do you ever think there's going
to be a time where everywhere is safe?
You know,
the Internet gives you a lot of education
on what cities that have no hard time.
They don't tell you, but they
don't really feel yet. You know,
every weekend you see the murder
camp in Chicago. It's crazy.
Every weekend the murder con Chicago,
these fucking countries ain't no safer.
Dominican Republican, Puerto
Rico a couple of years,
but think about a year ago that
is many shootings in Puerto Rico.
One weekend as they do in fucking
Chicago on the weekend. You know,
look at the shit that happens in La. We
don't hear everything. What's happening?
Dominican Republic, all these
people are dying. I die.
I don't know what does that to
many bar. It's this. It's that.
What do you think Jane? What's
it? What do you think Jamie?
Speculation. I heard that there's lots
of deals that get made from like front,
like if you had a friend that was
like maybe refill in mini bars,
your other friend would then refill the
little bottles with not actual liquor or
something like that and like
they just kind of refill those.
I've seen videos online, it's not actually
happened in the Dominican Republic,
but where all inclusive resorts,
so that's what the video said.
They're just refilling bottles of
Kabocha and Hennessy and all sorts of,
just like with Brown water, I don't
know what the fuck they're even doing.
It's like a whole system.
They have this like 15 people.
The little factor in the back of the
shed on the beach just filling up empty
bottles of shit. So
just ripping people off.
I don't know if that's what's happening
in the Dr, but that's what I've read.
Speculation online says that there's
this sort of something going on online.
Not any, it's again a speculation.
It's nowhere legit. I don't know.
There's, see that seems
to make sense, right?
If someone had a scam and those little
mini bar bottles or kind of expense on a
bad batch and just like you
get bad batches of drugs,
they've got to find out they got some
homemade fentanyl or whatever. Yeah, yeah.
Maybe they got some bullshit homemade
booze that's poison that got spread
around. Yeah. Yeah.
But the whole thing is suspicious that
they're doing kinky shit at the hospital.
Kinky Shit. Yeah. What kind of Kinky
Shit? No answering no answer. No, I blow.
We don't know. Oh Blah, blah,
blah. You know what it is?
They probably overwhelmed. Imagine if
we're sitting over here talking about it,
how many people have been calling them?
How many people are furious because
they lost their loved one over there.
They don't know what the fuck is going on.
And then someone said that it's not
necessarily really an uptick that does not
necessarily really an uptick of deaths.
It's just that they're highlighting every
time someone dies and that the reality
is people die all the time. I don't know
if that makes sense. You know, like,
I mean how many people, if you
were just looking at Los Angeles,
they come here and they visit when
I'm having a heart attack and die.
It might be a lot, you
know, we don't know. I mean,
how many people come over
here from another country
every day and wind up dying
while they're here? Is that a normal
thing that people do? Cause people do.
I mean,
if people are dying of heart attacks and
all sorts of strokes and all sorts of
other shit,
is that because someone's doing something
to them or is it because 100,000
people a day come over here
and one of them a day dies?
I don't know what those numbers
are. I don't know if it's legit.
What'd he show them? People that
died. It's number grant numbers.
I guess this looks like only
maybe 12 to 15 people since March.
March. That's a lot. But is it, I
don't know. I don't know if that's it.
Or here in California, all these people
are older than no people. 50 or older.
Yeah, fit you right. Which can
happen in any point in time,
especially if you're on vacation doing
Viagara, drinking straight Jack Daniels,
fucking up a storm,
other than
you could have a heart attack,
bro. But all jokes aside,
no disrespect is that, can you a Google?
How many people is this an
uptick or are really, is it,
what's the best way to say
this? Die Per year. Yeah. Yeah.
What's the annual tourist rate
towards death rate and is it any different
from what we're experiencing now?
Because it would be weird if
we just found out that no,
this is just what happens and they're
just making a big deal out of this for a
story with this that you know, 55
year old drunk guys die every year.
Dominican Republic and Cuba and in
Puerto Rico and people get hammered on
vacation. Brows don't like it.
You know what I heard about Dominican
Republic pulled back on that.
I have no reason to go there. Why
they saw cocaine on the beach.
I do not like that idea at all.
When I heard that they sold
cocaine on the beach at a,
what's the big Mexican resort?
Where the people go for spring
break. Oh, I said one, but oh yeah.
Tell them no, no. I told them
they can't go and can't come.
They sell coke on the beach. All those
times when you sell coke on the beach,
I don't want to be on that beach and I
was at trinity. You know what I'm saying?
I just have this weird feeling about
that they sell coke on the beach.
They do that in um, Costa Rica too. I
had somebody offered me some below. No.
Yeah, yeah. I feel sexy.
Stab a funny joke about that.
But walking down the street and someone's
trying to say, I see coke, coke.
You've got coke. We've got, we'd got
coke. The guy would see me. Heroin.
I think it find heroin, I think goes the
fuck. Why'd you think I wanted heroin?
Man, I can afford coke. Very funny one.
About 2.7 American Americans visited
Dominican Republic last year,
which publicly releases data on only
about natural deaths such as car crashes
and drowns does not release information
about deaths by natural causes such as
heart attacks or strokes.
Even though it compiles reports on
Americans who die on all Americans who die
abroad. It's a matter of statistics
that certain number of travelers
will, will suffer serious
illnesses, accidents,
and even death while
traveling internationally.
The death rate in the Dominican Republic
is not any higher than the death rate
in the states official said.
That's what I'm talking about.
When people visit other countries,
don't expect them to stay alive because
you don't expect them to stay alive
here. They die all the time. But when
you're talking about what did they say,
what was the hundreds of thousands?
How many hundred thousand people visit
the Dominican Republic every year?
2.7 million visited last year. Americans
visited last year. Oh my God. Really?
2.7 million. Yeah. Wow. The fucking
10 people died. 1112 people have died.
I guess. Why did I think it was hundreds
of thousands? It's way more last year.
11 people died last year. No, this
year. This year. A couple months last,
but 12 people. That's a lot of fucking
people going over there. Man. People die.
But meanwhile, everybody's scared
to go to the Dominican Republic.
So it's like probably killing
their business and okay.
It was fine until we track
out the mini bar. Come on man.
Are you sure? You know some? Some
people I'm sure are getting the,
the scary one was the lady
who got attacked. There was
a lady who got attacked.
They beat her half to death.
She has no idea what happened.
She saw a guy with an
outfit on from the resort,
let go an employee's outfit and he fucking
clubbed her and beat the shit out of
her and she doesn't remember anything.
[inaudible] he left her for dead and
when they found her they thought she was
dead. You know, bro. Shit,
for the last 10, 20 years,
there ain't nowhere I really
want to go. Hawaii's awesome.
I'm scared of all that shit. Go to
Hawaii. It's the United States. We will,
I'm the nicest fucking people in the
world. Yeah, go ahead Joey. Or you know,
my wife and I said, Donald, we're
like all the places you want to go.
It's a six hour fucking
flight. It's true. You know,
go while doing what we do. We got some
of the best coach in the world here.
If you stopped down by San
Diego, mix it up a little bit.
One of the beaches go up north to Santa
Barbara. Go even up a little north,
you know, so we're going to
do that a little bit. I mean,
Santa Barbara is beautiful. Santa
Barbara is beautiful. Be On vacation,
you know, and you're an hour away.
We take too many fucking planes to be on
six hours to go to fucking Miami or New
York. I told about taking
it to the Jersey shore.
I thought about doing a lot of shit
like that. This so what you can do too.
You could do a couple day trip,
like go to Santa Barbara
for a day to Santa Barbara.
Go up past the San Luis
Obispo. That's real nice.
I don't know if you know this like
fucking eight hour days there.
I hate holidays cause it's softened such
this look like guys like you and me.
We worked through everything
but this mother fuckers,
the two weeks before Christmas,
they shut down on my ass.
They start singing jingle bells or shit,
you know, a week before mother's Day,
a week before Memorial
Day. It fucking kills me.
Like this memorial date
killed me. You got to figure,
I was in New York for three weeks,
you know, walking around. I was like,
come home in the first day. I come
back the Memorial Day weekend.
Nobody's having a party. Nobody's doing
shit. Finally Monday I told my wife,
I go, fuck it. I got
tickets for the dodger game.
Let's go to the dodger game and
what are you doing for the fourth?
I'm going to the beach. Nice. I'm
leaving fucking Wednesday morning.
When did we have a barbecue over my house
for the fourth when you brought your
daughter, when was the last time? That
was like three years ago. Years ago?
Yeah. She was two or three. She was
so, you know, she's six. She's so cute,
man. She pointed to me and went,
Yuck. I asked her the other day.
I go, you don't say yuck no more.
Then she goes, Nah, I grew that.
I came close to where you were holding
her. I came closer to say hi. I'm like,
how are you? Which is like Yuck.
And now if she sees you, she goes,
I know him. Yeah, that's what she still
remembers you. She's got, you know,
that's the door. The kids
memories are horrible.
And I remember being a kid and going
to my mom's bar and there were certain
people that would walk in and my
Mama Go, before you say anything,
I don't want you to know that he remembers
everything. He doesn't react to you.
He'll tell me at two in the
morning, I would think my mom,
shit like that dude came in, he had a gun,
he had something on his nose and
my Mama Go, Jesus fucking Christ.
So my mom would, and that's what's
crazy about kids. You a little people,
they in another room having a
conversation with your wife.
Three days later she'll tell me what that
conversation was and I'll just look at
it. I don't smoke in the house
no more. She's busted me once,
but she never said nothing to nobody.
This is, I can tell she's a Da.
She keeps her mouth shut. I walked
out, she was right there and I said,
I was talking to, her smoke
was coming out of my mouth.
She didn't say one word to
me and she hates smokers.
Like she fucking eight smokers.
Not because it's bad for them
because they ruined the environment.
That's hilarious. She's nothing about
health. She's like, they know good people.
Smokers are no good
because they're running the
environment daddy. So I'm like,
okay, what are you going to do? No,
I'm thinking about the Hawaiian thing.
I want you to hook me up
from a to z. Let me know.
I know it's a certain [inaudible] to
go playing. What time would he is?
Cause I don't know what time of the
year ago. Okay. That's all bullshit.
Fuck yeah. For Hawaii. Okay.
I'd go to Hawaii any day.
The air so that you don't go from like
December to February cause it ain't no
season or nothing like that. We
went in June before that we went,
last time we had gone was in
January or December. Yeah. It's um,
it's beautiful. The people are so
nice, man. It's just, it's last time.
I shouldn't say this, they'll
probably get getting mad.
You're going to make more people
come over there. It's fucking,
it's an amazing place to live, man.
They live in paradise. They live there.
They're on an island that's created by
a volcano in the middle of the ocean and
it's fucking gorgeous. It's so pretty.
What was just crazy? They show in
the water. Uh, we saw a lot of, um,
a lot of dolphins, man, [inaudible]
spinner spinner dolphins,
I guess they call them. I guess that's
what kind of dolphins they were.
I don't remember what kind of dolphins.
Um, but back in December we saw whales.
That was awesome. That's amazing man.
You see fucking whales breach
the surface of water. Like whoa,
Wild Ben just out there in boats and he
look for his splashes in the distance
and then we saw them that big schools
a dolphins, they swim under your boat.
It's wild shit man. You know,
cause they're just these crazy sea
mammals that are super intelligent,
live in the water right off.
Went off the coast. I mean,
that said it's such a paradise
because what Hawaii has it? No,
the place does is it's fully surrounded
by the most beautiful, pristine water.
There's no shit beaches on Hawaii.
It's all gorgeous water and then
scuba G. Yeah. No, he snorkeled.
Okay, so when you went to no, no.
That's kids the fuck out of me though.
I Wa that scares the fuck out of me.
Shock. Scare the fuck out. Okay guys,
you got killed. I love you. Thank you.
I love you too. I am fucking point.
I am petrified. I don't
know by you shouldn't do.
I grew up in a bar like I still remember
my mom taking me to coloniality though.
Being a little kid, getting
a hot dog. I got both times.
I went to Coney island. I had drama
the first time I went to Coney island,
I got caught. Now. What's
the, when the undertone.
Yeah. Yeah. Where you, you were at, you
go out and you're on your waist. Yeah.
I mean you were playing. Yeah.
We look at our parents and they're
two miles away. It's very dangerous.
I sold the fucking life guards. I had
to be five, maybe five, maybe four.
I was my first experience in Coney
island. Second experience in Coney Island.
They all, my cousins were jumping
up and down. I'll never forget it,
how to be hot, like those hot
days. We ran in, you know,
with swimming around and all of a sudden
we look up and there was the biggest
piece of shit.
It was 1314 inches
spinning around the beach,
just floating past us, walking
out and telling my mom,
I'm never going back.
That was the last time I went to Coney
island and then I went to Jersey and I
went to the beach and I loved it.
Everything was Hunky Dory and it started
here about 2003 I went down to the
beach and when we got there that
got in, the lifeguard walks over,
you know after you smoke a fucking
joint, you got the SPF on you.
The guy comes over and he goes to
the beach. Isn't closed officially,
but there's been a couple
shark sightings this morning.
So if you go into the wall,
I just want you to know,
let me know and wave over at me.
This is when you come up here and you
make the right turn down. Uh, you know,
I don't know. Anyways,
it's the other way of going down to the
beach after four or five way to sunset
and you get off. It's the other way.
What Canyon did you go down? Topanga.
Topanga. Canyon. Do It on that?
Yeah, that time we got right there.
As soon as we landed, had to
be 2003, 2002 the guys set up,
it's not close, but they'd been
seeing the couple spots are tiny.
I always try to go in the ocean. I'm
Cuban. My mother loved the beach.
We always went. Every time
I go to the beach, I go,
what the fuck is wrong
with me? And I buckle up.
I take four steps, I dip in,
and then I walk out a little bit.
And once I start bouncing, I go on.
Then I take a couple of
strokes. Joe, I feel great.
And as soon as one of those
fucking things touch my foot.
You never see a fat motherfucker
run as quick as you see.
I just run out straight and that's it.
I put my SPF on and I
don't go back on the water.
I go in just to refresh myself.
Did you see the fucking great wines
they saw sold the coast, the jersey,
the one that bit the guides and
stuff, fish when he's bringing,
did you see that unbelief? That's not
normal brother. I grew up in Jersey.
There's always been sharks,
but not great whites like that.
Great whites started.
The first time I ever saw
a shark was in Montauk.
Montauk is next to amity where
they really shot. George.
Charles is supposed to be hammering
on one of those. If you look,
I don't know what correctly
it is when they shot George,
it's supposed to be the
coast of fucking Long Island,
but if anybody knew when I was a kid,
I used to go to Montauk all the time.
That beach was no boy, no dog.
You'd be on the beach and a
fucking crab would walk up to you.
They walked back with business cheese.
This is unheard of guys. Come on.
That's just biting their bully. Is that
what that is? Is that a sack of meat?
They're chumming it other chumming.
Why is it biting that thing then?
Is that definitely what's going on?
What is the on that rope back there? Oh,
it sort of ripped it apart. Oh yeah.
Look there's salmon filets
2000 pounds or a fish. Fish.
Filets they think
the shark was 2000 pounds.
Sorry to stop. Stop doing this.
Cause it's hard for me to tell
what's going on. Okay. They dangled,
so what is it biting? What is that
yellow thing? It's like that. Oh,
buoy or something? Yeah, it looks
like it. But why would it bite a buoy?
It's a fucking animal. But you see
how they have that piece of fish?
They were dangling in the water.
It seemed to me like they were
trying to earn that, but that would,
that fish, it was already filleted so
it's like the body, the head and the tail.
It seemed to me like they're putting
that in the water to attract sharks.
I bet they know a spot where sharks
see, see what I'm talking about? See,
that's the part of the fish
that you can't, you know?
It's like he's got it opened up like a
filet and they're dragging it through the
water, I think to try to attract them.
Maybe they saw it and they're like,
let's see if we can get a close on. Yeah,
maybe. Right? Yeah. Fuck Shit.
Nevermind. Get it away. Throw it. Yeah.
See they're throwing that
in the water. I don't know.
Definitely try to bring them closer
to the boat. I don't give a fuck them.
They put a leg in the water,
looked at the size of that fucking
thing off the coast of Jersey.
That's what makes you want
to scratch your fucking head.
That a week later our seal attack,
the girl in the California beach,
a seal.
I saw one where a seal grabbed a girl's
leg and pulled her into the water off a
dock. That was a different one. This
is another, this is another one,
and they're blaming it on
a chemical in the ocean.
Hello knocks or something like that
that wants to seals. Uh, get that in.
Look at this girl. How she got dragged
in. Cause look at this. Look at this.
My brother.
Oh my God.
Oh my God. Yeah. Don't fuck that.
Why something's going on. Shit.
Holy Shit Bro.
I think the climate change
is everywhere. It's all over.
And the flag is that every
toll that thing car like wow,
that's crazy that they
got it on video too.
It just jumps up and
bites her fucking leg.
Maybe to pay back to this week. The dogs
trying to get the dog. Yeah. I
don't know what's going on here now.
It's a big giant shark. Oh Gee.
And then the rest of the dogs come in to
help its buddy and it sort of stays for
a second. I thought maybe it had one and
they're trying to get it to release it.
Did it. I don't believe so.
Looking at Jesus Christ,
that's a really crazy fucking
video. But the dogs are huge also.
There are no other bitch ass dogs like
yes. Be too sharp. Savages like that.
That's a fucking shark, bro. No
dog. You gotta be very careful.
You gotta be very careful.
Now something's going on and you have to
do think the world's coming to an end.
Not at all. What do you think?
How many Bravo fuck the world.
We got whistling and Dick
until something happens.
But we'll make all these shark attacks,
especially on the east coast the last
three weeks. Well, here's one thing,
especially on the east coast, one thing
could be lack of food, right? I mean,
they overfish the fuck out of the ocean.
People know for a fact
that that's a real problem.
That's a real problem over
fishing's a giant problem.
They're worried that the ocean fish in
some parts of the world will literally be
extinct. There'll be nothing
left and 50 60 a hundred years.
Who knows if they don't
clean up their act,
but you'll see the way they
do with commercial nets. Just,
just throw those fucking
things in and just insane.
Wide Nets just scooping up
everything and then they,
they get all these fish and they dump
them in the huddle of the boat and it's,
it's crazy how much fish they
kill. It's crazy how much,
what a desire for fish we all have.
But if sharks run out of shit to eat and
then the seals run out of shit to eat,
the sharks start running out of seals
when they start going after people.
What do seals eat? That's a good
question. I don't imagine they eat fish.
Yeah,
right. Here's goal. Yeah.
Seals up in San Francisco.
We're getting killed by sharks.
We have such a eye level at such a high
level that I guy was on a surfboard and
I couldn't imagine why the shark bit them.
And then they looked into it and they
said from underneath the shark just sees
they see us. I'll see you. Yeah. Yeah.
Was a crazy video of a shark taking a
seal out out on this one right here.
Right in front of all these people
on the, on the Marina, the Alcatraz,
Alcatraz. Okay. Watch this. Back it
up a little bit. What's the splatter?
The shark just jacks his fucking
seal right in front of everybody.
They're all looking out. Watch
this. Boom. Look at all that blood.
And everybody's like, what the
fuck? So oil slick a blood.
The shark comes out of the
water with the seal. I mean,
look at that blood that is madness.
Bright Red Blotch and a fucking huge
shark destroying a seal in front of
everybody just to let you
know, that's their world.
There is monsters right there. It's
just they can't get out of the water.
I mean,
imagine if that was like right next to
the woods and you know that if he didn't
go into the woods, you'd be okay.
But if you did go into the woods,
there's a giant gray thing that moves
30 miles an hour that just bite the legs
and arms off of everything it runs
into. Is that what the village was?
They scared them from going into the
woods because something's going to kill
them if they, yeah, they,
they'll, they put on a, a costume.
The village was about a bunch of people
that didn't know that it was like 2000
and [inaudible] they're going
to die by something. Yeah,
they scared them with some costume
or some shit. Right. Giant Shark.
But that's what it's like when
you're sitting on the dock.
They're looking out at that shark
fucking up, that seal in the water.
It's right there. I mean
you could just jump in.
I mean it is sort of like
being at the edge of the woods,
watching some mythical monster tear apart.
A creature in front of you. We
spoke when you went Hawaiian.
That's the first thing I said
to you though. I'm looking
out for the sharks dog.
I'm worried about nothing happened were
fun and they got hammerheads down there.
Well there's a lot of tiger
sharks, tiger sharks bite people.
Bull sharks are apparently the most
dangerous and they are the weird ones
because they go to freshwater,
they'll go like they found bull
sharks way up near Illinois,
like near Chicago on rivers,
bull sharks getting fresh water and
swim all the way up the river. In fact,
Johns was actually inspired by bull
sharks that bit people over like a
successive couple of days in New Jersey,
in a river in New Jersey. That's
the actual original story.
That inspired jaws came
from shark attacks and like,
I want to say like maybe the 50s or some
shit like that that were near a river
in New Jersey. Freshwater river,
speaking on the New Jersey.
Something I want to show you, see
if he could find that story. Jamie.
I know there's been sharks sippy river.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, exactly the same.
Same kind of story. Yeah,
exactly. They can go way up.
They can survive in fresh water. The bull
sharks are a, they're a weird animal.
I think that monster guy that, that
television show river monsters, that dude,
that cool guy. I think that
guy, uh, caught one somewhere,
if I remember correctly,
that guy that used to hang out with
wildboys Steve-o and Chris Pontius Manny,
he got into that water in the bay at
San Francisco with like 200 bull sharks.
The footage of it is fucking crazy. Oh
my God. He's like, you seem so insane.
There's no cage and
nothing, nothing. Mama CBOE.
How about when Steven was on that fucking
tree and the lions jumped up in the
tree to be with them? Like
what the fuck's on there?
T they took his hat from him,
took his hat off his head and like
what? What, what, what?
Like he was inches from death.
One of your fans sent me an article
for you about six months ago.
Really interesting. I got it
somewhere. My phone to gets on toilet.
So Rocky Balboa, rocky mountain more so.
Vesta alone was a young guy and he went
into a gym in Bayonne because he wanted
Chuck Wepner owners trainer to
train him. But Chuck Wepner,
his Tryna told him to fuck off because
so investors, that alone had done porn
social vessel salon the way out stole
chuck weapon's notebook that he wrote in
and that's,
we took the idea for rocky
is a true attribute here.
This, I never heard that there's isn't,
maybe it's true despite the fact that
still Sloan was sued by Wepner in 2003 for
using his story for rocky.
He ultimately settled for an undisclosed
amount of money in 2006 according to
Forbes,
seems to be in good spirit about whitners
tale being told on the big screen and
an interview with deadline chuck producer
Mike toll and said this Stallone was
supportive of everyone involved reading
the script and even showing up on set.
He and live had positive
dialogue during shooting.
Totally about check about it,
chuck. Hmm.
Um, that's weird that he's
used his story for rocky.
So the idea was that he uses story when
Chuck Wepner fought Muhammad Ali based
on, nobody kind of makes sense
that that would be based on,
cause Carl weathers was Kinda like a
Muhammad Ali character and rocky Balbo was
Kinda like chuck Webster. But if I
remember that fight correctly, I mean,
I remember Muhammad Ali beating
the shit out of Chuck Wepner.
I don't remember it being like
a close fight like they made,
didn't they make that
fight or draw wasn't rocky.
He would draw the Muhammad Ali knocked
him out. Chuck weapon low down.
He beat him. He beat him up. They
beat him up. He didn't knock him out.
But I think he went, I
think he went 12 round men.
That might've been 15 rounds my thing
back when they were doing 15 rounds,
matter of fact, I think it
did. I think if I remember
correctly, it went to distance. But again,
my boxing knowledge is not like my
MMA knowledge. It's like B level.
What year was that?
1975 it was built as the
give the white guy a break
[inaudible]
oh my God, that's hilarious. They
should've done that in rocky.
He's knocked out in the 15th round. Okay.
15th row. So that's what I'm saying.
It wasn't like rocky, rocky.
The story of rocky is this guy
who actually was a good fighter,
but you just never focused himself,
decides to focus himself for this
preposterous opportunity to fight for the
title and actually hurts
them actually hurts him.
And that's a draw at the end of the fight.
It's a crazy fucking war
and turns out to be a draw.
That was not chuck Wepner story. I mean,
unless they use part of
Chuck Wepner his life. Yeah.
He might have been,
might have his may be some truth to
that fucking story maybe. And stolen.
There's always been known to
have a sticky fingers. He stuck.
You're filling the expendables.
That was Eddie students. Yup.
And that used to take them
back. There was in those days,
that's what they did right. For
people. But people don't know is,
there's a couple people who do
that. They meet with a guy, Jamie,
I hate doing James. I got an idea. But
like I moved back to Columbus also.
The Lady Jamie turns the TV on
and there's this story on TV.
Jamie takes him to court
and wins even has the notes.
The appointment that his agent made for
him to meet Stallone Austin Long has to
shell him now is for the
amount of the script.
He doesn't have to give him
proceeds of what he made. Yeah.
So it's a tremendous scam if you do it
and get away with it. I've listened.
I'm not bad mountain alone.
Let me tell you some,
every time those Rockies come on,
I watch those fucking things and I am
more and more baffled that they kind of
still hold up.
And what's really baffling about
the Rockies is they keep on coming.
I mean, you know, they're
writing another one, creed crazy.
Now they've got Michael
B. Jordan. Yeah. You know,
did you see the video of Michael
B. Jordan going through that?
A tactical course? It's
fucking bad ass, man.
I don't know what movie
he's preparing for.
Please prepare for some fucking crazy
crazy shooting up movie. I guess.
You know, I did the heron tactical.
I did this thing with our boy and I didn't
know like my boy was John Brenton was
telling me that after movies he does,
you got to go there at six
months before the Joe Rogan.
He's going through one of these
courses like John Wick style.
You've got to go through
six months of this.
It says it's a with for Black Panther.
So this was when he was in that movie
Black Panther. So he's preparing for it.
She's a bunch of guns in
that movie though. So, I
don't know. Make sense? Yeah.
He did shoot a lot of guns in that
movie. Yeah, he was mercenary.
Don't you remember Michael B?
Jordan was a killer and
that movie remember the hand
to hand fight. So I guess,
yeah, well there was that
too, but I'm sure there was
some gunfights and just to be able to
handle it and look and look like this,
look like, I mean,
I don't know enough about shooting
to know if this looks good.
It looks good to me though.
You know what I'm saying?
Or if you watch like Tom Cruise
and collateral [inaudible]
when he goes into the
Japanese bond in Korea
town or whatever it is,
he's using tactical shooting. Right?
Like it's real tactical. Yeah.
I always knew that time cruisers
and the ultimate professional, he,
that's why he gets 20 80
million a movie, the whole deal.
But when I talked to her
boy, he was telling me, Nah,
that all these movies now
you go over there five,
six months before the movie
starts and it's, you know,
eight hours of training. I mean you got
to give it up for your boy John Wick.
Oh yeah, he's 56 he's doing
five hours a day Jujitsu.
He's doing Jujitsu and he, there's
a bunch of scenes of him doing that,
so he did it with the Henry rifle, one
of those Henry old school western rifle,
sh bang. What are those called?
You know those little load
them up ones where you,
I don't let her rest down to
reload memory. When we were kids,
we had those in the middle. You
pumped them to strongly BB, your shot,
your grandmother, you pumped it
like 80 times. If you hate it,
the mother Fucker, you start pumping
that bitch at like six in the morning.
You get all full. That was
the ultimate dangerous.
Who happened to give to a kid a
fucking beat. We had everything.
We had one of the, remember
the risks rockets, rockets,
was that what I call those
tubes? Surgical tube. Oh my God.
I had a friend that lived on the second
floor and he would just peg off kids as
they were walking home from school,
Ritchie vantage checking God.
He was in school too. So he
would run home from school,
go on his fucking on his
second third floor attic,
lay on the floor like a
mercenary and just shoot kids.
They couldn't invest in him. My God.
How funny was he? He would put nails,
he would put downs and like
tables like these school.
So when people put their books
down, they get caught by the nail.
He was just a fucking nut.
Now he's somewhere installing
elevators in Pennsylvania somewhere.
Who the fuck knows risks? Rockets are
so dangerous. We used to use marbles.
Let's take risks. Rockets buy a bag of
marbles and get a wrist rocket. Oh yeah.
Cause marbles. They fly consistently.
You can get used to where the trajectory
is gonna go. If you have a rock,
you know the fuck knows how much that
rock ways you know this rocks everything
that rock. It's hard to figure out
where the fuck things are going.
But when you get good with a marble,
you understand they're like right here.
I kind of can judge the arc of that
marble. You can start nailing things.
You can start nailing things. And when
you got your first marksman repeatedly,
you would get the marks from repeat
it. I never had one of those marks.
Repeat Pallets, B B's and guards.
I had one of those and I was
about eight my mother caught me,
gave me a beat and I had the
fucking double o seven knife.
That's a knife from the 70s they either
sold them in Newark or in Harlan.
I remember several oh sevens that a
wouldn't handle, wouldn't handle big.
I used to get the paint, the jeans.
Do you know when I was like
by this third grade, you know,
I used to shake him down on
the way out and then the way.
And do you know that? Because
they were worried about, yeah. Oh,
in the first, second grade before
my mother put me in Catholic school,
it was called shake down, take socks off.
Wow. Socks. How much money you went
out with. Does this count? No, no,
that's a marginal repeat. Oh look at it.
It was BBC pallets and that's
where you put the dots up on top.
You had a lot of fun kids got shot by
the cops. And holding that thing? None.
What are you talking about? None.
None. None. That's the seventies Nah.
[inaudible] talk to you first
before they shot you in the head.
When did they start to shoot and
they shoot you in the fucking leg?
Back then they were normal people
because they would neighborhood kids.
They knows days. The cops
in your neighborhood,
60% were from that neighborhood,
so they understood the person.
They understood the kid. They
knew he had mental health.
Now they'll get somebody from Culver
city and put them in San Diego.
They don't know the area.
When we were growing up,
especially when you were
staying with your Grandpa,
newer called those cops grew up
in Newark, the road and stuff.
Fucking crazy. Don't worry about them.
It's when you go out over the Rogan's,
you take your gun out. You
don't point it out, right. Joel,
put the gun down when
you see what I'm saying.
Like the cops were members of
the community, so they knew,
so they knew they weren't
going into everything cold.
They weren't going into everything called
I think the people that have to worry,
the monster cops that pulled people over
because you just fucking never know.
You see what happened yesterday? The cop,
the black dude in North
Carolina or wherever he was,
I don't know where he wasn't,
sorry if it's North Carolina,
he was smoking a blunt. The cop pulled
him over. He fucking dragged the cop.
Whoa. Grabbed him by the elbow,
Jamie. I know you saw it on the news.
Dragged them twice. Not once, but twice.
The cop will try to pull the gun. Then
the cop shot him in the leg. Oh Jesus.
And he still dropped the cop off and
he got away. Wow. What's out there?
The hole in his leg? Yeah.
No, they finally caught him.
He went into the ambulance. You
know, I won't get look at this.
So he's just smoking the blot. Looking
at him right in front of the cop.
The cop said he smoked marijuana.
So while he's driving off, is
he holding onto them? Yeah. Oh,
the side.
So the guy tried to
drive off and he hung on.
It looks like he hung onto
the car. Am I correct there?
I don't know. I don't know. I
can get the audio. That's um,
when you, uh, seeds reaching for his
gun, now look at what now look at that.
Those bullets. Yeah.
I mean, just driving off with them in
the car. He just dumped from the edge.
I Rogo Shit. What?
He just doesn't there and that
got fell over on the dirt.
He probably fucked himself. He
fucked himself up. That poor guy.
So was he holding on? So it's
like when the car takes off,
like what is he doing? It looks like
he's holding on, said escalate Joe Rogan.
I can't tell. So it usually has like it.
Yes. So they usually have that panel.
Who along the side where you put your
leg up if you see standing on it.
That's what I think is going on. But
he's holding onto the window too.
It looks like he's trying to hold it.
Let's say he's got his arm in
by this time he's got his lies.
He's holding onto a seatbelt
put up there. Right there.
He's holding onto his seatbelt.
Yeah. No it is. Look at him.
Look at his seatbelt. That is what he has
in his hand. Oh, that is what he said.
Oh yeah, that's it. That's what he
has. So he's holding the seatbelt, man.
She got his fucking gun out
and shoots the guy. Not yet.
Then he goes to grab for his gun.
It's that when he shoots him,
cause the dude does look like
he at one point in time, man,
leave me the fuck alone.
Look at his grill.
I'm just trying to smoke
my motherfucking blunt.
What is going on with his teeth? Is
that like some kind of iced out grill?
I don't know. Now that's when he
starts out. Boom. He shoots him. Wow.
But Ellie, he at least he shot him in
the leg and not in the no. Right, right,
right. But the whole
thing seems rather crazy.
He's hanging on with just a gun by Dash
Cam shows Florida man driving of course
from Florida.
Draft it off for the deputy dragging
from his car after a traffic stop.
The man is now facing an
attempted murder charge. But okay.
Was he dragging the car
or was the guy hanging on?
He was the guy hanging on while he's
trying to drive off. Was that the same
I guess? Yeah, but I mean, I don't know
if he told you to stop, you can't go.
So like he can't just drive
away and just drive away.
Once the car starts moving
and he's hanging onto the
door, you are dragging him?
Yeah, so he's hanging onto the
seatbelt and they're dragging him.
What should matter? You got a
hundred fucking stitches. Whether
the guys walked around
with a bandage slate.
The dude who got pulled over though,
he's hilarious. Play that again.
His reaction, he just
keeps puffing on the blunt,
put them back. I look at him, he
goes, I smelled marijuana man.
What are you talking about? What?
Look at him. He's hilarious.
He's right out of a movie
like he's just so sparkly. Are they?
Is He have a grill on? Can you tell?
It looks like he's got some kind of ice
step grill. Am I imagining that again?
Tell Joe Rogan what his name is. Rocco
rakochy. He's got a wild name too.
That is hilarious. The
whole thing is so funny.
Okay.
I hope the cops, okay. Rocky money.
That's his name. His name is rocky money.
I told you it off.
Yeah. Rocky money booed
off. Damn. Cops done lit up.
Rocky morning money. Rudolph Julia
to boot. Oh, that's hilarious.
The best name I've seen
in 14 years on the job.
Yeah, that's about as good as
the name. Rocky money. Rudolph.
That poor cow went to work yesterday
with a positive attitude and it gets
fucking drag.
They say smoking a black and mild
in the cops. Like I smell weed news.
I don't have weed. I don't have
marijuana. So was it just the cigar?
That's what he says. He said
it's just a black and mild.
It's a very distinct smell between
a black and mild and marijuana.
Well maybe if you're some
goofy cop and busy and low. No,
but I think it's marijuana. Pull them out
of there. What do you think it smells?
What does, what does a black and mild
smell like? Is that what it's called?
Black and mild. What does
it smell actually wrong
compared to smoking, but yeah,
it's a very strange, the distinct smell.
You can tell it between any cigar and
a black and mind. You can pick it out.
See, I don't know that. What if I
had become a cop and I smelled that?
Would I have to know what a
black and mild smells like?
He might've thought it was drugs. I was
like, weed. What does it smell like?
Thick cigarettes. Tobacco. A smoke?
Yeah. It doesn't smell anything.
Like weed smells. Great
pipes. I got a nice, it's close. Yeah.
Isn't it interesting that like the
smell of tobacco from cigarettes?
It's Kinda gross smell from a cigar.
Not that bad smell from a pipe.
A lot of people like that smell like
a lot of people like, like kids,
like the smell of pipes smells like
some tobacco burning in a pipe actually
smells good. Weird. I
like the smell of weed.
Fuck all this shit. That pipe
that bag in it. Yeah. Those,
the older guys used to that
smoke around them much. I know.
If it was nothing may not makes a real,
but what I'm saying [inaudible] drug.
When I was younger,
when I was in my teens,
it felt like people were smoking
more pipes at all the schools.
A t there was a teacher in my
grandma's schools smoked a pipe.
I still remember a teacher from my
high school vividly smoking a pipe.
I haven't seen anybody smoke with pipe.
And Steven Crowder gave
me one that's right here.
I smoked him when he
was on the show. Yeah,
but he gave it to you for refill
for brought tobacco and everything.
It's not bad. It's kind of a pain in the
ass. You got to keep it lit. You know,
it's not something that just
stays lit like a joint, you know,
you gotta Kinda keep, it wouldn't
make you feel like it's like tobacco,
you don't, it gives you that little high.
It's a nice little buzz like cigars.
I think of the best version of that cause
the cigar stays lip and you're getting
it from the leaf to like
cause like your tobacco,
your saliva or rather as
breaking down the tobacco.
Obviously I'm not a scientist,
but your saliva is doing something to
the tobacco of the leaf and it may, okay.
These little kids smoke
cigarettes. He's got a pipe. This little
kid's got a pipe. Is that a, yeah,
I was just
looking for kids. There's the one
on the left. Have a cigarette. Yeah,
he's got a cigarette. That's,
this one's probably fake,
but I know it's got a pipe that in the
50s and forties look at that kid smoking
cigarettes in the lower right hand
corner. Yeah. Kids are smoking shit. Yeah.
Wow. Look at that. All the
kids selling newspapers,
they were all fucking addicted to
cigarettes. Wow. Hey, do me a favor.
Send me that picture. I want
to try to get that picture.
Printing it for the studio. That's
like little rascals and shit. Yeah.
Wow. Yeah. Save. Save that picture.
See if we can buy a copy of that. That
was a kid and when they were growing up,
north Bergen is named is Olson Family
Olson that it'd be like telling them like
Jimmy Olsen live next to a body shop
by 13 he had already been
smoking like fucking eight years.
I swear to God he had cavities,
so he would just put the cigarette in
the tooth gap and just leave it there.
I'll talk to you with the cigarette
in the cavity. His teeth are green.
He's on Facebook now
and say, I thought, Ooh,
from time to time and
shit that way by them,
but that's how bad in the 70s and
sixties I think the 50s kids were fucking
smoking. Look at that Ad.
Give your throat to vacation,
smoke a fresh cigarette,
camels, Shit. It's a doctor,
a doctors telling you to
give your throat a vacation.
Chesterfield cigarettes are just
as pure as the water you drink.
Wow. People were evil back then.
They just lied down on that one.
The more doctors smoke camels when
it say than any other cigarette.
Well, of course I smoked camels.
I like to relax as much as anyone.
Your t zone will tell you
t for tastes t for throat
brought out from the inside. We the
first time you smoked a cigarette?
Probably 14 or 15 what happened to
you? I thought it was disgusting.
I thought I was about like nine. I
thought it was a fucking horrible.
I got dizzy and other than
turn the cigarette out,
I almost put the bathroom on fire.
My mother found that no good.
The next time I smoked one
again was many years later. Um,
Adam Ferrara used to smoke and he gave
me some of his cigarettes cause we were,
we were doing some sketch, I don't
remember exactly what it was about,
but I was supposed to be smoking
a cigarette and the sketch,
I was supposed to be like some
annoying poet smoking a cigarette.
So I kept smoking a cigarette while
we're practicing this thing and I'm just
blasted out of my mind.
Three or four cigarettes in,
we just smoke back to back to back and
you don't smoke. Oh my God, the nicotine.
I was like this is crazy. This is what
you're doing all the time. I was like,
you getting high all the time like this.
A fact science advances new data that
may completely change your idea of
cigarettes.
The experiences of camel smokers confirmed
camels can literally relieve fatigue
and irritability. That doesn't
naturally too. It says it's all good.
Does it naturally? Yeah,
man. People just get sick.
Crazy.
Millions and millions of
people got sick from smoking.
Just
taken it a big drag of chemicals
mixed with tobacco. I didn't,
they probably didn't mix the
chemicals with them back then.
Back then it was probably
just actual tobacco. These,
all of these ads are really good
smoke after you strenuous exercise.
Smoke after strenuous exercise. That's
hilarious. Asthmatic cigarettes.
Imagine you've got asthma. Someone
gives you a pack of cools here.
This'll help you. Hey, what you need,
what you need is camel. No filters.
How about a lucky strike?
Hilarious. How crazy is this?
How crazy would it be if
you took one of these ads?
Like if you knew your grandfather died
of cancer and you took one of these eyes
and fucking took it to the cigarette
companies. Got some bad ass attorneys.
I said, you know what, man, look at
what you guys were putting out in
the fifties and sixties doctors favorite
cigarette is Campbell cigarettes.
Are you fucking crazy?
If I think about the ad,
think about how outrageous with what
we know today that added outrageous.
It's fucking outrageous ranges. So evil,
my doctor's favorite cigarette.
Cause they're telling you
doctors and not saying like, no,
they did not say like my
accountant's favorite cigarette.
They're not saying my my police
officer's favorite cigarettes.
They're saying doctors to let you know
it's going to be okay because they know
it's not going to be okay and you
know it's not going to be okay.
You don't know. You don't
know. You really don't know.
I know you really don't know.
You went to the movies, you tote,
you're 10 years old, your
father gave you a nickel,
you went to the movies and Marlon Brando
was smoking a cigarette in the wild one
and all of a sudden you go home and you're
like, and you tell your friend, wow,
that looks so cool and your friend
goes, smoking is bad for you.
And you're like, no,
I just saw an article.
Four out of five doctors surveyed smoked
camel fucking cigarettes and they look
today. The actually, it's not bad for you.
It can literally remove
irritability, nose, throat,
and accessory organs not
adversely affected by smoking.
Chesterfields they did a six month study
and they said nothing was first such
report ever published
about any cigarette. Oh,
so it's chesterfields you
just get them and you're okay.
Imagine if there was one cigarette.
I just had it nailed dog.
I used to date a girl that
worked at a crazy house.
Like when people go on that crazy
[inaudible] that she used to print it out.
I was a broke comic. She used
to bring me home cigarettes.
I would smoke those cigarettes
and go off the reservation. Oh.
Like they will like low end cigarettes.
You guys see this shit
they put in there. I mean,
I could tell a visible
difference from what I smoked.
A camel or a Marlboro light. Did
you ever smoke sherm? What's charm?
Sherm. You don't chairman's?
No. Sharon was a,
something they were doing where
certain cigarettes they would dip in.
Formaldehyde. I smoked
weed with formaldehyde.
What's that like? Tremendous.
Just fucking traumatic.
But I was into that shit at that time
that Sherman supposedly turns people into
a Zombie. You take the joint, you'd
dip pad the formaldehyde or coat it.
My friend would coat it, let it
dry with it, get hard. So crazy.
You smoke that shit and it
be it. It'd be 10 hours.
Jamie, this says that it was, if
it, when people were doing it,
they would say it was embalming fluid
because it would make you turn into a
Zombie, but it was really just PCP.
Whew.
Really? They would call
it embalming fluid.
That's what the like urban
dictionary and some things,
and I'm looking up now calling
like what? What it actually was,
but did you look up sherm? Yeah, yeah,
yeah. That's fine. That's what it says.
So it's a, it's a hoax. I
don't know that it's up.
I'm sure some idiots probably did find
some formaldehyde or and bombing Flynn
dip it in. But well, after all
the bad press that PCP got,
I could imagine that people would
eventually be like, all right, listen the,
we've got to stop smoking PCP.
So they had to sneak it in things
he had a good PCP experience and
other things. I had 50 good ones,
good PCP experiences. But
guys, to be honest, you,
I didn't know I was doing PCP. Oh,
they called it THC crystal THC
crystals. That's what it was called.
THC Crystal. How do you know it was PCP?
Because years later I found that
the crystal didn't fucking exist.
Well, THC crystals is like
the crystals off of weeks.
So what they tell you at that time,
you asked the dealer like
where'd you get this from?
Word on the street was you took stems,
you threw them in an in a pot with boiling
water. And when it comes to a head,
the stuff that stays to the edge,
you scrape that off and you put it into
a powder form and that's what you snot,
that was the word on the street.
But what it really was was PC fucking
pee. It was animal tranquilizer.
Oh, so they were just saying that so
they could sell it so they could sell it.
And then when you go into
New York City in the 80s,
when you went to the weed spots,
yeah, they sold two types of weed,
but they all felt called a thing. So
the thing called trays, trays, trays,
that's a $3 bag. So when you
paid, they would sell you an uh,
a $10 bag. A sense to me. You
got five joints or something,
then they would have like a
special $20 from Buddha, Tai,
and you would get three joints, two
and a half joints, tight joints.
And then for the tray you get a tight
joint in is white powder that look like a
line of coke when you put it on the table.
So what you did was you rolled your
joint and you took that white line.
You sprinkled in the joint.
You smoked it. Bye Bye Irene.
Bye Bye Irene. And they always
gave it a weird name, like
a Jim Jones. Oh Gee. The time after
he drunk. You know what I'm saying?
After kill those people. So they would
give it, we had weird names. Jim Jones.
How crazy was that? Suicide. They
would give it to all these weird names.
Jimmy Jones named the town Jonestown
cause he know that's when the cops moving.
When you name a town after
yourself, like what are you doing?
I'm just running Vernon Ville and
not just the town but in Ghana. Yeah.
And made people sell everything and move
that. That's just a horrific fucking,
you know, he's been the guy and
a bunch of times, Steve Rinella.
You know who he is? That
guy from that? Yeah,
he's been on my podcast to
from the show mediator. Yeah.
He's a recorded a bunch
of episodes in Guyana,
living with the people that live in the
jungle. Fascinating Shit. Fascinating.
Watching all those people live and he's
interacting with them and hanging out
with them, both fishing with
them and shit. Just wild man.
They found pictographs on
a rock that's on a river.
They have no idea who made them knowing
that how old they are just sitting there
just probably a thousand years old.
They don't know what they mean to some
people from an ancient time ago in Ghana,
I wrote the Shit on a rock and
you can still see it today.
I want to see what that fucking
place looks like that Jim Jones had.
Now they just did a whatever, but no,
it's just a jungle that at
just grew up. Just rolled over.
They went back and they
read, dug up the old stage.
He had a landing strip too, right?
Yeah. That's where he shot that dog.
I still remember being a little kid and
I'm showing, uh, the guy getting shot.
The federal agent at camera falling? No.
The governor or the senator they showed,
they always showed this shot
of the camera going down there.
The reporters are about to get on the
plane and then a truck pulled up and guys
just opened fire on them. I think I
found with the camera rolling. Wow.
The lady still alive. The
senator, the woman did.
She got shot, woman got shot. The
congressman, whoever the congressman,
the son of the love of God,
he died but her assistant lived and
somebody else left and they just got
interviewed. It was either
the anniversary or some shit.
I hate all that shit. I can't see the
people he took down there. He just,
I don't know, culture dangerous.
It's very dangerous when one person
wants to be the only one to talk and tell
you what to do and make
the rules and be special.
When you got that one person that gathers
a group of people and has all those
people listened to him without question
and tries to say that he has the answers
for whatever reason that's appealing
to people. It's very weird,
but people fall into that trap
over and over and over again.
When you have a strong confident man who
is telling you what you know and then
you see them giving into the
power and for whatever reason,
it makes it even more attractive to
a certain segment of the population.
When you see someone reveling in the
power of being a cult leader, like a,
I guarantee you, when that guy in Waco,
what the fuck was his name, correct,
correct. David Koresh.
I guarantee you when,
when he was on the news and talking
about how they'll never give up.
I kid girls, we're probably beaten down
his door trying to get in that cult.
The crazier and the nuttier and the,
the more more apocalyptic your message,
the more people that want to join.
It's weird and they, they, they,
they're just, they just don't
have the ability to discern, oh,
this is not a good idea. This guy really
doesn't have his head on straight.
This guy might be
fucking completely crazy.
They've always realized those
things. That fuck fest anyway. Oh,
I got a 10 that guy slinging deck.
He's arrested that crushed
bang everybody's wife.
Yeah. You got it. Yeah. Yup.
The friend. I had a friend who grew up
in a coat and the stories real, oh yeah,
horrific. I know the friend. I know what
you're talking about. Yeah. Horrific.
You know, so you look at this shit and
you're like, I don't fucking dangerous.
And anytime someone is running any kind
of thing where they got to separate you
from everybody else come to us,
we're going to get you away from all
those people. It never goes well.
It fucking never goes
well. It never goes well.
They want control, they want
control and control of you.
And the best way to do that is get you
away from all these other pesky people
with all their questions.
They don't know. But we know,
we know what's really going on. We
know what this is really all about.
Next thing you know
you're going to call it,
how many cults are going on right now
that we don't know about is like a gang of
them that are just like
bubbling under the surface.
That one they found out about last
year. Right, and I was a Sexual York.
That's a real, they throw them
motherfuckers in jail over that one. Yeah.
That next one, one is a weird one,
right? Because I was like, motherfucker,
actors and actors and actresses,
which does a sex caught, right?
They're all sex calls. Then she
stopped saying sex calls. Right.
Is there a no sex cult? No sex calls. It
just, it's like Buddhist, like they go,
okay, you got six, whatever
you got. Just think about that.
A Guy who tells you he's God,
go blah blah, blah. Okay.
Wife,
crazy girl away in the middle of night
as she comes back the next day smelling
like cocking God knows what
else and you have to store,
respect the guy and call him
God. Yeah, they do. Yeah.
They such a sick, sick, fucking mind.
It sick and you have to be in such
a weak state as a human being.
They're really buying into that.
You can't call them, you know,
you can't call him. They
just fucked up. We had state,
maybe they had avoided
them live somewhere.
This is the way by filling
it and just, I don't see it.
I can never join a Co.
Well there's a bunch of different things
could have gone with the leader and you
got to give me your money. You got to
do all, you got to sell your house.
All those people that went to Jonestown
and sell their home whenever they add
and give them money to, hey, did you see
why? Wild country, wild, wild country.
Now, what is it? It's a
Netflix documentary about the
Pacific Northwest Colts
rock niche guy. The guy that
eventually went on to um,
he found this, this crazy cult. They
went on to buy this town up there.
I heard about it. It's
fucking amazing. I did listen.
We live around so much stupidity. Why
watching one sit down. Watch it on TV.
It's really good though. The documentary
is incredible. It's so well done.
And this Sheila lady who is running
things, she's poisoning people and shit.
It's crazy. They, they poison people.
She did all kinds of crazy stuff.
It was a, it's wild.
They shipped homeless people in to
vote so they could take over the town.
They just brought homeless people in
from everywhere. You just picked him up,
come in the homeless people like Yay.
We found a home and some of them were
like really into it and then they're like,
all right, we're done with
you. Get the fuck Outta here.
Kicked him out after
he took over the home.
Everyone in the town that lived there
before them was fucking hated them. They,
they, they, they had their
own police force armed guards.
I mean guys armed to the Dick. Okay.
Just carrying machine guns and shit.
Fuck. How the fuck is a
tool clock? Cause we uh,
that's what always happens with us.
[inaudible] how the fuck I told it was
like one o'clock and that'd be 1230 till
we, we have fun. I've known this
is crazy. I'm dealing you for,
I've known you for 23
years, man. Maybe more 22.
When did you get there? What
year? 97 was it? 97 yeah. Yeah.
22 years. It's a long time geography.
I used to go to the store and see
what we are walking around the round.
How long we've been there for.
Every time I go down there,
I got a fucking anxiety attack.
Really? Yeah. I get anxiety.
I can't believe I'm still there. It's
still so fun. I got up, I got a home.
Sometimes I just sit back by the
ice cube machine and look and go.
How lucky am I? I got a
fucking home. I got a buggy.
I know you do. I got up. Let's wrap
this pitch at a boogie add. Fucking pee.
All right. Oh man, both. Uh, I
love to see you. Love you too.
Happy for the July. They, everybody.
Charlotte next week. You dirty bitches.
I'm excited.
Thank you to everybody that came in
Atlantic city and Brando to Columbus.
We didn't talk about Baltimore.
The both got all the food in Baltimore
in Borgata or John Rollo. Yeah.
Shout out to John Rollo. Uh, alright.
Fuck. I love you guys. Love you. Bye.
[inaudible].