Four,
three,
two,
one.
Hello,
lex.
Hey,
we're here man.
What's going on?
We're here.
Thanks for doing this.
You brought notes.
You're seriously prepared when you're
jumping out of a plane is best to bring
a parachute.
This is my parachute.
I,
I understand.
Yeah.
Um,
how long have you been working in
artificial intelligence?
My whole life I think really?
So when I was a kid
I wanted to become a psychiatrist.
I wanted to understand the human mind.
I think the human mind is the most
beautiful mystery that our entire
civilization is taken on exploring
through science.
I think you look up at the stars and the
universe out there,
you know,
the grass Tyson here.
It's an amazing,
beautiful scientific journey that we're
taking on and exploring the stars.
But the mind to me is a bigger mystery,
more fascinating and it's been the thing
I've been fascinated by from the very
beginning of my life.
And just I think all of human
civilization has been wondering,
you know,
what is in this inside this thing,
the hundred trillion connections,
they're just firing all the time.
Somehow making the magic happen to where
you and I can look at each other,
make words all the fear or love life
death that happens is all because of
this thing in here and understanding why
is fascinating and what I early on
understood is that one of the best ways
for me at least to understand the human
mind is to try to build it and that's
what artificial intelligence is.
You know,
it's,
it's not enough to sort of from a
psychology perspective,
to study from a psychiatry perspective,
to investigate from the outside.
The best way to understand is to do
so.
You meet almost like reverse engineering
of brain.
There
is some stuff.
Exactly.
Reverse engineering the brain.
There's some stuff that you can't
understand until you tried to do it.
You can hypothesize you're.
I mean we're both martial artists from
various directions.
You can hypothesize about what is the
best martial art,
but until you get in the ring like what
the UFC did and test ideas is when you
first realize that the touch of death
that I've seen some youtube videos on,
that you perhaps cannot kill a person
with a single touch or your mind or
telepathy,
that there are certain things that work,
wrestling works,
punching works,
okay,
can we make it better?
Can we create something like a touch of
death?
Can we figure out how to turn the hips,
how to deliver a punch in the way that
does do a significant amount of damage,
and then you at that moment when you
start to try to do it and you face some
of the people that are trying to do the
same thing,
that's the scientific process and you
try,
you actually begin to understand what is
intelligence and you begin to also
understand how little we understand.
It's like a Richard Fineman who I'm
dressed after today.
Are you?
Here's a physicist.
I'm not sure if you're sure.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
He always used to wear this exact thing,
so I feel.
I feel pretty bad ass wearing it.
If you think you know astrophysics,
you don't know astrophysics.
That's right.
Well,
he said it about quantum physics.
Quantum physics.
That's right.
Uh,
so he was a quantum physicist and he
kind of,
I remember hear him talk about that
understanding the nature of the universe
of reality could be like an onion,
we don't know,
but it could be like an onion to where
you think,
you know,
you're studying a layer of an onion and
you peel it away and there's more and
you keep doing it.
And there's an infinite number of layers
with intelligence.
There's the same kind of component to
what we think we know.
We got it.
We figured out,
we figured out how to beat the human
world champion in chess,
we solved intelligence and then we tried
the next thing.
Wait a minute,
go is really difficult to solve as a
game.
And then you say,
okay,
I've,
I came up when the game of go was
impossible for artificial intelligence
systems to be and have now recently had
been beaten within the last like five
years.
Right?
And the last five years,
there's a lot of technical fascinating
things of why that victory is
interesting and important for artificial
intelligence.
It requires creativity,
correct?
It does not.
It just exhibits creativity.
So the technical aspects of why Alphago
from Google deepmind,
that,
that was the designers and the builders
of the system.
That was the victor.
They did a few very interesting
technical things where essentially you
develop a neural network.
This is this type of artificial
intelligence system that looks at a
board of go as a lot of elements on it
is black and white pieces and is able to
tell you how good is this situation and
how can I make it better?
And that idea.
So chess players can do this.
I'm not actually definitely with the
game of go second speak.
I'm Russian,
so chest to us as romanticized.
It's the beautiful game.
Uh,
I think that there you look at a board
and all your previous experiences,
all the things you've developed over
tens of years of practice and thinking
you get this instinct of what is the
right path to follow.
And that's exactly what the neural
network is doing and some of the in
some of the paths it has come up with
are surprising to other world champions.
So in that sense it says,
well,
this thing's exhibiting creativity
because it's coming up with solutions
that are something that's outside the
box.
Thinking from the perspective of the
human,
when why,
what do you differentiate between
requires creativity and exhibits
creativity?
I think one because we don't really
understand what creativity is and so
it's almost.
It's on the level of concepts such as
consciousness.
For example,
the question which there's a lot of
thinking about whether creating
something intelligent requires
consciousness requires for us to be
actual living beings aware of our own
existence in the same way.
Does doing something like building an
autonomous vehicle,
that's the area where I work in.
Does that require creativity?
Does that even require something like
consciousness and self awareness?
I mean,
I'm sure in La there's some degree of
creativity required to navigate traffic
and in that sense you start to think,
are there solutions that are outside of
the box and ai system you use to create
it?
It's once you start to build it,
you realize that to us humans,
certain things appear at creative,
certain things,
dope,
certain things we take for granted,
certain things we find beautiful and
certain things were like,
yeah,
that's.
Well,
there's creativity in different levels,
right?
These creativity like to write the stand
with Stephen King novel that requires
creativity.
There's something about his.
He's creating these stories.
He's giving voices to these characters.
He's developing these scenarios and
these dramatic sequences in the book
that's going to get you really sucked
in.
That's,
that's almost undeniable creativity,
right?
It.
So it's a.
he's imagining a world.
What is it always set in a New
Hampshire,
Massachusetts,
Maine,
Maine.
Right?
So he's imagining a world and imagine
the emotion of different levels
surrounding that world.
Yeah,
that's,
that's creative.
Although if you.
There's a few really good books,
including his own that talks about
writing a.
yeah,
he's got a great book on writing and
it's actually called on writing.
If there's anyone who can write a book
on writing.
Stephen King,
I think Steven Pressfield,
I hope I'm not saying the war of art and
the Lore of art,
beautiful book,
and I would say if from my recollection
they don't necessarily talk about
creativity very much,
that it's really hard work of putting in
the hours of every day of just grinding
it out.
Well,
pressfield talks about the muse.
Pressfield speaks of it almost in like a
strange,
mystical,
mystical sort of connection to the
unknown because he,
he almost,
I'm not even exactly sure if he believes
in the muse,
but he,
he,
I think if I could put words in his
mouth,
I have met him.
He's a great guy.
He was on the podcast once.
I think the way he treats it as if you
decide the muse is real and you show up
every day and you write as if the Muse
is real.
You get the benefits of the muse being
real.
That's right.
Whether or not there's actually a muse
that's giving you these wonderful ideas
and what is the muse?
So I think of artificial intelligence
the same way.
There's a quote by a Pamela,
a mccormick from 1979 book that I really
like.
Uh,
she talks about the history of
artificial intelligence.
Ai began with an ancient wish to forge
the gods.
And to me,
God's broadly speaking or religions
represents.
It's kind of like the muse.
It represents the limits of possibility,
the limits of our imagination.
So it's this thing that we don't quite
understand.
That is the muse,
that is God that's us,
US chimps are very narrow in our ability
to perceive and understand the world.
And there's clearly a much bigger,
beautiful,
mysterious world out there and God or
the Muse represents that world.
And for many people,
I think throughout history and
especially in in the past set of 100
years,
artificial intelligence has become to
represent that a little bit to the thing
which we don't understand.
And we crave for both terrified.
And we crave and creating this thing
that is greater,
that is able to understand the world
better than us.
And that in that sense,
artificial intelligence is the desire to
create the muse.
This other,
this imaginary thing.
And I think the,
one of the beautiful things,
if you talk about everybody from
Yamashta,
Sam Harris,
to all the people thinking about this,
is that there is a mix of fear of that,
of,
of that unknown,
of creating that unknown and an
excitement for it because there's
something in human nature that desires
creating that.
Because like I said,
creating is how you understand.
Hm.
Did you initially study biology?
Did you study the actual development of
the mind or what?
What is known about the evolution of the
human mind
of the human mind yet?
So my path is different as it's the same
for a lot of computer scientists and
roboticists is we ignore biology,
neuroscience,
the physiology,
anatomy of our own bodies,
and there's a lot of beliefs now that
you should really study biology and
she's studying neuroscience.
You should study your own brain,
the actual chemistry.
What's happening?
What is actually how are the neurons are
interconnected?
All the different kinds of systems in
there.
So
that is a little bit of a blind spot or
it's a big blind spot,
but the problem is.
So I started with more philosophy
almost,
it's where,
um,
if you think Sam Harris has last couple
of years,
it started kind of thinking about
artificial intelligence and he,
he has a back on your science,
but he's also a philosopher and I
started there by reading Camu and neat.
You are dusty yefsky thinking what is,
what is intelligence,
what is human morality,
a will.
So all of these concepts give you the
context for which you can then start
studying these problems.
And then I said there's a,
there's a magic that happens when you
build a robot that drives around.
I mean,
your father.
I'd like to be,
but I'm not yet.
Uh,
there's a creation aspect.
That's wonderful.
That's incredible.
It's for me,
I don't have any children at the moment,
but the act of creating a robot where
you programmed it and it moves around
and a sense senses the world is,
this is a magical moment.
Did you see Alien Covenant is a Scifi
Movie?
Yeah.
No
VRC near the alien films.
I,
uh,
so I grew up in the Soviet Union where
we didn't watch too many movies.
So I need to catch up,
we should catch up on that one in
particular because a lot of it has to do
with artificial intelligence.
There's actually a battle between,
spoiler alert to different but identical
artificially intelligent synthetic
beings that are there to aid the people
on the ship.
One of them is very creative and one of
them is not.
And the one that is not has to save them
from the one that is.
Spoiler alert,
I don't want to tell you who wins,
right?
There's,
there's a really fascinating scene at
the very beginning of the movie where
the creator of this artificially
intelligent being is discussing its
existence with the being itself and the
beings trying to figure out who made
him.
And it's this really fascinating moment
and this being winds up being a bit of a
problem because it possesses creativity
and it has the ability to think for
itself.
And May,
uh,
they found it to be a problem.
So they made a different version of it
which was not able to create.
And the one that was not able to create
was much more of more of a servant.
And there's this battle between these
two.
I think you would find it quite
fascinating.
It's a really good movie.
Yeah.
The same kind of theme carries through a
mock in 2001 space odyssey.
Sort of.
You've seen X.
Yep.
I've seen it.
So because of your.
I listened to your podcast and because
because of it,
I've watched it a second time because
the first time I watched it and Neil
degrasse Tyson moment where it was,
you said there's cut,
cut the cut the shit got the shit
moments for me.
For me,
the movie
winning is everything.
Everything about it was a,
I was rolling my eyes rolling your eyes.
What was the cut the shit moment.
So that's a general bad tendency that
liked to talk about amongst people who
are scientists that are actually trying
to do stuff that trying to build the
thing and it's,
it's very tempting to roll your eyes and
to now in a lot of aspects of artificial
intelligent discussion.
So on.
For me,
there's real reasons to roll your eyes
and there's just.
Well,
let me,
uh,
let me just describe it.
So this person in Mokena,
no spoiler alerts,
uh,
is in the middle,
what,
like a Jurassic Park type situation.
Whereas like in the middle of a land
that he owns,
yeah,
we don't really know where it is not
established,
but you have to fly over glaciers and
you get to this place and there's a
river is.
And he was fantastic compound.
And inside this company appears to be
working alone.
Right?
And he's like lifting
like he's like,
I'm doing curls,
I think like dumbbells and a drinking
heavily.
So the,
everything I know about science,
everything I know about engineering is
it doesn't happen alone.
So the situation of a compound with no
hundreds of engineers they're working on
this is not feasible.
It's not feasible,
it's not possible.
And the other moments like that were the
technical,
the discussion about how it's
technically done.
They,
they threw a few jargon despite stuff up
and it makes,
it doesn't make any sense.
Well that's where I am blissfully
ignorant.
So I watched it,
I go,
this movie's awesome.
And you're like,
ah,
I know too much.
Not too much,
but that's,
that's a stupid way to think for me.
Uh,
so once you suspend disbelief,
say okay,
well,
right.
Those are,
those are not important details.
Yeah,
but it is important.
I mean they could have gone to you or
someone who really has knowledge in it
and cleaned up those small aspects and
still kept the,
the theme of the story.
That's right.
They could have,
but they would make a different movie.
So that's slightly different.
I don't know if it's possible to make.
So you look at 2001 space odyssey.
I don't know if you've seen that movie
with it.
That's the kind of movie you will start
if you've talked to scientists that
you'll start making those kinds of
movies because
you can't actually use jargon that makes
sense because we don't know how to build
a lot of these systems.
So the way you need to film it and talk
about it is with mystery.
Is this hedgehog type
like you almost,
you say very little.
Yeah.
Leave it to your imagination to see what
happens here.
Everything was in the open even in
winter in terms of the actual
construction of the brain that when they
had that foam looking whatever gel
brain,
right?
Yeah.
He said if they gave a little bit more
ms Dot suttle mystery,
I think I would have enjoyed that movie
a lot more.
But the second time really because of
you,
you say,
I think it's your favorite Scifi.
It's absolutely one of my favorite side,
one of my favorite movies,
period.
I loved it.
Yeah.
So I,
I,
I watched it again and also Sam Harris
said that he also hated the movie and
then washed again and liked it.
So I gave it.
I gave it a chance.
Why would you see a movie again after
you hate it?
Uh,
because maybe you're self aware enough
to think there's something unhealthy
about the way I hated the movie.
Like you're like introspective enough to
know.
It's like I have the same experience
with Batman.
Okay.
I watched a which one?
Dark night?
I think it was Christian Bale,
Christian Bale.
And so to me,
the first time I watched that is a guy
in a costume,
like speaking excessively with
excessively low voice.
I mean it was just something with like
little bunny ears,
not bunny ears,
but the ears.
It's so silly.
But then you can go back and okay,
if we just accepted those,
that's the reality of the world we live
in now.
What's the human nature aspects that are
being explored here?
What is the,
the beautiful conflict between good and
evil as being explored here and what are
the awesome graphics effects that are
being on exhibit.
Right?
So if you could just suspend that,
that's beautiful.
The movie can become quite fun to watch,
but still to me,
not to offend anybody,
but a bad superhero.
Movies are difficult.
It's still difficult for me to watch.
Yeah.
Who was talking about that recently?
Was it Kelly?
Kelly slater?
No,
that was yesterday.
Yesterday.
Kyle.
He's kind of a guy.
He doesn't look super hero movies or
something.
He doesn't like superhero movies.
We're talking about Batman,
about Christian Bale's voice.
And he's like,
the most ridiculous thing was that he's
actually Batman.
Not those voice on Batman,
that part of it is way less ridiculous
than the fact that he's Batman is Batman
because anybody could do that voice.
Yeah.
So,
but I contradict.
Um,
I'm,
I'm a hypocrite because game of thrones
or Tolkien's,
Lord of the Rings,
I'm gonna tow.
It's totally believable to me.
Yeah,
of course.
Dragons and.
Well that's a fantasy world,
right?
That's the problem with something like
Batman or even Mokena is that it takes
place in this world.
Whereas they're in middle earth are in a
place that doesn't exist.
And if you.
It's like if you like Avatar,
if you make a movie about a place that
does not exist,
you can have all kinds of crazy shit in
that movie because it's not real.
That's right.
Yeah.
So,
but at the same time,
like star wars,
it's harder for me.
And you're saying star wars is a little
more real because it's,
it's feels feasible.
Like he could have spaceships flying
around.
Right?
What,
what's not feasible about star wars to.
Oh,
I'm not.
I'll leave that one to the other
undergrad size.
He was getting angry about the robot.
That's circular.
Whatever rolls around.
He's like slippery.
Yeah,
like trying to roll around all over the
sand.
It wouldn't work.
It would get no traction.
I was like,
that's true.
But if you had like glass tires and he
tried to drive over sand,
it was smooth.
You'd get nothing.
Yeah.
Is,
he's actually the guy that made me
realize,
you know the movie ghost with Patrick
swayze and it was at this pockets or
somewhere.
He was talking about the fact that.
So this guy could go through the walls.
Right.
It's a beautiful romantic movie that
everybody should watch.
Right.
But he doesn't seem to fall through
chairs when he sits on them,
right?
Say he can walk through walls,
but he can put his hand on the desk.
You can sit like his.
His blood has a magical shield that is
in this reality.
This is a quantum shield that protects
them from falling.
So.
So that's,
you know,
those devices.
Unnecessary movies.
I get it in.
Yeah.
But you got a good point.
He's got a good point to just cut the
shit moments.
They don't have to be there.
You know,
you just have to work them out in
advance,
but the problem is a lot of movie
producers think that they're smarter
than people.
They just decided on,
just put it in there.
The average person is not going to care.
I've had that conversation with movie
producers about martial arts and I was
like,
well,
this is just nonsense.
You can't do that.
Like because I was explaining martial
arts to someone and he was like,
ah,
the average person's not going to care.
I'm like,
oh,
the average person.
Okay,
well you brought me in as a martial arts
expert to talk to you about your movie
and I'm telling you right now.
This is horseshit.
Yeah.
I'm a huge believer,
Steve jobs philosophy where forget the
average person discussion because first
of all,
the average person will care.
A steve jobs designed with really push
the design of the interior of computers
to be beautiful,
not just the exterior.
Even if you never see it,
if you have attention to detail,
to every aspect of the design,
even if it's completely hidden from the
actual user in the end,
somehow that Karma,
whatever it is that like love for
everything you do and that loves seeps
through the product.
And the same.
I think with movies,
if you talk about space,
the 2001 odyssey,
there's
so many details.
I think there's probably these groups of
people that study every detail of that
movie and other,
um,
cooper films,
those little details matter.
Somehow they all come together to show
how deeply passionate you are about
telling the story.
Well,
Kubrick was a perfect example,
right?
Because he would put layer upon layer
upon layer of detail and the films that
people would never even recognize.
Like there's a bunch of correlations
between the Apollo Moon landings and the
shining.
You know,
there's like people have actually
studied it to the point where they think
that it's some sort of a confession that
Kubrick faked the moon landing because
it goes from the little boy having the
rocket ship on his sweater to the,
the number of the number of the room
that things happened.
There's like a bunch of very bizarre
connections in the film that Kubrick and
questionably engineered because he was
just a stupid,
smart man.
I mean,
he was so goddamn smart that he would do
complex mathematics for fun.
No spare time.
Kubrick was a legitimate genius and he
engineered that sort of complexity into
his films where he didn't have cut the
shit moments in his movies.
Not that I can recall.
No,
not even close.
This is very interesting.
I mean,
but that probably speaks to the reality
of Hollywood today that the cut the shit
moments don't affect the bottom line of
how much the movie makes.
Well,
it really depends on them film,
right?
I mean,
the cut the shit moments that Neil
degrasse Tyson found in gravity I didn't
see because I wasn't aware of what the
effects of gravity on a person's hair
would be.
You know,
he saw it and he was like,
this is ridiculous.
And then there were some things like,
why are these space station so close
together?
I just let it slide while the movie was
playing,
but then he went into great detail about
how preposterous it would be.
Those base stations were that close
together.
You get to them so quickly.
That's where the Sandra bullock and good
looking guy and George Clooney.
George Clooney.
Yeah.
Good looking guy.
So that.
Did that pass muster with that movie?
No,
he tore it apart and when he tore it
apart,
people went crazy.
They get so angry at him.
Yeah.
He reads the negative comments.
I actually recently,
because of doing a lot of work with
artificial intelligence and lecturing
about and so on,
have plugged into this community of
folks that are thinking about the future
of artificial intelligence,
artificial general intelligence,
and they are very much out of the box
thinkers to where the kind of messages I
get are our best.
So I let it.
I let them kind of explore those ideas
without sort of engaging to those
discussions.
I think
very complex discussion should be had
with people in person.
That's what I think.
And I think that when you allow
comments,
just random anonymous comments to enter
into your consciousness like you were
taking risks and you may,
you may run into a bunch of really
brilliant ideas that are,
um,
you know,
coming from people that are considerate
of thought these things through or you
might just run into a river of assholes
and it's entirely possible.
And I peeked into my comments today on
twitter.
I was like,
what in the fuck?
I started reading a couple of them,
some just morons and I'm like,
all right,
what about some shit?
I didn't even know what the fuck they
were talking about,
but,
but that's the risk you take when you
dive in.
You're going to get people that are
disproportionately upset.
disproportionately,
you know,
delusional or whatever it is in regards
to your position on something or whether
or not they even understand your
position.
They'll argue something that's an
incorrect interpretation of your
position.
Yeah,
and you've actually,
from what I've heard,
you've actually been to this podcast and
so on,
really good at being open minded and
it's something I try to preach as well.
So in ai discussions when you're talking
about Agi and talking about,
so there's a difference between narrow
ai and general artificial intelligence,
narrow ais,
the kinds of things that are the kind of
tools that are being applied now and
being quite effective.
And then there's general ai which is a
broad categorization of concepts that
are human level or super human level
intelligence.
And when you talk about Agi,
artificial general intelligence,
there's seems to be two camps of people,
ones who are really working deep in it.
Like that's the camp.
I kind of sit in and a lot of those
folks tend to roll their eyes and just
not engage in any discussion of the
future.
The idea is saying it's really hard to
do what we're doing and it's just really
hard to see how this becomes
intelligent.
And then there's another group of people
who say,
yeah,
but you're being very shortsighted that
you may not be able to do much now,
but the exponential,
the hard takeoff overnight,
it can become super intelligent and then
it'll be too late to think about.
Now the problem with those two camps,
as with any camps,
democratic republic,
any camps,
is they don't seem to be,
seem to be talking past each other as
opposed to both have really interesting
ideas.
If you go back to the analogy of a touch
of death,
a of this idea of MMA,
right?
So I'm the,
in this analogy,
I'm going to put myself in the UFC for a
second.
Uh,
in this analogy,
I'm,
you know,
like ranked in the top 20.
I'm working really hard.
My dream is to become a world champion.
I'm training three times a day.
I'm really working,
I'm an engineer,
I'm trying to build my skills up and
then there's other folks that come along
like Steven Seagal and so on that kind
of talk about other of martial arts or
other ideas of how you can do certain
things and I think,
I think Steven Seagal and could isn't
mine beyond to something.
I think we really need to be open
minded,
like a intro to civil.
I think toxicity or somebody talks as
well,
right?
Well,
Anderson Silva thinks Steven Seagal is.
I want to put this in a respectful way.
He understood so it has a wonderful
sense of humor and Anderson Silva is
very playful and he thought it would be
hilarious if people believe that he was
learning all of his martial arts from
statistics to go.
Got It.
He also loves Steven Seagal movies
legitimately so treated him with a great
deal of respect.
He also recognizes that Steven Seagal
actually is a master of Ikea,
though he really does understand the
Quito and was one of the very first
westerners that was teaching in Japan,
speaks fluent Japanese,
was teaching at a Dojo in Japan and is,
you know,
a legitimate master by Quito.
Right.
The problem with that Quito is it's,
it's one of those martial arts that has
merit in a,
in a vacuum.
They,
if you,
if you're in a world where there's no
ncaa wrestlers or know judo players or
no Brazilian Jujitsu,
black belts or no,
a Moitai kickboxers,
there might be something to that Ikea
stuff,
but in the world we're,
all those other martial arts exist and
we've examined all the intricacies of
hand to hand combat.
It falls horribly short.
Let's see.
This is the point I'm trying to make.
You just said that we've investigated
all the intricacies.
You said all the intricacies of hand to
hand combat.
I mean,
you're just speaking,
but you want to open your mind to the
possibility that I kito has,
uh,
some techniques that are effective that
are affected.
Yeah.
When I say all you're,
you're correct.
That's not a correct way of describing
it because there's always new moves that
are being like,
for instance,
I'm in this recent fight between Anthony
Pettis and Tony Ferguson.
Tony Ferguson actually used wing Chung
in a fight.
He,
he trapped one of Anthony Pettis his
hands and hit him with an elbow.
He basically used a technique that you
would use on a wing Chung dummy,
and he did it in an actual world class,
mixed martial arts fight and I remember
watching it.
Wow,
go on this crazy motherfucker actually
pulled that off because that's.
It's a technique that you just rarely
see anybody getting that proficient at
it that,
that fights in mma and Ferguson is
extremely creative and open minded guy
and he figured out a way to make that
work in a world class fight.
So.
And let me then ask you the question
there.
There's these people who still believe
in quite a lot of them that there is
this touch of death.
Right.
Do you.
So do you think it's possible to
discover through this rigorous
scientific process that is mma that
started pretty recently,
do you think,
not the touch of death,
but do you think we can get a 10 x
improvement in the amount of power the
human body can,
can generate in,
in,
and punching?
No,
no,
certainly not.
10 acts.
I think you can get incremental
improvements,
but it's all based entirely on your
frame.
Like if you're a person that has very
small hands and narrow shoulders,
you're kind of screwed.
There's not really a lot of room for
improvement.
You can,
you can certainly get incremental
improvement and your ability to generate
power,
but you'll never be able to generate the
same kind of power as say a guy with a
very big frame like a brock lesnar or
Derrick Lewis or um,
you know,
anyone who has.
There's like classic elements that go
with being able to generate large
amounts of power wide shoulders,
large hands.
There's,
there's a lot of characteristics of the
human frame itself.
Um,
those,
even those people,
there's only so much power you can
generate and we pretty much know how to
do that correctly.
So the way you're talking about as a
martial arts expert now is kind of the
way a lot of the experts in robotics and
ai talk about ai and when the topic of
touch of death is brought up,
now the analogy is not perfect.
I tend to use probably too many
analogies is
we maybe know the human body butter that
we know the possibility of Ai,
I would assume so,
right?
He has the possibility of ai is
basically limitless.
Once ai starts redesigning itself,
it's not obvious that that's true.
Our imagination allows it to be true.
When I,
I'm of two minds,
I am,
I,
I'm,
I'm both,
I can hold both beliefs that are
contradictory in my mind.
One is that idea is really far away,
almost bordering and bs.
And the other is it can be there
overnight and I think you can believe
both of those things.
So,
um,
there's another,
a quote from Barbara wouldn't,
it's a poem I've heard on a,
on a,
on a lecture somewhere that I really
like,
which is,
it's from the champions of the
impossible rather than the slaves at the
possible,
that evolution draws his creative force.
So I see a mosque as a representative of
the champion of the impossible.
I see exponential growth of ai within
the next several decades as the
impossible,
but it's the champions of the impossible
that actually make the impossible
happen.
Why would a
exponential growth of AI impossible?
Because that seems inevitable to me.
So it's not impossible and I'm sort of
using the word impossible.
Meaning magnificent.
The,
yeah,
it feels very difficult.
Very,
very difficult.
We don't even know where to begin brand
yet.
Like the touch of death actually feels.
I would see the touch of death is
horseshit,
but see you're an expert.
Ah,
and they touch you in the chest,
but we don't have the ability in the
body to generate
that kind of energy.
How do you know that?
That's a good question.
Um,
it's never been done.
We understand study notes.
Never Been,
how do you know it's never been done.
There could be someone out there with
magic that I.
That has escaped my grasp.
I know you've studied,
you've talked about with a Graham
Hancock and you've talked about the
history.
Maybe it was in Roman times.
There was that idea was discovered and
then it was lost because weapons and
much more effective ways of,
uh,
of delivering damage.
Now I find myself in a very
uncomfortable position of defending the
concept as a martial artist,
a defining the concept of martial arts.
Did you study a Jujitsu and judo and
wrestling,
wrestling
the hard ones?
Jitsu,
judo and wrestling.
Those are absolute martial arts in my
opinion.
This is what I mean.
Like if you are a guy who just has a
fantastic physique and incredible speed
and ridiculous power,
just you just congergate ridiculous
power.
If you just are just a per,
you know who deontay wilder is?
Yes.
He would champion the world boxer.
He's a fee.
You have,
what's his name?
Tyson fury on tomorrow.
Two undefeated guys,
right?
Yes.
Deontay wilder has fantastic power.
I mean,
he just knocks people flying across the
ring.
He's just,
I think deontay wilder,
if he just came off the street,
if he was 25 years old and no one ever
taught them how to box it all and you
just wrapped his hands up and had him
hit a bag,
he would be able to generate insane
amounts of force.
Now,
if you're a person that really didn't
have much power and you had a box with
deontay wilder and you were both the
same age and you are a person that knew
boxing and you stood in front of
Deontae,
it's entirely possible that deontay
wilder could knock you into another
dimension,
even though he had no experience in
boxing.
If he just held on you and hit you with
a haymaker,
he might be able to put you out.
If you're a person who is,
let's say,
built like you and a guy who exercises
who strong,
and then there's someone who's
identically built like you who's a black
belt in Brazilian Jujitsu and you don't
have any experience in martial arts at
all,
your fucked right?
Yes.
If you're a person who's built like you
who's a,
a guy who exercises and is healthy and
you grapple with the guy who was even
stronger than you and bigger than you,
but he has no experience in Brazilian
Jujitsu,
he's still fucked.
That's the difference.
That's why I think Brazilian Jujitsu and
judo and wrestling and particularly
those are absolutes in that you have
control of the body and once you grab a
hold of a person's body,
there's no lucky triangle chokes in
Jujitsu.
That's right.
Right.
I think,
uh,
I think I would say Jujitsu as the
highest representative of that.
I think in wrestling and judo,
having practiced those,
I've never been quite as humble and as I
have been in Jujitsu.
Yeah.
Especially when I started,
I was power lifting.
I was like,
I was a total meathead and you know,
a 130 pound guy or girl could tap you
easily.
Yeah.
It's confusing.
It's very confusing in wrestling,
you can get pretty far with that.
Had power in judo,
a little bit less so at its highest
levels at if you go to Japan,
for example,
where they,
I mean the whole dream of judo is
effortlessly throw your opponent,
but in,
you know,
if you go to gyms in America and so on,
there is some hard wrestling style
gripping and just beating each other up
pretty intensely where we're not talking
about beautiful tomatoes are these
beautiful throws were talking about some
scrapping some,
uh,
some wrestling style.
Yeah.
No,
I see what you're saying.
Yeah.
Um,
my experience with Jujitsu was very
humbling when I first started out.
I was a,
had a long background in martial arts
and striking and uh,
even wrestled in high school and then I
started taking Jujitsu and a guy who was
my size and I was young at the time and
he was basically close to my age,
just mauled me.
And he wasn't even a black belt.
I think he was a purple belt.
He might've been a blue belt.
I think it was a purple belt.
Um,
and it just destroyed me.
Just did anything he wanted to be choked
me,
arm barred me just and I remember
thinking,
man,
I am so delusional.
I thought I had a chance.
I thought just based on taking a couple
classes and learning what an Armbar is
and then being a strong person who has a
background in martial arts that I would
be able to at least hold him off a
little bit.
No,
and this is a uh,
that's so beautiful that I feel lucky to
have that had that experience of having
my ass kicked.
And Philadelphia is where I came up with
because in science you don't often get
that experience in the space of ideas.
You can't,
uh,
you can't choke each other out.
You can't beat each other up and
science.
And so it's easy to go your whole life.
I have so many people around me telling
me how smart I am a,
there's no way to actually know if I'm
smart or not because I think I'm full of
bs and in the same,
uh,
I in the same round is fighting.
There's no,
it's Hixon Gracie said it means the or
some of the solid rubber or somebody
that the math doesn't lie.
There's this deep honesty in it that was
really grateful.
Almost like wanting to talk about
bullies.
Are you talking about or even just my
fellow academics could benefit
significantly from training a little
bit.
I think so too.
It's a,
it's a beautiful thing to almost,
I think has been talked about in high
school,
sort of requiring it,
thinking about the meantime.
So I think it's a more humbling sport to
be honest than wrestling because you
could in wrestling,
like I said,
get away with some muscle.
It's also what martial arts we're
supposed to be in that a small person
who knows technique can beat a big
person who doesn't know the technique.
That's right.
That's what we've always hoped for.
Right.
When we saw the Bruce Lee movies and
Bruce Lee who was a smaller guy can beat
all these bigger guys just because he
had better technique that is actually
real in Jujitsu and it's one of the only
martial arts where that's a real.
Yeah.
And I,
uh,
I haven't
in Philadelphia.
It started,
we had Steve Maxwell here.
Sure.
That's kind of where the,
that was the spring of Jujitsu in
Philadelphia.
Yeah.
He was one of the very first American
black belts in Jujitsu.
Like way back in the day,
I believe he was a black belt in the
very early nineties when Jujitsu was
really just starting to come to America
and he had Max innercise in
Philadelphia.
It's still there.
And then I trained at a balance which is
a,
a few gracie folks.
Which film?
Inglorious rake,
mcglynn Hays basketball.
Go brothers.
So it,
I mean,
especially Vogel brothers,
these couple of black belts,
they come up together.
Is there.
Well,
they're smaller,
the little guys.
And I think those were the guys that
really humbled me pretty quickly.
Well,
little guys are the best to learn
technique from.
Yeah.
Because they can't rely on strength.
There's a lot of really big,
powerful,
you know,
250 pounds Jujitsu guys who never are
going to develop the sort of subtlety of
technique that some like the Mayo
brothers,
like smaller guys who just,
they've from the very beginning,
they've never had an advantage in weight
and size and so they've never been able
to use anything but perfect technique.
Eddie Bravo is another great example of
that too.
You know,
he,
he competed in the 140 pounds,
145 pound class,
you know,
um,
but to get back to artificial
intelligence.
So the idea is that there's two camps,
there's one camp that thinks that the
exponential increase in technology and
that once artificial intelligence become
sentient,
it could eventually improve upon its own
design and literally become a god in a
short amount of time.
And then there's the other school of
thought that thinks that is far outside
of the realm of what is possible today.
That even the speculation of this
eventually taking place is kind of
ludicrous to imagine.
Right.
Exactly.
And the balance needs to be struck
because I think I'd like to talk about
sort of the short term threats that are
there and it's really important to think
about,
but the longterm threats,
if they come to fruition,
will overpower everything.
Right?
That's really important to think about,
but what happens is if you think too
much about the encroaching doom of
humanity,
there is some aspect to it that is
paralyzing where you almost.
It turns you off from actually thinking
about the these ideas.
There's something so appealing.
It's like a black hole that pulls you in
and if you notice folks at Sam Harrison,
so on spend a large amount of the time
talking about the negative stuff about
something that's far away.
Not to say it's not wrong to talk about
it,
but they spend very little time about
the potential positive impacts in the
near term and also the negative impacts
of the near term.
So let's go over those fairness so that
way the more and more we put decisions
about our lives into the hands of
artificial intelligence systems,
whether you get a loan or a in the
autonomous vehicle context or in terms
of recommending jobs for you on Linkedin
or all of these kinds of things,
the idea of fairness becomes a bias in
these machine learning systems becomes a
really big threat because the way
current,
the way current artificial intelligence
systems function is they train on data.
So there's no way to,
for them to somehow gain a greater
intelligence than our,
than the data we provide them with.
So we provide them with actual data and
so they carry over if we're not careful,
the biases in that data,
the discrimination that's inherent in
our current society is as represented by
the data.
So they'll just carry that forward.
Like also a.
So there's people working in this,
uh,
more so to see,
to show really the negative impacts in
terms of getting a loan or whether to
say whether this particular human being
should be convicted or not of a crime.
Uh,
there's,
there's ideas there that can carry,
you know,
in our criminal system there's
discrimination and if you use data from
that criminal system to then assist the
ciders,
judges,
juries,
lawyers in making this community and
make a decision of what kind of policy
person gets,
they're going to carry that forward.
You mean like racial economic bias is
racial economic?
Yep.
Geographical.
And that's a sort of,
I don't say that exact problem,
but it's,
it's,
you're aware of it because of the tools
we're using it only.
So the two ways that I'd like to talk
about neural networks with the jail do
it.
Okay.
So the current approaches are,
there's been a lot of,
uh,
demonstrated improvements,
exciting new improvements in our
advancements of artificial intelligence.
And those are for the most part have to
do when your networks,
something has been around since the 19
forties has gone to,
to ai winters where everyone was super
hyped and then super bummed and super
hyped again and bombed again.
And now we're in this other hype cycle.
And what you'll know xr is these
collections of interconnected simple
compute units.
They're all similar.
It's kind of like it's inspired by own
brain where have a bunch of little
neurons interconnected and the idea is
these interconnections are really
dominant and random,
but if you feed it with some data,
they'll learn to connect just like
they're doing our brain in a way that
interprets that data.
They formed representations of that data
and can make decisions,
but there's only two ways to train those
neural networks that we have.
Now.
One is we have to provide a large data
set.
If you want that annual now could tell
the difference between a cat and dog.
You have to give it 10,000
images of a cat and $10,000
with a dog.
You need to give those images and who
tells you what a picture of a cat and a
dog is.
It's humans,
so it has to be annotated.
So as teachers of these artificial
intelligence systems,
we have to collect this data.
We have to invest a significant amount
of effort and annotate that data and
then we teach neural networks to make
that prediction.
The what's not obvious there is how poor
of a method there is to achieve any kind
of greater degree of intelligence.
You're just not able to get very far
besides very specific narrow tasks of
cat versus dog or a,
should I give this person a loan or not?
These kinds of simple simple tasks,
I would argue autonomous vehicles that
are actually beyond the scope of that
kind of approach.
And then the other realm of where you
know networks can be trained is if you
can simulate that world.
So if the world is simple enough or it's
conducive to be formalized sufficiently
to where you can simulate it.
So a game of chess is just,
it's rules him a golden rule so you can
simulate it.
They had.
The big exciting thing about Google deep
mind is that there able to beat
the world champion by doing something
called competitive self play a,
which is the two systems play against
each other.
They don't need the human,
they play against each other,
but that only works and that's a
beautiful idea and super powerful and
really interesting and surprising,
but that only works on things like games
and simulation.
So now if I wanted to,
uh,
sorry to be going to analogies of like
USC for example,
if I wanted to train the system to
become the world champion,
uh,
be uh,
what's his name?
Numbering them add up,
right?
I could play the UFC game,
I could create the,
you networks that play,
use competitive self play to play in
that virtual world and they could become
state of the art,
the best fighter ever in that game.
But transferring that to the physical
world,
we don't know how to do that.
We don't know how to teach systems to do
stuff in the real world.
So some of the stuff that freaks you out
often is Boston dynamics robots.
Yeah.
Does every day I go to the instagram
page and just go,
what the fuck are you guys doing?
So,
uh,
nearing our demise.
Mark Graber CEO is a spoke of the class
I taught.
He is a,
he calls himself a bad boy of robotics,
so he's having a little fun with it.
He should definitely stop doing that.
Don't call yourself a bad boy if
anything.
That's true.
How old is he?
Okay.
He's one of the greatest roboticists of
our generation,
so that's wonderful.
How would you call yourself a.
don't call yourself a bad boy,
bro.
Okay,
so you say you're not the bad boy of
MMA?
Definitely not,
but I'm not even the bad man.
Bad Man,
but definitely not a bad boy.
Okay.
That's a little silly.
Yeah.
The those robots are actually
functioning in the physical world.
That's what I'm talking about.
And they are using something called
always I think coined,
I dunno,
seventies or eighties.
The term good old fashioned ai meaning
there is nothing like going on that you
would consider artificial intelligence,
which is usually connected to learning.
So these systems aren't learning.
It's not like you dropped a puppy into
the,
into the world and you kind of stumbled
around and figuring stuff out and learns
and gets better and better and better
and better.
That's the scary part.
That's the imagination that that's what
we imagined is we put something in this
world at first it's like harmless and
falls all over the place and all of a
sudden they figure something out and
like Elon Musk says the travels faster
than whatever.
Then you can only see what the problem
is.
There's no learning component there.
This is just purely there's hydraulics
and electric motors and there is 20 to
30 degrees of freedom and it's doing
hardcoded control algorithms to control
the task of how do you move efficiently
through space.
So this is the task of this work on a
really,
really hard problem is taking a robotic
manipulation,
taking arm,
grabbing a water bottle and lifting it
super hard for the somewhat unsolved to
this point and learning to do that.
We really don't know how to do that
right,
but this is what we're talking about
essentially is the convergence of these
robotic systems with artificial
intelligence systems,
right?
And as artificial intelligence,
intelligence systems evolve and then
this convergence becomes complete.
You're going to have the ability to do
things like the computer that beat
humans at go.
You're going to have creativity,
you're going to have a complex
understanding of language and
expression,
and you're going to have perhaps even
engineered things like emotions like
jealousy and anger.
I mean it's,
it's entirely possible,
but as you were saying,
we're going to have systems that could
potentially be biased the way human
beings are biased towards people of
certain economic groups or certain
geographic groups and you would use that
data that they have to discriminate just
like human beings discriminating.
What if you have all that in an
artificially intelligent robot that has
autonomy and that has the ability to
move.
This is what people are totally
concerned with and terrified of is that
all of these different systems that are
currently in Semite crude states,
they can't pick up a water bottle yet.
They can't really do much other than
they can do back flips,
but they.
You know,
I'm sure you've seen this,
the more recent Boston dynamic ones,
powercore yeah,
I saw that one the other day.
It's good.
They're getting better and better and
better,
and it's.
It's increasing every year.
Every year there's new abilities.
Did you see the Black Mirror episode?
Heavy metal?
Yeah,
and I think about quite a lot because
it's a functionally it has.
We know how to do most aspects of that
right now.
Right now.
When you close.
Yeah,
pretty close.
I mean I.
I don't remember exactly.
There's some kind of pebbles shooting
situation where it like hurts you by
shooting you somehow.
I figured.
Well,
it has bullets,
didn't it?
Bullets.
Yeah.
Is it basically a gun?
It had a knife.
It stuck into one of its arms.
Remember and come the spoiler alert.
It's just an amazing episode of how
terrifying it would be if some
emotionless robot with incredible
abilities is coming after you and wants
to terminate you
and I think about that a lot because I
love that episode because it's
terrifying for some reason,
but when I sit down and actually in the
work we're doing,
think about how we would do that so we
can do the actual movement of the robot.
Well,
we don't know how to do is to have
robots that do the full thing,
which is have some,
have,
have a goal of pursuing humans and
eradicated.
I'm not spoiler alert all over the
place.
Uh,
I think the goal of eradicating human,
so assuming their values are not aligned
somehow,
that's one we don't know how to do that.
And two is the entire process of just
navigating all over the world is really
difficult.
So we know how to go up the stairs.
But to say how to navigate the path you
took from home to the studio today,
how to get through that full path is so
much an unsolved problem.
But is it because you could do,
you could engineer or you could program
it into your tesla.
You can put it into your navigation
system and have it stop at Red Lights
drive for you take turns and it can do
that.
So first of all,
that I would argue is quite far away
from still,
but that's within 10,
20 years.
But what,
how much can it do now?
It can stay inside the lane,
on the highway or on different roads and
it can change lanes,
and what's being pushed now is they're
trying to be able to enter and exit the
highway,
so there's some basic highway driving.
It doesn't stop at traffic lights,
it doesn't stop at stop signs and it
doesn't interact with the complex
irrational human beings,
pedestrians and cyclists,
cars.
That's.
This is the onion I talked about is we
first in 2005,
the Darpa grand challenge.
Dopper organized this challenge in the
desert says,
let's go across the desert.
Let's see if we can build an autonomous
vehicle that goes across the desert.
Two thousand four,
the first one and everybody failed.
We're talking about some of the smartest
people in the world and really tried and
failed and so they did.
Again,
2005.
There's a few.
Stanford one is a really bad ass guy
from Cmu.
Read that.
I think he's like a marine.
He led the team there and they
succeeded.
The fourteens finished Stanford,
one that was in the desert and there was
this feeling that we solved the
autonomous driving,
but that's that onion because you then,
okay,
what's the next step?
We've got a card that travels across the
desert autonomously.
What's the next?
So then 2007.
They did the urban grant challenges,
the urban challenge.
Darpa urban challenge where you drove
around the city a little bit and again,
super hard problem.
People took it on a Cmu one.
That one,
the Stanford second I believe,
and then there was definitely a feeling
like,
yeah,
we now the car drive around the city.
It's definitely solved.
The problem is those cars were traveling
super slow first of all,
and second of all there's no
pedestrians.
There's no.
It wasn't a real city.
It was an artificial.
It's just basically having to stop and
different signs again,
one other layer of the onion and he'd
say,
okay,
when we actually have to put this car in
a city like La,
our,
we're going to make this work because if
there's no cars in the street and no
pedestrians in the street driving around
is still hard but doable and I think
solvable the next five years when you
put pedestrians,
everybody Jaywalks if you put human
beings into,
into this interaction,
it becomes much,
much harder.
Now.
It's not impossible and I think it's
very doable and with completely new
interesting ideas,
including revolutionizing infrastructure
and rethinking a transportation in
general,
it's possible to do the next five,
10 years,
maybe 20,
but it's not easy like everybody says.
And does anybody say it's easy?
Yeah.
This,
uh,
the,
there's a lot of height between
autonomous,
behind the autonomous vehicles.
Elon musk himself and other people have
promised autonomous vehicles that that
timeline is already past.
That has been going on in 2018.
We'll have autonomous vehicles now for
ge
semiautonomous now.
Right?
So I know they do.
They can break for pedestrians.
Like if they see pedestrians are
supposed to break for them and avoid
them,
right?
That's part of the technically no.
Was that an issue with an Uber Car that
hit a pedestrian that was operating
autonomously?
Someone,
a homeless person stepped out off of a
median,
right into traffic and it nailed it.
And then they found out it didn't have
just one of the settings
wasn't in place.
That's all right.
But that wasn't autonomous vehicles
being tested in Arizona.
And uh,
unfortunately there's a fatality.
A person,
a person died at.
Pedestrian was killed.
So what happened there?
That's the,
that's the thing I'm saying is really
hard.
That's full autonomy.
That's technically when the car,
you can remove the steering wheel in the
car to drive itself and take care of
everything.
Everything.
I've seen,
everything we're studying,
we're studying drivers and Tesla
vehicles.
We're building our own vehicles.
It seems that it will be a long way off
before console the fully autonomous
driving problem because of pedestrians
and.
But two things and pedestrians and
cyclists and the edge cases are driving
all this stuff we take for granted.
The same reason we take for granted how
hard it is to walk,
how hard it is to pick up this bottle,
our intuition about what's hard and easy
is really flawed as human beings.
Can I interject what if,
uh,
all cars were autonomous?
That's true.
If we got to a point where every single
car on the highway is operating off of a
similar algorithm or off the same
system,
then things would be far easier,
right?
Because then you have to,
don't,
don't deal with random kinetic
movements.
People just changing lanes,
people looking at their cell phone,
not paying attention to what they're
doing.
All sorts of things that you have to be
wary of right now.
Driving and pedestrians and bicyclists.
Totally.
And that's,
that's in the realm of things I'm
talking about where you think outside
the box and,
and revolutionize our transportation
system that requires government to,
uh,
to play along.
It seems like that's going that way
though,
right?
Do you feel like that one day we're
going to have autonomous driving pretty
much everywhere,
especially on the highway.
It's not going there in terms of,
uh,
it's,
it's very slow moving.
So if government does stuff very slow
moving with infrastructure,
one of the biggest things you can do for
autonomous driving will solve a lot of
problems is to paint lane markings
regularly.
And even that sucks have been extremely
difficult to do for,
for,
for.
Yeah,
for a politician
because right now there's not really the
desire for it.
But to explain to people what you mean
by that.
When the lanes are painted very clearly,
the cameras and the autonomous vehicles
can recognize them and stay inside those
lines much more easily.
Yeah.
There is two ways that car see the
world.
Three different sensors.
The big ones for autonomous vehicles is
lidar,
which is these lasers are being shuttled
over the place and three 60 and they can
give you this point cloud or how far
stuff as a way,
but they don't give you the visual
texture information of this is what
brand water bottle they are.
And cameras give you that information.
So what Tesla is using have eight
cameras,
I think is they perceive the world with,
with,
uh,
with cameras,
and those two things require different
things from the infrastructure.
Those two sensors,
cameras see the world,
the same arc as are humanized,
see the world.
So they need the lane markings,
they need infrastructure to be really
nicely visible,
traffic lights to be visible.
So the same kind of things as humans
like to have is the cameras like to
have.
And landmark is a big one.
The other,
there's a lot of interesting
infrastructure improvements that can
happen.
Like traffic lights or traffic lights
are super dumb right now.
They sense nothing about the world,
about the density of pedestrians,
about the approach and cars.
If,
if,
if traffic lights can communicate with
the car,
which it makes perfect sense,
it's a,
it's right there,
there's no size limitations.
It can have a computer inside of it.
Uh,
you can coordinate different things that
in terms of the same pedestrian kinds of
problem.
Well,
we have sensors now in streets.
So when you pull up to certain lights,
especially at night,
um,
the light will be red,
you pull up an instantaneously turns
green because it recognizes that you've
stepped over or driven over a sensor.
That's right.
So that's a,
that's a step in the right direction,
but that's really sort of crew 20 years,
30 years ago,
technology.
So you want to have something like the
power of a smartphone inside
every traffic light.
It's pretty basic to do,
but there is way outside of my expertise
is how do you get government to do these
kinds of improvements.
So if I'm mistaken,
correct me if I'm mistaken,
but you're,
you're looking at things in terms of
what we can do right now,
right?
And a guy like Elon musk or Sam Harris
is saying,
yeah,
but look at where technology leads us.
If you go back to 1960,
the kind of computers that they use to
do the Apollo mission,
you've got a whole room full of
computers that doesn't have nearly the
same power as the phone that's in your
pocket right now.
Now if you go into the future and
exponentially calculate like what's
going to take place in terms of our
ability to create autonomous vehicles or
ability to create artificial
intelligence and all of these things
going from what we have right now to
what could be in 20 years where we very
well might look at some sort of an
artificial being that can communicate
with you some sort of an x mark and that
type creature.
I mean,
that's,
that's not outside the realm of
possibility at all.
You have to be careful with the at all
part at all.
Uh,
it's our ability to predict the future
is really difficult.
But I agree with you.
It's not outside the realm of
possibility.
Yeah.
And the thing,
there's,
there's a few examples that brought
along just because I enjoy these
predictions.
So the,
the,
of how bad we are predicting stuff from
the engineers.
The very guys and gals like me sitting
before you made some of the worst
predictions in history in terms of both
pessimistic and optimistic.
The Wright brothers,
one of the Wright brothers before they
flew in 19.
Oh,
three predicted two years before that it
will be 50 years.
I confess that in 19.
Oh one.
That's one of the brothers talking.
I said to my brother,
Orville,
that man would not fly for 50 years.
Two years later,
we ourselves were making flights.
This demonstration of my inability as a
prophet gave me such shock that I have
ever since distress them myself and have
refrained from all prediction.
That's one of the Wright brothers,
one of the people working in the past
mystic estimation versus an optimistic
as explanation or A.
Exactly.
And,
and the same with a Albert Einstein for
me,
made these kind of pessimistic
observations,
uh,
for me,
three years before they,
the first critical chain reaction as
part of the,
he led the nuclear development,
the bomb.
He said that it would,
he has 90 percent confidence.
That's impossible three years before.
Okay.
So that's on the pessimistic side.
On the optimistic side,
the history of ai is laden with,
with optimistic predictions.
Uh,
the,
in uh,
19,
65,
one of the seminar
people in ai,
Herbert Simon said machines will be
capable within 20 years of doing any
work command can do.
He also said within 10 years of digital
computer will be the world chess
champion that's in 58 and we didn't do
that until 90 something 90 years and 40
years.
But that's one person.
It's a guy taking a stab in the dark
based on what data and what's he,
what's he based this off of our
imagination.
We have more data points now though,
don't you think in terms of.
No,
not about the future.
That's the thing,
not about the future,
but about what's possible right now.
Right?
And if you look at the past is a really
bad predictor of the future.
If you look at the past,
what we've done,
the immense advancement of technology
has given us in many ways optimism about
what's possible,
but exactly what is possible.
We're not good at.
So I am much more confident that the
world will look very fascinating.
The different in the future,
whether ai will be part of that world is
unclear.
It could be we will all live in a
virtual reality world for or for
example,
one of the things I'm really think about
is to me a s s a really dumb ai on 1
billion smartphones is potentially more
impactful than a superintelligent ai on
one smartphone.
That the,
the,
the fact that everybody now has
smartphones,
this kind of access to information,
the way we communicate the,
the globalization of everything,
the potential impact there of just even
subtle improvements in ai could be.
It could completely change the fabric of
our society in a way where these
discussions about an ex,
that type lady walking around will be
silly because we'll all be either living
on Mars or living in virtual reality or
in this.
There's so many exciting possibilities
and what I believe in is we have to
think about them.
We have to talk about them.
Technology's always the source of
danger,
of risk.
All of the biggest things that
threatened our civilization at the small
and large scale all are connected to
misuse of technology.
We develop and at the same time it's
that very technology that will empower
us and save us.
So there's a Max tegmark brilliant guy,
like three point zero.
I recommend people read his book on
artificial general intelligence.
He talks about the race that there
there's a,
there's a race that can't be stopped.
One is the development of technology and
the other is the development of our
wisdom of how to stop or the how to
control the technology and it's this
kind of race and
our wisdom is now is always one step
behind and then that's why we need to
invest in it and keep sort of,
keep always thinking about new ideas.
So right now we're talking about Ai.
We don't know what it's going to look
like in five years.
We have to keep thinking about.
We have to through simulation,
explore different ideas through
conferences,
have debates come up with different
approaches of how to solve particular
problems.
Like I said,
with bias or how to solve deep fakes
where you fake.
You can make Donald Trump or president
of foreign president Obama saying
anything or you can have facebook
advertisement.
Harvard hypertargeted a advertisements
how we can deal with those situations
and constantly have this race of wisdom
versus,
uh,
the development of technology but not to
sit and think,
well,
look at the,
you know,
look at the development of technology,
imagine what it could do in 50 years and
we're all screwed because that's
important to sort of be nervous about it
in that way,
but it's not conducive to what do we do
about it and the people that know what
to do about it are the people trying to
build this technology,
building this future once
I didn't know what to do about it
because like,
well let's,
let's put it in terms of Elon Musk,
right?
Like Elon Musk is terrified of,
of artificial intelligence because he
thinks by the time it becomes sentient,
it'll be too late.
It'll be smarter than us.
And we'll,
we'll have essentially created our
successors.
Yes.
And let me quote Joe Rogan and say
that's just one guy.
Yeah.
Well Sam Harris thinks the same thing.
Yes.
And there's quite a few people that
think that Sam Harris.
Okay.
I think was one of the smartest people I
know and Ilan mosque intelligence aside
is one of the most impactful people I
know.
He's actually building these cars and in
the narrow ai sense,
if he's built these autopilot system
that we've been studying,
the way that system works is incredible.
It was very surprising to me on many
levels.
It's an incredible demonstration of what
ai can do in a positive way in the
world.
So I don't know,
but I people can disagree.
I'm not sure the functional value of his
fear about the possibility of this.
Correct.
There's functional value in pitting the
brakes before this takes place.
The just just to be a person who's
standing on top of the rocks with a
light to warn the boats.
Hey,
there's a rock here.
Like pay attention to where we're going
because there's perils ahead.
I think that's what he's saying.
That's an.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with saying that and I think there's.
There's plenty of room for people saying
what he saying and people saying what
you're saying.
I,
what would hurt us is if we tried to
silence either voice.
I think what we need in terms of our
understanding of this future is many,
many,
many of these conversations where you're
dealing with the,
the current state of technology versus a
bunch of creative interpretations of
where this could go and have discussions
about where it should go or what could
be the possible pitfalls of any current
or future actions.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with this.
So when you say like what's the benefit
of thinking in a negative way?
Well,
it's to prevent our demise.
So totally I agree on a percent nae
negativity or worry about the
existential threat is really important
to have as part of the conversation,
but there's this level,
there's this line.
It's hard to put into words is it is a
line that you cross when that worry
becomes hyperbole.
Yeah,
and then it.
There's something about the human psyche
where it becomes paralyzing for some
reason.
Right now when I have beers with my
friends than none ai folks,
we actually go,
we crossed that line all day and have
fun with it.
I talked to she get you drunk right now.
Maybe a regret every moment of it.
This I talked to Steve Pinker a
enlightenment.
Now his book kind of highlights that,
that kind of,
um,
that he's totally doesn't find that
appealing because that's crossing all
realms of rationality and reason.
Would you say that appealing?
What do you mean crossing the line into
what will happen in 50 years?
What could have happened?
He doesn't find that appealing.
It doesn't find it appealing because
he's studied and I'm not sure I agree
with him.
Uh,
to the degree that he takes it,
he finds that there's no evidence he
wants there to all our discussions to be
grounded in evidence and data.
And he,
he highlights the fact that there's
something about human psyche that
desires this negativity that it wants.
There's,
there's something undeniable where we
want to create an engineer.
The gods that overpower us and destroy
us.
We want to or we worry about it.
There's stuff we want to that we.
Let me rephrase that.
We want to worry about it.
There's something about the psyche that.
But
because you can't take the genie and put
it back in the bottle.
Yeah.
I mean,
when you say there's no reason to think
this way,
but if you do have cars that are semi
autonomous now and if you do have
computers that can beat human beings who
are world go champions and if you do
have computers,
computers that can be people at chess
and you do have people that are
consistently working on artificial
intelligence and you do Boston dynamics
who are getting these robots to do all
sorts of spectacular physical stunts and
then you think about the possible future
convergence of all these technologies
and then you think about the possibility
of this exponential increase in
technology that allows them to be
sentient like within a decade,
two decades,
three decades.
What?
What more evidence do you need your.
You're seeing all the building blocks of
a potential successor being laid out in
front of you and you're seeing what we
do with every single aspect of
technology.
We constantly and consistently improve
and innovate right?
With everything,
whether it's computers or cars or
anything.
Everything today is better than
everything.
That was 20 years ago,
so if you looked at artificial
intelligence,
which does agree does exist to a certain
extent,
and you,
you look at what it could potentially be
30,
40,
50 years from now,
whatever it is,
why wouldn't you look at all these data
points and say,
hey,
this could go bad.
I mean,
it could go great,
but it could also go bad.
I do not want to be mistaken as the
person who is not the champion or the
impossible.
I agree with you completely.
I think it's impossible.
I don't think it's impossible at all.
I think it's inevitable.
I don't.
I think it is inevitable.
Yes.
It's the Sam Harris argument.
If,
if superintelligence is nothing more
than information processing
[inaudible]
uh,
same as the argument of the simulation
that we're living in a simulation that's
very difficult to argue against the fact
that we're living in a simulation.
The question is when and what the world
would look like.
Right?
So it's like I said,
a race and,
and it's difficult.
You have to balance those two minds.
I agree with you.
Totally.
You and I disagree with my fellow
robotics folks who don't want to think
about it at all.
Of course they don't.
I
don't want to buy new houses.
Think they've got a lot of money
invested in this adventure.
They want to keep the party rolling.
They don't want to pull the brakes.
Everybody pulled the cords out of the
walls.
We've got to stop.
No one's going to do that.
No one's.
No one's going to come along and say,
Hey,
we've.
We've run all this data through a
computer,
and we found that if we just keep going
the way we're going in 30 years from
now,
we will have a successor that will
decide that human beings are outdated
and inefficient and dangerous to the the
actual world that we live in and we're
going to start wiping them out,
but that's not the exists right now.
It doesn't exist right now,
but if that did happen,
if someone did come to the UN and had
this multistage presentation data that
showed that if we continue on the path
we're going,
we have seven years before artificial
intelligence decides to eliminate human
beings based on these data points.
What do you.
What do they do?
What are the Boston Dynamics?
People do?
Well,
I'm building a house in Cambridge.
What are you talking about?
Man?
I'm not going anywhere.
Come on.
I just bought a new tesla.
I need to finance this thing.
Hey,
younger credit card bills.
I got student loans.
I'm still paying off.
Like what?
How do you stop people from doing what
they do for a living?
How do you say that?
Hey,
I know that you would like to look at
the future with rose colored glasses on,
but there's a real potential pitfall
that could be the extermination of the
human species.
Right,
and obviously I'm going way far with
this.
Yeah,
I like it.
I think every one of us trying to build
these systems are similar in sound to
the way you were talking about the touch
of death in that my dream and the dream
of many roboticist is to create
intelligent systems that will improve
our lives and working really hard at it.
Not for our house in Cambridge,
not for a billion dollar,
for selling a startup paycheck.
We love this stuff.
Some of you.
So obviously the motivations are
different for every single human being
that's involved in every endeavor.
So,
and we're trying really hard to build
these systems and is really hard.
So whenever the,
the question is,
well,
this is going to look at it
historically,
it's going to take off.
It can potentially take off any moment.
It's very difficult to really be
cognizant as an engineer about how it
takes off because you're trying to make
it take off in a positive direction and
you're failing.
Everybody is failing.
It's been really hard.
And so you have to acknowledge that
there,
that overnight,
some Ilan Musk type character might come
along and you know,
people with this boring company,
uh,
or with space x,
people didn't think anybody but NASA
could do what he's doing and he's doing
it.
It's hard to think about that too much.
You have to do that.
But the reality is we're trying to
create these super intelligent beings.
Sure,
but isn't the reality also that we have
done things in the past because we were
trying to do it.
And then we realized that these have
horrific consequences for the human race
like Oppenheimer and the Manhattan
project.
You know,
when he said,
I am death destroy one destroyer of
worlds.
When,
when he was quoting the Bhagavad Gita,
when he's detonating the first nuclear
bomb and realizing what he's done,
just because something's possible to do
doesn't necessarily mean it's a good
idea for human beings to do it.
Now we haven't destroyed the world with
Oppenheimer's discovery and through the
work of the Manhattan project,
we've managed to somehow or another keep
the lid on this shit for the last
incredible.
It's crazy,
right?
You know,
I mean for the last,
what,
70 years,
how long has it been?
Seven days.
Sounds right.
$10,000.
$20,000.
Nukes all over the world right now.
It's crazy.
I mean,
we literally could kill everything on
the planet and somehow we would not
somehow,
somehow in some amazing way we have not,
but that doesn't mean we.
I mean this a very short amount of time
in relation to the actual lifespan of
the earth itself and certainly in terms
of the time human history has been
around
and nuclear weapons.
Global warming is another one.
Sure.
But that's a side effect of our actions,
right?
We're talking about a direct effect of
human ingenuity and innovation.
The nuclear bomb,
it's a direct effect.
We tried to make it,
we made it.
There it goes.
Global warming's an accidental
consequence of human civilization,
so you can't.
I don't think it's possible to not build
a nuclear bomb.
You don't think it's possible to not
build it in terms of.
Because people are tribal,
they speak different languages,
they have different desires and needs
and they were add more.
So if all these engineers were working
towards it,
it was not possible to not build it.
Yep.
And the,
like I said,
there's something about us chimps in a
large collective where we,
uh,
are born and push forward towards
progress of technology.
You cannot stop the progress of
technology.
So the goal is to how to develop,
how to guide that development into a
positive direction.
Surely if we do understand that this has
taken place and we did drop these
enormous bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki
and killed untold amounts of innocent
people with these detonations that it's
not necessarily always a good thing to
pursue technology
it.
Nobody is.
So
you see what I'm saying?
I agree with your total.
I'm more playing devil's advocate than
anything,
but what I'm,
what I'm saying is you guys are looking
at these things like we're just trying
to make these things happen and what I
think people like Elon Musk and Sam
Harris and a bunch of others that are
gravely concerned about the potential
for ai are saying is that I understand
what you're doing,
but you've got to understand the other
side of it.
You've got to understand that there are
people out there that are terrified,
that if you do extrapolate,
if you do take this relentless thirst
for innovation and keep going with it,
when you look at what we can do so what
human beings can do so far in our crude
manner of 2018 will all the amazing
things they've been able to accomplish.
It's entirely possible that we might be
creating our successors.
This is not outside the realm of
possibility and all of our biological
limitations might be we,
we might figure out a better way and
this better way might be some sort of an
artificial creature.
Yep.
Ai began with our dream to forge the
gods and that's I would like.
I think that it's impossible to stop.
Well,
it's impossible to stop if you go Ted
Kaczynski and kill all the people.
I mean,
that's what Ted Kaczynski anticipated.
No,
the unibomber,
you know the whole story behind him know
what was he trying to stop who?
He's a fascinating cat.
Here's what's fascinating.
It was a bunch of fascinating things
about him,
but one of the more fascinating things
he was involved in the Harvard lsd
studies,
so they were nuke in that dude's brain
with acid and then he goes to Berkeley,
becomes a professor,
takes all this money from teaching and
just makes a cabin in the woods and
decides to kill people that are involved
in the creation of technology because he
thinks technology is eventually going to
kill off all the people.
So he becomes crazy and schizophrenia
pick and who knows what the fuck is
wrong with them and whether or not this
would have taken place inevitably,
or whether this was a direct result of
his being literally like drowned in Lsd.
We don't even know how much they gave
him or what the experiment entailed or
how many other people's gut,
their brain torched during these uh,
experiments.
But we do know for a fact that Ted
Kaczynski was a part of the Harvard lsd
studies.
And we do know that he went and did move
to the woods and write his manifesto and
start blowing up people that were
involved in technology.
And the basic thesis of his manifesto
that perhaps Lsd,
he opened his eyes to,
is that technology is gonna,
kill all humans.
And so we should.
It was gonna be the end of the human
race,
I think you may believe human race.
So they know what it is that what he
said.
You will get into industrial,
Rachel,
excuse me,
the industrial revolution and its
consequences have been a disaster for
the human race.
Yeah.
He extrapolated.
He was looking at where we're going and
these people that were responsible for
innovation and he was saying they're
doing this with no regard for the
consequences on the human race.
And he thought the way to stop that was
to kill people.
Obviously he's fucking demented,
but this is.
I mean he literally was saying what
we're saying right now.
You keep going,
we're fucked.
So the industrial revolution have to
think about that.
It's a really important message coming
from the wrong guy.
But where is it?
Where's all of this?
Taking us?
Yeah.
Where is it taste?
So I guess my underlying assumption is
the journey,
the current capitalist structure of
society that we always want a new iphone
just had a one of the best reviewers on
yesterday that always talks about
Marcus.
Yeah.
We always myself to pixel three.
I have a pixel to.
I'm thinking,
man,
maybe I needed a pixel three.
I don't know a better camera.
You know that whatever that is,
that fire that wants more butter,
butter.
I just don't think it's possible to
stop.
And the best thing we can do is to
explore ways to guided towards safety
where it helps us.
When you say it's not possible to stop
you mean collectively as an organism,
like the human race,
that it's a tendency that's just built
in.
It's certainly possible stop as an
individual because I know people like my
friend Ari who's given up on
smartphones,
he went to a flip phone and he doesn't
check social media anymore and he found
it to be toxic.
He didn't like it.
He thought it was too addicted to it and
he didn't like where it was leading him.
Yup.
So in front.
On an individual level,
it's possible
individual level,
but then and just like with Ted
Kaczynski and the individual level,
it's possible to do certain things that
tried to stop at a more dramatic ways,
but I just think the force of our.
This symbiotic,
this organism that's just this living,
breathing organism that is our
civilization will progress forward.
We're just curious apes,
it's,
it's this desire to explore the
universe.
Why?
Why do we want to do these things?
Why do we look up and we want to travel
and and it's not.
I don't think it's sort of a.
we're trying to optimize for survival.
In fact,
I don't think most of us would want to
be immortal.
The,
I think it's like Neil degrasse Tyson
talks about the fact that we're mortal.
The fact that one day we'll die is one
of the things that gives life meaning
and sort of trying to worry and trying
to sort of say,
wait a minute,
where's this going?
As opposed to riding the wave and doing,
riding the wave of,
of forward progress.
I mean,
it's one of the things he gets quite a
bit of.
Ironically hate for Steve Pinker,
but he really described in data how our
world is getting better and better with
hate from people that don't want to
admit that there's a trend towards
things getting better because they feel
like then people will ignore all the bad
things that are happening right now and
all the injustices which I think is a
very short sided thing,
but I think it's because of their own,
their own biases and the perspective
that they're trying to establish and
push instead of looking at things,
objectives and looking at the date and
say,
I see where you're going.
It doesn't discount the fact that
there's injustice in the world and crime
and violence and all sorts of terrible
things happen to people that are good
people on a daily basis,
but what he's saying is just look at the
actual trend of civilization and the
human species itself,
and there's an undeniable trend towards
peace.
Slowly but surely working towards peace.
Way Safer today.
Way Safer today than it was a thousand
years ago.
Just it is.
It just did.
Yeah,
and there's these interesting arguments
which his book kind of blew my mind to
this funny joke.
He says,
some people considered given nuclear,
the atom bomb the Nobel Peace Prize
because he believes I'm not an expert in
this at all,
but he believes that sort of or some
people believe that nuclear weapons are
actually responsible for a lot of the
decrease in violence because all of the
major people can do damage.
All the Russia and all the major states.
Could you do damage,
have a strong disincentive from engaging
in warfare.
And so these are the kinds of things you
don't,
I guess,
anticipate and say.
So I think it's,
it's very difficult to stop that for
progress,
but we have to really worry and think
about,
okay,
how do we avoid the list of things that
we worry about?
So one of the things that people really
worry about is the control problem is
basically ai becoming,
not necessarily super intelligent but
super powerful,
but too much of our lives into it.
That's where Elon Musk and others,
they want to provide regulation of some
sort saying,
wait a minute,
you have to put some bars on what this
thing can do from a government
perspective,
from a company perspective,
right?
But how
could you stop rogue states from doing
that?
How could you,
why would you,
why would China listen to us?
Why would Russia listen to us?
Why would other countries that are
capable of doing this and maybe don't
have the same sort of power that the
United States has and they would like to
establish that kind of power.
Why wouldn't they just take the cap off
in philosophical,
high level sense?
There's no reason.
But if you engineered in.
So I'm a big,
we'll do this thing with autonomous
vehicles called arguing machines.
We have multiple AI systems argue
against each other.
So it's,
it's possible that you'll have some ai
systems over supervising other AI
systems.
So have a sort of,
uh,
like,
in our,
in our nation there's a congress
arguing,
blue and red states being represented in
as this discourse going on debate and
have ai systems like that too.
It doesn't even necessarily need to be
one super powerful thing.
It could be ai supervising each other,
so there's this interesting ideas there
too to play with because ultimately what
are these artificial intelligence
systems doing?
We humans place power into their hands
first in order for them to run away with
it.
We need to put power into their hands,
so we'll have to figure out how we put
that power in initially so it doesn't
run away and how supervision can happen.
Right,
but this is
us.
You're talking about rational people.
What about other people?
Why would they engineer limitations into
their artificial intelligence and what
incentive would they have to do that to
somehow another limit their artificial
intelligence to keep it from having as
much power as ours.
There's really not a lot of incentive on
their side,
especially if there's some sort of
competitive advantage for their
artificial intelligence to be more
ruthless,
more sentient,
more autonomous.
I mean it's.
It seems like once again,
once the genie's out of the bottle,
it's going to be very hard.
I have a theory,
and this is a very bizarre theory,
but I've been running with this for
quite a few years now.
I think human beings are some sort of a
caterpillar and I think we're creating a
cocoon and through that cocoon we're
going to give birth to a butterfly and
then we're going to become something and
I think we're whether we're going to
have some sort of a symbiotic connection
to these electronic things where they're
going to replace our.
Our parts are failing parts with far
superior parts until we're not really a
person anymore.
Like what was that scarlet Johannson
movie?
The ghost in the shell.
I tried to watch part of it.
It's pretty stupid,
but she's hot as fuck,
so it kept my attention for a little
bit,
but in that they took her brain and put
it in this artificial body that was like
had super powers and they basically
replaced everything about her.
That wasn't her consciousness with these
artificial parts,
the Gerd,
oliver frame,
everything was just some new thing that
was far superior and she had these
abilities that no human being will ever
have.
I really wonder why we have this
insatiable thirst.
Why can't we,
if we're so logical,
we're so logical and so thoughtful in
some ways.
Why can't we be that way when it comes
to materialism?
Well,
I think one of the reasons why is
because materialism is the main engine
that pushes innovation.
If it wasn't for people's desire to get
the newest,
latest and greatest thing,
what would fund these new tvs?
Cell phones,
computers.
Well,
why do you really need a new laptop
every year?
Is it because of engineered obsolescence
where the laptop dies off and you have
to get a new one because they fucked you
and they built a shitty machine that's
designed to die.
So you buy a new one.
Really like iphone is done.
You.
Well,
it's not even an iphone.
So laptop.
Well,
it is.
It is it because you're,
you know,
you just see the number two point six
Gigahertz is better than two point four.
Oh,
it's the new one.
It has a 12 megapixel webcam instead of
an eight,
and for whatever reason we have this
desire to get those new things.
I think that's what fuels innovation and
in my cynical view of this thing that's
happening is that we have this bizarre
desire to fuel our demise and that we're
doing so by fueling technology,
by,
by motivating these companies to
continually innovate,
know if everybody just said,
you know what,
man,
I'm really in the log cabins and I want
to,
uh,
an ax or cut my own firewood.
And I realized that TV's rot my brain.
I just want to read books so fuck off.
And everybody started doing that and
everybody started living in like,
when it gets dark out,
I'll use candles and you know what?
I'm going to get my water from a well
and you know what I'm going to do.
And I like living better that way.
If people started doing that,
there would be no need for companies to
continually make new computers to make
new phones,
to make new smartwatches or whatever the
fuck they're they're making to make cars
that can drive themselves.
These things that were,
that were really,
really attached to.
If you looked at the human organism,
you're like,
you've somehow or another could
objective really remove yourself from
society and culture and all the things
that make us a person and you look at
what we do,
like what does this thing do?
We found this planet,
there's these little pink monkeys and
brown monkeys and yellow monkeys,
and what do they all into?
Well,
they all seem to be into making stuff
and what kind of stuff were they making?
Well,
they keep making better and better
stuff.
That's more and more capable.
Well,
where's it going?
What's going to replace them?
They're going to make a thing that's
better than them.
They're going to their,
their engineering.
These things.
Slowly but surely to do all the things
they do,
but do them better.
Yeah,
and it's a fascinating theory.
I mean it's,
it's not a theory.
It's,
it's an instructive way to think about
intelligence in life period.
So if you step back,
look across human history and look at
earth is an organism like what is this
thing doing?
The thing is,
I think at,
at,
in terms of scale and in terms of time,
you can look that way.
It's so many things like isn't there
billions or trillions of organisms on
our skin right now,
both of us that are,
have little civilizations,
right?
They have a different mechanism by which
they operate and interact.
But for us to say that we're intelligent
and those organisms or not is a very
narrow sighted view.
So they are operating under some force
of nature that,
uh,
that the Darwin has worked on trying to
understand some small elements of this
evolutionary theory.
But there's other more interesting
forces at play that we don't understand.
And there's some kind of force.
It could be a fundamental force of
physics that Einstein never got a chance
to discover is our desire for an iphone
update some,
some fundamental force of nature.
Somehow gravity in the strong force in
these things described by physics add up
to this drive for new things,
for creation.
And uh,
the fact that we die,
the,
that the fact that we're mortal.
The fact that what desires a built in to
us,
whether it's a sexual or intellectual or
whatever drives us,
apes like somehow that all combines to
this,
to this progress and towards what it is
a compelling way to think that if an
alien species did visit Earth,
I think they would probably see the
smartphone situation.
They see how many little lights are on
and how us apes are looking at them.
It's possible.
I think some people have said that they
would think the overlords are the
phones,
not the people.
So to think that that's now moving into
a direction where the future will be
something that is beyond human or survey
article.
Human ways we can't understand it is
really interesting.
Not just that,
but something that we're creating
ourselves,
grading ourselves,
and it's a,
a main focal point of our existence.
That's our purpose.
Yeah.
I mean,
if you think about a main focal point,
if you think about the,
uh,
the average person,
what they do,
there's a great percentage of our
population that has jobs where they work
and one of the ways that they placate
themselves doing these things that they
don't really enjoy doing is earning
money for.
Right?
They want a new car,
they want a new house,
they want a bigger TV.
They wanted this or that.
And the way they motivate themselves to
keep showing up at this shitty job is to
think if I just put in three more
months,
I can get that Mercedes.
If I just do this or that or that,
I can,
oh,
I can finance this new pixel
three.
Oh yeah.
And it's interesting because it's sort
of politicians,
what's the American dream is for you
here?
This thing,
I want my children to be better off than
me.
It's kind of desire,
you know,
you can almost see that that taken
farther and farther will be.
There'll be a presidential candidate and
5,000
years they'll say,
I want my children to be robots.
And you know what I mean?
Like sort of this idea that that's the
natural evolution and that is the
highest calling of our species.
That scares me because I value my own
life,
but does it
Gary you if if it comes out perfect.
Like if each robot is like a god in each
robot is beautiful and loving and they
they recognize all the great parts of
this existence and they avoid all the
jealousy and the nonsense and all the
stupid aspects of being a person.
We realized that a lot of these things
are just sort of biological engineered
tricks that are designed to keep us
surviving from generation after
generation,
but now here in this fantastic new age,
we don't need them anymore.
Yeah,
it's.
Well first one of the most
transformative moments of my life was
when I met spot many in person,
which is one of the legged robots in
Boston dynamics for the first time when
I met them,
my meant that little fella there was.
I know exactly how it works.
I know exactly how every aspect of it
works.
It's just a dumb robot.
But when I met him and he got up and he
looked at me,
there it is right there.
Have you seen a dance now?
Yeah.
The dance.
The dance is crazy.
It's.
I see.
It's not crazy on the technical side.
It's engineered.
It's obvious.
It's programmed,
but it's crazy to watch like,
wow,
there's something.
The reason that moment was
transformative because I know exactly
how it works and yet by watching it
something about the feeling of it,
you're like,
this thing is alive and there was this
terrifying moment.
Not Terrifying,
terrifying and appealing.
Where this is the future,
right?
Like this thing,
like this thing represents some future
that is totally that we don't cannot
understand.
Just like a future in the 18th century
of a future with planes and smartphones
with somebody who could understand that
this thing,
that little dog could have had a a human
consciousness in it.
That was the feeling had.
And I know exactly how it works.
There's nothing close to the
intelligence,
but it just gives you this picture of
what the possibilities are of these
living creatures and I think that's what
people feel when they see Boston
dynamics will call awesome.
This thing running around is they don't
care about the technicalities and how
far away we are.
They see it.
Look,
this thing is pretty human and the
possibilities of human like things that
supercede humans and can evolve and
learn so quickly,
exponentially fast is this terrifying
frontier that that really makes us think
as it did for me.
Maybe terrifying is a weird word because
when I.
When I look at it and I'm not a rational
and I look at there's.
There's videos that show the progression
of Boston dynamics robots from several
years ago to today what they're capable
of and it's.
It is a fascinating thing because you're
watching all the hard work of these
engineers and all these people that have
designed these systems and have figured
out all of these problems at these
things encounter and they've come with
solutions and they continue to innovate
and they're constantly doing it and
you're seeing this and you're like,
wow,
what are we going to see in a year?
What am I going to see in three years?
What I want to see in five years?
It's absolutely fascinating because if
you extrapolate and you just keep going,
boy,
you go 15,
20,
30,
50,
100 years,
now you have x Mokena
you,
yeah,
you have x Makkah,
and at least in our imagination and our
imagination and the problem is there'll
be so many other things that are super
exciting and interesting,
but that doesn't mean it's not crazy.
I mean there's many other things you
could focus on also that are also going
to be bizarre and crazy.
Sure.
But what about it just it?
It's going somewhere.
That fucker is getting better.
The the park core one is bananas.
You see it hopping from box to box and
left to right and leaping up in the air
and you're like,
whoa.
I think doesn't have any wires on it.
It's not connected to anything.
It's just jumping from box to box.
If that thing had a machine gun,
it was running across a hill at you,
he'd be like,
Oh fuck.
How long does the battery last said?
How many bullets does it have?
Let me,
let me just say that I would pick Tim
Kennedy over that dog for the next 50
years.
50.
Yeah,
man.
So I'm a big Tim Kennedy I'm talking
about.
Um,
but he'll probably have some robotic
additions to his body to improve the.
Well,
is he tim Kennedy anymore?
If the brain is Tim Kennedy,
then he still Tim Kennedy.
That's the way we think about it.
But there is huge concern about UN is
meeting about this autonomous weapons.
It,
it's,
um,
it's allowing you to make decisions
about who lives and who dies is really
concerning in the short term.
It's not about a robotic dog with a
shotgun running around.
It's more about our military wanting to
make destruction as efficient as
possible,
minimizing human life and drones.
Drones.
There's something really uncomfortable
to me about drones in how you compare
with,
uh,
Dan Carlin hardcore history.
It was the gang Iskcon.
There's something impersonal about what
drones are doing,
weight.
It moves you away from the actual
destruction that you're achieving.
Where I worry that our ability to encode
the ethics into these systems will go
wrong in ways we don't expect.
And so,
I mean folks at the UN talk about,
well,
you have these automated,
so drones that make that drop bombs all
over a particular area.
So the bigger and bigger the area is
over which you allow an artificial
intelligence system to make a decision
to drop the bombs,
the weirder and weirder it gets.
There's some line that presumably if
there's like three tanks that you would
like to destroy with a drone,
it's okay for ai assistant to say,
I would like to destroy the street.
Like I'll handle everything,
just give me the three tanks.
But this makes me uncomfortable as well
because I think,
uh,
I'm opposed to most wars.
But it's just military is military and
they tried to get the job done.
Now what if we now expand that to 10,
2100 tanks where you not let ai system
drop bombs all over very large areas.
How can that go wrong?
And that's terrifying.
And there's practical engineering
solutions to that oversight and there's,
that's something that engineers to sit
down and there's an engineering ethic
where you encoding,
you have meetings,
uh,
of how do we make this safe?
That's what you worry about.
A thing that keeps me up at night is the
40,000
people that die every year in auto
crashes like that.
I worry about not.
You have to understand like I worry
about the future of Agi taking over,
but that's not as large.
Agi Now Agi,
artificial general intelligence.
That's kind of the term is that people
have been using for this,
but I'm maybe because I'm in it,
I worry more about the 40,000
people that die in the United States in
the one point 2 million that die every
year from auto crashes.
There's something that is more real to
me about the death that's happening now
that could be helped and that's the
fight,
but a force.
If the threat becomes real,
then then that's a much,
you know,
that's a serious threat to humankind and
that's something that should be thought
about.
I just worry that I worry also about the
Ai Winter,
so I mentioned there's been two winters
in the seventies,
in the eighties,
the nineties when funding completely
dried up,
but more importantly just people stopped
getting into artificial intelligence and
became cynical about as possibilities
because there was a hype cycle where
everyone is really excited about the
possibilities of ai and then they
realized,
you know,
five,
10 years into the development that we
didn't actually achieve anything.
It was just too far off,
too far off.
Same as it was for virtual reality.
For the longest time.
Virtual reality was something that was
discussed like even in the eighties and
the nineties,
but it,
it just died off.
Nobody even thought about it.
Now it's come back to the forefront when
there's real ai,
a real excuse me,
real virtual reality that you can use
like htc vives or you know,
things along those lines.
We can put these helmets on and you
really do see these alternative worlds
that people have created in these video
games and it's you realize like there's
a practical application for this stuff
because the technology has caught up
with the concept.
Yeah,
and I actually don't know where people
stand on Vr.
We do quite a bit of stuff with Vr for
research purposes,
for simulating robotic systems,
but I don't know where the hype is.
I don't know if people calm down a
little bit on Vr.
So there was a hype in the eighties and
nineties.
I think it's ramped up quite a bit.
What does the other one that had the
oculus rift and what other,
what other than just those two?
Those are the main ones.
And there's other headsets that you can
work and use with and there's some you
can use just with a Samsung phone,
correct?
Yeah.
And the work of the next generation or
which next year to two are going to be
all a stand alone systems is gonna be an
oculus rift coming out.
You don't need a computer for at all.
So the ultimate
and fear and game fear,
the event horizon of that is the Matrix,
right?
That's,
that's what people were terrified of.
Have some sort of a virtual reality
world where you don't exist in the
physical sense anymore.
They just plug something into the brain
stem just like they do in the matrix and
you're just locked into this artificial
world.
Is that terrifying to you as that seems
to be less terrifying than ai killing
all of humankind?
Well,
it depends means
I mean,
what is life?
That's the real question,
right?
If you only exist inside of a computer
program,
but it's a wonderful program and you,
you whatever your consciousness is.
And we haven't really established what
that is,
right?
We don't,
we don't.
I mean there's a lot of really weird
hippie ideas out there,
but what consciousness is your body?
Just like an antenna man.
And it's just like tuning into
consciousness and consciousness is all
around you.
It's Gaia,
the mother earth.
It's the universe itself.
It's God.
It's love.
Okay.
Maybe,
I don't know.
But if you could take that,
whatever the fuck it is and send it in a
cell phone in New Zealand,
is that where your consciousness is now?
Because like if,
if we figure out what consciousness is
and get it to the point where we can
turn it into a program or duplicate it,
I mean that's sounds so far away.
But if you weigh up to someone from 18,
20 and said,
hey man,
one day I'm going to take a picture of
my Dick and I'm a sent to this girl.
She's going to get it on her phone.
They be like,
what the fuck are you talking about a
photo?
What do,
what do you mean you're going to.
What's a photo?
Oh,
it's like a picture.
But like you don't draw it.
It's perfect.
It looks exactly like that.
It's in hd and I'm going to make a video
of me taking a shit and I'm going to
send it to every.
Like what the fuck is this even possible
can out of here.
The Dat is essentially you're capturing
time,
you're capturing moments in time at a
very,
not a very crude sense,
but a crude sense in terms of comparing
it to the actual world in the moment
where it's happening.
Like here you and I are having this
conversation.
We're having it in front of this wooden
desk,
his paper in front of you to you and I.
We have access to all the textures,
the sounds.
We can feel the air conditioning.
We can look up,
we could see the,
the,
the ceiling.
We're,
we're,
we've got the whole thing in front of us
because we're really here,
but too many people that are watching
this on youtube right now.
They're getting a minimized crude
version of this
that's similar,
but it feels real.
It feels pretty real.
It's pretty close.
So I mean,
I've listened to your podcast for
awhile.
You usually have.
So when I listened to your podcast,
it feels like I'm sitting in with
friends listening to a conversation,
so it's not as intense as,
for example,
Dan Carlin's hardcore history where the
guy's like talking to me about the
darkest aspects of human nature.
That show's so good.
I don't think you can call it a podcast.
It's not a.
it's,
it's an experience.
You're there.
I was.
I was hanging out with him and getting
his con and I was in World War One.
World War Two,
painful attainment is an episode he had.
We taught very dark ideas about our
human nature and desiring the
observation of the torture and suffering
of others.
There's something really appealing to
us.
He has this whole episode how throughout
history we liked watching people die and
there's something really dark.
You're saying that if somebody streamed
or something like that,
now it would probably get hundreds of
millions of views.
Yeah,
and we would.
And we're protecting ourselves from our
own nature because we understand the
destructive aspects of it.
That's why youtube would pull something
like that,
right?
If you tied a person in between two
trucks and pulled them apart and put
that on youtube,
it would get millions of hits,
but youtube would pull it because we've
decided as a society collectively that
those kinds of images or gruesome and
terrible for us,
but nevertheless that experience of
listening to his podcasts,
let's show it feels real.
Just like Vr for me is really strongly
real aspects to it where I'm not sure.
I'm not sure if the
VR technology gets much better to where
if you had a choice between do you want
to live your life in Vr,
you you're going to die just like you
would in real life.
Meaning your body will die.
You're just going to hook up yourself to
a machine like it's a deprivation tank
and just all you are is in Vr and you're
going to live in that world.
Which life would you choose?
Would you choose life and Vr or would
you choose a real life?
That was the guy's decision in the
Matrix,
right?
The guy decided in the matrix,
you want it to be a special person in
the matrix.
He was eating that steak talking to the
guys and decided he was going to give
up.
Remember that?
Yup.
So what decision would you make?
I mean,
what is reality if it's not what you're
experiencing,
right?
If you're experiencing something but
it's not tactile in the sense like you
can't drag it somewhere and put it on a
scale and take a ruler to it and measure
it,
but in the moment of being there,
it seems like it is.
What is missing?
Well,
it's not real.
What is real then?
What is real?
Well,
that's the ultimate question in terms of
like are we living in a simulation?
That's one of the things that
[inaudible] brought up when I was
talking to them and this is one thing
that people have struggled with.
If we are one day going to come up with
an artificial reality,
it's indiscernible from reality in terms
of emotions,
in terms of experiences,
feel,
touch,
smell,
all of the sensory input that you get
from the regular world.
If that's inevitable,
if one day we do come up with that,
how are we to discern whether or not we
have already created that and we're
stuck in it right now
that we can't and there's a lot of
philosophical arguments for that,
but that gets it the.
Yeah.
The nature of reality is.
I mean,
it's fascinating because we're okay.
We're totally clueless about what it
means to be real.
It needs to exist to exist.
So consciousness for us.
I mean,
it's incredible.
You look at your own hand like I'm
pretty sure I'm on the Joe Rogan
experience podcast.
I'm pretty sure this is not real.
I'm imagining all of it.
There's a knife in front of me.
I mean it's surreal and I have no proof
that it's not fake and,
and those kinds of things actually come
into play with the way we think about
artificial intelligence to like what is
intelligence?
It seems like it seems like we're easily
impressed by by algorithms and robots.
We create that appear to have
intelligence,
but we still don't know what is
intelligent and how close those things
are to us
and we think that ourselves as this
biological entity that can think and
talk and cry and laugh,
that we're somehow or another more
important than sort of some sort of
silicone based thing that we create that
does everything that we do.
But far better.
Yeah.
I think,
uh,
I think if I were to take a stand still
right,
stand,
I hope I'm young one day run for
president in this platform by the way
that defending the rights.
I can't because I'm rushing,
but maybe a little cheesy rules,
uh,
that the robots will have rights and I,
I'll,
you know,
robots lives matter and I,
I actually believe that we're going to
have to start struggling with the idea
of how we interact with robots.
I've seen too often the abuse of robots
and not just the Boston dynamics,
but literally people.
You leave them alone with the robot.
That dark nature of Hue,
dark aspects of human nature comes out
and it's worrying to me I would like a
robot that spars but only can move it
like 50 percent of what I can move out
so I could fuck it up.
Yeah.
She shouldn't be able to practice like
really well.
Like you would develop like some awesome
like sparring instincts.
Yeah,
I a robot,
but there would still be consequences.
Like if you did fuck up and you got lazy
and it led,
kicked you,
you didn't check it.
It would hurt.
I would love to see a last stream of
that session because the,
you know,
there's so many ways I used to.
I mean I had practiced on a dummy.
There is aspects to a dummy that's
helpful in terms of positioning and
where were your stances and technique to
it.
I could certainly see that going wrong
in ways where a robot might not respect
you.
Tapping or world supposed to beat you to
death as tired as you fucking it up
every day and one day you get tired or
what have you,
sprain your ankle and it gets on top of
you and mounts you and just starts
blasting the face and to say he'll hook
or something.
You'd have to be able to say,
stop.
Well then no,
you're gonna have to use your martial
art to defend yourself,
right?
Because if you make it too easy for the
robot to just stop at any time,
then you're not really going to learn.
Like one of the consequences of training
if you're out of shape is if you get
tired people fuck you up.
And that's incentive for you to not get
tired.
Like there was so many times that I
would be in the gym,
like doing strength and conditioning.
And I think about moments where I got
tapped.
What guys caught me and something that I
was exhausted.
I couldn't get out of the triangle.
I'm like,
Shit.
And I just fucking die.
I just really push on the treadmill or
you know,
push on the um,
um,
airdyne bike or whatever it was that I
was doing,
thinking about those moments.
Getting tired.
Yeah,
those moments.
That's what I think about when I do like
sprints and stuff was um,
the feeling of competition,
those nerves of stepping in there and
just,
it's really hard to do that kind of
visualization.
But it was effective though.
And the,
the,
the feeling of consequences to you not
having any energy.
So you have to muster up the energy
because if you don't,
you're going to get fucked up or
something bad's going to happen to
someone you care about or something.
Something's gonna Happen to the world.
Maybe you're a superhero.
You saving the world from the robots.
That's right.
But I did go back
what we're talking about,
sorry to interrupt you,
but just to bring this all back around,
what,
what is,
what is this life and what is
consciousness and what does this
experience,
and if you can replicate this experience
in a way that's indiscernible,
will you choose to do that?
Like if someone says to you,
Hey Lex,
you don't have much time left,
but what?
We have an option,
we have an option and we can take your
consciousness.
As you know it right now,
put it into this program.
You will have no idea that this has
happened.
You're going to close your eyes.
You're going to wake up,
you're going to be in the most beautiful
green field.
It's going to be naked women everywhere.
Feasts,
everywhere you go,
it's going to be just picnic tables
filled with the most glorious food.
You're going to drive around a Ferrari
every day and fly around in a plane.
You never going to die.
You can have a great time or take a
chance.
Chances.
See what happens?
Shut off.
Well,
first of all,
I'm a simple man.
I don't need multiple women.
One is good.
I'm romantic,
you say,
but that's in this world,
this world.
You've got an incentive to not be greedy
in this other world where you can
breathe underwater and fly through the
air and you know,
not I.
I believe that scarcity is the
fundamental ingredient of happiness.
So if you give me 72 virgins,
whatever it is,
and we just keep one slut,
slut,
she a requirement.
You know,
somebody intelligent and interesting who
enjoys sexual intercourse was not just
enjoy sexual intercourse with a person.
Well that and keeps things interesting
lex.
We can engineer all this into your
experience as you don't need all these
different women.
I get it.
I understand that.
We've got this program for you.
Don't worry about it.
Okay.
You want one,
one and a normal car,
like maybe a Saab or something like
that.
Nothing crazy.
Yeah,
right.
Yeah.
But you're a simple man.
I get it.
No,
but you need to at chess with someone
who could beat you every now and then,
right?
Yeah,
but not just chess.
So engineers,
some flaws.
Like she needs to be able to lose her
shit.
Every once in a while the matrix or on
the red dress.
Which girl in the red dress that comes
right here.
Remember?
He goes like,
did you notice the girl in the red
dress?
It's like the one that catches his
attention.
I don't remember this.
This is right at the very beginning when
he's telling them what the Matrix is.
She walks by right here.
Oh,
there she is,
but Bam.
That's your girl.
The guy afterwards.
It's like I ended up telling you.
It's just not.
It's not.
Well.
Yeah,
but then I have certain features like
I'm not an iphone guy like android so
that,
that may be an iphone persons girl,
but that's nonsense.
I,
I blew up an iphone.
Came along.
That was better than android.
You wouldn't want to use it?
No,
it might just definition of better is
different.
Like,
uh,
I know for me a happiness lies in
android phones,
close connection.
Other human beings who are flawed but
interesting who are passionate about
what they do.
Yeah.
But this is all engineered into your
program.
Yeah.
That's.
I'm requesting features here because
you're requesting features,
but why?
Why android phones?
Is that like,
um,
I'm a Republican.
I'm a Democrat,
like android phones.
Is that what you're doing to get in
tribal?
Not Electronics.
I totally not drivable.
I was just representing,
if I figured the girl in the red dress,
it just seems like an iphone as a
feature set.
I imagined the kind of features I'm
asking you a lot.
Yeah,
and it seems like she's not interested
in dusty yefsky.
How would you know that?
So prejudice view just because she's
beautiful and she's got a fitting dress.
I don't know.
That's fair.
You,
you sexist son of a bitch.
I'm sorry.
Actually that was a totally.
She probably likes Nietzschean and sts
can come when I say she did her phd in
astrophysics.
Possibly.
Yeah.
That's what we're talking about.
All the trappings that.
Bam,
I'll take her all day.
I phone Andrew Commerce or if she's a
windows phone about that.
I'm going to give off windows phone.
Come on now.
I'll take her.
She's a windows phone.
I'll go with a flip phone from the early
two thousands.
I'll take a razor phone,
a Motorola razor phone with like 37
minutes of battery life.
But we're,
we're,
we're talking about all the learning
experiences and preferences that you've
developed in your time here on this
actual real earth or what we're assuming
is the actual real earth.
But how are we,
I mean,
if you're,
if you really are taking into account
the possibility that one day something
someone,
whether it's artificial intelligence
figures it out or we figured out
engineering a world,
us some sort of a simulation that is
just as real as this world.
Like where there is no,
there's no.
It's impossible to discern.
Not only is it not always impossible to
discern,
people choose not to discern anymore
because it's so well,
why bother?
Why bother discerning?
That's a fascinating concept to me,
but I think that world,
not to sound hippie or anything,
but I think that.
I think we live in a world that's pretty
damn good.
That is pretty good.
So.
But improving it with such fine,
fine ladies walking around.
It's not necessarily that the delta
that's positive.
Okay.
But that's one aspect of the
improvement.
What about improving it?
And in this new world,
there's no drone attacks in Yemen that
killed children.
I order,
there's no rape,
there's no sexual harassment,
there's no,
there's no racism,
there's no any.
All the negative aspects of our current
culture or engineered out,
I think.
I think a lot of religions have
struggled with this and of course I
would say I would want a world without
that,
but part
of me thinks that our world is
meaningful because of the suffering in
the world.
Right.
That's a real problem,
isn't it?
It's a real.
It's.
That is a fascinating concept.
It's almost impossible to ignore.
Do you appreciate love because of all
the hate,
you know,
like if you have a hard time finding a
girlfriend and just no one's compatible
and obviously the Hala letting the
ladies know,
but if you,
if you do have a hard time connecting
with someone and then you finally do
connect with someone off after all those
years of loneliness and this person's
perfectly compatible with you,
how much more will you appreciate them?
Then?
A guy like Dan Bilzerian was flying
around in a private jet bang and tens
all day long,
or maybe he's fucking drowning in his
own sorrow.
Maybe he's got too much,
too much prosperity and this,
you know,
yeah,
we had that with social networks to the
people that,
I mean,
you're pretty famous in the amount of
love you get is huge.
It's a,
it might be because of the overflow of
love.
It might be difficult to appreciate more
like genuine little moments of love.
And it's not for me.
No.
Um,
I,
I spent a lot of time thinking about
that and I also spent a lot of time
thinking about how titanic really
bizarre my place in the world is.
I mean,
I,
I think about it a lot and I spent a lot
of time being poor and being a loser.
Me,
my childhood was not the best.
I went through a lot of struggle when I
was young that I cling to like a safety
rep raft.
You know,
I,
I don't,
I don't ever think there's something
special about me and I try to let
everybody know that you,
anybody can do it.
I've done it.
You just have to just keep going though.
The 99 percent of this thing is just
showing up and keep going.
Keep improving,
keep working at things and keep going,
put the time in,
but the interesting thing is you haven't
actually,
a couple of days ago went back to your
first podcast and listen to it.
You haven't really changed much,
so you were.
I mean the audio got a little better and
but just like the year,
the genuine nature of the way you
interact hasn't changed and that's
fascinating because,
you know,
fame changes people.
Well,
I was already famous then,
but just in a different way.
I was famous.
I was already famous from fear factor.
I was already already had standup comedy
specials already had.
I'd already been on a sitcom.
Wasn't as famous as I am now,
but I understood what it is.
I'm a big believer in adversity and
struggle.
I think they're very important for you.
It's one of the reasons why appreciate
martial arts.
It's one of the reasons why I've been
drawn to it as a learning tool,
not just as something where it's a
puzzle that I'm fascinated to try to
figure out how to get better at the
puzzle.
And martial arts is a really good
example because you never really the
best,
especially when there's just so many
people doing it.
It's like you're always going to get
beat by guys.
And then I was never,
I was never putting the time into it as
a,
an adult outside of,
uh,
my taekwondo competition.
I was never really putting all day every
day into it.
Like a lot of people that I would train
would.
And so I'd always get dominated by the
really best guys.
So there's a certain amount of humility
that comes from that as well.
But there's,
there's a struggle in that you're
learning about yourself and your own
limits and the limits of the human mind
and endurance and just not understanding
all the various interactions of
techniques and that,
you know,
there's some,
there's humility to that in that I've
always described martial arts as a
vehicle for developing your own human
potential.
But I think marathon running a similar
aspects.
I think when you're just,
you figure out a way to keep pushing and
push through the control of your mind
and your desire and overcoming
adversity.
I think overcoming adversity is critical
for the human,
for humans.
We have this,
this,
um,
these set of reward systems that are
designed to do,
to reward us for overcoming,
for overcoming obstacles,
for overcoming a relationship,
struggles for overcoming physical
limitations.
And those rewards are great and there
are some of the most amazing moments in
life when you do overcome.
And I think this is sort of engineered
into the system.
So for me,
fame is almost like a cheat code.
It's like you don't really want it.
Don't dwell on that man.
Like that is,
that's like a free buffet.
Like you don't,
you know,
you want to go hunt your own food,
you want to make your own fire,
you want to cook yourself and feel the
satisfaction.
You don't want people feeding you grapes
while you lie down.
What is the hardest thing?
So you talked about challenge a lot.
What's the hardest thing you've won?
Have you been really humbled
martial arts?
For sure.
The most humbling.
Yeah,
from the moment I started,
I mean I got really good at taekwondo,
but even then I'd still get the fuck
beaten out of me by my friends and got
training part.
Especially when you're tired and you're
doing your rotating partners and guys
are bigger than you.
It's just,
it's just humbling,
you know,
martial arts,
very humbling.
No,
I got to call you out on something.
So you talk about education system
sometimes I've heard you say is a little
broken in high school and so on.
I'm not really calling out and just I
just want to talk about it because I
think it's important and as somebody who
loves math,
it talked about your own journey.
Was school didn't give you a passion?
Well you can maybe talk to that,
but for me what I always do,
maybe I'm sick in the head or something,
but for me math was exciting.
The way martial arts,
we're excited for you because it was
really hard.
I wanted to quit and the idea of,
of education,
I have that,
that,
that seems to be flawed nowadays a
little bit is that we want to make
education easier,
that we want to make more accessible and
so on.
Uh,
accessible of course is great,
but you kind of forget in that.
And those are all good goals.
You forget in that it's supposed to be
also hard and like teachers,
just the way you're wrestling coach,
if you like quit,
you say,
I can't do anymore.
I have to come up with some kind of
excuse.
You're wrestling coach looks at you
wants to say get your ass back on the
mat the same way I wish math teachers
did that.
When people say it's almost like cool
now to say i's not math sucks,
mass not for me or science sucks as his
teacher's boring.
I think there are,
there's room for some culture where
says,
no,
you're not.
If you just put in the time and you
struggle,
then that opens up the universe to you.
Like whether you become a neil degrasse
tyson or the next fields medal winner in
mathematics.
I would not argue with you for one
second.
I would also say that one of the more
beautiful things about human beings is
that we vary so much and that one person
who is just obsessed with playing the
trombone and to me,
I don't give a fuck about trombones,
but that's okay.
Like I can't be obsessed about
everything.
Some people love golf and they just want
to play it all day long.
I've never played golf a day in my life.
Set Miniature Golf and just fucking
around,
but that doesn't.
It's not bad or good and I think
there's.
There's definitely some skills that you
learned from mathematics that are hugely
significant if you want to go into type
of fields that you're involved in.
For me it's never been appealing,
but it's not that it was just difficult.
It's also that it just,
for whatever reason,
who I was at that time in that school
with those teachers and having the life
experience that I had,
that was not what I was drawn to,
but what I was drawn to,
his literature I was drawn to reading.
I was drawn to stories,
I was drawn to possibilities and
creativity.
I was drawn to all those things.
You are an artist of it too.
I used to be.
I used to want to be a comic book
illustrator.
That was,
that was a big thing when I was young.
I was really into comic books.
I was really into um,
a traditional comic books and also a lot
of the horror comics from the 19
seventies that black and white,
like creepy and eerie.
Did you ever see those things?
Creepy and eerie.
Like black and white?
Yeah,
they were.
There were a comic book series that I'm
existed,
like way back in the day was all there,
all horror and they were like really
cool illustrations and these wild
stories,
but it was comic books,
but they were all black and white.
That's creepy.
And Eerie.
That's the actual name?
Yeah.
Erie and creepy.
Where the names like that was from.
What year was that?
It says September,
but it doesn't say what year am I used
to get these when I was a little kid,
man,
I was like eight,
nine years old.
And the seventies,
good and evil.
Yeah,
it was,
uh,
they were,
they were my favorite,
like that's a cover of them and like
have like covers that were done by like
Frank Frazetta,
Boris Vallejo,
and just really cool shit.
And I was fat.
I love those.
When I was little I was always really
into horror movies and really into like
Bram,
like,
look at this werewolf one that was one
of my favorite ones.
That was a crazy werewolf that was like,
well,
all fours,
who's the hero?
Usually super heroes.
Everybody dies.
And those,
that's the beautiful thing about it.
Everybody gets fucked over.
There was nobody.
That was the thing that I really liked
about them was that nobody made it out
alive.
There was no one guy who figured it out
and rescued the woman and they wrote off
in the sunset,
but you turned the corner and they'd be
a fucking pack of wolves with glowing
eyes were waiting to tear everybody
apart.
And that'd be the end of the book.
And I just,
um,
I was just really into the
illustrations.
I found that fascinating.
I just,
I love those kind of horror movies and I
love those kinds of illness.
So that's what I wanted to do when I was
young.
Yeah,
I think the education system is
probably.
We've talked about creativity is
probably not as good at,
uh,
inspiring and feeding that creativity
because I think math and wrestling can
be taught systematically.
I think creativity is something.
Well actually I had known nothing about
it,
so I think it's harder to take somebody
like you when you're young and say and
inspire you to pursue that fire.
Whatever's inside.
Well,
one of the best ways to inspire people
is by giving them,
giving them these alternatives that are
so uninteresting,
like saying you're going to get a job
selling washing machines and you're
like,
fuck that.
I'm going to figure out a way to not get
a job selling washing machines.
Like what some of the best motivations
that I've ever had have been terrible
jobs because you have these terrible
jobs and go,
okay,
fuck that.
I'm going to figure out a way to not do
this,
you know,
and whether you want to call it add or
Adhd or whatever it is that makes kids
squirm in class.
I didn't score and every class I didn't
squirm and science class,
I didn't squirm in,
in,
you know,
an interesting subjects.
There's things that were interesting to
me that I would be locked in and
completely fascinated by and there was
things where I just couldn't wait to run
out of that room and I don't know what
the reason is,
but I do know that a lot of what we call
our education system is engineered for a
very specific result and that result is
you want to get a kid who can sit in
class and learn so that they could sit
in a job and perform and that for
whatever reason,
that was just.
I mean,
I didn't have the ideal childhood.
Maybe.
Maybe if I did I would be more inclined
to lean that way,
but I didn't want to do anything like
that.
Like,
I couldn't wait to get the fuck out of
school,
so I didn't ever have to listen to
anybody like that again.
And then just a few years later,
I mean,
you graduated from high school and
you're 18.
When I was 21,
I was a stand up comic and I was like,
I found it.
This is it.
I'm like,
good.
I found there's an actual job that
nobody told me about where you could
just make fun of Shit and people go out
and they pay money to hear you.
Uh,
create jokes and routines and bits.
Really.
You weren't terrified of standup getting
onstage and.
Oh,
I was definitely nervous the first time.
Probably more nervous and he was hard on
him fighting.
No,
it's different.
It's different.
The consequences aren't as grave,
but that's one of the,
they not know,
like embarrassment and you don't get
pummeled.
I mean there's,
there's,
you could say like,
emotionally it's probably more
devastating or as devastating.
But man,
losing a fight is,
it fucks you up for a long time.
You feel like shit for a long time.
Um,
but then you,
when you feel amazing for a long time
too,
when you kill onstage,
you only feel good for like an hour or
so,
and then it goes away.
It feels normal.
It's just normal.
It's just life,
you know.
But I think that it prepared me like
competing in martial arts,
the fear of that and then the,
how hard it is to stand opposite another
person who's the same size as you,
who's equally well trained,
who's also a martial arts expert.
And they ask you,
are you ready?
Are you ready?
You bow to each other and then they go
fight and then you're like,
fuck,
here we go.
Like that to me probably was like one of
the best prep.
And to do that from the time I was 15
until I was 21 was probably the best
preparation for anything.
That was difficult too because it was so
fucking scary.
And then to go from that into standup,
I think it prepared me for standing up
because I was already used to doing
things that were scary.
Now I seek scary things out.
I Thi,
I seek difficult things.
Uh,
picking up the bow and learning that
yes,
archery,
which is really difficult.
I mean there's some reasons why I got
attracted even to playing pool pools.
Very difficult.
It's very difficult to control your
nerves and high pressure situations so
that there's,
there's,
there's some benefits of that,
but here.
But it goes back to what you were saying
earlier,
how much of all this stuff,
like when you were saying that scarcity,
there's,
there's real value in scarcity and that
there's real value in struggle and how
much of all this is just engineered into
our human system that it has given us
the tools and the incentive to make it
to 2018 with the human species.
Yeah.
I think it's whoever the engineer is,
whether it's God or nature or whatever,
I think it's engineered and somehow that
we get to think about that.
When you try to create an artificial
intelligence system,
when you imagine what's a perfect system
for you,
where we talked about this with,
with the lady,
what's the perfect system for you?
If you had to really put down on paper
and engineer,
what's the experience of your life,
will you start to realize it actually
looks a lot like your current life.
So this is the problem that companies
are facing like Amazon and trying to
create Alexa.
What do you want from Alexa?
Do you want a tool that says what the
weather is or do you want to Alexa to
say,
Joe,
I don't want to talk to you right now.
I Have
Alexa where you have to work or over
like Alexa,
come on.
What do I do?
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Listen,
if I was rude,
I was insensitive.
I was tired of the commute was really
rough and they shouldn't be like I'm
seeing somebody else.
Do you remember?
Avatar depression?
Uh,
the movie Avatar and depression is a
psychological effect after the movies.
Yeah.
It was a real term that people were
using,
that psychologists were using because
people would see the movie Avatar,
which I loved.
A lot of people said,
oh,
it's fucking pocahontas was blue people
to those people.
I say,
fuck off.
You want to talk about suspension of
disbelief.
That to me,
that movie was the ultimate suspension
of disbelief.
I love that movie.
I fucking love that.
I can't.
I know James Cameron is working on like
15 sequels right now.
All simultaneously.
I wish that motherfucker would dole them
out.
He's like a,
a crack dealer that gets you hooked once
and then you just waiting outside in the
cold.
Shiver.
And for years,
um,
avatar depression was a psychological
term that psychologists were using to
describe this mass influx of people that
saw that movie and were so enthralled by
the way the Navi lived in Pandora that
they came back to this stupid to leave.
They wanted to be like the blue guy in
Avatar.
And it also,
there was a,
there was a mechanism in that film where
this regular person became a Navi.
He became through the Avatar and then
eventually that tree of life or whatever
it was,
they transferred his essence into this,
create this avatar.
And he became one of them.
He became one of them.
He absorbed their culture and it was
very much like our romanticized versions
of the native Americans that they lived
in symbiotic relationship with the
earth.
They only took what they needed.
They had spiritual connection to their
food and to nature and to the just the,
their existence was was noble and it was
honorable and it wasn't selfish and it
was powerful and it was spiritual and
that we're missing these things.
We're missing these things and I think
we are better at romanticizing them and
craving them as opposed to living them
as.
I mean,
you look at movies like happy people
with the life and the tiger den.
Live life in a tie.
GMS,
yeah,
I'm rushing center.
Herzog's film is part of you wants to be
like,
well,
I want to be out there in nature,
focusing on simple survival,
setting traps for animals,
cooking some soup,
a family around you,
and just kind of focusing on the basics.
But.
And I'm the same way,
like I go out hiking and I go out in
nature.
I would love to pick up hunting and I
want.
I'm crave that,
but if you just put me in the forest,
I'll probably.
It'd be like I'm taking your phone away
and you're staying here.
That's it.
You never go into return to your
facebook and your twitter and your and
your robots.
I don't know if I'll be so romantic
about that notion anymore.
I don't know either,
but I think that's also the genie in the
bottle,
right discussion.
I think that genie's out of the bottle
for so long.
You'd be like,
but what am I?
Facebook?
What have I got?
Some messages.
Let me check my email real quick.
No,
no,
no.
We're in the forest.
There's no wifi out here.
No wifi ever.
What the fuck?
How do people get your porn porn?
No,
that's another understudied.
Again,
not an expert,
but the impact of Internet pornography
on culture.
Oh yeah.
I'm,
it's significant.
And also ignored to a certain extent and
um,
if not ignored,
uh,
definitely purposefully left out of the
conversation.
Yeah.
There's a another phd student,
a person from Google came to give a tech
talk and he opened by saying 90 percent
of you in the audience have this month,
Google the pornographic term in our
search engine,
and it was really a great opener because
people were just all really
uncomfortable because we just kind of
hide it away into this,
but it certainly has an impact.
I think there's a suppression aspect to
that too.
That's unhealthy.
We,
we,
we have a suppression of our sexuality
because we think that somehow or another
it's negative,
right.
You know,
and especially for women,
I mean for women like men
and who is a sexual conqueror is thought
to be a stud.
Whereas a woman who seeks out a multiple
desirable sexual partners is thought to
be troubled or something wrong with her.
You know,
they,
they're criticized there use terms like
we used earlier,
like slut or whore,
you know,
there's no,
you call a man a mail slot.
They'll start laughing.
He up.
That's me,
dude.
Like men don't give a fuck about that.
It's not,
it's not stigmatized,
but somehow or another through our
culture,
it's stigmatized for women.
And then the idea of masturbation is
stigmatized.
These,
all these different things that we,
our puritan roots of our society starts
showing and our religious ideology
starts showing when we discuss our,
our issues that we have with sex and
pornography.
All right,
and for me,
this is something I think about a little
bit because my dream is to create an
artificial intelligence,
the human centered artificial
intelligence system that provides a
deep,
meaningful connection with another human
being.
And you have to consider the fact that
pornography or sex dolls will be part of
the journey somehow in society.
Something you're the dummy they'll be
using for martial arts would likely to
be in our development of,
uh,
of sex robots.
And we have to think about what's the
impact of those kinds of robots on
society.
But women in particular are violently
opposed to sex robots.
I've read,
uh,
read a couple articles written by women
about sex robots and the possibility of
future sex robots and the,
I shouldn't say violently,
but it's always negative.
So is the idea that men would want to
have sex with some beautiful thing
that's programmed to love them as
opposed to earning the love of a woman,
but you don't hear that same
interpretation from men,
from men.
It's,
it seems to be that there's a thought
about,
maybe it's Kinda Gross,
but also that it's inevitable and that,
uh,
and then there's like this,
like sort of nod to it.
Like how crazy would that be if you had
the perfect woman like the red,
the woman in the red dress in the
matrix?
Yeah.
But it comes over to your house and
she's perfect
because you're not thinking about the
alternative,
which is a male robot doll,
which will now be able to satisfy your
girlfriend wife better than you.
I think you'll hear from guys a lot more
than,
um,
maybe or maybe start competing with her.
She's fucking annoying.
She's always yelling at me.
Let her yell at the robot.
He doesn't know he's not going to care.
Then that robot turns into grappling.
Yeah.
And maybe she can just go ahead and get
fat with the robot.
He's not even even care.
Go ahead.
Just sit around each cheetos all day and
screaming at him.
He's your,
he's your,
your slave.
Good.
I mean,
he could work both ways,
right?
It can work the same way that a man
would,
uh,
you know,
a woman would see a man that is
interested in a sex robot to be
disgusting,
pathetic.
A man could see the same thing in a
woman that's interested in a sex robot
like,
okay,
this,
that is that what you want,
do some crude thing that just wants
physical pleasure and you don't even
care about a real,
actual emotional connection to a
biological human being like,
okay,
well then you're not my kind of woman
anyway.
And uh,
but if done well,
those are the kinds of,
in terms of threats of Ai,
to me,
if you can change the fabric of society
because like I'm old school in that
sense.
I,
I like monogamy.
For example,
you know,
when you say that because you don't have
a girlfriend,
monogamy one is,
one is better.
Well now the real reason and have a a
girlfriend is because it is fascinated
with people like you would with the
time.
Yes.
Is a huge challenge because because of
how much your romantic I am because how
much I care about people around me.
I feel like it's a significant
investment in time and also the amount
of work that you do.
I mean if you're.
If you're dedicated to a passion like
artificial intelligence and the sheer
amount of fucking studying and research
and programming to certain disciplines
in which you have to.
Certain disciplines require.
Like Steven pressfield talks about
writing.
You can get pretty far with two,
three hours a day when you're
programming,
when you see a lot of the engineering
tasks,
they just take up hours.
It's just hard,
which is why I really wanted one of the
reasons I may disagree with all,
well a bunch of things,
but he's an inspiration because I think
he's a pretty good dad.
Right?
And he finds the time for his sons while
being probably an order of magnitude
busier than I am and it's fascinating to
me how that's possible.
Well,
once you have children,
I mean there obviously are people that
are bad dads,
but once you have children,
your life shifts in an almost.
It's
indescribable way because you're.
You're different.
It's not just that your life is
different when you have a child like
your Deli.
There hasn't been a moment while we were
having this conversation that I haven't
been thinking about my children,
thinking about what they're doing,
where they are.
It's always running in the background.
It's a part of life.
You're,
you're connected to these people that
you love so much and they rely on you
for guidance and for,
for warmth and affection and but how did
you left have to change your life?
You just changed.
Man.
When you see the baby,
you change.
When you,
when you start feeding them,
you change.
When you hold them,
When you,
you hold their hand while they walk,
you change.
When they ask you questions,
When they laugh and Giggle,
you change.
When they smack in the face and you
pretend to fall down,
they laugh,
you change,
you just change,
man.
You change.
You become a different thing,
you become a dad,
so you almost can't help but the people
do help,
but though that's what's sad.
Some people resist it.
I mean,
I know people that have been terrible,
terrible parents.
They just,
they'd rather stay out all night and
never come and they don't want to take
care of their kids and they get,
they split up with the wife or the
girlfriend who's got the kid and they
don't give child support and it's a
really common theme and I mean there's a
lot of men out there that don't pay
child support.
That's a dark,
dark thing.
You have a child out there that needs
food and you don't want.
You're so fucking selfish.
You don't want to provide resources.
Not only do you not want to be there for
companionship,
you don't want to provide resources to
pay for the child's food.
You don't feel responsible for it.
I mean,
that was my case when I was a kid.
My Dad didn't pay child support and we
were very poor.
It's one of the reasons why we were so
poor and I know other people that have
that same experience,
so it's not everyone that becomes a
father or that impregnates I should say
a woman and becomes a and the other side
is true too.
There's women that are terrible mothers
for whatever reason.
I mean maybe they're broken
psychologically.
Maybe they have mental health issues
when whatever it is.
There's some women that are fucking
terrible moms and it's sad,
but it makes you appreciate women that
are great mom so much more.
You know,
when I see guys like you at the
inspiration is some looking for sort of
structural.
What's the process to then fit people
into your life?
But what I hear is when it happens,
you just do.
You can always put that this is the
thing,
man,
we're not living in a book.
We're not living in a movie.
It doesn't always happen.
Like you have to decide that you want it
to happen and you got to go looking for
it because if you don't,
you could just be older and still alone.
Time goes.
A lot of my friends that have never had
kids and now they're in their fifties.
I mean comedians.
You have to be on the road a lot,
not just on the road.
You have to be obsessed with comedy.
Like it's.
It's got to be something.
You're always writing new jokes because
you're always reading a new.
Especially if you put out a special
right,
you put like.
I just did a Netflix special.
It's out now,
so I'll really have like a half hour new
material.
That's it and I'm great by the way.
Thank you very much.
The first special I've washed,
it was actually really weird,
decided to go on a tangent,
but I've listened to you quite a bit,
but I've never looked at you doing
comedy and it was so different because
here you're just like Improv,
like a jazz musician here.
It's like a regular conversation.
The standard was special.
It was clear like that's like everything
is perfect.
The timing.
It's like watching you do a different
art almost.
It is kind of interesting.
It's like a song or something.
It's like you don't.
There's some roofing to it.
There's some improvisation to it,
but it's also there's a very clear
structure to it,
but that's,
that's it's so time intensive and you
have to.
You've got to be obsessed with it to
continue to do something like that,
so for some people that travel and the
road that takes priority over all things
including relationships and then you
never really settled down and so you
never.
You never have a significant
relationship with someone that you could
have a child with and I know many
friends that are like that and I know
friends who have gotten vasectomies
because they don't want it.
They liked this life and there's nothing
wrong with that either.
I always was upset by this notion that
in order to be a full and complete
adult,
you have to have a child.
You have to be a parent,
and I think even as a parent where I
think it's probably one of the most
significant things in my life,
I.
I reject that notion.
I think you could absolutely be a fully
developed person and an amazing
influence in society and amazing
contributor to your culture and your
community without ever having a child.
Whether you're a man or a woman.
It's entirely possible.
And the idea that it's not as silly.
Like we're,
we're all different in so many different
ways,
you know,
and we contribute in so many different
ways.
There's going to be people that are
obsessed with mathematics is going to be
people that are obsessed with
literature,
that's going to be people that are
obsessed with music and they don't all
have to be the same puck in person
because you really don't have enough
time for it to be the same person you
know,
and there's,
there's going to be people that love
having children.
They love being a dad or loved being a
mom.
And then it's going to be people that
don't want to have nothing to do with
that.
And they get snipped early and they're
like,
fuck off.
I'm going to smoke cigarettes and drink
booze and I'm going to fly around the
world and talk shit.
And those people are okay to like the
way we interact with each other.
That's most important.
That's what I think the way human
beings,
the way we form bonds and friendships,
the way we,
we contribute to each other's lives,
we,
we find our passion and create those
things are what's really important.
Yeah.
But there's also an element just looking
at my parents,
I think they got,
they're still together to garden
together.
What it means,
standards.
You get together when you're like 20 or
I should know this,
but 23 slash 20 whatever young.
And there is an element there where you
don't want to be too rational.
He just want to just dive in.
Right.
Should you be an MMA fighter?
Should you be like,
I'm,
I'm an academia now.
Uh,
so I'm a research scientist at Mit.
The pay is much,
much lower than all the offers I'm
getting nonstop as it rational.
I don't know what your passion
it is doing what you're doing currently.
Yeah.
But it's like,
it's
what are the other offers?
Like what kind of other jobs and are
they appealing in any way?
Yeah.
Yeah,
they're appealing,
so I,
I'm making a decision that's similar to
actually getting married,
which is so the officer,
well I shouldn't call them out,
but google phase with the usual,
the usual ai research,
pretty high positions and the I'm a,
just something in me that says I the
edge,
the chaos of this environment and mit is
something I'm drawn to.
It doesn't make sense so I could do what
I'm passionate about on a lot of places.
You just kind of dive in.
Navis,
I had a sense that a lot of our culture
creates that momentum and you just kinda
have to go with it.
And that's why my parents got together
like a lot of people there probably.
I mean a lot of couples wouldn't be
together if they weren't kind of
culturally forced to be together in
divorce was such a negative thing and it
grew together and we created a super
happy connection.
So I'm a little afraid of over
rationality about choosing the path of
life.
So you're saying like monogamy or not
monogamy?
Relationship don't always make sense.
They don't have to make sense.
You know what,
I think I'm a big believer in doing what
you want to do and if you want to be
involved in a monogamous relationship,
I think you should do it,
but if you don't want to be involved
one,
I think you should do that too.
I mean,
if you want to be like a nomad and
travel around the world and just live
out of a backpack,
I don't think there's anything wrong
with that.
As long as you're healthy and you
survive and you're not depressed and
you're not longing for something that
you're not participating in,
but I think when you are doing
something,
you don't want to be doing it.
It brings me back to was it throws
quote.
I guess I was fuck up.
Who made this?
What?
I think I know you're most men live
lives of silent desperation.
That's.
That's real man.
That's real.
That's what you don't want.
I think it's thorough,
right?
You don't want silent desperation.
Yeah,
it is.
Right.
I fucking love that quote because I've
seen it.
I've seen it in so many people's faces
and that's one thing I've managed to
avoid and I dunno if I avoided that by
luck or just by fact I'm stupid and I
just,
I just follow my instincts whether
they're right or wrong or and I make it
work,
but this goes back to what we were
discussing when in terms of what is the
nature of reality and what are these,
are we just finding these romanticized
interpretations of our own biological
needs and our human reward systems
that's creating these beautiful visions
of what is life and what is important
poetry and food and music and all the
passions and dancing and holding someone
in your arms that you care for deeply
and all those things.
Just little tricks or all those little
biological tricks in order just to keep,
keep on this very strange dance of human
civilization so that we can keep on
creating new and better products that
keep on moving innovation towards this
ultimate eventual goal.
Artificial intelligence of this giving
birth to the gods.
Yeah.
Giving birth to the guns.
So,
you know,
I did want to mention one thing about,
uh,
the one thing I really,
I don't understand fully,
but I've been thinking about for the
last couple of years at the application
of artificial intelligence to,
into politics.
I've heard you talked about sort of a
government being broken in the sense
that one guy,
one president that doesn't make any
sense.
I see you,
you get like,
you know,
people get hundreds of millions of likes
on their facebook pictures and uh,
instagram and we're always voting with
our fingers every single day.
And yet for the election process it
seems that we're voting like once every
four years it feels like this new
technology could bring about a world
where the voice of the people can be
heard on a daily basis.
Like where you could speak about the
issues you care about,
whether it's gun control and abortion,
all of these topics that are.
So,
he so debated.
It feels like there needs to be an
instagram for elections.
I agree.
And I think there's room for that.
I've been thinking about how to write a
few papers are proposing different
technologies.
It just feels like the people that are
playing politics need to our old school
that is like the influencers,
right?
If you look at Instagram,
I mean,
should Nicki Minaj be able to decide how
the world works because she's got the
most followers.
Should Kim Kardashians,
like who's influencing things and why
and you have to deal with the fickle
nature of human beings and do we give
enough patients towards the decisions of
these so called leaders that we're
electing to adored you just decided fuck
them.
They're out new person in because we
have like a really short attention span
when it comes to think,
especially today with the new cycles so
quick,
so the same process.
So the instagram might be a bad example
because yeah,
you get or twitter and you start
following Donald Trump or and you start
to sort of idolize these certain icons
that do we necessarily want them to
represent us?
I was more thinking about the,
the Amazon product reviews model
recommender systems or Netflix,
the movies.
You've watched the Netflix learning
enough about you to represent you in
your next movie selection.
So in the kind of movies like what do
you like [inaudible] Joe Rogan,
what are the kinds of movies that you
would like the recommender systems,
these artificial intelligence systems
learn based on your netflix election
that could be deeper understanding of
who you are than you're even aware of.
And I think there's that element.
I'm not sure exactly,
but there's that element of learning who
you are like,
do you think drugs should be legalized
or not?
Like,
do you think?
I do think immigration,
should we let everybody in?
I'll keep everybody out.
Should we all.
All of these topics with a red and blue
teams now have a hard to answer.
Of course you keep all the immigrants
out or of course you need to be more
compassionate of course,
but for most people is really a gray
area and exploring gray area.
The way
you would explore the gray area of
Netflix.
What is the next movie or watching?
Do you want to watch the Little Mermaid
or a godfather?
To me,
what that process of understanding who
you are.
I just.
It feels like that there's room for that
in our other problem.
Home is of course that you have.
There's grave consequences to these
decisions that you're going to make in
terms of the way it affects the
community and you might not have any
information that you're basing this on
at all.
You might be basing all these decisions,
decisions on misinformation,
propaganda,
nonsense advertising.
You'll be easily influenced.
You might not have looked into it at
all.
You can be ignorant about the subject
and it might just appeal to certain
dynamics that have been programmed into
your brain because you grew up religious
or you grew up in an atheist or you
know.
The real problem is whether or not
people are educated about the
consequences of these decisions.
We're going to see information.
Yeah,
and then I think,
I mean,
I think there's going to be a time in
our,
in our life where our ability to access
information is many steps better than it
is now with smartphones.
I think we're going like Elon Musk has
some neuro link thing that he's working
on right now,
is being very vague about it.
Increase the bandwidth of our human
interaction with machines is what he's
worth.
Yeah.
I'm.
I'm very interested to see where this
leads,
but I think that we can assume that
because something like the Internet came
along and because it's so accessible to
you and I right now with your phone,
just pick it up,
say,
hey google,
what the fuck is this?
And then you get the.
You get the answer almost
instantaneously.
That's gonna change what a person is as
that advances and I think we're much
more likely looking at some sort of a
symbiotic connection between us and
artificial intelligence and computer
augmented access to information than we
are looking at the rise of some
artificial being that takes us over and
fucks are girlfriend.
Well yeah.
That's the real existential threat.
Yeah,
I think so.
That's to me is super exciting.
The phone is a portal to this collective
that we have this collective
consciousness and it gives people a
voice.
I would say if anyone's like me,
you really know very little about a
politicians you're voting for,
or even the issues like global warming.
I'm embarrassed to say I like,
I know very little about it,
like if I'm actually being honest with
myself,
I've heard different,
like I know what I'm supposed to believe
as a scientist but actually know nothing
about concrete and not nothing concrete
about process about the va,
the environmental process.
And why is it so certain scientists
apparently completely agree.
So as a scientist,
um,
I kinda take on faith oftentimes what
the community agrees in my own
discipline I question,
but outside I just kind of take on faith
and the same thing with a gun control
and so on.
You just kind of say which team of my
own.
And I'm just going to take that on.
I just feel like it's such a disruptive
space to where people could be given
just a tiny bit more information to help
them.
Well maybe that's where something like
neuro link comes along.
It just enhances our ability to access
this stuff in a way that's much more
just more tangible than just being able
to google search it and maybe this,
this process is something that we really
can't anticipate.
It's going to have to happen to us.
Just like what we're talking about,
cell phone images that you could just
send to Australia with the click of a
button that no one would have ever
anticipated that 300 years ago.
Maybe we are beyond our.
Our capacity for understanding the
impact of all of this stuff.
Maybe kids coming up now.
What is that world going to look like
when you're too old to be sitting?
You'll be like 95 sitting on a porch
with a shotgun cleaning swing and what
do those kids look like when they're 18
years old?
Robots fucking x Ray vision and they
could read minds.
Yeah,
well yoga is going to happen.
They'd be saying,
robots are everywhere these days.
Back back in my day,
we used to put robots in their place.
They were serving.
Shut them off and now fuck your mom.
Now they want to go to the same school
as us.
Yeah.
And they want to.
They want to run for president.
You know,
they want to run for president.
Yeah.
They're more compassionate and smarter,
but we still hate them because they
don't go to the bathroom.
Yeah.
Well now we half the country,
look at them and the other love them and
Abraham Lincoln character will come
along.
That's what I'm pitching myself.
I'm telling you,
you Lincoln of the robot world of the
robot world,
that's the speeches that everybody
quotes in.
One other thing I got to say about
academia.
Okay?
In defense of academia,
so you've had a lot of really smart
people on including Sam Harris and uh,
Jordan Peterson.
And often the word academia is used to
replace a certain concept.
So I'm part of academia and most of
academia is engineering is biology,
is medicine is hard sciences.
The humanities that are slippery.
Exactly in humanity.
And I think a subset of humanities that
I know nothing about.
And there a subset.
I don't want to speak about gender
studies.
Say it.
I don't know man.
Candy man.
I actually live on Harvard campus,
so I go to mit,
but I live on Harvard campus and yet is
there.
They have apartments for you guys.
How does that work?
Yeah,
they hand them out as.
No,
I just,
I don't care to live on the campus.
What do you mean?
Uh,
sorry.
Like in Harvard Square.
Oh,
Harvard Square in Cambridge and
Cambridge.
Yeah.
So I,
I used go to catch a rising
star when it existed.
They used to be a great comedy club in
Cambridge.
There's a few.
There's a few good comedy clubs there.
Right.
Well there's a Chinese restaurant that
uh,
that has stand up there still.
How does that work?
Well,
it's upstairs.
There's like this,
a comedy club up there.
Yeah.
Do you ever,
ever,
because you've done your specialist in
Boston?
Yes,
I did.
At the Wilbur theater.
Have you ever considered just going back
to Boston and doing like that Chinese
restaurant?
The Ding Ho?
Yeah.
That was before my time when I came
around.
I started in 1988.
The Ding Ho had already ended,
but I,
you know,
I got to be friends with guys like Lenny
Clarke and Tony v and all these people
that told me about the ding ho and Kenny
Rogers and the comics that were in Barry
Crimmins who just passed away rest in
peace,
uh,
who was really the Godfather,
that whole scene and one of the major
reasons why that scene was so had such
really some rock solid morals and ethics
when it came to the creation of material
and standards.
It was a lot of it was barry crimmins
because he was just a,
that's just who he was as a person,
you know.
Um,
but that was before my time.
I came around when I came around like
four years after that stuff.
And so there was tons of comedy clubs.
It was everywhere,
but I just didn't get a chance to be
around that.
Uh,
that Ding Ho scene.
And you stayed in Boston for how many
before you moved out here?
I was in New York in a,
by the time I think I was in New York by
90 to 91.
Ninety two.
So it was in Boston for four or five
years doing stand up.
How'd you get to from Boston to New
York?
Met My match on Wendy's.
This opportunity for you to talk about.
What about Connecticut gets upset at me.
It's become a running theme to talk Shit
About Connecticut or I've heard you do a
ones.
I just had a buddy who did a Gig in
Connecticut.
He told me was fucking horrible.
I go,
I told you,
bitch should've listened to me.
Don't book gigs and Connecticut Fuck's
wrong with you?
This 49 other states.
But that's great.
You go back to Boston and do like small
gigs.
Small and sometimes.
Yeah,
I'll do.
Um,
yeah,
laugh.
Boston is a great club.
I used to do nick's comedy stop and all
the other ones there.
But I,
I,
you know,
I love the Wilbert Wilbert is a great
place to perform.
I Love Boston.
I would live there if it wasn't so
fucking cold in the winter.
But that's what keeps people like me
out.
Keeps the pussy
right.
Listen,
we got to end this.
We got to wrap it up.
We've already done three hours flies by
it.
Did it flew by A.
Can I say to?
Sure.
So first I got to give a shout out to my
shout out.
Shout out CEO,
a long,
long time friend Matt.
Her Randy from Chicago has been there
all along.
He's a of the podcast,
so he's probably listening.
Um,
him and his wife had just had a
beautiful baby girl.
So I want to just send my love to him
and I told myself I'll ended this way.
Okay,
let me end it the way he ended it.
Love is the answer.
Love is.
The answer is probably is unless you're
a robot.
Bye.