Hello Freak bitches,
but marijuana stays in your system
because it's fat soluble way longer,
like seven weeks.
Whereas,
um,
with coke it's a couple of fucking days.
I didn't tell you my marijuana story
when I came home from a dance club.
One night is right after it.
This before I started doing comedy.
He's living in Malden,
Granada highlands,
up on the hill there.
Those are nice.
But yeah,
I come up in the palace,
a palace and Sagas.
Yes.
We lived like a half a mile from it.
Okay.
I come home,
my buddies all went out.
Shit faced is the thing that tomato
sauce and it's like one in the morning
and I'm starving.
I make spaghetti.
I eat enough for like five people.
Okay.
I wake up like an hour later and my ears
are ringing in the rooms going like
this.
I started puking,
puking,
violently.
I hit my buddies,
come in,
I'm in the bathroom.
I hear them go into the kitchen.
They go,
he ate all the fuck.
They made Rasta Pasta loaded with and,
and they,
they ate this much of it.
They said they like a,
you know,
a tiny amount,
they will fucked up all night and this
is a guy who I only get high at that
point a couple of times in my life and
that now my roommate's talking to me.
Right.
He's right where you at?
He's like five feet away,
but it sounds like he's yelling from a
mile away.
I was tripping on the fucking they were
going to take.
They didn't know if they should take me
to the hospital,
not fucking puking.
I'm swearing at him and,
and,
and honest about it.
It was a week later,
I remember watching the superbowl and
still being fucked up
because it's so,
like you just said when you went,
when you ingested orally,
it's way stronger and,
and,
and it,
it little reason my system.
I don't know how long.
I mean,
you know,
you can look it up,
but I,
and this is from somebody who didn't.
I didn't smoke a lot of weed.
That's crazy.
Week later.
Oh,
at least a weekly.
No,
at least I'm probably being conservative
with that because it stays in.
If you saw how much I ate,
you know,
if you saw how much tomato sauce,
such a grease ball and,
and uh,
and they will like,
they will fucked up all night with this
much and they were like,
oh no,
you're making of the fingers like a
hockey puck.
Forget I'm not on TV.
But yeah,
about half the size of a hockey.
But I was sitting there like,
you know,
and my ears were ringing and they would
like I said,
my roommate's like that close to me and
it sounded like he was yelling down the
hallway.
It's interesting because as we talk
about this and we've talked a lot about
the damage guys,
because we've gone through all the
various techniques,
you know,
after you had,
a discussion with Brendan Schaub.
A lot of people came out and they
started saying,
hey,
should we feel bad for talking about
this sport?
And I,
and I've heard that conversation again,
you know,
at what point should we feel guilty for
watching guys?
We know our aging fighters and you know,
you could do the same thing with
football.
You can certainly do the same thing in
the military where there there's a lot
of traumatic brain injuries taking place
in the military as well.
One thing that I think people forget in
that I think people need to understand.
It's not to excuse anything or take away
from the conversation.
It's,
it's a little bit of a mitigation.
The,
the men and women who do sports like
this,
if you take it away from them,
they're going to find it elsewhere.
I mean,
it's,
it's a need.
You know,
for a guy like me had I not found mixed
martial arts,
I was going to find something.
There's,
there's like,
there's drive inside us to do something
extreme that makes people raise their
eyebrows and say,
are you sure you want it?
You really are going to do that.
They have that,
that desire,
and it's just a personality trait.
I mean,
if,
if mixed martial arts didn't exist,
I mean look at cowboy cerrone,
the things he does to,
to fill that hole in his life and you're
going to get a lot of guys.
That's why guys don't want to retire.
It's just part of who they are.
We all know the risks.
We all know everything we're up against.
We still sign the contract,
and so it's important to remind them
that if you know for people that are
anti this and anti that,
you know,
we're going to do something like that
anyways,
we're going to find something else to do
and at some point we've got to be
accountable for our own actions.
Well,
there's a wide variety of human beings.
There's always going to be sedentary.
People that sit in their couch is going
to be people who want to fucking rock
climb with no ropes.
My friend already went back to the flip
phone.
He goes,
no,
our fear stand up.
Comedian,
he defended his iphone and went to a
flip phone,
went off.
He does all of his social media stuff
either on a computer or not.
He doesn't check his twitter on his
phone.
His.
He's like,
I was getting too wrapped up in like I
would be talking to someone that goes to
this guy.
I want to finish
sleep last night on like literally the,
my iphone hit my forehead three times
and I finally gave up because I was
like,
what the fuck am I going to post?
Yeah,
another concussion,
you know,
I'm like,
I'm looking at.
I don't think it's spelled correctly and
it's probably like a bunch of weird
wingding character or something that
brings me back.
So what I was going to say is like
there's,
there's something about iphones that
drag people in,
right?
There's something about like being able
to look at videos and you're,
you're interacting with your phone.
Yeah.
The interaction that you get with those
old cars,
the field that you get,
the addiction that you get to get in
those things is very different than the
new cars.
And is there.
And I wanted to ask you this because
you're the expert on those older cars,
but is there like a point where it
crosses this line and it's not the same
experience anymore?
And was there like a sweet spot in the
production of cars?
Whereas we're there a spot where all the
technological advances and all the
advances of suspension,
although they may allow you to get
around a race track a little bit
quicker,
especially with like PDK transmissions
with dual clutch is working at the same
time.
They do allow you to get places faster,
but is it,
is it missing all the stuff that gets
people excited about cars.
I mean because I know that driving an
automatic car is fun.
It is satisfying,
but I also know it's not as satisfying
as shifting your own gears as the field
that you're going to get from a car like
yours.
And I think that that's something that's
missing.
I think ultimately moving forward the
manual may become a lost art because you
love kids growing up today that don't
know how to drive manual cars.
So the point of reference is completely,
you know,
most of us here I think learn driving a
manual car and everything that you said
is perfectly true.
That a see interaction between man and
machine,
which gets you down the road differently
in a manual than what it does in a new
car.