Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Hey everybody.
It's Joe Rogan and this is my podcast and
this is the new way I'm going to do my
commercial now because I can't keep
saying it the same fucking way,
but it turns into a regular way.
Halfway through it.
I,
somewhere along the line I give up.
I always give up.
Our podcast is sponsored by on it,
which is essentially a,
a,
a vitamin supplement and fitness company.
Uh,
it's a company that,
uh,
I am a part of.
I own a part of the company.
The reason being that,
uh,
I got involved in it and I believe in
the ethics of the company and I believe
what they're selling,
we are selling the best quality nutrients.
Some of them are nootropics,
some of them are sports
exercise ones like shroom tech,
sport Alpha brain is the,
uh,
the famous nootropic one.
We also sell hemp protein
powder with Maca and raw cocoa.
It's fucking fantastic stuff.
Kettle bells and battle ropes.
It's all essentially fitness and like
lifestyle and health supplements and a,
it's all stuff that I believe in.
It's all stuff that I've
always been taking like long
before I ever got involved
in this company.
So,
um,
if you,
uh,
if you're interested in it,
if you're interested in nootropics,
a very controversial area.
Good.
I want you to go,
just go to Google and just Google
the word nootropics and Oh,
tro pic.
It's all about supplementation to
enhance your brain's ability to produce
neurotransmitters.
It's all very complicated stuff.
And fucking I need a retard like me
should not be really talking about it
because I don't really
know what I'm saying.
You know what I'm saying?
I'm just like repeating
scientific shit that,
but I believe that if you believe in it,
I actually would take
that to heart because you,
you actually don't really,
I mean,
I don't know.
You're fine,
but you don't seem like
you need a lot of money.
You are on a network hosted in
network TV show for a lot of years.
You were a star talk radio,
news radio and everything.
I'm also an idiot.
I could've spent that money.
I could've right through that shit.
Yeah.
He's got Gold Buddhas.
I would never get involved with
anything that I don't believe in.
I just wouldn't,
I don't have,
I don't have another life to live.
Just I've got one and while
I'm already ahead and I'm,
you know,
I'm not,
uh,
I'm not worried about paying my
bills and everything's going well.
The last thing on overdue is get involved
in anything that I didn't really,
that's not true though because I did
do fear factor again for another term.
But you've got to really,
I really liked those guys and I worked
with does produce and I would be sick if
I saw somebody else doing it.
I really would have that even
though that show was retarded.
That was my baby.
I did 148 of those fucking things.
Um,
but uh,
there's no way I would be involved in a
compliment company unless I believed in
it and everything that we sell it on,
it was all stuff that I use in my daily
life that I've talked about long before
I got involved in this company especially,
which I feel are the,
the best,
uh,
as far as like strength and conditioning.
If I had to pick one exercise,
I think kettlebells is like the best
piece of exercise equipment that you can
have.
It's like a cannon ball
that's got a handle on it and
it's all about controlling
this fucking cannon ball and they
come in a bunch of different sizes.
I use sometimes as light is 35 pounds,
sometimes 50 pounds,
sometimes 70 pounds and they give you
amazing workouts to rectally apply to
Jujitsu for me,
but for any athletic endeavor where you
would have realized on explosiveness and
and and muscle power and it's all
exercises that make your body move as one
complete unit as opposed to like isolation
exercises was a lot of people do at
the gym.
When you see them lifting weights,
this is something where your entire body,
like there's things called Turkish
getups will you hold this weight up,
your mind and your back and
then you slowly and controlled
the stand all the way
up to your feet and then bring
it all the way back down.
It's a really odd thing you would think,
but it's really applicable for like
strength and fitness in real world.
A athletic pursuits and even
just for picking shit up,
and even if just for having a strong body,
it's better to have a strong body
than a weak ass bitch body there.
I said it
all right.
Unless you date like
girls are like bisexual,
they tend to like the bitch body.
Look,
Dave really liked that too.
For or bisexual.
They're like,
like a guy that's not guy like,
right.
That's too much of a gamble.
I secret.
Yeah.
G's going to gamble for a niche market.
I see.
You could probably get them
anyway if you bulked up,
Eh,
I don't know.
Anyway,
if supplements go to go to on a.com,
use the code name Brogan and you will
save 10% off any and all the supplements,
um,
the kettle bells in the battle ropes,
that shit does not work on.
We saw them as cheap as we can in there.
You know,
especially with the kettle bells,
it's very difficult.
It's like you're sending
cannon balls through the mail,
but there is durables.
Fuck.
And there'll be here forever.
All right.
That's it.
Mike Birbiglia is here.
Birbiglia excuse me,
Mike.
Birbiglia
fucking house.
Try my day.
Joe Rogan podcast.
My all,
sorry.
Commercials are brutal.
Okay.
Interesting.
To me though,
it's like something that I've not,
I've never investigated.
I've always just kept at arm's distance
that kind of neutral the nutrients and
the vitamins and things like that.
I've just had,
I don't understand it.
I'm not going to go near it.
But you and I've listened
and watched this podcast.
You seem to know a good bit about it.
Well,
um,
I know my,
from my personal experience,
it makes a big difference for me.
What I eat,
if I like,
if I really concentrated on
like the most important thing,
I think a is nutrients from food.
That's the most important thing.
You've got to eat healthy food and then
supplementation on top of that you have
to have the actual news.
So what'd you eat for lunch today?
Uh,
this morning I had a hemp protein shake.
I only ate once,
just had a hemp protein
shake with a banana,
banana,
coconut oil and I had two
cigarettes and coconut water.
Yeah,
no,
I,
I don't eat,
I don't need heavy in the mornings.
A really light in the morning and you
should use to just have a shake or have a
Kale shake.
That's my most common thing that I have.
I'm just,
if I'm lazy or if I'm
running out the door,
I don't have time to make it,
but it takes a few minutes to make.
It's,
I have to clean the Kale and clean celery
and cucumbers and then I take chunks
of ginger and raw garlic and
it was a thing called day fuck.
What was the name of the blender?
It's this bad ass blender,
but it's specifically
designed for this purpose.
It's got like a plunger and
you shove everything in there.
Vitamix.
But Vitamix.
Yes.
That is it.
Thank you.
And uh,
it,
it fucking whips it down to
like a drinkable consistency.
He put like pineapple in it
to make it taste good and uh,
it's fucking great man.
It doesn't taste that good.
But for your body it's great.
You know,
it gives you just like this
charge of like good stuff.
It's like your body knows it's got
all these nutrients to work with,
but isn't this inherent
contradiction with,
cause I know that you're,
you know,
you do the ultimate fighting,
uh,
stuff.
Yeah.
Is that what it is?
Ultimately it's called the
ultimate fighting championship,
but that seems to be people murdering
people like other people slamming all,
you're making it so that your
health is no longer a possibility.
You can look at it that way and
then that is certainly part of it,
but it would,
it also is,
is competition in the highest
and most dramatic form.
Sure.
That a human being can see other than war.
Right.
The way the Olympics is.
I mean,
it's not that healthiest thing
to be an Olympic gymnast.
Yeah.
Maybe.
But this is even worse because this
is another person dominating you.
You know,
the idea of losing and gymnastics is,
you know,
I'm sure a cruel bitch after years and
years of practice and you slip when you
land,
but it's nothing like
getting your ass kicked.
Yeah.
There's nothing like getting just the
fuck beat out of you in front of the
world.
And there's the emotions that are involved
in of control to where the place to
look is to look at the very,
very best guys.
If you look at the very like
the guys like Anderson Silva,
you know,
he's this insanely good fighter.
It's insanely good,
but such a nice guy,
like a sweetheart of a guy,
always laughing and always joking.
He's just controlled all of his demons
and all of his bullshit with like the
most intense form of competition,
physically available.
This is a lot going on
that people don't see.
They see people just
kicking people's asses.
It's not just that there's,
there's a whole side to like the killer.
We are,
I'm not even kidding.
I swear people will say I'm from,
you're from worse bags is,
I think there was a gig there.
I think that's why I'm remembering it.
I think it was one of
those Boston comedy gigs.
Did you ever work for Boston
comedy?
Oh yeah.
Yeah,
yeah,
yes.
Yeah.
I grew up driving by the [inaudible]
cuckoo where it would say comedy night and
yeah.
Was that a little,
how many stop?
Yeah.
Is it still in Nick's comedy star?
I don't know actually.
And then there's the
giggles out there and saw,
that's Mike Clark.
Great Pizza Place.
Oh yeah.
Pizza's great.
And it's right next door.
She sits pizzas.
Very underrated.
It's Greek pizza.
It's good giggles.
Was a great gig.
Mike Clark is Linny Clark's brother.
Yeah.
Fucking great.
Nice guy.
Yeah,
he's the best.
But we had three in my town,
Shrewsbury.
Very small town.
We had,
I had four pizzerias within a half mile.
Shewsbury pizzeria,
village B,
three,
a dean park and white city.
I thought that Massachusetts piece,
it was really good until
I moved back to New York.
And then I had to realize there's
a few places like in Yonkers,
there's a place in White Plains,
Nicky's Nicky's pizzeria.
They have a white pizza
that it's so fucking good.
I got to check.
How come they can't
make this anywhere else?
Like why is this not in California?
There's a,
we have a,
in our,
in my movie sleepwalk with me,
the,
there's a pizza pillow is
a pillow made of pizza,
uh,
as a prop.
And it was done by Roberta's,
which is in Brooklyn and is fantastic.
Checkout Roberta's if you can.
Yeah,
there's some like legit old school,
New York pizzerias.
It just can't be fucked
with their artisans.
Arturo's on Houseton it's like that.
There's a lot of them,
a lot of them.
If there was a cause like that,
I just remember a place in Yonkers,
I don't even remember the name of it,
but my friend used to know like the,
it was like his,
his buddy's dad bran it for,
you know,
a hundred years and uh,
it just was ridiculously good.
Thin crust pizza or it's like
this is just some weird place.
Like you look on the outside,
this is right.
If everybody knew about this,
it'd be a fucking mile long line.
I mean you go to that pink's hot dogs.
Isn't that the craziest
thing you've ever seen?
Yeah.
Cause they cook the hot dogs
at night or outside rather.
It's just this giant line of people
who are basically waiting to get,
I'm very mediocre hot dog.
Yeah.
But this pizza,
I love that phrase.
If everybody knew about it,
that's like,
that's like the thing that
they say in advertising rooms.
Like if we could just get
everyone to know about,
there's some shit like that
that just sneaks through.
Like we all know comics like
that that have just snow.
Yeah.
If everybody knew.
No for,
I mean,
who knows yours?
No,
Brian Holtzman for sure.
No doubt.
Brian holds right.
Holtzmann has made me laugh
harder saying inappropriate,
ridiculously inappropriate
shit than anyone.
Well,
that's how I feel.
I mean I'm talking about somebody talking
about Brody starting to get a little
famous though.
A lot of people know Brody now.
I'm talking about something pretty famous,
but,
but I feel like Stan hope it's like
that to that extent where it's like,
yeah,
he's very famous.
He has a big following,
but like if people saw live his,
his 90 minutes he puts on it,
people would be like,
oh,
that's the best comedian alive.
Yeah,
he's doing what I love
to watch as a comedian,
as a comedian.
He was like in me and I had
a conversation about it too.
It's like one of the things,
as you get older,
you really appreciate guys that are
still doing real fucking comedy.
There's still saying
what they really think.
Yeah.
So because somewhere along the line,
I mean,
we,
we're not,
we're not naming names,
but another one,
he's the one who told me to come here.
Anyway,
we're at the comedy cellar.
We were talking about
podcasts and he goes,
have you ever listened to Rogan's podcast?
And I go,
no.
He goes,
it's incredible.
You got to,
you got to go on.
It's incredible.
And so then I started listening to it
and then I just dropped you a note.
Oh,
that's awesome.
I Love Norton Norton and I
went to see dice in Vegas.
We went and sat in the audience,
Norton and I and Bobby
Kelly and Brian and uh,
Anthony Cool.
Mia and Sam Roberts.
We all went there,
drove a big fucking limo together.
We all had dinner.
It was like a gentleman's night is great.
It was fun.
We ate a steak house and
then we all went to a show.
That's fine.
Oh yeah.
Well,
yeah,
I did that with me.
Yeah,
I did that.
I'm going to counter that with a
much a Dorky or version of that,
which is,
uh,
my wife and I,
my wife and I and Ira Glass who
co wrote my film and his wife,
the four of us went to see Stan hope
at Caroline's comedy showing cause it's
cause Ira had never seen Stan hope.
And I was like,
he got to see this guy.
There's nothing like him.
Yeah.
I loved,
I loved dog.
And then of course Doug,
when he finds out IRA's there,
makes fun of IRA,
makes fun of public radio
for like 15 minutes.
And uh,
and I was like,
Ha,
you know,
becoming about me.
I just want to go see
a show or listen man,
if you're on national public radio,
it becomes about you,
you a few in your room
if you were in the room.
It's just,
that is a silly topic.
They do not have loved
to have any emotions.
Everything has to be
talking about it like this.
Completely unreasonable.
But Irish shows incredible.
It's very different.
Is it different this American life?
Have you ever listened to it?
Never.
Oh,
you'd love it.
Really is incredible.
It is.
Aye.
It's funny,
I've never had to sell it to anybody
before because people will listen to it so
much,
but like it's like,
um,
I've seen it in the
radio [inaudible] radio.
It's a,
it's a weekly radio documentary.
Imagine your favorite film documentary
and take that to radio and it's,
it's incredible what they do.
It's like a fucking miracle.
It's a fucking miracle.
You wouldn't,
you personally would love it,
dude.
I'm,
I'm on it.
I'll get on it today.
[inaudible] dot com
you should go on there.
Did you go on their website?
I'm saying look at like,
they have like a list of like
these are the legendary episodes,
the gateway drug gateway
drug of this American life.
Yeah.
Oh,
that's a good idea.
And say I like the episodes
that you guys should have that.
Yeah,
I'm lazy dude.
Where are you on that?
Where are you guys on that?
What's that?
We just put them up there,
but this is a lot of websites.
It's sort them out.
We can only do so much,
but you can only sit behind.
We're doing like three and
four of these a week sometimes.
Yeah.
Lately it's been for,
you know,
like we do,
like we did,
we're doing three together and I
did one yesterday with Brian Cowen,
just me and Brian and Paul
[inaudible] is another one,
by the way.
Comedian,
you might not know,
but it's fucking hilarious.
Hilarious.
Ridiculous.
Yeah.
He came over my house last night
and we had a little family barbecue.
It was fun.
Yeah,
he's nice.
He's just such a silly boy.
Yeah,
absolutely.
He's so fucking silly.
He's such a fun dude.
And Norton,
if people know,
I love that phrase.
If people knew about this,
Norton is a a guy,
even though everybody knows it
from the opie and Anthony Show,
and there's not enough people that know
how funny he has a standard stand up.
I saw him in Austin,
I was in town doing a UFC and I just,
I,
you know,
another thing,
I got a chance to just
sit down and watch a gig.
Oh yeah.
It was really,
it's really fun.
It's fun.
Yeah.
And especially if it's a guy like Norton.
He made me change my act a little bit.
Really?
Yeah.
Because I realized I was
doing a lot too long sets.
I like,
I did,
I wanted to do like these really long
sets because I didn't want anybody to feel
like they didn't get their money's worth.
But Norton did like an hour
and just fucking laid it down.
And I was like,
you know what I mean,
maybe that's a better thing.
Maybe.
So I cut my sets down from like an hour
and a half plus to like an hour and 10
minutes because I feel like nobody talk
for more than an hour and 10 minutes.
Man.
When I started working the door,
I started out working the
door at the DC improv.
And what does that,
that's his stupid clock.
Yeah,
he's going to fucking cat clock.
No,
that's not a distraction,
dude.
You're right.
Nobody has shown the door
at the DC Improv and it was,
and it was really like comedy
college cause I was opening for like,
you know,
every week you're like Jake Johansen,
Brian Regan,
right.
You know,
Mitch Hedberg,
Dave a towel,
you know,
and uh,
and Pablo Francisco.
Oh,
that's a lesson in comedy.
You watch him.
He's another,
if people knew about it.
Yeah.
What up alive Pablo Francisco
shows like he does back then,
at least the week I opened
farm did 45 minutes,
blew the doors off the room
in a way that I never seen.
Like I've never seen anything like that.
Pablo doesn't just do a comedy show.
It's like a multimedia presentation.
It's because he can make so many crazy
noises with his mouth and he has so many
nutty impressions of people.
It's like a multimedia
presentation sometimes.
He's somebody who if you,
if he really opened up and,
and did some personal stuff combined with
the talent that he has with the noises
and the sounds,
everything,
I don't think he can.
Oh Wow.
Would that be a good show?
Yeah.
It would be a very
good show.
Be something else.
Yeah.
He's a great guy too.
Probably my sisters.
That's one of the coolest things about
comedy is that a lot of people like
assume that every comic
has fucked up and that,
you know,
so many of them are antisocial and
depressed and I don't find that to be the
case.
I find to be the case.
It's like,
well,
there's a lot of funny guys like
Stan Hope they're fun to be around.
They're nice guys.
I love what Stan Hope said when there
was that whole comedy school debate
happening.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
I'll see something.
And just that he's going to have a
free one and in bids be their lives.
I just love that he's just like,
everybody's just show up
just to bring some drinks.
Like Stan hopes,
all things.
Just like you learn about comedy,
like offering the comedian you're
opening for drinks after the show.
Just asking questions.
That is a better way to learn.
I think that's how I learned.
I um,
I have a real problem with a comedy
classes that are taught by people or non
comedians.
I've seen that and I'm like,
that's just craziness.
That's like,
that doesn't even make sense.
That's like English speaking taught
by people who don't speak English,
like,
yeah,
if you don't,
if you haven't actually
done standup and you,
you have to do it for years,
he'd have to,
you have to get your dick kicked
into the dirt numerous occasions,
you know?
I mean,
don't you think that
made you as a comedian,
really tough sets in the beginning he
kind of realized what you got to do to
fix.
Yeah.
That's what my entire movie is about.
Just about just failure,
failure and failure and
then finding at the end,
the movie,
the character has just kind of want,
you see one sequence of,
oh,
this guy's going to figure it out.
Eventually.
I think we all like started off terrible.
I don't,
I've never met anybody
that started off good.
No,
I think it's a,
for me,
like I worked,
I always tell people I'll,
comedians or PR people
want to be Comedians,
get a job at a comedy club.
I worked at the DC Improv at the door
and then after I punched out from making
minimum wage,
I got to watch the show
for free and that's,
that's what you need.
You just need to see comedians over and
over and over again and go eventually
go,
okay,
I can,
I can do something like that.
It's a weird thing when you figure that
when you start to realize that it's a
craft,
but that yours is mine.
It seems like it's kind of
similar to other people's,
but it's not.
It's,
it's your weird take on shit and you
got to find out what the fuck that is.
You got to find the silly find the
preposterous Yassic so long man.
And you'd get conflicted and you
don't know if you're being foolish.
Shit,
am I being is,
is this an effected attitude
that I'm putting on?
Is it obvious?
Yeah.
When I was starting out,
I was totally putting on an athlete.
I hate that because it's so embarrassing.
It is embarrassing because
I looked back on those sets.
Well,
no,
cause I was in,
everybody does though.
I mean,
I even like Geraldo was one of my
favorite comedians of all time and was a
friend of mine and like he even said like,
he's like when I started
out like my first TV sets,
I sounded like Dave Attell.
I was on TV sounding like somebody else
before I figured out who I was.
And then he,
I mean,
I think Geraldo is one
of the great comics,
but like for me it was just,
I sounded like it sounded like Steven,
right.
Want to start out.
Then I sounded like Mitch Hedberg and
then eventually it sounded like myself.
Yeah,
it's hard to avoid,
man.
It's hard to avoid being like really
influenced by the guys that you know came
before you that were really good.
I caught myself sounding like
rich Jenny on stage ones.
Really just almost exactly.
It was like so,
such an obvious rip off the guy.
I was in the middle of a set like I did.
I kept going with the bit
and I finished my set,
like the audience didn't
even know to myself.
I was like,
Ooh,
you fraud.
Yeah.
I was like,
you fucking rich.
Jenny clone,
what are you doing?
Like a year ran or something like that,
you know,
but I'll never forget like how
embarrassing it was that if I like,
it was like if I was in the
room and I saw me on stage,
I be like,
Ooh,
who's this guy ripping off rich?
Cause he know this when you
know when guys will do that,
whether it's you're not
even ripping off material,
you just rip it off.
Being that guy.
Yeah.
People said that.
I had that with Steven,
right.
Mitch Hedberg and then inadvertently
Todd Barry people were like,
you sound like Todd Barry.
And I was like,
I'm not even watching.
I mean I liked Highbury lot.
He's a great comic.
But it wasn't like I was watching
a ton of top area at that time.
Well I think you just have a similar
tone to your voice and it's only mildly
Sam,
but people are crazy.
They'll find connections.
Yeah.
Fucking anything.
I got off stage once in Kentucky and
some guy came up to me with a list of
people.
It's like,
he said,
you know,
Patton Oswald this.
I go,
what are you talking about?
He goes,
you sounded like these people.
And I was like,
listen man,
I don't know what to tell you.
Did you have a good time?
You're looking at,
what are you saying?
You saying that I'm not me and then I've,
I've,
I'm,
I'm all of these people that's like,
what are you saying?
That's fine.
And there was a bunch of
[inaudible] to have a good time.
Yeah.
That's all I can say to him.
Listen,
I hope you had a good
time at the comedy show.
Crazy.
I to sit here and you're going to
analyze who my influences were and you're
angry at me for being
influenced by great comedians.
But I don't even think that's what it was.
I think it was like,
you know,
the people will try to find a
connection in anything they oh yeah.
You know,
when I listened to my recording
after the guy said that to me,
cause I was like,
what the fuck is this guy?
He like,
it was,
there was a couple of weeks
cure obscure ones in there too.
I don't remember who his references were,
but it was like,
like Richard Lewis was one
of them and I was like,
what do you,
what the fuck are you even saying?
And I went and listened to it
and I didn't hear any of it.
Somebody Wolf if they're looking and then
there's people that just are crazy and
their perceptions are just off and they'll
get a thought in their head and they
don't have the ability to discern
whether or not it's an objective thought,
whether or not it's a reasonable thought.
They just got that thought
and they fucking run with it.
And it with you.
They're like Todd Barry
sounds like Todd Barry.
Well it's funny
cause I,
I the person I listened to him the most,
it was woody Allen but no one ever
accuses me of sounding like Woody Allen
because I'm like a suburban white kid
grown up and he's this short Jewish man
from New York City and we just don't
look like each other in any way,
shape or form.
I think people who don't
make that connection.
Sure.
So do you feel like you were
influenced and delivery wise?
Yeah.
Realize what a great comic he was.
He's incredible.
That one album,
that one album,
which is a compilation
of I think three records.
Um,
he's in crazy woody
Allen's standup comedian,
I think it's called and it's so good.
What a Weird Guy,
Huh?
I mean married his daughter
in front of the world.
God is intensely weird,
is hard.
That is intense.
Intensely and super hot.
Awesome.
Is she super hot and
it's kind of super hot.
Awesome.
Oh Man,
I don't,
I don't see it.
I can't get behind the super
crazy creepy man.
Yeah.
I mean how did they ever even
develop that kind of a relationship?
That doesn't make any sense to me.
It seems to me like that
should never be able to happen.
It shouldn't be on the table.
Yeah.
Not One of the options.
And I wonder what the blow back
was for him for Woody Allen,
this great director in his career.
It was a big blow back there.
There are people,
cause I'm such a big fan of his,
there are people who I
talked to to this day who go,
once that happened,
I will not see his movies.
Yeah.
There's a lot of people,
I've heard that from a,
especially from women,
from women particularly.
Yeah.
Well the,
you know,
it's almost like you can't
trust them around your kids.
Like that's the,
that's the feeling that they get.
It's like he'll,
he's God,
he's just going to shoot,
he's not at the movie theater.
He's not at the movie theater
with you see the movies.
So you don't have to be
worried about their kids.
People that just won't,
they won't support you after,
like what,
what's the guy's name
that escaped to France?
Oh yeah.
Roman Polanski,
one of my favorite directors.
And he was,
yeah,
he was convicted of that horrible crime.
Yeah.
What did he do?
He wasn't convicted because he fled.
Right.
I'm,
it was,
he was,
he was drugged a teenage
girl and had sex with,
or something like that.
But then there's this whole,
there's this whole documentary
about that case called,
I think it's called wanted.
And,
um,
and it,
it shows the shades of gray.
In that case,
that case was really complex
and there was like a,
there was a judge who was really high
and mighty and kind of like got carried
away about his or her own ego
and how the judge him or herself,
I forget what it was,
was making headlines by saying certain
things in the cord and then it became
like a spectacular event where he might
have gotten like a year in jail or
something,
but then it got kind of
blown out of proportion.
It was going to be a big,
much bigger deal.
Yeah.
It's a really good movie actually.
I think it was on Hbo.
It's called,
wanted,
wanted.
It's like Roman Polanski
wanted or something like that.
In this case,
this is really disturbing man.
And then this is after his wife
had been murdered by the man.
So you got to realize like
this guy was a lot going on.
I mean what he did was
horrific for sure though.
But his,
I mean,
what has what a fucked up state of mind
he had to have been in after his wife
was murdered by the Manson
family while she was pregnant.
I,
I have to say like I being weird
shit happens in California.
Like I feel like the philanthropy stuff,
I'm just like,
when I watch it,
it feels so distant from
my existence in New York.
I'm like,
yeah,
that's some California shit
that I can't understand.
Do you like living in New York?
I love it.
Yeah.
I live in the city.
My wife and I lived in the city for a
while and then we just moved to Brooklyn
recently moved to Brooklyn,
get some space,
you know,
just like we were sick of living
in this little cramped area.
Oh see you have a bigger place.
Yeah,
we have like,
yeah,
we have a few bedrooms and it's,
and we're able to and also just walk
around and have some trees around.
We lived on the upper west
side in Manhattan and it
was like getting to a point
where our favorite,
like local restaurants were closing down.
H and h bagels closed down.
Nico's clothing,
a Greek restaurant closed down like
a lot of places were closing down.
Like to the point where like they closed
that this is a bad side of like when
times are bad.
We thought it was sad
when they closed down.
Barnes and noble,
like we were like,
oh that's too bad.
Our local bookstore got
shut down the circuit city.
I felt like we lost a circuit city
to the last one in this common man.
It's,
I mean think about it in our lifetime,
when,
has there ever been a period of time
where more businesses closed down down to
the,
I don't know.
In my lifetime I don't remember
anything like this profound but,
but,
but Brooklyn on the other hand is like
really burgeoning like oh really small
restaurants,
small bakeries,
small like ice cream shops like are able
to open there because the real estate
isn't bad.
Expensive to rent.
Commercial real estate isn't as expensive.
So it's so you're
getting like better food,
better like just baked goods.
The ice cream,
grocery stores,
local grocery stores with local produce.
Like it's,
it's bad.
I mean,
I don't want to sell it too hard,
but I think it's better.
Like we're happier there.
It seems like a little
bit of a compromise,
a little bit better or compromised.
Like your insights,
what it is.
You're in a suburban area,
but it's a little subsidy and it's slower.
We'll still be honest with you.
The people are a little slower.
You're kind of like,
you're at the ice cream
store and you're like,
ah,
come on.
Come on.
What are we doing?
What's going on?
You're just,
you're just,
you're walking over there like
you could a little brisk step,
you know,
like bringing a little pep to it.
Is it jazz music?
So use the fucking being so,
so crazy in New York.
That hive is so nuts.
It's so,
it mimics insects.
It's really crazy.
So when you get them all
together in this big,
you know,
thing that they've created and they're
all swarming and this giant population
center,
I mean it's really not that much
different than a beehive or an ant hill.
It's fucking crazy.
So many people there.
My wife and I went and this
was even more the case.
My wife and I rented a house in western
Massachusetts this summer for a month so
that we could just write in,
relax and like dude,
get away from like,
like Amherst north,
north of North Hampton.
Beautiful out there.
Gorgeous but so slow.
Oh my God.
Everything is like you go somewhere you
to order a cup of coffee or like we're
going to be here for a little bit.
Like,
yeah,
there's no law in the country.
And it's really nice though.
We,
um,
but it was funny because my wife has
been saying since we've been together,
probably about eight years,
got married four years ago.
And uh,
since we met,
when she was like,
I think that I belong in the country,
I think that we should move to Jenny.
And I was always like,
I can't,
like,
I gotta work.
This is work in the city cause
there's comedy clubs and,
and this is where the
my one man shows are.
And,
uh,
we finally took a month after being
together for eight years and went to the
country and we brought
our cat Ivan and uh,
and who had never been
anywhere but our apartment.
And there were mice in
the house and they were,
this is a really strange phenomenon.
They were parasitic mice.
It parasites in them,
which means they are
unafraid of people or cats.
Oh,
that means they have toxoplasma.
Yeah.
That's exactly what they have.
And,
and uh,
and so usually if you have a cat,
you don't even see mice because they
smell cats and they don't even come out.
In this case,
we had mice,
like they were like zombies.
They were walking towards us.
We were like batting them away
like a fucking video game.
And that's sick.
And those are the dangerous ones.
Those are the ones that can affect you,
is that right?
Oh yeah.
They have a massive impact on human
behavior that if they bite you is that if,
if it gets into your skin,
either through cat fecal matter,
you get a,
if the cat's infected,
you can get it from the cat.
You can get it from a livestock that a,
it comes in contact with the ship.
And so Ivan Eight,
one of the mice.
Oh No.
See we took them again.
So we instead of a month there,
we were there for two weeks.
Drove home after he ate the mouse,
then we took him to the vet and he got,
he took a,
you know,
whatever medicine to make
to knock that stuff out.
I don't think they can stop that stuff.
So brain parasites,
I thought it is what it is.
I think a whatever it was,
we're,
we've,
it's checked out.
I don't know.
They gave him medicine a Zombie.
Kat,
I know you guys on the cat.
Yeah.
That's not good.
He's old though.
He's 16 years old,
so time ago.
He's in his golden years out of
there before he infects the house.
It sounds crazy,
but toxoplasma really is something
that people have to have an issue with
because it does have an effect on
human behavior that makes people more
aggressive.
It slows your reaction time down.
And um,
a lot of the world has it.
A huge popular.
Really?
Yeah.
In France,
it's been as high in the,
I believe it was the 1950s in 1960s it
got as high as 80% and 80% of the country
had it.
And now it's down to the 50s.
This is all estimations of course.
Not like really testing
the entire population.
The estimate that America,
it's somewhere around 50 to 60 million
people are affected by it or anyone for
anyone getting their news
from Joe Rogan's podcast.
Yeah,
you're in trouble by the way,
cause I'm backed up it,
I've done no research challenge.
You what I read.
Yeah.
But uh,
it's the idea is that once you get it,
you got it.
That's it.
Wow.
Yeah.
So it's brain parasites.
Jesus makes the,
the mice sexually attracted to cat piss.
What a motherfucker like
what a crazy fucking disease.
Dead.
Well,
we,
my wife was on sitting on the couch
in the house and there was a mouse.
She looked next to her.
There's a
mouse just sitting there staring at her.
And Mom,
usually you see a mice,
a mouse in,
it just runs away immediately.
And in this case it was just staring
at her and she just ran away.
And then I had to chase
the mouse out of the house.
That something really
creepy about rodents.
I know.
Well,
have you ever heard the rat gang concept?
No,
I just heard about it.
That's recently,
there's a apparently a book.
Uh,
I have a comedian friend named John
Hodgman who's a very knowledgeable man and
uh,
he,
he's written a lot of very
funny and great books and he,
uh,
he's in the daily show is of correspond
on the daily show sometimes he,
he's on there.
But anyway,
he had,
this is telling me there's this
book and I think it's called rats.
It's all about the culture
of rats and that there's,
there's this phenomenon
theoretically called the rat king,
which is that certain rats are in such
an enclosed space that after a while
their tails are intertwined.
So their existing essentially
as one large rat unit.
Wow.
I don't know if I can substantiate this,
but people should look up rat king.
That sounds like some comic book Shit,
man.
Look,
I need to look that up.
Rat King.
That doesn't seem like it.
If it seems like something
you would know about,
was he just joking?
You wasn't joking.
Really.
No.
Fair that there's this book called brick,
I think rats and uh,
and it sheds a lot of light on Yom
intimately looking at myself in this one,
this camera and just gone.
Oh Man.
Have I put on weight on the road?
It's so painful.
The roads brutal road.
It's brutal.
It's hard to I what is this?
A rat king and the scientific museum.
Oh my God.
So it is real,
right?
Oh my God.
Brian,
pull this up on Wikipedia because this
is going to freak you the fuck out.
I see that as long as Bryan,
oh,
that son of a bitch.
Yo Brian,
how dare he,
the,
the loudness with which you shouted is
so inappropriate to what you're going to
tell him.
Yeah.
It's not,
no,
no.
You need to see this Wikipedia rat king.
He needed to see this.
It's this,
this is incredible,
man.
This is,
uh,
this really is a real phenomenon.
I thought your friend was
just fucking with you.
No,
no,
no.
We have a serious conversation about rats.
Whoa.
That seems like horrific.
Yeah.
If you go to it with folks,
if you go to the folks listening to this,
people would probably
tweet at you right now.
Facts about the rat king.
I bet some of your listeners and
viewers to know about the rat can't.
Hey,
we need you to pull something up man.
We just something crazy.
It's called a rat king.
So Mike Birbiglia said this to me.
I did not.
I thought he was just fucking around.
I thought it was friend
was just fucking around.
But apparently there are clumps of rats
that get connected together by the tail
and they grow together
while joined at the tails.
So there's like a group of,
like in this photo there's a group of,
it looks like 30 or 40 of them
just on top of each other,
connected by the tails.
Rat King just pull up rat king on Wiki.
It's the photo that connects to it.
What can you imagine if you
ran into that somewhere?
No,
no.
It's the,
it's the stuff of nightmares.
It's what one would,
one should fear.
Most rodents are fucking scary animals,
man.
This is so gross.
Gross little fuckers.
You got it.
Rat King,
the image of the top.
Look at that.
That click.
Oh my God.
I click on that.
That's real.
Is this live streaming the video?
Oh my God.
That thing.
This isn't sane.
Yeah.
I mean it's insane.
I just,
all these rats intertwined.
I came here today to blow
Joe Rogan's mind and I have,
oh,
you blew it.
You blew it wide open.
Cause I thought,
I thought we were having fun.
That's like your friend
is telling us a crazy.
He could read your mind.
No,
really.
A rat.
King's a real thing.
Fuck.
What's folklore mean then?
Well,
you know,
um,
I,
it doesn't necessarily
mean that it's not true.
Uh,
it means that,
uh,
it's probably been the
exaggerated and tossed down from,
uh,
superstitions,
but this is,
it's a rat big.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean there was,
there was,
there was a bunch of shit,
but it's obviously a real thing.
It's a real phenomenon.
There's,
this is in the scientific
museum in Germany.
I mean it really,
it really does happen,
but I think it's probably they don't,
they probably just are tied up in knots.
They're probably not like growing
together through the tales.
I don't think their tails become one unit.
I think they're just gross
and they just get tangled up.
Ira Glass I regressed to,
you mentioned earlier,
you don't know show this American life,
but he was saying the other day.
It's sometimes he's
struck with when we're,
you know,
we live in New York,
you live here in La with the degree to
which we are living like medieval lords
like we have at our
beck and call any food,
any type of food we want prepared
any way we want in a 25 minutes.
Yeah.
It's all a strange giant human construct.
Yes.
That doesn't resemble anything in nature.
Yeah.
Some nutty thing that they just
just goes up to the heavens.
Yeah.
Pops out of the ground.
Everything else is missing and
occasionally you'll see a tree,
one tree defiantly
looking for it's friends.
It's my mind.
That's why I loved the movie minority
report when it came out because I was just
like,
you watching a movie now you're like,
yeah,
about half of that
stuff is true right now.
Yeah.
It gives a futuristic,
but it was futuristic
in a way that was like,
you can just about see it coming.
Like you walk into the mall and they go,
Hello Joe Rogan.
Would you like the Nike shoes
that you bought last year?
Would you like another fresh pair?
Certainly it's going to happen,
right?
For sure.
Yeah.
It's gonna be,
they're gonna be able to
already exists on your phone.
The Internet always are already on Amazon.
You go on,
they said,
well you,
you might like this.
Yeah.
I bought a tee shirt from cafe press
and I bought it through Amazon and went
through Amazon.
Yeah,
there it goes.
Do you want to go through Amazon?
Like yo can see how that works?
Sure.
Cut through Amazon.
Yeah,
I love it.
It's amazing.
We live in a weird world.
Strange.
We're talking about one
click shopping on Amazon,
but it's the easiest way to buy anything.
And it's,
when you start doing it,
it becomes so God damn addictive
because it feels ridiculous.
I know.
You just get,
you can get obscure billiard supplies.
You can like weird shit.
Like I need a corporate tip tapper
and you can find that on Amazon.
And hardest,
hardest to return though.
I had so much shit that I just
won't return because it's like,
yeah,
you gotta,
you gotta take the hit I saw.
Yeah.
I saw the movie day for night recently,
a Truffaut film,
which is great.
Have you ever seen that?
No.
Day for night.
Did you get it from Amazon?
No,
but it's about making a film.
Yeah.
No,
I actually did.
I got it,
I think from Amazon and
then I was at the end of it,
I was like,
I'd like to have the
poster of this click on it.
Okay.
It's on the way.
Boom.
So crazy.
I get these,
uh,
obscure Mexican hot sauces,
Leu Kotecha.
I can't find them in any like
white people grocery store.
You have to go to the Mexican hood to get,
you could Kotecha or you
just go to amazon.com boom.
How do you resolve it?
And I'm like,
cause I,
cause you,
you were very knowledgeable about pizza.
How do you fit that into the Diet?
Because you have such a good diet.
Just Kinda make sure you
don't eat it all the time.
The most important
thing is that your base,
like you,
you,
you never want to deprive
your body of nutrients,
but you can have cheat days.
Totally.
Yeah.
Nothing wrong with that,
I think.
I think a cheap meals cheat days,
just as long as you're being reasonable,
as long as like 80% of your food is
really good food and healthy and every now
and then you have a burger
or something like that,
you could do that.
So we get away with it.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
I've tried vegetarian before.
I tried it when I was trying to
lose weight when I was a kid,
when I was fighting in different
weight classes and I didn't like it.
I felt,
I just felt shitty.
I just didn't feel,
I didn't feel like I was a very vibrant,
I haven't tried it again as an adult,
but I know I crave meat.
I crave it.
Like after a good workout I want to
fucking steak and I'll feel like my body
wants red meat and people say let's,
you know that's the only
evolved and lustful killing.
Those cows are knocking the live forever.
If you just let them walk around
and if people aren't killing cows,
something's going to kill cows.
Either cars cause you're going to hit
them with your cars cause they're going to
be everywhere.
Or you can have mountain lions running
around taking cows out in front of you
everyday.
That's a possibility too.
I think it's inhumane aspect of keeping
them in crates slightly larger than
their body.
That I think frustrates people.
Yeah.
I haven't had veal on a long time.
The veal was the first
one I tapped out on.
It was just like,
I can't do that.
That's just too creepy.
Taken a baby and not feeding it and
tying it in and not so can't move.
No,
no,
no.
Thanks.
Yeah,
it's so fucked up.
I'm just like,
Hey,
I've got no time for that.
Just so it's more tender.
Really.
What the fuck man?
What's funny is I'm looking at your image.
You're behind a computer,
but I can see you're
here and you can see me.
It's funny as it,
if you,
if your body and if you
have a really good physique,
if you ended up having my body,
you might go into a deep depression.
I'm like,
you'd be really upset if I had your body,
my comedy career would go away because
all I do is just make fun of my own body
and sour.
But you can make fun of
anything and you know if he can,
if you make fun of your own body,
if you're a self deprecating,
you can make fun of something else.
You actually defy because you're,
you're great.
I was listening your albums this week.
You defy vid Joe Piscopo rule,
which is that if you're,
if you get to fit,
you're no longer funny.
People are silly.
There's no rules to comedy.
Nobody should.
We should.
I think Pisco.
Where's the,
where the,
uh,
where's the line in the
sand where people are like,
oh,
okay.
That's how it works.
No,
with Pisco,
the problem was he just,
you know,
he had a few good things that he did
on Saturday night live if you're good
sketches.
But overall there wasn't that much there.
He didn't put enough effort into it.
He didn't.
Yeah.
It's no different than any other comic
like Michael Richards that you know,
goes from being an actor to be in a
comic and just can't really pull it off.
Yeah.
There's not much difference.
It's a hard road and no one has to tell
you that to become a standup comic is a
long,
hard fucking road.
Yeah.
And Eh,
there's not a lot of us who stay on it.
If you stop and think about like the
guys that you hung out with when you were
an open miker totally different.
Yeah.
And look at the guys that you know
now how many of them made it me and
Fitzsimmons you started out together.
So like literally like
weeks apart from each other.
So like he's like one of the only guys,
like from my group of open Miker is that,
that made it over the salmon net.
No one from my open mics working.
Yeah.
It so that it will actually,
no,
I shouldn't say that.
No one from my open mics is,
I still run into anything to,
Paulo was always a really funny guy
and he was always in really good shape.
But he was a football player.
You're right.
Nick is much more handsome than me.
Fantastic.
Had a hair.
I discovered this.
I went to Guantanamo Bay,
Cuba and the USO tour with a Depaulo
and Geraldo and Colin Quinn gaffing at a
bunch of guys.
And uh,
Geraldo is in great shape too.
And so it was DePaul cause we,
cause we were waiting on
the beach should we went,
we went swimming,
pulled over cause we couldn't
get through one of the gates.
We were like,
well let's just go swimming
in that beach right there.
And we all went swimming.
There's fun.
I did,
we still have photos of it.
And I'm like,
ah,
fuck.
It's really embarrassing for me.
Feels like a shame.
Yeah,
DePaul has always been good shape.
He was,
uh,
one,
one of the guys when I was in open miker
he was a a bit more established than
me.
He was ahead of me by at
least maybe like two years.
Yeah.
He was an established
professional Micah time.
Yes.
Yeah.
Louis was also about
two years ahead of me.
Those guys,
when I first started doing open mics,
they were just doing
professional gigs and a,
I got to see a Depaulo
once on stage and I'm like,
look at this handsome motherfucker,
this football player looking dude.
No.
And he was hilarious and I,
and I,
that was a nice thing for me to see as a,
uh,
you know,
a young guy who was involved
in athletics myself.
It was like,
okay,
so there is no rule.
Yeah.
Like anything can,
you know,
and then when I remember when I,
my first saw Kennison,
that's when I realized there was no rules.
That's when I first,
I like,
oh,
anything can be comedy.
And it's just whether or not,
it's funny.
That's comedy too.
This is a different thing he's doing.
That's right.
Gwen Kinison was going,
I love it.
Look at this face.
I was married
that fucking because I,
because we could get him,
remember when he,
uh,
he was one of my earliest influences.
Um,
when he did that bit about,
uh,
about getting married,
the devil has even tried to scare you.
It's like,
Oh,
you've been married though.
This is going to be like
fucking Club Med for you.
Come on here and this is
where we torches souls,
blah,
blah.
You're married.
How will be like
he was,
he was the first,
to me,
that like really cemented in my head
that anything could be comedy because I
always loved comedy,
but I was always like way too loud and
aggressive and stupid to connect myself
to someone like Jerry Seinfeld.
You know,
like,
I was like,
that would,
I would have to be a totally
different person to be.
That kind of came back.
I could never do that.
Just,
I don't think I could do that.
Yeah.
But then I saw Kennis and I was like,
oh,
there's no rules.
You don't have to beat Jerry Seinfeld.
You just have to be whatever.
It's funny from you,
whatever comes out of you
podcast must be great
for you because you're,
when you tore,
now it's probably your audiences
who get your sense of humor.
Yeah.
As opposed to like fear,
fear factor fans who were like,
well let's see him do
the bugs in the mouth.
Yeah.
The fear fear factor was hard for,
cause I heard that bid on
your album where you're like,
that's just a show.
I host it.
I'm not,
that's not me.
That wasn't my idea.
It's a lot of people though.
It's such a big thing because it's on
television that it has to like define you
friend.
Then it has to be your thing.
But I was always like,
why?
Like it's just,
it's my Gig,
but that's crazy.
But the technology of these podcasts
right now is that you can't actually say,
yeah,
no,
I'm this,
I'm going to tell you what I am.
It's this w you,
you
get an opportunity to express yourself
in a way deeper way than would ever be
possible in a million tonight show.
Oh,
appearances.
You'd never be able to
find out that across.
That was always my goal.
Starting out.
It's cause I would do these hell gigs.
I drove like I do in the movie.
It's like I drove,
I drove my mom's station
wagon all over the country.
I bought incidentally,
it's like,
oh,
I only find out at this age now.
It's like people's parents gave them
their car or like bought them a car.
I bought my mom's station wagon for $2,200
I had a hundred thousand miles on it.
Like she marked it up or my mom
marked up first still was really good.
I drove it around the country and I and
I would perform at these gigs who'd be
like,
you know,
like every just so people
have a point of reference.
Like when I was starting out,
like whenever you're in
the middle of nowhere,
you're in like you know,
Cherry Hill,
Pennsylvania,
New Jersey and you drive by like a
best western and it says comedy night,
Wednesday.
That was my life.
I was comedy night,
Wednesday.
I took a lot of those to let a
lot of those Barry Katz Gigs.
Yeah.
And so,
so my goal when I was in that stage,
cause I wouldn't do well,
you know,
the audiences wouldn't like me.
They came to see something
different than what it was.
I wasn't also that good.
So it was like,
it was the combination of what I would
become was like a soft spoken kind of
storyteller.
And then what they wanted
was like fast jokes,
Lenny.
Yeah,
they won Lindy Clark.
Yeah.
Who's great comic.
But yeah,
he could kill it anywhere.
And so what I was like,
I want people eventually to
come to see my shows on purpose
and that's why he's here.
That's why I started,
started to keeping a mailing list.
And you also,
uh,
got very successful with your blogs.
I remember you were the first guy.
We were somewhere,
I can't remember what city it was,
but you were in a big place.
You were in like this,
this big theater.
And I,
and I go,
damn,
I go,
Mike Birbiglia is playing.
Here.
I go,
how the fuck is he doing that?
And then I forget who I was with.
Um,
it was either Joey Diaz or Ari.
Should fear.
One of those guys was like,
he's got this blog really,
really popular.
He's got this blog.
And I was like,
damn man,
that's a big impact.
Like this was years ago before
we ever even did the podcast.
And I remember thinking like,
that's a lot of impact from,
you know,
connecting with people on the Internet.
Well part of it was like I,
I wrote my blog,
it was called my secret public
journal and I still do it.
And uh,
and then Bob,
the Bob and Tom show out of it,
you know,
out of Indianapolis and
there syndicated was like,
just read your secret
public journal on our show.
So I would call in every week.
And it was actually very similar,
like cable guy,
cable guy used to do
stuff like that radio,
you know that cable guy used to do
like he used to do Collins every week.
So like all over the place.
He like,
he would be doing like 20,
25 phones a week.
Wow.
Yeah.
Holy Shit.
We thought about that.
A really hard worker.
Okay.
I mean,
I don't know what he does now,
but,
but he backed up.
I've met him a long time ago in
Montreal when he was just starting out.
Nobody knew about him was
like the early nineties.
And he was a nice fucking nice guy,
had a great time family.
I hung out with him one night and uh,
we,
we partied at the comedy
works in Montreal,
got hammered out of there.
It was a great dude,
man.
We had some fun and uh,
he's got some great
potato chips and sent us,
he listens to the podcast series,
sent over,
uh,
his potato chips.
He's guy was cheeseburger,
potato chips get tastes.
The pickles,
you can,
he has Cheezburger potatoes.
It is probably the worst
thing on earth for you.
Like,
I don't know how the fuck they're
giving you all these different flavors,
but it's like a joke.
I mean like you eat,
you eat a chip and you like,
I'd taste the burger.
There's the ketchup,
there's a pickle.
What the fuck?
Yeah,
last night and my hotel,
because I had any,
I hadn't eat,
I'd eaten dinner at that in between
stage like 6:00 PM and then it's midnight
and you're going to,
I got to eat something.
So I went to the mini bar
and I had pirate's booty.
That shit.
I had pirate's booty in the flavor
was aged Cheddar and I was like,
what the fuck is aged Cheddar in this
like manufactured chip that's from some
factory somewhere.
It's like,
is that really aged Cheddar?
What creates the taste of age?
It's like strawberry.
It doesn't taste anything
like strawberries.
It's just what we,
we agree to.
Strawberry got like great gum.
Grape gum doesn't taste
like fucking great.
The last thing that should tastes great,
it tastes like grape gum.
Right?
You know,
and with that purple grape soda,
they suddenly lit grapes.
We get it in our head that
that's the great flavor.
Yeah,
it's grape soda.
Even have grapes in it now.
Right?
It's just some fucking sugar water.
But we know there's a fake grape tastes
that we accept and it's like the gum
tastes that grape gum tastes.
It's fake.
It's a fake grape.
We just go,
yeah,
it's great.
That doesn't mean anything like great,
like what are you talking about?
You know?
It's like if I gave you a
cheeseburger and it tasted like feet,
you know it's fast liquids on Amazon now,
Larry the cable guy,
she's very retainer chip package
one read three to hug a three damn
cheeseburger,
potato chips.
That's another guy.
By the way,
it doesn't need the money.
So he clearly believes in cheeseburger,
potato chips.
Look,
they were very tasty,
but I was feeling like with each chip,
I was rolling the crazy dice.
I was like,
what's in this shit?
Who knows what kind of it was
going to grow breasts on you?
You know what it's like?
It's like,
it's like,
it's like Willy Wonka and
the chocolate factory.
When they take the things
like what does it tastes like?
Oh,
it tastes like a,
you know,
whatever the thing was.
That's exactly what it's like.
Dude,
I didn't even think of that.
I forgot about that.
That's exactly what it's like.
Yeah,
Dude.
It,
I'm telling you that you remember.
Do you guys remember?
I forget what it was.
It's like,
does it taste like this?
And he's like,
yeah,
it does.
I don't remember.
But I do remember was like a piece of
gum that basically tasted like an ex a
food experience,
right?
Yeah.
Well they're getting,
they closing,
they're closing in on,
it's like ghost fleet.
It's ghostly distinct.
It's not like,
you know,
Habanero pepper distinct flavor.
It's a ghostly like,
oh,
there's the mustard in that fucking thing.
But it's really good.
It's really good.
But um,
your,
your role in the health dice,
there's,
you know,
it'd be good with this potato
chips or like some kind of cheese,
meaty cheese.
Oh,
Jesus.
You're getting my dick hard
meaty case.
When you talk to Europeans,
are they say that what's
killing us is the preservatives.
Oh yeah.
Because you're very overweight and they
eat cheese and wine and all this stuff
on pasteurized cheese.
They have a lot of
unpasteurized cheese in Europe.
You can't even get it over here.
It's like I had a friend from France
and he used to have to smuggle it in
smuggling unpasteurized cheese in France.
Yeah.
It's so crazy.
And by the way,
there's a reason why your body
has a lactose intolerance.
It's because you're drinking milk
that's been boiled down is dead.
There's no enzymes in it.
There's no like all this stuff that
makes your body naturally digest it.
It doesn't exist.
He goes,
so the idea is that like we have
to protect people from bad milk.
Yeah.
But you know,
what's a better idea?
Fresh milk.
We've got to figure out how to not
have milk sitting in a
supermarket for three months.
We got to have people
closer to their animals.
We had the,
um,
growing up,
we had the,
I don't know if you remember
this in Massachusetts,
the lung grin and [inaudible]
like milk store it when it was,
it was milk in glass bottles.
They would deliver it to your house.
Cops let him off.
Amazing.
And I don't think that
place exists anymore.
Yeah.
I don't know if that was
pasteurizer homogenized,
but,
uh,
the,
the used to have it at whole foods.
So now you've got to go to a,
there's like little specialty
markets are California.
They have it in whole foods.
No,
no,
not anymore.
Whole foods is like,
they're so big that they,
uh,
there's certain shit they
don't take a risk with.
Like there's a Kombucha that has
more than one half of 1% alcohol.
And because of that,
they carry it.
But it's just,
uh,
it's,
it was,
it's nothing,
it's not like a level
that can get you drunk,
but it is,
you know,
it ferments and it's really
fucking good for you.
And the one that ferments the most
is the really the best for you.
And they don't carry it because it's,
it's got,
it gets a little risky with the alcohol.
Right.
Very risky.
So that's why they don't,
they don't have that,
they don't have raw milk there anymore.
It's like,
it's too risky.
But I don't know if that's a
corporate decision and what,
but it's unfortunate because raw milk,
man,
it doesn't give you any
like weird stomach shit.
Tastes way better once you get
used to the fact what you drink.
It's like rich and creamy.
It's sick.
It's really fucking good.
Mine.
Uh,
I was finding California recently
and I was on a plane and I was,
I had one of those mornings where you
show up at the airport and you just,
you're so hungry that
you just grab anything.
I was like Chibo or whatever
that place is called the JFK.
Yeah.
You're just like,
I'll have any just in case,
you know,
I need something.
I'll have a banana,
have a sandwich,
anything.
You have his bag of stuff.
And I get on the plane and I'm just
scarfing down this chicken salad sandwich
and the flight attendant
comes over to me and he goes,
um,
excuse me sir.
I there nuts in that sandwich.
I'm like,
scarfing down the sandwich.
And I looked down,
I'm like,
I'm a film show.
I it,
here's walnuts and I know that
this is going to go badly.
And so I could,
as I'm talking,
I'm still eating the sandwich.
I'm like,
man.
And he's like,
um,
the woman who's two seats down from you,
she has a nut allergy so
you have to put that away.
And I was just like,
um,
I won't,
I won't like make her eat them,
you know,
like I won't rub them on her body.
I'm just going to eat it right here.
And he was like,
it's actually,
um,
even if the nuts are in the air.
And I looked over at the woman and I go,
excuse me,
I go,
well you have a reaction,
allergic reaction if there
are nuts in the hair.
And she goes,
yeah,
I have an allergy and it's,
I'll have a,
I'll,
an episode if there's nuts in the air.
And uh,
and I was just thinking like,
I didn't say this,
but I was like,
shouldn't leave the house.
Yeah.
Right.
Even real though,
you can't go in the grocery store.
So this is what happened.
I go,
oh no,
I was in that incident.
I was in that stage
where I was having like,
like eating,
like I was about to have eating blue
balls and where you're halfway through a
sandwich and you're like,
if I don't finish this sandwich,
I'm going to flip out.
So I said that the guy was like,
is there anywhere I can eat this sandwich?
And he said,
I'm not making this up.
He goes,
you can eat it in the bathroom.
Wow.
And so I w I mean,
I,
so I went to the bathroom and
I've finished my sandwich.
Jesus Christ.
But the nut allergy thing is strange.
It's like,
I really don't want people to die
because they have a nut allergy,
but I'm also kind of like,
well then I guess this is real you,
the allergy thing.
Yeah.
This is Neil.
Wow.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
They should have breathing things that
they have to where they're going in
public.
It shouldn't go on the hundred and
50 passengers right in the flight.
Yeah.
That's where the person
with the nut allergy.
Why can't you just have one
of those little Asian masks?
You know,
like the little white mass?
Yeah.
For starves.
It can be.
Wow,
this is really interesting.
Hmm.
That's doesn't seem right.
And then I asked her,
I go,
is this,
do you fly a lot?
I mean,
is this something you do?
and she said,
uh,
she said,
yeah,
and when I'm on southwest,
I call an advance.
When I call it advanced,
they take all the nuts off the plane.
Oh my God.
She said,
there are no nuts on the plane when I fly.
And I was just like,
who is this girl
power?
Does she wheeled
it is possible.
Here's the thing,
they're saying,
all those small amounts of peanut
protein can set off a severe reaction.
It is rare that people get an allergic
reaction from just breathing and small
particles of nuts or peanuts.
That does mean it's possible.
They said it's rare.
Yeah,
it's his most foods with peanuts in them
do not allow enough of the protein to
escape into the air causing a
reaction and just cause the smell.
Foods containing peanuts,
uh,
won't produce reaction because the
scent does not contain the protein.
So what w w she was just
freaking out at the possibility,
but most likely since it was like a food,
it wasn't just,
it's a dust from the
crunching of the peanuts.
Apparently that's enough apparently
to freak some people out.
It's rare,
but that's enough for some people,
which is crazy.
Yeah,
she should not.
She should drive.
We are weird thing.
No Man.
To be allergic to a of of food so badly,
like peanuts and not kill people.
Man.
They're fucking poison and were like
peanut m and m's and fucking drama.
Trump.
Imagine.
How weird would it be grown
up where everybody's eating
poison everywhere around
you.
Everybody's eating some shit that
if you go to the supermarket,
there's tubs of poison ivy.
You go and get some peanut butter.
That shit will kill.
You always felt that
way about cell though.
Oh really?
From from from moment one.
We're in cell phones started.
You be ubiquitous.
I was like,
this is going to be the
cigarettes of our time.
Well,
that's ridiculous.
That's really is bad as peanuts
to people allergic to peanuts.
People that allergic to peanuts had
fucking kills you dead and it's everywhere
in tubs of it and people are
eating it in front of you.
CHOMP,
chomp.
It's like a common food for kids.
Take the school,
peanut butter and Jelly,
but imagine if poison.
Think about having this
to your head all the time.
You get cancer from your cell phone.
You're a pussy.
That's what I say.
I'm going to send some brain
cancer patients your way.
It might be weird if
like in like 30 years.
It might be weird though,
and like 30 years.
It's like the whole entire
state has cancer of the brain.
We all die at the same time.
Everybody's right thumb
rots off your texting.
Thumb.
Yeah.
I don't,
I don't think that it's
a that much of a concern.
There's a lot of radiation
we just get from the sun.
There's a lot of radiation we get from
just the environment every time you fly
in a plane to get massive
amounts of radiation.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Every time you get flying a plane,
it's supposed to be worse than
going through those x ray machines.
Oh,
Jesus.
Yeah.
You're up in the fucking high altitude.
You're flying at 35,000 feet and yeah,
my wife won't do the new one.
The new x Ray.
Oh really?
She gets opted out.
She opts out.
She just is freaked out by it.
She's Rod.
Of radiation is right.
Yeah.
I don't think they've adequately
researched the longterm effects of putting
fucking weird particles
to people's bodies.
And it might work on,
you know,
there's a thing about any sort of
exposure to things that you might be fine,
I might be fine,
but one person,
just like the person
that's allergic to peanuts,
people's bodies are weird,
man.
One person could have a totally different
reaction to that radiation and really
get sick because of it.
Everybody's built so different.
You know,
there's just,
we have,
we,
we have similar but varied bodies and
we have to take that into consideration
when you,
you know,
find out what's,
what's bad for people.
For some people can't even have one drink.
Does that mean we should take drinks away?
That's ridiculous.
Cause for most of us,
drinks are great.
Some people cannot have that one drink.
So imagine living in a world,
and I have friends that have done this
where they look at everybody drinking.
Like you're just,
this is everything you're doing.
If I did,
I would be dead in an alley in a week.
I'd just fucking go on
a massive bender until,
uh,
I ran out of heartbeats.
You know,
and that's,
it's around us everywhere.
Yeah.
We varied too much.
We need to collectively,
there's is,
we've got a big spectrum
of physical,
psychological everything.
Do you ever thinking
about running for office?
Fuck that for
running for offices.
Like it'd be like becoming a pro wrestler.
It's a,
it would be like,
oh,
this Zillow way.
You could equate the two because you're
following like a script in a certain
way.
You're following a script in your ear.
You're entering into some
artificial sort of a situation.
This isn't,
this isn't real like Paul Ryan,
we don't know Paul Ryan.
We don't know Mitt Romney.
Mitt Romney doesn't even know.
Mitt Romney was very uninspired
by the speeches last night.
Sorry,
I'm in a movie.
I watched those speeches and I was really
actually really open minded to like,
Hey,
what do you guys God?
And then I just came away just being like,
oh,
okay.
Now it was all rhetoric.
It was all get back the country.
You,
if you have a small business,
you did build it.
And it was all just bad,
clunky,
shitty speeches.
Yeah.
They played a Reagan speech from when
Reagan was running against Jimmy Carter
and I was like,
God Damn Reagan in the
campaign trail could fuck it.
Throw it down.
Oh yeah.
He wasn't,
yeah,
being an actor in,
you know,
even though he was getting on in his
days when he was running for president,
the effects of the presidency,
he hadn't quite broken him down
like it did during his term.
But he,
he stomped Carter in this two minute
speech about what's the difference between
a recession and a depression or recession
is when a neighbor's out of a job,
a depression is when
you're out of a job and a,
and the crowd was cheering and you know,
and he's like,
and to get rid of this depression,
we need to put Jimmy Carter out of a job.
And the,
they went fucking ape shit.
I was like,
whoa.
You imagine having that guy
breathing down your heels.
Ronald Reagan,
handsome ass actor now
talking a lot of sense.
I'll wait till Clooney runs
for office and like 10 years,
no kids.
He's got no kids.
People are never going to listen
to a man who doesn't have children.
They're not going to listen to a man.
It doesn't have children.
Trust me,
the people who have children will never
listened to a man who doesn't have
children because they know that there's
a physiological change that happens in a
person's body and your brain and your
consciousness and your understanding of
relationships.
But when you,
when you have your own children,
and he doesn't have his own children yet,
but when he runs for president,
he's going to have two,
two year olds,
twins,
Donner's maybe we want to see your kids
get to be about 15 before you running.
She,
Matt Damon,
he has kids.
Matt Damon could run for office,
but the real problem is that the whole
system is completely fucked sideways by
corruption.
There's no way you can
run for office to do what?
To be the bidding of the,
you're going to be at the bidding of
these giant corporations are going to have
bullets in your brain.
Well,
you know what the game is.
It's true.
This is,
this thing's been bought and sold and
if it wasn't proved to us by Obama,
I mean come on.
A guy who was the parent or his,
his parent is a single mom,
right?
He's raised in a interracial relationship,
grows up poor lives in Hawaii for a while.
I mean you,
you,
you were talking about a
guy who's a total outsider,
right?
And look what happens when he gets in.
He passes things like the National Defense
Authorization Act that just blindly
allows them to arrest people and they
have no recourse and allows them to use
the military to,
to,
to block civil unrest and to stop
civil unrest in this country.
All Shit that's supposed to be prevented
in the constitution and he's just
allowing this stuff to go through.
Why is he allowing this
stuff to go through?
Is that what the,
the child of a single
parent would really want?
Not The fuck it is.
He doesn't have a say.
He's at the bidding.
They're all at the bidding of money.
And what is the best way to make money?
The best way to make money is
let these motherfuckers loose,
let them do what they want
to do and other countries,
little sleeves and make this happen is
as you give them reasons why we've got to
make this happen.
And that money just
keeps fucking flying in.
And these guys are in our vampire orgy
of blood money just dancing around and
drinking in it and they
don't want it to stop.
And so Obama,
who says that he's going to stop wars,
all the sudden he has to,
he wins a Nobel peace prize and he
has to send 30,000 more troops to
Afghanistan.
What is that?
Is that what do you really think?
That's what he wants to do.
Do you really think that's
what his big changes is?
Big changes that,
come on,
man,
it's all crazy.
No one does.
It's a,
this is a broken system.
You're watching these,
these candidates,
you know like this is,
this is the last death
throes of a dying situation,
a dying configuration in the configuration
of Democrat versus Republican.
You know,
and what we're going to do is get a man,
I got back to the small business,
to the families.
It's like eat.
It's like you're,
you're making those
close encounters noises,
dude.
Dude,
dude,
do you not even say anything?
He just making the noises
that the people want to hear.
You're making the conservative noise
you use is sort of underlyingly racist.
Look a little,
you know,
let's get it back away from this black
guy's Kinda fucked everything up.
Look how white my wife is.
He goes,
there's a little of that going on.
It's nod sands.
And meanwhile the same companies will
be controlling things no matter who's in
control.
We get ramped up and shit like gay
marriage and immigration and all this
different stuff that nobody really gives
a fuck about at the top of the heap.
And they just keep sucking
money out of the system.
The whole time we're dancing around
worrying about whether dude should be
labeled or write things down and say,
I'm of this now,
and you're of that now.
And you know,
and then it becomes legal that were,
were dicking around about that.
The same people are running shit
that I've always been running.
Shit.
It's hilarious.
Really.
It's when it becomes more
and more transparent,
you realize like what an incredible job
they've done of just keeping everybody
in the dark and just running
things from the background.
Yeah.
As far as like running the world,
it's really the,
the fucking banks have
done a fantastic job.
I mean in,
in despite of all the competition or
the access to information people have
today,
the fact they still run
it the way they run it,
it's like amazing.
I've done a great job.
They're bad motherfuckers.
Yeah,
just depressing.
It is depressing.
It's,
you know,
who would want,
what person of our age group would
want war at this stage of life?
What person would think
that that's the best option?
Culture.
Last night,
like Mccain and his speech was saying,
we should raise defense bending,
raise defense spending.
There are so crazy what
you guys are trying to say.
We,
we shouldn't spend so much money.
I was very confused by what,
what they were saying.
Their message was.
The word defense is a funny
word because it's not deep.
It's over the country.
So when you say raised defense spending,
I'm down for strengthening
anything in America,
but I think,
um,
I don't see any reason to send someone's
kids to some other fucking country to
shoot some people they never met because
some assholes say that that's the thing
that needs to be done that
don't make any sense to me.
It's not that you know,
you don't support the troops and it's not
that you don't think that it's good to
have a strong army because
I absolutely do and do,
but oh,
this is just fucking Kate,
praise Enos.
This is chaos.
And no one wants to admit it is.
So you're just,
you're dealing with these two guys
that are essentially going to,
it's going to very,
very little.
Maybe there's going to be like some
social debate going on in here,
maybe a,
you know,
gay people have a harder time.
It'll be harder to get medical pot.
I mean,
maybe.
But other than that,
what the fuck is going to change?
Not that much.
It's good
changes to 46.
All right.
Yeah,
we're good with tight.
You got to get out of here.
So just did I think at three I
got to go over and be on Conan.
I think at three they get three.
What time do you actually
go on stage there?
I don't know.
Well I heard they're going to wait
before you,
I'm in a haze of um,
kind of interviews and stuff like that
these days and come in here is just kind
of like taking time off.
I don't have to,
it's like we don't,
there's no hard interview questions.
It's just kind of hanging out.
It's hard when you're dealing with like,
you have to try to be entertaining
all the time and you have to like,
yeah.
Well you answered the same
questions over and over
and over again.
He,
uh,
I did,
I invited you to that WGA screening
the other night and it was,
um,
it was crazy cause Tim Robbins
was there and Tom Hanks where,
oh,
that's awesome.
Really crazy.
And that was crazy.
They were saying,
Tim Robbins was saying to me that he
was like what you're experiencing right
now,
this kind of haze of like
press junk and all that stuff.
It's basically what
they would do if they literally,
if they wanted to make you insane,
it's stick you in a room and ask you the
same question over and over again all
day.
Right until you crack and
that's what you're doing.
That's your life right now and yeah,
that's like if you were
like a guilty person,
they would bring in a series
of investigators that would
ask you the exact same
question and see if you
have the same answer.
Yeah,
that's actually a great idea,
isn't that you're gonna have
like a hundred investigators
and they give you the
same questions and you have
to give detailed stories.
You would fuck that thing off.
Yeah,
so it's been like a hay is,
wow.
What did you move called?
Sleepwalk with me.
Sleep walkways meaning you
the screen or did send,
did you get it?
I don't really get it yet.
I heard you want to watch the chair.
Let's watch the trailer,
throw it up,
trying to get it.
Here you go.
It's true.
I always had to tell people that because
inevitably someone will come up to me
and they'll be like,
good,
true.
I'll be like,
yeah,
and be like,
Whoa,
I don't know how to respond to that.
Like I guess I could say it louder,
you know,
like,
yeah,
they'd be like,
it's probably true.
So loud.
Okay.
Y'All ready to lip sync?
I can't hear you.
It's my lip sync joke.
So here's what happened.
My girlfriend Abby and I moved into,
she's great and my sister Janet got
and get your next coming your way,
but it'd be better on everyone
started talking about marriage
and that night I started walking.
My sleep
is a sleep walking thing going on
as things with my
girlfriend got more tense,
my sleepwalking more did
it Mac the first place.
This is the first time I remember
thinking maybe I should see a doctor,
and then I thought maybe I'll eat dinner
alone with dinner
and decided I'm not going to get married
until I'm sure that nothing else good
can happen in my life.
You just say that on stage.
One day I asked my girlfriend,
what do you fear most?
And she said,
I fear you'll meet someone
else and they'll leave me.
I'll be all alone.
And she said,
what do you feel?
Oh,
and I said,
bears
as your girlfriend heard the checks.
Now is,
she probably mentioned it.
You said you're going to
go see the doctor get,
don't you say you want to be a comedian?
You're a bartender.
I mean,
pick a damn plan and stick with it.
He's getting,
but he's not as funny as you.
My parents have been together 40 years,
which is,
yeah,
no,
but it's,
it's too long.
If you're ever in a relationship that's
moving towards marriage and you're not
ready to go to my sister Janet's wet
tshirt loser.
Sorry.
No,
I like it.
Great,
man.
It looks great.
It was a couple of really good
lines and he gave Mark Marin apart.
So that's a,
that's a big,
like altruistic move he had.
I had a,
I don't know,
first time I went on his podcast,
we,
we really threw down.
He really hated me.
He hated me for a long time and
he hated me for a long time.
Yeah,
he's crazy.
He hates everybody.
Hates himself.
But then the family tries
to be nice guy though.
He's been really nice to me in the last
tactic that people do.
Yeah.
They create conflict and then somehow
know the conflict gets resolved.
And then there's like this emotional
connection because you have something at
stake.
I think he's a little bit
addicted to conflict a little bit.
What did he not like about you?
Oh,
we didn't know each,
he just said this,
a distorted perception of me and this,
and he has this issue with people selling
out and had this issue with me doing
fear factor.
I'm like,
shut your fucking punk rock
nonsense selling out please.
But he's great in the movie.
And uh,
yeah.
Lauren Ambrose and Carol
Kane and Mark's a good guy.
He's just crazy.
Yeah.
But that's why he's good at what he does.
Get what he does.
Yeah.
He's very good at interviewing people.
Yes.
And he's not,
uh,
you know,
some people,
uh,
just can't quite get,
get the,
the spark going,
you know,
it's awkward interviews like when
someone's acts asking like halfhearted
questions or it doesn't
have the passion for it,
it was very uncomfortable to listen to.
That's most interviews.
Yeah,
isn't it?
Yeah.
Like that's why those press chunk,
it has to be,
especially for x stand up when you,
you know,
you,
so calm,
like always aware of
people's attention span.
You and I were talking the other day
about they want me to do all of these like
morning,
local morning TV shows and uh,
and it's hard because they don't,
when you say on those
local morning TV shows,
when you say a joke,
they'll say,
I don't know what you mean.
That's the worst.
That's the opposite of laughter.
The moment you have to
start explaining a joke,
you're done.
I was saying if you're,
if you're on one of those shows,
any comedian should do this.
If you're unwell.
Oh,
shows,
well you should do is just
immediately break into a Tracy Morgan.
It's almost getting pregnant.
He started rubbing your belly cause
that's like the funniest thing that's ever
happened on one of those morning
shows is Tracy Borg rubbing his belly.
This Mammane call and call.
Some will get them pregnant.
And when he did that,
this poor fool and this silly show
was just flabbergasted age or race.
He didn't know what to say.
Stuck with a wild man on your show
pregnant.
He would still have his belly go.
Does he?
His mom wait and call.
Did you,
did you write a book first?
Is that how this movie came out?
One man show.
It was a one man show
off Broadway in New York.
Sleepwalk with me,
the one man show and then,
and then I adapted it into a film.
And then along the way I actually did,
I wrote a book that was sleepwalk with me.
It was a chapter in the book,
sleepwalk with me and other
painfully true stories.
It was just comedic essays
about sort of painful.
So the sleep walking part is true.
Yeah.
I jumped through a second
story window and my sleep.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
Holy Shit Dude.
So you wake up when,
when you hit the ground as I was running
on the front lawn in my underwear
bleeding,
I'm like,
oh my God.
Yeah.
Second story window.
Quinta Inn in Walla Walla,
Washington.
Holy Shit was so you were on the road,
the road?
Yeah.
Oh my God.
How crazy are you on a one to 10?
What's going on here?
What's going on is I was diagnosed
with what's called rem behavior
disorder.
Uh,
but on a scale of one to 10,
eight
crazy,
crazy.
I Dunno.
Damn.
There's something up with comedians.
So do you have like a tool now that
you travel with like a belt that's like
smell,
like hooked up to like a no joke.
I sleep,
uh,
in every night and a
sleeping bag up to my neck.
And for a while I would wear mittens so
I couldn't wear open the sleeping bag
and I take medication,
I take,
I take an anti anxiety
that the doctor prescribed.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's so strange.
Do you,
is there a trigger?
Is there something that
anxiety,
stress,
sleep deprivation,
like all this stuff
that's really not good.
Sleep hygiene.
Wow.
And it makes you just complete.
Makes me not know.
Dreams.
It makes me act dreams and usually my
dreams have to do with me running away
from some kind of demon or wild animal.
Wow.
What the fuck man?
Holy Shit.
That's got to be crazy.
I told a story about,
um,
I've told us on stage before about being
in San Francisco during a fire and uh,
there was uh,
it was four 30 in the morning.
We all got evacuated from the hotel room
and a lot of people sleep with Ambien
when they're,
when they're woken up like that,
they don't know what the fuck is going on.
And you could see it in their face and
they would wake up in the middle of like
walking down the stairs.
So this guy was like in front of us
and he was in the middle and there's a
fucking whole line of people
trying to get out of this hotel.
Right.
Hundreds of people on
the stairs and it's a,
it's a really narrow staircase.
One person case as well.
Well people were waking up
like where are we doing?
What are we doing?
Like waking up in the middle of walking
down the stairs and the wife was like
yelling at the guy,
just keep walking the hotel to hotel.
What hotel?
Where are we?
We're in San Francisco.
The hotel's on fire were on fire.
Like literally didn't know
what the fuck was going on.
Just whacked out on Ambien.
Kevin James made a Turkey
when he was on Ambien.
Really?
I made a Turkey,
made a fucking target,
didn't know about it.
Got Up in the morning.
I was like,
what the fuck is all this like didn't
know that he went and cooked some food.
It's crazy.
Sorry.
My sister growing up when
she was like 11 or 12,
my mom found her walking down the
street over our neighborhood naked.
And I'm like thinking,
oh,
how,
what are the odds that maybe
just some guy drove by himself.
What a naked 11 year old.
Hey,
walking on the street,
my lucky day
guy who was convicted of he,
he murdered someone close to him,
like his,
his,
uh,
parents or his mother in
law or something like that,
drove to their house in his sleep.
Do you know this case?
There's cases where it's
been used as an alibi this,
but this guy got off.
Yeah.
No.
People who have gotten off
kilter with it like a crowbar,
I'm going to start sleepwalking,
cry.
Can't talk about it first on a podcast.
Dude,
that's a,
that's a
paper trail right there.
Fuck them.
Yeah.
How,
um,
how could you get away with that in the,
a court of law,
w w w w since you have it,
what would they say?
Like,
what is a,
if I killed somebody,
anything you do like,
well obviously when you
walked out that window,
I think there's no question
that you were drinking.
Yeah,
I had a dream that there was a guided
missile headed towards my hotel rooms.
And if there were all these,
there were all these military personnel
in the room and they said the military
personnel said to me,
the missile coordinates are
set specifically on you.
So I jumped out my window
so as to detonate outside
the window for the sake of
the platoon.
Wow.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
This guy beat his mother-in-law to
death and choked his father in law into
unconsciousness.
She is US Christ.
When was the last episode that you had?
That was even just a slight prob.
Well,
you know what's crazy is that making a
film is actually not the healthiest thing
for sleep,
sleep disorders.
So like I was having anxiety and sleep
deprived and I was sleep deprived and I
was directing and I was directing myself,
acting out things that
I'd done in my life.
So I was,
I had an episode where
I was sleep walking.
My wife came in and I was adjusting
lamps in the bedroom and she was like,
what are you doing?
And I'm just like,
we're shooting.
And she was like,
no,
we're not shooting.
And I go,
I'm sorry,
but we are like,
I was actually patronizing her,
which is the worst thing you can do
when you're sleep walking is just insult
people for not understanding
of your reality.
Like,
Oh,
you're so stupid,
you don't get it.
Don't get it.
Oh my God,
that's gotta be so weird as anybody
ever videotaped you doing it?
No,
but I have this,
I would have been the great
wacking credits for your movie.
You have this great,
well no,
no.
In the credits of the movie are the
actual photographs of the window.
I jumped through and me at the hospital,
I took photos of all of it
because when it happened,
I knew no one's going to believe this.
This is too crazy.
And so that's the credits of the movie,
but smashed the window and everything.
Like he did it,
like James Bond stuff
jumped through the window,
like the hulk.
Oh Mike.
And I say that cause that's how I
described it at the emergency room.
I was like,
you know,
the Hulk,
he just kind of jumped
through windows and walls.
That's like me.
Holy Shit.
And um,
yeah,
no,
I've never videoed myself,
but I have this great new video
technology called my wife who remembers
everything.
I see whatever I do or say.
So she's kind of explained
to me what it looks.
She's your dictator.
She dictates I,
it's kind of a hacky male men,
men,
woman thing.
But my wife remembers every thing,
every thing.
That's funny.
You're right,
uh,
rights here by the way.
Oh,
is it?
Yeah.
Well Dude,
thank you very much.
This is,
this is a story that we were talking
about if anybody's interested in looking
up.
Um,
there,
there was a guy from Toronto,
uh,
in,
he had a,
he lost his due to embezzlement
and he suffered from a gambling addiction.
So he,
the guy was in some serious,
serious debt.
So because of that,
he had a high level of
slight of stress and sleep,
induce insomnia.
And he drove,
he got up in his car,
Rosemond his bed.
He drove 14 miles of the
home of his wife's parents.
Yeah.
He removed a tire iron from the car,
entered the house and he beat
the mother-in-law to death,
choke the Father Law on consciousness.
And then he used a knife from
the kitchen to stab them.
I don't,
I don't buy that.
I don't buy that as an alibi.
Seems like a it.
Anyway.
Yeah.
And then he turned,
turned himself into a police station.
My that,
cause I mean I,
I have this disorder and I could not
imagine doing anything that like,
basically the reason I wear a sleeping
bag is that if you undo the sleeping bag,
the moment you start doing something
that requires dexterity and focus and
concentration,
that's what wakes you up.
I would imagine like driving a car is
a very specific traditional college.
Where am I in that?
Yeah,
because I think a,
I'm pretty sure this guy got off.
Yeah,
I don't,
yeah,
I think he got acquitted man.
And then if the jury acquitted parks of
murder and laid it later of attempted
murder,
all of the government appealed the
1992 in Supreme Court of Canada.
It's Canada though.
That's a problem.
They're too nice up there American.
Yeah,
like what the fuck are you talking about?
Oh,
you're sleepwalking when you beat
someone to death with a tire iron.
Yeah.
Nothing wakes you up like metal.
The bone crack over and
over again in your hands.
Vibrating in your hands.
You're mother-in-law's skull
really doesn't wake you up.
The Fuck Outta here.
You crazy ass.
All right,
Mike Birbiglia do your
movie looks fucking awesome
still.
It really looks cool.
It really funny.
It's even if people want to find it,
it's in 30 cities in theaters this weekend
and will it be available on Netflix
and iTunes and all that stuff available
spaces,
but it's right now it's going to,
it's booked.
If you go on sleep walk,
movie.com you can see in the next month
it's going to open it 170 movie theaters
in the country.
Listen,
if you ever want to come back
and when we love to have you,
anytime you want,
really whenever you're in town,
just anytime,
anytime,
just let me know.
And uh,
if you need help promoting anything,
let me know.
Hey,
we'll hook it up.
Thanks a lot.
So thank you very much for coming on.
Thanks to a on [inaudible] dot
com for sponsoring our podcast.
Use the code named Rogan.
Save yourself 10% of it and
all [inaudible] dirty mattress.
And um,
we will,
uh,
see you guys Friday.
We're probably gonna do an icehouse
chronicles here cause it's going to be a
Joey Diaz should fear me.
And uh,
and uh,
Doug Stan hope as well at the uh,
at the ice house.
Yeah,
Doug's gonna Count.
Ah,
fuck yeah,
Doug's going to be here Friday.
And of course,
uh,
Doug and I are also still doing the
end of the world show December 21st,
2012 at the Wiltern theater in La.
Well,
Joey Diaz and honey honey,
the band,
I said Hi.
I will,
I will for sure.
I love him.
So,
uh,
please buy a t shirt.
Yeah,
we're doing some thing
for tosh 0.0 on Friday.
So after that he's going to come down
and do the shows to the ice house.
So that's Friday and Saturday next
week on them and a Santa Barbara at the
Lobero theater.
I don't even know what that's like,
but Santa Barbara is pretty bad ass so
I can't wait to all that shit's on my
Twitter page.
Go to my Twitter page.
You go to barbecue plus Twitter page per
bigly@goddammitafterbigbigsbigsandredbanisredbanontwitterandadesksquad.tv.
If you want to buy the
new desk squad tee shirt,
that is like a,
it's like a rip off of a bunch of big
companies that probably going to wind up
suing him left to take it down.
So get in on it now while
it's still a collector's item.
That's right.
All right,
you freaks.
We will see you Friday.
Um,
thanks to everybody,
we don't have any more
podcasts this week doing,
she says Ice House Ice House.
Right.
Okay.
So we'll see you guys.
Um,
Friday on the ice house chronicles,
and then a next week I got up,
got a bunch of people next week.
A bunch of good shit's happening.
I'll,
I'll keep you guys in tune.
Thank you everybody for all the positive
messages on Twitter and Facebook and
all that good shit and all the cool people
that come out to the comic stores and
comedy stores.
I'm shows places I should stop
talking at a certain point in time.
I've said,
too many words are meaningless now.
It's all just noise out of my mouth.
You know what the fuck
I'm talking about people.
We love you guys.
Thank you very much.
See you soon.
Bye Bye.
[inaudible].