Did you,
did you,
did you do
Shane Moss,
ladies and gentlemen from our studio in
beautiful eight,
one eight.
Thanks for having me.
Thanks for coming buddy.
Yeah,
I was saying before the show you have
the Duncan trussell seal of approval.
Yeah,
thanks Duncan.
Yeah.
I just had my,
uh,
my second time on his show recently.
Oh yeah.
Awesome dude.
He's,
he's one of the rarest people I've ever
met in my life.
I don't know anyone like that now.
There's a few guys that I know that is
just a stone cold,
original.
Duncan's one of those.
Yeah,
he's hilarious.
Awesome.
Did He,
did he give you the full virtual reality
experience?
I did.
That stuff's amazing.
I can't let any.
He told me that the porn is really crazy
in it too,
but he didn't show me any of the point.
Gave me close to the porn.
He gave me the headset like judy got.
No,
no.
I got right up to the wall.
I'm like,
I'm not going.
I'm not going into the matrix.
Yeah,
I hit.
I hit like a wall in his room,
like shooting or dodging a thing or
whatever it is.
It is exceptionally realistic.
It's incredible.
Did you do the archery game where they.
The little guys?
Yeah.
There's another art tree one that I
played to.
That was A.
Yeah.
That's awesome.
There's one that you had to an archery
game where you had to dodge like and
you're like moving like the Matrix to
dodge away from there.
It was like a.
It was like a good workout.
Can see the arrows.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
No,
I would imagine it is a good workout
because I did his boxing one and that's
a good workout.
You look boxing against this guy,
this video guy and I showed it to some
fighters and I was like,
I really think that this could be an
amazing training tool if they could
figure out how to make the headset so
that maybe for the cord was in the back.
If it didn't interfere as long as you
didn't do anything where you had to spin
around,
it would probably be effective,
but it can.
They can map your body movements like
they had that Jamie,
you'd notice that,
um,
wasn't there an xbox one,
we're just sort of takes a picture of
your body as you're standing there,
connect had this fixed before the show
and you got to connect.
Can,
it can read your like heat body heat.
It can pick up,
sort.
Not like,
it's not reading your skeleton,
but it can pick up your limbs and stuff
so it picks up the length of your lens
as well,
where they're moving.
Like if you do the,
uh,
insanity or something like that,
that will work out.
It can tell how high you're lifting your
knees up and if you're not bringing them
up to the right level,
it'll tell you like bring them up
higher,
lift your legs higher level.
Wow.
High enough.
Like give you points based on how you're
doing and whatnot.
Obviously this is rudimentary in
comparison to what it's going to be in a
few years.
So yeah.
And with police training and stuff like
that,
especially once,
I don't know exactly how they do it,
but once it's like kind of wireless.
So you don't have the cord attached to
you and then maybe you could have like
larger facilities than just a small room
eventually.
And,
and,
uh,
doing that,
didn't you say that we're already doing
that.
They're doing warehouses,
they're setting up warehouses for VR VR
sets and they're going to have feedback
in the warehouses like,
like fans that blow a wind on you and is
going to be like movement and some parts
of the ground.
Some shit.
Yeah.
I've,
I played,
um,
I played one of the ones was a paintball
one with other people that were online
and um,
I mean I guess we've had kind of,
people have been playing other people
online,
but when you're doing it in virtual
reality,
it's just a totally different thing.
Well,
I can only imagine.
I saw there was one that they had these
people on an omnidirectional treadmill.
Have you seen those?
No.
You sit,
I can get the idea that you're in a
circular containment and you have like a
harness on your waist so you don't ever
walk forward and touch the bars.
Right?
So you're kind of strapped in place.
And then your feet dictate which way.
This surface that you're on spins,
it's like a,
it's a treadmill,
but it's not a treadmill like it's
always going.
So you have to keep up with it.
It's a treadmill that you propel,
which I've seen before.
Some people actually liked those.
They put them on like a serious incline
and they do crazy sprints on these.
A self propelling,
self moving treadmills.
So this guy had this.
Oh here.
Is that it?
Yeah,
there it is.
There's the omnidirectional treadmill.
So they got to see how he's hooked up to
this harness.
So he's in the center of it and it seems
to spin on bearings or something.
And so he's moving like literally moving
through this,
this virtual world.
You could have just enormous landscapes
that play out.
That's amazing.
Yeah thing.
Yeah,
people are going to get lost in there.
You're also going to get really fucking
tired because I'll tell you what,
like playing that archery game,
my arms were so tired just from holding
like it's like a static thing with your
left arm and particularly you're holding
your arm in one position and then your
right arm that you're drawn the
bowstring back.
You're holding that in one position,
like constantly game is like 20 minutes
long.
Did he do the paint brush stuff?
I did not.
I only did two things.
I did the boxing one.
Well I did three.
I did the archery one than I did the one
where you just stand there and the whale
comes up to you saying,
well the paint stuff I think is going to
be.
I think that is one that's kind of like
almost there already as far as how good
it is.
You know that the archery one,
it's like,
oh these little like two dimensional
kind of things that are,
you know,
it's not,
it's not like amazing graphics.
I think that was amazing though,
but.
But it will be a lot better in the
future,
but the paint one is,
is just this virtual paint.
When you paint like you use a spray can
hear,
like you put sparks in this area and
then you can like walk through it,
you can make a circle around yourself
and then walk through it and shrink it
and enlarge it and you can see all these
people that have like painted entire
ships like spaceships that you can then
go inside and walk around and see all
the different areas they've made and
you can add your own graffiti to it and
stuff like that.
I think that's going to be like to have
someone like Alex grey or something like
that.
Get in there,
you know?
Yeah.
I saw a,
I saw a demonstration of that.
Or they're doing it in three dimensional
deal.
It's going,
this guy made something like you're
describing as for little different rooms
that he has within the little.
Uh,
the virtual world is a big room.
You have,
you made for little ones than the.
And these are all little paint things
that you could make using the program.
And what a program is he on this call?
It's on vive.
It's called tilt brush.
Does the actual program.
Did you know the guy who invented
oculus?
There's only like 24.
Yeah.
Did you hear about the stuff going on
with them this weekend?
He's a trump supporter and his
girlfriend's a Gamer.
Gator paid like billion dollar million
dollar girlfriend.
Hold on.
What'd he say?
He paid for a fund that funded those
memes.
Like the trump memes.
There's a meme.
Funny.
Yeah,
I'll look it up while we're talking.
We're talking about.
Yeah,
that's hilarious.
There's a strange world that we're in
here.
Thinks his name,
something like Palmer Luckey.
Does that sound right?
Oh,
okay.
How weird.
I'm a meme fund that seems so counter
like it was more effective than the
commercials they put on TV.
Probably everyone on facebook and
especially because facebook's kind of
like a lot of older people are on there
now and they're real suckers for those.
Like I like America share this.
If you're brave enough
to share it.
There's a lot of that going around.
It's like those old letters that like
when I was a kid,
the chain letters had come and if you
didn't send it to like seven people,
you'd have bad luck or you know,
whatever it is.
And now people are falling for that with
like trump memes.
Are you aware of shit posting?
No.
Okay.
Jamie.
Jamie alerted me to this new thing.
Jamie's already interests catchy name.
I'm old.
So I need Jamie to keep me in touch with
the young folk.
Um,
but there's a thing called shit posting
and which shit posting is a,
correct me if I'm wrong,
but it's part of the alt right.
Correct.
Is that how it's not necessarily they do
it,
but I don't think it has to end.
It's not,
it's not,
doesn't have an affiliation.
So the,
but the idea is you just posting a bunch
of ridiculous shit like just to do it
right.
And you maybe your intelligence level,
maybe several steps above the stuff
you're posting and you're kind of half
trolling and being shitty at the same
time before the idea to form a trolling,
trolling,
taking the new.
It's a new turn.
The but by the same,
by the same shit posting like you know,
it's shit.
Is that the idea behind it?
The value of what you're posting is
shit.
Right?
The description,
right.
That
you're aware of it when you're doing it
right.
That's why it's like trolling yet and so
the idea is just to rile people up who
were like Hillary supporters or
something.
Huh?
This is the most bizarre political event
I can ever remember in my life is too
much.
I don't handle it well.
I try to not watch the news and stuff
and it's still just so pervasive.
You have
to watch it.
I know.
It's like a sports that you have to
follow.
It's like a sporting event you have to
There was a video that a bunch of
celebrities put out that is so god damn
confusing because it's celebrities
telling you to go out and vote and
they're showing all this stuff that
makes both of them look fucking
terrible.
It's such a confusing video because
there's all this stuff about Bengazi,
all this stuff about like the Hillary
Clinton scandals,
the various scandals is playing on in
the background while I'm ironman fuck's
named Robert Downey jr talks and then a
bunch of other celebrities talk and some
of them are like really ridiculous,
like some of them were starting to cry
when they're talking.
This is so important.
Being a part of that decision,
I might think it's not important.
I think you are not important,
but that's not true and the only one,
but there's another version of this that
has.
Okay.
Maybe maybe this is different.
I think I've been hoodwinked.
I think this is probably the real one
because it says save the day and the
channel saved the day and the other one
is someone.
Someone made it and took their speeches
with some of their imagery,
but then put a bunch of stuff in the
background showing like how fucked up
the Benghazi situation is.
How fucked up Donald Trump's past is,
how many people are suing trump
university and then it all.
So it makes this thing about saving the
day.
I guess most of what saved the day is is
like anti-trump,
but when you see the video that whoever
has created this put together online,
it shows a lot of fucked up hillary
stuff too.
It's really lets you know like,
hey,
you ain't saving shit stupid.
We're the other.
It's changing this culture and memes and
everything else.
It's,
it's completely changing what the role
of politicians is,
what the,
what the president actually does.
Whereas it used to be like you'd need a
representative to ride on horseback or
whatever and and now it's.
We don't really need any of that
anymore.
And so now it's just,
these are just people that are going
around giving pep talks because by
necessity they have to raise a certain
amount of money so they have to go to
each town and say,
America,
I liked America the most.
The other guy doesn't like America the
best and I support the troops the most.
The other person doesn't and they're
just giving the same talk and every.
They're not actually.
I don't know how much,
how they could have any time to actually
be doing the job.
You know,
they're just going around marketing and
it's kind of by necessity and how about
when they have,
when they're marketing and they have
another job already,
like they're already a senator or
something like that and they don't,
they don't give up the job,
they just start campaigning.
Like when the camp,
when the president was campaigning for
reelection,
like a good percentage of him working
with him,
doing his job was him campaigning to do
it again.
That's what the fuck that's.
And it's getting earlier and earlier
too.
So we'll,
we'll be done what we've been hearing
about this for like two years now and
then after the election we'll maybe get
like maybe a year break before they'll
start in on what the,
what the next election cycle is going to
be and everyone thinking this is very
important and very exciting and it's
time to change things.
Very important.
I don't have a solution,
but I do have a question like,
wouldn't it be better for everybody if
you couldn't advertise better for
everybody if you also couldn't pay
people to put promos up or posters up,
if that was completely off the table.
Like maybe you could say,
listen,
okay,
here's the deal.
People can support your campaign.
You know,
they can,
they can get behind you,
they can endorse you,
but no ads.
Yeah.
Like we need a cultural spam filter.
Because now even if these people
genuinely say it's just this person who
genuinely wants to make a difference as
super smart that they know just how to
do the job,
they won't be able to write.
They have to.
They have to go out.
Yeah.
Obama's very bright dude.
Seems like a hard working guy,
but he's still,
you know,
he's just out there giving pep talks and
having to,
you know,
raise funds and I think it's ridiculous
to try to pretend that one person is
even capable of running the United
States government.
Something so monstrously huge
encompassing the irs,
the CIA,
the NSA,
the FBI fucking garage down the line
with every union and all the different
special interest groups that he has to
know.
They,
they all contribute to his campaign.
He has to help them out.
There's just so many different people as
to me from other countries.
There's so many different foreign
interests he has to address.
There's so many different deals that are
on the table.
How the fuck could he.
It's like having 100 jobs and why not?
Rather than going to each small town and
giving the same speech.
I mean we have the Internet,
we have TV.
Why not just get together and have like
a podcast or like once a week where you
just talk about what you're doing and
what your plans are and you're shooting,
you're getting together with certain W,
whatever experts you're working with and
giving a summary on what's actually
happening and how things work so people
are involved and understand and can give
feedback on it rather than 100 percent.
I mean that's because right now there's
just no substance and even.
I used to think that debate,
the debates were like,
oh,
okay.
Finally there they're going to be
something.
You know,
they're a of substance,
but it's just you have one person on one
side,
one on the other in and they're just
digging their trenches and they're not
open to the other person's idea.
They're not having a conversation like,
I wish I wish someone would just make
these two children just sit down and
have a fucking conversation over over
tea or something like that.
Because all they're trying to do is
when,
yeah,
that's really what they're trying to do.
Trying to employ the best strategy for
success.
They're going to figure out a way to get
in that fucking White House.
Yeah.
It's just so stressful.
It's so strange and it goes along the
same lines to me is there's some certain
things that have been around for a long
time that I'm like,
how did they ever let this get in?
Like if you are operating for the
greater good of the people,
not for the most amount of money that
you're going to receive for making these
decisions,
but if you're operating for the greater
good of the people,
why would you let pharmaceutical drug
companies make advertisements?
Why would you let politicians make
advertisements?
Why would you let all the cigarette
industry?
How the fuck is that still around?
Yeah.
How?
Hi,
how are you still allowing that and then
you're saying that marijuana should be
illegal.
I mean there's so many of these ancient
things that are so ridiculous that had
been around forever.
Well,
and then things like the dea,
which just a.
What was that three weeks ago when they
decided what?
They weren't going to reschedule it even
though everything's going that direction
clearly and everything.
There's nothing pointing the other
direction,
right?
There's no.
There's not like,
well,
we have some conflicting studies and it
looks like marijuana could possibly do
some sort of memory damage or this or
that.
No,
there's none of that.
Yeah.
It's just,
it's,
it's kind of like.
I remember the gay marriage debate.
It's like 10 years ago it was just like,
I don't care if you're the most
homophobic,
you have your religious beliefs or
whatever it is,
but.
But the inability to see that this is
happening,
that this is where it's going and you're
just wasting a lot of time on a losing
battle is kind of troubling that people
aren't able to look at society and be
able to make better predictions.
Well,
they got caught up in a lot of it is
religious.
A giant percentage of it is the beliefs
that people have about key people that
are based on whatever religion they grew
up with.
It's the only reason why you would care
nipple.
We're agnostic.
I guarantee you if you like,
did some sort of a survey and checked
atheist versus pick whatever religious
designation and saw which ones were
against gay marriage,
it would be almost all of them.
The religious ones.
So there's no like there's no secular
argument against it.
The only argument against that is,
look,
you fucking people got it.
Light Gay folk style.
Don't get married,
don't do it.
Like you can't get pregnant.
They can't rope you in illegally.
Entangled to some other dude that you
might get tired of blowing.
Okay.
Yeah,
just,
just don't buy into it.
It's kind of like A.
I feel that way about some of the,
um,
when,
when they celebrate like Jessica Jones
or something like that where a sec.
Finally there's like a strong female
leader and it's like,
it was Jessica Jones.
It's a TV show on Netflix,
like one of those comic book TV show.
It's just the idea of how dare you think
we should know that fee.
Been some new store.
They're like up epo or whatever it was.
John's capital.
Siri fucked up and he didn't know what
it was.
But the idea of have like a strong
female lead being being a shitty like
action movie,
but like women can make shitty mindless
shooter movies too.
Like what?
Why is it,
why is that a positive thing?
Rather rather than having like a female
be president in a movie or you know,
some,
some substantial already had that.
Angela Bassett was president in one
movie one time and.
But the big one was of course a Gorney
weaver in fucking alien.
She's the best bad ass chick ever.
Who's more bad ass.
She didn't have any fucking superpowers.
Just a woman who survived on a spaceship
with a fucking creature that nobody had
ever seen before.
That movie was the shit.
And nobody,
nobody disliked that movie because a
woman was the lead.
See,
that's where all this ghostbusters shit
falls apart.
You know,
people are crying,
sexism and all the sudden,
no,
it wasn't good.
It just wasn't good.
You know,
there's a lot of.
I haven't seen it.
What was that movie that everyone loves
the wedding movie.
The wedding planner.
No bridesmaids,
bridesmaids.
Everybody loves that fucking movie.
Like universally,
I've never heard anybody who saw that
movie.
I didn't think it was funny.
I've only watched like an hour,
but I was laughing my ass off.
It's fucking funny and it's just funny.
It's funny with it.
It's like when Sarah Silverman goes up,
she's not funny for a chick.
Fucking funny.
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly.
It's like that's when,
when it's just that it's undeniable
alien is an undeniable movie and it
doesn't matter if like you would if it
was brewed.
It's perfect.
It's perfect as it is.
So like the idea that we need a female
leader so badly that we're willing to
take this one that's embroiled in
controversy.
She's in,
she faints,
she's fainting.
If we bring it up,
we're a sexist.
You're not supposed to fall asleep when
you're just walking around.
This is a,
I mostly just don't like the idea of
anytime there's like another Clinton or
another Bush just because like someone
else,
their father made it or her husband or
whatever else made it.
So now they also get to,
you know,
and people are like,
oh,
I remember that name change.
I mean,
that's why we keep doing spiderman
movies.
There's another spiderman reboot.
We're going to reboot the whole.
I mean,
that's what we do.
We like to reboot things.
How many King Kong?
So they made it's fucking crazy,
you know,
a gang of the hawks.
There's three different guys.
Have been the hook in modern days.
Eric Bana,
right?
Um,
uh,
the,
the Ed Norton.
And then the last one was microflow.
Mark Rufallo who was also in this
campaign.
He's very politically active.
That microflow guy.
But yeah,
we're having a Clinton reboot,
right?
I mean,
how many,
how many times can they do a Batman
movie?
There are many.
You guys have been Batman.
Christian Bale,
right?
Ben Affleck,
Michael Heaton,
George Clooney.
More Batman's in anyone,
right?
That's the most reboots.
Or has it been superman?
Superman had a TV show plus w why?
Why bother after Christopher Nolan?
I mean he knocked it out of the park
with A.
Which one was that?
That was the last three with Batman
begins.
And I'm dark night.
And um,
he's,
he's the guy he makes.
He made inception and interstellar and
Fermento and whatever.
Christian Bale's to just a motherfucker.
That guy's great and every time he's
great in everything.
You know,
you watching you,
you've,
I'm sure you've seen.
I'm a serial killer.
What is it?
American psycho.
Psycho.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
And I really,
that's a disturbing book,
man.
It's somehow or another way more fucked
up in book form because it's way more
graphic.
Did you read it?
No.
Bret Easton.
Ellis.
I don't read fiction actually.
I've been meaning to.
Oh really?
Yeah.
I don't know why.
It just doesn't attach to me.
That's really common.
There's a lot of people that don't
really.
Yes.
Natasha zero and uh,
and Moshe,
Moshe,
Kasher.
They call a like game of thrones.
They call it make them ups.
They don't like fiction things because
he could just make up anything.
Oh,
now the dragon comes at Eatsa.
I love it on TV and I don't know,
I think that if I read more fiction I
would have a.
I think it would help my vocabulary and,
and um,
I'd be a better communicator possibly,
but I just don't attach to it.
Yeah,
I like it.
I like,
I like a preposterous science fictiony
type stuff.
I think that would be my way in like
stuff that dealing with physics and
future and technology stuff.
I like horror ones too.
I was always a huge Stephen King fan
just because it's just such a escape,
you know,
like to read about something that's just
fun but crazy,
you know,
he just get lost in someone else's
ideas,
someone else's creativity and the only
way they really get to express it fully
is to just make up an entire world,
you know?
Whereas like if someone.
I mean,
you obviously your creative when you
write a book about anything,
you could write a book about nature.
He could be a wildlife biologist that
writes an amazing book about nature and
you can be creative in your telling of
these stories and make it exciting.
But this is kind of a difference to me
when I'm listening to a song or I'm
watching a movie or reading a book,
I always try to think this is someone's
creativity.
Like this is coming out of a person's
brain.
Invented this whole idea.
That's the premise.
Yeah.
That's fascinating.
To me,
you don't have a mind for that for well,
like people who are into like creating
movies especially think that's a very
specific mindset of like looking at all
these different things and go,
oh yeah,
I've got to piece these together and I
have to have an arc and you have to have
a hero and I have to have with this and
I have to have a.
okay,
how do I,
how do I mix this up?
How do I make it good?
I know that's like when I watch,
when I watch like Christopher Nolan or,
or Quintin Tarantino or something like
that,
like the story is so good.
I'll,
I'll like get teary eyed just at the
story structure,
you know,
and,
and it'll end up being like,
that was perfect.
That's exactly how it needed to end and
I'm blown away by that and jealous
because I can't imagine myself ever
thinking of anything like that.
Yeah,
no,
there's some movies that you just walk
out of there you like,
I'm going to do better at whatever I do
today.
I saw that movie.
Yeah.
You only used to tell me all the time
that all the time it was Paul Mooney,
Paul Mooney used to always say that when
he wanted to write,
he would go get entertained.
It goes,
go see a show,
go see a live show,
go to the movies,
he goes,
go be entertained,
and then you'll write better.
Yeah,
I mean,
I,
I thought that with,
when I,
when I kind of got into doing more
science stuff with my work rather than
just straight stand up,
um,
I,
I realized that,
well,
if you want to be interesting,
like read interesting things,
be interested in interesting things,
you know,
just it just fills that.
Well,
I want to talk to you about that,
but before I talked to him,
the problem,
want to forget about this,
you,
um,
we were talking about what I think we
say Kratom I think we call Kratom and
um,
this is something that is in the news
right now because it's helped a lot of
people overcome opioid addiction.
Yeah.
And they're about to make it schedule
one meaning that it has no medical use
whatsoever.
No,
no.
Right,
right.
Highly addictive,
you know,
medical use.
We're going to take it right now.
Right now it's legal to do.
Boy,
they're going to get you record
retroactive.
No statue of limitations on the illegal
drug.
That takes like an hour to kick in.
And so,
and this is a very mild dose.
It is 12,
23,
1:23 and started asking weird questions.
I'm already on some.
Oh,
you already on some before taking this
shit all day long?
Uh,
no.
I pick it in the bar.
Do podcasts.
Well,
um,
I still have some pain management issues
from an injury and the injury because
it's crazy.
It's crazy story.
Uh,
so I was,
this is a couple of years ago,
I,
I was in the best shape of my life and I
was rock climbing like three,
four times a week and doing crossfit and
all this.
And I was like,
I,
I've always been lanky like this my
whole life and I actually had muscles
for the first time in my life and just
like felt like superman and,
and I was supposed to be.
Rock climbing is on my birthday.
And um,
and there's some fires in Sedona where
the rock climbing is supposed to be and
so,
so we went for a hike instead just to
see a little bit of Sedona as my first
time there.
And I was out with my friend Mikey
and he,
so he,
he was like this,
he was like three,
400 pounds,
I think he was like 400 pounds.
I'm like,
his whole life,
he's been a hugely obese.
And then he went on this diet that he
just drank coffee with butter in it for
like 40 days.
That's it.
That's all he ate himself out.
And then he,
uh,
how much did you lose in 40 days?
Like a thousand pounds,
200 pounds.
He lost like all of his weight.
And then he was like a normal person.
That sounds crazy.
Sign us 200 pounds in 40 days.
I don't know if it was that much.
It was significant.
It was like,
well over a hundred pounds
and he and then he.
So then he started doing like Jujitsu,
sort of like becoming active for the
first time in his life and was like all
excited about this.
And so he was like,
oh,
I have this,
there's this one shortcut that I want to
take my,
my wife will never let me,
so let's,
let's go ahead and do that now.
And I liked that.
It let me take a shortcut because it was
too high of a jump and then I,
and we got to this and um,
and I looked and I was like,
yeah,
that's too high.
And he was like,
so because he's been so huge his whole
life,
he has no idea of how high you can jump
from like this.
He's never been able to show before.
And,
and I know because I'm an adrenaline
junkie,
I love heights.
I've been climbing trees and jumping off
shit my whole life.
And um,
and I was like,
this is too high.
And he's like,
oh,
I think if we like climb down a little
it be okay.
And I'm like,
I don't know.
And I was wearing barefoot running shoes
at the time and then he was determined
he was going to do it in high psych,
so it was jumping from a cliff onto
another cliff.
And so if you couldn't roll and if you
landed it wrong and you rolled off,
it was like death on hundreds of feet.
And um,
and uh,
and so now I'm like,
I'm gonna Watch this guy roll off this
cliff because he's new to like physical
activity.
It doesn't know what the fuck he's
doing.
And he's about to jump off this thing.
That's the lie on the other side.
He's been carrying around an extra 100
plus pounds on his legs his whole life.
His legs are probably strong as hell.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I imagine.
And uh,
it was weird because he had like weird
skin hanging off everywhere.
It's tough from a,
like stretch marks and stuff.
But he,
um,
so he was,
he was determined and I was like,
I was looking at it and I was like,
you know what,
I think that I could make it.
Oh.
And then I can,
I can like at least be there so he make
sure he doesn't roll off this fucking
cliff up front of me.
God.
And um,
uh,
yeah,
I mean,
you know,
some of those things you feel like a
fool in hindsight.
And I was like,
you know,
I've,
I've jumped off stuff higher than this.
It's just that I'm wearing bad shoes.
I can't roll.
I'm going to have to take with my feet.
And I even told them,
I was like,
I'm going to be risking breaking a heel
because I broke a heel once before when
I was a teenager.
I love jumping off shit.
Um,
and so,
but it wasn't like the end of the world.
I was like,
you know,
if that,
if I break a hail,
it won't,
I'll still be able to get around.
It's just like a couple month thing.
And I,
in my mind,
this is the worst of what's going to
happen.
And so I went for it and I,
and I jumped and I landed.
And um,
and then,
and I,
as soon as I landed,
I heard both of my heels break.
Um,
it just the sound shot through my body
and I heard it,
it sounded like a branch,
like snapping underwater and,
and I,
I was,
I think I was in shock or something
because I just kind of turned and looked
down on my side.
I just broke both my heels and I started
just like that.
And so he thought I was like joking.
So he was just about to do.
I'm like,
no,
I really broke both my heels.
You're going to have to go around and
try to help me down.
And I started making my way down.
It took them like a half hour,
45 minutes to get to me and I had to
kind of,
do you remember when you were in school
and gym class to be able to do that crab
block thing where like your bellies
facing the air?
Um,
so I had my left foot just was,
was already like five times that size
within like 30 seconds.
And so I couldn't use that at all.
And then my,
my right foot,
it's just a,
I couldn't even tell if it was totally
broken or bruised,
real bad buys,
able to use my toes thankfully.
And so I had to Kinda like a w,
one foot crab walk down and then he got
around to me and was like a couple of
people were trying to help me for a
little bit too steep for anyone to help
me.
So I just kinda had to make it down on
my own once we at level ground,
which took like three hours of just like
it was,
it was an exceptionally annoying.
Uh,
it was,
I mean,
it was painful.
I scoot down for a little bit and then
I'd have to take a break for a few
minutes and just like,
and just like roll around in the fetal
position in pain.
And um,
and then um,
and he was like,
he was like,
so this was his dumb idea.
And on the way down he's just like
standing there like next to me waiting
for me,
like trying to lighten the mood by
telling me jokes and stuff.
I'm like,
dude,
this is not the time for jokes.
I am fucking pissed right now.
And um,
as I can,
it's fine,
it's going to be fine.
I just fucking need to focus and get
through this and got down,
went to the hospital.
I still,
I mean it hurt real bad and we had to go
to a second hospital because the one was
too full in and then,
I mean,
I thought it was bad,
but I thought I was like,
this is more than just a little break.
This is,
this is a pretty big break.
And another doctor came in and he's
like,
this is,
this is really serious and uh,
and your,
your heels and like 20 pieces.
Oh Jesus,
give extra so I could freak out.
Yeah.
It's um,
it's actually the,
the uh,
I,
I made an album about it called my big
break and that's Paul.
That's the cover art as the x ray of,
of my heel.
So say x Ray postsurgery.
It's got all the screws and plates in
it.
Yeah.
Um,
I don't know.
I imagine I have the originals around
somewhere.
Um,
and I'm maybe somewhere way back in my
facebook,
you could see some of the scars and
stuff like that.
It's real grill,
so I'm not sure if you'd be able to find
it or not.
Um,
but,
uh,
so,
so they put these metal plates in and
kind of screwed in the pieces of the
bigger pieces of bone that were still
there,
like where they wanted them to be
eventually because it's,
you can't just put the bone,
it's like if you,
if you snap like a candy bar and try to
put it together,
there's all these crumbs and stuff like
that missing.
And so they just kind of put it in place
where it was supposed to be.
And,
and,
um,
and they were like,
well,
hopefully it just kinda grows back and
comes together.
Right.
And um,
and it did,
it really the real issue was.
So they,
um,
the way they did the surgery,
they told me ahead of time,
ladies and gentlemen,
it's a first,
you see that,
what am I looking at right here?
Yeah,
what is it that's the from where they
went in with the surgery.
So,
um,
they,
they said they didn't want to do the
surgery at first because they're like,
this is really complicated surgery,
but if we don't do it,
don't think you're ever going to walk
right again.
And um,
why did they not want to do they weren't
qualified to do it?
Is that the idea?
No,
this guy was like this guy,
I got referrals and this guy was like as
good of theirs.
Theirs go further back than that.
There's some real disgusting stuff.
Um,
so um,
they just,
just the area that it's in and so
there's,
this is,
it's like a 90 degree angle that they
have to cut in,
in the corner of,
uh,
oh,
there we go.
That doesn't look good.
That.
And that was like,
that was like months and months later
too.
That was post surgery.
This is like four months after the fact
that it looks like what it looked like.
Tissue.
Yeah,
a lot of scar tissue and stuff.
So see where it's open there in that
corner.
Ripped open.
They're like,
I hope this corner doesn't rip open
because this sometimes happens with this
surgery and if it does,
you're going to be really susceptible to
infection.
And so I had,
I couldn't when I was at the time I
lived in Malibu and my place had like 50
steps and there's no way I could like
get up with groceries and everything
with two broken feet.
I could get around on crutches a little
bit.
But uh,
I ended up having to spend like three
months in my parents basement because I
couldn't care for myself or anything.
So like on top of having to cancel three
months of work and not have,
you know,
we don't have a safety net and having no
income and you know,
it was,
it was actually like,
I'm very grateful for my parents and
everything,
but it's,
you know,
it's just embarrassing and you're like,
oh,
I had to move him at my parents
basement.
I'm sure they understand them.
It's not like you just,
you know,
we were a loser and wake up on time,
lost your apartment,
you know,
this is just fuck man.
The worst part to come to start walking
again.
So after three months I got back on the
road and um,
and there was still this,
this little kind of wound that it opened
up,
wasn't healing and then I started,
it was just taking the,
they told me it was going to take like
at least six months to like start
walking and it ended up taking much
longer than that because so about four
or five months in,
I got on the road and then,
um,
and then a,
a doctor thought that maybe I was
getting a,
like just a topical infection and gave
me some stuff that wasn't good enough
for the infection.
And then,
um,
I started.
So about four or five months later I
started having fevers and then I went
into the hospital and then they're like,
you have a bone infection.
And I was like,
Ugh,
God.
Because they are like,
this is really serious because that's
when you can lose your foot and stuff.
If they can't stop the infection,
they just have to cut it off.
Jesus came back,
canceled every,
all my work again.
Came back to La.
They did a surgery and um,
and I was really thankful that I'd
happened to sign up for the health care.
This was right when the universal
healthcare,
it just came out.
Otherwise I'd be bankrupt from it,
but it was still certainly it was not
perfect at all.
Uh,
they wouldn't let me do stuff out of
state.
I had to get myself back to California.
And.
And what do you mean by stuff out of
state?
You mean surgical procedure?
Surgery and hospital checkups I had to
pay,
like do them in California because of
your insurance?
Yeah.
And so when I was in Wisconsin I had to
pay out of pocket for that and,
and it's like kind of not supposed to be
that way either,
but there was the,
I mean I would,
I would call and try to in the insurance
company will be like,
you need this one form.
Okay,
I call this company and they'd be like,
yeah,
only doctors can get that form.
And so I'd tell my doctor and he'd be
like,
no,
you can get that.
You have to go here.
And then it was like around and around,
sometimes I'd have to like pretend I was
a doctor and then I was on the phone
with people just to get this fucking
form that I need.
And so I paid out of pocket.
So I was like,
you know,
getting medical bills were piling up.
And so the second surgery,
what they did was they just cut out,
they took out the hardware,
that's what,
that's what got infected.
And then they kind of were where the
holes were from the screws.
They,
they kind of drill those out a little
bit and then they just cut off it cut as
big of a hole as they possibly could in
my foot to suck out as much of the
infection as possible.
And so I thought I was going to be in a
hospital for and I still hadn't walked
at this point.
And then I thought I was going to be
there,
like you'll be in a hospital for like a
week and a half or so,
two weeks.
And I was like,
okay,
fine.
I like,
I'm in.
I finally,
someone's going to be like,
taking care of me,
we're just going to get this done,
right.
I have my computer,
I was in good spirits and,
and getting a lot of work done and
stuff.
And um,
and then like two days later they were
like,
your insurance is saying that they think
you're better and you need to go home
and now we need to show you how to care
for yourself.
So I had to train me on how to.
I had to give Myself Ivy antibiotics
three times a day.
Yeah,
they had,
they,
they put ivy,
they put lines in my arm and I had to
like make sure that their sanitary all
the time.
And I'd have to get a minute.
Hold on a second.
That's a complex medical procedure.
Giving yourself an ivy dude.
I had to google it.
I like fucking Google.
What's the name of your insurance
company?
Um,
I don't know,
do I have the.
That's insane.
Um,
the fact I'm trying.
So that's the other thing is I have like
two different insurance companies.
So this is like health net and then
there's like this lakeside medical,
which one will never know which one is
like the I call one and they'd be like,
no,
that's your,
your other company.
I called the other one.
No,
that's kind of,
it was just a year of dealing with this.
So because of the fact that this was so
expensive,
they just decided to say,
fuck this guy,
let's make him do all the medical stuff
himself.
Yeah.
They were like,
have you ever heard of that before?
well he's a young guy.
He seems like he's in good spirits and
healthy.
Seems like a bright guy.
Like he could take care of himself.
I think it was the logic behind it.
And so let's,
let's get them out of here because it's
is expensive.
What's that?
Could you fight it?
I tried.
I was like,
what?
Your,
I can't do this on my own.
Then when they showed me what I had to
do,
it was so once I get the ibs hooked up
and I'd have to figure out how to like
get bubbles out of the lines and stuff
like that.
Like I was googling,
how do you get bubbles out of the lines
and that's literally what I say.
Then I had to,
the first time they showed me what I had
to do.
I,
I couldn't believe it.
They're like,
no,
watch this because you're going to have
to do this yourself.
And then so this huge hole in my foot
was packed full of gauze and they
started pulling out this gauze.
I didn't know how big the hole was at
first,
but then it was like one of those magic
scarves on calming.
Yeah.
And then they're like,
so you're gonna need to take this out
and then look in here.
Look in your whole.
You're going to need to clean it out and
like clean off your bone and stuff.
Oh,
everyday you could see your bone it.
Oh yeah.
I had to like scrub it off and then.
And then I had to pack it full of Shit
again and all of this with like wearing
gloves and a mask and everything like
that.
And,
and then I,
and then I'd have to like put a rubber
thing on to,
to take a shower.
I had to do this three times a day and
then I couldn't sleep either because I
needed the IB antibiotics had to be
every eight hours and it took two hours
to do them.
And so I could never get like a full
eight hour rest.
So I was like mad it up.
Uh,
took two hours for the IB fluids to go
in and kick in.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
So you have to do.
Oh,
so I'd hang up these bags and stuff.
I'd hook up the ivs,
then I'd spend 20 minutes with my foot
and then,
and then after,
after like a few weeks of that,
see,
they would always be like,
okay,
we can get you another home visit or
something like that.
It would be like a week after I actually
needed it because then I got,
I got this vacuum Suction Cup thing that
they put on my feet and um,
and they,
uh,
and it just kind of sucks all the
infection stuff out and,
and uh,
uh,
gets,
gets rid of it,
closes up and creates like blood flow
into that area.
So it generates the things that actually
work amazingly well.
But,
but so then I had this device and like a
vacuum and I started performing again.
I'd have to like take this vacuum off
myself and like close up my fucking foot
hole and then go on stage and perform
and then get off and put this back on,
back on.
And,
and,
uh,
I remember it because I had before I,
before I,
um,
I went through a big breakup,
before I broke my feet and when I,
and I had been in like 12 years of
relationships.
And so I was like,
I'm not dating for a year.
I'm not going to have sex.
I'm not going to think about women for a
year.
I'm just going to get my head straight
and I did that and it was great and got
tons of work done and then then when I
started getting back into things,
broke feet,
it was a no,
I had already I broke my feet during
this time,
which,
which helped when like can you just
don't have a sex drive with both of your
feet are broken and um,
and then,
but when I started getting back into it
and like I remember I brought a girl
back back to my hotel when I still had
this fucking vacuum,
uh,
on my foot and I was just like,
it was fucking awkward and I hadn't had
sex in like a year or two.
So I'm like trying to figure out how to
have sex again.
I got a fucking vacuum attached to my
foot hole.
Was your health like,
I mean,
what kind of like energy levels did you
have?
It would seem like if you're going
through,
your body's trying to repair itself for
such a long period of time it has to
wear on you,
right?
Yeah.
I mean,
it was,
it was more just the depression of it
all in,
in the stress was,
was harder than I was getting plenty of
sleep and stuff,
but was,
it was a depressing time,
but ultimately it was kind of,
it was kind of good in a way in building
and some,
a little bit.
I mean,
I got a good elvanto um,
I,
so,
I mean when I started in Boston and I
started doing comedy,
I was fearless.
I would do like a ballsiest stuff,
always trying new material and I just
did not give a shit and I got a lot of
attention for it and I caught some
breaks early on and once I started
making money and doing the road it was
like,
then you're worried about like getting
negative comment cards and all this shit
and that's like my livelihood.
And it was,
it was just watering down what I was
doing and I wasn't fearless on stage
anymore.
Um,
it.
And,
and so after breaking my feet and having
three months of my parents' house,
it kind of was just like,
I don't give a fuck anymore.
I'm just doing exactly what I want to do
and it was,
it was,
uh,
it really created a change in,
in my career.
I thought that album and like the new
act that I'm doing now or the best that
I've ever been.
How long ago was the incident and the
accident?
And how long did it take you to recover?
Um,
so it was,
it was two years ago,
um,
in May.
And then I about one year in I started
using a cane and then that's when I,
that was really hard when I started
using a cane because I was like,
yes,
the light at the end of the tunnel.
And then I realized,
oh,
every other step that I take for the
rest of my life I think is going to hurt
just every other step.
And so it's like always.
That's why,
that's why I take kratom before podcasts
because there's always a part of my
brain that can't stop talk.
I can't stop thinking about my stupid
fucking foot.
Is it hurting you right now?
Um,
no.
Right now it feels fine,
but when you would walk here,
um,
well the Kratom helps,
but if I,
if I'm not on that most days it's just
like having a pretty sore foot and then
some days,
like probably now it's coming along
better than I thought it would actually
about three days out of a month.
I have like this streak and I don't know
what causes it.
I don't know if it's inactivity,
the weather,
whatever.
I have a streak of like three days where
I can just be where I should be using a
cane again,
where if you saw me it'd be like,
what's wrong with that guy?
Years later?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Oh,
about a year and a half after I started
using a cane.
So I was on a cane for about six months
and then I started going without the
cane and just using it sometimes.
And uh,
yeah.
So it's been quite an ordeal.
Are you doing any exercising?
Actually,
I'm as crazy as this might sound.
I got back into rock climbing.
Um,
I know,
I know how that sounds.
Hear me out.
I only do indoor stuff.
So here's what I can't do,
I can't run or jump,
I can't do any quick activities and I
couldn't,
I couldn't do like squats or anything
like that on it.
Um,
but what I can do is slow,
deliberate movement that will help with
flexibility.
Right now it's mostly flexibility and
mobility issues and nerve damage issues
like the bones.
Totally fine.
Can you,
um,
stand on your tippy toes?
Can you stand on the balls of your feet?
I can a little bit on my bad foot.
I can't do like a,
I can't do a calf raise like a one
legged calf raise on you.
Could you bend down with your heels up?
Could you go all the way down?
Like could you stay on the balls of your
feet and then
Oh,
down in the squat position with your
heels off the ground.
I'm a little bit
what I was thinking of.
There's a thing called the Hindu squat
and what a Hindu squad is.
It's a bodyweight squat and I'm a big
proponent of it.
I love them.
I do them all the time and I do them in
sets of like 150,
160.
Sometimes when I'm in really good shape,
I do 200 at a time and then I do.
This is my main leg workouts.
I do those and then I do kettle bell
squats afterwards,
but the thing about the Hindu squats is
it's all body weight.
You don't use any weight.
Sometimes I put a weight vest on,
but most of the time I don't do any
weight,
but if you look at that diagram up
there,
you see when you go down your heels come
off the ground,
your hands go behind your heels and then
as you go up your hands stay parallel to
the floor in front of you.
So you go.
As you go up,
you push off with the balls of your feet
and not with your heel.
So as opposed to a regular,
a regular squat.
Rather if you had weight behind your
back with a bar,
that weight would be on your heel.
You would actually concentrate on
keeping it on your heel,
concentrated on keeping your.
You know,
when I do squats with weight,
I look up,
look straight up,
so I make sure that my spines and
alignment,
but there's a lot of weight on your heel
there.
Yeah.
With the squats.
No,
actually that doesn't the weight on the
heel that like the heels totally fine.
Um,
it's,
it's more of a mobility issue and,
and like all the tendons and stuff like
that that they went through during the
surgery and all the nerve damage from
it.
So like actually going up on my toes is,
is one of the harder parts maybe be a
good thing to break everything up in
there?
Yeah,
it does.
When I do like a really intense hike,
um,
my foot feels better.
Oh Man.
Yeah.
Well you should definitely do these then
I guarantee you they would help.
I want to get on the fucking Joe Rogan
program it.
Tell it,
tell me,
uh,
give me a rundown.
Everything I needed to do.
I want to start a.
I was in the best shape of my life and
in this whole thing it made me fall out
of all of it.
And I would love to get back there again
to you if it's just a mobility issue,
if you don't have actual pain,
your heel,
I bet you can get back to it because I
know a lot of guys have plates all over
their body.
They have all sorts of different things
holding their bones together and they
get back.
Yeah.
And I do.
I need to like break up the scar tissue
and all that kind of stuff to see woman
here.
Okay.
She's doing it wrong because you're
actually supposed to go on the balls of
your feet and you're supposed to drop
your ass all the way down to the back of
your calves.
People doing youtube things that to do
it right.
It was a guy named Matt fury is kind of
an odd duck.
But uh,
he's a big proponent of them.
He's got a bunch of videos of him doing
it online.
Here you go.
That's how you do it.
See how this guy,
as he goes down his heels come off the
ground and they touches the ground in a
circular motion.
And then he brings his arms parallel in
front of him.
These are great.
I think I could do that there.
Super easy.
For the first 10,
20 gets a little harder than than 30.
He gets a little harder than 40.
It's a little harder.
And then he started hitting like 90 and
you go,
okay,
I got 60 more of these motherfuckers to
go.
And then you know,
your,
your legs get super fatigued.
But that's like what I like to do for
legs.
I start off with Kettlebell swings just
to sort of get everything loosened up.
I do it light for a couple sets than I
do heavy ones.
And then from there everything's all
warmed up and loosened up.
Then I get into those Hindu squats and I
just do because I feel like that's
something that's always hard to do.
Like I went hiking in Nevada with a
couple friends of mine that were very
fit.
My friend Dan Dodi who was.
We were doing a TV show up there and
he's the.
He was the camera man and he was much
better than me at doing these things.
And it was realizing when I was doing
like,
God damn it,
this is a very specific thing,
like if you do it all the time,
if you like a camera cameraman,
especially have the get in some really
incredible shape and they do these
outdoor shows because they're constantly
carrying this camera and walking around.
So like if you were doing a show on
hiking and you had a guy following you,
this guy has to follow you.
All of a sudden he's carrying a big ass
fucking camera
as he's sitting there shooting what's
supposed to be you doing some impressive
thing.
Exactly.
He's the real athlete.
But uh,
just the ability to
pick your body up and down for long
periods of time.
Just hiking.
You know,
like you could lift weights and you can
do a lot of stuff that you feel like,
oh,
I'm in pretty good shape,
but it's the monotonous grind.
Have hours and hours of going up hills.
You Go,
Whoa,
this is something different.
Well,
it also with hiking it,
your,
your foot goes in all these
unpredictable angles and that that is
what's helping the most.
Like I,
I do stretches and stuff like that,
but I feel like the stretches,
I'm not mixing it up and was like,
I do a yoga has been helping when I got
back into rock climbing,
my gym had a yoga class so I was able to
do that.
I can't balance on one foot a little
bit.
Not very well.
Does it get shaky or like my,
my also,
I mean fortunately it was my dominant
leg that got hurt.
So I think it will keep on recovering
well because there was a little more
strength to start with,
but my calf is pretty atrophied and
everything,
so it's just also have to get a lot of
strength back.
Which was um,
I've also of been,
when I fill out a exercising,
I've been a little lazy about it too.
Isn't that interesting how easy that is
to do,
like even for me,
like I've been exercising my whole life,
but if I take a few days off,
I know I have to get back to it.
But part of me is like,
come on man,
fuck this.
I've never been an exercise guy,
but I was probably working out like
doing something about three hours a day,
like rock climbing or swimming,
jogging or crossfit or doing some boxing
stuff.
Yeah,
it was like,
I was just like on a kick because I also
had,
I had quit drinking,
which I drank again now.
But uh,
I quit drinking and smoking cigarettes
and so I was,
he smoke cigarettes now.
Um,
I'm vaping now.
I started after I started drinking
again,
cigarettes followed shortly after and
then I saw I've been smoking cigarettes
for about a year,
which I fucking can't stand cigarettes.
And so I've been vaping and I'm hoping
in like three months I'll be able to go
from vaping to chew.
I don't think I want to do the dip.
I tried dip recently.
It gives you a quite a buzz.
Yeah,
it's interesting stuff actually
accidentally swallowed it.
Um,
but here's a,
one of the most interesting things that
I learned from the injury was,
was how,
how your physical health or wellbeing
alters your perception of the world.
Like I,
um,
have you ever heard of the study?
They,
they,
they do like the hot and Cold Cup study
where they have someone come in to fill
out a survey,
you know,
that's what they tell them and then a
person gets in an elevator and they,
uh,
and there's,
there's someone in there like
confederate,
an actor is in there that's like,
here I,
my hands are full,
could you hold this cup for me?
And it's either like a hot cup of coffee
or whatever,
or cold drink and the person says,
sure takes the drink,
goes up the elevator,
gets off,
gives it back to them,
you know,
says Bob goes in and takes the survey
and then afterwards,
and this is what it's actually about.
Afterwards they go,
did you meet anyone in the way in?
And I actually,
someone I met someone in the elevator
and then they'll,
they'll be like,
so,
uh,
can you,
can you describe that person?
And if they had,
if they had the hot drink,
they'll,
uh,
they were more,
um,
they would more often describe them as
being like warm or friendly.
And if they had the cold drink,
they would,
they would describe them as like cold or
distant.
And,
and the idea is,
is that,
that,
um,
that the way our,
our brains evolved kind of these,
these higher ideas of,
of what like being distant as a
personality trait or whatever means he
has to be built over this preexisting
kind of a five senses kind of software.
And um,
and so,
so there's all these metaphors for,
so you call someone like bright or you
say we're having a deep conversation or
shallow.
So a lot of these ways in which we
describe life is,
is kind of used through these physical
metaphors.
And I remember when I,
when I broke my feet,
I remember thinking the whole fucking
world is broken.
Like I remember thinking like eyes on
eyes going down this mountain for like
three,
three hours.
And I wasn't just worried about my feet.
I also like in the fucking political
system is like everything just seemed
broken like the whole world.
And then I also remember after I got the
second surgery,
after the bone infection and stuff and
having to change all this,
I remember feeling like,
like something like this nagging feeling
that I couldn't get over as like some
things like missing from my life.
There's just this deep like hole
somewhere in my soul in my feet.
And then one day I realized I'm like,
oh,
there's a fucking hole in my foot.
There's an actual hole in my foot.
That's what's missing.
And,
and just how much that,
that your,
your physical senses can alter what your
perception of the world is for sure.
How you feel physically.
Yeah.
Changes how you interact with other
people.
It changes how people perceive you.
Attend changes,
the kind of conversations you have
because maybe you'll have more
enthusiasm or energy or friendliness or
whatever it is that when you engage
with.
Yeah.
Then you can have two broken feet and
they can give you morphine.
You going to be like,
oh,
life's fine.
That it's going to be great.
How do you go from morphine to this
Kratom stuff?
Oh,
this kratom stuff.
I just discovered like three weeks ago,
I haven't,
I haven't taken painkillers in like a,
and this isn't a,
I don't know,
I think the research is out on it.
I'm not saying people should do Kratom.
It's working for me.
Um,
do you ever try a cannabis edible?
Cannabis?
Yeah,
I like edibles.
I don't,
I'm not a big weed smoker.
I probably smoke like twice a week maybe
at the most.
That's hilarious.
Only in California.
Can you say that?
A big weed smoker.
I take days off.
I have like,
I've probably,
yeah,
probably once or twice a week.
I have like a hit of weed,
but I'm out of bolts help a bit and uh,
the CBDS,
I don't know if I can't tell if the CBDS
are helping or not.
Um,
it seems like they do a little bit,
but I'm still experimenting with some of
that stuff.
The kratom I just,
I was just in,
um,
I was in Wilmington,
North Carolina,
uh,
doing this dead crow club and I had,
I was,
when I'm doing lots of standup and on my
feet in one place is when it seems to
have a lot of trouble and um,
and I was just like bitching about it
because I was just having,
it was one of those three days where I
was just having a rough few days with it
and they're like,
you should go to the Kratom bar.
I was like,
what's that freedom bar?
These bars that they have,
like Kava and Kratom and stuff.
And so I went pretty skeptical,
especially when something's legal.
I'm like,
okay,
that's not going to do anything.
Um,
and I,
I had some.
And right away it was a,
uh,
it,
like within an hour I was like,
oh,
my foot feels perfect right now.
And I walked just like a normal person
when I'm on the stuff,
I'm a little skeptical,
I imagine.
I imagine there's some addictive.
Uh,
I,
I had a scientist sent me a paper about
it and I guess there are some side
effects.
I haven't read them all yet,
but it's just not near what,
like any other pain killer,
why are they making it a schedule one?
Is there a real issue that people could
die from it or what's the ld 50 with
his,
which is if people don't know lethal
dose at 50 percent,
meaning that if you give 100 rats a
certain amount,
50 percent of them are going to die at a
certain.
Yeah,
I have no idea.
Um,
I,
I haven't done enough research into it.
Um,
and,
and I imagine it's not that well
studied,
which I understand why,
you know,
the FDA or whatever,
can't just have companies making,
you know,
who knows what they're putting in a
bottle.
Right.
I get that.
Um,
but,
but I mean if you look at what people
are saying about Kratom people that
people that are trying to manage their
pain and nothing else works or
everything else is really addictive or
makes the movie or whatever.
This stuff is like,
I feel like very energetic,
energetic and enthusiastic and just
sharper than normal when I do it helped
people get off of opiates.
Um,
because it's,
it's a partial opiate.
Um,
yeah.
Yeah.
I don't know exactly what that means.
Stuff all the time.
How come you not like reading things on
it?
I'm
a smart guy.
Yeah,
probably taken it like 15 times now.
That's it.
Yeah.
Something like that.
Okay.
Um,
and twice in front of me.
Yeah.
Well I call that once.
That will count that as one eye.
It's going to be illegal next month.
So I'm like,
I'm going to try this stuff and see how
it feels.
What's the justification?
Is there any justification for the,
a scheduled one classification.
Is it something that people need to
worry about?
I mean if you look at how,
how the uh,
the Da just just didn't reschedule
marrow,
which has.
Think about it.
If you're them,
if you reschedule marijuana,
it's basically like you're saying,
hey,
should we just get rid of our own jobs?
You know,
should,
should we just,
should we just make a law that gets rid
of our jobs and that's a way of looking
at it.
That's a cynical way of looking at it.
The people who aren't aware of the
reality of all the facts and statistics,
they will look at you and go,
well,
that's ridiculous hippie bullshit.
But no,
nope.
It's not know that that
is going on.
And the was no way out.
There's no other way around it.
Yeah.
I mean the,
the,
the maps,
um,
organization which is actually
sponsoring my tour that I'm doing,
they have,
when I've had them on maps,
the Multidisciplinary Association of
Psychedelic Studies.
Um,
and they're,
they're the ones doing the MTMA trials
and stuff for ptsd and whatnot.
And they say they actually like working
with the FDA.
The FDA is not the problem at all.
It's the diy.
A bunch of cops.
Yeah.
Bunch of.
Listen,
one of the big issues with medical
marijuana or legalizing marijuana is
prison guard unions,
which is kind of hilarious.
Yeah.
It's like they are literally trying to
keep things illegal so they keep their
jobs.
So they have more hours.
Exactly.
It's crazy.
It's again,
one of those things.
It shouldn't be legal,
just like advertising drugs.
It's one of those.
Well one was when Nixon scheduled it in
the first place,
he hired a team of scientists and all of
these different different politicians
and different,
different experts in different fields to
advise him and then they advised him to
not schedule it,
to have it be legal and focus on
treatment for things.
And he was like,
nope,
we're doing.
We've got to get rid of these hippies.
Well that's what it did.
It really.
And this was something that came out
over the last year,
I don't know,
it was a freedom of information act or
whatever it was,
but they released some papers that
showed that what the drug war was truly
all about was the civil rights movement
in the hippies,
the antiwar movement and the civil
rights movement and that they were
trying to attack the leaders of the
civil rights movement and the leaders of
the antiwar movement.
And one thing they all had in common was
marijuana and LSD.
Mushrooms.
I'm sure too because.
So that's when the sweeping psychedelics
act of 1970 was passed.
It was all passed under the guise of
attacking the political forces that were
trying to take Nixon out of office.
Nixon was such a piece of shit.
No,
such a horrible,
horrible piece of shit when you're
really.
When you go back and see what that guy
did and who he was and what he stood
for.
It's
wow.
When you're like getting impeached,
I have to resign.
Wouldn't you like go back and look at
the things that he did and be like,
you know what?
Maybe we do a Redo on that whole
presidency and whatever he did,
just that.
We,
we reexamined that.
Yeah.
All the different things
was involved in.
Yeah.
They should have gone over every one of
his.
Everything that he passed with a fine
tooth comb,
but you got a crooked office.
I'm not a crook.
He was a real cook.
Will scary guy.
I have,
um,
I might take on,
on why all of that happened was because
of psychedelics.
Psychedelics have this testable effect
on,
um,
uh,
a person's openness.
So if I'm like,
there's big five personality indicator
that's not perfect by any means,
but uh,
it's,
it's used quite a bit in psychology.
So you have conscientiousness,
like I'm low in conscientiousness,
I'm a very disorganized person and I'm a
kind of messy.
I'm a agreeableness,
I'm a little low in agreeableness,
like I liked to argue with people and
stuff.
And then there is stability or sometimes
called neuroticism.
I'm in the middle there and then there's
extroversion also in the middle.
And then there's.
So if you're very high in openness,
that means like you not only are you not
averse to novelty or you can't get
enough of it,
you love new restaurants,
traveling,
meeting New People,
having,
uh,
you know,
going on adventures and,
and if your in the side effect is you're
the kind of person that maybe ends up
not having respect for authority and
ends up like getting in trouble with the
law or you're a little overly
spontaneous or a little too adventurous
and you break your feet or whatever it
might be.
Are you a Tarot card reader?
Yeah,
I know it sounds a lot like Taro cards
and really some of these things
shouldn't be taken much more seriously
than Tarot cards,
but no,
I do a nice job of you.
So you asked,
you asked people questions like,
um,
do you consider yourself a clean person?
Like strongly agree,
strongly disagree,
where wherever in between,
and so you're filling out questions like
that and that's how it's kind of
determining and it's self evaluation,
which there's problems there or there's
this,
uh,
there's a website called apply apple
sauce.
You'd go to it in and plug it in and it
goes through everything you've liked on
facebook and kind of determines your
personal traits based on that.
So if you're really low on openness,
you're like the kind of person that's
always been in their hometown,
kind of why go anywhere else?
This is great to traveling and scary to
you.
Your country is the best.
You haven't been to other countries,
but you know that your country is the
best and you're whatever church you're
brought up in is absolutely the right
one.
The other one's kind of sound
ridiculous.
And,
and outsiders are very scary and one
thing that,
um,
that psychedelics have been pretty well
studied to do now is that a single dose
of psychedelics will for a good amount
of time,
it often a year sometimes for the rest
of your life,
you'll be more open,
you'll rate higher in openness for the
rest of your life.
So people were doing more psychedelics
at this time and they were in.
So if you're low country or if you're
low in openness,
you're like,
you're often a pillar of the community
because you love laws.
Laws are your favorite.
You have this nice little playbook that
you can live life by and you wish there
were stricter so more people would
follow them.
So if you're a law maker,
these are your favorite people.
And then if these people were,
you know,
young and in college and like,
Oh,
what the heck,
everyone else is doing that.
And then all of a sudden becoming more
open and starting to question authority.
I think it did play a little bit of a
factor in,
in
I'm a little bit of the civil rights
movement.
So you think this was a conscious
decision by the powers that be to try to
limit psychedelics because they were
worried specifically about people
becoming more open?
No,
I think.
I don't think that they understood that
what was happening.
I think that psychedelics had this
effect.
I don't,
I don't think the government knows a
lot,
you know,
I
do either.
But they did do those other.
There's quite a few,
a lot of tests that went on with,
especially with Lsd,
with the military.
And then of course there was the
Harvard,
the very famous Harvard Lsd Studies,
which there's a good argument created
Ted Kaczynski.
I'm sure you're aware of that,
right?
You know,
the,
uh,
the was the German documentary,
believe it's called the net and it was
all highlighted how Ted Kaczynski the
unibomber was a part of these lsd
studies at Harvard.
They fucking fried that dude's brain.
He went to Berkeley.
He was probably crazy already,
but he went to Berkeley,
became a professor,
hoarded off all his money,
just saved enough money to implement his
plan and then bought that little cabin
in the woods and started killing people
who were involved in technology because
he was convinced because it was lsd
trips that and really he's right,
exceptionally bright guy.
Is that that?
That's.
That was what was kind of peculiar and
very scary about him like he was.
He was a genius.
Well,
that's how they found him out.
His brother recognized his crazy
rumbling scribe from the manifesto.
Brother met recognize the manifesto and
probably is thinking it might be his
brother anyway,
because when his brother came back from
the lsd trips,
apparently he was absolutely convinced
that technology was going to be the end
of mankind,
that we had to stop it in its tracks,
that it was just a Trojan horse and that
people were creating all this
technology,
but he was.
He was extrapolating who's seeing the
future and seeing everything and he's
right.
He's right.
I mean,
this is one of the things we're talking
about today as ai becomes more and more
of a reality.
You know,
even Elon Musk,
that famous speech,
he said that we're summoning the demon.
Like this is essentially what Ted
Kaczynski saw.
He's just in his crazy fucking head.
He said,
the way to fix this is to kill the algae
mean he's not idea poor execution.
Well,
not even a good idea,
just a,
an,
an odd reality.
The possibilities of the future.
Well,
so to clarify,
just so just so I'm not coming off like
I think it's a conspiracy.
I don't think the government knew any of
this stuff.
I don't think anyone knew a lot of these
effects.
I think.
I think like a lot of these cultural
memes are lost.
That happened.
It's just kind of something,
something that just kind of happened at
an idea that was stumbled upon that just
kind of ended up working in the interest
of the lawmakers.
So.
So I think people happened to start
taking more psychedelics because they're
popularized for therapy use and whatnot.
So.
So it just happened to be that people
started doing second Alex and it
happened to be during the civil rights
movement time and when people did take
psychedelics,
they happen and people didn't know this
at the time,
happened to be opening themselves up and
questioning authority more because
that's what they happened to make you
do.
And then all of a sudden there's a lot
more troublemakers out there for the
government.
And then the associate those two
together.
That's one of the things that I find
interesting.
I think it was timothy leary said this,
but apparently Terence Mckenna asked
Timothy leary and he denied that he ever
said it.
So no one knows who said it,
but it was one of those guys during that
time said that LSD has been known to
create a,
to cause people to go,
oh,
lsd has been known to cause people who
don't take it to go crazy.
Like that's a fun way more elegant than
that.
But,
um,
that
was,
uh,
that's really the way it is.
Like I know so many people that don't
smoke pot and when they hear I smoked
pot all the time,
they're like,
what's you smoke pot all the time?
Like how do you get things done?
Like potheads are lazy.
I'm like,
you're saying that you on smoke pot?
Like how can you say that?
Yeah,
I think it ended.
It affects everyone differently.
I know people that function at very high
levels and pretty much only do when
they're.
When they're on,
we'd like if,
if they,
if they stopped taking pot,
they become like,
become like dumbed down.
Like it helps them.
I don't know if it's a dependency or
whatnot but,
but some people like motivates them and
they can clean the house.
They can take care of shit and it
doesn't have that effect on me.
It makes me a little paranoid.
It makes me,
it,
it dulls me down a little bit.
I feel like hm.
But edibles,
I like edibles,
don't have that effect.
We'll do different strains have an
effect on any differently or.
I mean,
I feel like I've tried a bunch of
different strains and I can't find
anything that I like to at the end of
the night have a hit of weed if I'm like
by myself and watch a movie or something
like that,
or if I'm just hanging out with a friend
watching a movie in a social situation,
like I wouldn't want us.
The reason why I wouldn't want to smoke
weed like before doing this podcast is
because I would worry that I would get
in my head too much and,
and be over analyzing things.
Well also,
you're,
when you're doing something like this,
it's being broadcast.
Like if you and I were just hanging out
together.
Ridiculous Shit.
Yeah.
That's one of the things that we've done
on this podcast a million times.
Just just do it.
And then,
you know,
people say ridiculous Shit and say,
Oh my God.
So.
And then people realized,
oh,
everybody gets retarded when they smoke
pot.
It's not just me.
Yeah.
But I think that there's,
um,
there's some people like you that say
that the different strains don't affect
them any differently.
And I don't know that they don't,
I just can't figure out what it is,
what it is for me,
there's a real big difference,
particularly with like the cushions,
like any,
any like serious indicas,
like Degas have almost like a narcotic
effect.
I mean,
like I enjoy it,
I enjoy it,
but it's not what I would smoke before I
would go on stage,
see when I now I.
So here's the other problem,
I guess with my,
uh,
the way that I smoke,
when I first started my first got my
medical marijuana card went in to this
amazing.
The first time you walk into a
dispensary is like,
Oh my God,
the future.
Um,
and I,
you know,
went crazy.
I spent like 700 bucks.
Give me like money is no object.
Got Me,
I want the finest of every kind of
everything that you had have.
And then I realized that what happens
when you smoke the best of the best is
it for me.
I have one hit and then I can't,
I can't,
I'm in a coma,
one hit,
one hit and I am out or I'm like crazy
paranoid or a it.
But so now what I do is I just get.
Usually if I'm going to get we'd rather
than edibles,
I just get,
just get stuff out of the shake jar.
It's like five bucks a gram or whatever
the new shits on.
What is it?
Edible breast spray.
Is that what?
Is it like a cbd or is it Nan?
Nan?
No,
this would change your fucking life.
This,
uh,
has.
It's a thousand milligrams a dope.
I don't know how it works,
but you're only supposed to take six
pumps and you get a thousand milligrams
or something.
I don't know.
The whole thing is a thousand and it's
about,
that's not right.
Business agreements per spray.
This one.
This one 75.
Oh one.
Yeah,
there's different.
Smaller three,
75 milligram.
The whole bottle is that much.
But milligrams of spray.
Yeah.
Can I try it?
Yup.
That's probably under my tongue.
And then I think there's some that are
more potent.
This one's the most potent.
Anyway,
this one that's the most potent.
This is the thousand.
This was like a thousand milligrams
brown and you're not supposed to eat the
whole thing at one time.
You supposed to take like a nibble.
Well,
he makes it 1,502,
which is really problematic.
What I like about edibles is,
is how it's measured in.
There seems to be like a little
difference in between brands and stuff,
but I know five milligrams now thing 10
milligrams just kind of feel a little
good.
Fifteen milligrams.
I'm starting to get high 20 now I'm high
25 now I'm really high and I don't do
more than that.
I took 10 sprays and then did a podcast
and I was shitting my pants.
I think it might have been 12.
I might've done 12,
12 sprays and I did a podcast where the
whole time was doing the podcast as I
was skiing downhill.
Just hoping I didn't have to change like
an opening.
I didn't have to turn or avoided another
skier.
I was like,
oh Jesus.
Oh Jesus.
Stay up.
Just stay up.
Yeah,
I uh,
I,
I've been high on stage probably 20
times in my,
I've been doing comedy for like 12 years
or something like that and I probably
had 10 of those times where I felt like
I was giggling and having fun and it
helped the show and then I had 10 of
those times where I was just like,
I couldn't think straight,
I couldn't remember anything and it's
just not worth the risk for me.
It's total crap.
Shoot.
Yeah.
I,
one time I,
I said the setup of one joke with the
punch line of another joke and at the
time like it was just a really hot
audience and I was doing really well and
at the time they laughed and I was like,
I realized why I was like,
wait a second,
what are you guys laughing at?
And then I went back and I told both
jokes and explained what I screwed up.
So I like,
so I don't know what the fuck you guys
were laughing because what I said made
no sense.
Maybe it was just my inflection was
funny or something like that.
Wow,
that's funny.
Yeah.
Maybe they didn't want to seem stupid.
It's like one of those Dennis Miller
things laugh at as reference.
Oh yes.
You know,
it was a heartbreaker for me.
Somebody told me he doesn't really know
what he's talking about,
that he just comes up with these really
obscure because they work well in a joke
for him.
Mcdonald told me that,
hey,
he doesn't even know those things.
I'm like,
what?
Come on.
Yeah,
there is.
I just had a podcast talking with a guy,
like one of the reasons why we laugh at
things is because is because you're,
you're conveying that you have that same
knowledge.
You know,
that you get it,
that you understand the context for it
or whatever.
It's like advertising that you also know
this or you want to be in with the cool
crowd.
Crowd knows the joke.
Ah,
that's hilarious.
Yeah.
Is it hilarious,
Shane?
Because I want you to like me.
I know
it's weird that a lot of the,
some,
and I have plenty of movie references
and stuff now,
but it's,
it seems like a lot of the,
the,
uh,
quote unquote like smart comedy these
days is just like movie references.
It's like,
well,
why is that you watch a lot of TV,
like I don't get why that's smart that,
you know,
of this obscure show that like you just
watch tv,
you want,
you're going to alt rooms or something
is that,
is that happens in all rooms.
That's kind of.
But I mean I like art rooms as well,
but,
um,
but I,
I see that sometimes where I'm like,
that's just a movie that no one knows
about that you watched.
Like I don't get why that's smart.
That's not,
it's not like addictive.
Um,
intelligence is just like,
OOO,
other people don't know that.
So it seems like it's smart,
right?
You're clever because you remembered
something,
right.
That's pointless.
That was a complete waste of time.
So back to this Kratom stuff,
would you buy it?
Um,
you can get it on a head shop or you can
get it online for about another week.
That is so crazy.
And so then once it becomes schedule
one,
then it's like pot or heroin.
Like if you get caught with it,
you're going to jail.
Yeah,
I don't.
I mean the schedules don't necessarily
affect what the penalties are.
Like you'll get in more trouble for a
scheduled to cocaine then you will a
schedule one marijuana.
Um,
but so I don't know what the actual
penalties will be for,
but yeah,
I think it will be a scheduled one.
So they didn't have to establish
penalties but to the established
penalties based on science.
I mean,
did they have any logic behind what
they're saying or they just know.
I mean,
I,
I don't think they,
I don't think they establish and any
penalties based on science.
I don't think our prison system,
I think if the scientists were running
the prison system,
they would get scrap it and start all
over.
It'd be about reforming and
rehabilitation,
which is what it's supposed to be about.
And uh,
yeah,
I don't think.
I don't think we're doing great science
with our prison system in any way he
had.
The whole thing is just one person
telling another person what they can and
cannot put in their body where you can't
demonstrate that it's hurting anybody
else,
but that person,
to me that's like,
okay,
if that's the case,
well why is it okay to rock climb?
It was rock climbing is obviously
dangerous.
Why is it okay to Bungee jump?
Why is it okay to jump out of airplanes?
Yeah,
that stuff's all legal,
but you can't take this kratom stuff and
you can.
I mean,
you can,
uh,
where is it that they,
that they use those bullet ants and like
put them on their hands and like you can
trip doing that from the pain.
The pain is so intense that they trip
like they do with this during
ceremonies.
You can run a marathon and get into a
transcendental state because your body's
going through such torture that it goes
into this different part of your brain
that pushes you through it.
And um,
I mean you can hallucinate from lack of
sleep.
Um,
I,
for for like six months in my life,
I was trying to do the thing where every
two hours you sleep for like 20 minutes
or whatever for how long,
like six months.
Yeah.
I like trying like crazy weird different
things and um,
I go on all these weird different kicks.
Um,
it was a nightmare.
I started hallucinating after awhile.
So explain every two hours you sleep for
20 minutes.
I would set the alarm for like 20
minutes and yeah,
you know,
so I was,
it was before as a comedian and it was,
I was trying to,
I was working third shift in a factory
and then at the same time I was going to
school,
like just tech school for like a backup
plan.
I wanted to be a comedian,
but I also like very scared and didn't
know how to start and,
and um,
and so I was taking like 16 or 18
credits or something like that.
And um,
and then,
and I also had a social life,
so I was every two hours I just had a
time to take a nap.
And the crazy thing was,
is all ran together.
So if I,
if I was in there for a lecture,
um,
Monday and then,
and then on Friday there was a test on
it.
It was as if I just heard it,
it was like,
it was all one day,
can't we just talked about this
really weird.
And then I tried taking supplements and
stuff like that too,
like do energy boosting things and um,
and then one day,
one day my eye,
I got anal leakage from like all these
supplements I was taking and then I
decided to stop doing that.
It was just like,
it was like a Tan,
a oily
oil.
And I was like,
you know what,
this isn't worth it.
And I and I dropped out of school,
Jesus Christ and started sleeping
regularly and a weird life.
So if you went out like at 9:00 at
night,
you and your friends went out,
would you go somewhere at 11 and take a
nap?
Oh yeah,
yeah.
I couldn't go out that often.
But then most of the most ridiculous
things I've ever heard,
which she takes 20 minutes,
two hours later,
hey,
you guys want to eat?
And I got to take a nap.
I'll meet you guys there.
The thing was,
if you didn't like follow the schedule
really strictly is when,
when you'd get fucked.
So if I did end up having some drinks or
something like that and hanging out with
friends and not doing that nap or if I
was at work in
like,
I wouldn't get my break when I suppose
to,
um,
it would,
it would really fucked me up.
And I started hallucinating when I was
driving.
I fell asleep behind the wheel once and,
and uh,
like almost crashed my car,
went into a ditch and was able to drive
out of it.
And so I,
I've put an end to that experiment.
But yeah,
last week I couldn't believe I did it
for as long as I did.
Looking back on it,
it's like,
it didn't seem that crazy to me at the
time.
I don't know why.
What is that?
What is a 12 hours at 20 minutes?
Because it's half,
it's double right every,
every two hours.
So 12 hours at 20 minutes.
So you were,
you're essentially sleeping in.
So yeah,
like four hours a day I guess,
but by doing it in these long stretches
where two hours and 20 minutes,
two hours and 20 minutes.
You never really get into like heavy rem
sleep or.
No,
I don't think so.
I mean I,
I would,
I would start to,
I would like wake up in a little bit of
a dream state.
Yeah.
It was weird.
Weird.
Don't recommend it.
Did it for six months.
Yeah.
That's amazing that you have that kind
of like sticktuitiveness
when I get focused on something like.
Yeah.
Um,
but yeah,
I mean the point is,
is there's a million ways to trip.
You can't stop people from tripping.
Have you done the holotropic breathing
thing?
Um,
no,
but I just started hearing about this
recently.
Can you explain it to me?
Done it.
I've had a friend and my friend rob has
done it several times.
There's a,
there's people who really know how to do
it correctly.
There's a couple of different states.
Wolfen or what's that guy's name?
No,
no.
Wim Hoff Hoff.
Similar Wim Hof has some pretty some
psychedelic aspects to his breathing
technique.
I think too.
It definitely puts you in a state of
mind,
but the holotropic breathing thing,
somehow or another,
it forces your body into a psychedelic
state.
I've had actually a couple people that
have done it.
It takes awhile,
but through the specific style of
breathing cv find it Jamie.
So we could tell people what the fuck
we're talking about.
I haven't done it obviously,
but um,
I know of several people who do
Kundalini Yoga,
who have also done dmt and they say that
through coon Daleney practice.
When you get deep into it on a regular
basis,
when you do it daily,
you can achieve dmt like states on the
natch.
Well,
I went since doing dmt.
Now if I much mushrooms I can meditate
myself into a dmt state for like five to
10 minutes while you're on mushrooms.
Um,
I,
I did mushrooms in a float tank
recently.
I the.
And that was,
I don't know if it's because of how much
dmt I do or whatever,
but that was like a dmt trip to me.
Yeah,
it was like a little more controlled and
I could pop out of it anytime that I
wanted to.
But that was like for four.
I mean it would take me like five
minutes to get into it.
Um,
and then within five minutes,
I mean I had music playing inside of my
head and like these crazy,
like dmt stories happening in different
worlds that I was seeing and like
palaces and unlike other areas with like
scary,
weird clowns and stuff like that.
I was,
I mean I was the best trip of my life
and it was like full on hallucinations
because I did float tanks a couple times
just sober and I never really saw
anything.
I didn't like hallucinate or anything.
It was just kinda like meditation on
steroids.
I felt like
that definitely like meditation on
steroids,
but flow tanks or something where the
more comfortable you get with the more
experience,
the easier you slip into it.
So the quicker you slip into it into
like when I go into it,
I've done it so many times now because
it's in my house that I lay down and my
body goes up.
Here we go again.
Good to good times.
Just relaxed like I've done it.
Like it's not like when we go to,
can't believe I'm floating like those
states of mind that you get to when
you're in that I don't.
I can't believe I'm floating thing.
It takes you a while to relax.
Floating around.
You're bumping against the wall.
You're trying to center yourself.
I think that state though combined with
the mushrooms,
this has gotta be an accelerant.
Yeah.
So you've done that mushrooms and ended
up bringing on hallucinations for you as
well.
The strongest hallucinations honestly is
from too much edibles.
I've had too much edibles where I went
into the tank where I just got to when
we're going to die and you get in there
and I just have had full blown.
I had this one insane intense experience
where I felt like I was in a jungle,
like I was in a jungle and I was walking
through the jungle with these people and
they were all speaking the language and
I understood the language and in my mind
I was thinking in their language and
then I realized it.
I went,
oh my God,
I'm thinking of this other lane,
and then I'm out of it.
It went away,
but for the brief few moments where it
happened,
I mean I could remember feeling that the
dew on the ground and feeling the leaves
under my feet and walking through the
jungle with these people.
There's a lot of folks that believe that
the reason why we have instincts,
the reason why you know,
like an animal comes out of its mother's
body immediately goes to the breast and
instinctively start sucking at.
There's certain data that's just encoded
in our body and when it comes from is
the experiences of all the different
beings that existed before us,
that bread and eventually became us.
That this is just massive database of
experiences.
All your ancestors and they're all sort
of collected together.
So the idea is that occasionally you can
tap into some distant memory that's a
locked in like,
oh,
look what I found.
It's our high school yearbook.
This is crazy.
And you open up what's essentially your
Dnas high school yearbook from some
fucking Subsaharan experience when you
were half a monkey person.
Yeah.
Lakers are stored in DNA or something
like that.
Uh,
so that's,
I mean my,
my scientific mind would just say that,
you know,
it genes that are set up to have this
inclination to uh,
suck on your tits ended up being,
um,
passed on easier and,
and uh,
and whatnot.
But I have,
I've had full on.
I,
I remember specifically,
I had a mushroom trip like 10 years ago
where I must have taken a ton.
What happened was I was blackout drunk,
I took mushrooms,
I don't remember any of it.
And then I must've passed out and I just
woke up a trip.
I didn't know.
It took me like a couple minutes to
realize what was going on.
I was like,
am I dreaming?
Did I go crazy?
What happened,
I was like,
Oh,
I had mushrooms in the fridge.
I bet I gobbled those things.
And then I closed my eyes and I saw,
I saw like inside my brain was kind of
like a,
um,
the opening scene of fight club with
like electricity shooting around
different neurons,
blah,
blah blah.
And then it zoomed in and then I saw
like an individual neuron and then it
zoomed in and then I saw like a strip of
DNA and then it zoomed in and then I saw
like this little section of Dna and then
I,
and then it just exploded and I saw all
of life,
like going all the way back to.
So,
so I saw like all these different
battles and stuff and I'm like my
ancestors.
And then it went all the way back to
like being monkeys and all that and went
back to like this first little plant,
see the,
like springing spring sprouting and uh,
and then it was over.
And that's not.
I mean,
it wasn't,
it wasn't an accurate representation of
the history of evolution,
but it's still insane that my brain was
able to do that.
Pardon me?
Creativity though,
I mean,
isn't that you're bringing on mushrooms,
absorbing information that you already
know,
sort of manipulating it and
I think so.
I think it will be hard to have a
mechanism where
memories are stored and the problem with
that,
there's been studies done that show that
they exist and here's what they did.
They took these rats or mice and they
put a citrus spray in the air and then
they electrocuted their feet,
so every time they sprayed the citrus
smell,
they gave them a charge on their feet
and they're hurt them.
Their children who never experienced any
of this,
their DNA from these mice created these
children.
The children,
they would spray the citrus spray in the
air and they would automatically have
this terror response.
Like they would freak out.
They have accelerated panic level,
measurable.
So they realized,
and they weren't pregnant when they did
this or anything,
Huh?
Nope.
They.
They had a significant amount of time
between the actual experiences and uh,
when they're pregnant and you know,
rats and mice and shit,
they're,
they're not pregnant for very long.
Like I think a rat is pregnant for like
16 days or something like that.
And then they give birth,
something crazy like that.
I think that's what I am.
A hamster.
Maybe I'm,
maybe I'm confusing hamster,
but a hamster is pregnant for like 16
days and shit's out a letter and then 16
days later get pregnant again.
They could just,
so 21 days for a wrap.
Okay.
So,
um,
so it's real quick.
So they did these studies,
they,
they torture these little nieces,
zap their feet with that citrus spray in
the air and then there's a clear
indication that that memory of that
smell being attached to danger was
transmitted to their children.
That's incredible.
Yeah.
So this is why I think,
well,
it only makes sense.
I mean,
I don't know why people would be
incredulous about it because how else do
we get all these instincts?
I mean,
why would we assume that memories are
not somehow or another stored in the
very genetic meet like well members and
more bright?
It's in my hard drive.
I take it out.
I move it around.
Know your memory somehow or another is
in your consciousness.
We don't exactly know where.
We know when areas of the brain get
injured.
It affects memory.
We know that it could very well be that
the areas of the brain are involved in
processing memory,
not necessarily storing memory.
We don't know really.
Whoa.
Realistically that there's only one a,
like there's certain things like dmt is
produced not just in the brain but it's
also produced in the liver and in the
lungs.
They know this for a fact,
so it's one of those things where maybe
other things are stored in other parts
of the body.
We just assume that the very body itself
doesn't have some sort of memory,
but you know when you talk to people
that have limbs that have been removed,
they have phantom itches and things
along those lines.
That's one explanation for that
phenomenon is that you have a memory.
Your,
your actual tissue has a memory of that
limb.
Hmm.
I,
um,
well there's also a body map in,
in the brain and um,
yeah,
maybe that's why she's a good example.
Yeah.
But the mice examples,
probably the best one.
Well,
it does make me think of how,
um,
how information from our environment
can,
um,
can affect the fetal environment.
Like females,
females in lower income places or are in
lower parts of the social kind of
hierarchy in humans will tend to have.
And there's all these different species
that have where the species can kind of
pick,
depending on the environment,
whether it's going to be a male or
female.
So lower status females tend to have a
daughter is more in like the kings that
are higher status tend to have more sons
because sons,
sons,
if they're doing very well,
have the opportunity to make a bunch and
spread their genes on quite a bit more.
Um,
but a female,
even if it's like a lower status female
or low income or whatever,
female can always have at least a couple
of children.
Whereas a lot of men get kind of our
evolutionary dead ends,
you know,
if,
if a dudes brought up poor,
he's going to have a harder time finding
a mate basically.
So.
So it does seem like there's some
environmental influence that is somehow
recognized in the brain that has been
kind of selecting a little bit better
than chance whether you're going to have
like a male or female.
So there might be other mechanisms in
there like that can affect.
I just.
Yeah,
I can't conceptualize how,
how it would work,
but that's interesting.
I have,
I've read other studies like that and I
don't know enough about them,
haven't read it,
conceptualize why,
uh,
there would be a strong connection
between that smell,
which was always followed by an
electrocution.
That it's somehow to be stored in the
DNA of the animal,
which would be a smart thing to pass on
to them
children.
Oh,
would be.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Rupert sheldrake had an example about
this where he was talking about children
in inner cities.
They're not afraid of car accidents or
murder or a bank.
Robbers are real real threats that
worried about monsters even though they
don't ever see monsters.
They're worried about monsters in the
closet and he correlated it to an
ancient fear of cats like Jaguars and
leopards and lions and things that
killed people forever and that at night
these things with big teeth that hide in
the dark and we to get you the monsters,
but you know there's a video of this guy
where a lion or a tiger rather charges
them full clip,
charges them and it is as terrifying as
any harm movie you'll ever seen in your
life.
The thing veers off about 30 or 40 yards
away from him and decided not to run at
him,
but it's running at him.
Full clip with this insane speed that I
kind of knew the Tigers could run that
fast,
but until you see it,
you go,
oh my God,
they're so fast.
It's just this furious snarl and just
unbelievable pace as it moves towards
him and it's monster.
You know,
and if you saw that,
if that killed one of your friends and
you have children that would be passed
onto their kids,
they're like,
be scared of monsters.
Yeah.
Um,
I,
well sometimes some people take Iowasca
they report seeing like snakes or worms
as well.
Um,
jaguars too.
But um,
but I think that there's a physiological
reaction where your body's being
thinking that has been poisoned,
which it kind of has been in a little
bit of a way.
And I think that maybe in the
nonconscious there's,
there's this a projection of,
because I'm in your ancestral past,
if you're a poisoned,
it was probably because of a snake or
some parasite or bacteria or something
like that.
So maybe maybe that because that is,
like you said,
maybe stored in the DNA or in the memory
somehow.
Even if you've never ran into a snake,
perhaps you would hallucinate one.
If your body thinks that you're,
you've been poisoned being like what
happened here and kind of running
through a simulation of what must have
happened.
That certainly could be possible.
I mean,
there's a lot of variables.
I don't think it's a,
there's Zinnia
clear way at this time to figure out
what the hell's going on or you know,
like people that interpret dreams,
you know,
oh,
well that means is you don't know what
the fuck.
Right,
right.
I had a dream that I was running from
Godzilla on a skateboard with my cousin
who I haven't seen in 20 years.
You think that's.
You can interpret that.
No,
that's,
you know.
Oh,
well,
you're.
You're troubled by your past.
You and your cousin have this tension
and the last time you saw them,
you,
you saw lizard and maybe or maybe the
human imagination.
It's just bizarre.
Yeah.
It's very,
very,
very strange and incredibly powerful.
I mean the idea that we can dream and I
can have a dream where,
where I'm making up all of these people
or people that I know in doing perfect
impressions of them in maybe different
languages that you don't normally know
and you do it all without even realizing
you're doing it.
You think it's happening to you.
You don't even realize you're making up
the story line and writing the script
and putting together the actors and we
are doing it in your sleep,
like you wake up well rested.
If you sit and like read a book,
you'll get tired,
you'll get,
you'll get fatigued using your brain
like that,
but your brain can do all of that in
your sleep and you wake up,
well rested like it took.
It took no energy at all for the brain
to do that.
Well,
it's got to be drugs,
right?
I mean it's gotTa have something to do
with dmt.
They don't know for sure,
but they do believe that one year in
heavy rem sleep,
your brain is producing all this dmt.
Now that they know now the con would
research foundation has done those
studies on rats where they've proven
that live rats are producing
dimethyltryptamine and the pineal gland.
They know that this is actually the
source of it.
Right?
It was like the first time before it was
all just anecdotal evidence.
Now that they know that it's totally
possible that wants testing measures get
better and they can figure out how to
detect things at a more accurate rate,
they are eventually going to do studies
on people that are asleep and they're
going to be able to measure your dmt
levels and where it's coming from and
when it spikes and if they can somehow
or another,
you know,
they're starting to be able to do things
now where they can show you images and
you can receive those images in your
visual cortex.
Yeah.
That I have to think that eventually
they're going to be able to interpret
whatever kind of dreamed data is going
on in your head,
at least in some sort of crude form.
Dvr your dreams kind of eventually get
better and if we live a thousand years
from now,
I mean,
who knows what he's shown me here,
Jamie.
I was looking something up
that I remember someone came in here and
talking to us about this is called
dreams fear.
It's an APP that people were supposed to
download and type in what?
Like the dreams they just had an APP is
getting what it's called,
like big data.
It's getting all the information on what
metrics people are dreaming about
colors.
Oh yeah.
And they showed you the people around
you who are dreaming.
Yeah.
And this is like 2 million people have
downloaded this and you can find out
what other people are dreaming about.
Kind of like based on a map.
And I think the person that was in here
that was talking about,
I said that they're finding out people
are dreaming about the same things at
the same time as all over the world or
something like that.
I don't know who said that.
I don't because he said
it wasn't official data.
It was,
I don't,
I can't remember exactly.
Imagine if it's everybody dreaming about
having sexual.
Hillary realized like,
Whoa,
it's an epidemic.
And we realized she put it out there
from chem trails.
She spray it in the sky.
It's interesting that they have the um,
uh,
people,
people that can't talk or whatever.
I'm all like Stephen Hawking.
Basically you can show.
You can now show them.
You can give them Mris.
Show them pictures of,
of certain words,
um,
that are useful,
like bathroom or whatever it might be.
And then it can determine what part of
the brain is lighting up when they are
thinking of a bathroom and then on the
and then you can hook them up and you
can just concentrate on the word
bathroom and then it will know that
they're saying bathroom.
And um,
and so,
so this is Stephen hawkings just like
hates using new technology and shit.
So I'm,
that's why the.
Yeah,
he hates it.
Hates Tech.
That's why his voice is still like the
fucking shittier than my gps.
He likes old computers.
Yeah.
He just doesn't like learning the new
technology stuff.
That's like what gets them around and
talks for him and everything.
He's like,
ah,
who needs that new shit?
Wow.
Um,
but,
uh,
but yeah,
so once we can map the brain and figure
out.
But I mean,
yeah,
that's the dream to Dvr,
like dreams or do a dmt trip or
something like that and then slow it
down because it's a dmt trip.
There's just a billion things happening
all at once and it's impossible to
articulate.
I don't think you're ever going to be
able to slow it down because I think we
look at it in terms of what we would see
in normal reality,
like if you had a scene that you could
say,
when you know a you were 15,
you hit a home run and a little league
game and you remember it so clearly
because he was the.
You were the hero.
You came back.
Everybody carried you on your shoulders.
If you could go back and replay that
over and over again,
if you had a recording of it in your
mind and you can go back and see in real
time and replay it,
it would all make sense.
You'd see the grass moving in the
breeze.
You would see the clouds floating gently
overhead.
You'd see the players in the field.
You see people talking,
laughing in the stands.
It would all make sense because it's all
references and things that exist in this
dimension and this plane.
The problem with DMT is if you took even
one,
100th of the images that you're seeing,
just a little corner of it and just
looked at it and tried to examine what
the fuck it is.
It's constantly changing geometric
pattern.
It's somehow and intelligent don't like
to.
So to zoom in and it has some things
have an effect on it.
Like have you ever done dmt to a egos?
Those,
a South American songs that they can
play?
Um,
no,
I,
I do.
Um,
although I did,
I think he was,
the Shaman was doing them on my couple
of Iowasca ceremony singing,
but I asked her didn't really take for
me it was a bit of a disappointment or
did you go to a bad place?
No,
I just didn't have enough.
I'm strong enough.
Yeah.
I told them my mom and I was like,
I do lots of DMT.
I'm ready.
I just want to like,
fucking get there,
let's go for it.
And then it wasn't enough.
It was,
it was like a good mushroom trip.
Um,
and it was good,
but it wasn't.
Yeah,
it was enjoyable other than like sitting
in a room,
listen to other people,
throw up guy,
I just don't have the stomach for that
and it was also like,
I don't know,
it was
my bullshit detector was just kind of
going off a lot.
There's just a lot of people dressed in
white move things.
I was just like,
yeah,
there's a girl had a magic wand and I
thought
she was so hot to eyes like to sell hot.
No one's ever called your bullshit.
No,
no,
no.
The personnel would be banging it right
now.
Would wouldn't be on the spot.
Like a dude.
It never be able to fucking carrier out
a magic wand without some lady being
like,
what's up with that?
You're could Kanye West have a line of
magic ones?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
He's,
he's easy to
pull it off.
Drake do it.
It was the whole.
I was trying to be as open minded as
possible,
but it was also like the Shaman going
around and like blowing smoke on the
crown of my head was like a bit much for
me.
I was like,
all right,
this guy's gone blown my hair now.
If you were super high,
you'd be connecting with.
I know the smoke
and then I didn't like that you had to
like go and kneel in front of them to do
the thing.
I was just like,
so churchy.
Wait,
wait,
wait.
Yeah.
Kneel in front of him.
To like go and like sit down and from a
neil too.
Or is he stands up and he's sitting like
pouring the,
his dick was out actually come to think
of it.
But um,
yeah,
I mean if I,
if I was doing Iowasca or if I was
giving someone Iowasca I wouldn't be
bowing to them for being brave enough to
try it.
We're that.
He made you neil and yeah,
for me the wrong way.
It should.
I don't think I've heard that before,
but I have heard of like skeezy ceremony
guys.
This guy wasn't skeezy at all.
He was super cool and really bright and
everything.
I just thought I thought some of it was
a little silly.
Sorry I interrupted you.
No,
it's okay.
it's,
there's a lot of that to these things.
It's
what you're experiencing is so beyond
the reality that we all know that all
the other silly shit almost seems okay.
Yeah.
Know mother,
Gaia,
we open ourselves to please take me down
the path of wisdom and enlightened and I
opened myself to you.
I come here with acknowledgement of my
past troubles and,
and,
and you know,
this shit like,
look man,
you know what,
here's I actually
no,
they say to set an intention and
everything.
I set an intention.
I was like I want to understand why I
have some self esteem issues and why I
don't have more confidence and,
and I,
you know,
I was like I'm going to play along.
I'm going to be as open minded as
possible and I will say during the
Iowaska trip I was the most confident
I've ever felt in my entire life.
Like it was just a feeling like I could
do anything.
Unfortunately.
It was all geared toward like,
well this is a bunch of bullshit.
Like I was pretty confident that it was.
I was like,
can I just go outside and like trip by
myself because I feel great.
I'm just in a room of people like puking
and farting everywhere and like I just
can't.
It's not for me this thing and Boeing
magic wands and um,
and I also,
I have,
I have a couple things.
I think some people are misrepresenting
what's happening.
I think that I think that when you're,
um,
as,
as someone who's almost died like
probably 20 times in my life,
I've had like a near death experience
and like breaking my feet kind of
triggered the same sort of response and
your life flashes before your eyes and
goes kind of back in time a little bit.
Really that's underselling what the
brain does because it also projects all
these options going forward of like,
do I call an ambulance right now?
Do I cut it?
Yeah.
Am I going to be able to make it?
What's my life going to be like?
No.
And then,
um,
so I think that one,
when your life flashes before your eyes,
it's not like some,
hey,
let's just have a quick fond in this
stall.
Jic Run through what our life was and
visit some old memories.
This is your brain going like,
do we have anything for this situation?
Do we have,
have we seen a TV show that will get us
out of this,
do we do we remember first aid class and
it's going back and back and back and
I'm wondering if it's going back far
enough to what the fetal environment was
like.
I wonder if we do have memories
somewhere stored in it and because the
fetal environment could have easily been
all of these weird structures in cities
and fractal like,
like it,
it doesn't seem that odd to me that
that's what the environment before you
came out of the womb could look like.
And if it's taking you back,
do you mean before you came out of the
womb?
You mean like what you were experiencing
while you're in your mother's womb?
Yeah.
With your eyes closed and the little
bits of consciousness,
do you think the first little bits of
conscious might be tripping?
Yeah.
Like,
uh,
like these kind of fractal structures.
I think fractals are,
I mean fractals,
you're able to put a finite it,
you're able to fit infinity into a
finite space somehow.
It's the weird.
I'm a counterintuitive thing about
fractals,
but if you were,
if you made packets of information that
were fracked alike,
that would be a great way to transport
information or like transport ideas I
think.
And so I think that could be the very
origins of consciousness and then when
we came out we were seeing this,
but it was all like a blob you didn't
see like walls or pictures or like you
didn't,
so it
was just a blob of information coming at
you that you later had to be taught or
decipher and,
and,
but I think the origins of it could have
been like um,
these,
like I've seen a lot of holographic
cities and that kind of looked like
computer chips a little bit and that
sort of thing.
And it wouldn't surprise me if that's
what the first little like say you get
this machine where you can record
dreams.
If we can record then what's happening
when you're a fetus?
It wouldn't surprise me if it was
something like this and I think that I
think that um,
Iowaska and DMT have a way of triggering
a near death experience,
whether you're consciously aware of it
or not.
And it's like,
what the fuck is happening right now?
Just like when,
you know,
why do you think it triggers near death
experiences or it tricks your brain into
thinking maybe you're dying.
I've never had that experience on dmt.
Never had the experience where if it
made me feel like maybe I was dying,
it had made me feel like maybe I went
somewhere where I wasn't supposed to be.
Yeah.
Like all my God,
you fucked up now.
You went to a place where you're not
even supposed to see this yet.
I haven't necessarily felt it that much
myself either other than I felt like I,
you know,
I've forgotten that I'm a human that
smoke dmt.
I'm just like a different thing
entirely.
But I
just a little bit though,
for people that are like these fucking
hippies,
what are the yapping about?
The brain does produce endogenous
psychedelic chemicals.
It produces five methoxy DMT,
produces and dimethyltryptamine to super
potent psychedelic drugs the brain
produces and we don't understand why
it's entirely possible that if the adult
human brain produces it,
that a baby's brain producers at as
well,
so if it's in that womb state,
which is in a lot of ways sort of like a
sensory deprivation tank,
but with of course the feeling and the
cortisol effect of the mother and the
oxytocin and all the,
all the different hormones and
responding directly to the stress of the
mother.
There's a lot going on with the body
inside the body,
but we should assume that those brains
are experiencing what we know to be
possible in the human mind,
which is psychedelic chemicals.
And I've seen,
I've seen actual dreams on DMT trips
like a regular dream like you're used to
having,
which is unusual because that's nothing
what the normal dmt world.
See me look while you're talking
dmt or while you're dreaming.
Because I've,
I've had dreams where you go into the
DMT world.
I've experienced both.
Um,
but I've had,
I've smoked dmt and then I'd see like a,
a guy like walking down a hall holding a
box and then I'd look at them and he'd
look at me and be like,
oh,
and then start like twitching,
like,
like there was a glitch in the metrics
and he's like,
oh,
like making fun of me.
And then,
and then he just reached back and
grabbed the wall and pull it and it
would be like this veil that.
Then it became the whole world and
started like the DMT space.
You're more familiar.
Have you could sell that in a virtual
reality environment.
Like here's the game.
You wake up,
you're in a classroom,
you will,
you like,
you lift your head up.
Like,
oh,
I must have fallen asleep in class.
And everybody left me here.
You go out in the hallway and there's a
guy walking down the hallway and he's
carrying a box of books and you,
excuse me,
excuse me.
And you go up to him and he grab his
shoulder and he turns and looks at me
and goes,
oh,
that would be.
Yeah,
that's inevitable though.
They're going to be able to figure out a
way to create a virtual.
It's one of the acts of the things that
actually Mckenna believed that they were
going to be able to figure out how to
create a virtual dmt world,
which would give people the dmt
experience without actually taking dmt
is that your brain was somehow or
another synchronize with this virtual
world and you would have a full blown
dmt trip with.
And this is.
He thought this up.
I'm sure he was tripping,
but he thought this up,
like I believe the nineties or maybe
the.
He might might've even been the eighties
and he was talking about this is when
virtual reality was still like people
had predicted it's,
you know,
that virtual reality was going to blow
up and going to be huge.
But it took a long time until recently
where the technology caught up to the
concept.
Yeah.
Like they finally are starting to get
that hoverboard.
The Lexus one.
Is that the one you mean?
The one with the
error?
The same guy that made the pack,
that goes in water and then shoots the
air he made.
He made a board that you stand on that
uses fans and he hovers like 30,
40 feet above the ground.
Have you seen that video?
No.
Yeah,
yeah.
Talking about the Orioles Hoverboard,
which uses magnets somehow it's got like
some super cooled magnets with liquid
nitrogen or something like that I
believe.
And the Lexus one is really cool because
it's sort of a proof of concept.
And what they're doing right now is
they're using it and the guy stands on
it like a skateboard and he,
he sort of slides around on things and
it's only a couple inches off the
ground,
but it's clearly floating like you're
here now.
This is another one.
This is the other one.
This is another one called Arco Board.
Oh,
so this one's all fans.
This isn't the one that I was,
it might not be real.
This looks fake as fuck.
This looks like a sitcom actor.
Um,
well it was that real.
So,
um,
I could run fast and that I'm not
impressed on find the lexis one.
Whoa,
that is pretty dope though.
So is this real?
I don't believe that guy.
Oh Wow.
A bunch of fans.
Okay.
So if you.
If you just put flyboard air test one,
try to go to the lexus thing first.
I want to.
I want to show you this lexus thinks,
and I haven't seen this,
this is Alexis ones on magnets and
stuff.
Yeah,
it's super cooled magnets with some sort
of liquid nitrogen.
Look at that.
See how it's so all that air that's
coming out of the bottom.
That's the liquid nitrogen.
So I think lexus is assuming that this
technology sort of like back to the
futures shit that this technology
is eventually.
How are we going to get around with cars
and one of the interesting things about
that,
if they really do figure out how to do
this,
if we get around in cars that are not
connected to the ground with wheels,
even though there will be momentum as we
collide with each other,
if we fuck up,
it won't have nearly the same kind of
impact because you won't have the
friction of the row that makes the
vehicle absorb the energy of the other
vehicle.
It'll absorb it a little bit and then
bounce you back.
Yeah.
No.
Well with having.
Eventually our power lines will be super
conductors to.
So they're cooled down enough so you're
not losing all that.
You're losing something like a quarter
of the energy is just lost in the wires
and transit.
Right.
Um,
so I had to find the flyboard.
Yeah,
I'm flyboard air test.
Holy Shit.
This guy's flying.
Yeah.
Okay.
This is way cooler than that other piece
of shit
quit.
This is nuts.
How long can this guy stay on this thing
for like five or 10 minutes or something
like that in Wa.
Watch him stick this landing to it's,
it's incredible how much control he has
over it.
This is amazing.
Now,
is this available for public
consumption?
Um,
I think this is.
I think it will be a representative of
this company.
Employee.
I hope to be at will happily represent
the hover board company.
I want to.
I want to be associated with them.
Look at the crazy wind is coming from it
and that other frame you could see like
when there's a dark background,
you could see the force of the air below
it back up a little bit.
Jamie.
She could see the force of the air below
that thing.
See if you can.
Yeah,
look at that.
See that force like backup a little bit
so he could see it like,
look as he's flying,
how much air that thing must be pumping.
Look at that.
That's crazy.
And it's fucking up the water underneath
him as he's swimming around or is flying
around.
Whether that's incredible,
man.
Oh yeah.
I've watched the landing here.
Look at how accurate this is.
Wow.
That's like a five by five space that he
just landed dead center.
And he landed right next to two guys
that were so confident.
They just stood there while he's flying
around on what it looks like.
It's like a,
like a box.
Yeah.
It doesn't even look like a skateboard.
It looks like a circular,
like a small trampoline.
It's so small.
You know,
I'm fucking amazing.
Mission one coming soon.
Flyboard.
Um,
what is the data on this video?
Jamie is like a year ago,
maybe
April of this year.
Oh,
it's just a matter of time before
someone has one of those in.
They're flying right in front of your
window,
jerking off on your house.
One hundred percent going to happen,
right?
Someone's going to be the first guy.
They're like,
they're shooting down drones.
Someone's going to shoot one of those
that's going to go to Britney Spears
House and walk off on her roof and
they're going to get arrested.
And it'll be like the new thing,
like planking was a thing for awhile.
Jerking off Hubbard.
Eric's famous people's be a new thing.
Yeah.
We're going to not be able to control
the skies.
It's sorta like the ocean.
I think the ocean is fascinating for
friends who have friends that have
boats,
you know,
the guys liked to go fishing and I've
never had a boat,
but one of the things that I've always
thought was incredible.
It was like if you live like Siri,
Marina del Rey or something like that
and you have a boat and you hop out and
your boat,
you go out into another world,
you're,
you're a fucking space traveler on a
boat and you're roaming around this
enormous swath of ocean and you're free
to go left and right and up and down,
and there's no roads and there's no
restrictions.
You can do whatever you want.
So I,
I can't believe like people are so I,
I mean I think space travel is exciting
and everything,
but everyone's like,
what if we found aliens?
There's like there's aliens,
they're in the ocean and it's cheap to
get to them.
Just go to every time we go down deeper,
we've discovered all these new worlds
down there and they're constantly
finding crazy new life forms.
I wonder if like what would the number
or the percentage of documented life
forms in the ocean are because they're
always finding new freaky variations.
Did you ever see that m squared that
they found that has crab legs?
No.
Yeah,
it's crazy man.
It's a giant squid that they found in
Mexico and it was a camera that was
attached to one of those oil rigs,
so they were essentially just checking
the oil rig and there was this thing
that was floating right next to the
which is really freaky looking alien
squid that has like crab legs,
like really bizarre,
like obvious bends to the legs.
Like,
check this out,
look at this,
look at that fucking thing man.
Like look how long it's tentacles are.
It's enormous.
This is 2007.
Was the name of this video?
Jamie,
so people could
alien like squid filmed in oil drilling
site is this one I picked,
but that's exactly what I would call it.
Video courtesy of the Shell oil company
Shell doing a good job at finding aliens
in the ocean.
There's like that blue planet or
something.
One of those BBC documentaries like
planet earth,
but just ocean stuff and you watch it
and it's like you could show people and
they and they would think that you're
watching like Cgi made up thing like
about aliens.
Like have you ever seen anything like
this before?
Um,
that back it up.
So you can see that,
that image again with articulating bent
arms,
like,
what the fuck is that man?
Just look at that.
If you,
if you saw that thing floating in space,
right?
If they were already.
Well,
if they were on their way to the moon
and they saw that thing floating in
space,
go,
whoa.
Exactly.
There's an alien in space that's
watching over the planet.
Found that too.
They're very intelligent.
They can solve puzzles.
We would,
we would think that is the most
incredible discovery ever.
But we see this thing in the ocean like,
oh,
it's just here.
Yeah.
It depends on where you put things,
right.
Like if you put anything is more
interesting as you put it in space.
There was an orange,
we found an orange on the moon.
Oh my God.
And there's like that.
Like I was talking about how your brain
perceives things as metaphors,
everything that's like getting high is
good or you're feeling like up or rather
than down as bad,
you know,
and held under the Earth and heavens up
in the clouds and stuff.
There's something,
I don't know if it's just this natural
like are inherent fight against gravity
that makes us think like that's what you
want to pain to lift off to be up there.
You know?
Hell is definitely because of volcanoes.
I mean,
it only makes sense.
Well,
yeah,
it makes sense.
I mean,
have you ever been near a volcano
before?
Um,
no.
The Big island has awesome tours.
You could hop in a helicopter,
you fly over the big island of Hawaii
and you could actually watch the island
grow because the island grows something
like a foot a day or something like
that.
Like you can literally see the lava come
out of the,
out of the chutes and go into the ocean
and create new land.
And that's awesome.
Fucking awesome.
And you're flying over this helicopter,
the helicopter rather.
You're flying over this volcano and you
look down into lava,
you see the very center of the earth
oozing out of it's out of this weird
surface which has created the entire
Hawaiian island chain by the way,
the entire Hawaiian island chain.
It's just volcanoes.
That's all it is.
Volcanoes in the middle of the ocean
that erupted millions of years ago and
poke their way through the top and
there's constantly growing and changing
reality is far more interesting than
what humans were able to make up in
their wildest fantasies of trying to
explain it.
What was happening?
Well,
once we get a grip on reality or we get
a good account of reality,
then you can get pretty creative with
your imagination.
But the.
Yeah,
the this,
the actual reality of space is insane.
The idea that there's hundreds of
billions of galaxies out there and that
each one of them has an infinite
possibilities about what kind of planets
around there,
how far they are from their stars.
How many stars are in the solar system,
what else is out there in terms of life?
What are the possibilities of things
surviving out there?
They think it's possible that some
living things could maybe even survive
in space,
detached from a planet,
right?
Yeah.
I mean,
even the reality of evolution,
like,
right?
I mean when you,
when you get far enough into it and you
look at all these different examples,
it's the reality of evolution is
actually crazier than like there was a
god and he had a son named Jesus.
It is,
it's also more accurate.
Um,
but I,
I remember I used to be like,
how could anyone believe it?
I was very angry.
I raised a strictly Catholic,
so I had some bitterness about all of
that.
And um,
but then once I started learning more
about evolution and it's just like,
oh,
this is,
I didn't know half of this stuff.
It's no wonder these people,
you know,
no one's been given the opportunity,
learn it,
you know,
and when you're brought up in a small
town and that's just your upbringing,
never.
Yeah,
I mean,
man,
just stop and think about the big bang.
If you want a mind,
fuck yourself.
Think about the idea that these
scientists are proposing that the
universe itself,
everything that you say,
it was smaller than the head of a pin
and had infinite mass and somehow or
another exploded and created everything.
We've seen the stars today.
What are you sure
that's under debate?
I mean,
there's other proposals.
There's other scientific,
uh,
ideas that have been bandied about,
parallel universes,
brains,
membranes colliding,
you know,
the,
there's different universities in
dimensions or like just slightly
separated from each other and they
collide the endless process of expansion
and contraction and that that's what
happens at the entire universe.
Expands infinitely and then pulls back
into an infinitely small spot and then
like,
you know,
every x amount of billion years just
repeats the cycle.
Yeah.
No,
I mean,
I think that our,
I think that our brains are endlessly
fascinating to just that.
I mean humans like to give themselves a
lot of credit,
but I think that we have like,
like kind of like the movie inside out.
I think we have vast universes inside of
our head that seem all expensive.
And uh,
because I,
I think that dreams and hallucinating
are coming from within sight,
from inside the mind.
I don't believe that you're connecting
with different dimensions and stuff like
that,
but it certainly looks like it,
which means you have,
if I'm right,
a which,
who knows,
then it means that you have this whole
like multiverse set up just for running
all these different tests just for like
walking around and making decisions.
There's entire universes inside of your
head,
which
is totally possible,
but I don't,
I don't have a position.
I don't have a position on whether or
not it's in my mind or whether or not
it's real.
And I think it's entirely possible that
we need,
need to consider the possibility that
everything that's in your mind,
everything that's imaginary is actually
real.
Meaning that the imagination is
responsible for every single thing any
human has ever done.
Every car that's ever been built,
every podcasts ever been made.
Every television has ever been designed.
All of that has come out of the
imagination.
The imagination is as strange force
inside of human,
you know,
quote unquote consciousness that living,
physical or not living but solid
physical things come from like
literally.
It's the seed of these solid physical
things.
So when we say that,
you know,
were imagining or hallucinating that
we're experiencing some divine entity to
comes to us from another dimension and
explains the universe,
the nature of reality.
It's entirely possible that that is a
hallucination.
Meaning that physical thing,
you can't kidnap it.
You can't throw a net on it and bring it
back from you know the wormhole and Plop
it down in front of the police
department.
Say,
look,
I found it a proof of another dimension.
I brought something right?
But
if you went to visit with God,
say if,
if,
if someone proves that there is a heaven
and that God is real and you can have a
brief visit with God and you go to God
and you,
you talked to him and in 15 minutes
explains the nature of the universe and
love and the concept of positive energy
and all these different things.
Please take this back with you.
Please take this back with you and do
what you can to make the world a better
place.
Well,
if you have a trip or if you actually go
to meet God and or if you have a trip
where you imagine you meet God,
the experience is exactly the same.
Like we,
I don't think we know what's real and
what's not real.
I think we're super cocky and were real
nervous.
Like one of the reasons why we get
paranoid when we smoked pot is because
we start becoming aware of variables
that we might have suppressed or chosen
to ignore and then they,
we're confronted with them and all of
our insecurities and like a cascade tied
away sort of a situation where you can
handle all the data that you've been
putting aside like,
oh fuck
yeah,
I smoke weed and I'm like,
oh my fucking to do list.
I think about bills that didn't pay when
I was 18.
Like what do I do?
I'm going to do you.
There's weird things that happened to
the mind and I don't know how much of
what we call the imagination,
how we try to think of it as like,
oh,
it's just imagining things,
man.
I don't know.
I don't,
I don't.
I,
I think it's entirely possible that were
really hung up on this word real.
Like what's real and what's not real.
I think we're real hung up on that.
Real real.
Our Day to day lives is dependent on
imagination.
We've all imagined democracy are these
laws came.
We're a human invention that came from
imagination that we imagine is real.
Even even every corporation isn't an
actual thing.
It's an idea that we just imagined and
we take it for granted.
You don't have to go like,
you don't have to go like do I believe
in seven slash 11 or like you take it
for granted that seven slash 11 is just
an idea.
It's a,
it's,
it's a,
a judge could close down seven slash 11
with one of his ideas at any moment and
then it would no longer exist,
but the buildings are still there,
but you know,
7:11 is not the building.
It's not the employees,
it's,
it's just an idea,
an idea implemented in the physical form
that you can experience,
right?
You can go ahead
touch it,
you can walk in the door,
you could smell it,
but I just don't know if that makes it
real and then everything that happens to
you in your dream is not real.
I don't know.
I don't know what,
what really is in terms of like,
well,
if you want to be successful in this
world,
material world,
you have to consider the fact that laws
are real.
You can't drive a thousand miles an hour
in a 20 mile zone.
You can't punch babies.
There's a lot of real consequences for
real actions because this world has
rules.
Right?
Right.
But it doesn't mean that the trips that
you have,
these intense transcendent psychedelic
experiences are hallucinations.
It doesn't mean that they're not real.
It means we be entirely hung up on
containing our consciousness and our
thinking and our awareness to what we
can touch and bang on and pick up and
measure and the look.
I put it on a scale.
I know it's real and these physical laws
that we've applied to this reality,
what we call reality,
don't necessarily know if that.
I think it's entirely possible to me
that that might be a limiting factor on
how we perceive the universe around us
and that it's leftover from having to
worry about predators and hunting and
gathering.
And we're moving,
I believe slowly away from that.
No,
not even slowly and I think our ability
to alter reality through virtual reality
and even through our understanding and
application of psychedelic drugs,
there's like a psychedelic technology as
well as virtual technology and all of
these things are giving us this,
this ability to change the concept of
real,
like the realm of possibilities as we
can imagine that.
Because even to say that punching babies
is a bad thing,
I mean,
who,
who I'm fucking single guy and your baby
punch,
I um,
but here,
here's where I'm,
I try to be very,
very skeptical of my trips because I've
seen God in different universes and like
the whole bit and it seems like as real,
as anything I've ever experienced did
my,
my problem with my memory and perception
of it is,
is that it's just such a short amount of
time and it's so different and so
exciting that I think the brain,
I think that the brain just
automatically,
I think that's very salient in the
brain,
really attaches to this,
these new and novel new information
that's very exciting and it's a little
scary to your brain.
Remembers his scary things a lot.
Tricker is a bit of a stress response.
And I think that I,
I like to say that imagine instead there
was someone who was,
who was born on,
on a,
uh,
it was like they just have the brain
chemistry,
like the brains on Lsd all the time.
And then one day things are rainbow
colored,
whatever.
And that's fine,
and then one day when I get around just
fine and then one day when they're 30,
someone gives them a pill that brings
them to our reality.
It would seem just as mind blowing and
just as true like I get it now there's
these things called jobs and like these
entry level positions and like these
hierarchies and you can,
if you show up on time each day you can
establish yourself in this hierarchy,
you know,
and then you,
if you went in on different days,
it would seem like a different world.
Like I thought I had it all figured out,
but then I was like this person that was
in a cube typing away.
And then you think you have that figured
out and then you hit a casual Friday and
you're like,
it was weird.
I thought they all had uniforms and then
they all looked different.
You know,
like this is this.
To me,
this perception is just as much the trip
as any psychedelic will will ever get
you on.
It's that,
that's such a
short amount of time.
In reality,
it's very bizarre and we're.
We're accustomed to it.
Yeah.
We're just used to this.
It's entirely possible that your reality
is different than his reality,
than my reality.
Then another person's reality.
Then what you were talking about before
being how the way you view the world and
how the world seems to you is more
fucked up when you're hurt you,
when you were,
when you were injured.
Yup.
It might entirely be possible that when
you make good decisions,
when you decide to take care of your
body,
when you started to eat healthy,
when you side to meditate or do yoga or
practice mindfulness or set out an
intention for your day and say,
you know today I'm not going to complain
about anything.
You know,
I'm going to show up on time.
I'm not going to complain.
I'm being nice person and I'm going to
try to.
When I went to a negative thought comes
into my main,
my brain,
it's going to be a mandate.
I'm going to do my best to push that out
and replace it with a positive thought.
When someone chooses to exercise like
that sort of a protocol chooses to go
forth with like a like a list of things
that they're going to,
this is how I'm going to treat life as
I'm going to think about life and I'm
going to be fluid while I'm doing it,
but I'm not gonna.
Allow all these things that I know to be
detrimental aspects of life.
I'm not gonna.
Allow those in if I can help it.
Just doing that changes the world.
Right?
I mean she literally changes your world
and I think it's.
It's entirely possible that what you're
talking about when you're saying that
when you're enthusiastic and you're
embracing the psychedelic experience,
that it's possible that your brain
creates all this new stuff,
but that might be the point.
That might be the point of all of it.
When you have these psychedelic trips
and your brain on the psychedelic trips
interacts with those songs and the
music,
the ECO rose,
what?
I know you didn't have like the best
experience of it because you're the DMT,
which wasn't as strong in the IOWASCA,
but I've had experiences with the songs
where you see the experience moving to
the song,
well,
if a song can alter the way,
and I know there's something special
about sounds and music,
there's some special connection between
creative and creative sounds that people
have put together and concocted and put
together in some sort of a a beautiful
song.
There's A.
There's a response that the body has to
those like you know,
like if you're on a treadmill and a
great song comes on,
you feel like he could run faster.
Music contains some sort of inspiration.
Well,
there's A.
There's an effect,
right?
But that effect also has an effect on
the psychedelic world when you're
tripping.
Those songs have an effect.
Yeah.
My thought is that your mind and your
attitude might not just have an effect
on experiences when you're running into
people.
It might have an effect on the
psychedelic dreams might have an effect
on your future and it might not just be
hippy bullshit.
The thinking positive and choosing to
act and go forth in a positive way is
just a,
just like a good Karma Sorta Hippie,
nonsensical way of trying control
the uncontrollable,
which is this random world we live in
might not be true.
We just might think that because it's
comforting.
It might want to think that there's less
control than there actually is.
Um,
I think that.
Oh,
that's a lot.
Um,
I,
so one way in the way in which,
um,
so I,
I sometimes at home I'll have a,
I'll have like an animal planet,
like planet earth or whatever on,
on mute and then I'll be playing music
and I'll have people over and people
think that it's because I'm playing the
music through the TV.
People think that they're like,
what is this program?
What's this?
I'm like,
oh,
it's just that it's just on mute with
music playing over it.
But if I don't tell people that they'll
be watching it and if it's like a happy
go lucky song,
they're like,
oh man,
these animals.
Sure.
Got It.
Good.
Don't they look at how.
Look at how relaxing that looks just
laid out in the sun.
And then if it's like a real intense
dark song,
they're like,
oh my God,
are they ever going to make it?
Like,
it completely changes their perception
of it.
This is why we have soundtracks and
everything else.
And um,
I actually,
I actually think that music altering the
psychedelic state or world or perception
or whatever you want to say,
um,
is like I listen to this band spawn goal
that makes music specifically for an
emt.
I think that that's
is one of my rants really spangle song
that has this long rant where me and Jim
Breuer,
we're,
we're so barbecued on a pot lollipops
and this was like the early two
thousands,
some guy called in and um,
he,
uh,
asked us a question about something
about dmt.
And I went on this crazy rant about dmt
state and they put it into a song.
But that's,
uh,
I,
I wouldn't want to hear that while I'm
tripping.
I don't like when there's words in their
songs.
I try to only listen to music one's way
to aggro
Tuesday astic.
But I was just hanging out with my
friend and we were just so high.
We're barely should be talking to
people,
definitely not answering phone calls.
See to me that the fact that a different
song and I'll see like a different story
and it's pretty predictable.
Like I'll play the song again and I know
I'm going to see like this purple woman
dancing around or whatever.
Um,
and the fact that that influences that
perception,
that world that you're in is more of an
indicator to me that it's coming from
within your head and not like
transporting you to a different
dimension or making you perceive a
different dimension because why?
Why would it influence that dimension?
A better example,
I smoked dmt wants that.
I had my,
uh,
my dog jumped on my lap while I was on a
dmt trip and then it came into my dmt
trip,
like all colorful and in codes and
stuff.
And then I saw like,
like kind of a bit of a dream state of,
of where I would.
I saw myself setting my dog down.
But I was like sitting in a different
spot.
I was at the kitchen table and it's
where my dog would normally jump on my
lap and where I'd normally be like no,
and sit down.
And so it was like accessing that part
of the brain that has the memory,
like this is when we put the dog down
and then I,
I lifted it off of me and I think
there's all these.
I see lots of things like that,
like these,
uh,
like these exemplars,
like these kind of prototype objects
that your brain is using to retrieve.
Like if you,
if you're gonna throw a Frisbee,
I think that you're accessing like this,
this ideal frisbee throw in your mind.
You could probably close your eyes and
picture it right now.
And,
and I think that that's in there like
these prototypes that we,
that our brain draws off of because I've
seen that on a dmt trip,
like a silhouette of like a perfect
frisbee throw and then the guy's like
100 times doing like the same movement
or whatever.
And just things like that make me think
that it's just some neural process and
how the brain,
how the brain interprets reality at
different levels.
You might be right or
they might not be mutually exclusive,
they might intertwine.
It's entirely possible that everything
is connected and that when you are
imagining things in the DMT realm,
you're imagining things in another
dimension and they're happening in that
dimension because your imagination can
create things in that bizarre,
detached from your body world that you
experienced under intense psychedelic
states.
It might not be mutually exclusive,
it might not be,
oh,
this is all my imagination.
That might be true.
You like,
you might be creating this,
but that also might be real in that
dimension,
in that state as far as real goals,
you know,
this 15 minute lifetime.
And that's what you have.
You have a 15 minute dmt lifetime.
You're there for 15 minutes.
I have a most at the time,
you got to go deeper.
So I
usually use a,
um,
a vape pen and vape pen.
Yeah,
I have a,
um,
why do you use one of those?
Because it's a lot smoother.
And um,
and you can just draw bigger hits and
it's fast.
Do you use like a,
it's like an oil vaporizer.
It has like a little cup in it and you
put the dmt in this little cup and.
Okay.
So you're not talking about like a,
like a blue cigarette pen talking about
like a fat one,
like,
like you would use for your vaping?
Yeah.
Okay.
So there's not really a pen,
right?
Like a more of a vape pipe?
Um,
yeah,
just that thing.
It's uh,
it's pretty um,
put in,
put it in cheap pen and you're doing
like a g pen.
I know what it is.
Yeah.
So one of those,
um,
I've,
I've tried so many different methods of
smoking and that's just I think the most
potent way.
And so I had an intense one about a week
or two ago and I had um,
I had about six big reps,
but I was already in there.
And then I had two more big ones.
It was a,
it was a bit much.
It's going to be a little while before I
can go back in there.
Yeah,
I'm going to have to process for awhile.
I went for years after one or I do want
to go back.
Yeah,
yeah.
I wonder.
I went months recently.
It was so.
It was so heavy that I.
Reality was a,
I,
the way I describe it as very slippery
for like two weeks or everything seemed
fake.
Like every car driving cars.
I was constantly worried about cars
flying over from other lanes and
smashing into my windshield,
like all this weird paranoid thoughts.
Whereas when I logically and objectively
feel feel like it's possible that it was
the ego trying to regain control by like
activating distress and like physical
worry sort of intentions,
like worry about strangers,
worried about random crime or accidents
and things along those lines.
You know,
that it was like my brain was like,
hey,
the world's a hard fucking place.
You know?
It's like the conservative right wing
aspect of the mind sort of kicks in
tenfold.
Yeah,
yeah.
I,
I've experienced that.
I've been,
I've,
I've experienced where I'm walking down
the street and then I have to be like,
wait,
is this real?
Or was that real?
Because it seemed really real,
but here's my.
My take on it is that DMT is,
is to perfect,
like everything's too perfect in there
and symmetrical like it take,
it would take say this where this world
that we know is a simulation,
it would take far more computational
power to put all these little flaws in
to put like a spill on the coffee table
or whatever.
It was a 11 billion years since the big
bang and 4 billion years of evolution
all to get this fucking little spill on
a coffee table.
Whereas DMT is like these.
You can,
you can make good dmt representations
just using some fractal programs and
Alex gray paintings.
Yeah,
and that's with like we're doing this
with computers that we built in where
monkeys,
right.
Again,
isn't it just what we're used to.
We're used to this imperfect world,
so we think the imperfect world is
normal.
You know,
maybe this is the oddity.
Maybe the oddity of coffee spills is
what's really strange and that dmt
represents,
is the energy that creates the world
itself.
Unharnessed sort of unbridled,
not an unattached to culture,
language,
physical bodies.
Any anything that we come to accept as
being a normal thing,
I think there's a perfect world
simulated within our mind that we're
trying to act
hold on bae,
but why make that distinction is the
question and not that there's anything
wrong with what you're doing versus what
I'm doing,
but why make a choice that it's in your
mind versus where a lot of people like
to say,
who the fuck knows?
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
I say who the fuck knows as well.
I'm just trying to be objective,
scientific,
objective,
skeptical of my own perceptions because
when I'm in there,
I'll come out.
I'll be like,
I just saw God,
no doubt about it.
Do you feel like,
and this is one of the reasons why I'm
getting to this line of questioning,
is actually a point to it.
Do you feel like.
Because I know that you do a lot of
stuff with science and your part of your
presentation,
your comedy show involve science and
when you're under the scrutiny,
and this is a very good thing of,
of other scientists and other people
that are going to judge what you're
saying and making sure that you're,
you know,
you're,
you're correct about your facts.
Do you find that you tend to be more
skeptical or tend to lean towards
outcomes razor more acceptable answers,
more scientifically plausible or at
least a more scientifically acceptable
in like academic circles?
Absolutely.
Um,
I think that one,
my brain just likes working that way
anyway.
Um,
I was always like a big fan of math and
a very good at it and I kind of liked
numbers because you could make sense of
the world.
And,
and um,
and I would say that I,
I was actually scared to the psychedelic
show that I do now.
I was planning on doing it like five
years from now or so.
It was just,
I've been sitting on it for like a
couple of years really.
And um,
I was like,
well,
once I'm like a bigger name or
something,
then maybe I'll have the power to go out
and do this because I have my podcast,
I interviewed scientists each week and I
need to reach out to these people.
I'm like,
oh,
I don't want them thinking I'm like some
burnout or some lunatic or something
like that.
So absolutely that.
Absolutely,
um,
factors in,
in my perception of things as does.
I mean also,
none of,
none of my memories of any of this stuff
are reliable.
You don't be interesting with your,
uh,
with the idea you're talking about
before,
if you scan someone's brain and then you
saw,
you watched the replay of them hitting a
home run or something.
Well that memory wouldn't necessarily be
accurate.
In fact,
there's a good chance that it wouldn't
be.
Yeah.
And so you could,
you could see different people's,
how people's memory looks as opposed to
what was actually captured on,
on CC TV or whatever it might be,
you know,
as a,
your exam.
Well,
the hot and cold thing,
but how all the different factors that
sort of are involved.
And how you feel about things.
Yeah.
And,
and just everyone also were very ego
driven.
We tend to think that we tend to think
that we're smarter and more attractive
and more skilled driver or whatever.
All the above,
you know,
that uh,
do you know the study where they took
the faces and they morph to them.
I'm like 10 degrees,
five times in each way to make them more
or less attractive.
So you take your face and then you make
it 10 percent more symmetrical,
20 percent more symmetrical,
so on to like 50 percent and then you
make it less symmetrical.
And so you get a job,
a real faced by that and not in the ugly
one.
And then you mix up all of those faces
and you have a.
and you flash,
um,
all of the pictures I'll all mixed up to
a person and give them a second to pick
it or whatever.
And people,
pr people predictively a,
we'll pick the one that's 10 to 20
percent more attractive.
So it's,
you think of yourself as like 10 to 20
percent,
like around 50 percent smarter,
more attractive,
more skilled.
At driving whatever it might be,
because that gives you the confidence
which is often beneficial in life,
but it's not,
you're not thinking 30 percent more
because now you're delusional if some
people do though some.
Oh yeah,
there's tip that scale and,
and there's people with low self esteem
that don't,
you know,
there's a lot of factors.
Various.
Yeah,
there are.
And also one person's perception of you
like objective perception might be very
different like you and I might observe
someone and you might come away with a
take like,
oh this guy is this and that.
And I'd be like,
hmm,
I thought he was this or that.
And then we would discuss it and then I
figured out,
well he reminded you of this asshole
used to know and he reminded me and my
best friend from high school and just
weird
things.
And again,
things we bring into how we approach
anything.
Your brain to save.
I mean you can't,
you just can't sit and analyze every
little aspect every.
I could sit in this table and like
really see every single little grain of
it if I wanted to,
but at some point the brain has to be
like,
who cares?
That's not valuable information.
Yeah,
you have to eat unless you're going to
sleep too.
A lot of conclusions.
We stereotype.
We simplify,
overly simplify everything and that's
one of the reasons why we chastise
people for racism because we know how
easily the inclination to judge people
specifically on what they look like and
how unfair it is and how reminding
ourselves over and over again and that's
not cool.
It gives the whole culture more of a
relaxed feeling.
You know?
Humans are so strange,
man.
We're so.
It's so cool to be a person.
You know?
It's so.
It's so bizarre when you think about all
the variables and the possibilities of
human behavior and how different
cultures except certain things,
and we look different and we live in
different climates and we're such an odd
fucking creature that's just completely
overwhelming.
This globe.
Yeah.
It's existence is a bizarre thing that I
just,
I can't get my head around existence.
I always,
I never really liked it that much.
But existence.
Yeah.
Broke your heels or after.
Before when I was a kid.
When you were all crossfitted up.
He didn't like existence.
No,
I did.
Then
A.
Yeah,
you're right.
Then you were healthy and vibrant.
Yeah.
Energy.
Um,
I mean when I was like a young angsty,
like [inaudible] young man,
I'm very bitter about the world,
about a lot of very depressed.
Uh,
yeah.
I mean when I'd be,
when I started comedy,
when I've,
I mean I used to drink like a lunatic,
now I drink more like a normal person,
but um,
I would when I was my most hung over,
which I'd only get like four hangover as
a year.
Um,
but when I was as sick as I've ever
been,
that's when I get my best writing done.
It was like some self defense mechanism
where something like that.
My brain doesn't operate like that
anymore.
But,
well,
I think when you're in periods of
extreme emotion or energy or just a
transitionary mode in your life,
whether it's a,
a breakup or the end of a job,
or moving to a new place,
it's sort of kicks in this,
this effect is the newness,
the novelty of that experience sort of
kicks in this effect where you want to
express yourself.
You want to sort of reestablish,
you know,
your,
your point of view on things,
your perspective on things.
A lot of great stuff comes from that.
You know,
a lot of,
a lot of great music especially,
right?
I mean,
teen angst and anger is like,
wow,
where's the nirvana without angst,
right?
I mean,
one of the greatest bands of all time,
he raped me,
my friend.
Really?
Uh,
you know,
I mean,
that is just pure response to just the,
the,
the frustrations of the world,
preaching to the choir.
And Nirvana was my first love dude
to this day.
Remember Buddy mind playing it for me.
And uh,
we,
it was a cassette tape and it was,
we're in Newton,
Massachusetts.
It wasn't even my friend who's my
friend,
Jimmy's friend were over his house.
He was like,
you got to hear this.
It's called Nirvana.
And we play.
And we were both like,
what the fuck?
This guy's went deep.
It was smells like teen spirit,
you know,
I hadn't really listened to any music.
Um,
at the time that I discovered Nirvana,
I discovered Nirvana through weird Al
did a parody of smells like teen spirit
that I liked.
And then I was like,
that music sounds pretty cool.
And then I found the real version and
that was like the first time I found
that I enjoyed music.
That wasn't a joke.
My friend Eddie was in a band back in
those days and he was like,
he was in a metal,
it was like a metal band.
And um,
he was like,
that song,
like,
that band completely killed metal.
They completely killed hair bands like
poison and those kinds of bands,
they just died because they seem so
silly,
you know,
like,
it just seemed like a,
you,
it's,
you know,
it's like you had water in your ear and
you got the water out of your ear and
you could hear and you can,
hey man,
what's your stuff at Europe with cotton
mouth?
Do not wear makeup,
but no,
putting on hairspray.
I'm not teasing my hair up.
This is something about the,
the real rawness of that music.
I mean even guns n roses,
man.
Remember when Axel rose used to tease
his hair?
He says Harris all sprayed up and fucked
up like a,
like an eighties girl from Dallas.
That.
Yeah,
when Nirvana came along and it was like
losing them.
No more hairspray,
bro.
Let's just not working,
man.
Yeah,
I mean,
yeah,
there's so much great comedy that came
out of anger and go to.
Yeah,
there is areas
is teased up here.
If you go to the welcome to the jungle,
welcome to the jungle.
A video is the best example of it.
It's crazy,
man,
that the different shifts in culture and
what's acceptable and then just becomes
completely ridiculous.
Look at that,
get all that hair.
It's great
busy,
but that was what people did back then.
That was like a big,
a big look.
I'm ever.
He had so many tattoos.
I was like,
Oh my God,
that guy's ruined his body with all
those tattoos,
but I remember thinking that when I was
a kid,
still aI.
still haven't.
I'm a natural like midwestern aversion
to tattoos that like I think tattoos are
like I'm starting to grow and
appreciation for them,
but it's taken me work to,
to get there and I don't have any
myself.
It's embracing in the
finite
aspect of life.
This is not going to last like this idea
that you're going to ruin your body
forever.
Your body's not going to be around
You know,
like what's it gonna look like when
you're 80?
Do you think anybody wants to see your
back when you're 80?
It doesn't matter if this unit looks
like shit,
crazy wrinkly back and back,
and then when that time comes,
you're just going to be concentrating on
staying alive.
I liked the idea of having like little
snapshots from your life.
Even if even if say or tattoo has
nothing to do with anything,
the cool design,
you'll still remember that period of
your life a little bit more.
I think looking at that tattoo,
you'll remember when you got it and
where you were at that state.
That's what Anthony Bourdain has.
It was a gang of tattoos all from
different trips,
you know,
like get some different trips and so it
reminds them of that.
I got this in Bali,
this was from Hawaii.
This is.
And having something like that,
it's to him,
it's like these anchors for these
incredible experiences that he's at
because who the fuck has traveled more
over the world and that guy,
right?
I think you'd look good in a Japanese
body suit.
Dude.
What do you think?
What's the Japanese body suit go crazy
Yakuza style that go from the neck down.
They have everything all the way your
butt,
all the way down to your feet.
I'm not picturing what you're.
This guy.
I've never seen like a Yakuza Japanese
tattoo bodysuit.
Never seen.
This guy's crazy.
They do the whole.
Oh yeah,
that's you.
Yeah,
man.
I'm telling you.
You're missing out.
Is your future.
How do I not cold enough?
Thirty six.
Not too late.
Start now.
You'd be done intentionally.
Skipped work.
You're 40 sexually.
Like this dude.
Who?
What's a good luck?
That's scary to me.
Yeah,
I do.
I do really like those three d tattoos.
Yeah,
like really good ones.
So yeah.
Yeah,
if you'd just like Google Three d tattoo
images with like the girls weird,
like creepy leg that looks hollow.
I'm like that.
That leg.
They're like,
I think that cool as fuck.
Oh yeah.
That's amazing.
That's one of the best fencer.
That's incredible.
Really.
It's bizarre.
It's so bizarre.
It's like a wood carving.
If you haven't seen it.
It looks like a.
she's like a thin piece of wood.
We've carved out recess,
isn't it?
I think if I was going to get something
at either be something like that or I
don't know that I'll ever have a memory
that I'll get a tattoo of a star.
Jamie will get that brick star in the
middle of the top.
Yeah.
Whoa.
Holy Shit.
That's incredible.
Like,
look what he's done to like the outer
skin where it looks like rip parchment.
Yeah.
It is all of his,
uh,
his ideas.
We had a great fucking tattoos tattoo.
Yeah.
It's a,
you know,
you've got to find a good artist too.
You got to have someone you trust to
draw on,
you know the guy's foot.
Fucking freak me out,
man.
Maybe you should get that shit
one binder to not jump so much of.
Yeah.
I still love heights to this day.
Really?
Yeah.
I won't jump off shit anymore because I
would feel silly if I hurt myself again,
but I can't get enough.
Did you see that?
I put a video up on instagram a couple
of days ago that someone sent me.
Oh my God.
It was Kingston just posted of him up in
Hollywood.
He's the one that I put it.
It's pretty freaky,
but this other one is freaky because
it's like their most of it is looking
down and jumping down to their feet on
these little ledges like,
look at this,
watch this,
prepare to shit your pants.
Watch this,
watch this guy.
It drops down hanging over the edge.
I'm freaking out.
Just watching them.
See that's the kind of stuff that I
like.
I'm waiting.
I'm waiting to back.
I want to do that.
Oh,
let's see.
Did my hands are sweating right now?
I'm like,
dude,
just okay.
We did it.
Let's get outta here.
Climbed back up.
I've done weird shit like that.
So even though you busted your.
Oh Jesus Christ.
Yeah,
that's,
that's something that I could see myself
doing.
Dammit.
I can't watch this.
You could see yourself doing that.
Really?
Yeah.
Jumping.
I don't know.
I just have always had like I've always
been a bit of an adrenaline junkie.
I just tend to.
I like pushing it a little too far.
It gets me in trouble sometimes.
Well,
I guess he did that one time many times
in my life.
Yeah.
What other times I've been in,
I've had to go to jail and stuff like
that.
Just for my.
I've had a,
just drinking mostly like way,
way,
way back before I was a comedian or
anything.
I had a couple of drunk driving tickets
and I've run from cops like 100 times in
my life because he wants.
Yeah,
no,
like on feet,
on a car twice.
Actually twice.
The first time I got away.
The second time I didn't.
Jesus Christ.
Dude.
Criminal.
Yeah.
I just had like this very sheltered,
wholesome upbringing that like fucked
with my head because it just wasn't like
I just knew it wasn't reality and I just
try to do everything that I could to
like rebel against it.
It's kind of car.
Were you drive when you were running
away from the cops?
Um,
I was driving a 95 Honda civic stick
shift.
All that happened was the opposite.
We raised the guy that I know.
So,
so the cop was driving past me and then
he saw me and then he had to turn around
and uh,
I think guys like speeding or something
like that and then,
but he had to go past me and turned
around and it was like in my
neighborhood and I knew exactly.
I just took a couple turns quick and hid
behind a building,
turned my lights off and I saw like I
saw them through these windows.
It was real intense.
Pull up to the stop sign.
I saw him looking for me back and forth
through this road and then I saw him
take off in the other direction and then
I just fucking flipped around and I got
the hell out of there.
What was the,
what was he looking for you for?
I think I was just speeding and banks.
Yeah,
I think I met.
Who knows if I was like swerving or
whatever else or you just saw a kid that
was,
you know,
I was like 16,
17 at the time.
Saw a kid that was out at like one in
the morning or whatever and might've
done something.
I don't know,
the second time when I got caught,
um,
this is so fucking stupid.
I was driving and I was like flying.
I don't know what my reasoning was
exactly.
Like I said,
I was an adrenaline junkie but I was
like flying through stop signs and
stuff.
I was going 70 miles an hour in a 20
mile an hour zone and like three or four
in the morning I was trying to get back
to my friend's house before they went to
bed.
So I go to have a place to crash.
That was like my weird logic behind it.
And also it was fun for me to be be
trunk and driving this past and I blew
through stop signs and then I saw and
then I saw this car with its lights on
and I'm like,
fuck,
that's a cop.
But I just kept on driving anyway.
And I that fast.
And I kept on,
like swerving around corners and he was
catching up to me like pretty easily.
And um,
and then when he put his lights on I
pulled over and then he came up and I
was like,
oh,
thank God I thought you were this person
that was chasing me.
They had this,
this dodge neon that was like similar
kind of a made up like headlights that
would look similar.
Instastory yeah.
And,
and there's like a couple people,
a couple of cops showed up and I was,
because they called me in when,
uh,
when they're like,
this is,
this is chase.
But as soon as the guy put his lights
on,
I pulled right over and um,
and he,
uh,
I don't know if I was fucking fooling
these two dudes or what,
but it's like,
I think they're kind of let me go.
And then this woman cop showed up that
knew me because I have like $1,100
drinking tickets and shit.
She's like,
because that Shane Moss,
he's like,
he's up to something,
give them breath a lot.
And she comes over and I was wearing a
winter coat and she's like,
what's in your pockets?
And I looked down and there was,
I had two beer cans pocket,
but like going to bed more obvious I ah,
fuck.
And I took him out and then that was it.
That was my,
that was my second.
Dewey.
Yeah.
That never got another one good for,
you know.
Yeah,
that's a good time to end.
I was a 20 years old and I was,
I had a bit of arrested development.
I was a bit,
as a bit immature a bit.
Uh,
I was extremely rebellious,
a bit of an adrenaline junkie.
And where can people see your show?
Because we've got to wrap this up.
Yeah.
I have a 65 city tour with my show about
psychedelics.
It's called a good trip.
So if you live in the United States,
I will be in your area.
I'm making,
I'm making a large loop around the US
and then a small loop,
um,
and Shane Moss on twitter,
USSC.com and it shamed comedy on
twitter.
Comedy on twitter,
on instagram.
Uh,
I don't have an instagram actually.
And My podcast is here.
We are.
So if you go to here we are podcast.com.
I have a different scientists on each
week talking about the research.
Cool.
Thanks Shane.
Thank you so much.
Have a great time for me to be back
tomorrow with a John Anthony of the
famed magical Egypt one into DVD series.
A fucking fascinating discussion on
Egypt will certainly follow.
See you soon.
Bye.