Not only as a mortal technique here,
but his broad a motherfucker so
cool that he's wearing a fanny pack.
Bobby Bang, Bang. Independent of my
love for the fanny pack. This dude was,
she's out there all completely on his own,
on the Nache with true love for
the fanny pack. Much respect.
Not only am I bring it back to fanny pack,
I just started selling them.
So I sell a higher primate.com fanny pack.
It's a quality roots fanny pack,
just dice clay was in and he
had the dopest fanny pack,
this sweet leather fanny pack.
And it was so nice.
City bank was something wrong.
It was me by roots.
You know that company that makes bags,
it's like a dope fanny pack.
And I was like,
what'd you get done?
When I was jealous cause all my other
ones were functional but discuss thing.
But this was like, it was
actually fashionable. I was like,
I can bring it back with roots.
So I contacted roots and had them print
up the higher primate logo on a fanny
pack. So boom. Not just t shirts,
but now fanny packs a motherfucker's
branching out. See, there it is.
It's hard to see the logo,
but then some monkey with like
go, whoever coined the term fanny
packs are we fucking see. To me,
if it had been like survival pack, every
dude would have when like, oh dude,
I got my new survival pack. My, it's
not a man purse. It's a survival pack.
No Dude, it's a fanny pack. I don't
mind saying I'll put it on. Lie Down.
It's true strength that you're not
worried about the definitions of others.
Really word. These guys who have given
you a hard time during this rocket.
Rocket strong. No, not me. It was my
there. I would rock that one bucket.
Bucket strong. I like
that. Survive survival pat.
It's all in the market though.
Yeah, it's, it's a cock
shield. Keeping myself in them.
If an asteroid comes from the sky,
it'll hit my fanny pack
before it hits my deck.
Hopefully it'll deflect,
deflect it.
Listen if something's falling out of the
fanny pack and save your pack and
your leg and then two days today,
cell phones are very
durable, my friend. Correct.
I think you're out of line.
You've done those studies.
Yeah.
There's some fucking people that have
survived actually rocks falling from the
sky and hit it. I'm strange enough
a lady got hit in the arm recently.
It was like a, it went through her
house and like hit her arm. All right,
thank you. Can get great. Okay. Come
on. I mean she didn't catch a dome shot,
you know, that would have been some
whole other shit, you know? Yeah.
Well most likely you're going to die if
you get hit by some folks with Scott,
Donnie Darko, jet falling
out of the sky. Yeah. Engine.
Most likely. If something falls
from the sky, you're fucked.
But if it doesn't and it hits
your higher primate fanny pack,
you might survive, son. You
might get to that shit alive.
Better survival packs. Survival pack.
Indeed. Indeed. So if I have a pack,
just sounds too phony
though. Nah, you got to
put the survival pack and then you got
to put like the Joe Rogan Cock Shield
edition with like just like the metal
plate. I think it should just be implied.
A metal plate on the top of the cameo,
son c s I don't think I should sell it
should have a hole in it so you can see
play with your Dick. Ain't good parties.
So like diner, like the movie diner.
Remember when he got that girl Mickey
Rourke got that girl to touch his dick by
putting it through the popcorn. Oh,
that's an old school trick, right?
That might've been invented. And that
movie though, I'm not sure. Probably not.
When you think about all the perverts
in the world, that Shit's probably old.
Really old. She's um, anyway,
higher primary.com. That's dash shit
primate also. Yeah, it's both now.
Yeah. Now it's uh, it's actually, uh,
just hire primary tot come to about that.
Anyway,
we were sponsored by one 800
flowers.com because it's all molds,
Valentine's Day.
Sweeties fuck.
Valentine's Day is one
of those ones when you,
especially if you're just getting into
a check man, he got to respect that day.
Birthdays and that one
you can blow off Easter.
You don't have to say happy Easter,
but like this shit,
Valentine's Day to sit big one boys.
Y'All I the best thing I did the
best thing ever for Valentine's Day.
My son is born on Valentine's Day.
Oh, that's cool. That's awesome.
For the rest of my life. Like you got
the best gift I could ever give you. Oh,
that's beautiful.
So do forget your son wasn't born money.
That wasn't the case.
Go to one 800 flowers.com the podcast
sponsor one 800 flowers.com there.
They have right now a very special offer
of two dozen multicolored roses for
only 29 99 24 delicious and
beautiful roses for just 29 99.
You can't beat that anywhere. And
uh, if you missed the deadline,
1-800-FLOWERS still
has other great offers,
but you need to order now.
This is your last chance to get
it for Valentine's Day. One,
800 flowers.com 1-800-FLOWERS
is the only one that I trust.
We use 1-800-FLOWERS. Brian, in fact,
just recently used 1-800-FLOWERS
with great results.
I even did it the same day delivery.
I got it off the area and an
excellent move show spontaneity.
Yeah, girls like that. Show a man.
It takes action and either goes to
one 800 flowers.com or you can call
1-800-FLOWERS. Either way,
you use the code word J, r e.
If you go to one 800 flowers.com click
on the radio microphone in the upper
right hand corner and enter j r.
E.
That's one 800 flowers.com enter jre or
call wait on 1-800-FLOWERS and mentioned
j r e and k yourself.
Some beautiful roses just when it comes
with a key that she could wear as a
necklace later.
For what? For her chastity
belt. How dare you.
No. Once you, the roses
are the to her heart, sir.
How rude.
One 800 flowers.com I
know who's fucking off.
That's 1-800-FLOWERS
stock, Tom, so how'd you knew that name?
Just a guest that you need the name.
Name of the actual bouquets.
No heat in my heart was
so obvious is a key.
There's beautiful flowers.
That's the key to the the woman's heart.
That's the actual name.
Yo,
you are amazing fan already,
but now I'm amazed.
That's not a freestyle.
It's total freestyle.
That was a luck. That's what I
mean here. It was total luck.
I had no idea what that was. The name
of it. That was total luck. Look,
it's got a key. It's a bouquet.
I mean what the fuck else is?
It's like that's what
it's going to be called.
The trick guys into thinking that you
were a penthouse pet of the month.
Listen man, this ain't hard. It's key.
You only you would know about that.
Most guys, we're not know the Penthouse
peds carry keys are on their next.
Anyway,
our other sponsor is legal zoom.com which
Brian will most likely one day need.
Again, legalzoom.com not going to get
you that at any of that kind of trouble,
but what it can do is deal with any legal
bullshit that you would normally have
to go to a lawyer for and wait in line
to pay a lot of money, deal with it,
much cheaper,
much easier and with way less hassle
things like starting a business or
incorporating forming an LLC. You
could do that. It just 99 bucks,
you can get a last will for 69 bucks
a living trust, power of attorney,
all that kind of shit.
Legal Zoom can get all that done
for you and if you freak out,
if you're in the middle of it and
you're like, fuck, this is not,
this is not legal.
Legal Zoom will connect you to a
third party independent attorney.
So if you do panic,
that will connect you with attorney
that's not connected to them so well
connected in the fact that they connect
you. You know what the Fuck I'm saying?
Someone objective.
Is the call center here in like
America or is it like somewhere in like
Indonesia? Like a tide attorney? Listen,
I wasn't,
I would assume that good
your area,
if you live in Indonesia you're going
to get a fucking Indonesian attorney.
I can just imagine the call center being
like Mongolia or some shit like no.
According to our tribal law,
like the two of you have to meet
and fight with like a Yak ball.
I don't think so.
I think it has to be American.
And now for a special discount
for listening to this podcast,
enter the code word Rogan in the referral
box at checkout for more savings.
Legal Zoom is not a law firm,
but they can connect you with a third
party attorney and provide you with self
help services. This is what Brian
used to incorporate a desk squad.
It's what Arbor use for on it.
Uh,
legal zoom is a way that you can get a
lot of really important legal shit done
without actually having to go to a
lawyer. What's funny about that? No,
I'm just looking at this.
Divorce is chicks like I am so ready
to get some more dick. Oh yeah,
that's exactly what she's
saying. Perfect picture. Cause
she's a catch. If you just thought, well
just, you know, if you were like, so uh,
what's your situation? Well just getting
divorced right now unfortunately.
I mean fortunately
I'll be nice to you too.
Let's kiss junk.
We got fucked up and
look what he left behind.
Someone's gotta be tuned 99 no,
no, no, no, no. Nothing wrong.
Maybe she's in a wheelchair.
No, no. I mean beautiful woman.
Maybe somebody didn't fucker correctly.
How about that 99 come on man.
This is a lot of dudes out there that
don't fuck their girlfriend correctly.
It's true. Shit goes wrong. You
forget. You start, start getting lazy.
Just going for the titty grab and then
right into sticking it in and then I
totally see you going to
handle your business. Somebody
else will. Well you know,
maybe it's just the guy that showers
and then she talks to at the gym and you
know, he's, he's just friendly. He
didn't even try to get my phone number.
I'd see him at the gym.
It's just friendly.
It was like finally a guy
that doesn't have an agenda.
Next name, change. One 39
that's coming next, sweetie.
Changing names. There's too much weird
shit on the Internet about your real name.
Hooker. It's time to change. Change.
Switch up your Google search results.
legalzoom.com use the code word rogue
and save yourself some money. Green Card.
Get a green card.
You can get a green card.
They can get a green card for 595 dog.
They can shut up. Had a hot chick.
That's well, they, they're not saying
that you're going to get a green card.
That's one thing that's real important.
If you're actually going through
the paperwork already. Yeah.
Maybe legal zoom can help you out,
but if you just knock under a fucking
fence from Mexico and you're like,
well,
why does it go scrape together 500
that's the only place to sneak
under a fence. Come on, man.
You doesn't mean he's gotta be
Mexican. You can't sneak. You're right.
It could be Afghany.
I've been catching a lot of
people that are not Mexican.
Cross it to the Mexican border, Bro.
I'm sure. I would imagine so. They think
I've been watching the news. Lakey,
I last sponsor [inaudible] dot com
and n I t since Aubrey Marcus
was on the podcast yesterday.
We talked a lot about on it. I'll give
you an abbreviated podcast sponsor.
This is human optin.
Is that when you'd say
[inaudible] sometimes that
you're supposed to say n a n
and it seems like you'd say,
ah,
but really it's supposed to be an like I,
I forget.
There's a few examples of that where
it's the correct grammar is actually Ann
and I and I sometimes pretend them smart
and try to use it the right way and I
fuck it up.
I'm on it.com o n n I t,
a human optimization website.
We sell all sorts of strength conditioning
equipment, supplements, supplements,
both for athletic activities and also
for mood and cognition and even for your
immune system on it.com o.
N N.
I t used the Codeword Rogan save
10% off any and all. All right.
And mortal technique is here.
It's get cracking
Joe Rogan podcast.
He's back.
Ladies and gentlemen with the
new posse mortal technique.
The only guy this is posted on
the message board, uh, yesterday.
This is the only guy that brought a posse
to the podcast and they didn't suck.
Oh thank you. Cause usually when
you get posses you get like,
like you'll have like one cool dude
and his friends who are annoying,
you know that shit happens. We're also
just him, me, all my peoples holding down.
All right. This is my brother, Chino
XL Chino, my man. And that is my,
with Bobby Bowden. It was
throbbing. It was just his birthday.
So he's still recovering. Tom. It's
hard being on the road with these two
I'm sure especially cause
Bobby rocks a fanny pack
soldier and Barbara,
you'd be surprised what fanny,
how many wonders the fanny
pack does for me. Hey man,
it's great at the airport clip. Drop it
in that bag, pick it up at the other side.
Boom. Done. Survival
pack, survival. Surviving.
What am I going to survive? What do
you, what do you got another 50 years.
Come on man, you ain't survive and
shit. No one survived and shit.
Maybe the getting bypass.
Maybe the I exists now pat.
It really should be called a groupie
pack cause you could just flip it around
and keep all your personal
items and never leaves your,
oh you're a criminal yourself
relating me or anybody else.
Just him.
I don't know what you meant by that.
That just slide all the men in the room.
You said you confuse you the
fuck out of here with that.
You got a little cocky on there.
That's what happened there son.
You forgot where you were. It's a survival
plan as part of the survival pack.
The works survival. That's like
a Douchey word though, right?
Like survival.
Like you know like survival survivor
man is cool but like survival training,
we're going through survival training.
Like I'll come on man,
what are you doing and
you'll find the people are,
is there are people who really do
that type of like my friend told me,
uh, there was some ex military dude that
he liked trains executives on like this
survival like vacation weekend.
And it's basically like for people that
want to feel like they did something
important.
So He'd take them out to like this like
area in the countryside and they run a
bunch of obstacles and they get
them in shape for like, you know,
week or two and then bust their ass.
And then they call it
like survival training.
But that's obviously not
like real survival training.
So by that I guess he had jumped out of
like a parachute out of a fucking plane
into like a wilderness area and then
meet someone at a certain place like two
weeks later. Like all right, go
to like Lz one like you know,
15 miles away through like wolf dens and
mountain ranges forest and who the fuck
else knows? You know, you just
can't take the four oh five there.
You got to walk on the fucker.
That's the train.
They can be a real show that where they
took a guy and just dropped him off
hunger games style in the
middle of the woods. I'm,
I'm Kinda surprised they
haven't done that yet.
That'd be kind of very interesting.
They sorted, they like can survivor,
they do go and they have to like get
food and they, they do shit like that.
But it's very different than like taking
one person and like telling them that
they have to make it across a forest
and get to another side. You know,
I'd never really watched that show too
often are where their lives ever really
endanger.
That's the point.
It's always an Dorrance really more than
survival because you know that there's
a way out.
Let's take somebody who didn't even
know this was going to happen at all and
dropped them there. Yeah. Well
those people that are on that show,
you know like when you like you see that
everybody gets by okay and everybody's
okay and the, you know, like they're
not in danger because it's television.
They're,
they're in danger.
If you're in Borneo or one of those
places where they filmed survivor man,
survivor rather, you're in danger,
you're fucking for sure in danger.
There's a lot of shit out there.
Like just because he's a
bunch of cameras out there,
it doesn't mean they're going to keep
you safe. Like when we did fear factor,
there was a lot of times we just got
lucky with like, nobody got hurt,
but it's just because we got lucky like a
rattlesnake, which, you know, like bowls.
They made people ride bowls. All
right. That's just ridiculous. Dude.
They had a 90 pound girl. I say they, I'm
distancing myself from the shot. No, no.
I said like,
he wasn't in that,
like I wasn't even the tone at the top
of the book. If it was happening today,
I swear to God,
I would tell them not to do it.
I would tell the girl not to do it 100%.
Like there was a guy that was like a
crazy daredevil dude. I would have said,
you know, hey man, people have done it.
I Know Donaldson, Ronny [inaudible],
Ronny rides bulls, the crazy
fuck. But for most people,
it's a hair raising proposition
for this little 98 pound girl.
There's no way she's going to be able
to hang on. And these guys who were the,
the stunt guys were like,
don't worry about it. These
are stunt bowls. They're, uh,
they're, they're less aggressive.
There's stunt bolts. Yeah, but this,
I'm like the bold isn't
though. It's a fucking stud
ball to the bull. He's a bull.
There's no stunt bowls in the bowl world.
They don't have like a, well, you know,
I'm just thought, you know what man,
I'm not going to tell you as something,
you know what I mean?
That's my brother over there,
away about the amount of dudes.
You know what? I'm just gonna.
I'm showing you his boss and then
I'm going to stomp on your head.
Now they'll stop on your fucking head.
They'll kick you in the face.
We just got lucky. So like survivor
man, that guys, that's real shit.
Like there's nothing fake about that show.
But that's when that dude exists
by himself and, and you know,
he'll get to like a certain location
and I'll pick them up like in five days.
He even doesn't 10 days sometimes,
but that's the guy that carries his own
camera, right? Yes. That is 100% legit.
He's in danger.
He's in danger every show.
I think I seen him super dehydrated
at one time. It was really,
really bad if that mother fucker was
in Lyon territory, the survivor man,
survivor man or the survivor,
the show survivor on man.
I was making the comparison between the
two of them. Like that survivor show,
there's still in danger.
You're, you're still in danger.
You're doing a bunch of dangerous shit.
You're doing wild aggressive shit. But no,
no, you know, no more danger than if
anybody would be, if you were camping,
you know, camping, you're
doing dangerous shit different.
If it was like survivor Basra,
like survivor,
Mogadishu matter. I
mean survivor man, Shit.
Like that dude went to Africa and he
slept a night in Africa in this area where
we're lions live with a hot air
balloon. And he's, his idea was,
the idea for the show was if you were in
a hot air balloon and it ran out of gas
and it fell somewhere like wa or the
balloon got punctured or some shit and it
fell somewhere and you were trapped,
how would you get by?
How would you get out of it?
So this guy went to fucking Africa and
that was all he had for shelter was the
basket that this fucking,
this suppose that hot air balloon
had and then the flame thrower to,
to make the balloon inflate and go up.
You know,
they hit that the fire comes up and the
heat is what makes the balloon rise and
they drop it off when they
want it to fall. Well he uh,
had that as well and he was using that
to keep the lions away low and fire at
them because when he would set it up on
the ground, it was like a flame thrower.
Right. Cause it's when, when
it's underneath the, the
balloon, it's, you know,
it's blowing this fire up
into the inflated balloon.
But when it's on the ground,
he's just shooting it at the line.
It's just him and one can't it just
him and a camera and a camera and some
fucking lions. Did you hear in
the background you hear like,
yeah, that's good to know how
that show's going to end. Right?
It's just going to end with like a still
shot of like it was fucking camera on
the ground and people picking
out his NDA man. Well yeah,
I think what they do is they um,
they know where he is by GPS location
and I guess he probably has a satellite
phone. Like if everything went
terribly wrong and he had to call,
like if he breaks his leg or something
like that, he'll just die. I mean,
he has to get medical help so they'll,
they must have some sort of a plan,
but he still, his life is in
danger every step of the way. Oh,
I mean when you see people that
swim with sharks for example,
that's the part that I, I say, okay,
I did that with like baby sharks
and we'd like sand sharks.
They have something at
the mall of America.
I went back then with like my ex
girlfriend years and years and years ago.
It was cool. But when I see people
who swim with like 10 foot sharks,
12 foot in like the wild,
you know,
where the shark doesn't know
that you're a filmmaker.
It doesn't have any idea that this
is for discovery or anything else.
Right. And it's not a stunt
shark and they never will.
They don't understand anything with it.
All they know is what's in front of them.
Eat, eat, what's in front of him,
eat whatever we eat with them.
Used to eating well, they used to
eat. There's some people that have,
I don't know what it is,
I don't know what they're doing,
but they managed to not get killed.
I think if you get into the water,
the shark doesn't see you as prey as much
as it sees you if you're on the top of
the water.
I think the top of the water is a big
danger because people look like seals.
That's one.
One thing when you're down in the water,
I think you're more of a weird curiosity.
He looked like a swimming monkey water
and it, oh good. I get a snack. It's,
it's hard to figure out probably what
the fuck you are. You know? I think
the animals that are that stupid,
they just sort of get by doing the
same shit over and over and over again.
And for sharks, it's like, look for
seals. Boom, looked for seals, boom,
look for seals. Whoa, what the fuck is
this? Surfboard? It's tastes terrible.
You know, this tastes like Arby's. Get
this fucking Guy Adam, my marriage.
But if you like, look at
them, man, you look at their,
their black dead eyes and
you look at their, you know,
their body is just designed to just chew
or there's not a lot of thinking going
on. We had this conversation earlier
about what it means to be a hunter,
but wouldn't it be hunting really if
you were like in a rowboat with like a
Harpoon going after one of
them and not like, you know,
and like a giant vessel shooting at them
with a high powered rifle as they were
in a little boat.
You're going to die.
You're not going to beat a great
white shark, but all right. All right.
We're talking about,
you want to get extreme right now.
I don't mean like any kind of shark,
the shark or that's big a tiger shark.
I guess maybe like a six footer.
If you're really good with a spear,
you gotta get like four or five and,
but if he flips you in the water man,
most likely you're fucked. I mean, I
just depends on what kind of boat you're,
if you're in their element,
that's a cheating thing
anyway. If you're in a boat,
you're cheating. If you have anything
out, if you have anything. Yeah,
actually cheated.
Everyone can act.
You like drop all those weapons
and just go flesh to flesh. Yeah.
You got no chance. Don't have teeth.
Like y'all Niggas do have hands.
That doesn't,
the shark skin note is when you feel
it. It, when you rub it one way,
it's like completely rough and we'll
cut your skin and then when you go from
back to front, it's completely,
absolutely silky smooth.
Yo when we were little kids, we had like
a dissection program. And the last, uh,
the last thing that we did was
like third grade or something,
but they cut open a shark and we had to
take his kids out like it's children.
And when you felt the shark,
they said watch.
And the science teacher rubbed his hand
nose to the back and his hand was cut
open.
And he said that what the normal normal
sharks do is they just swim through a
school of fish. And since this skins
built like that, whatever they touch,
they cut.
And then on the second loop around they
can smell the blood or they can see one
of the fishes that they've
cut and go through it.
But if you touch the shark normal shot
from like, you know, back to front,
it's totally silky
smooth. Wow, that's weird.
Why would it be silky smooth that way?
That seems strange because
I think that thing,
it's just like a jagged sort of thing.
I have no idea if they can pull it
in and pull it out, you know? I mean,
there must be some mechanism.
All I know is that, hey man,
I don't want to get rubbed up on by them.
I don't want to pull,
I don't want them to pull anything in.
I'm pulling anything out on me.
Getting in the water with sharks,
playing civil, if you will.
There's a big issue now in Australia,
you know,
because they're calling the sharks.
They're killing a lot of great whites
because they've had so many people die
recently. They're just
like, enough is enough.
Too many people are
getting attacked by sharks.
Like we've got to kill some
of these fucking sharks,
and a lot of people think it's bad idea.
Those people are assholes.
Fucking
crazy. Assholes knows a lot of bad idea
or the sharks killing people. Yeah,
well you know what?
Is there a EH wrong?
Our planet suck it.
If there's a bunch of sharks out
there that are killing people,
it's time to start killing sharks,
period.
Anybody who wants to argue
is a fucking anti-American.
It's going on in Australia.
They support terrorism.
Is that what goes on, Joe Rizzo? A
shark. You're down with the enemy.
That's the ultimate,
not the NSA.
It's on our ultimate enemy or ultimate
enemy or fucking sharks. You know,
it's funny,
with all the shit that they listened to,
I'm always surprised that we still
have old kidnapping serial killers.
You figured if they were
tapping everybody's phone,
they could find anybody that they want it.
Yeah,
they would look at everybody's
phone. I just killed my
seven Tucker. Lol. You know,
like look at this mother fucker just
texted his friend. Who knows, dude,
someone someone's going to slip up. Oh,
well there's most certainly have. I'm,
I'm sure they've used it. I mean, if the,
if it's been around as long
as they say it's been around.
When you hear about the,
uh,
the actual coding of the NSA software
and how they first started doing it,
there was a guy there,
original NSA whistleblower.
I should pull this guy up and give
him his props because it's a pretty
fascinating story because he was a,
he was a whistle blower a long time ago
and he was the guy that was responsible
for making the software. And He, when
he, when he was making the software,
he was telling everybody like, hey, you
can't use this to just spy on everybody.
So he started doing all these interviews.
Um,
but it was before Edward
Snowden that so everybody,
everybody thinks of Edward Snowden as
the original, uh, NSA whistleblower.
But there was another guy before that.
There was another guy in 2002,
I believe. He came out
and, uh, yeah, here it is.
Bill Binney and,
uh,
this fucking guy told people
about this a long time ago.
There's a story of it on Youtube,
on, uh, the RT America channel.
That's Bill Binney, B,
I, N, n, e, y, and a,
he was a u s intelligence official.
And you worked for the NSA and he turned
into a whistle blower in a October
31st, 2001 after more than
30 years with the agency.
He was a high profile critic of his
former employers during the George W.
Bush administration and was subject
to an FBI investigations, of course,
including a raid on his home. Of
course, fucking thugs. Where's he at?
Where's he doing time now? He's not,
he's not doing time. That's what's crazy.
Where is he?
Because he called this before they did it,
whereas Edward Snowden called
it while it was happening.
So Edward Snowden got in trouble.
This guy was predicting the future and
he was saying that when he found out that
they were able to spy on everyone
and that they were using this system,
uh, the, the system that was a, it was
initially called trailblazer and uh,
it was a,
a system intended to analyze data carried
on communications networks such as the
internet, including social networks. Yes.
And he found out that they were actually,
they were starting to do it on there.
They were just trying to do
with everybody and he called it,
he said that's their plan. Their plan is
to monitor every email, every phone call.
And he said, the guy, you know,
he said, look, this is unamerican.
And the guy stuck his neck out there.
He got away with it though.
It's really interesting because
he just predicted it and you know,
he wasn't actually talking about
something that had happened,
but he got out of the NSA and said,
this is going on.
You know what's crazy though?
So for the first couple of years,
I mean making music.
People used to call me a
conspiracy theorist and I
always used to laugh and I'd
be like, all right, well
let's play it down. Let's,
let's Encyclopedia Brown this bitch right
now and tell me what is my conspiracy
that the government spies on you?
I was right about that. You know,
I released a record talking about how
you know we're going to war for false
reasons, that this is a false
premise to be in war. Okay,
well we found out that no
weapons of mass destruction,
I never said that Bush was
directly responsible for
nine 11 I said that I never
believed that government's version
because they couldn't even tell the truth
about the air to breathe. I always felt
like the story was in complete what's,
what's the conspiracy theory?
That's absolutely fucking true.
Now we find out that there are layers
upon layers upon layers of what's going on
in the world.
I said it,
the government itself was involved in
the drug trade in Peruvian cocaine.
So people said, oh my God, how can you
use this conspiracy theory? Really?
And now we find out that they
protect certain Mexican cartels,
it as long as they sell
out to other homeys.
The absolute truth of the drug game here
in America is they don't go after the
little fish to get the big fish.
You know what I mean?
They want the big fish so he can rat
out all the little fish and they can all
spend time in the jail because only the
main dude has the $10 million attorney.
So I mean, I don't blame this guy for
just being fed up and saying, hey man,
this is exactly what's going on or
what's going to go on in the future.
I'm just surprised that somebody
hasn't found a way to give him cancer
assumption and kill him off in a way
that doesn't raise that much suspicion.
Like I said,
he did it so long ago,
right before it ever became a public
issue that he quit in 2001 and that's when
he started talking and doing
all these interviews. Um,
you know what it is in three nine 11, 2001
post nine 11. It's when he quit. Look,
the dude is essentially, I mean he's
a real patriot. That's what he is.
He's a guy who was working in the,
in the office of,
he's working for the defense of the
country in the right way. I mean,
that's what he's doing.
He's, he, he doesn't,
he wants there to be like laws.
He wants there to be protection of rights
as well though he wants us to be able
to go after terrorists,
but he doesn't think the government
should be able to just willy nilly looking
at everybody's fucking emails.
But the government shouldn't,
shouldn't become a terrorist
in the process of going
after terrorists. Exactly.
And you're torturing random people
full in order to do that. Then you are
becoming the terrorists themselves.
And then there's no distinction really,
because one is a,
is a hidden danger that
people are terrified of.
And the other one is
exactly the same thing.
A hidden danger that people are
terrified from someone in power. He says,
you know what? I don't like
this guy. I don't like Rogan.
You know he's talking about the ATF.
That's my business. You know what?
I want you guys to ruin his fucking life.
I want you to go after him. You know it.
Well, it's been proven that they
do that with the IRS, right?
They use the IRS to go after
political enemies. I mean there,
there are a lot of fucking hedge rolled
because of that shit cause it got public.
Yet people have this, there's a lot
of no nonsense people out there.
That's the real issue.
There's a lot of people like harsh.
You believe in big foot, you believe
in conspiracy theories swollen.
What do you think the
government's out to get you?
There's a lot of these people that like
to pretend that it's foolish to think
that the government is involved
in anything shady ever.
And if they're always above ground,
they have too much power.
Whenever you get groups of
people that have that much power,
when you have essentially
the power to create laws,
the power to to go in to the the very
laws that were established in the
beginning of this nation and change them
so that you can get away with shit that
would ordinarily be illegal,
right?
Like all those things are only done
by people who have too much power.
They're not in,
they're never things that people vote on,
nobody of the people who never vote to
give themselves less rights and people
never vote to give more
trust in the government.
And the government's just sort of takes
it slowly but surely in the best way to
take it is to tell you there's a bunch
of enemies they have to protect you from.
It's a timeless age old trick.
And the idea that that's a conspiracy
theory is ignoring all of human history
from the jump,
everything ever done by people with guns,
swords or arrows, right? Everything
ever done was done with deception.
It was done by establishing enemies
and protecting you from those enemies.
They're they're timeless techniques and
the idea that the greatest government
conquer that.
We would stop doing that in 2014 that
after all they've learned after all these
years they go, you know what,
all that time tested shit.
We're going to set it aside and we're
going to be ethical. We're going to do,
we're going to be the ethical
because we're bomb was in office.
Now we're going to be ethical. I,
but there were people who believed in
his fairy tale and I did it. I wanted to,
I wanted,
I wanted to get in and go gotcha pitches.
I was fucking child of a single mom.
I was smoked weed is
there,
I remember in Harlem when he was
elected and it was like pandemonium.
I Shit you not that it,
it just so happened that they were moving
like a subway car. I'm pretty big deal.
People will usually want
to see him in the street.
But they were moving a subway car via
like a tractor trailer and they were
moving it through one 25th
from one side to another.
And they had a jumbo tron set up by
like the state building and he gave his
address and there were like hundred
thousand people in the street right there.
And they followed the procession
of the subway everywhere.
I saw an old lady get out of her car
and start dancing, you know what I mean?
And she was just like, look in she,
she must have been like 80 years old.
And I was like, Yo, my grandma, if you
see so happy, she's like, you know,
you got to understand,
I grew up in a time where people looked
at me like I wasn't a fucking human
being. And to see that, I mean,
look, I always discuss the, these,
these variations of oppression because
people try to liken what happens to
Africans and native to native Americans
to other struggles and other people
being oppressed. But you know what, you,
you can't you no one ever tried to,
for example,
kill somebody else from another
group because they knew how to read.
You know what I mean?
Like these things were specifically done
to a people to try and take away from
the legitimacy that they have to
dehumanize because that's the only way to
really do something that
negative to someone.
You have to find some sort of different
way to define them as a person so that
then you can justify it, not just to
yourself but to other groups of people.
You know, normal people
won't be like, Hey man,
I'm just going to kill this person and
take their land and their gold and their
oil or whatever it is. But
now it's like, oh my God, no.
These people and the way they are are
wicked and their wickedness is going to
spread to the rest of us so much.
Well, we have belief systems,
man and belief systems. Once they're in
place, they can be really scary. You know,
if you have a belief system that this
group that you're going after or all evil
and God is on your side and they
need to be smitten from the earth.
But that's on our side. Yeah. That's
the other one. God on your side.
And that's what I think turns a lot of
people off about religion. It's not,
there's no personal response
as much as you know, the, the,
the right wingers that are our
religious scream about, oh,
we want people and not get out.
I have personal,
why don't you take some personal
responsibility? You know, don't,
don't put it on God.
Put her on you.
You feel uncomfortable with
this being this way or you,
you don't like these
people for some reason.
Or maybe you've actually done the history
and you know that these people have a
legitimate reason to be unhappy with
this government or know that they've been
treated unfairly in some
way, shape, or form.
And I think there's a difference
between being angry, angry,
and having holy anger and having
a righteous anger, you know? And,
and being angry for reason,
not just being upset and feeling
like your quote unquote the victim,
but technically looking at
a situation and saying, no,
I was treated unfairly and you
know what I was taken advantage of.
And I think from the time that people
had been a caveman to, you know,
tomorrow all anger comes from being
treated unfairly or the perception that
you're treated unfairly. Anything lied
to you, treated me unfairly. You told,
you told someone else the truth,
but you told me a lie.
You know you stole from me, you treated
me unfairly, I let you into my house,
I protected you and you fucking
repaid me by robbing me.
All of that comes back to it.
And I just think that if this
government is even going to survive,
it really has to address the amount of
cynicism that exists in America right now.
Because that was the whole point.
I thought of Obama coming in,
the idea that people were so cynical
about a government under Bush that saw
McCain as an extension to that. They were
like, oh my God again, another one. Well,
who are we going to go to war with now?
But then when he came in,
he was supposed to be, you know,
the, the, the great unifier,
but he turned into a great pacifier.
He was just like, okay, cool,
everything's going to be
good. I'm going to, Oh,
I'm going to intellectualize all of this
and make it seem rational, you know,
so I'll get away with a whole bunch of
shit that if Mitt Romney had been elected
or if McCain had been elected and
done the exact same shit that he did,
they would have gone crazy.
They,
where are the people that are
more marching on Washington to,
to go against the war? We're
at a now. That's why, you
know, I keep it real Rogan.
I do a lot of activism.
We did a show yesterday to raise money
for people that were victims of that
typhoon in the Philippines,
you know,
and it's going straight to them because
of working with grassroots organizations.
But a lot of times when I see these big
activist groups and they come up to me
and I'm just like, Yo, where
the fuck are you now? You know,
you were all waving your flag, you
know, when it was the Bush era,
but now that Obama was in power, you
don't want to make any waves, you know?
Now I see people on Msnbc.
You're advocating a war in Syria.
You don't even know what the
fuck is going on. You know,
you don't know anything about
the history of that struggle.
You know the thing anybody,
uh, about the, the, the, the,
the idea of what's going to
actually happen once they
get attacked and they have
to call their clients. I mean,
there are clients, state of Russia,
there a vassal of Russia now.
They basically sold themselves off
because of the chemical weapons thing.
They said, all right, we'll give you the
chemical weapons then you and the UN,
we'll deal with that personally.
It enables them to say, all right,
we're going to be partners forever
and ever as long as Russia exists,
Syria will be here.
And that's the deal that they had to make.
And there are plenty of people
who made that deal with America.
As long as they exist,
man will be good.
But as soon as America is endanger guests,
what my ass is in danger too. You know,
there are plenty of places like Guam,
America holds on to Puerto Rico like
it's balls. Israel, I'll tell you right?
Puerto Rico is one of the weirdest ones,
right? Because it's sort of a state,
but not really a state. Well, it's
a commonwealth, right? It received,
it received a charter of independence
from Spain in like 1898 and literally the
next year the USS Maine exploded.
But when people did research,
you know,
decades later they found out the ship
imploded, exploded from the inside.
And ironically,
here's another interesting tidbit.
All of the white officers were on the
land when the ship exploded and the only
people on the ship were like the deck
hands and the people of color. And
Are you implying that someone in the
government blew up that ship, sir,
is that she has never happened before.
Remember the USS Maine,
that's what they say.
That's never even been planned.
There's a lot of people that feel that
the Bush administration had planned a
false flag on Iran,
but that's false because the Bush
administration was awesome and if they did
plan it it would have happened.
So you don't know what the fuck you
talking about? They were perfect.
They had god on their side. God got
underside side. Yo, I swear to God,
there was so many times
when I've seen people,
like when I go to colleges and there's
some preacher dude like in front of the
college arguing with the atheists and
I always ask him, I'm like, Yo Dude,
do you do you believe in the president?
And he said, I absolutely support,
you know, President
Bush. I was like, what?
What would he have to do to lose
your support? Like what, what,
what sort of things
would he have to abuse?
Could he kill someone and
still gain your support?
You know when the guy was like, well
that depends who, and I'm just like,
wait a minute, do what? Do you be mid?
Depends who the v ordered the deaths
of some people overseas who aren't
Christians,
he's forgiven,
but if he like shot someone next
door who he went to church with me,
he should burn in hell forever.
I mean at that point I think the select
of morality is what bothers a lot of
people about religion in general.
It's just like, okay cool.
I'm only going to care about the lives
of certain human beings because they
share the same belief system of mine,
but the moment that you don't,
then I feel so threatened
by your existence that I
don't care if your children
live or die.
Well,
you heard the,
the latest revelations about the NSA that
they were ordering drone strikes based
on metadata. They were ordering
drones, tribes based on GPS,
location of phones that
they were tracking. So they,
they might not have even known that
the guy that they were looking for was
inside the building and they just randomly
targeted buildings where these phones
existed. You know? That's if that's
true, that means they just said, okay,
well we're going to have to kill a whole
bunch of fucking people to get this
phone right.
Fun that he may not even be,
he'll hold my phone today, man.
Yeah. Uh, the, the whole thing here,
I'll pull it up because, uh, they were,
they did a story of it
on, um, on Rt. Yeah.
Use of NSA metadata defined drone.
Target kills.
That's crazy. Kill civilians.
They would find these,
I mean,
this is really hard to believe,
but they would find these people by the
location of their phone and then send in
the missiles. Jeez. That's,
that's evil shit. Wow.
That's really evil shit. And I know
there's bad people in the world for sure,
but that is not in any way,
shape or form the way to handle it.
There's gotta be a better way to kill
people because there's bad people that you
have to kill. You can't just kill
everybody around them. That shit's crazy.
You'll turn everybody against you a well,
you or I'm against you.
We should all be against, right. It's
murder. You're a murderer. You're,
you're just murdering people
in a way that is sanctioned.
But what strikes me about that is that
this government has no problem doing that
anyway. They call it collateral damage.
They say, okay, you know, we have,
we have a military target. It happens
to be near a school. You know what,
that's collateral damage.
Anybody could even think about doing
something like this though with the
metadata that's like insane, extreme
collateral damage. It's insane.
That's how they feel about it.
Glenn Greenwald, uh, is that
the guy, uh, who put this out?
I liked that guy. I liked
him too. My friend Sam Harris
hates his guts though. Why?
He thinks Sam Harris is a anti Islam.
Uh,
he's t Sam Harris is a neuroscientist,
is an author and he's,
he's pretty strong proponent of
atheism. Right? And, uh, this guy,
Glenn Greenwald, thinks that he's
got an anti Muslim, uh, agenda,
anti Islam agenda.
You know what's interesting,
I had this discussion with somebody about
atheism and their way of dealing with,
um,
different cultures and societies.
You can totally be an atheist to
be racist. It's like me, you know,
you can be a feminist
and you can be racist.
That's ridiculous to think that those two
things can't coexist in the same being.
My thing is this, when I hear
people like Darwin, sorry,
Richard Dawkins and people who are
Darwinists, um, have conversations.
What's interesting to me is the,
the,
the level of civilization that they'll
attribute to like white Christian
society.
And even though they'll say it's barbaric,
it's still not as barbaric as those dark
brown people's cultures because they're
even more dangerous. And my thing is
this ticks, right? My thing is this,
it's like if someone says allow
walk bar before they go into war,
and that is the, the, the benchmark
to say that this is, you know,
a religious killing.
Then what about all the soldiers of
America who say the Lord's prayer before
they go into combat? Isn't
that interpreted as, Oh man,
Jesus helped me kill these motherfuckers.
Really?
Then you're making a sacrifice then is
Christ a blood God to you or is it a god
of peace? That's the question that I
have to ask. And that is the part where,
you know,
when I speak to people who are atheists
who don't believe in in theism and stuff
like that,
you have to separate that from actual
historians and people who have studied the
history of religion and the history of
different cultures and societies to say
which one is more so called civil to one
another because I think we've fallen to
this idea of the civilized savage.
You know the idea that certain cultures
brought civilization to other people.
Nobody ever brought
civilization to anybody.
Civilization is the act of
being civil to one another.
When you take somebody else's shit
and then you say, Oh, guess what?
You're going to use our way of
doing things now rather than yours.
You didn't civilize anybody.
You just took them over and you enslave
them in a very polite way sometimes and
sometimes in a not so very polite way.
Cause colonization is too nice of a
word for rape. Genocide and fucking,
yeah.
Is it ever summation of population?
Has anybody ever taken over a country?
Nice. It's always not so nice. I mean the,
the, the horrors that happen
in this country alone when
it's hard to believe that
just a couple of hundred years ago,
all this stuff wasn't here and I need
a couple hundred years ago is nothing.
It's a blink of an eye.
Well that's what we
used to get an argument.
We may have talked to us about this on
the first show when people were like, oh,
you know, the aliens had to help those
people back in the day. And I was like,
Yo dude, if they helped them, you know,
for the over the course of 10,000 years
build a pyramid, then maybe they helped
you because about 200 years ago you were
driving a horse and carriage and now
you've got a rover on Mars, so you got
a little boost to from the aliens buddy.
You know what I mean?
I think that it's just
ridiculous to assume one
culture had communication in one
culture,
couldn't possibly add if they've been
here and they've been here the whole time.
Well, if, if it is possible that we
were ever visited by aliens, who knows?
Maybe it takes a long
fucking time to get here.
Maybe they can only come here once or
twice in a generation. I don't know.
They set up shop here dude,
that if that's the case,
wouldn't there be levels of aliens?
Just like there's levels
of human civilization,
like human civilization goes from having
a horse and buggy to having a car to
having an airplane.
Wouldn't alien civilization go from
there to maybe some of them reach us and
these are like the real ghetto aliens
that are barely getting their shit
together out there in the world.
They're not,
they don't have any fucking alien
comes like, what are you doing?
Very sketchy science. They
fucking blow up. Sometimes.
Those are the guys who crashed at Roswell.
They'll like,
they're more advanced than us,
but there's still kind of fucked up.
And then there's dudes that are so far
advanced than them that they make them
look like cave people.
And these people don't no longer have
bodies and they travel interdimensionally
and they, they exist. That's what,
that's what I think it's like a big too,
like there's no saying like what dimension
they're in. You know what I mean?
Or how our eyes are calibrated, what
we are, what we can or can't see. Well,
I mean I used to be really attracted
to the idea that aliens came and helped
people.
I was very,
very attracted to the idea and I'm still
attracted to it because I think it'd be
insanely fascinating because it really
follows what human beings would do if we,
if we were super advanced and we came
to a planet and we found some primitive
life forms, for sure we would
drop off some of our fucking Jizz.
We would definitely give them
some of our DNA. We're gross.
We thought we could touch this world
in some way. We decided to do that.
He did fuck the Avatar, didn't
he? Yes. Side big blue cat.
Think about what we're talking about doing
the Mars. Is that beastiality hold on.
That's interspecies
beastiality cause they talk.
It's just you're fucking an alien.
No, no, it's not BC. I don't know.
It's interspecies. It's not
beastiality isn't the fuck aliens man.
Shit fucking be.
We're calling her an animal.
We don't know what her final animal,
she talks.
Should we establish that shit back in star
trek when Kirk, fuck that green check.
I remember that. That was it. That's
precedent. It's legal presence.
She didn't have the girl didn't have
a tail. I don't give a fuck dude.
She had like a nose, like a cat.
Dude's hot. You mother fucker.
I fucked that Avatar Bitch. But at
the end of the my respect that, yeah.
By the end of the movie,
I wanted to live.
I wanted to live with
the Navi in the trees.
I wanted to be camping and
shooting arrows and fly.
So it was taking the consensus are
jre that fucking a 10 foot tall cat.
What bitch is not beastiality.
What about the planet of the apes?
When they cut the scene,
they were supposed to read
the market mark version joint.
You're supposed to be a scene where he
was having sex with the eight. No. Yeah.
Do they filmed it and they were
saying, is it BCI? He's like, it it.
Is it wrong
to be interspecies you
know what I'm saying? Yeah,
yeah. Listen, it's okay to fuck hot
aliens. I'm gonna say it right now.
If a hot alien comes to visit
me in the middle of the night,
if I get away with it, I'm
gonna fuck her. I respect that.
I'm not mad at her dad [inaudible] but
what if there he's looked like hers.
Oh, topsy turvy world. Oh Man.
What if the intonation,
everything was perfect, right?
Except that she had a really deep voice.
Like
I fucked a few smokers and my day
really hot chick with a big edge voice.
They're just ready to take you under their
wing. I'll take care of it. She's hot.
I'll deal with it.
I'm totally just never talked to
her on the phone. My thoughts,
thoughts on aliens visiting with
people though that people don't really
understand how long a hundred years is.
We think of like 400 years ago.
It was being like, wow, 400 years ago, you
know, back then they didn't have cameras.
Back then they didn't have automobiles.
Everybody rode horses and then 400 years
before that, in 400 years before that,
you stop and think about what we
were talking about with Egypt.
You're talking about a culture that
existed for thousands of years,
thousands, thousands of years and
the, obviously we're smart as fuck.
They wrote down a lot of shit.
Just what they left behind.
Forget about what was found during the
burning of the library of Alexandria.
I mean they,
when they found that they destroyed all
these like ancient records and all this
information about how they did their,
their construct,
I mean who knows what the fuck was in
there when they burnt all that stuff.
But what these burned several
times. Yeah, but what the, yes,
it was what they left behind though carved
in the stones. It's magnificent shit.
I mean all their high rig lifts
there did the beautiful works of art.
They left behind like the symmetry of
their buildings and the mathematics.
They're construction. It's so obvious.
There were super, super advanced people,
like they were really advanced.
And we just think of that as being like,
well, there's no way aliens must did it.
No, it's real possible that a human race,
a human culture can get super advanced
and fuck it all up and it could be fucked
up by disease and it can be fucked up
by asteroids and it can be fucked up by
other humans invading them,
which would happen to Egypt.
They got invaded by the Nubians
and the Nubians took older.
That's why the older fair though,
than the more recent Pharaoh's all had
black African faces like the Pharaoh in
the face of the Sphinx is
a very distinctly different
face than some of the more
Sephardic pharaohs that you saw,
like in the early days. Right. Yeah.
And the other thing is this,
that Egypt initially begin, um,
as a society that rose from other places,
you know what I mean?
There were other civilizations
that predated it such as Sumeria,
things of that nature. And
when you look at it, yes,
of course they could have easily took
from those civilizations as well. Sure.
We took from other civilizations for sure.
We took from,
from tribes and from other view,
I mean our constitution itself is based
on an air coy confederacy and something
that people don't really realize
or pay attention to that yes,
we didn't just get corn
from indigenous people.
We got this idea that different places
could be under the same federal state,
but still guests what have laws of their
own that are respected by the federal
gov or forceful that,
that they are forced to respect because
this is a different tribes and these
tribes are not going to tolerate you
telling them how to live. However,
we will combine forces for
the survivability of all of
us together as opposed to
individual tribe.
Wasn't that the whole forming of
the constitution as well? I mean,
didn't they get the ideas in the
constitution from studying the, the great,
um,
the great civilizations of the past like
Rome and Greece and all their ideals
about how society should be put together
and use those ideas and a lot of ways
to formulate the constitution?
Well, I mean, Napoleon civil code also
influenced a lot of western societies.
Europe's legal system now,
but I think you know,
when we talk about whether it's aliens
or whether it's anybody that interferes
in, in a human society,
you want to think that,
what would their agenda be?
What do they want?
What could they possibly have to gain
for all of it? Resources, land. I mean,
if you read the Bible that
says that, you know, the, the,
the sons of heaven made it with
the daughters of men. You know,
who's to say that's angels. Maybe
that's, we came down to fuck a woman.
It's absolutely possible
that it did happen.
I know people don't like to hear that
look all great. You believe in aliens.
That's not even what I'm saying.
I'm saying it's absolutely possible
because this fucking thing is so big.
It's so big. The idea that we've
never been visited before is silly.
But if we pay attention to the way we
treat the things on this planet that we
can control and we think about how
the fuck they would deal with us,
we should be probably pretty
happy that it is bullshit.
Because if there are anything like us,
I wouldn't,
I wouldn't put it past them
creating us at a monkeys.
I wouldn't put it past some
super advanced alien species.
Look at some stupid chimps and
go get these dumb mother fuckers.
Let's take some of our shit and put
it into then and then come back in a
thousand years. All my God, they got
planes and buildings and who knows?
It is possible that that happened. It
sounds quite ridiculous. Don't worry.
I know that and I know it sounds it,
but I'm not saying it's impossible.
I'm not saying it's likely.
It's certainly there's,
there is a chance that this
planet has been visited before.
Just the fact that we can
go to Mars with a drone.
We know that we sent these
manned vehicles into space.
We know that their satellites in orbit,
we've used the space shuttle.
We've used rockets there.
There's,
without a doubt a rover that's
moving around on the Mars right now.
If a vis a rover moving around on Mars,
we sent it from this planet.
We're monkeys.
I mean,
we're a couple of hundred years
removed from slavery in this country.
We just came up with the
Internet 20 years ago.
We already have a robot
moving around on Mars.
If there's something else out
there that's a hundred years,
a thousand years more advanced than us,
if they haven't blown themselves up for
sure they would send some shit our way.
If they came here a long,
long ass time ago,
the universe is 13 point
whatever billion years old.
Allegedly earth is only
4.6 billion years old.
I mean that's there's a hell of a long,
it's a long time.
That window that leaves nine fucking
billion plus years that someone else could
have been in a much more
stable solar system,
developed a civilization that's
not based on dominator culture.
Empires figured out of boulder and
that they might've had it completely
psychedelic culture like from the jump
they were eating mushrooms never got out
of it.
They might live in a tropical climate,
like the whole planet might be a
stable tropical climate where they're
consistently engaging in
mushroom use and they,
they developed the ability
to read each other's minds,
it like a fucking thousand years into
their civilization and they'd just been
rocking it freestyle since then.
And here they are 10 billion years
older than you know this planet.
But if we are like a
downgraded version of humans,
then human humans like 4.0 must
be really frightening creatures.
Oh,
it's something that can like look into
your mind and see you control things at
the head and the people who
don't necessarily believe this,
but who won't even subscribe
to the possibility.
These are the same people that think that
laws hold our country together rather
than the iron fist of a
talking monkey. Well, there,
there's what holds this shit hurt me.
I will destroy you if you break these
things that I've written about the NSA
whistleblower. The fucking FBI breaks
into his house. Get on the floor trader.
I heard a word to that
when you were talking. Um,
there's a woman named Dr. Karen Mason.
She has a talking about the
evolution of the species and uh,
she says that there are hurt.
There we is,
that we're all homo erectus
because we walk up. Right.
But there's also different people on
this planet that a call home on noetic is
meaning that they have more than just
the five senses that people have.
So we're not all the same species.
Some people are more devolved
or evolved than others.
So you can't say that though, man. People
will accuse your racism, but no, no,
no, no. Don't say that. You can't say that
there's some people are just dumber. No,
no. Different species of
people. Meaning that you could,
you know how sometimes you could just
think of a friend and they'll call you?
Well, how about this just don't,
there's no term too. It's not,
it's not so much dependent on the ideas
of compartmentalizing people in the way
we do in terms of race
or in terms of religion.
It wouldn't be like to say that one
person of this color or this is not even
holler creed would have been smarter.
It would have been a specific
individual that's born within that line.
Either. It could be here in
America, it could be in Mexico,
it could be in Nigeria
or Scandinavia somewhere,
but for example,
there are types of intelligences that
we really do appreciate in this country.
We look at science and math and we
say, oh man, you're really smart.
You know you're going to
be a fucking engineer. But people
don't appreciate social intelligence,
emotional intelligence.
You know?
Imagine somebody that's able to come
into a room and they look at you and they
like, you know what, Joe? Joe Walks
different today. That means he sad.
You know what I mean? Or you know, he,
he's worried about something. Or you know,
when he's,
when he's checks his phone a lot,
he only key only interrupts the podcast
to speak to his chalk child or something.
So something must be wrong at home.
People who pick up on those things, right?
It's, it's, it's incredibly, it's not like
female intuition, that sexist bullshit.
It's the idea that people in
general, male, female, whatever,
some of them are just more in touch with
the idea of giving a fuck about how the
people around them exist and
therefore they're just a more,
I wouldn't say a more
considerate human being,
but they have more emotional and to
pay more attention to developing that
musical intelligence. For example,
people could say, all right,
I hear a note that's a g sharp.
Now I'm going to create a whole song
around it and it's already finished in my
head. That's a musical
genius. Physical intelligence.
People who say, you know you,
you MMA shit, God damn it.
That's physical intelligence.
Anyone who's got a fight in the ring in
and calibrate and exact punch or know
how to move somebody or to to to
step them in this direction other,
that's an incredible physical genius that
they have to possess in order to carry
on something like that and not kid
knocked the fuck out by someone's swing on
you as hard as they possibly can,
but only certain intelligences are valued
in this country and in the world in
terms of human society as opposed to
delving into what they would really be if
we took them each at not just face value,
but what they represent for our
human culture. You know some,
I know that's why some people fuck with
animals more than they fuck with people.
I know people that they're
like, oh, I love my dog.
Why can't you love a
dog more than a person?
Sometimes a dog is more human
being than a human. You know,
you got a homeless person in
the street who's crying you.
Most people will walk right by him.
You put your dog next to a homeless
person was fucking and tears. Somehow.
I've seen it. My dog that doesn't like
nobody will go over there like, hey man,
like kind of look at you like sad. Like
why are you sad? Why are you hurting?
Who the fuck would do that? As a normal
person, we're trained to ignore that.
Whereas something like a dog is
trained to say, hey man, no, someone,
someone's in pain that's not right.
As if to say,
I wish I could help you if I wasn't
trapped in this fucking body.
You know what happens when people start
really paying attention to a lot of
homeless people and hanging out with them?
You realize the fucking crazy and if you
bring those mother fuckers in your life,
your life is going to be chaos.
Can we take that crazy crying lady
underneath the bridge and say, come on,
come on on my house, Doug. Stan help
used to do that. You know what happened?
They got in a knife fight and
it's fucking driveway. Uh,
the woman's stabbed her boyfriend.
Yeah. Doug, you still let him,
he had a front lawn. He lived in. Nobody's
saying you got to breastfeed them.
I'm just saying that you're saying,
I know what you're saying.
It's a very romanticized ideal that the
reality is we want to go out there and
fucking bring homeless people
in your life every day.
You only got 24 hours in a fucking
[inaudible] up with it all.
Shit be screaming and crying.
No, no soap. Look, hey,
you're on fucking shit together or
you're crazy. It's one of those two,
and if you,
if you crazy,
that's the real issue that when the
Reagan administration was here, they,
they changed the laws.
They changed the,
the standards as far as like taking people
that you had to take care of and they
let a lot of people out of
mental hospitals that were,
they were infirmed for life and they got
him out and then these people were just
like, free. You're free. You're on your
own. If you could take care of yourself,
but then again,
when we think about it,
then let's take that then and then let's
not make it romanticized. Idealized.
If these people are sick,
if they have a disease,
then shouldn't they be taken care of?
Shouldn't they be right? No question,
no question.
If someone had fucking pneumonia and
they were lying on the fucking highway,
some, uh, you called the
ambulance, they would come get
him. Somebody sitting there,
there are schizophrenia,
you know what I mean?
Or they have multiple personality
disorder. They're more liable to, to,
to hurt themselves and they're their
danger to themselves and to other people.
Those people need to be taken care
of. For example, I look at that,
the way I look at drug addiction.
Those people don't belong in
prison for 40 or 50 years.
They obviously need treatment.
They need to be fixed,
but we only give a fuck when it's a
Phillip Seymour Hoffman that that dies.
And then when a, where are the rest
of their heroin addicts? You know,
I went off on Twitter the other day
because I was like, Yo Dude, you know,
the NYP ds investigating
who sold them the hot dose.
Really,
you know,
I know lots of people I've known through
my life that either almost died or died
of a damn heroin overdose or some kind
of drug overdose and the NYP d didn't go
meticulously looking
for the specific dealer.
You want to know where the
heroin is coming from, homie?
I told them you can go first stop.
You need to do is Afghanistan.
That's where it's coming from.
And the poppy fields are being protected
by our troops because the war lords
that we want to stay in power that are
willing to give us access are the ones
that need the money. So we allowed
them to grow the poppy and we disallow.
The Taliban supported it too.
But listen, don't bring any homeless
people in your house. Trust me.
I know he's saying that all make sense?
But you got to trust.
Had a background in comedy. Don't
watch it. Come in your house.
They don't even know what toilet paper is.
Dude,
fix everybody that's
close to Valentine's Day.
I know he can't be captain.
Save a hoe. You can't.
You can't be that guy. I'll tear. We're
trying to fix the world. Nice to that.
God did a problem is the really fucking
crazy people. You're not going to fix.
You could,
you could work all day everyday for the
rest of your life and you wouldn't put a
dent in that shit.
And I think that they have to
someone hallmark of our society.
It's a question.
Do you think those people started that
way or do you think it was the things
that happened to them within the
course of their life more often?
That makes sense.
You would be crazy to assume
either or. You're, you know,
no one has any idea what the background
of a lot of those people are other than
the people that have
treated them in the past,
they probably don't even know
what the fuck happened to them.
There's a lot of really sick people out
there that just happened to be homeless
people because we can't,
we can't them as insane enough
to institutionalize. Not,
not then to be crazy
enough to try to define it,
but wouldn't you think that the majority
of these cases of people who had
extreme trauma of some sort as a child?
I would imagine. Yeah, I would imagine.
Well, you know, abuse people, people
that have been homeless, I've met,
I knew quite a few people that were
homeless at the stages of their life from
the time when I used to
hang out in pool halls,
one of my best friends was homeless
for a long period of time when I was a
struggling comedian.
My friend Johnny was a pool hustler or
legit hundred percent pool house and it a
drug addict. But the pool
hustler thing is how he got by.
He was extraordinary pool player and
he would pretend to sock and he would,
he would go to places and he was a fast
talker and he was a slick dude and he
got a big thrill out of tricking guys
into playing him. And then you know,
he would like lose a little then complain
and then they would start talking shit
and calling them fat
and all this different.
And then it would slowly start playing
better and they like make it real
emotional with the guy and like he would
get thousands of dollars at a people
and a lot of it was psychological.
He just knew how to play people.
He had emotion tells
motional intelligence,
social intelligence and emotional
intelligence. He had both,
but he was homeless a
good portion of the time.
Like sometimes he would
come stay at my house.
This motherfucker hadn't slept in days
except under pool tables and he would
just conk out.
Like he got shot with a tranquilizer dart
and just sleep for like he slept in my
house for two solid days.
Straight ones because he was just burning
it best leave of his life probably.
Yeah man. The dude, the poor dude
was just out there and you know,
and he had issues himself.
He had a,
a lot of mental health issues himself
and I think that there's a lot of people
out there that are homeless
that have mental health,
which I think that's the
majority of a lot of the cases.
I think a lot of the homeless people
that have mental health issues,
and what's sad is that,
you know,
especially when you find people who
are supposed to be cared for by this
government.
And it goes back to what we were
talking about before and the imagine the
veterans that are homeless out there who
are paid dues and risk their lives to
this country and they are
completely looked over.
And you would think the people who say
that they love America so much wouldn't
be the ones that are bleeding it dry.
But ironically it's the people that are
criticizing this country for the things
it does wrong that love it the most.
Why?
Because we want to fix the things that
are wrong as opposed to people that say,
Hey, we just love America. And anything
you say against America is wrong. No,
that's not the case.
Because the people who usually say that
are the ones that are bleeding this
country dry by saying, Oh
man, I love America. You know,
I want to destroy unions.
Unions are destroying them. You know what?
I want to stop workers from doing this.
Dude, you're not doing it because you
love America. You love money. You know,
if you really loved America, how come
you've got a God damn plant overseas?
You know you could be
not making 10 billion.
You could be making 7 million a year,
but you would be feeding
10 times more people.
You know here in America
they would never do that.
Of course you billion is a big number.
I don't know what kind of
country you live in and stuff,
but that's what I'm talking about. Taxes.
My 3 billion pays for social programs.
Clean the streets.
Who Do you want to build these bridges?
That extra 3 billion is important,
right?
The only that they're not going
to pay it in taxes either.
It's not like it's when they go
to anything and that's right.
They weasel that shit. Yeah. I mean
come on. The NFL is like a charity
funnies things of all times. The NFL
is tax free. Is it team by team though?
Did I talk to the dude? The whole
thing is a charity organization. Please
get the fuck
in the world.
The UFC needs to get on that.
I don't know what the Fuck Dana White's
waiting for. We need to be tax free.
We need to irrigate the UFC.
Charity.
Charity should be a charity.
That's what I'm saying.
Crazy shit. You imagine the
UFC tried to become tax free.
You know who else was
like, oh my God, the NHL,
they're tax free to get the fuck
up and HR. That is hilarious. Mba.
That is. No, but I think they get that
they got to pay too many black people.
They got to play it. They're not happy
with this. 99% black people got dammit.
Make them pay taxes. I mean he's baseball.
They gotta pay to too many Latino,
too many Latinos.
These mother fuckers coming over here
throwing heat coming up. Money, bitch,
give me,
yeah,
taxes man.
The people that don't have it have
to pay taxes. It's a real God
damn mind blower. It's like,
well how does that get determined and
like religions that make money like
religions,
like say Scientology.
Scientology is a tax people
organization and tax free organization.
That was written by a science
fiction writer who l Ron Hubbard,
who publicly stated that the best way
to make a lot of money is to start your
own religion. And he got tax free. That
guy got tax rate. You know what's funny?
When I got out of prison,
I went to try and find a job and all these
places and everyone said no to me and
there was this one ad that was like,
come learn the secret to life
and get paid while doing it.
And it was like a $12 an hour job and
like 1999 when I just made parole and they
were advertising like, please come to
this area, you know you can learn. And,
and I walked in and it was a Scientology
center course and I walked in.
Lady was Super Nice. They're all
the most polite, no, no, no, no.
They just wanted to fucking sign.
They literally just brought me in.
They shoved me in front of a screen with
like four or five other people and they
played me like a Scientology video and
then they will, they, they asked us,
they were like, did you all understand
the truth in this video? And I was,
I was sitting, I was just like,
Yo, I really want it to be like,
what the fuck is wrong with you?
Like no one believes this shit.
But at the same time I sat
back and I said, you know what,
I really don't understand this religion
enough for me to make a commitment about
it right now. And they were
very polite to me. They're like,
thank you very much for your
time, sir. Take care of,
and it was somebody else in there
who really needed that job and
they just looked at me and
they would, they gave him
this kind of look like, cool,
cool. You're out in the running anymore.
And there were like, I was touched.
I had to swear to God,
Yo,
I could see the charlatan and the snake
oil coming out of the side of the jacket.
Dude. They were like, I was touched by
this video. Like I really thought it was.
I mean the dude, they're there
to get a job. Yeah. That was it.
Joe. You, I looked at it. You might be
right about this racist shit, by the way,
because the only other ones that don't
have to pay taxes, the golf league,
the PGA and the NHL
[inaudible]
all the owners that own a
fellow daddy's fucking creep.
The NBA should be pissed.
Yeah.
Doug Golf guys don't have to pay
tax like the most money. Right? Wow.
That's dark. That's dark racism.
Wow.
I think it's racism,
crying racism for the NBA and I
don't even watch basketball. Yeah.
The idea that you could get away with the
Scientology thing, that that could be,
we need to start her own fucking religion.
God dammit.
That's how you're really good.
That's how you're really locked down.
That's the quote right there.
When you're starting a
religion, God dammit. Well,
they have so much money that
they can get away with it.
Like Scientology is a number
to land owner in Los Angeles.
They own more buildings and
property and real estate.
In Los Angeles then like almost anybody.
The freakiest thing is,
you know how they rope off
everything at a time square when, uh,
when the ball is going to drop or whatever
and there's a certain time you can't
go past the barricades. One night
I was there and the guy said, well,
you remember the Church of
Scientology? And I said, yeah,
and he let me in through the back
through the barricade. Real Story. Dude.
Real Story.
He probably just wanted to fuck you.
[inaudible] handsome guy.
[inaudible]
came right out of just press a button.
Whoa.
You got to keep the ball moving.
What is the, wow, what are you supposed
to say? Amazing. He probably loved you,
dude. Scientologists try and make
friends. He was a police officer too.
That's hilarious. Well, they met.
It might have some sort of a deal.
Maybe they pay off the cops get,
get through the line.
I think that's the now brochures.
That's the only way you
really do get anything done.
I think a lot for a lot of
companies and corporations.
They just pay off whoever it
is that's in charge. Well,
the only reason why people aren't
investigating Scientology in this country,
but yet they are in other countries.
It's got to be just how
much money they have.
That's the one thing that makes sense.
Because if it was a new group that came
out of nowhere and they hadn't had all
this history owning all these buildings
and you found out like that they had
developed this religion based on the
scientific or a science fiction authors
writings and you would read it and go,
wait a minute, what the fuck?
What did these he meters,
you hold onto these these aluminum
cans and they tell me your personality.
Get the fuck Outta here. That's
not real. They would be shut down.
You would think that they
would be run out of town. Well,
I mean someone else could tell you, hey,
this cracker is really the flesh of,
you know, a Hebrew Zombie. You know?
I mean someone could put it in that
way and you would feel ridiculous.
As long as it's old, we're cool
with it. No, but that's what I mean.
As long as it's through a
certain period of time. Look,
I have a great respect for people who
I've seen use religion to make them a
better person. Well, when I see someone
become more pretentious, more judgmental,
more like I have all the answers and
unless you believe in exactly what I
believe,
then you're going to go to damnation.
That's when I see religion as like a
destructive thing that ends up ruining
people's lives. But when I see
people that honestly just take it,
and I think that's the thing with a lot,
with a lot of religions,
as long as the Kennan can be as
ridiculous as it's going to be, you know,
people will believe preposterous things.
All of the mask you to believe
something preposterous. You know the,
the ocean is divided, you know,
of Muhammad ascended into heaven,
you know what I mean? Or, or you know,
Jesus Christ was born of a virgin
and then died and came back to life.
And yet when you look at people's lives,
you know,
some people's lives are preposterous. You
know, there was a, there was a family,
my friend was staying and doing a photo
project down in Brazil and he was down
there and he was like, you know, there's
a whole there, two holes in the floor.
One hole is in the bathroom where everyone
goes to the bathroom and the other
hole is like literally right next door.
And they put like a,
like a bucket down there to catch shrimp.
And I'm like, wait a minute, wait.
So where is it like in a different
river or something like nine,
it's the same water. And I'm like,
really? Like yeah definitely.
It's the same exact water.
And he's like,
you have to understand that's the only
way they're going to eat anything that
day is to fish for shrimp
in that shit water.
And that's preposterous to me for you and
I to look at that and be like, Oh man,
you know who in this room would imagine,
you know,
I'm gonna put my hand in the toilet
to pick up my dinner tomorrow.
But that is the absolute reality that
people who are living in those types of
dire conditions, cause if they don't eat
that they're not going to fucking eat.
That's why I'm honestly not offended if
somebody, you know, steal someone. Oh,
I'm in some third world country. I mean,
not that I liked that shit, but yo,
you're taking something because you're
going to die if you don't sell it to eat.
And motherfuckers just stealing,
you know,
Reebok pumps cause they want to look
fucking cool. Like soccer. My Nigga,
the only person I know that's ever
actually started a religions, Alex Grey,
Alex Gray is the visionary artist.
I don't know if you've ever seen his work,
but everything he does is the
psychedelic portraits. They're,
they're like these really intense,
like a multicolored.
They look like dimethyltryptamine trips.
It's all like, uh, like Iowasca trips
or mushroom trips and all of his art.
This is the stuff coming out of people.
Yeah.
This is all of his stuff.
Well, he's, he's created his,
not only is he created his own religion,
but he got tax free status
and his city is trying to, uh,
to fight it. They still want
them to pay taxes. I think,
I don't know if he ever worked that out,
but he's actually trying to do it in a,
in a really like positive,
healthy way.
He's not trying to make money off people
are own people or give you a bunch of
rules that you have to follow.
He's just essentially,
he's a guy who really believes that
psychedelics are a connection to the true
God of the universe, love and
God and, and you know, the,
the energy that exists
when you have these, uh,
these powerful transformative
psychedelic experiences. So he, um,
he's building this thing
in upstate New York.
He came on and showed me
and Brian, his, uh, his, uh,
communities putting together up there,
but he's got this huge building that he's
making that he came on our podcast and
did a Kickstarter for it and raise the
money like in no time. It was amazing.
The people from this podcast fucking
represented, like in as positive,
a strong way as was humanly possible.
And a whole bunch of people
supported this and uh,
he got all his funding and he's
building this incredible building.
Look at this thing. Look it up. Tech.
It's on the other one behind in front
of you too. That this is going to be,
this is going to his church. Yeah.
It's all based on his artwork and uh,
it's like probably going to be one of the
most beautiful buildings in the world.
And where is he going to build this? And
upstate New York. He has like, uh, he has,
yeah,
he has like a temple and I'm still going
on something like a jungle in Columbia
or some shit. You know what I'm telling
you, the top of a mountain I met,
I've met the dude several
times and he is the real deal.
He really is a beautiful person.
He's all full of love.
The guy's like so loving and happy and
friendly. He's not evil in any way,
shape or form.
And he just wants to promote those,
those ideas and promote art. And,
and, and promote love. I mean,
you couldn't ask for a better guy
trying to create his own religion,
but what he's trying to do is you just
influence people in a very positive way.
She, Noah, Joe, it's usually never the guy
who creates it. All, right? Always things.
Heritage is always, it's always
the inheritance. That's so true.
Ever the fuck takes this shit over.
It's going to be like, listen, you know,
in order for you to really get the
psychedelic experience [inaudible] shit.
You know what I mean? Let me father
children with everyone's wife here.
It just, they all do that, right?
Eventually it was too hard
to hot girls walking around.
They love you so much because you're
the Messiah Tam on it hit this fucking
husband and hers.
It's just fucking up my flow.
Yeah, well that's just human nature, man.
I mean that's obviously the issue with
priest telling them they can't have sex.
You know, you'd create monsters. He
create monsters. When you suppress,
there's no way around it. If
you, if you suppress energy,
finds a way he threw in another way.
I really wouldn't do some in depth
research on when that started happening.
Cause nearly Orthodox
Church people who were um,
officials of the church
were allowed to have wives.
They were allowed to have a dispensation.
They were not to get married.
They got married by the pope.
I mean the Pope had children.
I mean I think at some point people looked
at it and probably in the Middle Ages
where people got real pious and you
know, when you examine the, the, the,
the changing of Christianity,
you find specific points where it becomes,
you know,
from that time where people are completely
nonviolent to becoming structured,
to be a violent society. You know,
people say, oh well who, who,
whose writings of those,
I always said it was Saint Augustine
and then it makes sense cause he dies in
the siege of hippo. Regis. During
that particular time, you know,
the eastern Roman empire was trying to
eradicate something called area aneurysm,
which is the idea that the father is
superior to the son. In other words,
the father created the sun and therefore
the sun was inferior to the father as
he was a creation.
The the people of the church hated this
idea and so they overthrew all of the
Germanic kingdoms that inherited the
western Roman Empire in order to to to
impose their idea of what Christianity
would be, which if you think about it,
would make that the first crusade ever.
In terms of Christianity Celibacy,
there's,
this is where it starts out celibacy.
The first mandate requiring priest to be
sell of it came in three o four a d so
the year three Oh four Canon
33 of the council of Elvira,
that is some Harry Potter Shit stated
that all bishops press putters and deacons
and all other clerics were to abstain
completely from their wives and not to
have children.
Wow.
A short time later and three 26 the
council of Nicea convened by Constantine
rejected a ban of priests marrying
requested by Spanish clerics.
Wow.
This is fantastic.
So they just decided they
were saying too much dick.
That's the only way around it.
That's exactly what was going on.
Does know they had too much power.
There was no rock stars back then.
You had poets, and by the way, when
you're dealing with 3000 and you know,
I mean 304 rather,
there was no one was reading the Bible.
They didn't figure out how to
read the Bible until, till uh,
till Martin Luther came along and
translated it into a phonetic language.
That was when most people come try to,
when do they chore was Latin.
The first time it was translated into gym,
Germanic egg
was, I believe in the fourth century
by a priest called will fill up.
And when I look at the actual
extension of where it is,
a lot of people were really
illiterate in the first place.
And the way that they learn to read,
I'm in Greece and in Rome was actually
by reading the Bible and reading the
actual scripture and saying,
oh,
it would be the way someone would read
a kid's book these days only you're not
reading a Kid's book.
You're reading what you're going to be
indoctrinated into for the rest of your
entire life. In other words.
That's the first book.
In the last book you're gonna read,
probably if you are sitting in there
and you're a peasant in the middle of
nowhere in the Middle Ages,
it says that Germanic
language translations of the
Bible have existed since the
Middle Ages,
and the most influential is Luther's
translation and that the Martin Luther
translations, I believe that was in
the 15 hundreds or something like that.
There's a great hardcore history podcast
on that called the something Thor.
Thor Thor's find it, find the
name of that. I forget what it is,
but it's all about Martin
Luther translated the Bible
into a phonetic language.
Yeah,
they couldn't read it.
So back then when a priest was
the only direct connection to God,
he was the only guy that was able
to tell you the word of God. He was,
here it is angels.
Here it is.
The gothic Bible or the will fill a bible.
Christian Bible as translated by the ref
will fill it in the fourth century into
the gothic language spoken by the eastern
Germanic peoples or the gothic tribes,
meaning the inheritors of the
Roman state as Rome fell in a four,
10. And then of course I think
in four 55 and then finally,
um,
what was the last four 76?
And back then the Germans were
totally different. Like the, the,
the whole country of Germany.
There was so many barbarians.
There's big fucking powerful,
scary. But this, this is,
this is the interesting point.
What makes them a barbarian
that they weren't with Rome,
if anything wasn't roam the most
barbaric out of all of them? Well,
I mean when I say barbarian,
I mean like Conan the barbarian.
We use a big giant to the fuckers
who ate meat and drink milk.
That was like primary staples of their
dying and any massive amount of protein,
but the protein content of their diet.
It's why they were so big.
They were enormous people.
I don't think they did a whole lot of
farming cause it's cold as shit up there.
So they're there, they're
eating, you know, a lot of
animal protein. And they were,
apparently,
they were enormous in comparison to a
lot of the people that would encounter
them. Like that was like the first
depictions from China, I believe,
of encountering German people.
They were like, Holy Shit,
are these fucking people big?
You know,
they were just enormous savage
people, you know? Well, I mean,
I dunno.
I'm sure that there were some sort of
human sacrifice here and there. Oh fuck.
Yeah. The thing is that everybody
did that. That shit was standard.
When you look at their, their tribal
societies though, I really would like to,
to sit down and examine what the,
the,
the process was for them in,
in their societies as opposed to when they
were romanized, you know, because that,
that people living in, in like some
mud hut in the middle of Germany,
I'm sure they had some different
idea of controlling themselves and,
and to,
in
similar to the way native American
people don't, didn't ever had a prison.
You know what I mean? Where the fuck did
you put the people that did bad things?
Will, you just have to fix
them or put them on sticks.
Somebody had to be fixed the islands
off. Someone had to be fixed. Yeah.
Or Kill Them. I think they'd probably
killed a lot of people too. Well,
that's the thing. I mean,
it depends on what he wants.
Society, you want to imagine.
I mean, I remember I watched the movie
300 right? And it was like, Oh man,
they seem, they make these Persians
seem like the wicked his people,
but when you look at it,
what were the Greeks still and
they were practicing infanticide.
It was still a monarchy. Sparta's
still had slaves like a motherfucker.
I give him the movie 300 a lot of
creative freedom because it was based on a
graphic novel and it's obviously got a
lot of, they're doing uncle [inaudible].
I know I don't have I Lao goes
through that movie. I loved it.
But to me it's a comic book.
Right?
The real problem with making a movie
about Spartans is you're going to have to
have a bunch of dudes fucking each
other. Okay. If you're gonna do it right,
you want to do it right.
You got to do a historically accurate,
which is why when Martin, when he was
like, oh dude, those Athenian boy lovers,
and I was like, wait a minute dude, exam
from Sparta dudes here in the gymnasium,
which means like naked in Greek
or something. It's off course.
There was a lot of man fucking
going on, but it was normal. I mean,
I'm not saying that they should
do it because it would, you know,
somehow or another discredit them,
but it is historical fact that the people
that live back then engaged in much
more homosexual activities.
Then we think of today that particular
area and that particular the Greeks and
the Romans and the Spartans
and all this fucking savages,
they were banging each other. They
always were and it was a part of life.
It was a normal thing. And men having
boys for lovers and like that was like,
I mean how many philosophers had said,
hey, that's not real. It's not spartan.
That's your boyfriend.
Fucking some veterans who come down and
put some gay guy up. Don't do it again.
That's, it's not, not,
it's not, you know, I mean,
how is that what you're talking
about murderers and, and,
and warmongers you're talking about
people that constantly engaged in the
slaughter of people.
Like why would it somehow or another
discredit them if they had gay sex?
Like who gives a shit? But it is the
reality. The reality is like this,
this picture of, it's a real depiction of
a, a real gladiator in a real young boy.
And cause that shit was like super calm.
Some people thought in that particular
age that the only true love that could
exist was between a man and a young boy.
That's unfortunately dow that
society chose to. I mean,
you know that in other words has been
used in a lot of times I've seen to taint
the uh, the arguments that are made
for, for, for gay rights and people say,
oh well now they're going to want
children that had absolutely nothing to do
with that.
That's a different complete era of time
in which people didn't have adult hood
defined the way we do now. And I think
that's the problem that that engages,
and I'm not being an apologist or
excusing it, it's just that when,
let's say this, the 1200 you
know, you become an adult,
not when you're 18 years old.
You know,
most people die when they were like 30
so if you're 18 you're damn near like the
equivalent of like a
being a middle aged man.
But if you think about it during
that particular very sparse,
hey, that's not where
he's supposed to put that.
What hasn't we put down your rock
real quick? This is called back mount.
Obviously I'm, one of them is
muscular and the other one is not.
Oh Brokeback Greek closing
on the guy on the bottom.
Even back then they had tops and bottoms
because it's like one dude who just
clearly is the one who's going
to get fucked every time.
And the other dude is going
to do all the fucking,
so you look at the guy on the bottom,
he's all smooth and shit.
It doesn't look that he does is sit ups,
doesn't do is squash the guy on top.
It's very ripped. I think the guy
in the bottle is kind of dough
that's tired, easy. The guy in
the bottom needs a lot of naps.
Yo.
But you couldn't have a movie like that
if you had a movie like that where you
showed the true lives, the spark wasn't
able to grow with it, right? Yeah.
But did they have a lot of gay sex
in that movie? No, not try Alexander.
I mean I was gay because Collin
Farrell was it. It was the,
the lead him and whatever
the other dude was in there.
And so let me ask you something.
In the MMA where like you have your balls
and someone else's face and they're on
the ground. Are you allowed to talk shit?
Are you allowed to talk shit like that?
Absolutely. Jake, when
you're on the floor,
if you want to fuck with the guy's head,
you could definitely do that.
As long as they do a lot of that
shit. Oh yeah. There's some dudes,
Nick Diaz talks mad shit during every one
of his fights. Everyone has his fights.
You standing in front of people
going, what? Bitch? What? Beck? Boom.
And then it pops you.
I'm fucking you up bitch.
Like he'll talk shit to you while he's,
no,
I don't mean that white frat boy
swag shit that they put before.
I just mean like Mexican first one.
But I'm just saying,
I know I picked that up on it. He has
came out. I'm just saying, you know,
that's just what I hear. Oh, what's up
bitch? Screw this right now. Like, Oh,
you know that men of costing in. That's
the way I see all the time with schools.
When I, when I used to wipe out
my, my thing is this though,
this is like an officer. We're talking
about an MMA fight we're talking about.
Right. But I mean in terms of,
in terms of the sexual portion,
I'm sure guys do. I'm sure
guys, fuck with guys. Look,
if someone's gonna fuck with you
and try to get inside your head,
they're going to try to do it by any
means necessary. There's no limit on that.
It like for example,
other sports,
they have a limit to what they can
say and then they're like, oh no,
this is like too,
didn't they get in trouble on some shit
in the NBA when they were talking about
somebody else's wife or you're
only allowed to say certain things.
You're talking about somebody
else's kids ear. Like for example,
in certain soccer leagues,
you're not allowed to mention somebody
who's family or talk about racism like
when you were in a scrum. I know the
football players are notorious for that.
Saying the darkest,
most evil shit to someone on another team.
I'm going to rape your babies. I'm like,
dude, you got to be a beautiful kid.
I'm going to fuck his face right
after I pound you into the ground.
Like dudes is without a
doubt said Shit like that.
It's psychological war man.
He does know cool,
but there's no,
but similar to some of the way some sports
regulated. Should it be regulated, Joe?
No, no. It's free speech.
Anything that you say it took your
house is on fire right now. Well,
that's different. First of all, you're
saying in the middle of a fight,
you can't. Yeah. You should be
able to say, your house is on fire.
How the fuck would you mom?
No, my house. Right. Or,
you know what could your dick out of my
face? Stop Talking Shit about my house.
What is this? Why don't you pull it
down so we could read it? I said,
this is a New York Knicks.
Camilio Anthony Carmelo is strange
from wife l law of whatever.
What is it about,
what is it about putting this up?
He pretty much said a comment
like when he was playing, I,
your wife tastes like honey nut cheerios
and then getting in trouble for that.
You know, it's funny.
Melo was, let's be honest,
pretty mellow was waiting
for him apparently. Um,
like uh, where they go to the
walk to the bus, like right there.
He was supposedly waiting for him. Oh
look, he's going to kick his ass. I mean,
again, they were both on the same
team together as different teams,
different things. Well, you know,
that's a choice he's going
to have to make on his own.
Yeah. Listen, I need that chair.
It's interesting to talk shit.
It's part of it look
like that.
You're clearly an asshole.
You clearly a piece of shit as a human
being and if you willing to be a piece of
shit as a human being just for, you know,
just to win, you can win without that.
You went without that and be healthier.
You know, especially fighting,
you know the odds of you really getting
inside a dude's head and causing them to
do somethings, going to make them lose
the fight. They're fucking professionals,
man. Those are the dudes who are really
good. Stop Brian. Stop putting shit up.
Distracting. But isn't it the dudes
that are winning, man, there's,
there's fucking Samurais.
They know what the fuck they're doing it.
But wouldn't the professionals know what
to say to get into someone's
head? No, no, no, no, no, no.
Isn't that a part of warfare? No, it's
a lot of guys are not good at all.
Like mystery writers ever. Misdirection
distraction. Yeah, of course.
You have the silent warrior now you're,
yeah. You're the one who's romanticizing.
No, no, no. Here.
Who will just sit there praying and some
Buddhist temple until he gets up like
Ken and Raju and goes and beats the shit
out of his opponent and then fly back
to Thailand so they can send them to that,
that fake statue and fights
the got later. No, I mean dude,
he's going to say some
fucked up shit in your ear.
No, you're wrong. This is
why you're wrong. Okay.
The greatest fighters almost
always are martial artists,
like real martial artists.
The guys like George Saint Pierre and
the guy's like Leo Machida, these guys,
they're not shit talkers ever at all.
They followed by the true martial arts
principles and it's one of the reasons
why they're so good.
They don't carry the burden of Shit.
Talking what a guy like Chael Sonnen
talking mad shit before a fight. Look,
Shayle Kann obviously back it up.
He's obviously a very good fighter,
but make no mistake about it.
There's a tremendous on him because of
that shit talking on top of the fact that
he's got to fight. That is an extra
opponent that you have inside the octagon,
knowing that if you lose my God,
you're going to look like a fucking idiot.
That shit is real and it's an enemy.
And it is also enforcing the ego,
which is,
it has to be left out as much as possible
in any situation where you're dealing
with extreme pressure because
it shows character, cracks,
cracks. But then what about, what
about a guy like Muhammad Ali?
Muhammad Ali was a brilliant,
a brilliant boxer,
and he was a brilliant sportsman and he
figured out how to get inside a lot of
people's heads and defeat them,
but he would have been able to do
that just by boxing them. Look,
it was beautiful what he did because
it was entertaining for all of us.
And by doing that, he also called a
tremendous amount of attention to himself.
But you know what I think he
did was a form of extreme.
The extreme braggadocious nature of the
way he would talk was so obvious that it
was almost like theater. Like
Howard Cosell said to him,
champions seem truculent.
He goes, whatever. Does
it mean if it's good,
I'm that like just that somebody in
somebody's ear saying whatever you want to
say to him.
You know,
and if you want you s you see him doing
that at that particular time. Sure is.
People wouldn't think he's wrong for that,
but someone would think that someone
who's talking shit on a football field
saying reckless things about someone
else's family, they're row. Oh well wait,
first of all, people definitely thought
he was wrong for that. I'm not saying,
do you think he's wrong for that? No, I
don't think anybody's wrong for anything.
I told you I think you should be able
to talk mad shit on the football.
But you said that people who do that
are a Douche bag cause he comes back.
Oh yeah. He was definitely
a Douche bag of Joe Frazier.
He was 100% of Douche bag of Joe Frazier.
He used to bring a gorilla,
a rubber gorilla during the time
of the fifties and sixties rather,
w where you're, you're dealing
with this. When they grew up,
Ali and Frazier grew up during the
worst racial time in all of history and
Muhammad Ali in this,
the history of this country,
60 was probably worse than that.
It's pretty bad. But I mean,
as far as like the turn of the times,
they're dealing with Martin Luther
King, The d, The all the race riots.
And then you're also dealing with
a new medium, which is television,
and you're dealing with this face
that is not only is this guy a,
an incredibly controversial figure,
but this guy was also a black African
American who doesn't want to fight in
Vietnam War,
and he's holding up a gorilla and he's
calling Joe Frazier, an uncle Tom,
and he's hitting this gorilla doll
saying that he's a big ugly gorilla.
Joe Frazier, and he's setting Joe
Frazier up to be like this, this,
this uncle Tom with the white man
champion. That doesn't question anything.
Well, he's, I mean, he savaged that guy's
reputation to destroyed that guy's mind.
He hate Joe Frazier hated him forever
and they could have just fought.
They could have just fought, you know,
they could have just did. He could've,
he could've left all that
racist shit out of there.
It could have left all that uncle
Tom Shit. Either he chose to do that.
Was he a douchebag? Look, man, I'm just
an observer watching a guy live his life.
But he was definitely a Douche bag of
Joe Frazier and Joe Frazier was pretty
open about it.
He hated that motherfucker for a long
time because of that shit used to make fun
of him even when he had like Parkinson's
and all the other shit about that.
Oh yeah, yeah. Joe Frazier, he taunted
Muhammad Ali's shaking and all that stuff.
I mean he, he was, he was upset
for a long ass fucking time and he,
when he knocked Muhammad Ali Down with
that left Hook and won that fight,
that first fight,
make no mistake about,
a lot of people were fucking
happy than Muhammad Ali.
The draft dodging black man who talks
all that shit got beat and lost his title
to the guy who's like a
good family man who, who,
you know goes to church allegedly a,
he's a fighter. He's a fucking who,
they're all crazy, every, every
fight. It's crazy. You know,
you're fucking throwing bones
at a man for a living, you know,
it's a nutty way to get by.
But he was the preferable one cause he
was much more humble and wasn't this guy,
you know, well shook up the
world. He wasn't that guy. He was,
he was a different guy. It
was just a tough guy from
the streets of Philadelphia.
So it totally different situation.
But people definitely hated,
I'll leave because of his talking shit.
They always hate guys who are confident.
There's always going to be people that
want a chip you down when you have that
con gone. Flint is Anderson
Silva coming back. Who knows man,
or it's a hard injury to come back
from you. Tell me, is he going well,
I don't know. Any prediction
you, you know, I wouldn't
have no idea. First of all,
I'm not a doctor. Second of all, I
don't know what's going on in his head.
You know,
you get the psychology of a guy who loses
twice in devastating fashion like that
once by catastrophic injury in a
fight. The weeds, quite honestly,
losing your boss the
first round and a pretty,
he was losing that fight in a big way
that first round and that guy was gaining
on him. That guy's scary guy,
that Chris Weidman, he's just,
he's a fucking beast and
he beat Anderson twice.
I saw some videos of him fighting other
people. He's a monster. He's a monster.
He's,
he's a really tough wrestler who grew up
getting his ass kicked by his brothers.
Those are the most
dangerous motherfuckers.
Those the youngest kids have
a family full of savages.
Dad was like a pro football player,
all stud athletes,
house full of Stud athlete Dudes,
you have to be tough as fuck
to be the young brother.
But they probably broke a bone of his
or her to grow around the metal plate on
his head.
He was relaying all the different times
he was bullied by his brothers and what
happened they,
they created a guy who gives zero
fucks and we'll punch your face in.
I mean that's what it is.
And Anderson Silva just couldn't
hang with that two times in a row.
We call over showboating and all that
stuff aside was showboating the first time
and during the first fight and it was,
but one of the reasons why your show
buttons cause he was getting smashed when
he took him down.
He wanted Weidman to keep that fight
standing where he has the best advantage
cause he took Weidman,
took Anderson to the ground early in
the first round and hit him with some
vicious ground and past stung him,
roll his eyes back in his head.
He hit him with a couple hard shots.
One very clean right hand that without
a doubt Anderson saw some sparks without
a doubt, and he knew that that
was a real dangerous position.
He couldn't hold this
guy back for very long.
Holding onto him on the ground is tough.
He's too strong, it's too good of a,
and he hits too hard.
So his best chance was to get
this guy to stand up with him.
So he started getting cocky with them,
talking shit,
trying to get into his head and that's,
that's what it actually cost him would
cost him was him not fighting like a
martial artist was him being like a guy
trying to play psychological warfare
instead of just fighting
with perfect technique.
He got the guy to stand up with him.
If he can keep that fight standing,
he should have the advantage.
He's much faster.
His technique is about as good
as it gets in all the land.
There's no better stand up striking
techniques in Anderson Silva's, but in,
in goading,
that guy into an ego battle,
he took some chances and
then you got cracked.
So I don't know if he's coming back,
man. Those are two big losses, you know,
I mean,
he says he's not in,
he's towards the end of his career, not
towards the beginning allegedly. Right.
You know,
some guys can stretch that shit out.
What's crazy is guys like Bernard Hopkins
who are 10 years older than him and
Bernard Hopkins has one of the
light heavyweight titles in boxing.
He's the 175 pound champion and
he's almost 50 years old. I mean,
no one's ever done that before,
but Bernard Hopkins fights
exactly the opposite of Anderson.
He's very safety technique oriented.
If you watch how Bernard fights,
he's a master.
I license a master with his footwork.
He's a master of positioning.
He's always in a good place.
You're always in a bad place.
He's just been around for so long and he
knows how to get guys out of their head,
but the way he gets guys out of their
head is he's, he fights rough with them.
He gets dirty with them. He pulls on
their heads a lot. He leans on them. He,
he fights rough.
If it's real rough and hill,
he'll force a boxer to get
into his clinch wars with him.
Almost like an MMA fight where
he wears the guy's arms out,
makes them too tired of
punch and then you know,
I mean he did that to a lot of dudes.
He did that to Felix Trinidad.
He Fuck Felix Trinidad.
I remember that fight.
A lot of people didn't see him winning.
Who's an unstuck flag and all that.
You know they had a green light on him
in New York back in the day. Yo Man,
Puerto Ricans were like, Yo, the
green light on that again, they were,
they were literally going
to put like a spirit.
That was hard when he came up here.
He, he squashed all that apparently.
I don't know how,
but I just let it know.
Once upon a time it was very real.
And then when back in the nineties
if you had beef with a Puerto Rican,
you had beef with a million of them.
They were not.
It was the 2010 he fuck Tito Trinidad.
I don't remember the exact year, but no,
it was like two it was like literally
2000 all right. Was it leaking into that?
Remember the Jerry Seinfeld thing?
He had beef with the Puerto Rican.
What was that only Seinfeld Dude?
Yeah. What was it over? It was,
it was over the PR parade. Like th they,
they had like an episode where they like,
you didn't make it in front
of the parade or level.
They then people were calling it racist
and all this other stuff. But yeah,
it's side. He had to squash the
beef with the Puerto Rican dude
right after September 11th it
was actually September 29th,
2001 the Madison Square Garden.
Crazy. Yeah. He stepped on the flight.
He apologized afterwards.
He said they actually had to move it
because it was supposed to be September
15th and that was right after September
11th so there was a Madison Square
Garden. Yup. And so they moved it
to September 29th wow. That's crazy.
And he beat the shit out of
Felix Trinidad. That was,
I remember that fight boxing performance
masterful. No, I remember that fight.
It was genius.
And then he fought Kelly Pavlick and that
was another genius performance. I mean,
that was another fight where was a
dangerous fight against a real knockout
puncher and just puck circles around
that kid. He's just so technical, man.
So who's gonna,
who's gonna fight the Wiedemann Dude now?
Well is gonna Fight Vitor Belfort. Yeah.
Yeah. That's an interesting fight. Well,
it's also interesting because there's a
real controversy regarding testosterone
use because Vito has a testosterone
use exemption and he's been fighting in
Brazil,
apparently has low testosterone.
So they give them the license to
take testosterone like all the time.
So he's essentially taking hormones,
taking male hormones,
and Weidman is not,
so Weidman is fighting completely
naturally with no enhancement whatsoever.
Just being a young guy
with normal [inaudible] see
limits and all, all kinds of,
maybe, I don't know what it
uses. Some guys don't use shit.
There's some guys that fight in the
UFC that don't use a god damn thing.
They just eat healthy food and
drink a lot of water. And that's it.
There's quite a few guys
who do that. Right. Um,
some guys take a variety of different
muscle enhancing supplements. You know,
there's like testosterone
boosters that are legal.
Like there's a one that on
its cells called t plus shown,
the people like weightlifters were showing
that it's a increased their ability
to lift weights in double blind placebo
studies where you're not using, you know,
using essentially a giant group of people.
They don't know what they're using and
the people that were using t plus got
higher, uh, higher improvement
in their, their weightlifting.
So there's a few things that you can do,
but for the most part,
most of the guys that get on it,
they get on the synthetic form,
they get an a on a synthetic
form of testosterone.
So this is like a few different
t plus and there's a couple,
there's a couple of other test boosters
and there's a few routes that are
supposed to work. Like tribulus is
supposed to have us a small effect.
Then there's some, there's
another, what does it,
Long Jack cat or something like that.
I forget.
There's another one that's supposed
to have some sort of an effect.
But for the most part,
it doesn't have any where near the effect
that actually taking testosterone will
have. So there's guys take it and Vitor
is taking it and they're, they uh,
there's a dispute as to whether or not
he's going to get licensed in Las Vegas.
And if he doesn't get
licensed to use testosterone,
then he has to get off of the
testosterone and then fight Wyman.
And if that happens,
man,
that's going to be really fascinating
because his hormone levels are going to be
all fucked up. If he's
used to taking a, an,
an extra natural form of testosterone,
injecting it into a system
and then you stopped doing it,
his body's going to have a much lower
level of testosterone in his training
camps.
Then even normally a regular human being,
but he would have a much
lower will drop off. Yeah.
Because his body's been used
to getting it externally.
His body's not producing it anymore.
So it's really interesting.
You don't have to,
they'll have to kickstart his body's
production of testosterone, which is like,
wow, that's crazy. So it's, it's,
it's controversial in that respect.
But skill wise it's a very
dangerous fight for both guys.
Weidman is a fucking beast, but God Damn
Vito Belfort looks scary as shit. Lately.
He took out Dan Henderson in
the first round, he took out,
you mean he took him out in a way that
no one's ever taken Dan Henderson out
like that is his striking is horrific.
It's very,
actually I went to, uh, like a
mixed martial arts competition,
but like it was like a local one that one
of my friends was supposed to fight in.
Um, but he got injured and
so he didn't find at the end,
but I ended up watching it and it was
actually pretty interesting. It was in a,
it was like in Long Island. Um,
and it was like a small gym.
It was full of like a few hundred people.
But it was really interesting.
Like I saw the difference in kind of how
they run those local spots and now I've
never actually been to one
of those big MMA things.
Tell me when you want to go, man, I'll
hook it up. Tell me when you want to go.
You heard it. You heard it here.
You just give me a day. Good.
Just tell me which one you want
to go, then we'll hook it up. No,
I definitely want to see it
on February 22nd holy Shit.
That's my birthday weekend,
Vegas. There it is.
Oh, you're planning on doing
this. This is what he's feeling.
That's the feeling you get when
you're anticipating a hangover.
That's what you just did. Do you, what's
the one after that just in case? Well,
there's a big one in Dallas after that.
A huge one that's for the welterweight
title and it's a Dallas Cowboy stadium,
so that's, that's a gigantic event.
That one, if you want that one, uh,
I'll give you the exact date of
that. That is, that's in March.
I think it's march.
I want to say 15th but hold on a second.
I'll tell you in one second.
Yeah. Is it March 15th yeah. Yeah.
That one is going to be gigantic.
That is 50,000 people, man in,
in Dallas at Dallas Cowboy stadium.
That's probably the best one to go
to cause that's going to be historic.
And the title fight.
Yeah,
there'll be a new new crowning of the
welterweight championship because, uh,
George stepped down. George Saint Pierre
stepped down. And so the guy who am,
I thought one the decision,
Johny Hendricks. I thought
it was a bad decision.
And I'm a huge George Saint Pierre Fan,
by the way of him as a
person and as a fighter.
But I thought it with all honesty,
that the decision was incorrect.
I thought Johnny went
through rounds to two.
So he's going to take on Robbie Lawler.
So that'll be the new UFC welterweight
champion. Dude, you got to come to that.
So he vacated the title and now they're
gonna they're gonna brawl out. Yes.
And there's also Carlos condit
was fighting Tyron Woodley,
which is fucking madness and chaos.
That's going to be an insane fight.
That's an insane, insane fight.
There's a lot of insane fights.
Diego Sanchez fight and miles jury.
That is a great fucking fight.
Miles jury is a beast.
Real tough young kid.
And Diego Sanchez is this
definition of the word savage.
This Cuban motherfucker, Hector Lombard.
You ever seen him fight a whole shit?
Is He scary? I heard of him.
God dammit. He's a monster.
He's a monster dude.
A an Olympic judoka judo specialist who,
who doesn't even use his grappling
just knocks people to fuck out.
He's a super athlete and um,
yeah,
he just fought Nate Marquardt and put
them away in the first round in the a
mugging and Nate,
Mark Schwartz,
the former Strikeforce champion and
lumbar just mugged him at one 70.
He's terrifying.
He thought his whole career,
one 85 is the Bella to champion at 185
pounds, but dropped down to one 70.
And he's just like a muscle.
I mean the dude is like 6%
body fat and just shredded,
shredded spring of just courted steel.
And he says,
everybody's has tried to get the fuck
away from him. Just throwing bombs at you.
The,
the move did a Wiedemann made vitamins,
Weidman part to, to uh, the weed
man. That's when we'll call it.
You don't weed man homie.
I'm not going to say that he's heard this.
I'm sure he's heard it a million times.
You know,
people called me that before I
break their fucking legs, homie.
He wouldn't say that. He's a super
nice guy now. He probably is.
Most things that I know that really,
really got it like that.
They don't have a star problems.
They just wait to the problems come to
them and they take care of him and they
keep it moving. Well the guy he's
fighting a super nice guy too.
Carlos condit is fighting this guy.
Jake shields is a Jujitsu black belt,
so world class grappler. So it's
a real, real interesting guy.
Just beat Woodley in his last fight.
So it's a very interesting,
very interesting fight.
And what about this, uh,
who's going to fight a Jon and Jon Jones?
Jon Jones is going to fight.
He's gonna fight in Baltimore and
he's gonna fight Glover to sharer.
Who's the scariest motherfucker?
All the 205 pound contenders.
Glover is the fucking
devil. He's scary. He's,
everybody knows that Glover was
on the sidelines for six months.
He had a visa issue and he couldn't get
to the United States and he was fucking
people up in small shows cause he was one
to chuck Adele's training partners and
he has been world class like top of
the food chain worldclass for almost a
decade now like Soca Jew before.
So could you make this big splash
and pride was knocking, knocked out,
little nog knocked out Ricardo Arona
before he did that glow over to sheriff
fucked him up in the WEC.
But Glover had visa issues.
So for six years everybody
knew that Glover was like
having real problems trying
to fight in America but he's fighting in
Brazil and just beaten the fucking shit
out of people. Man. He's a
beast. What was the visa issue?
He was resilient and sometimes you know,
you have an issue getting a um, the,
the visa to fight American money.
He didn't have the money,
he wasn't fighting for the UFC back then.
He was fighting for a smaller
organizations and you know,
you got to have a visa before
the UFC can even sign you.
It's funny because we were going to
have a discussion later on today. Um,
Dan and like chunking,
we wouldn't have a talk about immigration
and we were discussing this specific
issue about, um, they were saying,
oh, you know, it's the law. The,
all the critics are saying, oh, it's
the, the law has to be enforced.
It's not just the law, it's the law for
poor people. Because when you're rich,
apparently some of my friends who are
lawyers that handle immigration cases,
they'll tell me straight
up, no, listen,
there are rich families from places in
Asia and the Middle East that when they
want to come here, they buy
a green card. And I was like,
what do you mean by a green
card and lower, it wasn't rich.
They set up a company in order to,
to employ certain people here it has to
be a certain way. It's like 200, $300,000.
And when they pay into it,
they immediately are given green cards
to manage the business here as long as
they employ a certain amount of
Americans. But like you say, you know,
he probably just didn't have
the people backing him up. Yeah,
you got to have mad cash to buy or you
make a fake company in order to get green
cards, but it can be
done. We had $1,000. Look,
if you are really wealthy man from Iceland
and you wanted to come to America and
get a green card, I'm sure it could
be arranged. And someone, you know,
guys got a billion Coonara in
front of your money is, you know,
whatever their money is over there.
But my friend Glover,
this a guy who is going to be fighting
Jon Jones who also, uh, um, I,
I'm actually friends with John Jones.
I love that guy. That's a tough fight.
Tough fight for both guys.
Glow Glover is a beast,
but Jon Jones is a God damn freak athlete.
He's a freak and I think Jon
Jones is going to be old.
Tra motivated for this fight. I
felt like he, he learned something.
His last title defense was a tough
fight against Gustafson who's a beast.
It was a great, great fight.
Really, really close fight.
John One that decision and I think,
you know,
really realize he was in a
war and his bearing down,
he's saying all the right things and I
think he's going to try to look to put on
a show against this clover cat.
But Glover is scary as fuck, man.
What are they going to fight? They're
going to find in Baltimore in April.
Glow over puts people to sleep, man.
He puts people to sleep with one punch.
He fought Ryan Bader and
Ryan Bader heard him,
Ryan Bader tagged him and wobbled him.
And as Ryan Bader moved into closest show,
Glover to share shut his fucking
lights off. He's a monster man.
He's been around a long ass
time and he hits fucking hard.
We had his trainer,
John Hackleman was on the podcast and he
was talking about holding the myths for
this dude. And he's like,
he hits you different. He's
like, Hackleman by the way,
was a kickboxing champion.
Motherfuckers been around since the
70s doing karate and Campo and he's,
he's seen it all.
And then some,
and he talks about Glover's like in
this fucking guy hits you. You're like,
you feel the knuckles through your hand,
like you're holding the pads for him.
He's like, I've never felt
it like that. He goes,
I've never had anybody punched me that
hard. He goes, not chocked, not anybody.
And he goes, chuck is up murderous
puncher. This guy punches even harder.
He's like, it's like ridiculous. Like Mike
Tyson style, punching power. He's like,
he, if he hits you, you're fucked.
And he did that to Ryan Bader.
Ryan Bader tagged him.
I don't wobbled and covering up.
And Ryan Bader moved in for the kill and
clover just [inaudible] just dropped a
haymaker on and he see his eyes
go sideways and his legs give out
motherfucking. It's hard.
Recently, I forget who it was,
but one person was really wearing
down in his mouth, fuck his leg.
He was just working on the leg,
beating the shit out of
his leg and then does
hit him with the overhand right.
She knocked dude out. Mike.
Well this has been a few of those,
you know,
it was at a kickboxing match or was
it a MMA fight? It was an MMA fight.
Was it the UFC? I believe so. It
might've been a Edson Barboza.
Edson Barboza is one of the most scary
guys when it comes to a leg kicks in the
UFC. He's one of the,
uh, the top lightweights.
He's actually fighting Donald Serone
that's coming up soon. Caught. Damn.
That's kind of be a good buck.
I guess it's the American Airlines
Center jail there a lot of good. Okay.
Is there a lot of gambling
at these events? Oh yeah.
In Vegas on 100%. The one,
if you want to come to the,
uh, Vito Belfort, Chris
Weidman fight, that's in May,
that's May 24th. If you want to come
to that, that's going to be in Vegas.
And I just hope they see if they don't
give Vitara testosterone use exemption.
I mean, I understand what everybody says.
It's not fair. I understand the logic,
but if they don't give it to him,
he really shouldn't be fighting for the
title unless he can get his hormones
back in order. I, if it's been taking
testosterone for a long period of time,
I don't understand how his body's just
going to start magically producing it
again on its own unless they figure out
something that they could give him that
will kickstart is production of
testosterone. But if that's the case,
shouldn't have been doing that in the
first place. So I don't know. I mean,
if the guy really does need testosterone,
I hope they give it to
them because if they don't,
he's not going to really be able to fight.
Right.
Not to the same level that he's going
to be able to fight if he's on it.
Honestly.
But wasn't my Tyson taking like pills or
mood on him pills when he fought Lennox
Lewis away, he told me this story.
They said things on antidepressants.
He was taking some sort of medication.
Yeah, that's happened before. Um,
guys kiss on his cheek and all. He's
trying to be nice to him. He said,
I love you. He said, I love Edm Ma. You
know, not to make fun of Mike Tyson.
You know, he's a monster even now. But
I'm just saying when I look at that,
I'm like, all right, how could he
not have been affected by that?
And you are mood altering drugs and now
they're asking you to fight for your
life.
And then at the end of it you put a flower
and then it goes hair and then kissed
him on the cheek. Yeah. I don't know
what he was on when he fought Lennox,
but I wouldn't be surprised man.
He was high on drugs during major fights.
He definitely said that,
that he was a,
he was doing coke all the time
and uh, he even used a, a,
a fake penis to a avoid detection.
He, one of those fake rubber penis.
He's a bad motherfucker,
dude.
I love the fact that he comes out and
just tell us everything about everything
that he did.
That was crazy.
It makes me more inclined to believe that
he never raped that girl first of all.
And it makes me more inclined to sort of
forgive him for being so fucking crazy.
The, all the horrible things
that he definitely did do.
It's like the guy was living in a wild,
reckless life.
He's telling you all he did.
He's telling me he's opening up the
door like this is all the Shit I did.
I was doing coke and fighting
people and people are like, oh,
here's the rubber Dick. Like to
him, Jesus Christ, I think he's,
he's a classic story in my opinion, is
the greatest heavyweight champion of all.
I think so, yes. I put them
at the top of the list.
I think for a brief moment in time,
people want to consider his whole entire
career towards the end out of prison
after prison post-prison but
I think that before then,
I think when he was in his prime,
the guy that beat Larry Holmes,
I think the guy that beat Marvis Frasier,
I think that that Mike
Tyson brand heavyweight,
but he also had small paper champion
dudes that he fought and a bunch of them
obviously not the ones you mentioned, and
then the razor Ruddick fight was crazy.
Those people really gave
him a run for his money. He,
he had to punish them as much as
they were trying to punish him.
But for some of them, for example,
the bus, the dug this thing,
he took that shit lightly.
He walked in like it was whatever.
And it went over with some other fighters,
but not with buster Douglas.
Well that was also post-prison. He wasn't
the same guy, right? Wasn't it? No,
no, no, no, no. I'm wrong. No,
buster Douglas happened before
and all the crazy shit happened.
Then he went to prison. Right.
And they lost his title in the,
and then he came back and then he came
back and he fought Holyfield and have
those Holyfield Dubach holes.
Those were fucking crazy.
When we bid Holyfield's ear, that
was all post-prison. You're right.
When he was getting, he was saying that
Holyfield was headbutting him. Yeah,
he does all the time.
Go back and you look at all the tapes.
No headbutts everybody.
But Tyson did it too.
I mean they had buttered each other and
the point being that Tyson like didn't
stay at the same level when custom auto
died. And then Kevin Rooney took over.
I think he maintained that
level for a little bit,
but I think that the fame and
the fortune and the madness,
we're too crazy when you have
your own fucking lions, when you,
you live in in a gigantic hundred fucking
room house and bought 15 Bentley's,
you know, for every person you've
ever met is, he's a, he's a mad man.
You got a bunch of factory
loading as people. But I
mean again, but I just think,
I don't think you can keep it up,
but I think that when he was at his best,
I think he only kept it up for a few
years, like two years, three years.
But I think during that time he
was the greatest of all time.
That's my personal opinion.
I don't think anybody ever sent shockwaves
through the boxing world the way that
guy did when he emerged on the scene
and just started starching people with
fucking haymakers that came at the speed
that Roberto Duran would throw them.
Yet it's coming from a guy who's 215
pounds and just launching motherfuckers
into orbit. That right hook
to the body. White upper.
Cut that with snap your fucking head
back that up because when I see the, the,
the, the old youtube videos of him
fighting upper cut his, the way he merged,
I don't know how someone's
jaw was intact after that.
He was for Russias but you can't keep
it up forever man. It's red lining.
When you red line and
engine you'd go back,
you'd get that bitch up to 9,000 rpm
and then you kind of shift gears.
You have to, and he didn't ever shift
gears. Somebody red line to to this,
somebody told me we were having this
discussion about like music and I went to
the Berkeley College of music and
I was telling kids like, listen,
people don't generally
get rich off of music,
which what artists do is they take that
nest egg of money that they do or that
they get from music and they
invested wisely and something else.
The richest rappers,
quote unquote,
are people who have made some money in
music and they say, Oh, you know what?
I'm going to start like a construction
company or our contracting company or I'm
going to buy six waffle houses
or I'm going to get, you know,
a clothing company or whatever it is and
that's how they make that money. What,
what is the twilight for fighters,
Joe? Where do they fall back on?
The pen is on a fighter.
It depends entirely on the restaurant.
Some guys become commentators like
chill son and he'll eventually be a
commentator for sure.
He is one now.
Rashad Evans is doing commentary now
while he's fighting. Brian Stan retired.
He became a commentator. Kenny Florian
retired. He became a commentator.
A lot of them are there and
they're also becoming judges.
Ricardo Alomeda as a judge in
New York now and he's also,
a lot of them are coaches.
That's most likely the best path for them,
especially the guys that
still love the sport.
They still want to be around the sport.
Like Duane Ludwig is the coach of
the year. He won coach of the year.
Congratulations. My friend Dwayne, he won
coach of the year for 2013 rightly so,
because he did a tremendous
job of transitioning between
being a great fighter
to being an even better coach. I mean an
amazing coach for this team. Alpha male.
He's just changed that whole fucking team.
I mean they,
they're all striking like at
a very high level now. Much,
much higher than they were before.
So that's a good transition for Dwayne
and he's doing very well with that.
But some guys, uh, they just
quit and go into business.
Keith Jardine open up a coffee company.
He's a caveman coffee. That's Keith.
And uh, my friend Tate, who
also was former MMA fighter,
they open up a coffee company.
Some guys go into acting,
you know Gina Gershon is like a
famous actress now. Gina Gershon.
Gina Damn. What's her name? Gina Carano.
Gina Gershon is obviously
a famous actress too. Um,
there was another rumor that Clinton
fucked her too. That's why it was,
I'd fallen all this. Jesus went
and fucked everybody. Love Him.
Last American presidential, Dick's Linger,
ladies and gentlemen, Dude, what was he?
They say he smashed out
Liz Hurley. Yeah. Yeah.
This is a picture of
them stare at each other,
looking at each other's eyes and
you're like, oh yeah, for sure.
It's just too romantic. The look I'm
looking at, but it wasn't at times.
Tom Sizemore. That was dry
snitching. He was, yes.
He was a dry snitch up that dirty son of
a bitch. That Nigga was a snitch. He is.
That's what I said. That's the first
thing I said on the Fred. I said,
but this tells me Tom Sizemore can't
keep a fucking secret dude. Yeah,
that's weak.
And you go on throw bill under the bus.
There's the picture. Come
on son. Look at his eyes.
No one escapes that deck.
That deck octopus comes out and grabs.
I mean, that is like a
dominant submissive picture.
If ever people were not touching, but
one was encroaching Ludas body language.
He's leaning towards her. Look at
her. Look at her left shoulder.
Turns slightly away from him. She wants
to lay down right now. Look at her list.
Dirty too dirty, dirty, dirty people.
I love it. I wish I was there.
I beat off in the corner.
I wouldn't say a word
slick willy tearing it up.
I don't know how we got on that subject.
We were talking about Mike Tyson
beat the fuck out of people.
Tremendous.
You'll need to fuck up the picture of
we're putting Hillary and get that picture
down.
You don't need to fuck
up all of our minds,
but thinking about the guilt that
he must have suffered right after it
not worth it. Shit. Oh Kiss.
And she knows. She knows
right bag and the one in the back
was like, Yo, look at her. Fuck.
Oh my God. Look at that
woman. Oh Wow. Yeah. Not
they play dress up. Look Paul Revere's
right behind them to his right.
Look at that as Paul Revere. That
woman. That woman's a hater. No,
the woman right there. You get up to
her. Look at that. She knows. She knows.
That is the classic. She's either face
the Dick. I did it. She definitely,
she definitely knows that
something's going on under the table
car. Her and her husband, she
was like that motherfucker.
Did you see the way he kissed Elizabeth
early? Oh, he's such a pig. I,
I despise him rush. Limbaugh's
right. Look at him. Disgusting.
You know what's funny though,
when I heard about this,
it was so interesting that I heard
conservatives come out the woodwork.
Um, who was it? I think it was rand
Paul was like, Oh man, this is terrible.
The president should apologize,
but wait a minute homie.
Where were you when Newt
Gingrich was running for office?
Because didn't he drop his wife and then
deal with another woman and then deal
with another one and mean,
isn't that the,
that the benchmark of men
that are in power, they're
just looking to play. Gotcha.
All these shit heads. Are they just
using that like it's points on a blanket.
Nobody ever fuck no, they scored on you.
They caught you, they scored on you.
They got points now and they just going
to use those points to try to shut you
down and build them up.
But it all just makes everybody
look like a bunch of bitches.
Because if that was going
on amongst your friends,
let's say if there was 10 of your
friends and one of your friends was not
particularly happy with
his wife's relationship,
and so he started banging
Elizabeth Hurley and all. Yeah,
guys found out about it. I wouldn't dry
snitch. I wouldn't play Tom Sizemore.
I'll tell you, you went
out and you, you snitch,
you have no one would want to hang out
with you anymore. Right. He'd be like,
what the fuck tech, but oh
man, who's going to party
with Tom Sizemore now? Not me.
I'll tell you that Tom.
Go Fuck yourself pal
secret.
Keep that motherfucker. I met
Tom Sizemore. He's a cool dude.
That's why I was, I was shocked.
I did a show called the list.
He came on and it was like a thing
for VH one. It was pretty cool. Man,
I think was him and a Rob Halford from
Judas priest. We're on the same show.
Did he, did he know or was
he secretly being recorded?
Oh, I don't know man. I
don't know. I, I, you know,
I don't know if he even really said
it. I'm just talking shit. Like I said,
I met the guy. He's a nice guy. Oh,
so let's set it in some interview
or something like that. Allegedly.
That's what everyone's saying and
there's a picture of him. Look man,
the dude also did a lot of drugs. He
probably is not thinking so good like his,
uh, his judgments, quite suspect.
He's not the kind of guy you would want
to have some information if Tom Sizemore
fines up dead.
Vince foster style on a hill.
No, no blood at the scene
of the crime. Super ugly.
Yeah. Vince, for the strange death
of Vince foster is a fantastic book.
You want to talk about a weird
death that appears to be murder.
This was during the
Clinton administration.
There's a guy named Vince foster and he
knew some things about some things and a
bunch of people knew some things
and Vince foster might've been a,
a liability and a,
he wound up dead holding onto the gun
in his hand with the thumb still on the
trigger,
which they say never happens.
They say that when someone shoots
themselves and you commit suicide,
you're hand goes,
the gun just goes flying.
Like you don't hold onto
the gun violence of a gun.
It give you've ever shot at gotten,
you know the guns have a kick. Well,
if you're not conscious,
you're not going to hold onto that
gun and see where Vince foster has.
It's his thumb, like trapped in
where holding on to the, to the gun.
He's also lying down in an
area where there was no blood.
There's more blood missing from his
body then was at the scene of the crime.
His body was moved.
Somebody moved him there.
It doesn't mean that
he didn't kill himself.
He's each still could have killed himself.
He could have killed himself with a gay
lover and the gay lover wanting to cover
up the story.
So he grabbed the body and dropped it
off somewhere and put the gun in his
Thomas. Who knows? And I'm just
making that gay little part up.
I Dunno why I went there.
That's what I did get two of those images
that Brian read bringing up with the
fucking Greek shit. Whatever the reason
was that whoever killed him, whoever
killed him, it was, it's
most likely that, uh,
whether it was he killed himself
or somebody else killed him,
they moved his body and a, they put a
gun in his Tom, it just doesn't add up.
It doesn't add up. It's a, it's
a strange case because, uh,
that's when the Whitewater
shit was going on, right.
Water. What was the, what was the,
the land deal that the Clintons
were involved with? Water.
They lost money on the deal. Supposedly
it wasn't white water. The Nixon Shit. No,
no, no, no. What was the
Watergate, Watergate. Nixon.
All this water talk water is a problem
with presence. You know, it was crazy.
I tell you a personal story.
When I was incarcerated,
I was in Pennsylvania and I was
processed through an area. Um,
and there was this a district
attorney named Ray Greek car. Um,
he disappeared. And another people
who are watching from Pennsylvania,
they knew this story, um, shot the PA.
And the crazy thing is that he literally,
he was investigating the Sandusky thing.
Yeah. A lot of people don't know that.
They found his fucking laptop without a,
without a hard and
he disappeared going,
gone.
And the asa that tried my case
was in disbarred after uh,
like two,
it was like maybe two or three a,
a case is after me for
tampering with evidence.
It's supposedly there was some shootout
and like he had removed shell casings
from the scene of the fucking room.
How about that other judge in,
in Pennsylvania that got accused
of sending kids Jay Holmes,
he was selling and selling them for money.
He made $3 million over the course
of fucking like fucking 10 years.
The guys I had judge and he's making
sure that kids go to jail for paper.
Fuck for money. Oh God, that's crazy.
There's not a whole small enough or
dark enough to shove him and you know,
you get a kill that guy,
that guy,
you should put them in a corner and some
parent you give a parent that gun and
he going to shoot that fucking guy in
the head. And you feed them to pigs.
That's it. So you don't let that
guy rot away and live at jail.
He chose to take children and put them
in horrendous situations where you know
they were sexually abused, you know, do
you know they were physically tortured?
100% and they could have been let free
and they could have enjoyed their lives.
They could have got their shit together.
They could have been musicians or
comedians or athletes or whatever the fuck
they could have been without that horrific
life experience that they were forced
to endure because of a corrupt shot.
Shoot that motherfucker right in the head.
Throw them in a box, let the rats
eat them, throw them in the ground,
let the worms digest his body.
Fuck him. Fuck his tombstone,
no coffin.
Getting that whole stupid,
make him dig his own fucking hall and
then shoot them right in the Dick.
Shit. Fuck him. The
crazy shit is though that
a lot of people never made that connection
between his disappearance and it was
only something recent that happened.
Still not, they're not
investigating it. You know,
you don't hear him a word about it?
Well I mean she'd be something
that area and PA's a little like that
Steubenville situation where it's all some
like you know, local good old boys type
town with, you know, I'll be honest,
I heard rumors while I was there,
I can't confirm or deny them and I won't
say that they're true cause I don't
want to get sued.
But the reality is that I always heard
rumors that the judges in that county or
that two of them in specific would drive
drunk all the time and every single day
a cop would follow them so that
if they veer too far off the road,
he would take them out, put
them in his car, drive it,
and then come back and get his other car
100% I wouldn't doubt it for a God damn
that when then whenever someone that
had like an issue with drug addiction or
something,
like they would always clean it up for
like a cop's kid or for the judges child
or something like that. So, I mean when
you talk about a tier justice system,
it's ironic that people say, Oh man,
technique. You make conscious music,
and I always remind them,
being conscious doesn't imply
that you're going to do anything.
It just means you know
that something's wrong.
But I think that the consciousness of
this society is much more aware of the
divide and conquer shit that
we were talking about in
the beginning of the show.
That's harder to do today because
I don't have a beef with Canada.
I don't have a beef with Mexico and
have beef with any part of the world.
I've met people in other
places and they've been just
like me and I've talked to
people online which showed us just like
you know when you see a lot of different
people,
you're right,
but I think that this connection that
we're all experiencing online is a very
different way of experiencing the
world and that the divide and conquer,
it's almost impossible now.
It's almost impossible as long as we can
understand each other. Now, let me ask.
If people, for example, they
think that something's fake,
they think something's not real,
then they're upset about it.
Let's say people found out right now that
the Superbowl was staged just as much
as something like wrestling
would be all right.
Now the injuries are real just
like they say it or I say, hey man,
you know the wrestling's fake what
the injuries are real. You know?
I think that people would be on the
verge of ripping the place apart.
Well you would, you could fake, you
could fix a Superbowl, but the fake,
the Superbowl would not fake.
But obviously to say, all
right, we want, we would,
we would be more inclined
if this team won or if this,
and I know people would say that's so
impractical. That could never happen.
The world series has been accused
of being fixed several times.
This is what you could do.
This is what has been done.
What they can do is they can hire referees
and make sure that the referees are
paid for and bought off and bribed.
And then if there is a situation where
a questionable call can be made right,
where they can call it
one way or the other,
especially before they used
to use instant replays. Right.
I mean the instant replay
thing clears up a lot of shit.
There's a lot of things that, I mean,
if a ball's not in a ball is not in.
If a dude's foot is out of bounds,
the dude's puts out of bounds.
If you looking at the instant replays,
not much you could say,
but before all that man, God damn, they
must have rigged a lot of games then.
Then basketball referees didn't was a
fucking bring those and bringing them out
of Philly and what was going on?
What was the story? Uh, they had,
and I think it was like 12 of them
and they were all referees. Yeah.
They had it for years. Like they were
just on the payroll and hilarious.
They were connected.
How they got caught is one of the bookies.
They ended up tapping
like a bookies phone.
And so basically the bookies was
painting. I'm gonna leave a moment. Well,
it only makes sense when you think
about the amount of money involved in
gambling. You know, that's a thought about
a fixed fights too. I mean, the, the real,
the fixing fights, it's not
like, you know, the champions
paying you off to lose.
Now the fixing fights is someone is
wa wants a bed, a fuck load of money,
a fuck load of money. Like here's a
good example. And people have said,
I'm crazy for thinking this,
but Manny Pacquiao,
when Manny Pacquiao fought Tim Bradley,
Tim Bradley won that
fight in no one's eyes,
but maybe 10 Bradley's family and a
couple of people at home that really hate
Manny Pacquiao. Most people saw
Manny Pacquiao boxes face off.
They saw him not his face off, but he
won that fight. He wanted to fight.
In my opinion, it was a
terrible, terrible decision.
But when you find out that someone voted,
uh,
that someone like put the
scores in and that same,
someone put the same like really
ridiculous score in another fight where it
doesn't make any sense.
And then you watching over and over again.
You seeing these,
these scores that don't make any sense.
He's seeing these fights that most people
thought the fight one fight or clearly
won and they have like two fighters are
two judges we'll call it where it's a,
you know the the one one fires
winning by like six, seven,
eight rounds and then the other one makes
it a draw and you're like how the fuck
could that be?
Well the way it could be is because
then it's not a majority decision and
there's unanimous decisions.
Rather it's an unanimous decision
cause unanimous decision bets.
So you can bet a huge amount of money
that Manny pack hill is not going to beat
Timothy Bradley by unanimous decision.
You're going to see,
you're going to bet a fucking that
it's going to be a split decision and
everybody's going to go, are you fucking
crazy? You really to take that bet.
It's like x to one. No one, no one
ever sees split decisions. Well,
if one judge has paid off just one judge,
all they have to do is say it's a
draw and everybody else is like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
What did you watch? That wasn't a draw.
But the guy who makes the money is the
guy who paid off the referee to make an a
jaw or the judge to make it a
draw and they win that bet. Clean
the odds on to first, uh, scoring
being a touchback safety, safety.
I mean incredible what God's word.
Like super sick people got rich to
us off of that. Yeah. And I mean,
I don't know if it's possible
that you could just rig that.
Is it possible that will be enough.
I mean, that would be enough.
What's possible or what's it? Yeah, you
pay the center off. I mean the center.
And so what does he do?
What does he have to do in his center?
Basically threw the ball over,
you know, the quarterback's head.
Did you do it on purpose
you think? I mean, he did.
He didn't do that the whole season.
Pretty much do it for $10 million.
I mean that's, but then you've got
to account for that $10 million.
You've got to show why
you have that $10 million.
Who's to say maybe it's $10 million
cash is king. No wash in America,
go wash it to cash is king.
We all know that a truck load
of pussy shows up at his house.
Shh.
They lower that back door like one of
those aircraft carriers where they lower
the door.
All the girls with keys. Cow. Yeah.
Without a doubt.
We know the judges had been paid off.
We know that referees has been paid off.
We know that this corruption,
whenever this game just,
it gets harder with fighters
because at the end of the day,
I mean a fighter trains and
harder on them to do. It looks,
you can see it. It's
obvious. Joe has someone,
has someone got paid to throw
a fight and then I may and UFC
not in the unit. I don't know. I shouldn't
say no. I said I don't know of him,
but I do know of them in
pride. In fact, Eddie Bravo,
they offered him a fight in Japan and
they told him in no uncertain terms that
they can make so that he wins the fight
and that they can make it so that he
wins the fight any way he wants to win.
And he thought it was a double cross.
He, the way Eddie, Eddie is like, what?
What are you talking about? Like you
got to fix the fight. First of all,
Eddie would never do that.
He would never compete in a fake fight.
He just wouldn't do it.
He wouldn't be able to live with himself.
I know him never do it.
No matter how much money they paid him.
And if he did do it, he would tell people
right afterwards I did a fake fight.
He wouldn't be able to handle it.
He would say, look man, I feel bad,
but they gave me a half a million
bucks. I had to fucking do it, you know?
And he would just joke around about how
it happened. He would never fake it.
But what they did was they came
to him and they told him that.
So if that's the case, one of two
things are going on. Either they,
it would be a double cross where he would
go there thing and it was a fake fight
and that do it. Beat the shit out
of him and he couldn't say nothing.
That's possible. Or he could go
there and the guy would lay down,
the guy would give up or they would have
what they would call a hard shoot or
like a or a hard work and hard
work is you're sparring real hard,
you're fucking, the guy will kick you
with some leg kicks if shit goes wrong,
you could get your draw broken,
you could get tagged and get knocked out.
I mean there's hard works where a guy
loses that he's supposed to win because
the guy got injured because something
went wrong. Sometimes things happen,
but if you're skillful you can
make it look like a real fight.
And there's for sure that happened in k
one for sure that happened in pride for
sure. 100% I know there's some dudes
that told me themselves that they,
through fights,
they got paid a shitload of money and
they tapped out the Japanese dude,
they got caught like heel
hooks or something like that.
And the guy won and he's a hero and
he's like a pro wrestler in Japan was
without a doubt there's been some fan
and he walks away with like yeah million
dollars in like whale blubber.
It's possible man.
I mean you could come up to some guy,
you know,
you can take some fighter who doesn't
make that much money and if he doesn't
have strong ethics and you,
you say to him, Hey man,
look what we want to pay a lot of money
down on you losing by submission to this
dude. Cause you know the odds of
him submitting you are really small.
So what I want to do is set it up so that
you know, he doesn't even have to know.
You just have to give him a submission.
And so they would, you know,
they would tangle and you know,
he would like give up an arm bar or
something like that or give up his neck
shooting on a double,
a real obvious double where he's like
literally lay in there for the gaiety and
let the guy tap you.
That could happen.
I mean it could also happen
because a guy makes a brain fart,
he forgets and he leaves his neck out
there and a dude snatches it up and closes
it on him.
But it could happen that you give your
neck up and guys do give their neck up
sometimes when they want out of a fight.
Chill son is publicly said that he had
some issues with that and his career with
pressure that he'd be in big fights.
He wound up losing by
submission and he's like,
he felt like he gave them the
submission like you wanted out of there.
He left an arm and a
guy caught the arm bar.
Like you really felt like he
just couldn't take the pressure.
I was like a subconscious
thing telling you, you know we,
we talked about that before. About how
there's a gentle complacency in failure.
It's sometimes people will say,
you know what,
I could've done that if I tried harder.
And that's what they always
say as if to say I could have done it.
Like that was a possibility,
but I just didn't try hard enough that
that doesn't make sense for obvious
reasons.
But at the same time,
that eases a lot of the anxiety and the
tension that people feel because it's
like, all right, you know what?
I had a chance to do this and now I don't
have to feel the pressure of dealing
with,
or I've found some measure of success and
that's all I really need to deal with.
I don't care about
anything farther than that.
I got what I wanted to get out
of this game and that's it.
And if I happen to get tons of money,
then fuck it.
Well,
you know,
there's some dudes that can definitely
find a way to lose and they, uh,
the psychological burden of,
of trying to get your shit together and
when sometimes it's too hard for people,
so they almost look to lose to get
it over with. That's, that's real.
Some people can't take, take
pressure. Pressure is a strange thing.
And pressure of not knowing the future,
the anticipation of something happening
and not being able to control it,
especially when it deals
with physical violence. So me
kicking your ass, you know,
some dudes just turtle up, they
turtle up, try to protect themselves,
take a beating and wait for the referee
of pull them off. It's happened before.
And then there's other guys
that we'll never do that.
There's other guys that will fight with
their last fucking breath and they're
just [inaudible] code shit with
it. Just like, Yo, you got to,
you're going to have to drag
me out of here. Yeah. It's
in the nature of some guy.
And then there's some guys
that are just real intelligent.
If they start getting hurt though,
start to happen.
You know like George George Saint Pierre
did that early in his career when he
fought Matt Hughes. Matt Hughes
was, or excuse me, Matt Serra,
Matt Serra was fucking him up and he
was like, Whoa, this is, I got a tap.
It was just getting mounted and pounded
on. He started to happen, didn't you know,
lost his title,
lost his title Matt Serra Cause he was
getting fucking pounded on, but he knew,
he's like,
I am way too hurt.
I'm not getting out of this one and
this dude's going to put me to sleep and
then it's going to be real bad if I
don't tap. Some guys don't do that.
Some guys rather go out, some guys rather
get choked out. They don't tap, you know,
war machine. He's going to be on the
podcast. Wednesday I'd fucking dude,
his last fight, he got caught in a
rear naked choke, decided not to tap,
just went night night and just went,
got choked unconscious.
The referee pulled the guy off
of him. That's what he said, hey,
I'll never got a tap. Like, that's it.
I'm fighting to my last breath and if
he choked me out, he choked me out.
And that, that happens. In fact, his last
opponent that the same thing, war machine,
put him to sleep, got the guy
in the room naked, put them out.
I didn't want to tap,
didn't want to lose.
And that's what happens if this guys
like that and there's guys who just tap,
they go, you got me. And then
they go back to the drawing board.
It's hard to say who's more
intelligent because, uh,
I admire the war machine approach,
but I also admire the guy
who realizes if I tap,
I go back to the gym and
I still have a right arm.
If I don't tap my fucking arm gets
snapped, then I have to go through be,
have they going to put bolts in my arm?
They gonna fucking have this, you know,
put screws in there to
keep torn ligaments,
be fucked for six months at least
it might not ever be the same again.
Even when it heals up.
There's guys that have gotten injuries
where they never came back 100% and
that's just part of the game. That's
part of reality. So it's who's, who's,
who's more intelligent as the guy,
more intelligent that taps
or the guy more intelligent
that says,
you know what man,
I'm going to figure out a way to win
this fight even though I'm in a terrible
situation. And if he makes it then
he's a hero. And if he doesn't,
he goes to sleep.
Well,
most intelligent is probably the guy
who who's bribing him to lose. No,
that's the least intelligent cause that's
like $20 million getting into trouble.
He's going to get, where has he gotten
caught yet during that trip and the UFC,
has anyone got caught?
What did you see?
That Russian snooker player who
got busted for a sneaker and uh,
excuse me,
English,
the Russian Russian organized
crime was a bribing the sneaker,
they call it sneaker snowcat pay.
I was just out there and they
wanted this guy to shots.
They wanted them to miss
shots. Just, you know,
cause he's a really famous
world champion player. And a,
I think it was hurricane
Higgins let's say,
but it was a huge scandal because
they love this sneaker in England.
Yeah. You know, I had a great
time when I was out there. Um, I,
I gotta Say England to me reminds me of
like the same type of enthusiasm that
people had and like the 90s for hip hop
where they're not afraid to boo somebody,
you know, you go, you
didn't go to New York,
they'll get like an obligatory clap.
That's a second one.
It's like this tepid sort of
loose. It's like, it's Kinda like,
you know when your mom made you shake
hands with your brother and you hated each
other, it's like, hey chick hazard your
brother. I fucked this dude. Say Cancer,
your brother, I'm gonna smack you in the
fucking mouth. Like, all right, thank you.
Here you go. I love you bro. Yeah.
That thing where you can't wait.
You know what I mean? But it's
like the people in New York, Yo,
you go to like an underground hip
hop show. When you go to some shit,
they'll sit through an opener that
they hate. This is something I,
not that I love bullying or
something like that and it's just,
it's funny to see people, it'd be
like, I really don't want to be nice.
It'd be nice.
I don't know.
I come from an era where they were like,
get him off the stage. Still exist.
Certain certain shows or like that.
This is a different says some people's
fans that will not tolerate it.
Like I saw someone waiting too
long for someone to be on stage.
I've random fan Joe. He was waiting
for Wu Tang. He jumped on the stage.
It was like get woo Tang on here.
And the the fucking opener was like,
oh hold on man. He goes, no
man, you suck Dick Money.
And I was like God damn yo all that. Just
because I'm trying to entertain y'all.
Why these motherfuckers smoking weed in
her back trying to get this set together.
What kind of Shit? But it
happens all the time, you know?
But in England I just feel like they just
have like a more ruthless approach to
it. Like I've seen people
get booed to fuck off there.
They really are like enthusiastic about
it. You know, I had, I had a great time.
It's just weird because when I walk
around there and I meet people,
they have no idea what I do
if they don't know what I do.
And then I walked into a cab for example,
and this old man was like,
what you do for a living? He said, yeah,
you strike me as a type of
man to be an entertainer,
perhaps a a singer or a rapper.
And I was just like,
I looked at him and I want him
to be like you racist. Fuck.
Like what makes you think that I'm at?
But then I thought about it for a second.
I was like, no, you know, actually
I just teach, you know, Middle Age,
medieval history and the history of
antiquity. And the guy's like, really?
And you know he lied to that. No, no,
no. Cause Cause I, cause I, I've studied,
I studied with her for years.
So I mean I had,
I had a passion for learning about the
past like a few years ago where I really,
really got into it. So technically at some
of the prison programs that I've done,
I've taught, um, the history of antiquity,
like Aye. Aye. Aye. Tell kids like,
all right, the way that you or anybody in
this room will believe in Christianity,
Judaism or Islam.
People used to believe in these
creation mythologies of Sumerian and
Mesopotamian times to give people an
idea and an impression of a world that
exists beyond there where belief
is not put into a concrete form.
This could be someone's belief,
but your belief doesn't necessarily
signify that that's exactly what the world
is. It's just what you believe
the world is. You know,
similar to the way people will flip a
penny in the air and they think, oh man,
it's just 50,
50 and then take the same penny and flick
it across the ground and it's not 50,
50.
It's 80,
20 that it's going to be tails because
the face of Lincoln is a fraction of a
gram heavier than the
actual monument or the back,
or it was on the old copper pennies.
So it would fall to similar to the way,
if you're holding a TV and spinning in
a circle, you're going to fall forward,
not backward.
So that's what a lot of them are getting.
They think they're getting the 50 50
shot from the world, but you're not,
you're getting spun across the table
from the moment you come out the womb.
You know you're going to be in jail here
and then they're going to tell you, oh,
we want to reintroduce you to society.
How are you going to be
reintroduced to society?
It will never part of in the first
place. But back to the point I, this guy,
this guy's like, you
know, Oh, you do? I was,
I going to teach middle aged histories
like antiquity. I was like, sir,
you know what an antiquity is? You know,
Rome, Babylon, Greece, Egypt. He's like,
Oh yeah. So I feel like he's
tested me on this guy's like,
and middle-age English history. You say?
I'm like, yeah, you know, I was like, um,
it's like, whereabouts there? I was
like, you know, Oh, Essex West, Sussex,
Sussex, Kent, east Anglia
Mercia Northumbria,
which was divided in half along with
Strathclyde when the Scottish king decided
to pledge fealty to the British king
and they dial Radia and the rest,
Yo. So the dude's like, oh,
well there you get into that.
So what made you interested in that
nun? She's, and leaned over to him.
And I was like, you know, to be honest,
I was just really tired of motherfuckers
mistaken me for some kind of singer,
actor every time I stepped in some place.
So I wanted to get some
new shit to tell people.
I didn't seem to be totally cool with it.
They got a great sense of humor out there.
I love it. I'm a big fan of England.
I go there, uh, I, to
go there once every year
or so and do stand up there.
That's a very unique crowd.
Very unique crowd over there. Very
smart, very well read. Real cool people.
You know,
they hackle like politely
[inaudible] it's not like
they want to be a dick,
but it's just like haven't paid.
I'll give you the alleyoop if you can
throw it back in my face, I'll take it.
I'll be cool with it like that.
You know what I mean?
A good Haeckel,
but it's like,
it's hard to say what's a good heckle
to somebody because the people that suck
at it are always going to suck at it
and then we were all going to get a good
one this time and now you're
not going to ruin the show.
Some people can be smart and they know
what to say at the right time and it's
funny and other people,
they just ruined the whole thing.
But some people plant hecklers,
don't they? No. Well not
that I know of. Not that I,
they do to work off of a,
I have never known a single comedian to
ever plant someone in the audience and
work off of them if they have,
if I have heard stories of doing it,
it's all been hearsay.
I've never,
never heard of one person that plants a
guy that I think it would be so obvious.
I mean people have had people in the
audience as a part of a gag, right?
They've set things up like as a Jew,
like Brian Holtzman,
you just always have people in
the back of the whole audience.
Ask him about his gay son.
It was like a gag.
It was a bit that he would
do and we would always do.
Tell us about your gay
son and he would go, sir,
there's no need to talk
about that right now.
But since it's been brought up and they
would tell this story about his case,
it's a fake, you know, just a bit.
But we, that would almost be like,
that's like the closest to a plant
in the audience I've ever heard of.
Have you ever heard anybody
planting hecklers? Yeah.
Yeah. I'll think about
it. I've never heard,
I don't know. I definitely not a
single one of my friends ever done it,
but a good heckler will or any good,
bad,
someone that heckles you in the right way
actually gives you fuel as a comedian,
don't they? They, it makes you
to bounce off of stuff, right?
Depends on when they do it,
because they could do it in the middle,
in the middle of the day.
They could do it. I mean,
I've had guys yell something stupid out
with totally the wrong timing and people
pile on them,
smack them in the head.
I've seen violence break out because of
hecklers or people got tired of someone
who keeps yelling shit out. I mean, people
throw in drinks at each other throwing.
I've seen people throw chairs at each
other because of the hecklers from most
part hecklers or cons.
They're just annoying.
Shitheads that need attention and don't
deserve it. I liked, uh, what was I think,
I don't know if he played it the first
time I was here, the Bill Hicks, uh,
response to the hecklers.
Oh my God.
Cause I'm a cop and he goes,
I can, I don't have a cock.
I could yell at performers.
Did I run into people like that?
It,
God bless their hearts and 99% of the
people at the shows that I do are total
soldier supporters.
And then there's like the 1% that they're
just there to just fuck around and
play these stupid little games and
it's like they'll put, I'm like, Yo,
please no flash. And they're like, well,
why not? And I'm just like, listen,
you take one flash photo with
a day that doesn't bother you.
But if I get up 800 of these
fucking things everyday,
I'm going to go blind tomorrow.
And they're like, well,
can you just take mine then instead I was
like, no, you're not understanding me.
You're going to turn the flash
off or you're going to leave. Oh,
well w w w w I'm like, okay, you're drunk.
It's the countdown to when
my first name becomes,
fuck you get this fucker out of here.
Leave.
And the security is
not here to protect me.
They're here to protect the U
for me because when I flip out,
I'm going to snap your neck like
a breadstick for fucking green.
No, this is all violent talk and
I'm not really comfortable with it,
especially in the [inaudible]
story or drunk fan.
Not trying to have a good time though.
You never beat up a fan right now.
I've got too crazy. He never beat
him a van. They got too crazy.
You're fucking lying to you never beat
up a fan. What about another comedian?
No. And that would be to have a comedian.
Never. It doesn't have to go to that.
It's silly
bullshit.
Fucking [inaudible] beat up a kid.
Never beat up a fan.
It wouldn't
do it. This is stupid. I mean, if I'm
fighting someone's defend myself. No,
I don't want,
I'm trying to make is 99% of the people
that come to the shows total down or
totally cool. Damn difference. That
little guy, that would be like,
if you had a 300 person
show to be three assholes,
every 300 persons shall be
three people screaming shit out.
It's more than 99 did
you gotta understand?
Usually those people get kicked out in
the middle of it because I honestly,
hip hop shows, they have a lot of
ejections. Yeah, I'm still getting,
my show's going to get kicked out before
I get on stage, you know, get cold.
There'll be heckling the guys on before
me and the the security of the venue.
We usually get rid of them
before I get up there.
Do you bring your own openness to
this stuff? Yeah, always. Okay.
If you don't and you get stuck
with Shitty Comedians, Matt,
and you get stuck with dudes who
will step on your material too.
That's another thing that like bad comics
will do. Even if they're not stealing,
like say if you've got
a bit about Mike Tyson,
they'll come up with a new bit about Mike
Tyson and just do it right before you
so that the subject is already stale by
the time he gets called stepping on your
material. We call it, we call
it set trippin. Uh, okay.
Like you trip on someone's set,
like you take a piece of what they,
what they did on this set. Like maybe
it won't be exactly the same thing,
but you'll do the same call and response
to the audience again and again.
Or you'll have a verse or a song
about the same kind of thing.
Or you'll give an introduction or a
speech about a song that has the same kind
of connotation that somebody else will,
and then that person,
then the headliner gets
on and we're almost like,
oh well we heard this already with your
kiddos. That was a, that was one man.
See his tricks and say you should do that.
Right before he would bring guys up,
he would do their best bits. Like he
did this, this dude Johnny Sanchez man.
It was a funny dude. He had
this great bit about um, uh,
Iranians po and the been mad at him
for parking in their parking spot and
yelling at him in broken English.
He had this funny bit and men
see they were taping at TV,
show him and see what's hosting and he's
just jacked his bit and did it right
before him.
So this is closing bit
and the dude's doing it right before
he goes up there and he's just like,
he's got no weapons is going up there,
unarmed. He's been not only that,
he's going up there with the,
with the emotional burden at this shithead
just stole a bit right before he goes
on stage and it was a,
that was what he would do.
Like you would see him
at the comedy store,
he would do one of Paul Mooneys bits and
then Moonee would go on later on in the
night and do the same bit
instead of, you know, Mexicans,
he'd be talking about black people.
They would be the same bit.
We already heard this star.
Take the top and take it out and then
put the other thing in there. Yeah. Yeah.
That's a,
that's a very extreme form of
a stepping on your material,
but it happens all the time.
When guys I talked to guys to this day
that are on the road and there'll be the
headline or in the Middle Act
always wants to be the headliner.
They'll want to one day be the headline.
They want to blow the headliner
off the stage. They love talent.
People love saying, Oh, this
guy couldn't follow me. Yeah.
I middled forum in West Virginia and he
couldn't follow me. People love that.
So they'll, they'll fuck with you.
Like you have to bring your own guys.
You want to bring,
you don't want that sort of competitive
sense that backstab you bullshit.
That's no fun.
So then you're really arranging is a
package deal for you and the other people
that also ranging that the people go
on before me are really funny that that
goes without saying.
But the most important part to me,
because the worst thing you want to
do is go on after someone eats it.
When you go on, after someone's
bombing on stage, it's sucks, man.
The crowd isn't a bad mommy
about it. Dude, tell me about it.
They don't want to fucking,
they don't want to believe that they paid
money to see this asshole talk and you
got to do you. You're not coming in. And
also that associated would shoot as if,
oh, you brought this person, show me what
the nose suck. Yeah, they think you suck.
They think, and a lot of comics do
that though, man. They stack the deck.
They'll bring really shitty opening
acts to make them look like a hero.
They come in and rescue it. A lot of
dudes do that. That bring terrible,
terrible opening acts
on purpose or people.
How about people who pay to open up?
Why? No, no, I've never heard of that.
But I know Tony Hinchcliffe.
It's got to be opening up for a dude
and then the dude stopped using him and
started using a guy who
was way worse than him.
And the only thing that made any sense
was that he just thought Tony was too
strong. This, this guys
that do that, man, there's,
there's a few guys that do that
kind of shit. They want them,
they want to make sure they're the
star and then the guy before him,
it doesn't make it hard for them.
The audience thing I was thinking of
by the way, it was, uh, I think, uh,
Andy Kaufman used to do that.
Oh, did it. And that makes sense.
Any Kaufman was more of a
performance art is a showman. Yeah.
I never thought he was a funny
stand up cause he really wasn't.
He was a really funny guy.
He was a great actor.
He was a fascinating character study.
You know,
he did a lot of weird shit like he would,
he would work at Jerry's Deli when
he was on taxi, he was on tax,
he was on a hit sitcom and it would
work as a real busboy at Jerry's Deli.
So he would go to Jerry's Deli and
like wait tables and like clean.
That's probably where he got a lot of
material need to fucking people that are
rambling at some Deli table and some
shitbox place where he's working.
I think it was more of
a performance art piece.
He wanted people to freak out the fact
that this guy who on the biggest hit
television show on in America,
he was working washing tables. I
mean it was, it was, uh, he was like,
he would read books on stage. Like he
would go on stage and play a mighty mouse.
Here I come to save the day over and
over and over again and just stand there
and go here where I can
call them to save the day.
And he would do it for like a half hour.
The He,
it was like performance
art more even than it was.
That does sound like some avant
garde bullshit. If I saw that,
if I paid fucking 24 with my dreams,
God knows what the fuck he was on.
Who's a d.
He did a lot of transcendental meditation.
I know that he was a big TM guy.
He might,
I think he might've actually been clean
and sober and just into really like
heavy meditation,
but he did a lot of crazy shit.
Like the thing he did
wear his wrestling women,
well he would do pro wrestling and get
really slapped down by these guys and get
beat up by these guys. He would challenge
them and then he would wrestle women.
He would like, like say that he was
the Inter gender champion exclusively.
I'll fight any woman in there and they
would all go crazy thinking he was
serious. It was all performance
art, but it was, you know,
in that context it's undeniably genius.
I mean what he did was
incredible stuff because just he,
he always lost by the way,
and he just made everybody angry.
I mean it was a performance,
like if he wanted to,
he's scrawny is fucking all that good.
But if he really wanted to kick
that chick's acids, come on.
She a small woman.
He's letting her be now.
Well I'm not, and that's Bob's a Moodle.
Who's his friend who was a referee?
It's a joke.
Let me get in my concerts. I've learned
a lot about it by just doing it,
but I wanted to,
can we capture the old days of the
carnivals where any before it in the main
room,
wrestlers used to go from town to town
and carnivals and all for $500 to any man
that could last in the ring
with them for three minutes.
So I figured if I could offer a
prize and make it like a contest,
it can get, he gets to like grab women and
like, yeah, he's trying to pin her now.
He's actually pinning it for real.
But I couldn't probably,
well challenge men in the audience
because I'd get beaten. Right. Okay.
Right.
Stronger than me.
So I figured if I challenge women,
there are enough women who are
almost as big or as big as me,
who they would have a
good chance to beat me.
I love that he said that with a straight
face. Joe, what was his alter ego?
His name?
Tony.
Tony Clifton. Clifton. Tony
Clifton. Yeah. Which was
actually, yeah, that was his, uh,
was bombs and mood. It's still
does Tony Clifton, right.
He still puts on like an outfit. Pretends
he's Tony Clifton says Tony Clifton.
It is like a whole cult, cult Deb. A
few, but I believe that he's still alive.
Right? Yeah. People believe crop.
Well, they believe everybody's alive.
Tupacs so I've Kennedy still alive.
I've heard Elvis is still alive.
Nobody late. Bruce Lee. I've
heard that one yet. See, so
did you get in an argument with Tupac
when he was alive back in the day? Well,
we were teenagers. I wouldn't necessarily
call it an reo when argument, you know?
Okay.
So that's a no, Brian,
luckily. And uh, you know,
luckily we talked about it before he
passed, so everything is all good.
That's, that's nice. Yeah.
That's good. That must be an
interesting thing though. No,
dude like that man, you
know? Right. For sure.
That's an interesting thing, right?
Think about it. You know that dude,
and then he vanished one of the
greatest rappers ever. Right.
And then gone and then still,
no one knows who killed him.
That's what's really crazy about it.
One of the most crazy things ever.
Yeah. The, the whole thing, the whole
thing, the biggie thing. Like it's like,
oh, miss and not talking to not be
solved. You know what I mean? Yeah,
yeah. How could it not be solved?
Right. How could it not be solved?
How was it possible?
How's it humanly possible that in
2014 that hasn't been resolved?
And then what you ever read that rolling
stone piece on the whole thing, right.
Find out the rampart guys were all
corrupt us. Fucking crazy, man.
It's, it's an interesting
too that that era of, of rap,
like those were the two prominent
personalities. And both of them died.
Shootouts. You know what a
fucked up situation. Yup.
Like does he know about, yeah,
we're just talking about that. Yeah.
No,
that's crazy man.
To think that you know in the
middle of the Strip in Vegas.
Yeah. Yeah. Especially in Vegas
with all, with all the
surveillance cameras is when
everything was crazy. Yeah.
It's insane. It's insane to
think that no one caught anybody.
No one caught anybody.
Her read something about the guy.
I can't recall the guy's name,
the guy who last year I was
involved with the whole,
he ended up being found in the bear
mountain and he burned them out.
The former police officer,
some kind of way.
There was an intermingling with rampart
and that and that whole situation much
more recent.
He was a police officer after that,
but this without a doubt,
if there was the kind of level of
corruption that rampart it had,
there has to be something left over.
I mean the idea that they cleaned it off,
spic and span and nice and pretty
clean and polished it up and the old no
whatsoever. No having problems.
Now with the sheriff's department,
are they in what way?
Leave Bucca same thing that they have
like an inner culture within the sheriff
and they favored certain police
officers and certain people,
especially with the whole,
since the sheriff controls the
jail systems in California,
so a lot of them are getting,
you know what corruption and
bribery and it happens man.
Ultimate power corrupts just nothing.
There's no way around it. Just basically
Chevrolet Bucca knew about it and
just turn, turn the cheek on it,
you know what I mean? He did the Joe
Paterno basically. I mean, you know,
and the thing is is they,
they caught like a core of them and
they have like what happened is internal
affairs hired an inmate
and he's an informant.
So the enemy was getting cell phones,
drugs.
Oh.
So they actually got an inmate to be yeah.
And basically gave up the sheriff
and they kept finding out.
So they build a whole case it,
you know, a few years about it.
And what they did is the sheriff move
the inmate and they couldn't locate him.
His attorney or his handler
couldn't locate him inside
the jail system. So they,
you know,
the,
if finally the pressure came to sheriff
Lee Baca and he just basically turned
the cheek and it took them for a while,
like they start harassing him.
Like he got really, really serious because
his, his handler couldn't find them.
Like, what do you mean you can't
find them inside the jail system?
Wow. That's interesting man. Yeah,
I think that's going to be real hard
to do their, their whole culture,
the culture of law enforcement is having
to adapt. Yeah. It's a whole different,
it has to adapt because people find
out about shit way quicker today.
It's so easy to spread the news, social
media, camera, camera people like,
I can't imagine all the
abuses motherfuckers got
away with before this camera.
Think about it as the actual phone that
they snuck in and gave to him and he was
sending to inmates was where a lot of
that evidence was coming in front of you.
Cause the phone and he's taking
pictures of everything. Whites. Wow.
It's already inside,
you know?
Well,
you know,
it's gonna be harder and harder for
those motherfuckers to do shit like that.
But if there's any where they're
gonna be able to pull it off,
it is in prison where they can
control people. So, so in every case,
the sale and then, you know,
it was when Joe was locked. Um,
he was telling me crazy story that at
that federal prison where he was at,
they said that there was a scandal
where like the, the guards had,
the female CEO's have been selling
pussy to inmates. That's so common.
It's like four or 5,000 a pounds of,
when we had Victor Conte,
he was the guy who got busted
the ball called scandal.
Remember that with Barry Bonds
and their salaries got steroids.
He was in prison and they were,
they were all banging this, the,
the female guards that female
guards returning tricks. Wow.
That's crazy. I love it.
That's American ingenuity.
You're in the middle of nowhere. You
know, what do those guys need? Pussy.
What'd she have to sell puts? Hey,
let's make a deal. Let's make a deal.
Husband is somewhere like you
were watching her husband.
They probably fucking selling
ass both of them together.
They work in the same institution.
Hey, easy. She was just,
what does that bad am I lying?
Joe's no gay people in jail.
The want a good blow job from
a nice security guy. Oh God,
I'm going to have to frisk you.
They about probably had like a little game
with their play. Keeping it real goes,
what are you going to first? What
are your real goals? Way Wrong.
Don't make me suck it. I'm a, I'm
an officer of the law. You suck it.
Give the guy a fat envelope that
he had been hiding up his ass.
Is that a security is a female
security guard that you have to fuck,
but you know what? You would take it man.
If you were locked up for a long time,
that that's better than
nothing. Sure. Yeah,
so girls who would never be able to
sell pussy on the outside on the inside,
it's a valuable commodity.
Their Miss America text checked out
every too many images in his head.
This was one podcast you could
tell flabbergasted. Shocked.
It's just funny because every time I
turn around you got to get Brian to stop
putting shit up there.
You're like,
that's part of the fun part of the show
is contracting me to understand society
craves conflict.
You can't just have a smooth running show.
You have to have some things.
Brian Interior drunk come and do
the openers for Joe Sometimes. Uh,
he's still alive now. I have it
don't once in a while. All right,
so he does comedy on his own. You
bring, you bring your own openers,
your little homies too. Yeah. Okay. Dues.
Do you set them up like
any hecklers and shit like
that shit would be so obvious,
man. No, it wouldn't do, oh listen.
It wouldn't be a smart thing to do first
of all because it would be fake and
then the, the fake vibe would
get out there somehow or another,
they would sneak through the
fucking button. If it's part of,
show me the performance. If you're not
doing it to get to what you're doing.
It depends on what you're doing.
I mean you can set up something in the
audience where you have like a fake fight
with somebody and the whole thing
is like, yeah, you could do it.
But the way I feel about standup when I,
if I went to see Joey Diaz,
okay,
it was my favorite comedian and if Joey
Diaz had someone go on in the audience
and fake heckle him and he
had all these canned lines,
he threw it that and I
thought it was brilliant.
But then I found out that it was
fake. I would be, I would feel sick.
I'd feel grossed out if I ever did that.
I would feel sick if I ever like tricked
a bunch of people to think that I came
up with a smooth line when when someone
heckles me and I come up with something
on the fly and it nails them and
then they look really stupid.
That's like an art.
There's an art to finding the right
thing to say at the right time.
We were in Ohio,
we had this fucking dude took his shirt
off and he was standing in the crowd
with his shirt off. I mean it was, you
couldn't, you couldn't plant a better guy.
I think I saw that as a video.
The dude was crazy and Brian and I saw
him hours later, like after the show.
I mean I hugged the guy and everything.
I mean he wasn't a violent guy,
but someone decided to like take advantage
of the fact that it was this loud guy
and they'd beat the shit out of him.
We found him when we were getting to
our car like two o'clock in the morning,
we were leaving that steak and
shake. Right. We had eight and we,
we've got to our car and
this dude was fucked up man.
His eyes bloody blood common all over
his fucking, all over his clothes.
He was somebody who just beat the shit
out of him, man for heckling. Yeah.
Well probably this is the guy. Look, you
guys got no shirt on and the audience
with his finger.
Oh Damn Yard.
Hey,
that's that is that guy personified.
It's got no shirt on fucking dues.
I wish we got the video of him
fucked up later in the night.
We should do like a bloody pulp
because it would have been so perfect.
The perfect way to end that video.
Somebody who gets tuned him up,
it was a free shot because he was so
drunk they could take advantage of it.
You guys got to leave. We've got
to wrap this thing up. Anyway,
we're running up the top five,
10 minutes.
I wanted to ask you one thing before
we go. We only have five minutes left,
but um, you, you were,
you specialized like in ancient
history and you're, you're,
you're really a big fan
of like ancient cultures.
Have you paid attention to any of this
go Beckley Tepi Shit that they're finding
in Turkey? What the, the arc? No,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. Go.
Beckley Tapi is a new
structure that they found.
It was like a cattle herder
or something like that.
Found this stone and uncovered it,
like kicked some dirt around on it and
then started digging around it and they
realize it's massive.
Called in some people,
they found out that the whole area had
been filled with dirt on purpose at the
very earliest 12,000 years ago.
Right?
So it's at least 12,000 years old
and that's when it was fully covered.
That's one was filled in and it's this
huge gigantic structure because I think a
Iran, all these look like there's some
images of what they've discovered so far.
Why are fucking images loading so slow?
What is it,
1990 it's just a fucking
geo cities website.
There's um, gigantic, 19 foot
tall stone columns, the, all the,
all these reliefs, three d reliefs of
these animals that are drawn on it.
But this whole thing throws
the origins or the, the,
the dates of civilization into a,
a kind of a chaotic situation
because it's so old.
It's at a time where they thought
people would just basically hunter and
gatherers and these hundred gathers,
created these enormous stone
structures is really complex thing.
Like all his carvings on it.
And these are three d reliefs,
meaning that they took the stone away,
they cut it away to make this image.
They didn't carve it into this stone,
which would be the easy way to do it.
They carved the stone out and left
the three dimensional image of these,
you know, animals and they've
only uncovered 5% of it so far,
and it's fucking enormous, enormous
stone structure that was covered up.
So they know for a fact that, and this
is in central Turkey, it's in, uh,
it's an area called Gold Beckley,
Beckley, Tempe. I don't know. Um, I don't,
I know that the,
it was,
there was a civilization called the
Hittites that lived in central Turkey and
they had this site Hook Tusha.
And what I think is interesting about
that is that it was totally in it,
miles and miles away from water.
In other words,
most of these civilizations take place
near some sort of river near some sort of
stream.
But the ironic thing about this,
civilizations existed for thousands of
years in Turkey and yet there was no
water that was physically
near it.
There was like 50 miles away.
So you're going to tell me every single
day someone rode 50 miles to get water.
And they were saying what was going on
was probably that there was an internal
spring that allowed for there to be
water inside a city for it to flourish to
the level it did. Could be, they
also had an irrigation back then too.
Well that is one, one suggestion,
but they didn't have an aqueduct.
The similar to the way
people look at them in,
in Roman times and I guess they may
have diverted water through a stream or,
or by damming a river.
But whatever the case may be is I think
people are going to start finding more
and more of these things
as time progresses.
And I think what we're talking
about also is that, uh,
not just on land but also on,
see, you know what I mean? In,
in the seat when you go underwater.
People found recently that there were, uh,
ancient Egyptian civilizations are people
in the Middle Eastern Mediterranean,
but it existed for like three,
4,000 years that have been buried because
in reality there were probably plenty
of places that were above sea level,
you know, 10,000 years ago. Oh,
no question about it. The, the, the,
the tide or rather the ocean's levels
have risen and fallen fruit. No doubt,
no doubt, no question.
You know, but besides rap,
I started writing a book
recently and then one of them,
I'm specifically going to be able to deal
with this specific fact and, and the,
the history of humankind that is
severely underwritten. I mean,
this is what you're writing a history
book and that wouldn't say what's not a
history book.
It's more like a book of philosophy.
It's more like a book of philosophies,
you know what I mean?
And it's a little humorous, you know
what I mean? It couldn't, cause I, I,
I want to show people the
sort of perpetual hypocrisy
that we're willing to live
in, that people have always lived
in some ways. I mean, there were,
but not only that we live in, but that
we're willing to live in. You know, it's,
it reminds me of a quote from Mark
Twain where he's like, you know,
the difference between writing fiction
and writing reality is that you have to
make reality seem believable.
You know,
because it's so preposterous that you
have to include some sort of element that
brings it home,
similar to the way that a comedian will
criticize society and then talk about
how fucked up it is. And at the end
of it say, Hey, well guess what?
I'm just as fucked.
And you know how I know it's this fucking
bad because I'm part of this fucked up
society. And that's the ironic part of the
joke, cause that, you know what I mean?
Oh No, no, no, no. I'm the coca sub
and I'm going to go get a coke now.
So fuck all the rest of you
because that's just how it is.
I think that when you look at
civilizations in the human development,
you find just a series of,
of,
of pure savagery and then you
find a nobleman and strange and,
and almost irreconcilable
places within that society.
So when I look at them over
the course of human evolution,
I really wanted to address that.
And the fact that, you know, yes,
we're a civilization of talking monkeys
that have achieved some sort of growth
over the years, whether it's through
grooming because we place a gigantic,
uh, we place a gigantic amount
of value on how were groomed.
We placed a gigantic amount of value
on our superstitions. In other words,
if I believe something and you
don't believe the same thing,
I'm threatened by your belief system,
not you or me specifically,
but in terms of how we communicate and
how we've communicated over the years.
Now,
has that always been a positive thing
or has it always been a negative thing?
Well,
when we were dividing ourselves among
different actual races like homo erectus
or Homo Habilis,
then maybe it was a positive thing to
not include these people in our society
because,
or these animals are hominids
in our society because it
wouldn't created a bunch
of different strand of humanity.
Dude, you need a podcast of your own
shit. Run out of time, man.
The mortal technique podcast,
launching next month. Oh,
you should just start with an
iPhone. Start talking. Anyway,
when we were at an airport, I got
that shit. The middle passage.
Shout to the whole rebel ohms. Follow
him. A mortal tech on Twitter and guys,
what are your Twitter Twitter
handles at Twitter? Hold on.
Spell that. What is Bobby B? B
obby bout it. B O, u t I t bone,
twitter.com boom. At Chino XL at
Twitter, at [inaudible] Instagram.
Thank you very much.
Lift the state apparel.com
thanks to legal zoom.com.
Use the codeword Rogan at checkout.
Save yourself some cash.
Thanks also to 1-800-FLOWERS.
That's one 800 full hours.
Uh,
thank you to a on it.
Use the Codeword Rogan and save 10%
off any and all supplements. All right,
we will see you tomorrow with
a artists, Molly crab, apple.
And then we have on Wednesday war
machine and Thursday, Joey Coco Diaz.
Much love. See You
fuckers soon. Let's do it.