No Joe Rogan now what were you gonna say?
I'm not telling you that lead
or is going to beat Jon Jones,
but something,
something's going to happen.
Something you think if
anybody could do it.
Um,
we talked about [inaudible] been around
a long time and he's had a couple of
them,
but everybody loses to Anderson
Silva find the shame that I have,
but I was thinking about it the other
day and I watch the count down and watch
the interview and I'm like,
you know,
I'm not saying he's
going to beat Jon Jones,
but I probably experiences
on motherfucker.
It is a motherfucker.
The Joe Rogan experience
podcast is brought to you by
[inaudible] dot com if you
go to o,
n n I t get yourself some Alpha brain.
You can give me some music.
What is Alpha brain?
Joe Alpha brain is a cognitive
enhancing supplement.
It's a fucking vitamins for your dome son.
We have all sorts of other shit on it.
All of it is like the best high end
nutritional supplements we can sell.
The best stuff we could sell at the
best prices we can afford with the best
setup order,
the first 30 pills,
you have a 100% money back guarantee.
You don't even have to return
the product if you don't like it.
That's how confident we are that we're
selling you good shit and they're going
to want to keep buying it.
A nutrition is the most important
thing before supplements.
Get your fucking nutrition streets on.
Don't try to beat and cheeseburgers and
take Alpha brain and think it's called
going to balance itself out.
If you want to be healthy,
you got to eat healthy food.
That's number one.
Number two,
get your fucking body in order,
son.
Just drop a little body fat.
Get dropped.
You're working heart resting heart rate.
You gotta be in shape a little bit,
at least a little,
and then start fucking
around with vitamins.
But uh,
get off your ass.
Get 30 pitch.
Go to [inaudible] Dot Com
k sell some kettle bells.
Be All manly as fuck,
right?
Joe Diaz,
some battle ropes,
right?
Cock suckers,
some hemp protein powder.
You fucking freak bitches.
I didn't get the hemp.
You as a good,
oh,
it's delicious.
Oh,
it's the best tasting stuff ever.
What's its flavor it with Stevia?
So it was no sugar in it.
It's like we'll only one gram of sugar.
It's a raw cocoa.
It's a Maca,
which is like something's supposed to,
it's supposed to enhance your sexuality,
supposed to fire you up.
I don't know if it works.
Uh,
and then,
um,
there's a,
the Stevia,
Stevia is used as the sweetener
for the show hemp chocolate,
chocolate,
and it's the finest quality
hemp hearts available.
We just went and got the best shit and
we could only buy 50 pounds of it a day.
It's Kinda crazy.
We can't grow it in America.
It's not,
you can't get high on it.
You can't test positive.
Like people say if,
um,
what if I get tested for work?
You cannot test positive,
but oddly enough,
if you eat poppy seed bagels,
you do test positive for heroin.
It's kind of crazy halfway house.
They tell you that.
Yeah.
You can not eat poppy seed bagels,
but you can take hemp protein powder.
It doesn't,
it's not,
there's no THC in it,
but it's illegal to grow anyway.
It's our government's way
of fucking you in the ass.
If you're a farmer,
it's a great crop and we have
to buy it from Canadians.
It's fucking ridiculous.
It has nothing to do with marijuana.
It's completely non you.
Uh,
you eat it.
It's healthy.
It's a,
it's got a lot of protein in.
It contains the essential amino acids.
It's a great fiber for
making clothes with,
and he can go on and on and on about the,
the benefits of industrial hemp,
hemp as a commodity.
But there's a,
there's some creepy shit going on that,
that's illegal because it makes no sense.
It doesn't have anything to do.
Even a little bit has nothing
to do with getting high.
It's a,
it's a really fucking creepy racket,
but it's one that this government
is all caught up in your fucks.
Anyway,
go to [inaudible] dot com go to
the death squad teeth pickup.
Um,
some,
some delicious cat tee shirts.
Death Squad.
Dot.
TV.
There's the new one that the uh,
the dope ass.
What?
I called the hip now cat.
Cause I believe he's hypnotizing me
when I stare at that little creepy fuck.
It's a very creepy kind of love.
That cat is Hitler stash or is chaplain
staffs has been removed and it's at
Penthouse keyhole save.
You have a penthouse key.
You can open it.
Oh really?
Is that what it is?
Well,
his just his hip.
No ring in the center.
Freaks me the fuck out.
That's a creepy cat.
How high were you in when
you came up with that one?
Pretty high.
Pretty High,
right?
You'd have to be anyway.
Death Squad.
Dot TV.
Go check it out.
And uh,
that's it.
Joe Diaz is here.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Billy Corbin canceled on us.
The laser represents
experience trying by day.
Joe Rogan podcast.
Powerful Joe.
Damn.
What's up?
Beautiful.
Hey,
we got a good podcast with Mac Danzig
and we're waiting for Billy Corbin,
who was the,
uh,
director of cocaine cowboys.
And then I looked down at my phone.
He had been telling me
that he had to cancel.
So you were close by.
He said,
fuck it,
let's drop in any way.
Bummed out that I was getting on the one
34 when he called the first time and I
just gotten the right hand lane right.
And I just did 65 like
the rest of the civilians.
When you called back,
I wasn't on forest lawn and I fucking
kick that into that Hov lane and I had
sons of anarchy behind Matt,
this black bike about him.
So I knew what the cops are going to pull
anybody that he was going down first.
He was my beer.
I got in front of him in the Hov Lane
and I just shot that motherfucker.
Hell bent for free all the way
till you called me and said,
Nah,
we're going to,
and I said,
hold on.
I'm back in the Hov lane and I went
through cars and there was an unmarked
police car and the right hand lane.
He didn't even see me.
I just slipped right back behind him.
I took my time after that.
He just,
it's 65 like a fucking sat.
Yeah.
That's like a thing that we do out here.
He was like your roll
the dice in the Hov Lane,
400 400 bucks,
64 60 and if you call
it a licensing point,
like when I go for it,
I go for,
I go for the nine 20th package.
Most of the 920 hour package that
she go over the line and you find,
because you can only cut into Hov
where the lines say you're permitted.
So I do the nine 60 package,
which nine pointy in court
altogether court costs.
You got to drop a hundred for
the victim compensation fund,
another hundred from the deaf
kids from Chinese society.
You're going to run into a by
16 halala about minivans and
fucking southern California.
That makes them think they
should be in the left lane.
Kills you people anywhere in
this great country of laws.
When you drive in,
there's somebody doing 65 and the
left hand get out of your way,
get out of your way.
Only in California,
they'll sit there and fucking
tore menu and they'll,
they'll give you the finger like they
don't think that they should have to move.
It's something that never made it
out here and back where I grew up,
the,
the highways were more narrow.
Like there was a lot of two lane
highways so it was just good,
good citizenship.
You know,
getting out of the lane,
there was only two lanes.
So if you're in the left lane,
you're trying to go fast.
If you're in the right lane,
you're going slow.
But these douchebags have
this wealth of lanes,
you know,
they,
they have six,
seven,
eight lanes.
So you can go run me,
we'll just go around me.
Why don't you just not
be in the fast lane,
you twat lane number two and do 65
minimum yield going 60 miles an hour in a
minivan.
And you're mad that people don't,
don't want you in their way.
That's ridiculous.
You don't have to be in the left lane.
That's for passing people.
You stupid.
Fuck.
And the worst is like a,
when I go up north,
I'm like,
when you go up north and the one
on one after you pass a certain,
it's beautiful.
It opens right to fuck up.
It's beautiful driving and he,
you are doing fucking Haiti.
You're on cruise.
You got the Eagle's Hotel California
and you get behind the fucking seven 50
that's doing 65 and that's
when you start to burn.
I'm thinking to myself,
for starters,
he's a Jew driving a German car.
I'll confused this.
Cox,
Cox mother fuckers got no loyalty Shit,
right?
That's number one.
Number two.
Number two,
he's doing 65 [inaudible] seven cards
because the only reason I would buy a
seven series if when a cop pulls me
over back to rip the ticket in his face,
all my attorney,
that's the only way I would drive a
seven if I could do 90 all the time,
Joe.
It's not,
I don't see the beauty in it.
I don't see it.
Unless you're going to do 90 then it's
okay to give me this like a seven series,
five dose.
You should shoot yourself.
That's a Toyota fucking Corolla.
You just paid more.
You want to impress people,
you know after your dope dude,
you're talking about
this three series BMW.
I have an m three nine but you have
an m three I say fucking difference.
It's a beautiful,
I love that.
But the people that get to
three holding onto that,
I'm famous to cars.
Joe Has a three fucking
thing that drives brilliant,
but there's some people can't afford
the three that ghetto basically good for
fucking Lexis fucking rx.
A smaller one than that.
They haven't.
Why?
They were tiny one and they have an I am.
It's just like tiny little buzz mo mobile.
But it looks like a fact that
you all told me that in push.
Yeah,
the one that,
how much of that porch grow wholesale
rethink a hundred he's got a 900 901 which
is the newest generation.
It's more than a hundred okay.
That's a Carrera.
So he might be able to get that one for
less than a hundred it's not the career
ass.
You pull me all with
that car and I'm like,
yes,
sure officer.
Do you know how fast she was doing?
It doesn't matter because
this is how I do it.
What license?
I don't have what we ended up picking.
You rip it up.
You give it to them.
You give them the name
of your fucking attorney.
He's got a Yamaka on it
with a stock going to it.
Here you
go.
Call Him in 10 minutes.
I'll tell you what the shooting
star coming out of the picture.
Jesus bleeding on the floor and shit.
Hit.
Remember that?
All right,
got stuck.
Take this cock sucker.
You're going to pull me off with
doing 90 I'm in northern California.
You know when you get up
here it's beautiful to drive.
You can't know six in the
morning and do your thing.
Yeah,
but that area is filled
with cops waiting the bag.
I've seen it and I got pulled over one
night on the one 30 cause there's pilots.
When you're coming from the one old one
noise where it becomes hilly and you get
caught up on those
motherfucking hills late night,
you got the music on,
you're listening to the radio,
whatever.
You're on the phone with your buddies.
When you go over that hill,
look at you.
It's predominant.
Yeah.
You're doing 90 yeah,
by mistake.
You know really you're doing
90 they come right behind you.
Yeah.
There's a lot of spots where they wait.
We ride to San Francisco was fucking
parking ticket central driving,
speeding ticket central
and you got to really,
you got to stick to the law
of the vagueness around La.
That's the one leniency we have.
There's not that many cops was ticket city
bold.
Really?
I'm Connie.
I'm a fucking hippie loving cock suckers.
Not Though the cops in bold the had this
thing by a and they were telling me the
statistic once.
It was like one of the highest
on the Nash National Average.
This isn't the 80s right.
But I'm that one Irish Irish
takes you into Longmont.
Okay.
On Irish in between,
uh,
28th and 30th street.
They would now more people.
It was like a Nashville.
They just sit there by the mental health
center and they get you on that 20 with
the blinking light.
35 cause if you ain't used to that,
you don't know what's cracking.
Right.
So you don't even see that 35 you're
doing 35 watts and you see plenty.
Bam.
That's how they get you right there.
Boom.
I got,
I got nailed on that 35
20 that's really cool.
And I went to court,
they told me in court they're like,
oh you fell for the fucking,
they have a name for it
and boulder at the time,
the alley,
that's where they
just,
so it's a setup.
It's,
it's,
it's almost like the,
the transition is so quick.
It's designed just to give you a ticket
or else I just was at with it.
They said be careful because
the transition Nashville,
when you're going from Nashville,
Chattanooga,
we were talking one day and they go dog,
they kill motherfuckers.
There really is,
it goes from 75 to 60 within a
minute and you don't see in the cops.
It's right there.
Hey man,
you got to get through.
No,
for the states and towns,
there's a much more of a police state in
other places than there is here when it
comes to that,
when it comes to speeding
and shit like that.
Like I remember in Connecticut,
like Connecticut state troopers
were brutal because they all,
they had to do that everyday.
They're just pulling people over.
That's what they're looking for.
That's their number one crime.
They're just trying to pull people
over and write them tickets as much as
possible.
They become glorified revenue collectors.
It's really rich,
especially rich white
people in the rich areas.
They just,
they don't give a fuck and just sit there.
It's crazy.
The cops actually have a quota that
they have to make and it's been exposed
like,
uh,
the,
they were,
they were offering price.
It was in California.
There was some something
that we're offering,
you know,
officers something more.
If they got more rests.
It was,
it was proven that
they've got more tickets,
that they would get some benefit from it.
But you know,
you're not allowed to do that
because would have nobody drives.
Nobody speeds at all and you
have to write 10 tickets a day,
but what if everybody's,
we're assuming that everyone's
going to break the law,
and if that's not the case that you
don't have a job because that's your job
basically,
every day you're going out
there and you're parking,
you're waiting for people
to go by and speed.
Well,
if nobody speeds anymore,
everybody just quits.
How do you make that
10 ticketed day quota?
We'll get don't.
Well,
what the fuck happens then?
What happens in you pull
over people for bullshit,
the fake tickets.
I mean,
is it possible that we can get to a point
where nobody's doing anything illegal
anymore and we don't need traffic cops?
If that happens,
the fuck are they going
to do with all that?
What they need,
that money,
they've got that built into the budget.
The amount of tickets they get,
they build that into the budget.
They know it's coming in.
They know,
well,
we get it.
You know,
I don't know.
I don't have to pay the tickets awake.
Sally does have those.
That's $100,000 for this
common ala is brutal.
It's crazy.
That's why I'm in La.
I see like budgets.
They talk about how they're,
they go shut down the system for three
days a week and four days a week that
they're out of money.
I just go to Hollywood and look around.
That's a moneymaking machine and Hollywood
and they got those black chicks or
the angry angry sisters driving them
ticket motherfucking cause those angry
hangry sisters that
left her with four kids.
She got rickets,
you know,
Shit like that.
I mean these sisters are beautiful
and they're driving around dog.
I had it.
I had a car in Hollywood that was
given to me and they never gave me the
registration and the registration
expired and they would hunt me down.
Did you know that really it would just
drive around and give me a ticket every
day just on spike for the registration.
They make that motherfucking
quoted that way.
Let me tell you something.
In La,
the biggest thing when you move to
Hollywood is your first 90 days you get
banged up.
I got my,
I got Stan hoax car towed
him one night by mistake.
Really parked it by on sunset.
I mean it's fucking ridiculous down there.
They will destroy you.
It feels like the kind of have
to be on top of everything.
No,
there's so many people there
and there's so many dirt bags.
Oh my God.
They have people living in Hollywood,
like the percentage,
like there's a lot of
Nice people in Hollywood.
I know know a lot of like
really normal people.
Folks would be surprised
when you meet like folks,
people who actually live in West Hollywood
and have like a little house in West
Hollywood.
I met some really wonderful,
nice people there,
but there's also a giant percentage
of crazy fucks in that city.
There's a lot of them,
young kids,
they move here after college.
Their parents give them a credit card,
go out there,
you know whatever you do till
the credit cards over though.
We've seen at the store how many people
come and go with just having this
conversation this morning at breakfast,
how many people went,
came at,
had seven great minutes,
went to Montreal,
got a deal for a quarter of a Mil,
fucking late nineties two
thousands and once
they'd fucking got down,
they went to the Improv.
They got sandwiched in between Joe Rogan
and Nick Dipaolo one night and they
realize how bad they
really were and they said,
you know what,
I'm going to go back and re run daddy's
fucking transmission shop because the
work,
and I've seen it,
how many people came and went to this?
You've been here people that
we're going to be stars.
Yeah,
there was a lot of that.
That's definitely happened.
I think it's easy to lose your,
your way,
lose your,
your intention.
It's easy to,
it's easy to just fucking get
caught up in the fear of it all.
You know,
the uncertainty of it all and
just get swept away in it,
which that happens a lot of people,
man.
A lot of people,
they just can't ever
build any momentum up.
The can't ever build any success up there.
Always just slipping
around that just can't,
it can't get control.
And so then they just quit.
It's too much stress.
It's too much pressure,
you know?
Yeah,
she does.
I mean,
we've been here,
I've been here trying,
swinging.
You know,
AAA has been his swing and trying,
you know,
I mean,
it's really weird that I just
never seen just given up.
I always felt like a lot of times I go
to auditions and I see people that would,
were at the store with me doing
spots now running the camera.
I don't want addition people
that I knew was actors years ago,
running cameras and commercial audition.
Right.
And when I'm walking out though,
chase me,
how's it going?
Yeah.
I started doing this.
I really want to direct commercials and
as I'm getting into my car and I'm like,
they never really knew what they
wanted to do in the first place.
They didn't really want to sink that Ti.
If I came to you one day and said,
uh,
you know,
I'm going to become a fucking writer,
I'm going to become a director.
You like Joe,
wait,
what the fuck?
Yeah,
no
think I would say that.
You know why Ron Howard?
No,
no,
no.
You don't understand what
trying to say to you,
but there's a lot of people
that in the middle of the game,
they changed.
Ron Howard was an accident.
I've got a couple of years in this.
It's not like you come in here and there's
a lot of people have gotten here and
said,
fuck it.
I'm not going to do,
I know I bumped into standards.
Where's wild?
Willy Parsons wears a lot of what?
Judy Turner was.
A lot of these people that,
you know,
we're working for a long time.
She knew that was huge and he
told him he was still working.
By the way,
it shouldn't go does a movie here that,
but I shouldn't have said Judy.
She just came to my mind was this little
just trying to come up at the store a
lot of years.
You know a lot of those guys,
you just don't,
in my book,
you just never stopped being a stand up.
Yeah.
I don't know.
Well,
it's
just the pressure of performing is,
is different.
I think the pressure perform for you
and I is we that we enjoy it because we
know that we're putting in the work and
we want to go up there and give you a
good show.
We want to go up there
and give you some fun.
It's fun for us.
It's fun for you.
We want to do it.
But for some folks they
just become more private.
They don't want to deal
with the criticism.
They don't want to deal with
the critiquing of their work.
They don't want to have the stress
of it and they'd rather get a job.
Like as a writer,
that happens to a lot of guys.
They just decided no one to
stand up performing thing.
It's just too fucking harsh.
You know?
It's,
I would rather get a job as a writer.
It's easier,
it's more relaxing and then some
of them come back and forth.
You know,
the beauty of is that if
you really think about it,
the part of this job is
the nucleus is the writing.
Yeah.
So they're not really stray.
No hint changes.
Completely fucking different.
Like I'm a producer now what?
Ah,
what the fuck?
She's a weird part.
The director kind of makes sense,
right?
Because that's more of a creative,
much more creative thing or an editor
or something along those lines.
But yeah,
producer,
well maybe they don't
like the performing part.
Maybe,
you know,
maybe they don't like the artistic part,
but they really love movies.
I don't know man.
Everybody's got their own fucking path.
But for me,
I think for you and I,
there was only standup,
we weren't going to be anything else.
We were always going to be standing up.
And we,
we know that too.
When like when we were running into,
someone will know if a guy's a real,
I'll call you about this guy.
I'll say,
hey man,
have you seen blah,
blah,
blah.
He's fucking real.
That guy's rail,
that guy's real,
very funny guy.
And you know what I mean?
It's like there's a few,
there's,
there's not that many.
There's like,
this may be a thousand professional
comedians in this country.
If you really stop and think about it,
people that make a
living by telling jokes,
is there even a thousand?
Let's be conservative and
say there's a thousand.
And for those,
how many of them are like national,
like touring headliners is like,
it was like 300 maybe two
5,300 something like that.
It's not that many people like that man.
And it's because not
everybody's supposed to do it.
We don't,
the world doesn't need more
than 300 good standup comedians.
Okay.
Them enough is enough.
Crazy assholes talking,
talking shit and a,
and making people laugh.
That's like plenty.
W the,
the,
the vast majority of people will never
be a professional stand up comedian and
they shouldn't be.
They have something else.
They,
they,
this is just a step on the way to them,
just finding themselves in some other way.
But for you and I,
it was always,
it was like I,
you know,
I was on news radio and one
time the producer said to me,
why are you doing this?
Why are you still doing standup?
You're an actor now.
And I was like,
Oh my God,
I'm ready to quit right now.
I was like,
are you crazy?
Like you don't get it.
You know,
you can't possibly understand how
much different it is to be on a set,
repeating brilliant words
and someone else wrote,
you know,
in front of a bunch of,
other folks are doing the same thing and
you're doing it in front of an audience
that has to see the same
scene over and over again.
And then you get to watch it
and people enjoy it and this,
there's satisfaction in that.
But it can't fuck with stand up.
My God,
it can't fuck with stand up.
Bass quote I've heard the
last six months is by a boy.
Vinny Credo.
What'd he say?
He goes general one at this.
They got a second chance.
They get cut standups.
There ain't no cut motherfucker.
I mean for Vinny kernel to
say that I got goosebumps.
My whole body goes,
well,
we were having coffee one day
and he's talking about comedic.
These guys supposed to
be comedic actors get,
I'm in a fucking audition room.
They die.
People just laugh as a courtesy.
Hey,
who did I fight in 1964
because it looks sad.
He'll forget who the fuck talking about.
You know what
I'm saying?
And then he went right back
to that beautiful statement.
Yeah.
And he goes,
all I know is I've been in plenty of
rooms with these comedic actors from
television show,
and once they hit cut that
fucking in heaven standups,
we don't hear cut.
I was like,
Damn Vinnie,
colonel droplet like a bad motherfucker.
There's a,
there's certainly an art to acting.
No doubt about it.
Definitely.
But it's definitely,
there's,
there's also the,
the,
the real thing about auditions
is that's not normal.
You're,
you're pretending you're
sitting down at a desk,
the guys holding a piece of paper and
you've got to pretend that this is a real,
it's a real scene.
You've got to pretend
it's really happening.
I mean you're pretending you're
in a different environment,
you're pretending everything.
If you're in the movie,
unless you're doing some crazy fucking
CGI screen where everything behind you is
a green screen,
you're actually like in Brooklyn,
you're actually in front of the house.
You're actually pointing
the fake gun at the guy.
I mean,
there's a lot of shit going on that
would lead you to be better prepared to
pretend that you're actually in the
scene than being in a conference room and
there's some guy who's
reading like reading,
like tell us where you put the money
or you're going to be in big fucking
trouble.
Like that's how the guy reads it to you
and he's supposed to go blood money guy.
What am I supposed to be real?
Come on.
It's like ridiculous.
It's so fake that if for you
to be real in that audition,
you almost have,
you almost have to be fucking crazy
for you to be real in that wacky ass
audition room.
I mean that's that dude just
not wearing a viking outfit.
How were you pretending
you were on a boat?
You're just doing it.
You're just pretending it's some of the
silliest shit ever wants to be there.
They should take like,
uh,
auditions that they filmed
that were like super silly.
It preposterous,
especially for like B movies where they're
like got their cousins and I know I
do to Preuss is on moving and he brought
all his friends in that don't act at
all and they all played parts.
That's how to do that.
All the best movies because they
don't know what the fuck's going on.
They don't know what the fuck's going on.
It's the guy that comes in and goes,
made me,
me,
me again.
Oh my God.
You know,
it's like I trained at Juilliard.
What's his name?
What's the guy trained
doctor for the last month.
Boogie nights has been on
HBO every fucking nights.
Every night.
And you got to watch the movie.
It's a great movie.
But who's the guy in that?
The crazy guy tries to make out with
market Walberg he's in a bunch of movies
now.
Uh,
see Riley's not the guy from
stepbrothers name with the blonde hair.
He's kind of Chubby and shit.
He's got a bunch of those.
Nelson Riley.
Well you can't,
you can't have a salt like Denzel and him.
You can't have a cell phone on set.
Can have a cell phone and said,
well that's smart man cell.
Here's a test cell phone.
Paul Thomas Anderson.
No,
that's director.
If there's 10 zero,
he is a cell phone.
He abandoned ship really cannot focus on,
well you know,
in like when everybody got mad at 'em,
uh,
Batman.
Remember when he screamed at some
guy for walking in front of a shot?
John C.
Reilly Jonsi right now that's the,
that's the crazy
dummy.
William H Macy.
No,
that's the guy that shot himself.
Nina Hartley.
Where's boy?
He played a camera guy.
Boom.
But he's always,
he tries to make out with him in
1980 and she buys the corvette.
You sure he's in Boogie nights.
Yeah.
How's this possible?
Oh,
Phillip Seymour Hoffman.
Jesus Christ.
Like that guy.
Remember that guy's name?
I love that guy.
I'm going to throw your mover.
He's really good dog.
He plays himself.
I,
it's like a dick in that
movie with Jennifer Aniston.
And,
uh,
he,
he plays the kid's friend like a washed
up back to their lives in New York and
he's the leaving and
Jesus Christ superstar.
But he really,
I mean,
yeah.
Yeah.
Have you seen that Jennifer Aniston may
time frame and should I watch it one
time?
Terrible.
But he's never bad in anything grazing.
He's good and fucking boogie nights.
But last week they were
saying that there was a,
an award show and I'm like,
uh,
and Venice and he showed up with a stained
shirt who's had was fucked up and he
had been on the couch.
And it's amazing how those guys act
because they don't want to act like,
let me,
let me tell you that I don't care,
but I really care.
He was in the big Lebowski to fuck.
Yeah Bro.
That dude's spending a bunch
of things really good shit.
He's the real deal.
This new movie,
they say he's really good as new movie.
It's good and that's going
to win an award this year.
They stay.
Thank God the master or something.
It looks like his other movie too though,
doesn't it?
Where he played like the president or
he convinces somebody or something crazy.
Played like the president.
Who did he play?
What movie was that?
He played,
he,
it came out recently.
It wasn't the president.
It was somebody famous that he played.
Uh,
but he's a new movie.
It looks like that movie.
Well,
he was in the ides of March.
That was the,
uh,
the most famous,
I think,
recent movie.
You sure are.
You sure you're confusing
him with somebody else?
What's his name again?
Phillip Seymour Hoffman.
How dare you.
Jesus Christ.
He was in money ball.
I just got movies.
Good.
Moneyball.
He's going to be in right.
He's really good.
What's that?
What's his newest movie?
Uh,
the newest one is a late quartet.
No,
under that.
The master,
the master is the one they say is bad ass.
Really?
It's kind of weird,
but he's really good.
It's like a,
he convinces somebody to join Scientology.
I don't fucking,
he's a beast.
He's a,
he's a great actor.
He's a [inaudible].
He played a Truman Capote's is,
those motherfuckers really do
go on doing their own sense,
you know,
that's their strength.
They,
they,
you know,
they take it to the next
limit like that to watch it.
The only guy seen in a room that
fucks it up in a room like that.
I seen two motherfuckers fucking diploma.
I'm going to table.
They are who?
Christopher Walken.
But one of the baddest motherfuckers
that was on his tail was Phil apartment.
Oh yeah,
he can audition.
He was a such a professional bill Hartman
and could light up a room by himself
though.
That's a real gift.
Not too many.
When people clap on the scene when do a
movie scene and at the end when they go
cut and the motherfuckers are like,
yeah,
like what the fuck did we just see?
You know when they were saying when the,
when they did a,
I went one day on the Adam Sandler
when Christopher Walken was there,
but there was saying when I got there
the days early that when that mother
fucker does this scene,
he locks you in on the set.
Like I'm the set that people are like,
like you have to look
at the person to cut,
cut,
cut.
And they're like,
oh fuck.
That's how much he locks you
in like he used and probe.
When you watch that movie
where he shoots himself,
you know deedee mile and be a hunter.
I was watching that about two months ago.
He was brilliant.
He locked me out.
Oh,
he's playing the fucking guy.
That's all he was.
He was on heroin,
whatever they were giving him and
Vietnam and he was on a game of his,
he made money by playing Russian roulette.
She's,
how do you prepare for that character?
Do you want to tell me?
Do you want to what I think teacher on
Melrose did tell you about that shit.
You think about that
motherfucker and that you know,
he had to come up with that
character from somewhere.
So there was motherfuckers
walking around that said,
you know what?
Fuck my family.
I've already killed 50
fucking donkey Kong's Vietnam.
I killed everybody.
Russians,
French.
I'm just like,
practice killing myself now.
They put that band on,
they do a little bit number two and that
shit was pure over there that it's like
bouncing.
Did you see him in that?
Remember that?
What's his name,
came to get him and he
couldn't get queued them.
They were childhood friends.
He couldn't get through to him,
Bro.
Imagine how deep you are playing that.
That's a scary thinking
that you're going to,
what are you doing today?
I'm going to go shoot pool.
I'm going to go over to him to play
Russian roulette for a few hours.
I said,
Yo,
what the fuck is,
how crazy are the Russians
if they came up with that?
Is that who invented a gas?
It's called Russian roulette.
Brian know anything about it?
I have no idea.
I mean,
is that what it's it?
That's,
that's must be there.
The invention of Russian roulette,
right.
Christopher Walken made a movie
that's not a popular movie.
I mean,
one of his best movies
was the one that he takes.
The acid will move with Natalie Wood.
Isn't there a movie where he
does something altered states?
Who's in that office?
Dates was um,
John hurt.
Yeah.
William hurt.
Julian hurt.
Yeah.
William hurt played the scientists for me.
One of the best times I ever seen
Christopher Walker is a movie called that
close range with Sean Penn.
He played the dad like dad.
He's very good in that very fucking good.
And the movie,
like the week before they
pulled the budget or something.
So the movie never,
Mcdonald's got the soundtrack.
Yeah.
I ran away and was a good movie.
Yes.
That's a very good move.
If you haven't watched that,
people have been hitting me
up for a good movie lately.
Watch at close range.
1985 that was Donna.
You know who don't have
lines in that movie.
You know,
it was going to have a movie like that.
Don't have wines.
Who was a star at 24.
He ain't got a fever.
Heat.
The Sutherland and Crispin
Grover Glover is in that movie.
Uh,
Sean Penn's brother.
I mean,
they're fucking phenomenal.
Yeah.
This is a for not I get fucking movie,
man.
I get goosebumps thinking
about when he tells Sean Penn,
Sean Penn thousand,
I'm,
I'm not going to rob with you know more.
And he's like,
what are you going to do?
You got a girl,
you got rent,
you've got a job,
when are you going to do,
what are you going to
do when you get there?
Fuck you.
And they start getting it out.
He buys a quarter ounce of weed from him
and he shoots the girl and then at the
end,
and Sean Penn comes to his house with
at nine millimeter and then he and he
goes,
freezing motherfucker,
don't even,
spoiler spoiler.
Oh my God,
I'm getting goosebumps.
Just thinking I forgot all about that.
And here's the,
here's the clinker.
I'm like Caroline's,
I'm doing the motherfucking
Toyota comedy festival.
They put me up,
you know,
1255 the show was,
there's nine people,
but I made the festival,
but guess who stayed the
assistant from the Sopranos,
right?
So she comes up to me,
she goes,
are you busy tomorrow?
This is when the Sopranos for a start.
I go in and know and she goes,
would you mind coming to
my office at 11 o'clock?
Somebody wants to meet you.
This is a true story.
I go,
what?
And she goes,
she wrote the paper,
she goes,
here's what you're going to go.
11 o'clock I was headed to
buffalo for $450 as a feature.
Okay?
And she goes,
no,
no.
You got to come to my office tomorrow.
So I go to this place,
it's on 48th street,
up the block from Roger Paul's Office,
and I'm sitting out front
and a blind Chubby lady.
Cute,
real like you could tell she was hot and
here you get tired of a cab and sees me
and go,
excuse me,
you were an actor.
And I go,
no,
I'm going to stand up.
And she was doing me a favor.
Go Up to my office and
leave your name and number.
And I go,
what office?
She goes,
whatever.
Walking.
And I go,
my 11 o'clock,
I'm year 11 o'clock.
And she goes,
oh my God.
My assistant called me last night,
come,
forget the coffee.
And I'm in the elevator.
I go,
can I ask you a personal question?
They really,
Christopher Walken's
while he was just like,
fuck yeah.
And I go,
I fucking love that dude.
And I go his best movies at close range.
A lot of people would say,
deer hunter.
This bitch looked at me and she goes,
you just got three quarters in my door.
That is his best movie.
We have an argument at the
house every day about it.
So what was this about
there you got dragged into,
they drank.
No,
no,
I'm talking about the street when her,
it wasn't the Sopranos.
David call me in front of audition,
but this woman who brought you arrested
for walking his wife and she was working
for the soprano's cast it,
her and her partner,
cashless or primal.
She's the one that night anymore.
Now she's retired.
She retired.
I put some problems,
but before that it was Christopher
Walken's wife that puts you in that show.
That's where you met with,
wow,
that's crazy.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
it makes sense though.
Successful relationship
with a lot of those people.
It's all in the business.
People understand how
nutty that business is,
you know?
You know,
I was thinking about it and when they
started accusing him of throwing that
Natalie Wood off the boat shed,
Christopher Walken,
wasn't he on the boat?
He,
no,
no.
He was on the boat.
It was,
but that's not who they know.
No,
it was a,
you know,
uh,
it takes a fif.
Yeah.
What is his name?
Robert.
Robert Raglin.
It takes a thief.
I just took it deep.
What was the show he had
after that with the red head?
With the hot redhead?
Jesus.
Carol Christ.
You're killing me.
I kill your dog.
I'd take it deep.
Brian,
you weren't even around for it.
Takes a thief.
Your head with a fucking exploded.
How do you say his name again?
Robert Wagner.
Redhead.
Oh,
a Stephanie from mother fucking powers.
She was the first original cougar.
Yeah.
They think that he killed.
No,
ma'am.
There's a guy who apparently
is putting out a book.
Right?
I think,
think that he,
uh,
killed Natalie Wood.
Yeah.
His memory came back after 20 years.
Once he got the book deal.
Once again,
once they get in the 50,000,
he fucking remembered.
He snapped out of his alcoholism.
He's been on a couple.
Uh,
and CIS is
yeah,
and a few,
two and a half men's.
I wonder what the fuck,
man.
Wow.
That's a crazy thing that to,
I mean,
if this guy bullshit it,
could you imagine if your wife died in
a tragic accident and then years later
some motherfucker is writing
a book claiming that you
killed her and you have to
deal with the fact that you lost her
anyway and you loved her and you miss her.
And this guy who you know,
who knows why the fuck
he's is that you breathing?
No
sitting here holding my breath.
Cock sucker.
No.
What was her name again?
He would,
if he didn't kill her,
if he really didn't kill her,
then this guy,
what a piece of shit this guy is.
That would be a horrible thing.
And it's based on when
they got back from fishing,
something like that.
And if he did kill her,
well,
he's a piece of shit
and this guy's a hero.
Right?
Keeping chasing after it.
Wow.
This is really interesting.
The only full sentence I could completely
deciphered during the entire argument
was get off my fucking
boat set by Robert Wagner.
Wow.
The day after woods body was
found off the coast of California.
This Guy Davern said that he
was asked to go to Wagner,
his bedroom,
and his Beverly hills home where he
met with a lawyer and was told to say
nothing.
The captain wrote,
Wagner informed me he would
hire an attorney who had
handled my statement about
Natalie Wood's disappearance and drowning,
which he did before
Natalie Wood's funeral,
I signed a statement appointed district
attorney drafted one completely void of
facts of the facts surrounding
Natalie was disappearance.
Wow.
That's crazy,
man.
They might've got shrunk and he threw
her off the fucking boat and she just
drown.
What you was that brother?
1981 November 28th,
1981 wow.
They got an a drunk fighting.
He threw her off the boat.
Holy Shit.
If this guy is telling the truth,
that's horrific because that guy's
got to live with that and got,
damn.
Natalie Wood was hot.
Oh my God.
Ooh.
She was no makeup,
no Claire.
All that was 1981 though that bitch
waked up track a glass of orange juice.
And that's what she looked like.
Yeah.
This is really crazy,
man.
The detectives at the WHO is at the
heart of the original case said that he
believed Wagner's account.
He added that the actress was very
small so that it was believable that she
drowned quickly while yeah,
Christopher Walken was on the boat.
Yeah.
Wow.
It says Christopher Walken began talking
about his total pursuit of a career
which he admitted was more important
to him than his personal life.
He clearly thought Natalie
should live like that too.
Wow.
So,
uh,
they got in an argument that was
what started off the argument.
It sounds like Christopher Walken was
trying to get some pussy and Robert Wagner
was there and they were all drunk and
they were all getting shitty with each
other and he fucking threw off the
boat and he tried to be captain,
save a hoe.
And Robert Wagner said,
what bitch you ain't going home with?
Nobody grabbed it by the fucking
head doing true in that ocean.
Well that's so scary,
man.
Which could have happened.
We weren't there and who the fuck knows?
Oh Man.
They had that kids too.
That kids.
Yeah,
they had two children.
Oh God.
What a mess.
Dude.
Is there anything worse than relationships
gone wrong where you're screaming and
yelling at each other while drunk?
That is like one of the
lowest forms of mankind.
A relationship gone wrong where you're
both drunk and you're yelling at him.
It's just Charles boot
Koski ask and it's sadness.
Whatever the woman you date,
you got to do the opposite.
If she has a cocktail once in a while,
you smoke riva,
she smokes reef.
You have one.
Yeah.
Cause when you both do
something that's the same,
it's not going to pay it off.
It seems to be that it
works in some paypal.
You know some people that
professional pool players,
they're both,
they're both men and female.
Both professional pool
players and it works.
Some people do that with
golfing and it works.
Some people do that.
It works with some comedians.
Tom and Christina,
the perfect example,
it works great.
Fucking works.
Those people are happy as fuck.
Thomas common his wife
for super happy and say,
well it doesn't,
you know,
so it's not always,
but it's a low percentage is low.
What I'm trying to say is every time I've
dated a woman when I was younger that
she,
let's say she did blow and I did blow.
At first it was great because
she sucking your Dick,
your light and her ass one five but 10
somewhere along the line it gets a stray
when she's watching
you because you got it,
you don't want to share it with,
oh Geez.
I'm saying you don't want,
you got your period bitch,
you,
you no good to me.
You know,
so you're doing blow by yourself.
No.
So she's like,
are you doing blow?
No.
And your jaw is going now.
She wants to do a line now she wants
you to fuck and she's got that blood and
you got your on the
blow.
Fuck that.
When the chick had a period,
I don't show up.
Really lucky.
Yeah.
Fuck you.
Just in case she even,
it's that,
that I made that mistake one time.
Whenever it chicks out with a period that
she started getting naked and she had
like a,
you know,
she had the fuse right in the front
and I have to like five or six hours.
They can only suck your
Dick so many times I'm like,
maybe I'll eat her ass.
And I went to either as,
yeah,
like a half a ever.
If that shit,
the next day mark Babbitt picked me up.
Half of the kids that
picked me up to that.
Where is he these days?
I Dunno,
I dunno.
I think he's the vice president
of Sandusky cooperation and shit.
Who is the head of the laugh stop
in Houston during the glory days,
the glory days where you would go there.
People don't know about Houston,
Texas,
man.
People do not know about Houston,
Texas.
What it used to be,
first of all,
it's the first,
first place in the country
that I could sell out shows.
The very first place was Houston,
Texas and when the laugh
stop was in his prime glory,
they had a Monday night open mic night
where they would go from fucking whatever
they started.
Was it eight with APM,
they started,
that shit would go straight onto til two
o'clock in the fucking morning and the
place would be packed back and
there was a hundred comics looking
people at seven leave at 10 and another
hundred people come at 10 30 and leave
at two.
It was a legit,
they were legit comics out of that scene.
They were good comics,
but the scene crumbled and
a lot of guys stayed there.
And guys that jettisoned,
they came to la with,
they didn't find success quick enough.
It wasn't what they
thought it was going to be.
They didn't adapt for whatever reason.
And we lost a lot of guys who like,
in my opinion,
you know,
could have been like fucking all,
all time.
Funny guys,
really fucking funny guys.
They just,
whatever reason,
they never got out of that Houston scene.
But that Houston scene
was a mother fucker man.
It's Kinison and Hicks left behind
the remanence of that scene.
They started it when they had that,
uh,
the annex,
the,
the comedy annex,
which was in Houston and that's
where s Kennison was just on fire.
Man.
He was just coming out of the gates gun.
He was so unique that his opening
acts would all sound like him.
They'd all stop talking like Yam.
They all would do like his cadence.
They couldn't help it.
It's like they thought it
was so hypnotized by him.
They thought that might be
the only way to do comedy now.
You know,
and they,
they would,
they would go on stage,
like you would watch them and be like,
this guy's like doing
a Kennison impression.
This is weird.
That's how much of a motherfucker he was.
And so when Kennison left,
it was just,
boom,
just left this ripple of a community.
And you know,
there's all in Jimmy Pineapple and all
these other guys that the toured with
them and that we're a part of the outlaws.
No,
they were all sort of left behind.
And some guys,
some guys survived and some guys didn't.
But that was,
uh,
that was the,
the,
the burst of that scene.
It was Kennison and then fucking nothing,
man.
No,
nothing.
You know,
I mean,
I know they had the comedy,
what'd they call it,
the comedy union going for awhile
and we got the Houston Improv,
you know,
and Houston Improv.
How's that?
I,
you know she had open mic nights.
I think they have open
mic night on Wednesday,
but not like that.
Got of open Mike Nights.
They don't understand.
But I think they have a couple
of rooms around town in Houston.
Yeah.
I haven't talked to slit other laptops.
Done the new laptops.
Done right.
Done.
Everything's done.
The last spot is done.
That's done too.
So all that's left is to comedy showcase,
which is on the south side and the Improv
or theater or the house of Blues there
as well.
Poppy,
the Improv must've closed a lot of places
down because they get the top talent.
Like if you're going to a
town and there's an Improv,
that's the top talent,
you know,
it always is.
It's always,
you look at the line that was Jim brewer.
It's this guy,
Tracy Morgan.
It's always like top named guys,
you know?
So what a club like that
moves into your town.
It's probably hard to be the last stop.
And now I think the only reason because
it's that they didn't keep up the same
level of quality.
They have like local headliners who was
like one of the few places where like
San Francisco's one,
um,
Denver's one and Boston's another
one where you have like legit local
headliners,
but like there's nobody talks about
like legit local Chicago headliners.
How many guys are like in Chicago that
are just headline and clubs around
Chicago?
There's not that many.
Larry Reed,
I reread,
but he,
but he's been around for a long,
who else was out of Chicago?
But I knew there's a,
there's a funny fucking guy.
I always forget his name and that's a
shame because I thought he was one of the
best monologist I ever saw on stage.
And when I,
you don't remember his name?
No,
he's a school teacher and he's got like
four kids and he doesn't like traveling.
So he just does yoga rooms and
then anything local in Chicago.
But the story goes that one night
he was on stage in the room.
It was in the old days when
Kennison would do a theater,
he would go right to the local
comedy club and get onstage.
Really?
So they said that one night they
told him before that night they go,
look,
we don't want to offend you but kinnisons
coming in and when they come in and
we're going to give you like you get off,
we'll pay you.
And they said there Kennison came and I
had worked with him in myrtle beach and
I left in awe of him.
He had one bit about
getting on a bus and a,
but I was just dying.
And uh,
somebody told me the story years later
that kindness and came in and they were
like,
we'll get them off the stage.
Can if somebody ordered a drink and
started listening to a guy and go down and
let me watch the guy.
That's how good they get.
He's a brutal now he's got,
this is 10 years ago
when I worked with him.
Well,
I can't say,
must have been a fan of comedy and you
know how you can't get that good without
being a fam,
you know,
told the guy you want to go on the road.
And the guys like Doug,
I'm dead.
I got a wife and kid and
I'm a school teacher.
It kind of seems like if you
ever fucking come though,
ain't look me up.
While he's a great kid,
he still works.
He still works locally.
You know,
it's nice when you find new town on the
road and that's where we found Thomas a
girl.
When we did that,
a maximum comedy tour.
Thomas the girl was one
of the opening acts.
They would have a new
opening act and every place,
and you know some,
some guys are pretty good,
but Tommy really stood out.
I was like,
this kid's fucking pool.
Is Tommy Cigar?
The nicest guy I haven't had,
haven't lately have coffee with
Bert Kreischer three times a week.
Beautiful.
Two blocks from my house,
you know,
now I can meet Chris Mcguire to Starbucks.
You just wrapped up the burn,
the burn and it had the
wrap party last night.
You know,
I was with Brody this morning.
We know a lot of really nice pieces.
Yeah Bro.
We're really like,
you know,
Tony High and cliff,
it's grody said a joke last night.
That motherfucker's bathroom bone.
Tony Hinchliffe Brody said a joke last
night and the burn and I immediately knew
fucking Tony wrote it.
That's how much of a fan
I am a Tony's about that.
He goes to Mcdonald's as
he eats the happy meal,
but he keeps the burger
or something like that.
Something very witty.
I don't,
I'm not giving it justice,
but it made me fucking lame
stuff's a very good writer.
And I knew he was,
it was Tony's.
I knew it was totally,
we were real lucky that we know somebody,
uh,
many cool,
funny and nice people and they were like,
we all feed off of each other.
You know,
that's a very important part of any
like real strong seen a real strong
community,
you know.
And I think we're a part of a very strong,
uh,
and fun stand up community.
You know,
this is a more,
more of a community now I think,
uh,
at this stage in our lives
than it's ever been before.
And we think about all the people
that were like networked with,
you know,
it's pretty unusual and how
everybody is doing so well.
Like I just got off the phone with Aubrey,
went down to see a Ari and
a in Austin last weekend.
Yeah.
And it was talking to Ari was like,
are you fucking headlined
the Cap City Comedy Club?
Like that's legit at Cap
City Comedy Club in Austin.
That is a legit weekend.
You headlined a legit club and for the
longest time dude couldn't get booked
places.
No.
And now you know,
you see him headlining a legit place.
It's like,
wow,
this is seeing your friends prosper and
seeing people around you prosper and
seeing them grow and seeing them do shit.
That's hilarious on stage,
man.
It's like nothing more energizing.
There's not nothing more beneficial to
you as a person and your growth and your
own inspiration because it's like
inspiration without jealousy.
It's inspiration without,
you know,
without any of the negative
aspects attached to it,
like no fear or insecurity that's
causing you to be inspired to action.
Now you're just inspired by watching
somebody else do what you do,
someone that you love,
so you like watching them up.
They're killing,
you know,
four years ago I was very,
this solution with this business.
What are you really?
Yeah.
It was after the Carlos thing and the
comedy store when they all went back and
there was no real solidarity.
I became a comic because of people like
Lenny Bruce that he would do comedy and
then shoot over to Chelsea and shoot
heroine with the jazz musicians and fuck a
stripper.
That was the lifestyle I wanted when I
was 28 I was a little crazy and I was
content with that.
I couldn't handle a family.
I was pretty content with that.
Knowing you content with that is great.
That was a little disenchanted.
I'm not going to lie to nobody.
I didn't want to do it and I didn't want
to hang out with those fucking people
at the store ever again.
I didn't want to see him.
The,
the real problem was
when that all went down,
everybody sorta pussied out
except and stuff for you
and Ari,
you and Ra.
We're the only ones already took
like a year off of that place.
And you never went,
I take,
I take my friends and family
series because at the end
of that it's all you got.
I got no family.
Yeah.
So and on top of that,
I know the old saying,
you know,
you got to close one door
before another one opens.
We were done at the store.
I was done at the store.
Uh,
and uh,
I went and applied for a job
as a car fucking salesman.
I took the Piss test.
But like I obviously think melted.
So the THC,
so they never called back.
They were scared and all of a sudden,
what kind of cars are
we going to sell for it?
Right on my block.
Friendly for it.
I could sell it.
Like,
listen,
I can sell chariots.
I don't give a fuck.
You come in,
I'll sell you a champion.
You know what I'm saying?
You know me dog.
I said you're fucking cherry.
It don't matter.
You know the car I'm selling today.
This is the best car on the market.
This particular car today,
fucking Mercedes,
this is for tourists
or rocky fucking world.
Even though in the back
of my head I don't,
you know,
but uh,
I opened for you when July in Irvine
and there was no Twitter then and there
were five shows.
It was 4th of July weekend and the place
was sold that and that was the first
time I was ever impressed
with the computer and all
the years I was around you
then I did a podcast here
with you about two years ago.
You got the tape,
the footage is on youtube,
right.
Sat here and said to,
I didn't want to be on Twitter.
I didn't want to be on Facebook.
You guys got the footage.
I eat my words dog.
I'm a big boy.
And I started fucking around on Twitter
cause you started telling me and I
started doing it.
Just how I seen everybody was
fucking up just writing jokes,
bro.
You know,
every week or every three days,
and I go,
deep dog,
I don't give a fuck.
You got to go deep on Twitter.
If you want some mother fucking retweets,
you got to take them into murky waters,
whatever the fuck you say.
You know,
I tell you man,
these people on Twitter are my family now.
I retweeted on CNN the other day.
Oh fuck yeah.
Fuck yeah.
No,
no,
no.
It's amazing.
It's the only one in the
whole Chris Brown story.
They retweeted my tweet.
I was like,
yes.
Yeah.
Of all the Shit I've done.
That was like a real accomplished.
Yes.
Oh,
you feel like fucking great,
don't you?
I was like,
yes,
but it's amazing what's
going on right now.
I've never loved stand up more than that.
I am turning down audition.
If they're not in my realm,
I don't want to bother with that world.
No one else figured that out recently,
Brian Cowen.
Yeah.
It's all at the exact same garden.
I don't want to,
I don't want to do it.
It's not elevating me
is not making me happy.
You're going to call it.
They call me in for two broke girls.
Two in the afternoon.
They want to be to be
there at five 30 really?
Who the fuck are you?
I don't have a life.
First of all,
you got to respect me.
That's number one.
There's a fucking man.
Number two for a Goomba.
I'm the Goombas.
Am I gonna play?
How's it going to change my life?
So somebody going to see me
at eight o'clock at night?
I turned it down.
I want to do it unless it's something
great now I don't want to do it.
I'm very content with what I'm doing.
I'm very content with the stand up.
I'm very content with the writing.
I'm content with this circle right now.
We have people around us,
dog.
I don't have anybody around me.
I don't want to have no more.
I get out,
I work out.
I meet people for coffee and now
the Duncan and Brian made up.
Yeah,
no,
no.
The positive is not perfect now.
That ain't no stopping us.
These people are done.
They created a monster and
we created it all on Twitter.
And I love it.
I love my people on Twitter.
Twitter is big,
but the podcast is the biggest thing.
They know.
They know you because of this.
Twitter is just the way they stay in
touch with you and go down and dirty with
these motherfuckers on
Twitter and they feel me.
They feel the [inaudible]
most of the,
so it's all everything.
It's a combination of all these things.
It's uh,
it's your standup being funny.
It's the,
the Twitter you'd be,
you'd be able to connect with them and
it's the podcast where they get to know
you.
It's all those things above,
but it's all those things that just didn't
exist for us just a little while ago,
you know,
and the impact that it has
now since fucking nuts.
Brian went on stage in Sacramento.
They went berserk.
I insisted ladies,
gentleman,
you know,
have iPod.
God Man.
Brian went from the stage
and he called ca collect.
That's how brains so ca collect.
Tell Him Brian Red Bolt.
Yeah,
it's fine.
And then I went up right.
Probably had one of the best
heads I've ever had in my life.
I,
um,
I've,
I'm having these new sets now.
My set,
sir,
I've got all this new shit
I'm working on and it's,
it's so fun.
It's all these new light
weapons and turns and it's like,
this is shit that didn't even exist
a month ago and it's crushing.
You know,
it's like,
it's so exciting to watch you just pop
out of the ground and become a fucking
tree.
You know?
It's,
it's really fun,
man.
It's exciting.
Joined the people.
I never used to enjoy the people.
Yeah,
the comedy.
It's always dumped.
People coming up to me,
a fat man.
These people call me fat man,
but they love me.
They love.
So it's a different fat man.
I love it.
I love it that the,
we communicate.
We smoked dope.
I wasn't at the mall of America last week,
bitch.
The mall,
a motherfucker in America.
We had 60 people up on that fucking
garage panel puffing like savages.
You know,
people brought cookies.
This is it.
This is a movement.
He shouldn't talk about
the sunlight because a Ari,
uh,
almost got arrested.
Who gives a fuck?
He got arrested.
He got arrested because he's playing
that hunt for the edible thing.
We ain't got time for that.
What are you can somebody
emailed me today in Chicago.
You're going to go to play
hunt for the yellow pan.
I'm going to fucking adult dog.
Got a skateboard?
No.
Are,
you can't do that shit.
Ari was doing it when he was just in
Texas last week and he was doing it.
Was he doing it online?
Yeah.
Oh,
sorry.
No,
no,
no.
That is super illegal.
He gets set up.
Has got to be careful.
One one follower that doesn't like them.
Well,
I don't think he's aware of
the repercussions of getting
busted and that mother
Fucker,
he'll go to jail.
No sons.
Antiquey you'll get that little
[inaudible] he's over though.
Shave it.
They'll put some fucking,
some fucking whatever the fuck they put
in your ads before they bang it and you
know,
it ain't fun.
Especially in Texas.
I couldn't imagine doing time now anyway.
Did they have air conditioning?
Oh yeah.
Marketing a swimming pool.
Massages.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
They got everything.
Stakes.
Lots of tales on Sunday.
Get the fuck.
The only personal gives you massage.
That is against your will.
You don't know what it is
to get a massage again.
She was like,
you can fight this or
we could take the ride.
You might get a happy ending
and you might get choked to him.
I would,
uh,
I would want to teach a few dudes
Jujitsu and just have impromptu sparring
sessions where you don't
just teach a few dudes.
You just say to keep your
shit sharp and then just,
uh,
all right,
come on,
let's go.
We're going to roll here.
Lay some mattresses down and go at it.
And as long as you teach him some shit,
maybe they'll offer you good sparring
partners and then maybe you could at least
keep up a level of fitness and it's
trying to stay alive when the joy,
yeah.
You know,
man,
I mean you don't want to go in there
because of a hunt for the animals.
No.
Cause then they're going to
hunt for your fucking edible,
your ass hole.
Deep,
deep,
deep in the murky waters of that muscle
aren't gets baked with people after
shows.
I don't do that anymore.
You're not smoking when people see me too.
I had a guy come up to me then I was
positive it was a cop once and I was like,
all right,
this is ridiculous.
I just,
I didn't,
you know,
I also knew somebody that had um,
something putting his
pot that it wasn't pot.
It doesn't,
still to this day doesn't know what it is.
It might've been math.
Might've been someone
sprinkled math on down the
road.
Dude,
seven tried to give me DMT in Sacramento.
Who knows what that is.
Yeah.
That's like schedule it,
it gets really shady cause that's like
super illegal shit and we already know
that people have been set up in the past.
Like you gotta really think about that.
Like that's the 15 year old kid who was
arrested in Florida because a undercover
cop pretend to be in
high school with them,
flirted with them and got them.
You buy into that shit.
Look,
this is what you're doing in California.
Okay.
What heads when you
declare yourself a head,
it's a different story.
We're not stoners.
That's 13 year olds.
I look at high times.
I'm a head,
okay,
we're smoking dope 30 fucking years.
No,
none of use a head.
no,
no.
You guys are head bolt as a head.
It's a fucking understanding.
It's an understanding.
It's an understanding pro and I could
tell when I look at some of these eyes,
I won't take edibles that much.
Eat.
I don't like the fucking big
thing or a chocolate bar,
but if somebody comes to me,
I could tell when they have real REFA.
I could tell because their heads,
they're not drunk and not sloppy.
I could tell I had just mow go,
you don't fuck with nothing else.
When I look at his eyes and I go,
what'd you listen to?
And it was a dog at Harrison.
Sabbath was,
it's a head.
It's a head.
When I was done,
I want to shoot myself.
That type of shit.
Their heads.
Then they quit on themselves.
It wouldn't harm themselves,
Bro.
I've been doing this for 30 years.
Ain't nobody gonna set you up.
Or if you smoke a joint with somebody,
how,
how am I going to set you up in that
light if you smoke a joint with somebody,
if,
even if I'm in fucking,
but I tell you got an
offer from a weed store,
Michigan.
The fly me out and do comedy.
Really Nice.
Number two.
Hell yeah.
Oh yeah.
Fuck yeah.
Why not?
What's the name of the store?
I don't know.
They didn't send me all the details.
They just went mad flavor.
You gotta change it.
Twitter,
we need Joey d,
You know Jim's got Joey Diaz on Twitter.
Let me checked me.
You do.
I'm the baddest motherfucker
you got involve.
Joey D is,
yeah,
but anyway,
the problem is no business
giving them bad bro.
You know,
I heard in New York in
the 70s on Halloween,
they would put razor blades and
apples and give them to kids.
You know what?
If you ate an apple on Halloween,
go fuck yourself.
You're supposed to go to
for the fucking doe Ray.
Me,
I never really candy and
Halloween I went for the money.
I went for the pennies and
the fucking dollar bills.
They changed.
I grew up early.
When I came from Cuba,
I was in New York City
and those buildings,
those buildings,
the juice,
they give you fucking cash.
How much?
A dollar a quarter and the 70s
somebody give you a fucking quarter.
That's a little juice
drink from the hot dog,
man.
You know I'm not going to,
don't listen.
Take your little m and m's and all
this shit and shove it up your ass.
Isn't it strange when you really think
back about the price of shit when you
were a kid?
When you see like comic books for 25
cents and you think about how ridiculous,
like you hear like what
someone's wage was.
He got $5 a week working for
the ranch and you're like,
what?
What's the price for tickets now for a
concert like a hundred and fifth well,
didn't you say Bob Dylan?
Oh,
two 25 and yeah.
What's the guy say to us?
$300 that's what we are in Santa Barbara.
I think he said three fifth and Madison.
February 24th look it up.
1980 I paid $15 and 50 cents
for pink Floyd the wall.
And that's where the service tag,
we have a service tax they have now you
know what Tom is just service tax was
what?
50 cents?
That was dollars.
Now it's like $5 more than that is it?
You think about it.
So in 30 years to the,
so let's say it doubles every 10 years,
it should be 60 $70 for a ticket.
Why are we paying 300 200
for a ticket for anything?
This was pink Floyd,
the wall.
That's as good as it gets.
Why at the Nassau Coliseum?
Well,
it's just weird how everything
got more expensive like that,
that weird thing of inflation
that I never really,
totally understood.
Like why does why the things have
to get more expensive every year?
But it does.
Why does gas have to get more expensive?
Who Does?
Why do people have to make more money?
I don't know.
But they do and it just keeps,
the number gets higher and yeah,
people are,
I mean for sure if you have more money,
you're going to be able
to buy more things,
but then when those more things
costs more money as well,
you're just raising the numbers,
but it all balances itself out.
It's just so,
it's a weird sort of a trend to me that
things constantly get more expensive,
constantly get more
expensive like no one's ever,
they're not going to
lock in iPhone and say,
Ladies and gentlemen is iPhone is $200
it would be $200 to the end of fucking
time.
The iPhone 80 that comes out will be
$200 that's what we're charging for a
fucking iPhone.
You can't say that because you don't
know what the fuck $200 is going to be
worth in 20 years.
You don't know what it's
going to be worth in a decade.
You don't know what it's going to be
worth if the fucking economy collapses,
like in Russia,
like it went down in the Soviet Union,
like it's going down in Greece.
I mean,
Greece is a,
they're really running a very real
possibility of leaving the European Union.
That's going to fuck the dollar up.
It's going to fuck everybody up.
What happens then?
It was,
well,
how much does it cost to get your car
washed now is at $18 you know what?
How much do you get an
hour is minimum wage?
$20 an hour now,
you know,
it gets at a certain point in time
that's going to keep going up.
Told Julia the day that I was
out of touch with reality,
but I went car shopping.
Yeah.
I sold cars for 10 years,
a four runner.
When I quit selling cars of 22,000 loaded
with the fucking under Greece and the
fucking stars and Colorado,
it's 40 $50,000 for $20,000 I
looked at a Honda last week.
It was 10 years old with
a hundred thousand miles.
They still want to 13 grant and
the blue book is 14 five wow.
Kelley blue book or you know me.
I know all that shit.
I fucked him.
Look at that stuff.
I have friends in the car
because I called Colorado.
I asked around,
I was even thinking of getting
a car shipped from Colorado,
from my buddy and I'm the,
he's the general manager
of one month Toyota.
They gave me a fucking dollar
over invoice right away.
Give a fuck.
He goes,
come get the car.
So I'm thinking about doing that.
I'm trying to put it together.
Uh,
it's just,
I was out of touch.
You know what helps me,
the prices and things,
like I told you,
you know,
we live around here
with BMWs and Mercedes,
so we forget.
But I go to Pittsburgh and I watch,
I go to Houston,
I go to all of those cities.
I look at these people,
I look at the people that come
into the shows and I'm like,
Bro,
we're in fucking Trump.
I look at these malls
empty across America.
Empty Bro more.
I'm America is one thing.
They,
you know what I'm saying?
Everybody wants to have a
business at the mall of America.
Have you been there,
Jim Zine to make motherfucking paper?
Minneapolis?
I was very impressed.
I mean the airport,
just 10 minutes from mall of America,
not dirty.
They designed that city.
So they get your pocket,
you land,
there's 22 airports and each amp,
what hasn't shut up to the mall
of America every 10 minutes later,
bro.
It's for sinking land just to shop,
which you could land just to shop.
Damn.
Four floors deep.
Fucking four floors deal exercise in it.
Oh,
you to see this thing.
You got to see this thing.
And then they have an whole area
where you're an amusement park.
Used to be a fucking dead.
It used to be the old twin stadium.
So think of a fucking stadium,
a baseball stadium.
And that's just a little piece of it.
That's just,
I walked around,
the one day was an hour and a half walk.
Wow.
He walked around the whole thing.
Fucking hold her.
I didn't go up the stairs.
Don't get me wrong.
It's like a carry the way my
Gaultier fuck that I'm talking about.
But I walked around that mall.
Wow.
Fucking mall.
But it tells me that Bro,
this country's in trouble.
We were talking about
the phone that they have,
they don't have five pound bag of sugar
is normal because the price of sugar
went up.
You have to buy it by the
pound or three pound bags.
Gas has gone up.
Everything has gone up,
but the price of cocaine,
it's still 35 at Graham.
You said it went down.
It went down.
It was 40 or 62 years ago
when last time I bought blow,
five years ago it was
60 I go to open padre,
pick up the grant for
50 if the guy was high,
you know what I'm saying?
If I had been there a couple of times now,
35 $35 you get jazzed up foot
and it's better than ever.
They say better than ever.
Gives you your skin rash.
Don't fucking heroin.
Did you read about heroin?
Did you read about new weed in
New York City amongst teens?
What
I mean,
oh,
teens are going nuts in New York city.
We thought we'd,
and so his eyes good.
More of it.
Now what are we going to do?
Give may dd pills and SOS,
but why don't you get these fucking,
you know,
at a certain point in time it's becomes,
okay,
I don't know what it is.
17 1819 whatever it is.
You think it's okay for you.
If you have a good childhood,
if you have good parents,
go for it.
But it's not,
I don't,
I don't buy that.
That's going to hurt you.
I don't think it's going to
hurt 18 year olds are this day.
Say that if you smoke
it when you're young,
that it can diminish your Iq.
I've,
I've heard that,
but I'm like,
how do you find that out?
You take two people,
make them live the exact
same circumstances,
you know,
and get one of them high
and one of them doesn't.
They both follow the same diet.
They both have the same genetics.
They're twins.
But other than that,
how the fuck are you gonna tell
me that that's what's going on.
How do you know what his Iq would've been?
Who you're not you,
you're just extrapolating.
You know,
there's a lot of other
environmental factors that
could lead to someone being in
an area where there's a disproportionate
portion amount of people with a low Iq.
You know,
it's the Iq test itself is not really
necessarily a good judge of intelligence.
Cause a little bit is about
understanding how tests work.
So I really fucking smart people that
just don't know how this test works and
they,
they know how to be very
intelligent in their own world.
They didn't know how to be
very intelligent in their
own occupation or their
own,
their own world in a way that you
wouldn't be able to plug into.
It's just because you write some fucking
shit on a piece of paper that requires
thinking.
It doesn't mean this is a real accurate
measurement of real intelligence,
usable intelligence
because it just doesn't,
you know,
real intelligence is social intelligence.
There's a lot of people
that are socially brilliant.
I mean how many guys we met
that aren't that good looking,
but they're always getting laid.
Everybody loves him.
People come around and grabbing them.
They can't wait to hear him talk.
What is that?
That's a social intelligence is a,
there's a talent to that.
There's something to that and
to discount that is silly.
And to say that,
you know,
the only kind of intelligence should
be standing in front of a computer,
punch in numbers.
And that's stupid because
there's a social intelligence.
If a guy can talk some crazy freak who's
never done it before and to sucking his
dick in a,
in an alleyway somewhere,
I can't believe I'm doing this.
That's in social
intelligence that he allowed,
you know,
he pulled that off.
Yeah.
I mean that's what you saying.
You could sell cars.
That's a social intelligence.
You're like,
wall,
I saw you and you are,
you are a black belt and talking,
oh,
I don't give a fuck.
You know,
get down with the best of them.
All that you know.
And bold.
It's tough to talk to those people
like a rock and boulder because social
assembly real.
Yeah,
they're very intelligent.
You know?
Can I get this on a grant?
You know,
those people in Boulder
love Djo told me there's once
a friend of mine said to me,
Bro,
you have to forgive these people in
bold because some of these astronauts,
you know at the university there,
so their intellect is so high that they
have no social skills has been sucked
in.
It's not that they're assholes
are trying to be bad people,
is that they really,
the introverts,
they don't know.
It's,
and I understand that shit.
I understand between the guy that's
a dick and there's a guy that uh,
has his fucking face in a book.
Yeah.
And He loves it and he doesn't
care about the outcome.
They don't concentrate on social shit.
They just don't blow the blow up.
What
Dan and then,
and then,
then,
then it told you when I was
heavy into martial arts,
but I was like a teenager.
I would get like social anxiety
when I had to talk to somebody.
I would get anxious if I had talked
to somebody in return a video.
If I would get anxious,
if I would go to uh,
the,
uh,
the mailbox and get something,
or if I go to the bank
and deposit a check,
I would get socially anxiety and anxiety
where I couldn't talk very well for no
reason because I just wasn't
used to talking to people.
All I wanted to do was train.
So it was just training
and fighting all day.
It was just locked into this one form
in my mind where most of my day was
dedicated to movements and
learning how to strike things.
And then I would go out into the outside
world and I would be really awkward.
It's real weird.
Lasted a couple of years,
stand up,
changed it for me,
teaching and stand up.
The two things that changed
it for teaching made stand
up easier because it was
tea.
I would teach whole classes and uh,
I got used to being able to do that.
Used to be able to talk in front of
classes and explain the right way to get,
you know,
Mo momentum and technique.
And all this different shit
that was kind of complicated.
And when I explained it to the class,
I would get more and more confidence
because I was doing that when I was a
teenager.
You know,
get your black belt this week.
You'll end John Shot Black Ron bank.
Kleefish Ron van Cleef.
You know,
I was still working out.
There's a video of him online,
I think he's even older than that,
but I think he's in his sixties.
He's got 63 Rodney tournament,
I think he was 62 years old.
He fought in a karate tournament.
Bright six.
I heard Dan and assign throat.
Just got his brown belt in Jujitsu,
but did he really?
Oh,
you 70 Dan Inosanto.
I believe it's got to
be sacked on Jujitsu.
He's,
I think he's been involved in,
in Jujitsu for old nice guy was in Marina
del Ray and he still teaches Jeet Kune
Dough.
Well,
yeah.
Yeah.
I mean Eric Paulson was
one of his students,
I believe.
Uh,
Paulson is a,
a guy who's a sometimes
more famous for as a coach,
but he was a great fighter for a while.
He was a shootout champion and Paulson,
I think the main style that he
originally claimed was [inaudible] see,
but if you're in a g Condo,
you're essentially into m and a because
with g Cuando was Bruce Lee Style and
the style that Bruce Lee always,
uh,
always preached was
used whatever's useful,
learn everything,
learn,
whatever's useful,
whether it's boxing.
I mean he had,
he wrote a book,
the Tao of Jeet Kune do it,
which just essentially
like copied techniques,
how to throw punches correctly
from old boxing manuals.
He was like,
it was like just sort of documenting all
the stuff that we know works and he had
some unique ideas as Bruce Lee did that
to this day are starting to be adopted
by people like,
uh,
like Bruce Lee was the,
the one of the first guys to say,
you should lead with your strong hand.
Because in boxing you always
lead with your jab and then your,
your power hand is your shorthand.
You're your strong hand,
which you throw less of.
And Bruce Lee said,
that doesn't make any sense.
You should throw more punches with your,
your dominant hand.
The,
the jab in the hooks are more frequent
so you should lead with your more
dominant hand.
And then boxer started doing that.
Oscar de la Hoya and did that.
Um,
there's quite a few
boxers today to do that.
I thought,
I don't know if who's Julio?
Cesar Chavez Jr does it.
Andre Ward does it.
Shad Dawson does it.
It's really interesting man.
It's a lot of fighters that do that now.
So Bruce Lee like predicted this
shit like way back deep in the 70s.
So when you say that a guy like
Eric Paulson is a g condo guy,
like anybody who's smart,
it's really a g condone guy.
Cause g can doe is just like,
it's,
it's figure it all out.
Pull it all together.
You know what kicking from Moy Tai,
you know,
punches from karate.
This,
this hook from boxing.
This is a double leg take down.
That's from wrestling.
Here's a headlock that comes from a,
you know,
whatever.
A catch wrestling in the AA.
He was doing like arm bars and
shit and movies like way back.
Tap,
tap.
Yeah.
Sam Mo.
It's funny,
last night I was watching pedis against
the Joe low zone when he knocked him
out.
And you said,
uh,
you know that we were talking to,
they were talking about taekwondo
black though him and so it was Duke.
Yeah.
Well I'm going to see Friday
Duke and I'm Chael Sonnen.
Friday Duke motherfucking roof.
Where are you at this weekend?
See German town on Friday in Milwaukee,
Wisconsin.
Go to a brown paper tickets
and Thursday I'm in Madison,
Wisconsin at Brown paper tickets.
So Wednesday Milwaukee,
Thursday
and a Friday Milwaukee.
So Thursday Madison,
Friday Milwaukee and my brother,
death squad.
Bad motherfucker.
Stan hope will be an Appleton,
Wisconsin an hour from me.
So this is all happened Thursday night.
The 20th where I'm in Madison with
Duncan Trussell Brown paper tickets.
And your brother Doug.
Stan hope is an hour up the road so
that state will be all fucked up.
Oh,
that's beauties up there for the weekend.
It was still tickets available for stand.
I did see that.
And then tomorrow night I'm in Milwaukee.
I see my man Chels Sonnen's
flying in to Duke Roufus is,
and I'm going to go over and see him in
the afternoon and then Stan hope is up
in Appleton the rest of the week
and tickets are still available.
The skyline comedy club.
He's a good man.
Let's give some plugs.
A Rogun is in Toronto.
Brian,
we got it.
Change the background to my Twitter page.
Can we do that because it's
still got April on there.
It's got march,
April,
and capitalize the last one from Calgary,
the last one I might use.
Stern.
Oh,
did I say Twitter?
Sorry.
USTREAM.
Ustream and somebody started
doing it and then they stopped.
I don't know.
You could have someone else
there that works there,
right?
Yeah,
because it says follow Joe and get
notified every time he goes live.
I never put that up on anything.
We've got a good weekend that
I think our reason Toronto,
check this out at NBC La.
I just tweeted that American Airlines
has to canceled over 300 flights this
week.
What?
So,
I don't know why they're cancelled them,
but if you're flying or American Eagle,
you might want to show
him the American Airways.
Tamala wanna fuck.
Is that about,
I don't know.
They just tweeted it.
Holy Shit.
But they haven't said why.
I don't know if that
planes are all fucked or,
oh,
I'm not going to fucking medicine.
Oh my God.
You got to find out if
you take you for thing,
it's still good.
I gotta get Outta here.
I'm going to Toronto this weekend.
They'd better not be some fucking
terrible how American Airlines,
right?
Yeah.
No,
no,
no.
Oh,
by the way,
the end of the world show,
the tickets will go on
sale on September the 28th.
So that's nine days from today and
that is going to set it right there.
See that right?
Yes.
Uh,
September 28th,
um,
it'll be Joe Diaz,
Doug,
Stan hope,
honey,
honey and me.
And,
uh,
it's going to be a fucking,
a festival,
a celebration of the end of history,
which we don't really
think it's going to happen.
We just,
it's not really end of the world.
We're just,
we just want to have a good time.
So we thought it'd be fun to put on
like a super show so it will be a honey
honey.
We'll call up and they'll,
they'll do some songs first and then it
will be a show with dia as Stan hope in
myself and we're going to have a
fucking blast and can't wait to do it.
And just a,
an opportunity to do something like this.
I don't on a regular basis in la because
we don't do too many shows in la.
We do a lot out here in Pasadena
and this one's going to be fun.
So that's going to be a September 28.
Those tickets go on sale and um,
which we've chosen.
You and I are doing together.
You're not yoga.
You can do,
oh,
that's right.
We do in Arizona,
Arizona and Minneapolis.
October 19th.
Brendan Walsh is out for Arizona man.
Why?
I Dunno,
he booked something else.
So I reached your fee is coming.
I thought,
I wish if he was doing something else.
No,
I wish.
Feel free is coming.
He is.
Or Red Banner Dunkin.
Somebody else.
Well we have to find out.
Find out.
No one else is booked.
Who else is book?
No,
she'll feel lost that weekend.
I told him did.
Yeah.
When did he lose that week
and he said he forgot.
You forgot that you had given it flags.
No Way.
That's crazy.
He's crazy.
Something happened.
Cause I asked him,
you're going to go to Arizona because
I seen Brandon Walsh and he goes,
no,
I think he has Brendan first or something.
So he didn't know he called Shaundra.
I Dunno what happened.
I don't know.
That doesn't make sense to me,
but that's good.
That's good.
We'll figure it.
Well either way.
October you and I are going to be
there so other people will be there.
Most likely Brian,
I'll be there too.
Um,
did you call ca collect,
collect bitches?
Like
fuck,
I didn't even know FCA is
fucked it up in Sacramento.
I want to know if you guys
are just fucking Haggen.
Someone's saying that
the pilot thing is a,
it's a uh,
pilot strike from American Airlines.
That's what's going on.
It says American Airlines,
American Ecos,
that they will cancel 300 flights.
It's weak to cope with the high number
of pilots reporting sick and an increase
in maintenance reports filed by Cruz
has shut him down the old fashion way.
Fucking sit outside,
go to the hospital and get an Mri.
Then you say you had a
headache motherfucker.
Yeah.
Woopsies they've already
canceled 249 flights this week.
300 by [inaudible] heard
they get paid shit.
I heard that uh,
pilots that it's a like a really
a tough job to get by with it.
They'll make good money.
You think they would,
but they don't apparently.
Hm.
Yeah.
I don't know.
Fucking tough job man.
Flying a whole fucking tube full of
souls through the air constantly because
just cause we get off the plane
don't mean their afternoon.
It's done.
Then a followup drew
and go to San Francisco.
We'll fucking Baltimore somehow hole,
you know,
and the other way.
And it's the other way too.
Yeah.
And some of them don't
get much sleep either.
That scares the shit.
Sleep on the plane.
12 with turn around this 12 hour turn
around and let's say they go back to the
room.
What?
You'd never had insomnia.
I've had fucking insomnia
like a motherfucker.
They probably take ambien so
they're all fucking ambien doubt.
I've known dudes to take ambien.
They get all of a sudden get
real squirrely with reality.
Reality becomes a little
slippery dolphin on them,
you know?
Do you know the dudes?
If you ever known anybody
that needs that shit?
Yeah.
Well you don't want to like when someone
needs that Ambien ship and that's all I
needed.
I did one of those,
I did a fucking 16th of those things.
Rush Limbaugh was on.
I did the 16th I did a pill cut in half,
cut in half again,
cut in half again.
It was an eighth or a 16th of a oxycotton
really got a friend of mine game.
It had a lay down.
Never again.
My blood pressure dropped.
What's it is?
It rushed doing like a
hundred of those pitches.
That's when I thought about that.
My heart went out to him.
I think it was on,
it was 50 a day.
He was doing,
there was no,
I was eating,
I ate an eighth,
and it was fucking mind
boggling what I felt like,
how bad I felt like that
just crushes your body.
That fucking synthetic heroin.
Yeah.
And that's like one of the biggest
problems we have in this fucking country.
And this is one of the biggest
problems we have in this country.
That fucking synthetic heroin.
No.
Kill your dog.
He'll start pissing fucking
green and shit like that.
Yeah.
I guess he got up to 30 pills a day.
This one is saying,
I swore I read that at one
point in time was I called,
I read 50.
That's fucking crazy.
That's to a pop.
That's 25 times a day.
He would pop two of them if you pop fifth.
Yeah.
This is his,
um,
he,
his housekeeper got busted
buying them for him.
Like his pitch,
he sent her out to go buy buy pills for
him and she said he took as many as 30
oxycontin's a day.
So I don't know.
I don't know if she's right.
She could be crazy.
I don't know her.
You can't just listen to
someone that says that,
you know?
But those,
those people that take that shit,
that and a,
an ambient is a,
is another one that's a scary one.
I used to sell value and when I first got
divorced in Colorado was buying and in
Colorado it was real
volumes with the Vietnam,
not these motherfucking
things that make it,
what's the difference?
Those,
the Mac,
those fives and those times with the V
in the middle where the V was cut out.
What did they do?
What volumes just put
you on another planet.
So I use them as to come
down from something,
you know,
you do an eight ball of coke,
it's seven in the morning.
You got to come down and you gotta
be watching daytime television until
lunchtime.
We valued and the chill out.
And one time in Beaumont,
man,
I owe deed.
I'm in my 30 of those
motherfuckers in three days.
This is in 2006 I had to stay in Houston
for four days at the Intercontinental.
I couldn't even talk
on the phone to people.
People hire me.
I know this was 2005
or six I have to alone.
I went to Houston.
I wanted these fucking pills and the
kids like we ain't got him and we got
volume.
I said,
I can give me the fucking volumes.
What the fuck?
I was in Beaumont,
Texas.
The home of,
what's her name?
Uh,
Bobby McGee.
He,
what was her fucking name?
The girl he used to
come to the comic store?
No.
What's the fucking cool girl?
The one that sent it?
Bobby McGee.
What's her name?
Me and Bobby.
We can take a cow man.
Yeah.
Yeah,
she's from Beaumont.
That's where a little museum is
that so Slade ham had a room.
Boma.
I get there on a Thursday.
I'm looking for blowing shit.
I'm like,
Bro,
I ain't got no,
we got valid.
Janis Joplin try anybody
who wants to know.
I said,
what the fuck?
Give me the fucking 30 volumes,
like all eat two or three of them.
I bring the rest of La and give them out.
I know a friend who was like Valium
and as soon as you shoot them here,
the first night,
the second night,
eight to next day,
I didn't have reefer,
I pop one in for lunch that night I went
to the club and I started drinking them
a fucking Nigga.
Meisters now where people don't know about
volumes as they sit your fucking fat.
So you eat a 10 milligram Valium,
five of it goes into your body of
the five goes into your fucking fat.
So what happens is the next day when
you wake up and you drink your water
thinking you're all healthy and you
hit that fucking one hit of a joint,
that volume kicks right back up again.
But what are you do?
You put a tenant side of you?
So now you got the five that you popped
and the five that's motherfucking
lurking in there.
So now you're popping these every day.
That's why I love when the
people tell me that he values,
cause this shit just pops up in your fat.
You will never get that out of.
And people.
We volumes 50% of them when
they go to the fucking gym,
so that just just in your factory,
every time you touch alcohol you
smoke a shaker and a smoker volume.
It just kicks that Shit back
until your system is shit.
It's amazing until it just piles up.
So I bought 30 of them.
Dirty,
dirty was a Thursday night at 11 when
I got him the first night I pop one,
the next day I pop one
that none of that pop.
Two or three of them drank Yeager by
Saturday I pop two in the afternoon.
I couldn't fall asleep.
I went to the club after club,
I had a brown bag.
I didn't know what was in there.
It wasn't like an a week container
and I just kept popping up,
tricking Yeager,
mice to the second show I had to do on
a stool and the management knew I was
whacked out.
They pay me my money.
I buy an eight ball from chick,
gives me a number,
but in the fucking dilemma,
I didn't give a fuck her.
She had a boyfriend.
She told me she had to go home,
wait for the boyfriend.
I went home by myself and
did the fucking eight ball,
called the dealer and
then called the chicken.
She was like,
I'm ready to come over and suck your Dick.
Now she comes over with the dealer,
comes over.
I leave with him and he
takes me deep into the Boma.
More fucking Caribou down there.
Just some Christian was,
gosh,
I'm good old Christians.
I was selling some cocaine straight
from fucking Noriega's dash four in the
morning.
My jaw would drive him back.
I'm fucking paranoid.
We're going to get pulled over.
I get back to the hotel Sunday,
Saturday night,
it was Saturday going into Sunday.
My flight southwest was leaving
at like nine from Houston.
I had a stoke.
I was getting picked up at
six 30 it's four or five.
I pick up another eight boy.
I go back to the room.
The chick shows up.
She sucks my dick one time,
but it was so dead.
It was way beyond dead.
It was dead.
No Houdini attend chicks from the
room sucking it fingers up my ass.
Alpha brain,
nothing,
nothing.
Any of those pills.
I was going straight on blow for five,
six hours plus the amount of volumes I
had dog at eight o'clock in the morning
to cocaine was gone.
She was all sucked up.
She was laying in one bed.
You know those hotels that have two beds?
Yes.
I went to get the Brown paper
bag and stick my hand there.
There was nothing in there.
I flip the bag over.
Nothing.
Here I am.
Join.
I hate dirty fucking valuable.
Three days I couldn't fucking believe
I drank a bunch of water and went to
sleep.
Right.
Well,
Sunday,
maybe 10 o'clock I go to see.
I'm trying to fuck her at this point.
My Dick is flat.
It's got blood on it.
I'm scratching it from trying to walk off
in the bathroom where I'm sniffing her
bra,
sniffing a fucking feet,
something because you need to bang
something out the fall asleep.
Right,
because you're fucking all jacked up.
I'm trying to bang one out.
Next thing you know dog.
I swear to God,
I hear boom,
boom,
boom.
I just passed out.
I'm on the bed.
I must have jerked myself off to sleep,
whatever,
cause I went back.
She was in the other bed.
That's how coked up I was.
It was a naked lady.
But how it's checking off.
That's the disease and the pills.
I couldn't even wake her up no more.
She's like,
you're not going to get it hard.
Don't wake me up.
Pick was flat.
It had scratches from me
trying to whack it off.
It was all small.
Only the helmet comes out and
you've got to start from scratch.
So all you're whacking off at
first and they got to work at work,
at work and all of a sudden it just dies.
You think of your uncle playing bass.
So now Joe Rogan,
this was horrible.
I hit boom,
boom,
boom.
But like the feds or something,
I opened up my eyes.
I looked at the clock.
It's one o'clock.
The kid came at seven to pick me up.
I didn't pick up the phone.
They knocked.
I didn't hear it.
I guess the CIC Wold Cup left.
I woke up,
it was the hotel managers,
are you staying another night?
And I'm like,
yeah.
And he goes on,
he payment and I just went in my
pocket game like a hundred dollar bill.
It would keep the change.
I went right back to sleep.
I woke up the next month
I slept straight 24 hours.
They slept straight through
a Monday morning at eight
I called my friend who was
an attorney to come to [inaudible]
pick me up and he goes,
you're going to make your flight?
No,
I didn't even call southwest.
I haven't had to buy another plane ticket.
So I just said,
I drove with him.
I went and got a big Mexican meal.
I was dehydrated,
everything.
And I went and got another big
Mexican meal and then he goes,
what do you want to do?
You want to go to my house?
And I said,
no,
take me to the intercontinental.
Pete had a deal over there for like
60 night before Philippe fucks it up.
So I stayed in there for three days.
We pay fuck it up.
He got fucked up with a chicken,
had a dick in her pussy,
the best states.
She had a pussy and they're still calling.
Her name is Nikki.
He kept calling the tricky cause
she got a dick in her pussy.
But anyway,
back to the situation I got to,
I told tell went Monday
I lived off room service,
the money I made and Beaumont had a call
Terry to send me like the credit card
number.
I had eaten it because all
I could do is eat to refuel.
I couldn't even talk to nobody.
My agents were calling me,
where are you?
They want to say it.
I would call people and I couldn't.
This side of my face wasn't moving though.
Like
I was proud of to like when you know when
you go to the dentist and your face is
dead.
That's how bad I was.
I didn't make it out of fucking Houston.
Felt Thursday took me five days and that's
the last time I basically had a pill.
That's why after that I knew
something had to be done.
Matt has had to be taken.
I got a book.
He outta here.
Get outta here.
Powerful I mad flavor.
Listen,
there's a dude who's got your name is
Joel on Twitter so you don't have mad
flavor.
You don't have Joey Diaz.
He gotta get Joey Diaz.
We need to figure out how to get that.
If anybody knows how to do that,
contact me.
It's ridiculous that some dude named Joel
is running around out there with Joey
Diaz.
His name.
We need to have Joey Diaz
be Joey Diaz on Twitter.
Mad flavors too.
Goddamn obscure.
It's confusing the fuck out of people,
right?
Am I right Brian?
I think joy days would be
definitely better but better,
right?
I like mad flavor.
I love mad flavor.
Planet Rock.
Even Joey Planet Rock Diaz.
I was never when you were
applying planet rock,
bro.
I'm still planning rock.
Whatever the mind frame your brother.
Great to see you.
I love you man.
Love you to death that I
wanted to come up here.
I haven't had an intimate one in a while,
but two more weeks and we'll come up
and do one to five and really get down.
Yeah,
let's get down.
Argue with talking about the
Martians talking about stressing,
stressing.
All right,
we'll still send me,
I love you guys by the way.
I love the guys that still
come to me and they stay.
I went to this restaurant and I
asked her and she didn't have it,
so we left and they take
a picture of the menu.
People actually to go.
Thank you very much for all
the love you give me back.
Love you motherfucker.
Thanks to whoever the fuck that sculptor
is that made the sculpture of the
Werewolf.
Fucking the gorilla in the ass.
Whoever you are out there,
mass man,
he did a fucking amazing job.
I think it's wicked.
It'll be up in the new studio.
And um,
thanks to [inaudible] dot
com for sponsoring the show.
Go to o n n I t.
Use a code name,
Rogan,
and you'll save 10% off any and
all supplements and desk squad.
Dot.
Tv for all your kitty cat tee shirt.
Needs hip.
No.
Or shop squad.tv.
Yeah,
either.
Well,
we'll just,
you know,
you know how to find a bitch.
I see your Madison tomorrow.
We'll see you tonight at the Ice House.
So he's going to be here tonight.
It's Joey Dom,
I rera.
Doug Benson,
Greg Fitzsimmons.
Ari should fear Brian Red band.
It's going to be stacked.
It's a crazy,
crazy fucking shit.
She was coming to
Sheffield chew is coming.
All right.
Sigora had to last minute
and shift.
Fear snuck in and took a spot.
So boom.
Done.
Sansia goodbye everybody.
We'll see you soon.
Okay.