The Joe Rogan experience that became an
issue in Abu Dhabi with a lot of
wrestlers,
arrests.
I should take guys down and just hold
them in positions and not go for
submissions.
Just try to go for points and you know,
and people will get furious.
They'd be like,
well this isn't Jujitsu,
but some people felt like the only way
to compete with these guys is to do what
they're doing is to fight smart.
The only way you can win is to to fight
on points.
Would you rather lose on points then
when by holding a guy down?
Yeah.
I have lost like,
that doesn't bother you.
Does that mean you don't.
You show me a good loser.
I'll show you a loser,
muddy,
but you know,
yeah.
I rather lose on points with keeping my
mentality always with the objective to
get into a better place then to stop my
game and try to find out how I'm going
to win this match while using the time
on my side.
So I have five matches where I lost when
I could've went.
I was winning on points and then I went
for something or I try to advance the
position and I lost it and then doing it
and then whatever the guy sweating me
and then I lost because the time ran
out.
So I have lost matches like that and it
served as a good learning experience and
everything and you know,
yeah.
I rather lose on points then to sit
there and stopped again and wait for the
time to,
to,
to run out because I w I don't know if I
would feel like shit,
you know,
I feel like deep inside me I have a
thing that I feel really bad if I don't
try to go for the next position.
I feel guilty almost.
So you're checking my grandfather's like
I tweeted something yesterday,
somebody sent me that.
I was talking about how I felt when my
child was born that it was.
Oh,
I was thinking about how crazy it must
be.
Um,
how many different babies being born
right now?
If you could see them all in real time
in front of you,
like on a giant screen,
you'd be like a baby invasion.
I mean you don't think about it because
you're only in that hospital room while
that one's being born.
Well,
somebody sent me a tweet and that tweet
is a link that shows in real time every
baby being born all around the world and
it is a fucking invasion.
It is scary APP.
Yeah,
it is.
Like if Obama gave out his cell phone,
so it's like heaven.
It's just one baby baby baby,
baby,
baby.
Switzerland,
Africa,
Indonesia,
China,
Diana.
Nah,
Nah.
And that's just the reported babies.
That's not the little tikes shit out in
the bottom of a fucking grass hut in the
middle of the jungle.
No,
they didn't count those.
They only counted the ones.
The ones that are in the census.
Yeah,
I mean we'll look at that.
Those are the babies.
See those babies on both sides.
Holy Shit.
That's scary.
Isn't that incredible?
Yeah.
Those are all babies
deaths going about.
I don't see a lot of.
Yeah.
Second,
not a lot of us.
Birth most times that only google Dr.
Com.
That's all it is.
Well,
it's good.
Dr. Com,
black size hose.
So the stuff that we can see,
it's all like real blurry.
That's the other stuff.
Do you think this is what the NSA sees?
They see like every new human being
coming online?
Yeah.
The NSA is.
They're paying attention 24 hours a day
to every one of these babies.
Make sure they're not fucking doing
anything illegal,
so I'll get all these babies is crazy.
There's a fucking in.
You should have run out of oxygen or
something.
It's terrifying man and I don't see a
lot of American flags either.
Man.
I see a lot of those other countries
around the red Chinese flag.
That bothers me as an American.
I think we need to do our job and do
some more fucking.
Most of the deaths.
China is number one.
Most birth India.
Look at that.
It just stopped.
What if freaked out?
No,
because the computer crash.
I just.
Well,
what if they just stopped having babies?
What if one day we went on that thing
and it was a day where there was no
babies.
Um,
so I did a podcast today with a guy from
cracked.com.
Dan O'brian are at a really funny book
called how to fight presidents.
He literally took every president in the
history of America to see who was the
baddest ass,
who's the one guy you wouldn't want to
fight and who would win in a fight if
they were pitted against each other.
It's like,
it's in some ways the greatest book of
all time.
And like I said,
I go,
this is the,
this is going to be the greatest
podcasts of all time.
It was the funniest thing because we got
into a heavy heated argument about who
would win in a fight and you got to put
a couple of presidents up at the top of
the list.
You got to put a blanket because he was
renowned for his physical strength.
There is.
He fought vampires to right?
Well,
he did,
but he used in the movie he used an ax,
but Abe Lincoln was 64 and had.
What's that disease where your arms are
longer,
you have really long arms,
like longer than your body had crazy one
and he was,
he was known to be really strong and
very,
very tough.
Acuity
was stable on the table.
I think you also have to think of people
that lived during that era.
There were a lot tougher period.
They grew up doing everything with their
hands,
right?
Building things.
So no,
that's not what we were talking about.
Were you talking about this?
So then he said,
I said,
what about Barack Obama?
And he got quiet it.
Dan's a comedian,
really good guy.
He got quiet and he said,
well,
I can't really,
you know,
I,
I'd rather leave that alone.
I said,
why?
He said,
well,
I try not to.
You try not to include any living
presidents because it caused too much
trouble.
I said,
what do you mean?
He said,
well,
I went through sort of a thing about how
Barack Obama's not that tough a
president and it'd be easy to kick his
ass and uh,
you know,
I was doing it tongue in cheek,
you'd probably kick him here and he's
kind of skinny and you could do and he
gets a call from the secret service
because he posted it as a blog.
He posted as a blog from cracked.com.
Well,
he said the reason,
the only blog that's not up there
anymore is that because he got called
down to the federal building,
I believe.
I think that's what he said.
It's on my podcast.
And he had to go line by line with these
agents on what he,
by what he was saying.
And he was like,
well,
I said,
you know,
Dick Tornado instead of a penis cycling,
because it's kind of funnier.
He was trying to teach them a humor.
These guys were totally fucked her list.
He got all nervous.
He was like apologizing.
He made them a to take it down and it
was a chapter that was isolated from the
book.
I'd be like,
so that I was like,
we live in America,
how now you have to be careful when
you've threatened to president,
you will get called.
But guys,
guys,
come on,
come on man.
I mean,
and,
and he took his job,
can't,
they probably can't.
Well,
they tell me no way to go.
Like,
yeah,
they probably knew.
Of course he's joking,
but there's a thing that you set in
motion a certain status.
What happens?
Because they said we will subpoena
everybody that made a comment on your,
on the blog,
kick his ass and,
and,
and Dan said,
well,
it's a bunch of 14 year olds have fun
with that.
And the main guy had called them first.
He goes,
look,
I know you're kidding.
I know you got a sense of humor.
You've got to go down and talk to these
guys.
It's just the way it is,
pal.