Yeah, I'm tired of fucking windy
twice. Worry recording that.
I'm glad. I'm glad I peppered in with.
That's right. That's right. I kept going.
That's right. Gives Zero folks
your right though. Joe Rogan.
Good experience. But we do have
sponsors and we appreciate our sponsors.
We try to give you
sponsors that we would use.
We tried to give you sponsors is I
would buy that. This makes sense.
One of them's carbonite.
Carbonates. Way To backup your shit.
Did you know that about
12,000 laptops are lost?
Every God damn week at us
airports. 12 Zen. Seriously?
Yes. 12,000 it's insane.
12,000 with carbonite.
Carbonite to sweet set up.
You can you back up all your shit.
It does it automatically. It does.
You don't even have to think about it.
You don't just leave your computer on
it backs it up for you and if you leave
your computer at the airport and they
steal it or someone takes it and doesn't
turn it in,
you just get another computer if you can,
and you download all the information
and it's like you got the same goddamn
computer. It's, it's a beautiful
thing and it's very important.
If you're a traveling person or if you
have important data that you don't want
to lose the loss of one person's laptop,
that it glues essential business files
could leave to disastrous consequences
for the entire company and the earth.
The Earth,
right? My clan just save the earth.
Exactly like my clean engine design.
The engine that runs on water,
professor x and you had all the
information and you left your shit at the
airport. Every I think about how
many movies are based on that.
We've got to get the briefcase.
The files are in that computer and I now,
now they're in the cloud baby.
Everything's in the cloud.
It's going to be really
hard to write a shitty plot.
Go to carbonite.com type in the
offer code, J r e for a free trial,
no credit card required plus two free
bonus months with your subscription.
That's carbonite.com and
the offer code is j. R e.
We use it here on the Joe Rogan
experience podcast. It's a,
it's a very sweet way to backup data and
do it very easily. All right. Use it.
Abuse it, enjoy it. Reply it terrible.
Have you have the worst rapper ever?
I'd be the worst freestyle rapper.
I don't believe they're really freestyle
and I think they're saying some shit
they already wrote. How about that? I said
he said it. I said it. Hip Hop exposed.
We're also brought to you by stamps.com
stamps.com especially with the holidays
here. Um, this is a great way to save a
lot of time. stamps.com allows you to,
they give you a free digital scale with
this a bone and software that we're
giving you right now.
They give you a free scale,
$55 where they're up to $55 with a
free postage and you just weigh it.
You print up your actual us postage
from a printer or regular home printer,
put it on your shit. Mailman
comes handed to him. You're done.
You don't have to go to the post office.
You don't have to go to the most office
if you don't have to stand behind the
guy flexing his ass muscles. Do you get a
guy in front of you? A lot? All the time.
I was at the post office and hey dash
half a cent Haight Ashbury in San
Francisco and there was a sign,
it said,
please don't put wet items on the counter
and you know there wouldn't be a sign
unless you know there a problem.
People are bringing in like wet thing.
I mean like that stamp machine is like,
that's the greatest thing ever.
If you don't have to go find some loser,
I got this wet baby seal, I have to
send it to, you know, I might be auto.
Where's reporting against the wall moist.
Go to stamps.com uh,
use the offer code j r e and
get $110 bonus offers. Offer.
Don't get it. You ain't even office
manager. An office was only 110 bucks.
Everybody would have $110 bonus offer,
including a digital scale and up to
$55 of free speech. Free postage.
Should go to stamps.com
before you do anything else,
click on the old school microphone in the
top corner of the homepage and type in
j. R e all you freaks. We're also brought
to you by [inaudible] dot com that's o,
n N. I t. Lots of new shit
on it including digest tech,
a digestive enzymes. Very excited
about this to Jeff digestive enzymes,
how they help your body absorb
the nutrients in your food.
All of it is explained on on at.com with
out me a beating the science down with
my shitty vocabulary and poor,
poor actual knowledge,
but it's a very fascinating
a digestive supplement.
We sell all kinds of different
supplements, new mood,
which is a five HTP supplement,
which is actually helps your brain boost
serotonin and makes you feel happy.
It's one of the things that people
tell you to not take if you are on SSR.
I's however they don't want you having
too much serotonin and Brian calendar
cause it's not good for the dome.
Apparently he could overflow and think
that life is like way groovier than yeah,
I do anyway.
Pure happiness.
Good for you or one way or another.
But with that, if you're not on them,
it's fantastic stuff and it's
actually a natural, simple,
very easy to describe.
There's science to it on [inaudible] dot
com and there's also a hundred percent
money back guarantee on the first
order of 30 pills within 90 days.
Like try it. You don't like it. You
don't have to return your money.
No one's trying to sell you anything.
That's bunk.
It's all good stuff that we use.
It's called the best shit we
can buy for human optimization.
And with that said,
this is episode four 20 of the
Joe Rogan experience podcast.
My little buddy red band is out rocking
the house in San Francisco tonight, sir,
it is Brian Callan and Tom rose are here
to bring in the most retarded hothead,
holidays.
This is our day.
All Day.
I'm Kinda tired of four 20 I'm already
tired of it. I'm tired of the name.
I'm tired of that number. I'm talking
to people before 20 dudes floor,
20 years. People have, people have it need
to belong to some kind of a tribe.
They, even if it's a pot tribe,
like it's so funny how human
beings cluster in groups.
They just get nationalistic over any
cause. Well, in all fairness though,
the pot tribe and the psychedelic tribes
are very different because they know
some shit that other people don't know.
Like if you're dealing with their pots,
going to rot your brain. Yeah.
All right dude. Right. Good.
Good luck with that thinking.
Know potheads unite in that you know
that we know like this is a good thing,
right? This is a good, this is
a good supplement. Supplements.
He lives in the heart hurting anybody.
This is not bad for you. You know,
you know a woman, bad law. My friend
threw a party and he had a pot,
cookies and crackers and a pregnant woman.
She was five months,
six months pregnant.
She had a bunch of them by accident,
so they rushed to the hospital
and she got, she was all bunched.
I mean really high.
She didn't realize,
I mean really high and you know
what the doctor said, doctor said,
don't worry about it.
It won't transfer to the fetus.
It's fine if you drink alcohol way worse.
And by the way,
alcohol is even worse for a baby.
Then cocaine by far. And I was amazed,
but he said it was actually no worry
at all that she'd eaten those popcorn.
That's not it. I'm not advocating
pregnant women eat hot on it.
Might be writing poetry a lot earlier,
but I was very surprised to hear that.
Yeah, you might be, you might be,
um, very mellow when it comes out of,
he might not be crying. He might be going,
dude, when he comes out of your, well,
it's interesting what the fetus
is protected from by the mother,
by the body.
You know,
it's interesting what gets through and
then what animals gets through because
like with chickens, you know, I'm
still, I've started to raise chickens.
You can feed them food.
That's kind of a little bad because
their body just processed it.
I didn't want effect the eggs at all.
Well you don't want to give him like
rotten moldy fucking worm covered food,
but you can give them some
food that you would need. Sure.
And they'll eat the shit out of it.
Give them some rotten fruit.
They'll go fucking crazy that they eat.
If you want the shelves to be a
certain way, they feed them. Um,
I think and for the calcium, they'll feed
them stones. A certain type of a pebble.
It's actually feed them shells,
shells,
their own egg shells and
smash them up in their food.
[inaudible] you don't want to,
you want to disguise it though,
because if you don't have to,
sky's it than the chicken will know that
eggs like eggshells tastes delicious.
So fuck up their own eggs.
And when they start eating their own eggs,
he got to [inaudible]
babies to make the soup.
Don't pick that baby. Otherwise it'll
just be eaten eggs all the time.
And you just go into the chicken house.
That just massive fucking cannibalism.
There's just something people feed
chickens, chickens to regular basis.
Well that was the, that was, they
were doing that for awhile. You know,
big chicken farms would grind up the
beaks and the feet and things like that.
They had nothing to do with them back
and feed them right back to them.
That became more more respect for
such a delicious little creature.
They were asked and how mad cow disease
started mad cow disease is the same
disease that cannibals in New Guinea get.
They get a brain disease.
I think it's the nature, the
pronunciation, I'm probably
going to butcher this,
but I think it's like Jane Jacobs,
crux Feld disease,
and it's essentially the
same disease as this uh,
cannibalism disease that the cows get
mad cow disease comes from feeding cows,
cows that's really feeding
and typically a feeding cows.
The central nervous system,
another cow.
So they take the spinal cord and things
they couldn't really sell or use and
they grind it up and they would feed
in that. They'd put it back in the,
in the feed as protein. Yeah. House.
Which by the way, complete herbivores.
They're not supposed to be eating.
I mean they would eat the occasional
bug accidentally in their body,
can process it,
but they're not eating animals.
If the account stumbles
across a carcass of a horse,
it doesn't just start challenged at,
oh man, they eat grass, the grass.
So it's so fucked up that they mix this
in unbeknown list in their feed. Yeah.
And it's, it's so, so evil that
nature made it so that you know,
their whole bodies breakdown when they
do that and they get this horrible
central nervous system sold by weight.
So what they'll do is like the
last three months or whatever, uh,
and maybe a marker of there before
they get slaughtered, they put a,
an estrogen pump behind their ear and
the estrogen will actually add weight to
their bodies. Oh yeah. It's good stuff.
We'll do the weird thing
is these priorities. Yeah.
Pre Hounds are [inaudible] how do you say
[inaudible] [inaudible] you can boil
a prion and it will not die. Yeah.
And that's what causes this mad
cow disease. Yeah. They can like,
they can withstand like a
thousand degrees. The teams.
Yeah. Crazy. They do not die.
They don't die.
It's not like you can boil mad cow
disease meet and be fine if you're,
if you eat it,
if it's you,
it was usually an hotdogs or hamburgers
because they were gay or blending the
central nervous. You guys make me want
to go on a full fish diet. The sweat,
then the fishing should fishing plastic
people and everything. Right? Everything.
Yeah. Mercury is bad. Yeah. I had
um, arsenic in my body from sardines.
Yep. I was eating Kansas. Sorry. I used
to love, sorry. Do you really need two,
three cans a date? I'm like the fish
on the cartoon because Joe fucking eat.
Of course Joe being the extremist,
it's never just one hand.
I like sardines. Time to
eat a thousand. I'm a whale.
I just used to love eating them and uh,
I went to the doctor to get my
blood work done and he goes,
you've helped arsenic in your system. Wow.
And I'm like, how much? And he's like,
very little. Like you don't have
to worry about being poisoned,
but we need to find out how it's
getting in there. And I was like, what?
Like if someone poisoned, but
no, it's just eating sardines.
I cut it out. All went away. I was like,
wow. He goes, it's very common. He's like,
especially with sardines,
apparently because they're bottom feeders.
They're always at the bottom that were
the heavy metals accumulate. Well,
you told me that.
I remember and I stopped eating sardines.
We broke the ocean. You to
Kansas, sardines at their foods.
If you eat too much of it,
you're getting arsenic in your body.
Don't eat bluefin tuna either
and don't now. How about now?
How about don't eat it now because all
the shit that's pouring into the ocean,
they're finding there's a 3% jump in the,
uh,
amount of radioactive activity that
there's some detecting and tuna.
That's just now. You mean that's, that's
from you're talking about from the, uh,
from [inaudible]. Yeah. I mean, the,
these tune are traveling all over
the fucking ocean. They're like,
they're on a jetliner
liner is schools of them.
They're getting caught up in the
water that's coming from Japan.
A lot of water coming from
Japan that's radioactive.
And who knows what's
going to actually happen.
We've never had this happen before.
It's total speculation as to what's
going to happen with Fukushima.
They have not resolved it.
We don't know the consequences.
We don't know how bad it's going to get.
It's basically on the edge.
If they get hit again,
like they got hit there before.
Yeah,
you're talking a monstrous disaster
because they can't shut those things down.
It's abundantly clear that
all the evidence is in place.
They can't shut them down.
So then it's about storing wastes and
keeping it cool and it's just a big
fucking hole,
a big stinky nuclear hole in the ground.
It's water's getting into it. You can't
get near ass. Russian can't even get near.
You can get near for like a minute or
30 seconds and your Dick will probably
break off, but you might live.
Yeah, no thanks. We're so weird.
We're so weird that we've done this
and in such a short period of time,
people don't realize what a short
period of time it is to ruin two spots
forever. The three, the four mile, three
mile island, whatever the fuck it is,
that spots probably fucked,
but not as fucked as Chernobyl and
definitely not as fucked as Fukushima.
Those places are foe a
duct to places in the,
what was it, 70 years of
using nuclear power, right.
Seven years of understanding it.
We've already fucked two spots up forever.
Like for way longer than
there's been history. Yeah.
Probably longer than we even looked
like this when Enrico fair man,
there's guys developed the first
nuclear reaction at the university,
I think of Chicago.
Uh,
they were literally in the gym and I are
in an area right there and it started
to click and there's a great
story that I'm going to butcher,
but it's a great story about these,
these brilliant scientists.
Enrico Fermi was this guy from
Italy comes along and says,
they create the first nuclear reaction.
They realize we have a
nuclear reaction here.
Problem is not sure if we
can shut it down. Uh, and,
and so they had a guy with
buckets of water and, uh,
and he had some other thing, like there
was a hatchet to, to hit a cut a rope,
so something would fall on top of it.
There was the snow.
They really just didn't know for sure
that they were going to be able to shut
the thing off.
And they were able to though,
and I'm sorry about butchering that story,
but I just,
I just heard it about Oppenheimer speech
when they detonated the first nuclear
bomb. Oh yeah. What was it? He quoted
like something from hamlet or something,
right? Bhagavad Gita.
Yeah. Oh, well, yeah.
I am become death destroyer
of worlds. Wow. Yeah, Dude.
I mean, you want to talk about the
perfect shit to say after you just
blew up a nuclear bomb, right,
right. He was interested in guy.
Did you see that Oliver Stone?
Uh, untold history of America,
but I heard it was amazing. I just watched
the entire thing. How many hours is it?
I don't know. It's like a, I'm gonna order
it right now. It's fantastic. And, uh, I,
I was very impressed. Uh, and, and it,
it covers Oppenheimer and you know, the,
you know,
there's a big communist scare in the
United States and all this witch hunt.
And apparently Oppenheimer
was like a liberal and a,
it's a belongs to every capacity.
Doesn't belong to every Communist Party,
but they let they let him slide,
uh,
because he had the knowledge
to give them the bum.
Yeah. And I believe at the end of
his life, he was very vocal about,
he was very anti nuclear bomb at
the end of his life, you know?
Wow. Right. Well, the guy that invented
the AK 47, I wish I would have invented a,
yeah.
Lauren and I like say Kalashnikov. I
think his name is. Yes, exactly. Yeah.
There is a, there's the quote, watch
Oppenheimer say this, this is even here.
Not Be the same.
People look at him saying, man, cried.
You see him up and people were silent.
I remember flying from the Hindu
scripture of the Bhagavad Gita.
Vishnu,
trying to persuade
you shouldn't do his duty.
Twain impresses him,
takes on multi armed form who says,
now I am becoming death. The
destroyer of worlds. Wow.
I suppose we all thought
that one way or another.
Wow.
He's haunted, isn't it? Yeah.
That's a hard to that story.
Wow. That's hardcore. Not Be,
could you imagine what it's like
to have no nuclear bomb ever.
And then all the sudden the nuclear
bombs here and it's coming from your
imagined that Jeanie,
you know, uh, that, that untold
history of America, you'll love it.
And there's a great thing in there about
the Cuban missile crisis and how close
we actually came to nuclear annihilation
in this country and in the world.
It's right. And apparently there
was like one, uh, Admiral Guy,
submarine Russian submarine,
a nuclear sub guy who stopped it all
because they had lost communication with
Moscow and their orders were
if they lost communication,
that means they've been attacked and
that they should launch the things.
So like they were totally about to attack
and it was this one guy's decision not
to do it. God, that would
have jam denialist it half
God,
there wasn't some fucking,
what was the guy who used to be the
attorney general? John Ashcroft.
We got to sing that Eagle Song,
that Christian, he goes song. Yeah,
the Christian Eagle Shoreham he wrote
a song, he wrote his own song. Yeah,
he was the attorney general
at one point in time. I mean,
that's a big position of power.
Could you imagine if a guy like that
was the guy who got to make the call?
At the end of the day, it is the admirals
and those guys who have to actually,
you know, make that call on the
submarine, but people have made it,
obviously they dropped
one of the Enola Gay,
they dropped the other one on Nagasaki.
What was the plane that dropped? Did that,
there was another plane. They know a
game. There was one other plane. Right.
Did I ever tell you Larry Small? I
don't, I'm sorry. I didn't know the name.
I'm changing subjects now again. What
was the question? I'm sorry about that.
I said there was the Enola gay,
but it was another plane that drops
him on Nagasaki. That's trivia.
A little boy with a bombs,
right?
Yeah, I've seen it. It's at the,
uh, Air Force Museum and date.
It's, yeah. I would watch that stupid
movie, Wolverine, the, the new one,
and he's a part of the,
uh, the Nagasaki now
one of them. And you know, the, the,
there's a nuclear blast and he gets
fucked up on the nuclear power, but he,
you know, turns back into
Wolverine again. Boxcar,
that's the box car.
There's another guy,
great guy I know who is the president
of the Smithsonian Museum and he used to
keep a name dropper. I
know, I know. I know.
And even intellectual named
John [inaudible] name dropper.
Sonya. Exactly what I must say, that
she was having tea with Oppenheimer.
I should be speaking this way.
Of course,
you get away with a great Taylor Michael,
of course, when you speak this way,
to get away with a great deal of
Joseph. I could pull in Jamaica, but my,
he used to keep a,
and a model of the Enola gay on
his desk and around his desk.
He had a red bonnet.
And when people would come in.
And this one person said to him,
you know,
I find your plane very offensive because
it dropped the bomb and killed 100,000
people. And he said, I agree
it's a terrible, um, symbol,
but I have also a red
bonnet around here. And, uh,
the bonnet belongs to my wife was a,
uh,
was in fact at a prisoner of war in
a Japanese in a concentration camp.
And she was, she had rickets
cause they wouldn't give her,
they weren't giving her enough
food or anything for that matter.
And when the bomb was dropped,
the Japanese surrender to my, my,
this little girl was liberated two days
later and ended up being my wife and
giving birth to my children.
So I actually liked the Enola gay.
It was kind of a
controversial thing to say,
but I remember there was something that,
yeah,
pilots said they, it was interviewed
about it or we talked about when they,
when he dropped that bomb,
uh,
that the plane felt like someone was
beating it with a telephone pole that like
the after blast. Oh my God. That
explosion. And, you know, they were,
they dropped it and they're, you know,
they're moving as far as philosophy.
And he said, even enough, not enough
that it still hold plane was just right
rocket. Yeah. That must
somebody fucked them up. I
mean, of course had to be, well,
I just think more than anything what
it does to your imagination and how you
must've felt the fear he misspelled at,
at the power human beings have to destroy.
It takes so long to build something.
Think about how long it would take to
build a city and then think how quickly
you can destroy a city or how long it
takes to build a human being and how easy
it is to destroy that human being.
That's always been the thing
about life that has kept me, uh,
I think in some ways motivated in that.
I don't know how much time I have,
but we were talking about it.
Stay positive and keep trying
to accomplish stuff cause
there's not a whole lot
of time to waste in a way to have my fun
before the whole Shit House goes up in
Jim Morrison.
Uh, and on that, on that, that,
that series was fantastic. Uh,
Gorbachev was totally wanted
to denuclearize know Russia
before the Soviet Union
collapsed. Uh, he realized that
it, you know, it was, phew, feudal,
they've spent all this money
and did a lot of that money,
could be educating and feeding really
poor Russian people. But Reagan, you know,
they were set on spending all this
money on the star wars program,
which all this money had been earmarked
for it, which is totally unnecessary.
And the Russians were totally,
you know,
doing whatever we wanted for these
treaties. And Reagan was just, you know,
big Dick Actor guy, you know,
playing hardball for, uh, you know,
the, the money war machine
of this country. But,
and that's actually what
they said, that, you know,
led to Gorbachev's demise and why the
Soviet Union ultimately collapsed. Well,
it was really interesting.
That was a super job,
actually was like this really
visionary, you know, smart.
He was like an agricultural leader.
He was like a farmer.
That's how he came to power in
Russia. But it had, you know,
that Reagan and then he totally,
you know, we wanted to do away with,
with all nuclear weapons and be friends
with the United States and rig and just,
you know, was the cowboy actor. But
before that, the Reagan doctrine
there, there was a very,
there was a systematic like decision
among many people in the United States
state, look, let's force the Soviets
into an arms race because they're,
our economy cannot support.
That's exactly what happened.
And so what we'll do is we'll literally,
that was the, the idea behind star wars,
the idea behind the STI and, and, and,
and just really pushing that arms
race on the Soviets, not just
nuclear, but also a
conventionally, you know,
we developed planes that flew way better
than those migs because we had an a
metal alloy that burned hotter
that could withstand more heat.
So our planes were faster and flew higher.
And that was a huge
advantage over the mix.
So the Soviets very quickly realized that
they were not going to able to compete
technologically with us. And, um,
that was, that's exactly right. Peep.
And lot of people say that the Soviet
first of all comments system was a failed
experiment for the most part.
But a lot of people say that so
much of it had to do with, you know,
I went there when I was 17 and 1985 and
one of the things that struck me was
seeing bread lines, people waiting
in line for bread in the morning.
And the other thing that really struck
me about being there at 17 years old,
and I'm not kidding about this,
no one smiles, no one smiles.
And I had grown up over the all over
the world and seeing different people.
Usually the people that I was around
look a little bit differently than I did.
Um, they were, uh, Pakistani or were
Indian or they were, they were a Lebanese.
When I went to Russia,
what was striking was that they looked,
they were Caucasian.
That somehow I saw all these
people that looked American and,
and they weren't smiling
and the food was terrible.
And there was this really in the way
they would clap when we would go to, um,
we went and saw these shows. They don't
clap like this, like the way we do,
they clap like this, all of them
at the same time. Like, uh, ah,
I like that.
That's how they clown the uniformity in
that society that was forced on them was
men. It was mind blowing. Um, I went
to Saint Petersburg about 10 years ago.
It was a it, yeah. I
see what you're saying.
Pretty bleak. But I mean, I
was here. There's a little
bit different though. Yeah.
I mean, I didn't want to,
I think a lot has changed.
I think things were way bleaker
when you were there, but I,
I see they weren't as happy
blamed the Mongols, but it wasn't,
it was a pretty cool time.
It was conquered those motherfuckers for
hundreds of years. Yeah. The Concord,
everybody. Yeah. The Mongols came
through Moscow in the winter.
They came through the,
through the fucking attacked Russia in
the winter because nobody else would do
it that way. And they didn't
need, they didn't see it coming.
Did I tell you how they, why they were
so hard to follow into the desert. Who?
The Mongols, you didn't have to
tell me. I know a lot about them,
but go ahead if you want to.
Well, just when you were fucking
educated. No, because did I tell you,
cause they were like, we
got some societies would get
their arms together. Have I,
have I briefed you? Have I briefed
you on the phone? Goes my friend.
I'm glad you, I'm glad
you asked. Uh, they,
they would get these arms together and
go into the Gobi desert after them cause
they'd be so fed up with their fucking
rates and stuff and everything else.
Problem was you can get about six days
in and [inaudible] that's when your water
starts to run out and then you have to
turn back around because you've got to
feed all your horses. Everybody
water, it's really dry.
You can maybe get six days in,
here's what the Mongols would be doing.
They'd be drinking their horses blood.
They'd be tapping a vein and just,
and just hang into of reach.
And then when you turn around all parched,
they'd wait until you were about a
day from home. They'd be like, oh,
they're really thirsty.
Here we come boys.
And they just close in
on you and district.
They did a lot of ruthless shit.
They were,
there were the most ruthless
motherfuckers of all time. Yeah.
And and gangs con ran into a huge problem
because he was doing these raids with
his,
his boys and you know,
like they would bring the young kids along
to teach them how to do these things.
And they also had a philosophy that if
you are a human being from another tribe,
whatever, you're basically
chattel. You're, you're on
the same level as a goat.
And stuff like that.
Problem was that these boys were
growing up seeing this horrific shit,
rape and stealing and looting and killing.
They started doing that
to their own women.
They started doing that to their own
people because these young warriors came
back to, you know, when they'd be
at the village and they would go,
I'm taking that. I want to rape
that girl. I'm taking this end.
Gangs can realized there was going to be
a breakdown from within kind of a snake
eating its own tail. And he had, uh, he,
he then had to really instill
the idea of the things that,
that glue is society together.
Not only do you,
you can't just tell
warriors how to behave,
you have to tell them why they have
to behave that way if you don't have a
philosophy. And it was a real crisis
for him and for his empire. Um,
which is the demise of the Mongol people.
Uh,
the demise of the uncle people apparently
was when they would come in and they
sacked most of what we know as
the Middle East. For example. Um,
the Middle East had its own renaissance
and it was destroyed by the Mongols.
They were huge shit heads.
But I think what happens to any
invading army is you start marrying,
you start there.
Not Everybody's an asshole.
You start ideas of win the day
or are you like, well, how much
is can we destroy until, you know,
there was a bunch of
issues with the Mongols.
One of them was the Gingiss Kahn died.
And his sons inherited his empire and
the son's never had to go through what he
went through.
So they were never the same man he was.
They didn't have the character
that he had that didn't,
they weren't brilliant
military strategists like he
was Dan Carlin's five part
series.
If anybody is interested in it and you
want to like learn about the Mongols
without actually having to read a book,
it's actually,
it's difficult and annoying.
Um, hardcore history.
It's called wrath of the con and it's an
amazing five part series in the Mongols
will freak you out man. Like there was a,
they were headed into Gin, China, these,
uh,
Arab dudes,
they were trying to check out China and
to see if maybe they should go in there
and kick some ass and take some, take some
riches or they had heard great things.
They got there and they
saw it in the distance.
What they thought was
a snow capped mountain.
It turned out to be a mountain of bones,
just a pile of bones because the
Mongols had killed a million people.
They killed every one.
They killed everyone in these cities
where they had 40 foot high clay walls and
they'd get there and there'd
be no one there. And the,
the choirs mean Shah's troops had to
turn around because the ground had become
decayed from rotting flesh.
It was just mud everywhere.
And the smell was so thick in the
air that his troops were dying.
They were dying from the fucking,
the odors of the dead bodies are so
many dead bodies. The roads were gone.
There was no roads.
It was just mud from decaying flesh.
I asked us historian on my podcast if
they were really that bad and he's spent
his life studying the Mongols I snow.
They really that bad. And he said, yeah,
they were really
well. Uh, there were Great Wall of China.
The Great Wall of China was built to
keep the Mongols out. Yeah. And uh,
if you go there now, I was just, I
just got back from China on Monday.
I went to the Great
Wall like two weeks ago,
but the first time I went to the Great
Wall was about 12 years ago. And, uh,
there's Mongolian people
hang out on the top,
just a few of them that are like selling
things like woman's selling postcards
and cheap stuff. And, uh, I bought
some postcards. It was like a dollar.
I gave the woman a 10. She wouldn't
give me the change. Uh, so, you know,
they change. They might, uh,
be rotten people historically,
but I also want to remind you that they'll
cheat yet the Great Wall, Tom. Tom,
that's outrageous. The Great Wall.
She wouldn't give you change.
How did that go down? Uh, you know,
good friends, good friends. You know,
it was just to keep the money. That was
awkward. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah.
Good friends, good
friends, good friends. Uh,
I would just set the Great Wall and again,
did you get your money? Uh, I didn't.
They, they, there was a few.
They're selling like cokes and some
different trinkets. I didn't, uh,
I didn't fall for it this
time. It's crazy. The wall $10.
I never got it back. No. Wow.
No, no, no. A detailed question.
Now at the Great Wall, I know it
is a TMC, Cancun. He had my friend,
my good friend, I've got, I've got
it. I've got a video on Youtube, uh,
Beijing, Tom Rhodes, Beijing, and it's
on there. I had my camera running. Oh,
you could see the woman,
the woman.
And she's not giving me the
change in my little Beijing video.
And what's all the video title again? It's
Tom Rhodes. Beijing. Okay. Uh, and what,
and what's in that video
also is the greatest thing.
As great as the Great Wall is,
there is a Toboggan slide
that you go down as a little,
you get it sit on like a little loose
plastic thing and you got to stick between
your legs and you push it forward to
go fast and pull it back to slow down.
And it's windy and it's got some
huge drops in it. And I went there.
I don't remember that.
Damn. There's three,
there's three sections that tourists
can go to the Great Wall. Yeah.
And there's only the one section that
has this fantastic, magnificent slide.
Right. And it's thrilling. And then you,
you get down to the bottom and there
a big, it's on that Beijing video.
I've filmed it while I did it,
but I just,
I just did it again a few weeks ago
and at the bottom, uh, are there,
it is exactly. Uh, is there, there's
some, there's some Chinese, a soldier,
communist guys would like military
jackets on down at the bottom on these big
turns going slow down,
slow down. You're moving.
Because obviously they've had a few
people like fly off lip off the corners.
Oh my God. Whoa. How are you slowing down?
How do you slow it down and what you just,
you pull this stick towards you.
Oh my God. And I did it. I wouldn't see
that was in winter when I first went,
but I just did it again, man. It's, it's,
I wanted to go right back up at the top.
Is that as great as the Great Wall is?
I think that slide is even cooler and
that's so avoid the Mongols at the top.
I want to see the Mongo footage.
I want to see that broader is
the only manmade structure.
From what I understand that you can see.
Apparently that's horse shit.
I said that too. It sounds
like it is. Here it is.
Oh yeah. Yeah. There's the Mongolia
[inaudible]. Cool. You look at and go, oh,
winter with the snow on it.
Okay. 10 cars this go. Oh.
Oh. [inaudible] never chip. All right.
How much is, yeah,
what's that? 10 10 yeah,
it's good change. Okay.
Will you do that a one?
Yeah. Yeah. Where's my chain?
Let's go have a little, no, no.
10 10 [inaudible] James [inaudible].
No, one 10 12 times here. I'm
[inaudible] the Great Wall.
Give me one of them. Okay. And
then we're either, okay. All right.
It sounds to me like you asked her a 10
I gave her a 10 it was a dollar for the
postcards. Right? But she was
saying, yeah, 10 Oh, okay. Very good.
Have you go back? I think it
was a miscommunication. No, she,
she thought you were paying
10 bucks. That's what it
sounded like to me. 10 cars.
The woman knew fully what was happening.
Oh listen,
I trust you $1 and get it. All
right. How much is he guys? 10. 10?
Yeah. 10. 10 yeah, like
change, change, change. Okay.
What you do that like 10 times?
He seems like the Taller,
okay, so she and change. She
did say change. I change.
What can we all love?
She's pushed you to look at her.
She's kind of like,
she slapped you with your knuckle.
Her knuckles.
She's every bit as wide
as you are by the way.
And then where are you should probably
eat you. Yeah, like no one's around.
I just saw, I just spent three weeks
in China and she probably would
eat you by drink. My horses will give
you that too. Is that the compensation?
That was it. Yeah. That's actually not bad
deal. That wasn't a bad cold metal dude.
You won. You won the bronze. Ah, I just
got back from China on Monday and it's,
I have to say, the nice thing about
our country is the prices. The price.
You don't have to, how much is this a
200 are you kidding me? That you know,
they'll give you like the highest price.
You want to buy something and you know
it's only a couple of dollars and they'll
say, how much is that? $80 he was like,
no way that that can be $80 and then
you get them down. You're like halfway.
Why don't you just tell me what you need?
But some telling me the price you need.
[inaudible] oh yeah,
part, it's partnering.
But don't we have that here with car
sales and certain why's it gotta be like
that? Why can't you just give me
the price? I don't understand it.
I heard it's my charge.
What you need on the little extra over
and just tell me what to say. That's,
I literally,
that's how I do it.
Cry, go. Listen. I know you
want to make some money on this.
I'm not going to kill you. I'm not,
I don't have any energy to haggle.
If you want to take a little
bit advantage of me, it's fine.
Just give me a price I can live with.
I don't want to hear that.
I got completely destroyed and it's a
hundred bucks extra, whatever. Yeah,
like whatever. I don't want to do that.
But some people love it. They don't,
they don't want to buy anything unless
they can haggle. They like, come on z,
you gotta help me out here.
Give me something, give me
a little something like it.
Yeah. It's like there's a thrill
involved in the negotiation.
You can walk away knowing that
they saved $5 or whatever.
If you think about it though, that's
kind of exactly how Wall Street works.
I mean you,
you think something's worth something
and the other person thinks it's worse to
this. I mean with this take
derivatives are that way.
I'm betting on the company going up.
You're betting on the company going down
and he's betting on the company staying
where it is. So let's look, there's,
there's a financial instrument
that reflects that. I'll buy,
I'll short it or I'll go long on
it. That's exactly how, you know,
huge sums of money are
made and lost and every day
you're absolutely right. I was
just, when I was in Hong Kong,
I got to go on Bloomberg
financial television. Whoa.
And I was interviewed by like their four
main host and Bloomberg financial news
goes all over the world.
And uh,
for some reason this guy
that the guy that, uh,
coordinated the shows had a link with
Bloomberg and I'm on there and it's there
for Maine worldwide hosts
and they're all like,
all these questions kept and they had to,
they're asking me about the markets,
you know,
that's a sure sign of the apocalypse
when I'm on Bloomberg television and
they're asking,
they're just throwing all these financial
questions at me. Like I asked you
what did I think of, uh, Ben Bernanke?
He retiring and I said,
I think now he has to turn in
his skin suit and go back to lizard form.
And the guy goes,
reptilian. And I go, yeah, there's like,
I mean, they were like such serious,
I mean there was a,
there was a Steven Seagal
is Asian will not stop.
He does not know way better than Steven
Seagal looks like. And I hate tie.
He looked like an athletic Steven Seagal
Cowen. How dare you? A little bit there.
He looks fantastic. He's a good looking
at me. He's a good looking guys call.
How dare you,
how dare you to Steven Seagal.
You look like a good little Steven Seagal.
I hate being called Steven Seagal.
Sorry. Yeah. Okay man.
And the podcast goes down hate
if those skills were necessary.
Knock, knock, knock, knock. Who's
there? Steven Seagal. Steven Seagal.
Who at Showbiz.
Oh God showed the Showbiz joke.
Anyway,
I'm on this financial thing and
they're throwing these questions at me.
It was uh, it was ridiculous. And the,
the attractive Asian woman
tried to get all philosophical.
Let me hear that with me.
A lot to say about how many
killer before this. Yeah,
it's actually something I thought
of the last time I was on your show.
I said this thing about pockets
started all our financial problems.
And so,
um,
let me buy you a drink and I haven't
been to groundwater for the Douche bag.
Please.
There we go.
The guy pushed it is, he goes, he
goes, what's up, what's up? They all,
they're all calling. Ooh. All right.
Probably the last time you're going
to have a Canadian. Others, right.
But see what that guy did there.
He goes,
what's the worst pump comeback Glen
you have for a heckler? And I said,
it's too filthy to say on television.
And he says, what's your second best one?
So I mean he, the dude should
have left it alone. And this is,
I'm on live television and I'm trying to
be clever and quick in this barrage of
questioning that guy and that.
And then they all get like, Whoa,
we're concentrating on
were abandoned for markets.
Well you fucked up then son.
Oh, I could get over is a,
in this video is how weird are dresses
that girls, both of their vaginas,
that is a [inaudible] mind,
right?
This strange dresses she's got on,
she's got this little thing. It's
draped over the opening of the vagina.
Just so clever.
Like the parts that we're going to show
is right up to the gateway of the vagina.
And then from there there's nothing
but a breeze. Nothing but a breeze.
And to cross legs and this tiny,
the thinnest possible type of cloth we
can make the thinnest lightest most times
see through.
You could see pubic hair right through
the fucking thing that's there. Hey man,
you're getting a little too detailed
and it's just weird. It's just weird.
Our women are allowed to do that.
It's so rude.
No wonder why alimony laws are
in the position they're in, in.
We're at a severe disadvantage.
Disadvantages by their
attire. They're there.
They're there. They're fucking dangling.
A carrot there dangling the carrot.
It's rude. I never realized that it's
total dangle. There isn't a move.
I don't want that.
How about the fact they've got shoes on
that make their ass do something that it
never does in real life.
You're leaning forward is if you just
begging for someone to fuck the doggy
style, like all day long, you're
just accentuating your ass.
You're leaning forward like you're just,
you're giving step one to a five step
process of doggy style and you're already
at step one everywhere
you go. Genius. Why?
Why isn't the man who invented high heels?
Why isn't that a household name
that that's the most genius thing?
Because you can get guys will spend,
I put myself in debt buying girls dinner.
Who looked that good and high heels and
the heels come off in their back of your
house and everything else
changed and you're like, aw man.
That's just somehow that's
a huge difference. I mean,
I'm totally different.
That doesn't do a damn thing to me.
Really doesn't do anything to me.
I don't get it at all. I mean,
if a woman has beautiful legs,
the legs are beautiful and like
if she's barefoot just as hot.
Well, when [inaudible] walked
with confidence and heels,
not like those big stripper fuck stiletto
things, but like, like Nice, nice,
nice high heels.
We see a woman who was like
walks confidently and know
what I'm saying is like
it. Yeah, it is definitely
a debilitating, yeah.
It's like a man who's really crappy.
Caveman drew up.
It's like a man is really
good at the trapeze
with skill he's acquired.
Oh.
What I'm saying is that a woman can
have not such a great ass when and they,
the right heels. You can get very
fooled where you, oh, I see. Wow. Yeah.
It definitely accentuates. Things
come off and you're like, oh,
well that wasn't exactly what I did. Like
lingerie does do shit for me. I mean,
I guess it does. If it looks good, it
looks good. I mean, but if like, you know,
is it necessary? No. No. I noticed
when a woman dresses well and cool,
like some girls dress really
cool in an effortless way.
I find that very attractive.
You're a weird motherfucker.
That's why you're into fashion. Yes,
I am turned to the left fashion.
What if a girl showed up at your house
with velcro shoes on and a fanny pack,
but she had a banging ass banger.
Yeah, it wouldn't really bother you.
Bother me at all when you're talking
about a girl computer, burlap sack.
I don't give a shit. Forget that. In
moments when she was naked and it's like,
guys, I've always been the kind
of guy like my friends back. Nah,
I would have did it, but I couldn't get
past her feet. Shut the fuck up you baby.
There are some feet. They're really
will fuck you up. She could have holes.
All right.
She's got to go back and ask if there's
an evolutionary thing for that though.
Someone's got some crazy fucked
up feet. You're like, Hey,
am I going to have to carry you?
That's what I'm looking for. Food.
It's going to be a certain point in time
where you're not going to be able to
make it. Are you going? I wonder if that's
true. It's 100% what it is. Cause I do.
I also did be feet. How can we
not weirded out about her elbows?
I like petite arched feet that I
think are an arched foot is very sexy.
A petite foot. Really? That's
so weird. Yeah. Yeah. That's
not good. I liked the arch.
A a flat foot on a,
I like the foot of a woman who
I can go hiking. A woman who's
got some sturdiness to her. Yeah,
you have to have a little tiny fee.
Fucking Weirdo.
He wants these checks to be
like barely able to talk. Okay,
brow. Excuse me sir. You just led me into,
I can't give you chances to high.
Can you do food?
I'm going to happen. They have to
have a German accent on in her life
and he's the cow. We're married.
What's the ideal way? Right, right.
He'll wait for me. Another dimension. If
you weren't married, what's the ideal way?
About 80 pounds?
No, no, no, no. It's a breeding thing
I need, I need about one 15 is good.
One 15 one 2015 but athletic. I like
athletic. I like broad shoulders,
small waist and a and
high insertion calves.
It's funny, man. The
the skirt thing, it's a,
it's a very weird thing when you see them
walking down the street and especially
in Hollywood,
like on Melrose,
you'll see people walking on the street
where their skirt and these are not
sluts. I shouldn't even use that
word. We shouldn't slut shame.
It's really not nice. Yeah, and women
who want to have sex with people,
they don't slots.
No.
Mary Helen just enjoying their life.
Lord,
I hate myself for using their angel from
the Lord. What I should say, these are,
these are not prostitutes.
These are just girls like to dress in
style and sexy and they're wearing these
shorts that are just, there's just
a little canopy over your vagina.
I mean it's dangling,
right?
I mean right there you're talking about
maybe three in chart to get work done,
maybe three inches and they have a skirt
that like the lower part of their ass.
It's a normal thing to see the lower
part of a girl's ass and a skirt in
Hollywood. It's a normal thing.
Exactly. It's ridiculous. It's,
it fucks the whole game up. It
completely ruins distracting. It's,
it completely ruins our ability to form
rational thoughts and figure out if we
were at before the podcast you were
talking about how important it is to keep
your mind on the right things. Yeah.
In a way some societies are like,
you know what?
All women are going to be completely
covered cause nobody's getting any fucking
work done. Maybe that's where the
burger came from. Burger King,
we need to build a fucking pyramid,
goddammit.
We don't need to be staring at my
ass all day cover these veterans.
We've got work to do, cover them. Cover
covering lab. We got to build pyramids.
We gonna push rocks. Nobody
wanted to push push rods. Yeah.
They just want to stare at chicks and
ministers. We'll hook up eventually.
If you have enough attracted people and
the of the opposite sex in the same room
for long enough things are going.
Yeah. Even if you're not in the same
room, it's exactly, they smell each other.
We're fucking Weirdos.
Um,
it's interesting because everybody will
remember when you were in high school,
when you were learning about Rome and
the collapse of the empire and it was
always about the,
the excesses.
It was always Caligula and the vomitorium,
which apparently allegedly weren't real.
Apparently there's no real evidence that
there was vomitorium that they really
like stick a fat down there
there. Oh yeah. Tour. Let me,
let me make sure that's true
because, uh, I believe I read that,
but it could have been another of those,
I've read articles,
that's one of the problems with
fucking the internet as you'll read,
like really convincing articles and
then you start like saying it like it's
Gospel truth. And then you read an
article that's totally contradict,
contrary to that, totally the opposite
conclusion. And that's very convincing to,
and you're like, God,
that's why books are.
That's why historians who do a lot of
primary research and really work on their
source material though,
that's why,
that's where you should get the bulk of
your information. Professors and and,
and history.
Oh this is interesting.
Vomitorium is actually a passage situated
below or behind a tier of seeds in an
amphitheater or stadium through which
big crowds can exit rapidly at the end of
the performance.
So it's actually the idea is like the
idea of a vomitorium like that's I it
sounds like it was ignorance. It sounds
like a, whoever was talking about,
I didn't understand that that was a,
from a Latin word,
which means to spew forth meaning how
to get crowds in and out of places.
Well,
so like we like decided that it was,
there was a room that they
would go after dinner and vomit,
but for sure someone's done that
right. For someone, for sure.
If someone stuck a feather than it
throats that they could keep eating.
Sure why not if everything's happened
that's happened. I had a really cool,
this,
this professor at Oxford Philosophy press
professor was talking about the rise
of Christianity and why it took hold.
And one of the things he said is in,
during Rome, Rome was, you know, had,
had conquered so much of the world,
um,
and Rome was kind of bursting at the
scenes with Greek philosophy with their,
their, their, their elite were
taught by Greek, uh, tutors and,
and their documents officially
were written in Greek.
And so Socrates and Aristotle,
all the great philosophers had a
profound effect on the Roman empire,
their justice system. They're there,
their property, right laws and things.
And at the end of the day,
regardless,
the Roman empire was
crumbling from the inside out.
It was to came from the inside out.
And along comes this radical rabbi, uh,
Jesus Christ,
Christ Jesus of Nazareth who comes
along and with this radical idea and his
apostles, you know, later on took
these ideas into the Roman empire.
But it took hold basically,
you know,
the theory was because people
were looking for something more.
The idea that it's not just about reason,
it's about faith.
There's two articles that are hilarious.
Back to back,
just to prove what we were just
talking about. One of them was Jesus,
a Roman invention and the,
there's an article on Huffington Post
that there's a guy who, uh, is a,
a biblical scholar,
allegedly who is a,
has these revelations threatening to undo
Christianity and that he believes that
he's got proof that they're, that
the, the, the idea of Christian was a,
a creation with the idea of Jesus Christ
was a creation by the Romans. Well,
it lasted, that's for sure. Yeah, but
I mean it's possible there could be,
but it's fascinating. There's that
and, but if you further, by the way,
Huffington post has one of those weird
things where tries to get you to not back
click, wow, those are so gross. Why
would we try to scroll backwards?
It just resets the page. Scroll
backwards or hate that shades. It only,
it happens only on the,
when you use the swipe thing on a
laptop to go backwards. But it doesn't,
if you actually use the Arrow, but you've
got to go out there and use the arrow.
But you go to a Catholic answers and
then the title of the article is, no,
the Romans did not invent Jesus.
So it's like you could find
whatever you want to find.
You could find the Romans invented Jesus.
You could find that Jesus
was a real historical guy.
Well, if it, yeah.
Christianity filled in the, uh,
power vacuum after the collapse of
the Roman Empire. Constantinople,
his wife was a Christian
Constantine. Yeah. Uh, and uh,
some reason that what caused that,
why they decided to submit it.
Yeah.
Christianity is not in Italy,
decided to accept the idea that Christ
was Lord, you know, cry that, that he was,
he was more than just flesh.
But do you ever see the God who was there,
um, God who wasn't there was a
documentary [inaudible] 2005, disproving?
Well, uh, apparently, uh, according
to the documentary, disproving the,
uh, the, the actual birth
and life of Jesus Christ.
The saying that it was just a myth.
Well,
well either way,
what I think is actually interesting and
kind of radical about the idea of was
in Rome, the entire ethos and Credo of
the, of the country was, might makes,
right. I mean, there's
statues were muscular,
it was all about domination and there was
the week and there were the strong and
they had a whole pantheon of gods that,
you know,
kind of supported something of
that and, and, and their gods also,
we're kind of gods that were a little
bit out of reach if you didn't,
don't pray to them too much
cause you might anchor them.
They were always a little bit out of
reach, you know? Yeah. I mean, they were,
they were, they were their own. Yeah.
They were their own kind of entity
that you could sort of sometimes have
communion with,
but you had to be very careful because
they were jealous and they would do
things to you. The idea that you and
your wife, right, sure. They would do.
That's what Zeus did. Write a song
to leave it. But, but what, um,
what Christianity came along and said was,
which is interesting and I'm, I'm just,
I'm not, I've never been very religious
but love, love, love thy enemy. Uh,
um, and the idea of forgiveness,
um, and the idea of love in general,
those are very,
it's interesting how powerful and soft,
but how powerful and resonant those
ideas are and how they stayed powerful,
uh, help the needy, help the weak.
The meek shall inherit the earth.
Those I talking like a preacher,
they're very enduring ideas in the
beauty Birtle era when that it's put on.
That was,
that was a radical yet even the example
of whether it's true and I love of him
being Sacral, you know,
crucified and torture and stuff.
Those ideas are all like ideas that
everyone has. If you're a moral person,
if you love your friends
and neighbors, if you, you,
you realize after life and years of
experience what's good and what's bad,
you know, when it works out,
it seems to work. I want,
I'm nice to people write that shit down.
I mean this, they say that that was,
you know, there was anything
other than that. Well,
it did though have an effect on history
and it did change things. No one knows.
No one knows where the
fuck of it came from.
No one knows where any of these
obvious tampon. And not only that,
by the time you are getting them the,
the,
the way they'd been broken down from
ancient Hebrew to Latin, to Greek,
ancient Hebrew,
there's still struggling with most of it.
It's like three quarters of the words in
ancient Hebrews like some debate about,
because they had numbers
and numbers were letters,
the letters or numbers and the
numerical value to the words.
So anybody saying that it means anything.
It's like, boy, you sure that's a,
you need a lot of fucking scholars to
sit down and break that shit down for you
to be confident about what you've read in
English. But what the Bible says, stop.
I believe in God, but I think, uh,
all the evidence took the fucking air out
of the room. All the evidence, uh, uh,
points that God's in
asshole it'd be exist.
Why would he put the three major
religions capital in the same spot?
And then I've traveled all over the world.
Why couldn't he have put like
the Jews capitol in Hawaii,
like the Christians in
the Caribbean where,
why would he have more
than one where everybody,
everyone would be happy to visit the
other person's place. Christianity,
Christianity,
Islam come from the, I mean the Old
Testament is recognized in both,
in both religions. Right.
As, as the first book.
Do you know all over stone's son converted
to Islam? No, I didn't do he really,
that's what you know, you
raised your kid, right?
Awesome. Yeah. You knocked
it out of the park.
That is the old white American Dad.
Super fucking storm.
I think I'm going to convert to,
there's only one way.
See the writing on the wall. Don't ask
you what this fucking breeze is going.
Yeah.
I'm joining that team.
Hello? Uh, well, um, uh,
Cat Stevens decided,
I guess he got really Christian then he
decided to be a Muslim. Yeah. I mean he,
he went deep and he basically
stopped recording. I know for years.
Didn't he do a new album recently?
Yeah, we did a couple of years ago.
That's a strange cat man.
Who knows man,
more than one guy has done it more than
one guy, smarter than me. He's converted.
I don't to all sorts of things,
man.
I've met brilliant people that converted
to Mormonism. I'm like, Huh? I mean,
I don't know what it is. I don't know
what's going on. I don't even want to ask.
I don't. I'm too slow. But
it's the, it's the, it's,
it's the ideas that I was talking about
where those go simple ideas that seem
like they're, like you said, I
don't know where they came from,
but the fact that they lasted and,
and maybe they,
I think they always existed with
human beings. Like it's, you know,
it's things that people learn. Everyone
learns. If you're in a tribal situation,
everyone learns comradery.
You all learned that.
You don't want your family
members get eaten by a lion.
We all learn how to keep each other
together and we all feel the rush of
survival. We all love each other.
There's a little bit of a difference.
The differences this, and
this was, this was the,
the essentially what the
Christians, I believe, uh,
the idea at the example of Christianity
contributed was idea that yes,
tribes will say that about each other,
the mangoes and everybody else.
The difference was that along comes this,
this guy, whether you know he was God,
he existed. The idea was all of
us are of the same moral worth.
We all come from the same father.
No matter what your skillset,
no matter what your skin color,
no matter what your background
and that idea it has lasted.
And that idea is the cornerstone of
our justice system and everything else.
That that is the contract.
That's what every hippie
figures out when they get high,
what happens is every hippie
figures that out when they get high,
we're all the same man. We are all
the same dude. You eat a pot Brownie,
that's exactly what you'll figure out.
Figure out where all exactly the same.
So it's like,
you know,
the idea that this was some mass magical
thing to figure out, like come on.
Well, everybody figures out that it was
given forum, like the Bible gave it forms,
sort of,
you know,
it also just was wrapped up by a bunch
of bishops and content team to try to
control people. But you still need symbols
I guess to, you know, to fall back.
I couldn't do the pagans
were too hard to pin down.
These motherfuckers are worshiping
the moon and shit and like stop there,
there to make too much sense.
You know,
they would celebrate during the summer
solstice and the winter solstice.
They all these celebrations
they would not budge from.
So Christianity had to say,
ah, let's see, listen to this.
What a fucking coincidence.
Odd Jog.
Fucking God was born in the same day as
you went and sold to one of the odds.
You guys gotta join us, join up with us.
Come on. We up the fucking same thing.
We call it Christmas. We said
we'll put a tree out, you know,
and they started like incorporating
pagan aspects into their,
where are we running naked this April?
Jesus was supposed to be born in April.
He wasn't born in July was kind of
December, you know, it's pretty wild.
I always forget about like one of the
enduring qualities of at least Catholicism
is the idea of confession.
That is a very strong,
strong thing to be able to go to a priest
once a week or every day and confess
your sins,
right.
And be absolved of them. Wow.
And it's totally anonymous.
Talk about the first therapy.
There is clearly that that was bullshit.
Biggest things. People wasn't the
first. There you are crazy that that we,
that was invented purely to control
rebellion to figure out who's doing what.
Wrong. To figure out who's or trying
to overthrow the Catholic church. Oh,
a hundred percent dude.
You weren't even allowed to do you mean?
You mean like being
able to confess fashion?
They want to know what the fuck you did.
They want to keep tracks on everybody.
Tell us what you did or you're
going to fucking fry in hell.
But now you don't have to fry in hell.
Congratulations. Go see a few of these.
And we got all the
information we need from you.
So if you were hanging out with
Martin Luther, the Anabaptist,
you were thinking about taking over
the Catholic church because the fucking
Catholic Church wouldn't let you print
the Bible out in a phonetic form.
No one could read the Bible.
You had to rely on priests until
Martin Luther came along and so they,
they were fucking flight and
people on fire for that man to him.
Martin Luther was branded a heretic
and he had to leave wherever. Germany,
Germany, yeah, I know Germany,
but I can't,
I'm trying to think of the town.
Good way to fucking find out what
people are looking, but I like, oh,
it's the real, it's really what it
was invented for. It's, it's a total,
a hundred percent position of power
and control. That's all it is.
You mean this guy is either way,
either way.
It worked and it kept people very loyal
to the church and continues to be to
keeps people scared.
You know,
there are priests that are out there
that are listening to you and not telling
people things.
I liked it. Lenny Bruce, he had a,
he had a priest outfit and he would
go around Miami and like he would take
confessions and talk to people. He
just, there was a little period,
I don't know where you bought it
or had it made, but it's hilarious.
One of Lenny Bruce Biographies.
So he's just, you know,
Jewish guy and he's dressed up like
a priest, want to people's houses,
listening to their confessions.
They just, the idea of it, you know,
you get absolved. You not only that,
you could absolve people and get
a free pass through purgatory,
have to do some bad shit if you donate
money to the church. That's right.
There was selling free pass.
Uh, I was in, um, uh,
Naples, uh, in September,
Italian city dropper and
there was a church there. Oh,
really? Corrupt. I saw a guy, uh, uh,
trying to snatch and an iPad out of some
older Australian couples backpack and
the wife saw him again away from there and
to do, just shrugged, like, uh, you know,
I guess I've lost money touch. You know
why? Like I'm a thief, that's what I do.
But in Naples,
there was a church of a souls in
purgatory and there was all these like,
uh,
you know,
skulls in front of it and whenever it
was made in the 13 hundreds or whatever,
but these like rich Catholics there,
they were concerned about
the soul stuck in purgatory.
So they spent all this money and made
this, uh, this church for them. Well,
purgatory was even invented to try
to convert pagans because they were,
the Irish believed in the land of fe.
They live,
but they believed in this land
where like fairies and elves lived,
that it was like just over there, you
know, probably because of mushrooms,
they're probably eating mushrooms.
I mean,
it's most likely if you tried to figure
out like why you would think that ELLs
were in some like nearby
dimension that you could reach.
And so the Catholics had convinced
him, oh Nah, that's purgatory. Yeah,
we know about that. Yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah. That's when you go,
when you're not a good guy.
I've got to stay there for a little bottle
and a half in so you don't have to go
all the way to hell.
Well,
I'd also like family can buy you off that.
Yeah.
The penalty box for Dante is divine.
The divine comedy was all about
purgatory, right? That was the great work.
The divine comedy. It's amazing
what people wouldn't fan to control.
People like the stupid shit that
they [inaudible] ology story.
Well that kind of stuff. I
mean, when you got to direct,
when you know there's a direct
path between the Christians
trying to incorporate
the Pagans, the pagans, not wanting
to be altering of the timelines of it,
you know, like, Oh, our celebration,
same as your celebration.
Let's figure out how to make this happen.
I'm less cynical about,
I'm actually a little bit more of a fan
of the idea that I, that those ideas
carried, uh, carry forth and have
lasted so long because there is,
there is truth to them. The
idea that we're all the same
moral worth. For example,
uh,
the idea of [inaudible] fucking lecture.
That was the interesting thing about gets
intellectually interesting, so smooth.
That was the interesting thing about
China was am I lagers chrome belief system
is so different that they are like their,
their holidays are different.
Their whole mindset and like all these
things that we just accepted our reality.
There's a whole different mental
world going on in the channel
Dow, right? Confucius, that's the idea of
being balanced, balanced as huge harmony,
being in harmony with everything
around you. Do you ever hear that,
that they did this great study where
they had Chinese people look at that fish
tank and Americans look at a fish tank?
No. When they asked them to describe it,
they, Americans described the
fish and the Chinese didn't net.
The fish were just a part of,
they described the relationship
between the seaweed, the stones, uh,
the fish,
how much water was in the tank.
They were looking at the whole thing
and how it all related to each other.
The fish were just a part. There
were no more important. For example,
then the stones,
when they asked Americans to describe
how many stones or what kind of seaweed
the Americans had no idea because
they were just looking at the fish.
This is the way they came up with a
December 25th date for Jesus. They, uh,
that the, the, the world was created.
This is awesome. Laughing. Um,
the, they tried to figure out,
um,
when from the idea of when he was
conceived and to go from there.
That's, that's where it was a, that's
where they started it out from.
It came from the point of
conception, which was, um,
and didn't the Pagan
holiday involve a tree. So,
and we just incorporated that tree.
Yeah. Maybe. I don't know. I'm
trying, I'm trying to find this thing.
Shit.
Well, again, the Internet again.
Sorry. I'm Brian [inaudible].
You can't talk about Chinese people and
fish without a me telling this story.
Uh, Joe, are you ready for this?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. You
got the information? Yeah.
No, I don't. It's, um, it's,
it's kind of ambiguous.
There's a lot of debate on this.
This is not something that like
anybody really assure of when this, uh,
this dude was actually born,
the church leaders decided that they
needed a Christian alternative to rival
popular solstice celebrations.
They chose December 25th as the date
of Christ's birth and held the first
recorded feast of activity in Rome.
Um,
so the idea was they reckon the world was
created in the spring equinox and four
days later on March 25th light was created
since the existence of Jesus signaled
the beginning of the new
era or a new creation,
the biblical chronographs [inaudible]
assume that Jesus has conception would
have also fallen on March 25th placing
his birth in December nine months later
seems logical. I mean, they created
the earth and then four days later
light Duh Duh. What? Okay.
It seems like a good day or a
problem with that very historic,
keep in mind that it is the Internet.
So we're not sure if it's a
hundred percent true. Yeah,
this is all I want to hear. Tom
Rhodes. I tell the story please.
So I was just in Hong Kong
a few weeks ago and uh,
I remembered this story of something
that happened to me the very first time I
went to Hong Kong was like 12 years ago.
And I'd never been to Hong Kong and China
and I was really excited and wanted to
see it.
I was staying at the Shangri la hotel,
the most opulent, fancy, luxurious
hotel I've ever been in my life.
I mean above, beyond
Fivestars, just swink.
And so the first day I just walked and
walked and I wanted to soak a as much of
Hong Kong and my eyeballs. I could just
see the city and I'm walking around.
And when I got back to my hotel
room at the end of the day,
they had put a goldfish in a little
goldfish bowl on my desk and it had a note
and it said,
traveling is sacred,
but no one deserves to be alone.
That's why we've provided the goldfish.
It's awesome to be your friend and
keep you company during your stay here.
Thank you.
So two nights later,
Fatboy slim is doing a concert on
the Calhoun side of the harbor.
I love Fatboy slim. I'd never seen
him. I had a, you know, somehow
got some ecstasy or whatever it was.
And uh,
it was,
it was such a great night.
These Chinese people were just
so stylish and fashionable.
They looked like he had fallen
out of fashion magazines.
I just had such a great time dancing in
the middle and a Fatboy slim was just
electrifying that night. And I drank tons
and I got really, really drunk, you know,
life of a car. Uh, that night
when I'm sleeping back in my hotel room,
I shit the bed.
I'm like,
Huh,
awake, you know, that kind of a wet or
drunk sleep. And I thought it was a Fart,
you know,
and I looked,
I blow it out and it's like wet
ass p goes all over the bed.
And I had never,
I'd never should've been before.
I'd never should've been
in my welcome to the team.
I just absolutely say I have
absolutely ashamed that it happened.
I felt the title. So the next day I
went and I walked all over the city.
And you know, uh, when I
came back to my hotel room,
they had taken my golden.
You didn't even bother. Nobody
deserves to be alone except for you.
You been shitting Hickory.
Bad Shit and x freak.
That's the problem. Actually.
See sexy until you shit though.
It's such a lovely thing.
They put a little goldfish
in my room. That's nice man.
Beautiful. So Nice. Hey, someone makes a
really good point on this message board.
How the fuck did Christianity, uh, sure.
Everyone being equal
and yet still slavery?
That was exactly the debate.
The Abraham had slaves. Uh,
so the, the, the slaveholders would cite
the Old Testament, but you're right.
I mean, that was in fact, right?
It's also what Martin Luther King and
a lot of a lot of abolitionists used to
as, as fuel to fight the
slave trade, which was what?
That we are all have the same
father. Am I not a man? The,
the abolitionists always
reciting those kinds of things.
But why would they, uh, going if
they're going by the Old Testament,
the old testament's the real deal,
the new testament is the one that's got
clear fuckery attached to it, right? Well,
so if you're going to go by the word of
God, then oldest shit, you can get less.
I don't know the fuck.
The fundamental difference was this,
the young Ted seat that Christ said,
the good news is all of us can be
essentially, uh, Jews are okay, are, are,
are children of have the same father.
So it's not,
the Old Testament was very
much for the, you know, in,
in taught in the temple and ms for this
small group of people called the Jews.
But along comes Christ who says,
you know, you can't tell people,
talk how people read the book of
Leviticus about it, how to quarter a calf.
It just, you know, there's
just all not to eat off spray.
None of this shit is relevant.
What monitors matters is that you do
want to others as you'd have them do unto
that Christ guy. That's the
idea. That would be the idea. Oh,
let's just all allegedly Joe
Rogan's going to hell because Jesus,
it's individualized
mating.
Fascinating thing that in 2013 just this
conversation is very dangerous to some
people. This is a dangerous topic. Yeah.
People get angry at you for discussing
whether or not a Zombie existed,
whether or not a guy died and three days
later came back to life because he was
mad.
I'm not making that argument,
man. I'm not having any,
I'm not all I'm talking about.
Yeah, no, I know. Historical figure,
but it's talking about that.
I'm just talking about what was,
what Christianity's tenants are.
That's all me up
and thinking about how many people
are going full bore for the, you know,
historical,
Biblical version.
There's the Gallup poll most recent that
they did in like the late two thousands
about someone. They asked him, dude,
how old do you believe the earth is?
Do you believe in the Biblical
version of creationism?
And like 46% said they thought the
earth was less than 10,000 years old as
stated in the Bible. Well, that's more
proof that if that statistic is right,
that's scary. It's not, I'm sure, because
it's, first of all, it's a statistic,
which means that the only people
that answer idiots, right? So you're,
you're getting idiots that answer these
fucking, these, these questionnaires,
nobody, nobody will though life or a job
or time you always hit no thanks. Yeah.
Nobody does that.
So it's,
but out of those people that are
dumb enough to answer that form,
46% think the earth, 10,000
years old. That's amazing.
I've had debates with people
who, you know, who I thought
were fairly intelligent,
fair minded people who just insist that
what they read in the Bible is literally
true. Yeah. There's a
lot of people like that.
I liked him, met people in Australia
who called Easter Flying Zombie Day.
That's a good name for it. I went super
bunny day two, giant fucking evil bunny.
I like the idea. I like the idea
of trying to give you candy.
If you leave on symbolism and
beats something, then okay.
Yeah. It's, well, you know,
and it's also a unique way for
people to turn their life around.
You believe in this one guy's teachings
and this one guy's teachings really
still, you know, the way
they're translated in sort
of an employee, you know,
sort of use today in the
best aspects of Christianity.
Very beneficial for a lot of people.
And so having something like that,
whether it's based on a real person
or whether it's based on an idea,
it's very beneficial to alcoholics,
you know, like 12 step programs.
How many fighters do you think of?
The guy was right.
Jesus was just like a brilliant
comedian and just very misunderstood.
It's right that like plank in
the eye line. I mean that's,
I had to have been a joke.
I don't think that was totally a joke.
One good minute turning wine
into water snacks was dog shit.
I think it was just a really preachy guy.
Constantly telling everybody how to live
their life. Like to where the jokes,
where's the jokes bro? What am I,
how many fighters strong opens,
strongest spiders.
There's this, what'd you say Joe? A large
percentage. Yeah, probably more than, um,
like the average person,
if you took the, uh,
they say that atheism is on the
rise in America and uh, you know,
some guy wrote an article about a by 20,
41 or something like that.
There being no more religion.
I think that's a big fucking leap.
But the idea is that atheism is
on the rise. Um, I don't think,
I think in with fighters though, you're
dealing with a lot of them of course,
almost more so in boxing than an MMA.
But in,
even in MMA, a lot of them are
coming from poor backgrounds.
A lot of them are coming from uh,
places where people were, you know,
the strong religious footholds. Right.
You know, Iowa and shit like that.
Like wrestlers, a lot of
Christians, you know. Yeah.
I saw that Tyson documentary last week.
And uh,
I love at the beginning when custom
Mata takes him under his wing and he's
teaching him and he told him that he had
to convince him cause he had low self
esteem coming from the
street and everything.
But he is one of the main
factors that he's telling me.
If you don't have the warrior spirit,
you'll never going to be a winner. He,
I have to believe in yourself as the,
you know,
the mythical warrior.
Yeah. Champion. In a way that's may work.
A lot of boxers find solace in the idea
that there's something bigger than, than,
than,
than fighting for it.
I've heard many fighters say they're
doing the Lord's work. It's fascinating.
Yeah. I'm doing God's work.
I'm, there's not just one guy,
many guys saying I'm doing God's work.
[inaudible] no, I don't believe he is.
I mean, he might be a little bit, but, uh,
I don't think for the most
part it is period tires
personally. Um, you know what,
I've said that and people give me
a hard time about that. I mean,
only GSP knows what he
should or shouldn't do. Um,
I think the guy is just an amazing
representative of martial arts.
He's like such a true martial artist and
such a great champion for a long time.
I mean, he was at the top of the sport
in an incredibly talented stack division.
And he dominated that
division for a long time.
But I think every fighter has got
a life time inside the octagon.
There's a amount of time
that you can spend in there.
George has fought more minutes inside the
five and a half hours than any fighter
ever.
That's a,
that's a long time and he's taken 50%
of all the blows he's ever taken his
entire career in the last three fights.
Wow.
875 the shots I believe too as well.
The one of the things I was talking about
was how in the lead up to this fight
was how difficult he is to hit.
And Johnny Hendricks hits really hard,
but he's difficult to hit,
which was fairly true. Once
he got loose on the feet.
Um, like say I would say in certain
rounds, like in the third round,
it was hard for Johnny hit
him in the fifth round,
was hard for trying to hit him.
George got loose,
but Johnny still like when they got close
was able to land some horrible shots
on him while George is
going for the take down.
Johnny hit them with three
or four absolutely brutal
elbows to the head and then
a couple really hard uppercuts as is
trying to hold onto his leg and take them
down and Johnny blasted them with like
it leased to flush upper cuts on the chin
with in the kitty.
It's hard.
Anybody who thought that George won
that first round, I'm like, well,
I don't know what you judge
a fight on. You know, look,
Johnny blasted his leg over and over
again with these from the college look so
hard. Knees and people try to pretend
that those don't count or something.
I don't know why you're not scoring
that like those are debilitating.
That's a smart move.
It's damaged, it's real.
It's happening right
in front of your face.
But because it's such an easy thing to do,
just need someone in the leg.
People don't think it's a big deal.
It's almost as good as a leg kick.
It's almost as good as electric depending
on how good it looks. So painful. Yeah.
And the way Hendricks throws him,
it might be as good as a leg kick.
He fucking really leans into those knees.
So He's hit him.
He hit him with horrible fucking elbows
when he was trying to take them down,
he hit him with a horrible uppercut.
We was holding onto a single,
at least one or two horrible uppercuts
and then blasted his knee. And you know,
I mean, and took them down
once. I mean, it's just like,
I don't know what people are
looking at. I mean, I dunno.
I know you people love towards CPA. Look
at his face. At the end of that fight,
George gets busted up in a lot of fights
and still dominates them. You know, he,
he has that kind of skin. So some people
just don't like Bj. Penn never gets cut.
He's just got this incredible skin. Yeah,
he's got, he's got a lot of scar tissue.
So I played.
Yes.
But I think that there's gonna come a
time when George is going to have to
retire.
So when is that time going to be?
When a guide to me starts talking about
retiring and thinking about getting out,
that's when he should get out. I agree.
And when a guy does a post fight thing,
it says, look, I gotta I gotta stop.
And it could just be the
pressure of forget about all
the shots that he's taken,
all the brutal five round
fights that he's been in.
Just the pressure of being at the top.
I guess your while you don't want to
fucking deal with that shit anymore.
He's made a ton of money and
even if he's not going to retire,
the idea of stepping back
and chilling out for a bit,
like he said in the post fight press
conference, it's probably a good idea. My,
my feeling also is that, you know, if
he's be, if he's blurry in one eye,
if his,
if he's having trouble remembering,
I don't want to see a human being that
beautiful have a problem with his brain
and a problem with his eyes.
And what is your brain and your eye worth?
It's not worth $12 million.
It was worth a lot more than that.
And I want to see a guy like George saint
walk away while he still can not carry
down on a shield.
You know,
fighting is a young man's sport and
there's a certain amount of years.
Dana White's at GSP versus Hendricks
rematches on track, you know,
and also it turns out that George
is getting sued by his ex manager.
He's got a lot of shit going on, which
can really fuck with your head. You know,
there's some million dollar lawsuit
hovering over his head. Yeah,
I think George is a great guy and I
think he's an amazing example of what's
possible with hard work and discipline.
And he's a real champion, a true champion.
I like to see a true champion go out on
top and there's just not many of ever
done it. He's the only one that I
couldn't remember his Marvin Hagler.
Marvin Hagler is the only
fighter that never came back,
went out in a fight that
most people believe he won.
He fought sugar ray Leonard.
And a lot of people believe
that he won that decision.
It was if it was a close enough fight
that it wasn't the worst robbery in
history,
but a lot of people believe that haggle
should've won and Hagler stepped out and
that was it.
That was such a great period in boxing,
man. There was so many great fights.
You know, I always think that
like Pacquiao and Mayweather, not,
I think they deprived us of like
two great fights and rematches.
I mean there was so many haggler
Thomas Hitman, Hearns uh, the uh,
what was the Cuban guy?
Smart man, sugary load,
the Roberta [inaudible] epic fights.
Then Duran Duran vs packet
would have been an amazing
say, similar style, touching
their belly like fucking beer.
They had similar bearded man.
That would've been a war.
Duran had more of a beard,
you know, but pack yet with that goatee
looks very devil like you see Duran,
like those old pictures of him and his
eyes. If you're at a game, bread pit bull,
you know,
let's talk to the pin through that though.
He had that same literally the same
eyes, like just, just ferocity.
He was a bad motherfucker.
Dude. Everybody. I've talked
to him as a real boxer.
They always say my favorite bag.
I was like, boom, boom, man.
Seeing his favorite fighter.
Roberto Duran.
So many boxers who are real great boxers.
We'll, we'll talk about Duran. Like,
you know, there's a lot of people
that people forget like Aaron Pryor.
I remember when your car got cocaine
in the corner before the 13th round.
I don't remember that. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. Panama Lewis, the
guy was eventually, uh, he,
he got kicked,
kicked out of boxing for
a, another fight where, uh,
I think it was a Billy resto and uh,
I forget the guy's name,
but um, he took, took the
padding out of someone's gloves.
And so there's this young up and
coming kid who, uh, fought this, this,
you know,
experienced veteran.
The news is expected to beat and
instead he got busted up really bad.
Like I said, both eyes swollen lots
vision is, I had to retire from boxing,
but after the fight,
they grabbed the guy's hands and they
could feel there was no padding on his
knuckles. Oh my God. It
was just taped up knuckles.
That's all he had and he
just fuck this guy up.
And for people who don't know a boxing
glove, it's fairly thick. Yeah, it's,
it's still dangerous.
You could certainly get knocked out,
but there's a lot of padding like
when a knuckle hits you like,
especially when it goes over your eye,
whereas a raw knuckle goes right into
your eye and he's just getting smashed.
Man.
He got smashed and after the fight it
turned out that Panama Lewis had done this
and Panama Lewis was the same
guy that gave the, the, this,
this bottle that Aaron Pryor was like
a serious cocaine addicts and the Aaron
Pryor, like I said, uh, you know,
it was like leading into one of the
later rounds and panel. I said, no,
not that battle. The one on one
I made and he brings a body,
gives it to Aaron Pryor and Aaron probably
just goes out there like a fucking
man possessed and destroys Alexis are
grail and knocks him out in the next
round. That was fights were sick and the
word on the street was always that, not,
not that I was on the
street when I got the word,
but the word in the boxing gym where I
trained at was that everybody always knew
that it was cocaine. Panama, Louis
literally gave him cocaine, God.
And he went out there coked up.
If you haven't seen,
if you haven't seen Aaron Pryor and
Alexis Arguello fight youtube that shit
because
I love that so many fights are on youtube.
I don't know if we
talked about this before.
I read this brilliant book
last year called [inaudible].
It was a flame of pure fire about
Jack Dempsey and the roaring twenties.
And he was such an interesting character,
but it's great as,
as I was reading this book, you can go
back and look up the fights on youtube.
So I'm reading about this, you know,
these fights and like the 19 teens and uh,
you know, even before him, the, uh,
Jack Johnson fight in Havana where
this French Guy Colten [inaudible] or
whatever his name was, it was,
uh, knocks him out and you get,
Jack Johnson is on the floor and he like,
he, he lifts his glove up cause it was,
he wanted to block that sun from his eyes
while the guy's like counting him out.
The idea was that he took a
dive, right. And then, but
uh, like a Dempsey and Furpa,
this Argentinian guy, the first
round, you watch it on youtube,
there's like a football gets knocked down
five times in the first round or maybe
it's like seven.
Damn.
She's clobbering him and then he comes
back over over and then allowed to get up
for po knocked. That was so many
rules were made after this fight for,
for apoe knocks Dempsey out of the ring.
He landed on the sports writers table
and the sportswriters helped him get back
up. You know, he was so beloved
and get back in the ring.
So from that fight it a
fighter could never, uh,
he has to get back into the ring on
his own ability. You can't be helped.
And then also in that fight,
he's knocking for bow down
and he's standing over him
and as he's trying to get
up, he just plowed him every time he's
chatting. And it was also that fight.
They made the role. When a guy gets
knocked down, you have to, you know,
back away and go to a neutral corner
cause back then you could stand over a guy
and as he's trying to get up,
you can just keep on. Yeah.
That's most of the old fights.
If you watch most of those old fights,
they would stand over you as
a county [inaudible] tutto
fights, which by the way,
makes more sense. Yeah, it really
does make more sense. I mean,
if a guy fucking knocks you down,
why, why do you let him get up again?
Why can't you stand over him? You, you're,
you're the one who knocked him down.
Pull up Dempsey FERPA. That the first like
minute and a half is just, it's insane.
[inaudible] murderous puncher to man.
God Damn, those guys were tough as shit.
You know how he started in like a, he
was born in Colorado and he lived in the,
uh, like mining camps in
Utah and he would go to, uh,
like bars and mining camps and say,
who's the toughest guy here?
And that's how he,
like as a teenager,
he just walking into a mining camp and
people would all bet on it and he'd make
a little money, but like,
he was just pure bad ass.
Wow. That's a hard way to make a
living, hone into the mining kid.
Who's the toughest guy here? Mind Jimmy's
Jimmy Burke's uncle already Burke.
He used to do that. He, when they were,
where he worked on the railroad tracks,
when they would lay the railroad and
uh, those, those camps, he was 16,
but he grew up with a father, was a
pro boxer, uh, fought for the title.
So he would fight grown men.
And that's how we learned how to fight
boxing back then was a real Spec,
a very popular sport. It's the way
it wasn't in Mexico. If you're,
if you're a great boxer, you're
a national hero. I mean they,
they show up for those fights. That's
what it's going to be like in America.
But America, nobody even knows who the
heavyweight title holder is. I know.
If you looked at, have you seen who
that best American heavyweight is? Well,
let me just, no one knows who the
Klitschkos are. They don't know.
The average person doesn't know it's a
fight. Fans might know. It's amazing.
The average person has no
idea that heavyweight champ.
It's so corrupt. Well no,
because he's boring as fuck. If he was
exciting, like if he, if he was, you know,
like a Manny Pacquiao, everybody knows
who Manny Pacquiao, Manny Pacquiao,
always 145 pounds.
Everybody knows who he is.
Why doesn't everybody know who
the heavyweight title holder is?
Cause he jabs and hangs
on to grabs and hangs on.
He's a jab and hold Goliath fights or
more exciting. Well he's boring. Yeah.
Mike Tyson was a heavy fighter.
Fights. We're super excited. Yeah.
It's just a matter of the style of the
fighter and Klitschkos have this very
intelligent, safe style. And
it's very hard to beat them.
They just jabbed the shit out of you.
And they're tall as fuck.
They use their reach
advantage and never get close.
They don't get stupid and start winging
punches with you. Right. You know, there,
especially in iron man. Yeah,
I mean in the way Mayweather,
what I noticed is that he stands on
the outside and he takes one shot.
It's really like one left watch.
It's not like flurries and combinations
cause that's always dangerous.
If you watch him step back,
he's not staying in a phone
booth. He's moving movies,
stepping back, Bang, come
in, Bang. And he might,
he might hit you with two sometimes. Like,
like he'll, he'll lead with like that,
that, that upper, that, that upper hook,
that up hook or whatever app or punch
a particular, what do you call it?
Upper cut. Sorry. He'll, he'll upper cut
and then maybe come over to the right.
But that's it.
And then he pulls back.
But for the most part he stands back and
take pot shots. He's really good at it.
Did you see that Mayweather fight?
Uh, there was some Mexican guy,
Canelo Alvarez and the Mexican guys.
Dad gets up at the pre fight
press conference. No, no, none.
He keeps going in a different guy
and he's calling, keeps calling me.
Whether like a
talking about that fighter
is a front runner. He's the
front runner and all that.
He's a different guy.
You're talking about a Garcia.
Danny Garcia who's a dad is like,
it's really colorful character.
What was that with Mayweather.
He was saying then it's no dude who's like
Mayweather, like a similar, he's black.
I always like him or never let your
dad is very temporary towers Connor.
He actually fought. They fought.
They fought. He fought Mayweather.
Yeah. Subdued is really
good. Yeah. Mayweather's just
smarter than all of them.
That's what he is.
He's the smartest one of all of them.
He knows how to not get hit. He knows how
to just pot shot you hit you with jabs,
uses reflex, uses smart boxing
and you, he doesn't get hit.
You get hit and he doesn't
get that amazing. Sorry.
He's won the game.
That's what a lot of boxes that come
from boxing fighter fighter families. Um,
they, their, their fathers and uncles
have learned, you know, there's no upside,
there's no upside of eating out of a
straw when you're 35 cause your head,
you've got Pluto pugilistic dementia,
at least start with not getting it.
He's got his trainer, he's trained or
Rogers is fucking cousin or his uncle,
his uncle and his trainer Rogers. He
was a good fighter. Black Mamba. Yeah.
Roger May where there was
a bad mother fucker. Yep.
But he's got problems from fighting.
They all do. Look at Freddy Roach.
She's like one of the greatest trainers
ever who used to be a really tough
fighter. He's got problems too. He's got
Parkinson's trauma related Parkinson's.
Everybody pays man.
There's no free rides.
And my thoughts on the guy
like George Saint Pierre, ours,
it would be beautiful to see a guy
like him go out on top. I agree.
But if he feels like he didn't put forth
his best effort and he wants to go one
more against Johny Hendricks and show
what he could really do, you know,
but somewhere down the line we're going
to have to have this conversation.
Whether it's this fight, whether it's
the next fight, whether it's two,
three fights from now, it's going to be
a certain point in time where George,
who has more minutes inside the
octagon that any fighter ever,
that's one statistic that you
looked at five and a half hours.
And then you also look at the one that
he's taking 50% of the shots in the last
three fights. Those are two,
this disturbing statistics.
Not Disturbing, but I,
here's the best way to describe it.
There are two things you should look at.
You should look at those two things.
And that's the reality of
this sport we live in. And
the best that we, that we, uh,
that we watch.
But the best way to,
to make sure that this doesn't happen
is to discuss it. That's the only way.
If we keep this shit in the dark and
no one talks about it and no one ever
brings up the fact that hey,
you know,
you're not gonna be able to
take shots like that forever.
There has to be a point in time.
You could safely do it for a certain
amount of time, as long as you're careful,
as long as they have good defense, as
long as you're smart with your training.
But there's gonna come a point in time,
you probably shouldn't.
I was kind of shocked that the,
that they counted the number
of times he's taken a blow.
It's 875 times in the past, in, in,
in the five and a half hours
he's been in the octagon.
That does not count the number of times
he's gotten hit in the head in training
camp and training camp. You know, I've
talked to enough fighters where you're,
you walk, you walk away with a headache,
man. Of course. You know, of
course you do. You're not,
you're getting hit in the face. Look
at his face. Wow. Yeah, dude, trust me.
There's something going on.
You gotta be careful, you know,
and he was talking up to the
fight about losing memory.
He lost memory during the fight. It's
not cool. Yeah, I don't like seeing that.
And He'd also told me on
this podcast that he, um,
hit me and he wonders what it is
that he like misses time sometimes.
And he actually was wondering like, you
know, not saying that it was aliens,
but it could be possible that,
you know,
when people talk about missing time from
abductions, that that happens to him.
You know, this is something that he's
had from the time he was young. I'm like,
man, I don't know. I mean, maybe it's
possible. It's possible. It's aliens,
but it's also,
there's other things to think about when
you start talking about like missing
time. When you start talking
about there's, there's,
there's a real issue
with cognitive function.
If you're talking about like
periods of your life that disappear.
I don't think anything's worth
that, I don't think. Yeah. I mean,
I don't know what it is. It might be
nothing. It might be a nutrition thing.
And I'm not, obviously not a
neurologist. I'm not a doctor.
I don't know what the fuck
he's actually experiencing.
I don't know if maybe
it's just a Deja Vu thing.
I don't know what the fuck it is,
but when someone starts talking about
things like that and also talking about
possibly retiring,
all those things,
she'd be taken into consideration and
it should be approached very carefully.
We also know that continued head trauma
for football and boxing and things does
cause problems. There's no way
around it. I mean there's no way,
it seems like everybody who does
it for a certain amount of time,
there's a certain number
of times you can get hit.
There's just where you start feeling
that you have damn like chocolate.
Dal is the perfect example. Chocolate
Dell used to have a fucking iron jaw.
It was one of the things that was so
scary about him is that he could knock you
out and it was really hard
to get him out of there.
He has so much fucking heart and so
such an intense high drive to finish the
fight and he took tremendous shots
like right on the button got rocked and
plastic. You write back and knocked
you out happened all the time.
He would just scare the fuck out of guys
cause he would just charge you and he
was just throwing bombs your way and
taking everything you throw at him and
spitting it out. Hit hard. Huh? Like
what he did to Tito. Like watch,
watch this thing. What? He stops
Tito. He just fucking attacks him.
I mean he was a man.
He was tall dude.
He was a Berzerker Lucas,
look at this.
This is a ferocious attack.
God put put up Chuck Liddell
versus Bob Ballou put that one on.
You want to see another one like that?
Chuck Liddell was one of
the scariest champions ever.
He was one of the scariest guys ever cause
he beat guys even that were like more
skilled in him.
He beat guys that like he probably
shouldn't have beaten. He just,
he beat everybody.
You know along the way learning,
you know how to become the champion.
He was just smashing people.
He could just uncork that right.
He's been on rice has me. I mean,
of course it got towards the later end
of his career where he just couldn't take
shots anymore.
You just couldn't take them anymore.
And essentially what he described it as,
his brain knows what's coming.
He's almost like he's too tough for his
own good and his brain knows what kind
of punishment that he's going to get
because it's happened so many times before
because he would just bite down as a
mouth piece and just fucking deal with it
and get to you and blast you out.
You know?
And his brain just wouldn't
let him do it anymore.
So He'd get hit and his brain
would go like check please.
Wow. Yeah. That's, that's,
that makes a lot of sense. Cause they,
the same thing with, um, Vandelay Silva.
Like he, he just, he goes
right out now, you know, when
he gets hit, uh, not as bad.
I think vandelays Chin is probably a
little more durables. And Chuck was,
trucks was at the end, you know,
chuck at the end. Uh, he just,
he was really in good shape. He's still
at heart, you know you still get hit hard.
Still have the desire,
just couldn't take the shots anymore.
There's also the idea that if these guys
are learning and they're working with
boxers as they learn how to punch
the way Johnny Hendricks says,
I don't care how strong your jaws,
you're not taking a shot
from Johnny Hendricks.
He puts people to sleep cause he hits so
hard and if he connects, see you later.
If he connects flush.
Yeah.
That's the key is like how hard
is he actually hitting you?
Is he ever hitting you like dead on the
Monday? If you watch this past weekend,
Tyron Woodley knocked out Josh Koscheck.
He hit him with a right hand.
That was as as hard a punch as a human
can throw like as hard upon body.
By the way, built like a super hero. It
doesn't even look real. I mean come on.
We've talked about three podcasts in the
roads. Clear. We're in love with them.
Let's keep talking about,
I'm never get tired of that.
He hits so fucking hard that
like if he hits you flush, man,
very few people are going
to be able to absorb that.
But every now and then you
say that there's some Mark
Hunt type dude that could
just take it one. Let's just start
there. That's a whole different thing.
Those are, those are some
tough motherfucker got friends
who played pro football.
I said Samoan somehow it's
just a whole different thing.
You have like thicker bones.
Oh my God. They're like
bigger people. Plus they have,
they come from a whole long line of
Warriors, Polynesian people, you know,
some molens come from a
New Zealanders to come
long, long, some bad mother fuckers.
Apparently Galleries Tanga barely
smos are not to be fucked with. I,
years ago I lived in San Francisco
and there were these guys that, uh,
these Samoan guys that worked at
this garage where I got my car fixed,
but there was this one guy who I though
it was this really gentle, wonderful guy.
He was the one that I, you know, kind of
considered like my friend, you know. Um,
and I took my car there one day and he
wasn't there and I'm like, you know,
wherever, so you know, whatever his name
was. And uh, his friend goes, oh yeah,
he's in jail.
He gotten to,
he was playing pool and somebody pissed
him off in a bar and he beat the guy to
death with the, with the,
the pool, the ball Samoan.
You just grabbed a ball off the,
off the billiards table and be the guy
who does with it and they seem like the
nicest gym.
This guy,
oh my God,
guys aren't until you got pissed off
and they've got a pool ball in there.
Imagine that type of thing.
Look at that little don't reach,
look at the way he used to just, Oh
my God. Yeah. He was a murderer dude.
He was a murderer.
Um,
chuck at his best is one of the scary
John Macarthur looking at reach.
And so that was Larry landless.
Yeah, chuck was fucking,
it's got a wide head man.
Chuck was brutal. Yeah.
But every guy gets to a time like,
look,
if you could repair the human body, if
you could get chuck Liddell back to the,
the, the, the ability to absorb
punishment that he had when he was 20,
he would be dominating again today.
He'd be smashing people.
He would be smashing Pete.
He was, yeah, he was,
I mean it was guys who could beat him.
I'm saying it's boxing rampage beat it
in pride and he went into that fight,
injured, but when rampage beat
him in the UFC, he was probably,
chuck was probably already
starting to show signs of wear.
Rampage knocked him out and then,
uh,
Rashad Evans knocked him out bad with
one punch and then rich Franklin knocked
him out. So there was a lot going on
with chuck Keech. Our Dean dropped him.
There was a lot going on,
which he had clearly gotten to a
point where he's taken to me shots.
But if you can get them back to when he
was like in his early twenties and his
first fight in the UFC,
he would be a top contender or
the champion [inaudible] guys.
They're boxing now as much better than
it was then, isn't it? He didn't care.
He would, first of all, his boxing
wasn't that bad. He had good counters.
It's just his attack was so ruthless.
I mean he was chocolate dough was
trained by John Hackleman is a,
a very knowledgeable trainer and
Chuck's capable of being as technical as
anybody,
but he doesn't,
he hits you and he knows you're hurt
and the swarm has come and bitch.
It's locus over the hills. It's lightning
and thunder to fucking earthquake.
He can't stand up for and knuckles
are flying towards your fucking face.
What do you like it or not? There's
not a lot of technique involved in,
I mean there's technique, but there's
not a lot of strategies. I should,
what I should say, he's just uncorking
power shot after power shot. And if you,
you know, 10 if you connect to his
chin somewhere along the line, yeah,
good luck stopping him. Good luck. He
could take a fucking tremendous shot, man.
God, look at him knocking out random
and is that an annulment? Yeah,
that was randomly not Olympian.
That's Mike Tyson's. Better
looking brother, right.
Not Random and out with a
leaping left hook. Yeah. He, he,
he was a fucking monster man.
He was a murderer.
Spent a lot of times he wasn't
dude's out when he was at the peak,
when he was the best.
He was a fucking ferocious fighter.
He's one of the main reasons why the UFC
became so successful because watching
him fight was like watching a fucking war.
You would watch,
it was like you two are going to
stand in the middle of the cage,
is going to impose his will on you
and just put knuckles to your face.
Shins. Yeah, that's him and Vandelay.
This was already after chuck
had had probably, you know,
he was probably in the twilight of his
career when him and Vandelay went at it.
He just didn't quite have as
much pep to his step as he did,
but it was still a fucking amazing
fight. What a fight. I got that fight.
So tough. Look at Vandelay that's on the
wall. This is fight a big picture of it.
It's like, like when the, they made
the, um, that Jim and my back, my, uh,
garage, look at them
taking those shots. Man.
They took photos from classic fights and
to me this was like one of the all time
who won this fight. Chuck wanted
decision was a great fight though,
but it was like,
to me it was like such a classic because
this was the fight that we always
wanted to see. When Vandelay was in
pride and chuck was running the UFC,
everybody wanted to see chuck
versus Vandelay, you know,
so much faster than you think to like
he can knock you out by moving backward.
Like look at the Randy coture knockouts.
He knocked out Randy while
he's moving backward.
Like if you slide that
video back a little bit,
the one when he knocked out Randy, he
not, yeah, it was right after this.
He knocked out Randy,
like Randy was charged at him and he
would slide back and uncork these punches.
There wasn't a lot of wind up in the
shot that he knocked Randy out with.
He was just loose. He was
loose. He just was a wild man.
Like here it goes. Watch. This is the
one, this is when he fought. Look at this,
how he knocks out. Randy
backs up, boom, boom.
As he's backing up Randy's charging and
as he's backing up he clips him with
like,
you know a 100 millisecond right hand
that takes your fucking face ages.
He was awesome.
Awesome man.
He's one of the reasons why the UFC
became so successful because watching his
fights, you were guaranteed.
You're going to see fury,
you're going to see primal fury.
You're going to see one of the
wildest men alive. I like that.
You described him one time
with the greatest way you went.
You said he's a wolf and somebody said,
what do you mean?
He said he's the Kinda guy
jumping a fire and say,
let's see who burns first bitch. It's
the craziest way to describe that. Yeah,
he would take you into DC is going to
burn first and for the longest time he was
successful doing that because
he could take a tremendous shot.
But ultimately his wild reckless nature
led to him taking quite a few shots and
you know, he look, the UFC took care of
him. You know, he wanted one last fight.
He got it with Franklin and then he
decided that's it and now he has a job.
He like,
he's like an ambassador for the sport.
It goes all over the country tours
basis towards gyms. Right. You know, he,
he's got like a great gig in the UFC now.
They take care of them.
And I love the fact that they told him
like this is, you know, enough is enough.
He got to a point where,
you know,
chucking and Dana had a long standing
relationship and before chuck was in the
UFC or before Dana ran the UFC,
chuck was a being managed by Dana as
was Tito. Danny used to manage them.
And you know, when we started
writing, you know that, yeah, on my,
I did a podcast with Brendan Schaub,
that fighter and the kid
with Dana in his office.
And he talked about how he had already
boxed Tito and it didn't go well for Tito
cause well Tito wasn't a
boxer, a wrestler, he would
take guys down and he says,
he said that in an MMA fight,
Tito would pull his head with a spine and
everything. But he said, yeah,
but he challenged him to a
boxing match and you know,
and it was, it was funny, he,
Dana's still gets create like the fact
that I said to him, what keeps your edge?
Like what drives you? He goes, I want
this to be the biggest sport in the world.
And I said,
you're the most bristly dude.
He answers his tweets and fights with
people on Twitter. And somebody was like,
why do you do that? And he goes,
because it's fucking fun. That's why.
And I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm the fighter and
the kid, cause I'm on Fox, they bleep out.
Fuck. They believed that every, you know,
he's literally like every other word
is fuck. But um, he's got such an edge.
That guy, he bleep it
out. It's so annoying.
You need to stop doing
podcasts on somebody else's
when you don't need a wing.
You don't need anybody that ever beeps.
You stop your stupid nonsense. It's
so dumb. It chose me. That's so dumb.
And you know what? Not on my podcast
and on the Brock Callen show,
it's gonna make people avoid that goes
against the reason of having a podcast.
Yeah. I didn't know these
people, man. It annoys people.
I get a lot of mail about
it. I'm sorry. I always,
I'm always having to apologize
for it. Yeah, it's gross, man.
The idea that someone could fucking tell
you what you can or can't say. Yeah.
It's a, it's against
podcasting. Exactly. Exactly.
The whole point of this is that
we can do what we want. How? Yeah.
Why'd you let a corporation do that?
I don't.
I didn't know they were going to
do it. Bail on that. My mistake.
Do you have a contract? Yeah. One year.
You son of a bitch. Yeah. After it's over.
Tell them the only way you're
doing it. Again, as if,
let's say it's a podcast Fox,
let's do this, right? Maybe I'll come
over to your network. I'll make a network.
All right, I'll make one. There we go.
I'll get the prime accounts
show and your network. Yeah.
Just so you can use my office. You
can use this. I'm moving out here.
I'm going to be your neighbors soon.
Good. You know that's happening.
I use the studio. Listen, man, you
gotta be on your own. This is this.
This doesn't make any sense,
but everybody thinks they have
to do it with somebody else.
Everybody thinks like, oh, I gotta.
If I was in the Fox, more people,
more eyes going to the way you get eyes
on you as the Goddamn Internet man.
It's the people that enjoy it and they
tell people they enjoy it spreads,
and that's a job. That's
it. That's all you gotta do.
Make something that people like.
Boom. Right. It's that easy.
Don't need Fox or HBO or showtime or why
would you meet them if you're going to
do a podcast, if you want to do a show,
yeah, you need Fox. Yeah. You know,
if you want to do a drama
or a sitcom or a talk show,
look and look at one hour specials.
Now nowadays you can start doing almost
your own thing. Yeah. Yet, I mean, look,
yeah, you definitely can. You
can release some on the Internet.
A lot of people have done it,
but the bottom line is anybody that's
telling you to not swear my name,
what kind of game we plan. Exactly.
What a silly game. Really plan.
I lost my bad wolf. Lost my mind. By the
way. It's not TV. You don't have to work.
It's not the FCC. The FCC is not
involved. So if the FCC is not involved,
why in the world? I'm loving my podcast
and I, you know, I do it real small.
I don't have any commercials. I don't
want anybody telling me what to do.
And I'm like talking to people around
the world. This guy does bishop,
you ever heard of him? I have, but
listen, man, you don't need to have,
just because you have commercials,
it doesn't mean anybody can tell you what
to do. Nobody can tell you what to do.
I have a lot of commercials.
Nobody gets to tell me what to do.
You don't allow it. It's
real simple. The idea,
someone would allow it or that
you need to your language,
but it's not necessary and there's this
thing in your head where, you know,
I don't have anybody telling me what
to do so I don't have commercials.
You can have commercials too. You just
don't let them tell you what to do.
It's like they don't have to be mutually
exclusive. Yeah, the, we're brainwashed.
I stand corrected, but it's a silly
thing. It's a silly thing like,
do you think that corporations wouldn't
want to have anything to do with you
because you're swearing
the corporate.
Every time I do a corporate GIG,
they're like, don't use the f word.
They fucking love it. I'm just going to
talk to you like a normal human being.
Guess what they say? Fuck too. Oh my
God and shit and things like that.
It's even more cause it's suppressed.
These people were all buttoned down.
They're not allowed to talk about this
shit and all of a sudden you're talking
about sucking your own Dick.
You're talking about,
you know where I'm going
to be swearing by the way.
November 29th and 30th
and wise guys in Utah,
Salt Lake City. I'll just tell
you what, she now love it.
There you have you done that club?
No.
I hear great things though and I hear
Salt Lake City like one of the best places
to perform because people are so fired
up for anybody to come into town and just
start talking some shit. That's what
I'll be doing. So much buttoned down,
you know, thinking there is so much, you
know, really strong, which by the way,
Mormons or if you're going to give me
a cult that's going to be my neighbor.
I'll take more men all day.
Some of the nicest fucking great.
We help you and everything.
They have a great sense of community.
I mean they believe some wacky shit, but
they're nice. Absolutely that Wacky Shit,
whatever it is with them, it seems
to work a little bit. They are.
They do a lot of help for non Mormons.
Whenever there's disaster,
so I'll be in Salt Lake City November
29th November 30th I'm at the state
theater in Austin,
Texas.
November 30th Austin tells is going
to tell you this guy, Dez bishop,
it really interesting guy. He's American
plug you and you can tell I'm sorry.
Please, please plug away Tom Rhodes and
fucking hilarious comedian Austin, Texas.
If the people in Austin,
especially,
I know what kind of comedy you freaks
like and Tom Rhodes is your man. He's,
you're an old school road dog dude.
You and I had been friends for fucking,
God knows how long we met each
other when we were on NBC together.
We had the Tom road show back when it
was long Herod days. That's right. Yeah.
We hung out together and one
of those functions, it was
a, it was, I think it was,
it was in New York City.
They had this big announcement of the
season at the Lincoln Center and all the
people like stars from the show, from
each show would come across the stage.
Let me, let me give you a calm.
We inhibit an after party,
a big swanky affair and uh,
thank God you were there because it
was all like acthar people and stuff.
Thank God you are that you and I like
we're, yeah, we have steel. We were like,
we're hanging out. We, you know,
you've got to go to these things
and you drank any hob nominees.
There are nice people for the most part,
but they're all actors.
And then I was like, Tom
Rhodes. Yeah. He's like Joe
Rogan. Like oh fellow comedian.
Give me a hug. 1818 years ago,
17 years ago. Tom Rhodes was,
I've always thought of you
because I told you this already,
but I worked really hard at my stand up.
I was a new comic.
I got up and I did an okay job in
front of people with some stuff.
And you looked at me and you were such
an established comic and you literally
looked at him at me and you,
you went,
you went, you're a screen
bro, you're a screen.
And that was a seminal moment
for me because I went, if I,
if Tom Rhodes said that and I
know you meant it, I was like,
I'm doing something right.
I'm in the right direction.
That's pretty cool for you know,
and you,
you didn't have to say that you just went
out of your way. You don't remember it.
Cause you obviously,
you know,
close. We had a good
comedy man. I'm, you know,
and I'm not afraid to tell
a young guy that, you know,
I think he's got a good future.
You are, you've always been like that.
And I love that. I love guys like that.
You and Stan hopes like that.
I'm like
the warrior spirit man.
You gotta, you know,
every warrior needs to eventually
move onto Wiseman and you know,
you gotta when you see a young
warrior and you know the guys,
you know these approaching standup from
like a pure place and you know it's,
I think it's good to encourage people.
I think it is as well,
but it's so I love it just because I,
the older guys did it to me, you
know? Yeah. They did to me as well.
I don't look at it in terms of like
an old warrior, a young warrior.
I look at it terms of I love standup
and when someone's doing good standup,
I enjoy it. I like it as a, as a person
in the audience. Right. I enjoy it.
I'll never, I'll never stopped.
I've met people that did, I met,
I've met a lot of people
that really love standup,
then became a standup and then didn't
love it anymore. Right. Terrible.
When you see the light.
I did a Gig,
I went to the Friar's club in La and
I get in there and with my friends,
I'll tell you why because
somebody asked me to do,
I get there and it's literally
like scattering of people
in suits and I can hear
them eating and I look at my buddies
and I go like this. I say, dude,
I'm just telling you I'm going
to do 40 minutes just on birds.
I'm doing 40 minutes on bird humor only.
I get up there.
My friends are howling crickets, everybody
else's like, what's this guy doing?
My friends are dying. Right. You
decided to tank it on purpose.
I was just being esoteric
and fun and crazy.
I get someone over to a table and a
guy says to me, an older man says,
you got a lot of guts and
a lot of imagination kid,
you're going to go a long way and it
was red buttons. Wow. Pretty cool.
He's nice.
I've been better if somebody else told
us store instead of you telling them
about yourself.
Well I, I wanted to tell you about
that. This guy does. Bishop man,
he's really interesting dude. Uh, he's
originally from New York. He's his,
his parents. Uh, he's got
deep family ties in Ireland,
so he went to school there.
That's where he started being a comedian.
He's gone on to have a, a brilliant
television career in Ireland. Uh,
he's living in Beijing now for the past
year cause he wants to learn mandarin
Chinese and do stand up
comedy and Chinese. Wow.
So like I did shows in Beijing with him
at this really cool place called the
bookworm.
It was a,
it's a bookstore where like a full
service bar in the center and it was,
it was really great. See plays
that held like a hundred, you know,
the weekends were sold out. It
was really cool. Multiethnic,
multinational people.
But his story is amazing.
I arrived there the first night
and I went to this Chinese, uh,
language, local open mic night, did he?
He puts on and hosts and here's
this guy that I know and he, he's,
he's doing comedy in Mandarin,
Chinese now.
How many room full of Chinese people?
How many Chinese comedians are there?
It's brand new. They're brand
new, brand new, there's illegal,
there's a guy named Joe
Wong who apparently he was
a comic in Boston and he did
Letterman and now he's moved back
there. Whoa. Uh, and he's like the,
he's there like, you know, whatever
spiritual leader of comedy steel,
the shit out of people's hands.
[inaudible] Chris rock stuff.
That's hilarious.
You did that in Holland who did it with
Bill Hicks material didn't Dutch. Wow.
Yeah.
And uh,
he was becoming really popular but
then it got out what he had done.
Well it was actually like doing all Bill
Hicks is act and other buddy. He's like,
this young man is kind of really a
lot of interesting things to say.
He's got a very bright mind and people
are like, wait a minute, I heard
that shit before. Show path ideas,
man. It's amazing. He's, you know,
and after he told him eat, we're
talking afterwards and he's like, yeah,
I'm kind of like, yeah, I feel like
I'm back at open mic night level.
The guy's been a comedian for almost
20 years and he's like, yeah, you know,
I wish my Chinese is better.
He's like being a typical comedian,
not giving himself enough credit.
And I'm like, I'm like, dude,
I just watched you do 10 fucking
minutes and China and get laughs.
That's incredible. Don't, don't be coming
off going, I still got some work to do.
I mean, he did all your
books. What are you, Tom,
has standup change to topped it
all this year, these years? Like,
or do you still look at it
in the same way? And I, you
know, I mean, it's a, I mean,
you know, you have tough times in your
life when you're up and down, but I mean,
I've, I've always loved it. I think
as far as contemporary comedy,
I think it's way better than it used
to be. Uh, like back when I started,
I think there's way more originality
and edginess and a dark humor.
I think like back in the, in like
the late eighties, uh, there was,
there was a lot of like,
conformity.
It felt like a lot of guys were trying
to be Jerry Seinfeld and get on telling
me to where there wasn't
a lot of ferocious voices.
And I think that's why like,
you know, Bill Hicks stood out so
much in the era and that, you know,
like a prior was just speaking pure truth,
you know,
that kind of thing. I think now
there's, there's way more dangerous,
interesting stuff happening in comedy.
So I mean, as a, as a comedy lover,
I love it.
The only thing that's
missing right now is clubs.
There's not as many clubs as they used
to be, but I think as far as like ideas,
there's more information now that are,
let's get into the comedians.
There's more stories.
There's more to the audience,
more things that you could
read. There's more, I mean,
you're getting crazy stories you could
talk about on stage all day long on
Twitter.
Every fucking day your Facebook is
filled with some one nutty story after
another Nadine's story that can
ultimately be turned into a bit.
If you have the time and the
resources you can get on stage,
you can kind of craft an act today.
Um, you know, it's the fucking,
there's a wealth of information
that's coming at ya,
but it's just harder to find
clubs and a lot of places.
I don't know. I think,
uh, don't you think a
lot of clubs are opening and in some
places and I think the worldwide comedy
scene definitely theZ is exploding right
now. What if you're in like Saint Louis,
what do you got? You gotta like is an
Improv, their funny bone is a funny bone.
I mean if you want to like start out,
they have an open mic night.
What's the scene like? They do, you know,
is it more than one club mean ideally
you want several clubs cause most likely
gonna burn one of those
bridges. Yeah, because you're,
if you're a comedian you probably would
like temperamental. You're impulsive,
stupid shit you drink. People still
don't really come to comedy as much.
I mean like I was talking about bill
burr about this. Like, you know,
I was watching him the other day and
that show we did and, and I, and I said,
you know, you now of course bill does
theaters and stuff, but for the most part,
for a long time, I always say
that there are people out there,
they'll make you laugh way harder
than any movie you've ever seen yet.
They still can't sell out on a Friday.
[inaudible]
few weeks ago. And he said, he goes,
I call that period killing in obscurity
when you're just like killing and you
haven't, you're not selling
tickets. Right. And you're
uh, we all go through that.
Y'all go through that moment before
anything really hits for you where you're
like, God damn like this, this
stuff. It sounded pretty good.
I'm getting into a groove here,
you know,
I feel like I'm actually
like a legit headline.
I wouldn't mind telling someone
to come see me. You know,
it takes like 10 years
before you feel that.
But once you do feel like no one knows
who the fuck you are. Like, you know,
you could be,
you're in a hotel somewhere and as yeah,
you can be as good or even better maybe
than some people that are on television,
but nobody knows. Like Diaz is a perfect
example of that. For the longest time,
Joey Diaz was absolutely
murdering it and no one knew.
I think you're a good
example how funny you are.
A lot of people don't know and
they think of you as an actor.
They don't know how funny you are as a
standup. Yeah, you're fucking hilarious.
Dude. I've tooken my friend Justin
is, he uh, came to see us in Vegas.
He was raving about how funny you were.
He was crying.
He kept repeating your lines and shit.
That's one of those things where like,
people know you now more I think even
because of the Internet than they knew you
from TV shows.
You did lab mad TV or this podcast
actually has been a hugely instrumental in
getting people,
at least to my shows and stuff.
But to think about crazy it is
all the movies that you've done,
all the different things that you'd done.
And there's still a lot of people
that didn't hear about. Yeah,
but then you will not mention any names,
but we all know certain people who sell
a lot of tickets and then you, you know,
your friends go back and come
back from seeing them. And I go,
what the fuck did I just
watch? Right? Like, oh my God,
that's terrible. And you go,
well, you know it's different when you're
on a show. You've got writers and like,
sorry,
you know,
but there's a lot of people that are like
killing on stage to 50 people a night.
That's right.
The owner's mad at them.
Can't figure out that you got to do
fucking everything. Pressed morning,
you're going to do every
radio shows on the Friday,
three radio shows in the morning, two in
the afternoon, still have full, no one's,
hey man, it is about, it is about the
Internet. I've learned that from you.
Like now that I've been tweeting and
stuff. It is, you get people to your shows
a lot easier. Well, that's a nice thing.
But you know what's really
about the Internet? You're
entertaining people. Yeah.
You're giving these
people for entertainment.
The reason why you have
this connection with them,
they're coming to see you with a co in
the clubs is you've already entertain
them. They enjoy your,
your work, they enjoy you.
Whatever you put out they've taken in.
And it's true. If it makes them feel,
it's more personal that
come up to me in London after shows
and they've heard me on your show and
they've, you know, they've
heard my podcast and it's
like, they know you. Yeah.
It's not just like a little
seven minute TV spot.
These people know like serious
details about your life. Yeah.
Philosophy in the way you,
he would never be able to get this sort
of a connection with people if you just
did Letterman a hundred times. Right. You
wouldn't, they would never get you. Yeah.
We're also at an age now, the three
of us were, uh, and I've noticed this,
a lot of guys are,
they don't have guidance and they don't
have a responsible older male to teach
them certain things. And we're the
age that their father would be. And I,
I noticed and I start, I'm starting to
take it very seriously. Like, you know,
when people listen to me on this
podcast or on my podcast or whatever,
they're really listening and they're,
then they're paying attention and,
and in a way you feel responsible.
You feel like, you know,
I'm way more careful with what I say.
I'm way more careful with
the information I give out.
I've got to make sure I know
it. Remember Joe are now, right?
We used to start this pocket. I
just be spewing shit. I'd be like,
add another then research truth.
People would give them so mad at me.
They would send me the
fucking text messages. Michael
County spreading decipher,
right. It's just called talking
shit, talking shit. Yeah,
we've heard something but you
heard it wrong or whatever.
And you start talking and
then people realized, oh,
8 million people are listening to you.
It's like I'm to fucking start paying
attention what I say here because uh,
well that's the thing with technology
now everybody can call you on your shit
instantly change.
Like the iPhones are totally
little answering machine
and they, oh, by the way,
oh by the way.
Oh and by the way,
my shirt open and my person I told
you that story about at the time,
uh, I was with my wife and we're, well,
we're like talking about Guantanamo
Bay and I'm like, what are,
I wonder what the top 10 torture songs
where they top songs that we talked with
these people with.
She whips it up on the phone.
Two seconds later we got the list.
Like number one was a song
called fuck your God by d a seed
biocide did some death metal things.
That's totally appropriate,
but like the rest, the rest of the songs
made absolutely no sense whatsoever.
It was like, um, queen,
we will rock you was one of them
will have that Brian May guitar riff.
I could listen to that over and over.
Don Mclean's uh,
American American pie was more God
is that this is it. Fuck your God.
Tyree meow mix TV. Commercial. Yeah.
Yeah. Me, I'm Yam. Yam, Yam, Yam,
Yam, Yam. Yeah. Oh, that's great.
Enter Sandman by Metallica.
I can listen to that over and over.
I can't think of Metallica and not think
of Jim Barney the dinosaur that grower.
Why gymbaroo loves
Metallica. Yeah, Zee. Yeah.
Well I remember that first for
them all to, yeah. Yeah. Now he is.
When I first met Breuer,
he would fucking,
it would just be like rocking
out to himself. He was
singing Metallica solvency.
What happened? I got the roses.
You know about this. Well,
what happened to axel rose?
Did you just go crazy?
I think everybody goes crazy
when you get that famous.
I think that's what's happening to Kanye
West. That's what happens to lady Gaga.
That's what happens to everybody there.
They're too famous.
It's almost unmanageable. That's what
happened to Madonna and I think, look,
they hang onto it better than probably
any of us would, but they still crazy.
You go crazy, you go crazy. How could
you not go crazy? Everybody goes crazy.
Imagine being lady Gaga. Can you imagine
like what is that like? I know of
a woman who dated a very famous celebrity.
I won't mention, she was saying,
she was telling me that he got to a
point where he just couldn't really,
he was just like,
you get so famous that he would have
like these sex parties and he would just,
she ended up getting sucked into that for
text and she's banging his friends and
he'd be sitting on the couch like Nero
watching this shit just got crazier and
crazier and it got crazier and
crazier and then he couldn't,
he couldn't come unless he was like,
unless it was, she was doing crazy shit.
Like hang her tongue on another guy.
Really feel bad for that guy.
I know she kept having an amp it up.
He would really hit an exterior.
He was really conservative,
like people thought,
but when they'd get together it
was just fucking on and he just,
then she had to finally break up with them
because finally she was in a rotation.
Hold on a second. When you say,
when you say he's conservative,
like his appearance or his public
persona was very accomplished. Famous,
famous guy. Okay, so you remember that
Bob Crane guy from Hogan's heroes?
He liked it. He was banging chicks, all
of that. Buddy didn't want to give it up.
That's why he was getting tired of off
the rails when he was murdered by his
buddy who he was banging girls with you.
I don't know if anybody was
ever convicted to that. It was,
I don't believe that was a fun movie.
It's a really good moment. You're still,
what's it called, Greg Kinnear?
Autofocus. Yeah, I think so. Really?
It's about a lot of fun really.
And speaking of Lady Gaga,
did you know Bradley Manning who took
all those military secrets and gave him
the Wiki leaks and endangered the lives
of American service men and women all
over the world? Uh, when he would,
he had these disks on his desk.
A statement or question is,
none of that is he had these
disks on his desk and when,
so when like sensitive
information will pop up,
he would pop the distant and
download all this information. Right.
So he labeled the discs. Lady Gaga. Yeah.
And so like people walk by his desk and
it was fucking guys listen to lady Gaga
that way. No. I think that lady Gaga
should also be implicated for treason.
That's all I'm saying.
I'm just want to make a case
for you that we'll look stream.
So I want to make a case for that right
now. She should be implicated. Yeah,
I think she's, she's treasonous
little bit. A little bit, man.
Treasonous yourself. Radley. Many
wants to get a sex change. Chelsea,
Chelsea manning. He's a cutie.
He's a little cutie pie.
How dare you write petite.
I know you're going to do all that.
Then what the to that want the
government to pay for yours?
That's what he wanted.
Yeah. Well maybe, I don't know. Who
knows how long he's wanted that,
but I couldn't imagine what it would
be like just to be in the position that
that guys in,
you know,
just to be in the position to have this
information that you think needs to get
out. So you release it and then they keep
you in solitary naked for like years.
For years. They're like, guy
was, I mean he was going crazy.
Is that what I did too? Yeah.
Psychological torture. Yeah. Yeah.
They did some and they kept them.
They keep you in solitary for them.
Nothing to joke about when you're
really thinking about it. Yeah. Torture.
For years,
they kept him in solitary.
They kept in solitary Froedtert
own time and you know,
now who knows?
I mean,
they might not even be true that
he wants to have a sex change.
They might've just released that. Who the
fuck knows? Right, right, right. Yeah.
Who knows. I mean, it
might just be like, check,
check out what we're going to put
about you in the news. You know, look,
you want to have a sexual
[inaudible] character. Yeah.
Maybe this is working for
the government just did.
Did he have the chance to actually give
a a speech? I think that his trial,
he mentioned the fact that he was
wanting to have a gender change,
that his trial,
I'm saying did he give a speech
about why he did it or I don't know.
The whole thing is really strange,
man,
because it's changed our whole idea
of what the government is between the
Bradley Manning wikileaks thing
and the Edward Snowden thing.
It's essentially changed our entire
idea of what the government is like.
In one fell swoop.
It all became this giant spy network,
which we never would have imagined.
We never would have imagined
that his reach and all that.
Now it's amazing how things have changed.
People don't realize what a big impact
that really has had on the confidence of
the American people because now all
the people that were like borderline
believing and Alex Jones and wondering
what the fuck is really going on with the
new world order now it's all
like on paper, like the gut,
the Obama,
they're only collecting better data
and that turns out to be bullshit and
everybody could. Apollo press person
has some sense. It's ridiculous.
It's like there's so,
it's so obvious now that there's this
giant spy network and everyone's sucked
into it. The whole world is
literally connected to this,
these chords and no one wants to admit
it and tapping in on Angela Merkel,
the PRI, everybody, every world leader,
their personal cell phones. Yeah.
We knew everybody's,
we've also have known forever that both
sides were always spying on each other.
That's why the president
goes into his tent,
which it scrambles all
kinds of information.
Mike Swick told me that he was working
at the embassy in Russia. Mike WIC, um,
before he was at Mike's spoke MMA
fighter before he was an MMA fighter.
He did security at this embassy and he
said that they used to find things that
the Russians had put in the buildings
that were powered by the motion of the
building.
The subtle sway of the building was what
powered these devices that they use.
He said it was so far
beyond anything they had.
And you know what's really interesting,
a lot of the shit that they got that
the Russians got a lot of shit that the
Americans got during the
space race was from the Nazis.
It was operation paperclip.
We took all the best Nazi scientists
from Germany and just knock a [inaudible]
and changed the last names. Old Bit,
well, bit fiddled around, little bit,
exonerated them, gave them positions
of power, like the head of NASA.
Wernher von Braun was unknown Nazi who?
The Simon Thall weasel way.
Was it Simon Wiesenthal
Center Center for uh, uh,
they said that they would punish
him for crimes against humanity.
They said they would try
him if he was alive today,
they would try Wernher von Braun
for crimes against humanity.
That's what there's the head of NASA.
The head of NASA was a Goddamn Nazi,
like a real Nazi.
There's,
there was a documentary on these people
that had been through the camps and were
describing where if I'm was like an expo,
say on were winter von Braun,
and they were talking about how they
would see him while they were looking at
people hung,
they would hang the five slow as Jews
outside of this Berlin rocket factory
every day to make sure that
everybody worked hardest.
And they would see von Braun walk past
the bodies like to say that he wasn't a
Nazi. They're like, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no. He was a Nazi.
He was there while all this was going on.
He was a part of all this and this guy,
you know,
he had the tattoos and everything and
he was describing this and it was really
intense. It was really intense
to think that, you know,
just because someone is like really good
at something, we'll take them over here,
put them on TV, Polish them up, give
them a haircut, smile. Wernher von Braun,
the head of NASA says we can be
on the moon inside 24 months.
We got along,
we got a lot of German physicists led,
including I believe Albert
Einstein because of the
antisemitism that was arising
in the early thirties already.
And they came over and it wasn't,
it really just because they were
awesome. I mean, we had to control them.
They would, they, the Nazis had
created some incredible devices. BMW,
they were creating incredible
fucking engines for, for jets.
I mean they had some amazing engineering
and machine gun I think was wasn't Nazi
invention. So there was a German
invention operation paperclip. Um, they,
they took a gang of scientists,
it was in 1945 and they brought them
all over here and put them to work in a
bunch of different segments of our,
a military industrial complex.
But also in NASA. They designed
missiles. They designed everything.
They did all kinds of shit over here,
but the, the space race was greatly,
greatly aided by these people. Like we
literally didn't have a program until we,
until we brought Wernher von Braun
over here. Huh. That's amazing, man.
That's some amazing shit. That's just
how they did things. They say, Hey, yeah,
either bad guys, but look, they
know a lot of shit about rockets.
It was also a race for world domination.
I mean,
there were I the conflicting ideologies,
man,
and it was winner take all and a
lot of ways. Oh yeah. Well you have,
it was a scary time. Everybody's
rushing to make the nuke. I mean,
if they, they make the new first, they
win. Yeah. We got, you know, if we all,
we all die a fire.
If it wasn't for that Bhagavad Gita quote,
motherfucker that was crying earlier.
If it wasn't for him,
somebody else would've got it.
Probably would have been the Nazis.
They probably would have figured it out.
No question. They were on their way.
That was,
that was the whole thing.
The Manhattan project was basically a
race to get the bomb before they did.
She apparently though historians
say that they were further,
they were actually given up on trying or
they were further away than we thought
it allegedly. Yeah. American propaganda.
We got 1,800 technicians and scientists
along with 3,700 family members.
Those with special skills or knowledge
or taken to detention and interrogation
centers,
such as one code named dust bin to be
held and interrogated and in some cases
for months.
And then they took these motherfuckers
and slowly brought them out and started
reintroducing them. A
lot of brainpower. Wow.
A lot of brainpower. That's amazing.
They're still catching those guys, man.
They're every now and then the fine
second, Argentina and places like that.
A lot of them went down there. A lot
of them went to South America actually.
They flee. I mean, you gotta
think and they've chased down
a lot of them. Man. They,
they're,
they've been,
and they found out into the
field a lot of, they, they, uh,
I mean there's a lot of
Germans that live in Argentina.
My mother's from Buenos Aires.
I've been to Argentina to citing Spanish.
There's so many. Uh, I do not.
Um, what's your background? Uh,
ethnicity? Uh, I'm actually, um,
are you a Nazi, your Army Nazi, blah?
I'm Italian and Irish on my mother's side
and English and French on my father's
side it, and it's, most of the immigrants
down there are Italian or Germany,
German and there's,
they still have like German language,
newspapers and some areas really vast,
large German popular.
Yeah. That's where a lot of people went
and hid out and then were hunted down
eventually. Jesus Christ,
it's quite a scary thing.
They just move to these towns and just
repopulated a bunch of fucking sociopath,
psychos do the tango until
just how many catches on.
All of them are not a bad place to go
down to two and not a bad place today.
Well, women are stunning.
It's a great steaks.
I had a friend who just got back from
Columbia. I was like, oh my goodness.
He goes,
it's like 10 to one women to men that
women are beautiful women in the world.
He said they have these incredible bodies
and they're dying to meet American men.
You said it's the most ridiculous thing
ever. He goes, every American man,
she'd just go to Columbia.
Well I'm a, I can't do that.
Well you're married but a single.
But someone who is not happy.
So what I'm saying, someone who doesn't
live the perfect life like Bryan County,
they're having, they're having
problems. They hear get this.
So Columbia has a lot of those video
chat things and guys will spend a lot of
money on this video chat things.
Here's the problem.
Guys are flying down there
to meet their girlfriends,
their cyber girlfriends and hanging
out there and getting all hung up and
marriages it getting ruined.
Everything else. Oh, I'm like,
so there's been a lot of problems.
Yeah.
Careful of the cyber chat
cloud. The webcam there.
Sirens, man. They are sirens.
They will, they will. You listen
to, how are we not even men?
I mean they're probably not even women.
They're probably men for the most
part with fucking fake pictures.
I'll use the gross you video chat with
like think about, well the Nigerians,
how much the money they pulled out of
lonely men. They've done an amazing job.
It's an amazing thing they've done. Like
what, what do they scamming old men.
There's this one show,
uh,
that was exposing this guy that got
sucked into this Nigerian scam and I think
he gave off $250,000,
which was like all the money he had saved
his entire life and he couldn't meet
this girl tried to meet her.
He flew all the way to Europe and uh,
she ducked him,
you know,
like they had an email exchange and
they were supposed to meet at a certain
place. She doesn't meet him. Of course,
the only, she only speaks through email.
She sends pictures and
only speaks through email.
He's never actually spoke
to her on the phone.
So it's poor fucking guy flies all the
way to Europe and she gives them some
kind of hootenanny excuse,
you know, oh, this happened,
my family. And this was like,
it's very hard for me right now.
I don't know where I'd be without you.
Thank you for understanding. And
then, you know, he just keeps,
sends money since he's more money
Dominique. Oh, he's dumb as fuck.
But he's also just sad and old
and lonely and uh, you know,
he was an older man and she was young
and beautiful and in the pictures.
So he flew back again. The guy flew to
Europe twice. God, twice. Nothing older.
People shouldn't be allowed on the
Internet. There should be guidelines.
Know somebody should keep an eye on
older people. You know, I get these,
I get those emails. Like I'm, the tears
are coming from my eyes. I have no money.
My grandfather got,
um,
he got addicted to buying things
out of catalogs before he died,
before he died. Um, he, he
went through a real bad period.
He only lived for a year
after my grandmother died.
Took care of my grandmother for 12
years and my grandmother had a stroke.
She had to like take care of her day in,
day out for 12 years.
And then when she died,
he was dead in a year.
And in that one year period
he went off the rails.
And one of the things that he did was
he would buy things off of catalogs who
would just call and just
to talk to anybody just to
talk to people on the phone.
He was like really lonely,
sad man.
Well he was used to having his wife
with him like all day every day.
And his family lived like an hour
outside of town, you know, they lived in,
it was a substantial drive.
So they would come to visit him on
the weekends or when they could,
but they couldn't be with them all the
time and he didn't want to leave his
house.
He wanted to stay in his house.
So it was this crazy situation where
the only way this is going to work with
these guys going to be happy and to be
living with somebody who doesn't want to
leave his house and he was getting
dementia and but category we have,
they have to take catalogs from him cause
he was just constantly ordering things
on catalog. Yeah. It was sad
shit man. People do that.
They say people go to funerals like
that just so they can be around people.
Wow. So when people go and they don't
have any friends anymore, you know,
like get to a certain age and where's
your friends are all gone. Yeah.
That I think about that a lot.
That's I that that just must be so hard.
I blocked my, I remember my, you
know, he's married to the
guy for 55 years, 60 years,
and then he was gone and I walked into
the, to the casket and that was it, man.
That was it.
That was somebody she had been with for
55 60 years and they were just gone.
You know? And that adjustment
is, is a weird thing, man.
Yeah. And also the reality that you're
going to go to, I mean, you know it,
I know what we all know,
but it seems almost abstract until you
see it in front of you and then you go,
oh, this is what's going to happen one
day. It's just going to not be here.
I'm going to just be gone. You're going
to be gone. She's going to be gone.
Everybody's finite.
We just,
it's just so hard to recognize that while
it's all happening while you're living
your life,
it's so hard to appreciate it.
All right. Well until people start
like my father, uh, you know,
died in 2009 and my sister
died in 2011 hardcore.
Two of the people I love the most in
the world is at 10. So I mean you never,
life just seems like some endless thread.
It's just going to keep going on and on
and until you get punched in the heart
and have somebody very dear to
you who you love and you know,
taken away from you that
doesn't don't on you.
Is your sister younger or older
than you? Younger. Yeah, she was 37.
Got Breast Cancer.
Oh No.
Yeah. Where's that at? My father was
killed by a drunk driver. Nano. No. Yeah.
So I mean,
you know,
one you can understand and the other
one is senseless and both of them are
senseless. What is causing
breast cancer? Bryan County,
you've probably known this gotta be there.
The food or a mass produced food.
You know, like in Europe, my wife is from
Holland and she always points it out.
Like there's,
there's a lot of foods that were
sold in America that had just a day.
The governments in Europe don't
allow on the, on the grocery shelves,
just certain ingredients and shit.
The, the incidence of breast cancer
and in Japan was very, very low.
And when they started changing into
more of a western diet, it did rise. Uh,
so that, that would suggest
that diet plays a large,
it's got to have something to do. Fish
oil and stuff like that. Pollution.
This is probably a fucking slew
of factors. Nutrition, pollutions,
brass water. Tim Ferriss went to, uh,
to where they live the longest in,
in Okinawa. And, uh,
what he was actually looking
at is what they don't eat.
And one of the things about those,
Oh, can I add this up? No Pussy.
But there they have, um, like they talk
about they have a very, very diet, um,
and all this stuff, but the,
the blue potatoes, not rice,
and there's all these theories,
but a huge part of it is their sense
of community. Um, they find that,
that people who have a purpose and
never retire, and a sense of community,
like when they're really a tight
community, they live longer.
And so when most health
professionals are looking at health,
they're talking about graphs and while
they eat this and this pro, no, in fact,
human connection when,
when you,
when people feel supported
emotionally and connected.
And I'm not saying this was
the case with your sister,
I'm not saying that cancer,
I'm not sure.
Oh,
I,
I that never even crossed my mind that
you would be in playing totally agreeing
with what you're saying. Because
like, when people retire,
let you see a lot of people retire
or their wife dies or whatever,
like they die a few years later.
Think your theory
makes perfect sense.
The outliers with a mountain Gladwell's,
yeah, it's been a little while.
He talks about this town Rosetta,
which is Italian town.
There's an Italian town called
that they were marble. Uh, they,
there was a marble query and next nearby.
And when the mobile query in Rosetta
in Italy was no longer had any marble,
they moved to a part of Pennsylvania
where they had a query nearby.
They formed their own town.
And in the 50s,
a heart disease was an absolute
epidemic epidemic in this country.
One of the things they found was in,
in, um, Rosetta people were just as fat.
They cooked with Lard, not even with
olive oil. They were dying of old age.
And they said maybe they come from an
hardy stock from this town Rosetta.
So they looked at people who had emigrated
from other towns in the United States,
from Rosetta. No, they were
dying of heart disease too.
Why weren't people dying of
heart disease and Rosetta,
why were they dying of old age?
Even though they were fat,
even though they didn't eat
very healthy necessarily,
or they ate a lot of sugar and pastries?
Well,
the conclusion was probably that
they had such strong community,
such a bond.
Even if you were a guy who is a
nerd or a guy who is whatever was,
wasn't winning and things, there was
such a support system for people. Um,
there were parks and people
would talk to each other, uh,
going to and from work and there were
community things that they would do and it
was such a strong community.
They look forward to hanging out,
they look forward to hanging out.
And that plays a factor in jail.
Enjoying your life, enjoying
your life. It's everything. Yeah.
It's everything. Enjoying what
you're doing, having a good time,
but then also having that sense of
purpose and not, you know, like yeah.
Boy or something.
And then you retire and then you have,
you have nothing to do
in your mind is occupied.
Well, I think with stand up, like,
you know, I talked to guys like you,
like I'm never quitting.
I've never,
that's always been my,
my thought as well.
It never even crossed my mind to
not do it. Yeah. Carlin never quit.
No. You know, I mean, even Richard Prior,
when he was on his deathbed, came back,
did more stand up. It was just
on stage. He couldn't even walk,
can barely talk. I've worked with them.
I did like five weeks with them. Really?
Yeah. The comedy store when he was, when
he made his comeback before he died,
I saw him on to,
I think it was his 50th birthday.
My father is the reason I'm a comedian
and my dad loved comedy and he had
Richard Pryor albums. And so like, I
used to listen to them. Uh, like in my,
my dad was such a fan. He had
cassettes and drove around in the car.
And by listening to prior as
a kid with my dad, so, uh,
my dad was living in La and prior was,
it was after he got sick and he,
you know, he was in a wheelchair.
Two guys had to lift him up
in the wheelchair and put
him on stage at the comedy
store.
But it was still such a thrill to be in
the same room with this guy who is like,
the reason I'm a comedian and like this,
this ultimate loving bond I had
with my dad. And like, you know,
love of dirty jokes and comedy and
laughter and humor. And I think,
and in prior could barely keep his
head up. And you know, he was so, uh,
Bill [inaudible] and uh, but he did do
a 20 minute Hong Kong and licking pussy.
I would get my dad to pay attention to me.
He was busy and so
under so much pressure.
And the way I would get them to,
I remember as a kid is I would recite
movies and comics. That's, and,
and cause I knew I could recite them
and he would laugh. And that was a,
I knew it would kind of relieve the
pressure of his crazy fucking job.
And what was his job? He was a banker, you
know, and uh, I think he did other stuff,
you know, for the government. I don't
know, but he was gone a lot. You know,
he had this, he had to solve
all the problems, I think.
And I always felt that way.
But, um, he just, I could always
see the stress on his face.
I could always see that the, the insanity
that he was going through. And I,
and I remember one time he would relax
is when he would laugh at me. So I would,
I would quote Monty python or I, yeah,
I've got really good at memorizing. So,
you know, whatever man. What a joy.
I hope I have a son who
entertains the shit out of me.
[inaudible] I got a video I'll show you.
My son doesn't, he's two and a half.
He will,
he sits at the drums for one hour at
a time and he doesn't want to get off.
You guys call those loads and there now
Tom Rhodes. Yeah, I'm getting up there.
Get up there. Yeah, because by the way,
it comes a point in time when he sperms
no good. No more. You'll be a good dad,
Tom. Yeah, I can't wait. My wife wants
to wait. Uh, you know, I'm ready to go.
She wants to wait for what? She's just
enjoying this, traveling the world,
doing cool gigs all over the world and
you don't even have a place to stay.
Right. You're still down in the hotel
thing. She's constantly booked Europe,
Asia, you know. Great.
And I may in New Zealand
at the New Zealand comedy
festival and then I did like
a best of the fest tour. Like, oh my God,
who doesn't want to go to New Zealand?
It's great. And your wife loves it. My
wife loves it. She loves comedy. She's,
you know, on the planet. One woman
on this planet has to travel,
loves to hang out and
like a drink and you know,
laugh with comedians cause that's what
I've, you know. Wow, that's cool man. She,
she's, that's great too.
That's a very rare thing.
I don't know of any other guy that's
doing that. I don't hear it bro.
Especially a high level guy,
like maybe the guys that are in the
beginning when they're just starting out.
But like, you could do it in the
beginning because you're not,
unless you're independently wealthy,
your family or money living on
the fucking couch and the couch,
the couch and people's,
you know,
all those friends couch that
first 10 years of, you know,
taking buses and hitchhiking to gigs
and sleeping on people's couches.
It's like now where it's come in, life
is, it's sweet. It's great. You know,
I got gigs in while going back to London,
I'm doing the Soho Theater and like
February I got a Gig in Barcelona,
I'm doing a tour of Holland at the end
of January. It's just like, it's awesome.
And then they're just like arguing
so much work in the states. I mean I,
I can only, uh, you know why pay
rent on a place I'm never at.
Yeah. So you work more in Europe than you
do in America? No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
It's about, no, it's 50, 50,
50. You know what I mean?
Like I'm in the states 50% of the time
and then 50% of the time outside or a
high tech nomad brother,
you'd probably go international
more than anybody I know.
Then if that's the case,
if you're like 50 50,
who else do you know that does like 50%
of their stuff internationally? Hello?
I've been doing it for a long
time. No. Yeah, you have stand up.
Does a bit international, but
not that much. Eight cities,
like I stayed up absolutely kills me
when he talks about like, you know,
I'll be like, you know, cause he's,
he's pretty adored in England and he's
doing these nice, you know, you know,
theaters and, you know, selling
some nice tickets. And, uh,
he talked to him about it and he's,
he's like,
he thinks everywhere is like Mexico.
He's just like,
you just complaining about things.
It's horrendous.
He just, he thinks so little of a,
some of the places that he goes,
it just kills me. I'm like,
didn't you enjoy the food?
He might not be being theatrical.
I think he is. I think stand up.
He loves to be a contrarian and um,
you know,
cause I mean there's certain aspects of
travel that I just, I, you know, like, uh,
it depends where I'm at in the
world with time off. Uh, and we'll,
we'll go somewhere and we'll rent
an apartment somewhere exotic.
Like last November I did the Jakarta
comedy festival and my wife and I went to
Bali for two months. That's Indonesia for
anybody who doesn't know. And then, uh,
like in June we went to key
west for a couple of weeks.
In September we had rented an
apartment in Rome. We've done,
we've done that the last few years. What
is your favorite place to, uh, uh, I,
you know, I uh, San Francisco, Sydney,
Amsterdam.
But if you were to retire somewhere,
do you think there's a country you would
go to if you didn't live in the states?
Ah, I uh, I mean I always liked Paris,
my wife, her favorite cities, Rome.
And she's really been the
last three years in a row.
We've gone to Rome to the first two years.
Like seeing monuments and all these,
uh, you know, paintings and
things. I wanted to see this
last time we went there.
It was great.
I just pretended like I lived there for
like a week or just like going to nice
restaurants. And when you're
pranking roam, where do you perform?
I haven't performed there.
I'll just go on their own on trips.
I should set up a Gig there cause
I've been, I love going there. Yeah.
You don't ever have the desire to
like have a place where you know,
like this is where you put your family
photo and this is where you put your
underwear. You know what
I did that I, you know,
I threw everything in the storage
when I moved to Amsterdam.
So I had everything in storage for five
years. And then you look for five year,
five years. Wow. Yeah. And I had a, I
was on television for three. I had uh,
my own late night talk show for two years
on Dutch television in English and it
was subtitled in Dutch. And uh, and then
when that finished the same network,
let me do one year as a
presenter on a travel program.
So I had a wonderful life there,
but when it finished and I love
making television and I moved back,
I moved to La,
got everything out of storage and I
looked at my shit and I'm like, this is,
what am I, my empire of $20
purchases? I mean, everything.
Was there anything that meant anything
to me? It was like a book or a CD,
you know? All those are like 20 bucks.
He is my empire, $20 purchase it.
The things that did matter are the
family photos and then like, you know,
things from your life, family
and little, your comedy career,
a little memorabilia and stuff. So like
when I threw everything back in storage,
uh,
I got rid of like most of
like the furniture and shit
like that and just got it
even smaller to like what
was really important to me,
like my book collection and
different, uh, you know,
archives of videos and photo years
ago you had a place in Korea town.
That's what, that's when I got came
back. Uh, that place was great.
And you came over that one night.
We had a great night.
There was this girl who I went to high
school with WHO's an old friend of mine.
You and her got into like
this insane argument.
I don't know what she
said about she's a, I, I,
I,
I forget what it was.
But you like schooled her on something
that she was misinformed about and you
guys, uh, I don't remember.
You don't remember that too
much? I remember there was,
we got really high. There
was one I read, I saw you.
I like the comedy store or somewhere.
There was one crazy girl that had some PR.
I don't remember what the idea was,
but it was so wrong on in like,
and she was like saying
it as if it was fact.
I don't remember what it was though.
It was something like that. Yeah,
I forgot what the thing was,
but it was something that
was [inaudible] we're having,
there's this great party at
my house. I had this, uh,
I had very little furniture.
My friend,
really good friend Charles
Esl who lived in the building.
He was in a band and he was like a
character comedian did a little stand up,
but he also had a band. So I
let him set up his, uh, his,
his band stuff in my living room.
So I,
there was a drum kit and a instruments
there and I just let these guys,
I'd left him.
The key is one of my best friends.
So when I'd be out of town half the time
and he could go in there and I had this
massive CD collection and stuff and he
would just beat on the drums. No, no,
he has abandoned would go practice.
They'd go pri,
they get an apartment and my apartment
in Korea town and that's where you came
over. And I had this great, like,
it's empty living room quick,
just like a musical instrument.
We're having a really nice party.
And then you and this girl got a,
you know,
one inch from each other's noses
and I don't remember it confronting,
I don't remember it. Right. I think the
girls had said something that was, um,
it was, uh, just not true,
not even close to being true.
I remember her just being a
little crazy and thinking, man,
Tom Hangs out with crazy people,
but maybe I made a crazy,
I'm still good friends with, uh, uh,
I'm still good friends with a, uh,
a good portion of people I went to
high school with. Wow. That was a, a,
it was from a small little
town, uh, Oviedo Florida.
There was a lot of really good people.
I mean, some of them are, you know, uh,
or you know, have different beliefs
and different ideas about things.
But so the little goofy is
that we transfer. No, no, no,
no, no, no. Not all of them.
No, no, no. I'm saying there's
a couple that are goofy. Um,
that girl was one of the hottest
girls in my eyes. Fall out.
Well that's the problem. That's also
the problem. When you're really hot,
you'll get away,
get away the same right across.
And I think that she had probably gotten
away with saying whatever she wanted
for a long time. You were one of the
first people do, um, you know. Yeah.
It seemed like it was, it was just, you
know, I remember were high at the time,
which really destroys bullshit.
Nothing destroys bullshit like marijuana.
And when someone's bullshit in
your high like, oh, come on man.
Tony would say that right? To Stop.
Like it's so obvious. This is not true.
This is not a true thing. You lay
man, is that, Oh God, it's everywhere.
There's honorary missing. Telling
me two plus two is 18. I'm like,
what the fuck are you stop making all
this noise Scientologists in about people
in la that are aren't used to
being told no, you're wrong.
What you're saying is just absolute
horseshit called on it. Right. You know,
or how about this, you're lying. Stop
lying is a little bit of that going on.
Oh my God, it's unbelievable. You know,
one of the things I was saying to
a friend we were talking about, uh,
the one thing that I don't like
about people that are struggling,
especially struggling his actors,
it's the arena that they're
forced to compete in the arena.
They're forced to compete is an arena
where they're constantly going to
auditions where there's this weird
social thing going on where there's one
person who's in control,
the casting director and
there's a director who's
observing you and your whole
thing is about getting these people to
like you quickly in a brief amount of
time.
And so they adopt like really obvious
democratic left wing sort of tendencies
and things to say. And
they adopt, you know,
a very left wing mindset because that's
the majority of the people in Hollywood
are fairly left wing and
they start spewing out shit
that they think people want
to hear as opposed to having a real
thoughtful opinion on something that's,
that's a very good point.
Very few people have the luxury of
having a real thoughtful opinion.
It's all about getting
someone to like you.
It's all about getting into the
door at is so, so, so true man.
Terrible way to thinking about that
the other day. That is so true.
That becomes this, this way
of you have to, you have,
you're bullied into speaking a
certain way. Cause if you don't,
you're going to be considered a shithead
or you know, not on the team man.
You're not on a ton of team
and you see it all the time.
Well the left wing aspect of it is
very strong kills ideas. Schubert,
I forget what he calls her love.
She calls herself a, you know,
a liberal conservative or whatever
because he wants to work in shows like,
you know,
he's sure he cracks,
never go to an audition with
a Mitt Romney shirt on there.
Not a single fucking
person would ever hire you.
And that's something that they would
really, it would prejudge you for sure.
I'm going to go get this Guy Outta here.
That is a hard game though. Acting man.
I know there was a, when I lived
in that building and Korea town,
there was a actor guy that lived
in my building, uh, you know,
it's starting to get up there
in age for an actor or whatever.
And I guess his was work kind of dried up.
And uh,
for some reason when I would see this guy,
he would tell me everything about his
life. For some reason he thought we were,
you know, whatever. Great friends.
I told the guy very little about me.
He just would always just spew
all this information himself.
And I remember him telling me,
cause it was a bar downstairs in that
building and him telling me one night the,
uh, I'm getting out of show
business story, I love the,
like you and I were talking about never
even considered stopping doing this.
But like, so I, it kills
me when somebody gives the,
I'm getting out of show business
speech, I've given my all, I've done
thickness and then the phone
is he the guy he, you know,
cause nothing had gone on for him.
He hadn't worked in a couple of years.
And then he got this little
roll on, um, a deadwood,
like say I don't,
maybe one line or you know,
he was on a horse or something and
then like a, and that, you know,
that rejuvenated his spirit.
But I remember the guy telling me sometime
after that that this girl had dumped
him and he's just, he's just incredulous.
He can't believe it happened.
And he just keeps saying to me,
but I was on deadwood, man. Whoa.
Like, who, who could dump me, God,
I was on this town, allows you to
reinvent yourself and reinvent,
invent your own reality,
man.
Do we not want to be involved in life
with someone who that people do that?
All of them, but thing
to say. Yeah. Yeah. Dumb.
It was another time where there was a
little cafe on the corner and he was a,
it was like a sunny Sunday or something.
He was sitting in front of their reading
the Big Sunday newspaper and he had the
homes section. He's looking through and
I'm just being a smart ass tonight. Um,
you know, I walk up to him and I go, hi,
your career must be doing really well.
Now if you're looking at the,
at the home section and he looks up
from his paper and he just goes, no,
just day dreaming and you know what I'm
going to do one day when I can afford a
house,
I'm going to build walls so high to
keep the shit in this city away from me.
Oh. It was like was just like the most
venomous guy. God, that anger. Like,
it's a sunny Sunday. Loosen up your
tongue so hard. I got to get him. No,
I've got a great story.
I had this is to build a wall
separate all this come from,
I knew a guy,
I'm acting class and you know how
long I was an acting class years.
I loved it by the way,
for a lot of reasons.
Mainly because it was
just fun to be in a just,
there's a lot of greatness and
Joe would always make fun of me,
but there was a guy, really good guy,
normal guy. So I thought, and he was,
and he, I hired him to shoot
me to shoot this audition.
So I go to his house and he's got this
great camera and on his wall is a dream
board and on his wall is
his, no, no, no, no. He's put his face,
he's put pictures on his face on the
cover of vanity fair and those magazines.
And he's got slogan's saying,
you're the guy,
you're the one and it's a dream
board. And it was big. It was good.
Covered his whole wall man. And
he's a good guy. And he's like,
he's a normal guy in a lot of ways.
He's just been told the wrong things.
Jay Davis. No, it is not. I love that.
It's almost like, like, you know,
go to a girl's and she's got too
many stuffed animals on the bed.
That's like the male equivalent though.
This guy,
he thought it's show business so much
that even know he was trying to visualize
his future and it never, I remember
going, oh, it's never gonna happen,
Bro.
No matter what.
Davis Jay Dad was very nice. He's a
great guy. He's a good dad, like sweets.
You know,
the reason he did is j so
enthusiastic like Jason Bourne. Yeah.
Is just an enthusiastic guy who's
just loves everybody. But, but uh,
this guy handsome, tall, you know,
suave and just, I was
like, you're a Dork, bro.
I gotta help you take that down.
Write down his picture,
his face over celebrities faces on
Vanity Fair and people magazine.
I'm not kidding. That's how he, he
can visualize himself doing that.
Well, I don't know, Joe, stop bringing me.
Say you're going to run into that guy
and he's not going to have made it and
he's going to go,
you're the reason.
I'm not saying I wouldn't
be taken down by secret
guy and I want, I want the best for him.
I love the guy actually. He's a great guy.
It's just nuts.
He was told what happens sometimes is
people are told something enough times and
they forget to stop and think.
It's exactly what you're talking
about with the Fox thing. It's like,
who says you can't swear and why
are you doing with somebody? Why is,
why are you doing with the court?
You forgot the idea of a podcast.
You have to keep thinking because you'll
make choices sometimes because you're
told that this works.
Who said it works?
I can't visualize running pumps back
in the NFL are fighting in the octagon.
Don't have it. No matter what
I do, ain't gonna happen.
I'm getting fucking knocked out because
my bone structure for a thousand reasons,
I don't have it. Okay, tried,
didn't work. So you know,
you've got to you,
yes you should dream big,
but you should also be
realistic with who you are.
So when you're saying someone told him
that all you have to do is use the power
of positive thing.
Correct.
Use the ID wage thinking
Rosie the law of attraction,
all that shit.
And what happens when you read enough
books about it and it's written enough.
You seen enough books written, you start
to go, this must be this, this is a truth.
There was a girl who came to
the pod to the comedy store.
She was friends with Kelly, Kirsten.
Very nice girl. And uh, one day, uh,
the day I met her,
she was in the back hanging out
with Kelly and all the comedians.
I was just joking around. And, uh, it
was like right around the time that,
what the bleep did they know, oh
boy, that's on, in the movies.
And people just had decided that they
were going to visualize their life.
And she was talking about it.
And I hadn't seen the movie yet,
but she had just told me, um, that she,
she was following the secret and her
life was going to be from here on out a
masterpiece because she was falling the
secret. And she was very nice. And I,
you know,
I didn't want to argue with her and I
wouldn't argue with someone about that
because I don't even,
I'm not sure what I believe when it comes
to the power of positive thinking and
I don't know how much of reality,
just because you can touch things
and bang on them with a hammer.
I'm not exactly sure how much your
intent has to do. I'll give it to,
I'll give you,
let me just break it down.
Nothing wrong with pots of thinking at
all until it gets in the way of critical
thing, right? So, so make sure,
if you want to be positive,
we should all be positive.
We were just talking about this button.
Make sure you don't lose sight of critical
thinking to be able to decipher the
meaningful difference between things.
It takes some thought and
experience and practice. This role.
I ran into her a year or so later, maybe
a year and a half later at the the, uh,
UCB and I was like, how's it going?
How's everything? She's like,
you know, I've been using the secret,
but it just doesn't work. She's like,
my life is just as much of a message
as ever before. And she was just,
it was really weird because she was a
real confused and she wanted to ask me
about it because we had had
this conversation about it
and there was essentially
the last time I'd seen her, you know,
and then she was like, it's just not,
everything is a mess.
I keep having these bad people in my life.
I keep dating the wrong guys.
I keep my,
my dad's sick was like all
these things that are going on,
but I never would have created if I
wanted to secret as you keep making bad
choices twice sports and stand up and
things are so important because if you
come up against objective
reality, yeah, there's that.
You can tell a joke and if you're not
funny, they're not going to laugh.
You can study Kung Fu on a mountain.
If you try to punch somebody hitting a
face who's been boxing and doing Moitai,
you're going to get cracked in the mouth
and you're going to feel the difference.
There is a place in in life,
we're objective.
Reality must be embraced and if you live
in La long enough and you start reading
books like that and you don't surround
yourself with people who tell you the
truth, people who have friends
who tell you the truth,
it's definitely that you'll
create your own reality.
You also need something that shows you
the truth and that's where like something
like a martial art or even like playing
chess or anything where it's like it is
a, there's a win lose situation
here. There's a reality.
You're as good as you showed to be good.
You can decide that your poetry
is the most amazing poetry ever.
If you can get three
other idiots to agree,
you could believe your own hype easily,
really quickly, not hard at all,
but you can't. If you go and play
basketball and you can't score a ball,
you can never think you're a
great basketball player. You like,
that ball is not going in here. This is
not happening. I've keep throwing it.
I keep missing the hall, so
get a good code, 30 to nothing,
three fucking games in a row.
This is bullshit. You know,
no matter what my mom says about that
being a good athlete, these guys are me.
Yeah, that's, that's an objective
reality. And refining your approach.
The whole point is you fail.
Figure out what you're doing wrong.
Get somebody to teach you the difference
and then refine it and go back,
go back it.
There is some aspect that requires a
positive approach and confidence and
thinking and almost hubris.
It all.
There's a part of that that's real
and that's where it gets really weird.
It's like it's not an either or situation.
There's a bunch of elements to success
in life and one of the elements seems to
be like a belief in yourself and a
belief that positive things are going to
happen.
And a belief in you know,
hard work and a belief in like even if
you're proven wrong sometimes and you see
what went wrong,
you've got to believe that you can
recover from that and keep going.
When you go on stage, like every time
you go on stage, you've done it before,
you've done it many times before
so you know that you can go do it.
And the crowd, you know Roars Brian
Cowen and you get on that stage.
But there's one point in time in your
life where you didn't fucking know this,
know whether it was the first time or
it might've been like deepen your first
year. You know, this is like a, a
year in, I was like, what am I doing?
It's a fucking guy. I'm still
terrible. Like this is brutal.
It's a brutal fucking occupation.
Hit or miss. Not only that,
it requires so much self examination
that you never want to do as a young man.
Right, right, right, right.
One of the most amazing conversations
I've had in a long time was with an author
named Dan Coyle,
who wrote a book called the talent code.
And he went and I had them all of the
podcasts and trop and bitch and I thought
he was going to [inaudible] a
guy named Dan Quayle oil. Well,
no, Dan Quayle wrote a book called the
[inaudible] oil. It was called potato,
it's called.
He's,
it's an amazing book called the talent
code where he went and studied all the
hotbeds of talent, like the schools
that put out the most world champions.
And he and he kept meeting the same
coach over and over again. Uh, yeah.
It was never a guy who gave
big speeches or anything.
He was just a guy obsessed
with information on what
he called deep practice.
The idea of practice, what you're bad
at, practice just beyond your reach and,
and practice very hard.
Well that's that Malcolm Gladwell thing
about the 10,000 hours thing. I mean,
which, you know, comedians
all hit that. Yeah.
Well Dan Quayle it takes it to another,
like there's a woman who's 77 in Russia.
She owns one court,
teaches in group classes,
put out more champion, more tennis
champions than anybody else in.
And it's because, and she's really
starts all steroids. Yeah, no,
it's just the way she
disseminates information. Um, the,
and there are music people would teach
you that there's this cello player in San
Francisco who puts out more worldclass
cellists because he just has a way of
communicating what Prac, how you should
practice. Yeah. That's a big thing, man.
Learning how to learn things. It's big
and a lot of people don't ever do it.
And learning how to teach kids things.
Like one of the things that
I'm realizing when a, I,
I'm a volunteer with my kid's class and
I watch like how little children were
talking about like five-year-old's absorb
information and how some of them just
don't get it. They just
don't get it. And guess what?
They don't get any extra help to ones.
The ones who don't get it.
There's 30 fucking kids in this class.
There's one lady who's teaching these
kids and if the kid doesn't get it,
he just doesn't get it. I didn't
get it. And when kids don't get it,
they get into this spiral of they're
behind because they didn't get the first
thing.
The second thing comes along.
They don't get that either cause
that's based in the first thing.
They're standing there like staring. It
creates shame. Creates, creates a stupid,
that's a terrible way to teach people.
Like kids need to be talked to
like individually, like one on one.
They need to learn things.
They definitely need some group time,
but they need to learn things and it
needs to be broken down differently for
different people. And we don't do it. We
don't, we don't teach people how to learn.
We don't teach people how
to get good at things.
We don't teach people how to discipline
themselves and we make it so that people
could just sort of skate by on life.
Well also what happens,
which is a very damaging idea, is the
idea that Oh, some people are born smart,
others aren't because you didn't get it.
And that,
that what happens is then you get gifted
programs and these kids are separated
over here and these kids over
here are the dummies. And My,
my very good friend of mine,
Hunter Motto wrote this book,
The straight a conspiracy motherfuckers
friends with all these authors. I'm very,
very smart. I'm brutal. Wait Til,
well, before we end, I know we have to,
and I want to get your take,
I'm sorry to jump in.
I want to get your tank if we can
on, on Robbie Lawler and, and,
and that fight with, uh, with
uh, Rory Mcdonald. And why,
how did you find how you explain
Robbie Lawler's renaissance? I mean,
he's such a Badass discipline
maturity, you know. Uh, he's,
he's training with really tough
fighters on a regular basis. You know,
he's been working with the
same striking co Co uh,
coach Matt [inaudible] has been
working with him for a long time,
but now he's at, at t and t now,
uh, at and t in American top team,
att. And um, that's a
great camp and a lot,
a lot of high level guys from the
trauma part, all those, so many.
So many guys even don't even know.
I mean there's got slews
of them all talented people
and so he's just putting it
all together, you know, it's just,
it's just a matter of him finally being
focused and also spending a lot of time
at 185 pounds and I'll drop it down to
one side. Oh right. He dropped down.
I'm telling you,
man,
he knocked out Josh Koscheck and the
first round and then there's Roy MacDonald
fight. Dude, he fucking hurt Roy
McDonald. He's one of the first,
I mean he heard them in the clinch to
hurt him when Rory was shooting for a take
down and going for the single,
he blasts him with left hands.
He heard him when he got on top of him.
He hurt him really bad in this
one exchange in the third round.
He had them fucking rocked.
It was a bad fucking moment for Rory,
but I'll tell you what, man, Rory
can take it. That kid is so tough.
He's so good and he's so technical,
but Robbie's just so God damn ferocious.
I was so impressed with Roy,
especially in the first round about
how he avoided Robbie's charges.
I watched that fight just like, like the
punches would come to his nose. Right.
He knew just how far to get back.
I watched that fight with a,
with a guy who took a bronze medal in
the Olympics in boxing. Tony Jeffries,
who teaches Brennan shop and he was,
he was watching Rory and he said,
he was like, he was like, that
guy's got the best footwork
I've seen. He said, as a,
from an MMA fighter. He said, his foot
works unbelievable. He's super technical.
Just Lawler was just a little
too much for him that night,
especially in that one
round when he heard him,
but it was still a really close fight. You
know, Roy, he's a bad motherfucker, man.
On the phone. He's, by the way,
he's going to get even better.
He's still young as shit. He's
24 years old. After this fight,
he's going to come back even stronger. And
here's my, here's my next question. Uh,
Hector Lombard fights. Johnny
Hendricks. What would happen? Oh, Jesus.
The world would explode and I agree.
Madness. Can you imagine that?
Imagine powerhouses like that.
Well,
there's a lot of guys out there for him
now for Hector Lombard and for Johnny
Hendricks. Say, how about
Tyron Woodley? Tyrone Woodley,
he's a fucking monster man.
Him Versus Hector Lombard would
be the most muscular contest ever.
Like the two most muscular man.
170, so stacked. It's crazy. Yeah.
What's up with your friend Nate Marquardt?
Is he going to retire now?
I don't know. I uh, I just exchanged
texts with him and, uh, I, I don't know.
I don't want to speak for
him. Um, I, I don't know,
I just think that at Nate's been
fighting for a very long time,
a very high level and, uh,
a lot of hard sparring too.
A lot of hard sparring.
You'd sparring party,
sparred with Shane Carwyn for
eight years. Good luck. Yeah,
that's an interesting story. Like when
they asked GSP to with Shane Carwyn,
he's like, why? Why would
I spoke with them? Why?
Because to learn 70 fucking pounds
by Shane. Carmen hits like a,
like a fricking mule kick.
Yeah.
It's like getting punched by a telephone
pole at the end of a telephone pole.
Just Dong Dong. It's got the biggest
hand. Shane's got the biggest,
thickest hands I've ever seen. Big His
hands ever in the UFC. I believe it. Yeah,
he had like three XL or four XL gloves.
They're ridiculous.
They're like these giant
canned hands arms. It's a tough
guy, man. He and you know,
and for the longest time Nate and him were
training partners and they would spar.
And the idea that Nate who would fight
eventually in his best way class at 170
pounds to be fighting a guy who was
one of the bigger heavyweights. Crazy.
That's how smart he was or how
good he was. Nate, Nate is when,
when I talked to Brendan and train with
him for eight years, and Shane the,
when they talk about Nate and you know,
I mean,
and remember Nate's GSPS main
sparring partner for a long time,
I believe was named one of
his biggest trading partners.
Uh, you know, they, they,
they talk about Nate and hidden hushed
tones. He was as bad as like, I mean,
Nate is a bad motherfucker,
man at his best.
If you go back and watch
like the Tyron Woodley fight,
when he fought with me in strike
force and knocked him out,
it was Nate then my one of his
finest performance. It's incredible.
He beat a lot of good
guys at 185 pounds to me.
Stop Martin Kampmann and 185 pounds.
Um,
Wilson go Veja I stopped
flying a hundred feet. Yeah.
Knocked Damien Maia with one punch.
Yep. Name was a bad mother fucker.
But it goes back to the GSP thing.
It's like they all have a certain
amount of time in this game. Yeah.
There's a certain amount of shots you can
take. There's a certain amount of time.
It's chill son. And I said,
what are you going to do?
You've been competing since
you are nine years old.
Like well how do you replace the
juice of competition? And he said,
I have no idea.
I mean that's a huge part for,
I think a lot of guys who are extreme
winters, extreme athletes, you know,
which I consider cage
fighters to be, no doubt. Um,
I think that substituting that all
that you get from that is very,
very difficult man.
Yeah.
Well there's also the fact that that's
how they define themselves. You know,
it's like, could you imagine if all
the sudden you just weren't funny? Yep.
Like you would go on stage
and you just eat shit.
You just weren't funny and people found
you just tasteful and they would boom,
didn't drag me off the stage, man. Yeah.
You try to figure out like what is,
what went wrong here? Do you do? Yeah.
What do you do? Well with a fighter,
that's what it's like.
It's like,
it comes a point in time where
your body is just, it's taken its,
its share of blows and that's it.
You start to see it,
they start to have these breakdowns
started to have these injuries and knee
injuries, back injuries, neck injuries,
elbow injuries, shoulder surgery.
All this stuff starts to happen. The
weird wheels literally start falling off.
Yeah. You know, and until they
figure out a way to make it so that,
that doesn't happen, you
know, until it's always, yeah.
Been the deal with athlete's foot,
great football players and great
baseball players. What, when, when,
when the crowd started cheering,
um, what do you do now?
And that's always been an
issue for a lot of athletes.
It's a deal with the
devil. You know, you, you,
you have 10 incredible years
and then the rest of the time,
by the time you're 32, you're a veteran
and it's time to quit. A lot of times,
you know, [inaudible]
you've got to, I always,
that's why I think than a lot of ways
you've got to feed your brain at the same
time. Yeah. You get, definitely
got to feed your brain.
But I think as also like what's going to
happen if they figure out a way to fix
things,
like what's going to happen in the future
if the consequences of fighting or not
as extreme.
Like,
like if one day they get to a point where
they can regenerate neuro tissue and
speed up injuries,
traumatic brain injuries just re
rehabilitate your brain to 100% probably a
better and better body probably get
better and better or or not. I mean,
one of the things that they
find with people is that, again,
I'm sorry to bring up Dan Coyle again,
but you know, you stop developing like a,
people type 80 words a minute
and they don't get any better.
People play golf and they stop at an 85
handicap because most people will get
good enough and then stop it.
To get that much better requires a
whole different level of practice,
a different kind of practice.
You've gotta be obsessed. You've got
to get a fucking crazy person. Well,
you remember when you're
first starting out,
when you're doing comedy and there was
guys that were with you in the open mic
days and they just fucking
kind of dropped off and grow.
They didn't mess with it. Exactly. You
got to do, I love that spirit when you're,
when you're a young
comedian and it's like, Eh,
you're looking for a joke everywhere.
Yeah. What's funny about a tree? Oh man,
we can write about a table or you know,
microphones.
When I used to drive newspapers,
I had this,
a van that didn't have
any radio in it and uh,
it was the best thing ever because this,
this monotonous work that I would
do and it was high on Dunkin donuts,
coffee and fucking Boston cream donuts
had this mad sugar rush and I was up at
five o'clock in the morning throwing
newspapers out the window and driving
around by myself. I would get all my
material. That's where I get all my,
I don't play music in my car a lot of
times because I know, all right, if I,
if I'm driving,
you know,
and it's nice because at the end of the
day I feel like I accomplished something
when I surprise myself with an idea that
that to me is coming up with an idea
and surprising myself with a bit like
the other day I came up with something,
but it just,
it's such a good feeling.
It's better almost then performing
it in some ways, you know? Yeah.
Well it's a gift. It's a gift
for your time and focused. Yeah.
You, Tom and focused gives
you this gift. You know,
when you sit in front of a computer for
hours and hours and you just got this
one line, you're like, ah,
one line. That's one line.
Just that's all you need it.
That's all you need.
Then you take that one line,
you cut and paste it into your little
folder and you're like, Bam. Yeah.
If you don't show up that thought,
that line doesn't get written.
If you don't sit in front of that
computer, that line doesn't get written.
I love that idea to show that what you
just said is that if you've got to show
up, got to show in a way,
if you keep showing up,
something will be revealed to you. That's
the whole point of Pressfield's work.
You know, the war of art. That's his whole
thing, you know, showing up. So thing.
Did you ever see the podcast? I've read
both his books. He's amazing. Oh Man.
Really, really cool guy. Yeah, we did
a podcast together. Me, him and Aubrey.
I think it's amazing. Is Red
is nonfiction stuff. I've read,
well I've read both now,
but uh,
mostly the nonfiction stuff is
what I'd read for the nonfiction.
I didn't read the legend
of Bagger Vance and stuff.
Be read his fiction stuff though about
like the Romans and the Greeks and he's
got a lot of really wild
shit, man. He's awesome.
But just this whole thing is about having
that habit to just work to get it done.
And it applies to like anything creative,
not just to writing but like the pre
pretty much anything you would want to do,
whether it's practicing music or you know,
creating a film.
Just fucking actually go to work.
And that's what a lot of people don't
going to because the world is filled with
weak bitches. That's how we're going
to end this. Ladies and gentlemen.
Tell be a weak bitch.
Get it together.
Thank you. Say November
29th and 30th guys, where,
where are you going to appeal
apparently. Do you say that? Yes.
Apparently I'll be here at the time.
Rose is going to be an Austin, Texas.
Is this true?
Apparently November 30th stateside don't
come to our shows unless you want to
laugh really hard,
especially Tom Rhodes
and have the high level
podcast stamp of approval. The,
the standup comedian gold
star, they're, they're uh,
they're out there and they're two
of the funniest guys working today.
Go see him and fucking dirty bitches.
That's Tom Rhodes and Brian Cowen.
Follow them on Twitter as well.
Thanks to our sponsors,
including stamps.com that we do today.
What are we doing to buy
stamps.com stamps? Top calm,
powerful stamps.com a beautiful
way to send shit through the mail.
Go to stamps.com use the code word j r
e and get your one on 100 and hundred
dollar has $110 bonus offer,
including a digital scale
and put $55 or free postage.
Who all thanks also to
carbonite. Um, wait,
am I god damn it.
I'm fucking terrible at these things.
I never know where I put them on my
folder. Um, thanks also to carbonite.
Go to carbonite.com
type in the offer code,
J r e for a free trial,
no credit card required plus two free
bonus months with your subscription.
That's carbonite.com go there
and said fucking awesome set up.
We use it here at the chew.
It'll get experience and thanks to
[inaudible] dot com that's o n n I t,
makers of Alpha brain. Use a
codeword Rogan. Save yourself
10% off anything else.
Also governments Halabach we will
be podcasting all this weekend,
Brian Cowen and ask as we go out on the
manliness of manly adventures hunting
deer in Wisconsin will be
cold cold. We'll be cool. Yes,
we will be doing it for Steve
or Nellis TV show meat eater.
We're doing it again round two last time.
Last time we were in Montana,
this time we're in Wisconsin, we
give zero fucks. We play zero games.
We're out there folks sling a deck
and given out bubble gum and we'll be
podcasting the entire
week that we're there.
So we'll have a bunch of shit for
you when we get back. And, uh,
we love the fuck out of you people and we
appreciate the fuck out of you as well.
Big Kiss and let's see a ceiling.