Hello Freak bitches,
not I recently that,
you know,
these,
the people that want to,
to fight and then he got lost me Phi and
Blah Blah Blah.
And then you find out what they did
until the runup or what did you do?
Oh,
I got drunk,
let's see,
weeks before hello.
What a fucking surprise if you will not
live in it.
And if you're not,
you know,
getting,
really immersing yourself and in every
way in the language that you speak to
yourself and in the way that you do
everything else.
Once you expect your mind's not going to
support you if you don't support it.
Yeah.
That was one of the things that I felt
when Jon Jones tested positive for
cocaine three weeks out of his fight
with Daniel Cormier,
I was like,
Ooh.
Like he's not even other.
I look,
I only was anything wrong with doing,
I don't know if there's anything wrong
with doing cocaine.
I just,
I don't think it's a positive drug,
but some people enjoy it.
Um,
some people enjoy drinking.
I enjoy drinking.
I don't think that's positive drug
necessarily either.
So,
I don't know cause I don't have
experience with cocaine,
but that's not something you're supposed
to be doing three weeks outside of a
world title fight with one of the best
wrestlers in the sport.
One of the most difficult challenges
you've ever faced in your professional
career and you're out doing blow just 21
days before.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
Sometimes the most talented take the
gifts that they've been given and just
abused them in a way.
I met Jon Jones.
He's um,
it's different to say the least.
And what,
where he was,
I didn't know he was,
it was kind of,
I only met him briefly.
Why was it I made him in Russia,
the legend that is a show there and a,
yeah,
he was just,
he was very sort of,
it was all over the place,
bouncing around and I just,
I just didn't expect him to be like
that.
Expect.
And what do you mean by all over the
place bounds?
It just,
he just said to me,
Hi blue eyes and was like,
hello,
he's my from dangerous and I'm not.
I was like,
hi.
I just found it a bit strange.
Maybe I read into with you.
I just found him different.
Let's just say that I just found him
different and I,
I'm trying to read into this.
I,
and I'm trying to avoid it badly.
He,
I don't know him.
I met,
he was,
it was different.
Let's put it that way,
you know?
But um,
if,
if they,
if someone,
I don't know,
you don't know what's going on in his
life and you know,
life and you could say that about
everyone.
He could say that about a serial killer,
couldn't ya?
But we do know what's going in his life.
It's not as full,
you know,
really.
I mean,
there is some things that you shouldn't
do and you know,
he shouldn't be doing it.
But these reasons,
if you listen to John's coaches,
they will tell you that John Surrounds
himself with the wrong people.
And John is an extremely talented guy.
Amazing.
It's like maybe one of the most talented
guys to ever compete in the sport and
incredibly strong mentally too.
Because despite all of his issues with
maybe not preparing as well as he could
when the chips are down,
that guy gets through things.
He overcomes adversity.
He's not a front runner.
He's the one that broke his toe,
isn't a,
that was terrific.
So he's gone,
but he didn't even realize that was
happening that that happened actually in
the final flurry where he stopped chill
son and a more impressive performance is
when he fought vitor Belfort,
Vito or completely hyper extended his
arm and he would not tap,
you know,
it was for his title Vi tour came that
close.
Was it for the title?
I believe it was.
It might've been non title fight,
but [inaudible] came find out if that
was a title fight or non title fight.
Either way [inaudible] came that close
to legitimately beating John Jones.
That clothes got a lot fully locked in
Armbar that would have made 90% of the
professional fighters in the world tap.
Well that's what makes him who he is.
But he,
but he couldn't say notice it was a
title fight.
Yeah.
Jamie just looked at him.
He couldn't say no to some blow.
Well he could say no,
he want it.
Didn't want us to get some sort of,
I don't know of any,
his weakness,
I don't know these people,
there's some sort of weakness,
weakness or don't know if it is
deliberate,
it's not.
He shouldn't be something you should be
doing.
It's also indulgence.
It's like he likes to party,
you know,
but then there's isn't there also the
issue that fighters in particular,
especially guys that are about a lot of
hard gym sessions and a lot of hard
fights,
they have impulse control problems and
those impulse control problems.
I'm obviously not a scientist or a
doctor,
but when you talk to neurologists and
neuroscientists,
they will tell you that there are direct
correlations between head impacts and
poor impulse control.
Right.
It is absolutely a direct impact.
And I,
you know,
not looking for a scapegoat in my own
life,
but I've looked back at some of the poor
decision making that I've done in my
life,
particularly in my fighting times,
like back then and I was like,
I wonder if a lot of that was getting
hit in the head a lot.
Like,
like it can't be good to get kicked in
the head.
It's just never good.
Not In the past,
just not good.
And so if you've been kicked in the head
or punched in the face or whatever,
you know,
any kind of impact.
And that's the thing about football
players,
they're saying now is it even a shot to
the chest even getting tackled like
someone rams at you and slams their
shoulders into your chest.
The brain gets jostled around.
Yeah.
You might not have a bruise on your
face,
but your brain is receiving essentially
the same impact as a punch.
Yeah,
I was just kinda crazy.
You know,
people might not like,
they split it as a shade that Jon Jones
has gone.
Like,
you know what I mean?
Cause he's got a lot back on him.
You know what I mean?
He's got to look back on him and they
fuck,
you know,
he's also got to figure out what it is
that he took.
You know,
they,
they don't even exactly to have an
isolated what he took,
but the whole lifestyle,
it's,
it's cert most certainly an issue.
And it's almost like one of those things
where you say you don't know what you
got until it's gone.
Well,
it was kind of gone for a little while,
but not really.
He was always still in the mix and there
was always multimillion dollar fights,
a waiting.
And then he fought over in saint proves.
So he's back in the mix and everything's
looking good.
He's slated to fight at UFC 200 against
Daniel cormier is gonna make like 10
million bucks.
It's going to be giant.
And then whoosh,
it's gone for something that if you
talked to people that are experts in
performance enhancing drugs,
they will tell you that this clomiphene
is what he got popped for,
which is an anti estrogen supplement
that's not even beneficial.
The only time that stuff's beneficial as
a set of,
essentially when you're coming off of
steroids,
but yet he didn't test positive for
steroids before or after.
So it could have been a tainted
supplement.
It could have been a mistake.
It could have been,
who knows what wacky shit he was taken.
I mean,
I don't know.
I just think that,
you know,
people forget that they locked sometimes
you've still got off guidance,
you know,
you still go,
oh,
have a guide and you know,
to just say,
look,
is that the best thing you should be
doing or someone to talk.
So,
you know what I mean?
It's not going to be high five and you,
cause you're going to,
you know,
stick a lot of bugle your nose.
Isn't it harder though,
I think for champions because once they
like dominate someone to kick someone's
ass,
like say if you fight the,
the most difficult fight of your career,
you fight,
you know,
uh,
well there's Daniel Cormier,
whoever it is,
you'd dominate them,
you win and a beautiful fashion and then
you know,
you like,
God damn it,
I am the fucking man.
Yeah.
And then you just want to do whatever
you want to do after that,
and it's indulgence and chaos.
Yeah.
He did it.
Or is both the eight comes to bite you
on the ass all the time.
[inaudible] yeah.