Dum,
dum,
[inaudible].
Yes.
We're live John Dudley.
Phone away.
And let's get popping.
No,
I got,
I,
I have some,
some important subjects that I wanted to
vent about.
So did you put them on a little note?
Yeah,
I've got a notepad.
I'm pretty good about doing homework.
So I love your podcast.
So listening through there is craft you
talked about.
I was like,
Oh yeah,
I got to get on.
Are you got to bring it up?
Yeah.
So John Dudley,
world famous archery coach.
Uh,
he's got a TV show.
He's got a podcast,
uh,
found out about you because of the TV
show first,
the podcast Sacramento.
I became obsessed with.
If you're in the archery,
like I know some of these people that
are listening to this podcast,
they get into archery because it sounds
fun.
Like,
Ooh,
maybe I need a new hobby.
And then you go down that crazy rabbit
hole.
Well,
what I found you,
you're,
you're down the rabbit hole like a few
light years.
You're gone,
man.
Freaking Johnny Depp.
Then Johnny,
you're gone.
You're gone down though.
The archery rabbit hole.
I had no idea the rabbit hole goes so
deep,
but let's show this video.
We're going to play this video.
This is before John came up here.
He did.
Now I just set need to explain how
difficult it is just to even hit a
target at 100 yards.
This is at a hundred.
Yeah.
One hundred yards is a football length
of a football field and I'm gonna.
Shut that thing off.
It's just shut the volume off there.
I'm 100 yards of length of a football
field and for archery is just.
It's so hard to hit something as wide as
your wingspan at 100 yards for the
average person,
and so John made this ridiculous shot on
one of the gorilla kettlebells from
onnit.
Yeah,
this was a solo play.
This here,
unbelievable challenge.
I've got Joe Rogan's favorite workout
tool.
I've got an onnit kettle,
Bell,
primal and Kong is going to have to make
a decision whether he's going to let
this era pass or not.
I'm going to try to put an Arrow through
that two inch handle right there and
actually at this distance of a hundred
yards and the angle that arrows to come
in,
I bet it's even smaller.
This is going to be an unbelievable
challenge.
Definitely going to have to defy the
odds,
my ideas.
There it is right here on this shelf and
I've got a curtain right behind so
hopefully it'll stop the Arrow but also
let it do its thing so that would
capture all this on tape right at dark.
I'm going to put an Arrow through a two
inch gap and the handle if calm lets it
pass.
There it is.
Check it out.
Just so ridiculous
that that actually went in that little
hole at 100 yards.
Did you have to try more than one
attempt at.
This was actually my first shot with
everything set up because I had to do a
little bit of homework.
What I did was I knew I couldn't see the
hole in the handle good enough to aim at
it,
so I actually cited my bow into where I
hit four and a half inches high from
Kong's face,
so I literally aimed right at Kong shiny
face and I had my both cited in to hit
four and a half inches high to make it
through the gap.
That's insane.
Yup.
Yeah.
Spellman right here.
Sharon was running the iphone but I had
four cameras out so we can get some cool
angles and stuff and I wanted to wait
till night so that that lighted nock
could give a little bit more.
Wow factor for everyone watching this.
It's such a ridiculous shot,
but this is a hundred yards thanks to
the audit people to for that was awesome
and getting that thing look at that and
it was pretty crazy.
There you go,
Joe.
How awesome is that?
It's pretty amazing.
And you guys watch that on Youtube.
It just went off on youtube.
On the knock on archery.
Yeah.
Not.
Did you guys put it up to you?
We'll put a link up.
Okay.
Jamie just put you,
if you can tweet it and I'll,
I'll retweet it when we get a chance.
That is insanely hard to do.
It's A.
I mean,
I never did any archery whatsoever until
about three years ago.
I mean,
maybe I might've done it.
I think I might've done it in the boy
scouts.
Yeah.
Everyone says that.
You know what's funny is every person
that finds out one,
they're in disbelief that there's
actually like professional archers,
but then they say,
oh,
I tried archery like back in school on
time and Jim and I loved it and,
but then everyone says,
but I hit my arm.
Right.
Remember that they tried it once and
they loved it,
but they hit their arm.
That's what they always say.
Yeah.
That's.
I always thought you had to wear those
risk.
Things.
Like when I would see people that were
shooting bows without those risks
things.
I'm like,
they're like riding a motorcycle without
a helmet.
These people are crazy.
They're loose people.
Well,
the way some people shoot it is like
riding a bike without a helmet,
appeal some skin off.
You do it the wrong way.
Well,
that's what I've been going into over
these last couple of days with you and
this one more more fascinating aspects
about this.
I want to.
I don't want to call it a sport because
I think archery is a lot of different
things.
It's a discipline for sure,
but in when it's done correctly in lot
of ways it's almost like a martial art.
It's like learning.
It's like a weapon.
Art,
like in martial arts,
when you see someone do something,
like if someone's like really good at
judo or something like that,
like when they execute throw and it's
just perfect position and perfect
technique.
It's beautiful.
You know,
this is like a beauty to it.
Yeah.
And when you see an an archer like I was
talking to you about that this when I
was watching and trying to get it in my
head,
this sort of follow that you have in
what you do and it's super similar in a
lot of ways and something that I really
didn't predict.
Like I guess I just always assumed that
I kind of know what something is.
If it seems pretty straightforward,
like,
oh yeah,
you pull the string back and then you
let the Arrow fly.
Pretty straightforward,
like I think that's most people's idea
of what archery is,
but then when you really pay attention
to the technical aspects of all the
different stuff that's going on and all
the different things you think about and
how you literally can not have anything
on your mind other than all the
technique involved,
your foot placement,
your technique,
and standing,
your breathing,
where you're drawing it back,
the position of your front shoulder,
the position of your rear elbow,
how you're pulling,
where it,
how,
what do you,
how do you respond after the hour was
released?
There's so much going on that like when
you put it all together like it,
it has.
It leaves no room for homework.
There's no room for relationship
bullshit.
There's no room for taxes.
There's no room in there.
Man.
If you want to make a nice shot like
that,
like I guarantee you,
if we can have a brain scan of your head
the second you release that Arrow at a
hundred yards to go in that two inch
gap,
there would be nothing in there other
than what you did.
It would be no other.
No other cells would be fired up.
Nope.
No.
That's one thing.
And actually like yesterday when we were
shooting
there,
the end of the day,
you got to the point where you almost,
your mind was clear.
It's almost like for me,
you know,
your family came home,
like things are winding down.
You knew that like work was over and we.
It was like right before dark and like
for me,
I love shooting at first light and it
lasts light because it seems like that's
what I'm not really worried about.
Someone texting me or calling me.
I'm not worried about problem at home
and I shoot with a clear mind and I am
way more efficient in my practice and it
is a form of meditation.
I mean,
it's like you said,
it's an art and if you're clouded than
you,
it will reflect that on the target.
I mean it's like if your arrows are in
one spot,
then you know you have a single focus
and it's almost like the more those
arrows are spread,
that's a representation of how many
other thoughts and distractions you have
going in your mind.
I mean,
and I look at it that way when I shoot,
I'm trying to narrow everything down to
just a movement and you look at good
golfers,
the ones that swing easy and it just
literally looks like flow.
There's such good strikers and there's
so much more efficient when you see
people that are trying to be robotic
and,
and almost like hack something.
Then it's like too systematic.
You know,
you see someone like that does
professional karate or something.
If they're in a forums competition,
if they're like
real rigid going around.
It's just not what it's meant to be.
I mean it's supposed to be a dance.
It's supposed to be like literally a
mental musical that's plan and if your
mind is clear then it's,
it's a form of meditation really is no
question about it.
And that same state of total complete
concentration exists in a bunch of
different disciplines and I,
you know,
finding it in archery now rec or I
should say recognizing it,
I definitely haven't hit it.
But finding that,
seeing it and recognizing that sort of a
super high level flow that comes into
play when someone's excellent at what
they do.
Um,
I've seen that in pool.
I've seen that watching professional
pool players like perfect example of
what you were talking about,
striking the ball really hard as a
golfer.
There's a guy named Francisco Bustamante
is one of the best pool players in the
world and he's from the Philippines and
Francisco Bustamante has the most
ridiculous break you would think if you
watch his break shot,
that he weighs 400 pounds and has arms
like tree trunks.
You watch that break just blah,
blah,
blah.
It all just the triangle.
If you watch them,
just watch the speed of the ball and
it's effortless.
The way he does it,
he's just,
he has this perfect amount of timing and
flow here.
You could see him do it here.
This isn't him.
This is a different guy.
It just look up a Bustamante Francisco
Bustamante breaking.
That's what it says that there.
Well,
there's definitely not him.
This is a some overweight gentlemen.
What if it gained.
Oh,
that is him.
That is.
He was just.
It's a weird.
He's in a weird pose.
Oh,
that's what it is.
It's just a weird pose.
I thought when he was bent over,
I thought that was his whole body.
Yeah,
it's loading,
but he's a tiny guy.
Like if you see him physically.
Yeah.
I mean he.
It might weigh like,
well he's a little fat now he's getting
older,
but when he was young he probably
weighed like 140 pounds,
but he was like,
oh my goodness.
Those balls,
they go flying everywhere.
No one's like him.
Jihad dog.
He's excited.
I think he just one on the break or
something like that.
I've seen him make six balls on the
brake,
like he's playing nine ball.
He make six balls in the break.
He's got three balls to run out.
It's just insanely good,
but he's just a devastating player all
around.
And one of the things when you watch him
play and a lot of the Filipinos,
Filipinos are so good.
There's so many really good Filipino
pool players,
but they have this gentle flow to what
they're doing.
Like everything is like a ballet,
like effortless.
Deloitte of the q does like all the work
and everything looks like it looks like
so flowing.
Like a dance,
like a dance.
Well,
the one thing that's so cool about,
well the one thing I'm really proud of
is an archer,
is that I've got to the point where I
have a platform to get people involved.
And that was
when I found out that you really liked
my podcasts,
which the podcasts are totally geared
around education and learning.
You know,
that's what that I got to a platform to
where I could help people.
And now there's people like you that are
coming in that never really have
considered that whole world.
And they come in and I look at people
that like,
you know,
they go to the YMC A,
they want to take like touchy or they
want to take yoga.
They're looking for a stress free type
of hobby.
And archery is a great sport for that.
It's growing so much.
I mean Hollywood's embracing it
obviously with a lot of the movies,
but they're,
they're not portraying it as an art
form.
When that movie the hell's it called,
where's the girl who go hungry again
when she started becoming more famous or
that movie rather became popular.
Archery took off.
Oh yeah.
A lot of people got involved.
Yeah.
I mean,
you look at,
um,
you look at the avengers,
you look at hunger games,
there's,
there's actually so many,
even a lot of the sitcoms now p,
you know,
obviously crossbows are popular because
of the walking dead,
but when it comes to like true archery,
you just see a lot more archers coming
in.
Lord of the rings,
you know,
legless was so popular because of,
because of that.
And it's really such a cool sport.
I mean,
it's an Olympic sport and we've.
We've actually have a phenomenal Olympic
team here in the US.
Our men's team is definitely going to be
contenders for another metal.
They were silver medalist last year and
so you were saying that compound bows
are not in the Olympics and the recurve
bows,
it's recurve bows and that's kind of a
tradition and honestly it's a different
style of art,
but it's super graceful to.
And I mean I think it's everyone has
something that they like to do.
Some people like the simplicity of a
sport.
It's like there's people that go and
want to only have a long bow or they
don't want sites.
They just want the zen part of trying to
pull back with with no sites,
but then there's also people like us
that want to see how finite and accurate
you can become.
So they liked the techie side,
which is where compound bows come in and
they're just.
They're much more efficient and
obviously the accuracy as we seen is,
is almost mindblowing mindblowing
guy like me because I'm a gadget dork.
So it combines both things.
It combines the zen aspect of complete
and total discipline and focus and
looking at one task and be drowning out
the rest of the world,
but it also has like geeky stuff,
like different kinds of sites and this
is a new cam that they just came out
with and these are different kinds of
strings and when you do this,
that makes this better and this is so
much going on with it.
Oh yeah.
You can,
you know,
if I look back at the bose I started
with and I've,
I've only been shooting since 97,
so 19 years I guess it seemed.
I'm getting old now,
but um,
that's a long time.
The bose that I use then that are at the
house.
You wonder how in the heck he shot that
good with.
Um,
and actually,
um,
two months ago I was at the Olympic
headquarters,
like the Olympic Museum.
So they have all these awesome Olympic
artifacts of like swim trunks,
people oil or like,
you know,
the javelin.
I got to see the original recurve bow,
like Jay bars was actually on display
and they constantly change them.
So if you're visiting the museum,
you're not seeing the same things all
the time,
but you look at those pieces of
equipment,
the bikes,
the bikes that people wrote in the
Olympic Games,
it's like,
holy cow,
how are they that efficient?
It's almost more impressive because now
we've gotten so advanced in our
equipment that it's easier to be at the
level,
I think than 20 years ago because the
equipment just wasn't there.
You know,
I almost wonder if those people didn't
have to put in two or three times the
time and be just that much more elegant
at what they did because their equipment
was almost a handicap back then.
Could they perform the same kind of
feats?
Like could someone shoot an Arrow like
that?
Like was it a common thing to be able to
shoot what you did 100 yards and
shooting through that two inch opening
into the Kettlebell handle?
Um,
I'm sure there are people that were,
there's a lot,
there's actually a lot of people in
archery now that are pushing this
envelope.
I mean,
long distance shooting is becoming super
popular and you know,
to a lot of the real target archers that
are out there that are listening to this
podcast.
See,
when we go to a full feed of tournament,
we shoot 30 feet,
fetus stand for um,
well now it's world archery.
So a world archery event.
If you shot a,
a full target round,
you would shoot arrows at 30 or 30
meters,
50 meters,
70 meters and 90 meters.
So I found out from you that 90 meters
is 99 yards.
It's one of the easiest metric
conversions that do.
You take the first number and you add it
to the second.
So if you've got 40,
take the floor and added behind the 40,
you got 44 yards.
If it's 40 meters.
So yeah,
that's one of the one metric system that
I never forget,
but I'm so 99 yards is where we would
stand on the line and shoot at,
you know,
and I,
I think I told you that back in 2005,
I was really focused on shooting well
for the u s team when I was on the
compound team and there were several
tournaments that I was really focused
on.
I knew that I was going to be shooting.
I'm a national championship and in
Britain and in Australia,
I was going to be going.
I think I shot one in Poland,
um,
had won one or two here in the.
But you know,
in that year I think I logged.
I mean I shot two,
three,
$400 a day and 90 meters for me,
the further you go out,
it's like putting a bigger microscope on
things that you're doing wrong.
You know,
it's,
it's just like an art or um,
if you look at a golfer that's making
long putts,
obviously it's magnifying mistakes and
they're swinging or golfers that are
drivers,
you know,
people that really are just sitting
there trying to be accurate at the long
game.
It magnifies mistakes.
So I really like shooting at longer
distances.
I know you do too because it magnifies a
mistake and you can correct it easier
and it really helps bring things
together.
But that year I shot well over 30,000
arrows at 99 yards during steering
training things.
Yeah.
I mean,
and there's professional archers,
there's archery,
there's archers right now somewhere
that's preparing for a world cup event
or something.
And there's people that literally have
calluses thicker and most weightlifters
just from grabbing a hold of that
release or you know,
I remember looking at an Olympic recurve
shooters fingers one time,
um,
and I remember his,
his hands,
his three fingers that he grabs a string
with.
It looked like a frog hand because the
tips were so big from pulling blood
because he,
and I mean these guys,
you look at the people that are like the
Olympic training centers that are just
there,
they get up,
they go eat and then they shoot until
five or six at night and they eat and
then they go and do a weight training
session.
I bet you there's people that do a
thousand errors a day.
So you know,
you can build up some stamina.
Yeah,
it's really impressive.
Um,
but in saying that,
I think with archery it's,
you know,
you know that I'm really big into
fitness as well.
I credit my fitness and my story is an
athlete prior to being an archer as part
of what's helped me be successful and
there's a big difference between
quantity and quality and a lot of people
make the mistake I think with any sport
of just trying to practice more or train
more.
And even weightlifters,
you know,
I see people that I go in the gym and
they're like on one exercise and then
when I leave the gym in 50 minutes or an
hour were like maybe done two different
types of exercise and it's just,
it's not efficient,
you know,
I think a lot of people as athletes
sometimes miss the boat of quality over
over the quantity in.
And I was always that way.
There's days where I go practice and I
may only make 100 shots,
but once I started realizing that I'm
breaking down,
I know to step away.
You don't try to push through it.
Yeah.
And I told you that yesterday too.
There was a time where I said,
you know,
if,
if we're just out here getting
repetition,
I guess that's one thing,
but we really don't need to do that.
Aiming at a target.
We had a really good point too about
those bad shots and bad repetitions.
You gotta you gotta get those out of
your head.
So it's not just that you made a bad
shot.
Now you have to make a bunch of good
shots to try to get away with you from
the effect of the bad shot.
It's not as simple as the one bad shot.
No,
it's imprinting.
I mean it's,
it's an imprint and I think with any
type of athletic,
you know,
and it's probably that way with
fighters.
I'm sure too if you get someone that's
just really in a rhythm and a flow,
if also when they start making a mistake
or doing something bad as a coach,
he try to get them back into that rhythm
again so that you can weed out that
imprint.
You know,
and that's tough as an athlete sometimes
you know,
people that,
and I'm sure for fighters,
you know,
you look at people that come out and
have a disappointing loss.
It's almost like that's an imprint.
It is.
And that's why that statement and you're
only as good as your last fight.
It was so disturbing to fighters.
Yeah.
And and that's one thing,
one of the most important things that I
learned as a competitive archer and I
was,
I had a temper when I first started as a
pro,
if I made a bad shot,
you know,
Kinda like when you kind of put one in
the pool
when you put one of the pool and you
were like,
frigate,
you are pissed off.
I,
that's how I would be on a,
on a,
on a tournament,
you know,
I would freak and ran my stabilizer
under the ground so hard that I would
crack it in my mind problem was.
And that just did it once I did a,
this is really complicated,
Geeky sort of an explanation folks,
but there's a certain type of release
where it's attention based release and
as we're practicing with and difference
between pulling a trigger and then
allowing the tension,
but you have to hold the safety while
you pull it back.
Otherwise the Arrow just,
it just fly.
It means it's not like,
it's not like it's going to shoot
anything.
It's going really slow,
but it logs in a very embarrassing and
just very disappointing when this book
comes off your thing,
as you're pulling the bow back,
it goes blank and you go,
what the fuck?
I did this.
I did it three times,
did it yesterday and today.
Super.
It's super embarrassing.
But uh,
so that's,
uh,
yeah,
I was definitely annoyed myself.
Well,
when I would make something like that,
that would really trigger me into a
pissed off realm,
I would let one mistake affect
everything else after that.
And a lot of athletes,
they're really good athletes that I
watch and any sport tennis players,
golfers,
the key is when you have a negative
moment to not let it affect what hasn't
happened yet.
So I'm a guy came up to me one time
after I made a bad shot and he could
tell I was getting hot and he looked at
me and he said,
you know,
the only arrows you have control on
right now are the ones that are still in
that quiver.
And for me that,
like,
it completely changed my outcome as a
professional archer.
And I've,
I've brought so much of what archery has
done to me as an athlete into my life
and there's times were you just
something really torques you off and you
have to just like look at,
okay,
everything I do from here on out is the
only thing I have control on because
that's history.
There's no,
I haven't figured out a way.
Once that released,
glows playing to actually grab that
Arrow and pull it back and stick it back
in the quiver or put it back on the
string.
It's like a perfect representation of
life.
You make a decision.
If it was shit,
you have to reset and say,
what do I need to do with myself to get
back on track in life?
We make bad decisions at times,
but how do we make a good decision to
get back on,
get back online?
Yeah.
It's,
it's management of the mind in a lot of
ways.
Yup.
And it's one of the things that I also
like about our true love about archery
is that it's absolute like you,
you can't pull that Arrow back like it's
flying through the air.
And either it hits the Bullseye or you
missed.
It's just it is what it is.
It doesn't care about where you live.
It doesn't care who your uncle is,
it doesn't care how much money you make
you here,
it doesn't care like the the arrows
going to go.
It's an absolute discipline and I think
you coming from professionals or coming
from sports or other sports background,
we played a lot of football
when you play sports,
but especially insanely competitive
sports,
you learn where all the edges are to be
had.
You learn with all the edges are to be
had as far as technique,
as far as conditioning,
so it all the different things you have
to do in order to be successful and to
win.
And everyone knows that in most sports,
especially in the physical sport like
football,
there's a fucking lot of work involved.
There's not a single person who jumps
off the bench who doesn't have any
training whatsoever and kicks ass and
football.
You just don't.
You gotta learn and you have to learn
how to move.
You have to learn all the different
plays.
You have to learn.
Technique involved in different aspects
of the sport and I think coming from a
competitive background in athletics,
you've kind of translated that
understanding of where all the problems
are in archery because there's a lot of
people that are like,
they don't have good coaching and so
they start off with a lot of really bad
habits and then they have to figure out
a way to either break those habits or
they live with those habits and then
they do the best they with this sort of
limited path that they've carved in and
they seem to not be able to escape.
The same thing exists in martial arts.
One of the hardest things for me when I
used to teach was teaching people that
already had a bad technique imprinted in
their brain.
Like they would have one way of throwing
a kick or something like that and that
would have to go,
oh Jesus.
I got to figure out a way to break this
guy.
Have this thing.
Because as soon as he gets tired or as
soon as he panics,
the Nigos down,
the foot goes up.
It loses all the power of the hips,
don't engage.
It's like,
but if I could take a kid like a five
year old kid and show them that from the
beginning,
their instinct would be to throw it
correctly.
The instinct,
even when tired knee comes up,
hip turns over,
body extends full power and those things
are so hard to unlearn once you get like
a bad path.
That's why it's.
I really do think that archery and a lot
of ways is a martial art.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Well you look at the whole Asian culture
and I've said time and time again,
I've coached all over the world and you
know,
that's Kinda what I do now.
I do a lot of coaching that most people
don't even know about with teams that
just would rather have confidentiality
and whether or not they're working with
an outside source,
which is great.
But when I,
the probably the best place I ever
taught was when I went to India because
I actually taught those a Ha.
I was supposed to have 16 archers.
Once I got there,
there was about 140.
I mean,
it was unbelievable the anyone they
thought could be a potential winner for
their team was there and there was so
many kids and you know,
adults that were there and I remember I
took several members of the team that
had a bad habit of punching the trigger
and anticipating the shot,
which is a big negative in our tree and
I gave them a device.
Same one I gave you.
I gave him a release that forces them to
not think about actually aiming the
front side of the boat.
It's a device that makes them focus on
the movement of archery,
pulling through the bowl,
letting the front arm go for the back
arm to come back.
And I remember I gave him string and
that release.
I took all their bones away and locked
him up.
[inaudible].
I said,
until you can do this,
we're not going any further.
So I took those eight and I had them do
that to the side and then I came over
and I started trying to work on all
these other people and there was like
this person needed their boat,
worked on this person needed to watch me
shoot this,
people want to,
you know,
to take pictures or video of me
shooting.
Then we went to lunch.
Then the whole thing started over again.
Then when it came to dinnertime,
I told them,
you guys all go ahead.
I'm going to like,
pack up my gear.
Well,
once the whole big crowd left,
those same eight kids were still over
there with strings pulling on that
release and almost every one of them
were damn near bloody in their hand from
just executing.
And I came over.
I'm like,
oh my goodness.
Have you guys been here the whole day?
Yes sir.
There is like,
there's there that culture.
There's just no wonder to me why.
Like martial arts is such a discipline
because that culture teaches discipline
and hard work within that art better
than anything.
And I think that archery coming out of,
you know,
out of Asia,
I think all the like the Korean team are
so strong because of their disciplines
and I'm sure with the martial arts it's
exact same thing.
They're not afraid to take what the
coach says and just do it until the
coach Says No.
And a lot of people here in any sport
are looking for the shortcut.
People at the gym,
they want the show.
Yeah,
they want to shake that melts fat.
They want to be able to go in and get
the machine that does four minute abs or
whatever.
And the reality is you have to have
commitment and you have to have
discipline in anything in life.
Otherwise if you don't,
you're just going to be another person
bitching about while someone else has
something you don't because you're not
willing to put the effort in for it.
Yeah.
And then on the other hand,
it's not a good idea to cut your hands
with the.
You take some time off.
Kids
get slow,
slow down.
Don't be afraid to raise your hand and
say,
coach,
can we take a break here?
And then I pointed out to a lot of
people that,
um,
you know,
there's a lot of people that don't want
to get involved in anything like archery
that I'm interested in it because they
feel like,
uh,
they don't want to hunt,
they don't want to be a bow hunter.
I've,
I've heard that before.
I'm not interested in that.
And I'm like,
if even if you don't have to be
interested in that,
like that is the furthest end of the
extreme spectrum when it comes to
archery.
You could enjoy archery with just a
yard,
a yard and a target.
I mean,
you can,
you don't need to shoot anything other
than a target to,
to get like,
you know,
yesterday and today we're just shooting
targets and very fun,
super fulfilling.
Like at the end of the day,
you know,
especially because yesterday made a lot
of progress.
At the end of the day I was like,
wow,
you know,
this feels great.
Cleansing.
You've made a dramatic improvement.
I mean,
I'm,
I'm really pumped with how you are,
but what I love about archery is
hopefully you can't hear that they can.
This is Dang good by the way.
When,
when?
When Joe does his commercials,
which actually it's the only thing on
TV.
I don't fast forward through the
commercials because I love how you do
them,
but when he talks about the butter
coffee,
take his advice on it.
It's good.
I've enjoyed it.
Yeah.
Get some good coffee,
good grass fed butter and mct oil.
It was lined it all up.
It was.
Yeah,
it was awesome.
I think what's so cool about archery too
is it's not a sport that is limited by
your age and for that matter,
it's not totally limited by your
physical physique.
Well,
how about that guy that has no arms?
Oh yeah.
Matt,
is that believable and credible?
Yeah.
Matt Stutzman is.
I mean he should be Matt studs.
Minis.
I mean the armless archer,
he's so inspiring.
I mean is kind of.
His nickname is it's inspirational
archer and he's definitely just that for
someone to be able to shoot with their
legs is amazing.
And Actually Matt,
we haven't talked about this,
but matt and another pair archer here
from the u s named Jeff February that
she eats with his mouth.
He was in a motorcycle accident and now
he's a pair of archer.
Yeah,
there's Matt Stutzman right there.
So how does Matt.
He holds the ball with his right foot
and then his left foot's on the ground.
And how does he release the bow?
So.
Well,
he's,
he's actually um,
design jeff favor is next I think two on
to the right.
But so he's developed a release to where
he's actually able to push on it with
his chin and he's a,
he actually activates from back tension.
Now they've designed a release for where
he can hook on and he slowly starts to
continue to move back until it triggers
the string to fire them as he moves
back.
Who's still looking through his peep
site?
Yep.
Yeah,
it's a small movement.
You know how small the movement is.
I mean,
when I talk about that movement,
it's very finite.
It's a matter of an inch or two that I
think that's jeff right there.
Yeah,
there's Jeff Avery.
So yeah,
when I did,
um,
last year when I had to have my
shoulder,
my shoulder redone,
I did not want to miss archery season
and just really took it as a personal
challenge to not put my head down and I
learned to shoot.
It was actually my bow arm was the one I
had worked on,
so I had to learn to shoot with my mouth
using my opposite arm in my,
in my non dominant eye,
which was,
I'm thankful for it.
People always,
you know,
people ask me all the time if I regret
this or if I would do that different and
screw that.
I mean,
you can't.
The past is the past.
I just want to look forward on
everything.
When I,
when I messed up my shoulder,
I was bummed about it,
but in all fairness,
I thought it was a really good challenge
to look at a sport that I love from a
new direction,
to look at the technique involved.
Yep.
You know,
I think,
um,
someone said it,
I forget who it was that one of the best
ways to get good at something is to do
it with your opposite hand
and that not just doing it,
like say if like you,
you're boxing and you're working on
your,
uh,
your straight right hand.
A lot of times when you do your straight
lefthand and actually improves your
straight right hand because in learning
how to do it in an awkward way,
what you're doing is sort of programming
into your mind the critical aspects of
the technique.
How to throw the hips in window to
plant.
And then when you go over to your more
coordinated side,
it's just like super tuned in to the
critical aspects of the movement.
So then when you throw a left hand,
then he switched over to your right
side.
You're like,
damn,
it's just,
it's even better.
It's even faster.
It's even cleaner and I think that that
probably makes sense to the archery as
well.
I've been a lot of people would probably
benefit,
although it's not a traditional thing to
do.
Probably benefit from having both a
lefthanded bow and a right hand and ball
learning how to shoot lefthanded
well,
look at how many skateboarders get
better when they learn to skate goofy,
you know,
if they learn to skate with the opposite
foot back back when I was a skater,
you know,
either skated like straight footer.
He skated Goofy,
but then people didn't really switch
back and forth a lot at that time and
less like the freestyle skaters did back
then.
But then when I got away from skating
and started playing football for awhile
and then archery and then all of a
sudden you know,
the x games happen and you start seeing
guys like Tony Hawk or whatever.
You realize that the whole skating world
just completely went to like with the
freestyle skaters were and just being
able to switch either way and still
perform the exact same tricks.
And I think any athlete that's
listening,
and you know what's funny is sometimes
I've seen you say,
you know,
hey,
I'm talking about hunting today,
but some of your listeners might get
pissed,
but whatever,
because some people just want UFC or
some people don't like to hear the kid.
Never worry about that.
Yeah.
But what's super important is that
people need to take some of these
elements and apply them to their life.
And what I really believe is when I get
better as an athlete is when I recognize
whatever my biggest weakness is,
and that's what I focus on making my
strength.
I call it selective cycling.
I work on this with a lot of my
students.
I'll literally take the one thing that
they do the worst and that's all I want
them to do for almost a month because a
lot of psychology has shown that if you
have a negative habit,
it normally takes about 21 days to
recreate a positive habit,
right?
So you have to be able to take your
weakness and mentally be tough enough as
an athlete to be willing to make that
your strength.
And I've had several things in my career
that were my weakness that are now my
strongest aspect.
Field archery was my biggest weakness.
Now,
my biggest strength is the difference
between feel archery.
Well,
it's not on flat ground,
you know,
once you start changing angles and once
you start having to make shots and
canyons you have to learn.
When do you have to learn trajectory.
So field archery is,
you have like a course that you have to
run and it's all outdoors in the woods.
Yup.
It would be outdoors.
It would be,
you know,
the really difficult field courses are
like throughout like cliffs and
mountainous areas to where,
you know,
you have shots where they're straight up
way over your shoulder where you're
aiming non,
you know,
50 degree angles and then you're aiming
down or somewhere.
I've even had to aim straight down
between my legs.
Um,
those types of things are extremely
technical.
You know,
if you had golfers that had to play in
really difficult terrain,
obviously they have to start learning
draws and fades and they have to start
learning clubs that play differently in
the wind.
It would,
it would be the same thing it pointed
out,
just like when we shoot at longer
distances,
like I mean you were,
you were shooting amazing at eight
period,
80 yards on your rubber,
dear you rubber l key call it,
he's laughing the rubber.
It's,
but um,
you are shooting amazing and then you
would have one shot where something
wasn't right,
but it would show up.
And that's what field archery did to me.
It really started to open up my
weaknesses.
And for me as an athlete,
I'm always so competitive that I want to
know what I suck at because I think if
you're really going to master something,
regardless of the craft,
you have to be so well rounded.
And I mean the UFC is that way.
Even as a spectator.
I'm not a,
I'm not like a fight specialist by any
means,
but I,
I've always loved watching the UFC and
it's funny how the people who won the
early ufc vs how rounded you have to be
now to when you can't afford to have a
weakness.
So ignoring it isn't doing you any
favors.
Yeah,
it's a different world now,
completely different world and he also,
much like we were talking about before
in the UFC,
you have to be able to pretty much
execute from both sides.
It's very rare that someone only has
like a good right kick,
you know,
you have to learn how to kick with the
left side too.
But in Jujitsu that,
that exists as well.
Like there's a lot of guys that have a
strong side,
like the only,
like the past to the left or they don't
want it to pass through the ride.
They only submit guys off the right arm.
It's like it's real common to have a
side where you're really good at it.
What really,
uh,
one thing you said that the other day
when we were sitting there talking and
you were talking about setting up moves
for Jujitsu and how evolving it is,
how it continually evolves and all of a
sudden a new move we'll get invented and
you'll be practicing that.
And then someone just notices like,
wait,
there's a big weakness right there,
do this.
And we've kind of eliminated someone
getting
that moved done on you and then it's
like,
holy crap.
Well,
so how do we,
how do we actually combat that?
Right.
It's just a continual chess game.
Yeah.
It really is.
And the body can move and so many
different ways.
It's one of the more interesting aspects
of Jujitsu's.
There's so many different ways the body
can move.
So when two people are engaged in each
other,
where there's the possibilities of
attacks and counterattacks are near
infinite.
It's a,
it's,
it's a spectacular example of like an
extreme discipline and was something
that becomes just for a lot of people,
becomes a massive,
massive obsession.
You see the Anthony Bourdain thing that
he wanted to do through tournament.
Anthony Bourdain starts Jujitsu at 58
years old.
Okay.
He,
uh,
was,
I think he had quit smoking,
wasn't smoking anymore because he
stopped smoking when his daughter was
born,
I think.
But still,
it still was hitting the booze,
you know,
still wasn't eating healthy.
He was on statens for his blood pressure
or cholesterol,
I guess he just,
you know,
just wasn't healthy.
Yeah.
Gets into Jujitsu because of his wife.
His wife is a maniac.
She loves Jujitsu,
gets into it,
and now he's obsessed.
Trains every day,
often twice a day.
And he just wanted you to,
to tournament as a blue belt at.
What is it?
Fifty nine or something like that.
Fucking incredible.
Fifty nine year old Anthony Bourdain
took home the goal that is first Jujitsu
tournament.
I mean,
get the fuck Outta here.
That's awesome.
As someone who loves Jujitsu,
I'm just blown away.
I'm blown away.
I just love seeing a guy like him who is
a madman man.
So many different things.
And also a guy who was an artist and he,
his art being culinary,
being a chef.
I learned from watching his show that
that's an art form.
I didn't really consider it before I
watched.
Um,
no reservations is old show.
I watched him interact with all these
cooks and the like,
a light bulb went off.
I'm like,
oh,
cooking is art.
I never thought of it that way.
I thought it was like,
oh,
that guy now has a cook.
This guy makes some good this and that
guy cooked some good that,
but I didn't think of it in the same
way.
I look at like a maybe a guy who was an
amazing sculptor.
I didn't think about it that way and
then I realized that when I watched a
show it was like,
yeah,
really?
I never did.
I was just thought,
oh,
this guy's a good kick,
you know,
this guy knows how to make sausages or
this guy's really good at Lasagna or
something,
you know,
it didn't,
didn't,
didn't seem like an art.
So seeing him,
a guy who highlighted that there is an
art and cooking food.
Then become obsessed with this art of
Jujitsu,
which I think in a lot of ways,
like we were saying about archery
archery,
there's parallels.
I mean,
people think of Kendo,
which is a Japanese sword fighting art
that's unquestionably a martial art,
but then so is our strike archery and we
have.
Kendall is a martial art,
so his archery 100 percent because
archery involves a weapon involved,
but it's so much more than that man.
So much more than that.
At some weird,
crazy moving meditation that I feel like
when it goes well,
like yesterday when we shot really well
and we shot like tight groups at 80
yards.
Well after it's over.
Like physically,
you feel better.
You feel like charged up,
you feel elevated,
you feel better than if you did nothing.
Like there's like if you could take a
drug that makes you feel the way you
feel when you hit a perfect acts at 80
yards like that,
like you'd take that drug all day.
Oh yeah.
That was a cigarette.
Yeah,
and high on both side.
I've been pounded,
pounded that crap all lit up right now.
My Skin's Tingley.
Yeah.
It's very strange.
I guess discipline,
a martial art discipline,
but I think almost labeling these things
in any other way than just calling them
what they mean.
That is just.
It is archery.
You know when you put them in
categories,
when you categorize things as this is a
sport or this is a hobby or this is a.
It almost trivializes the benefits,
the positive benefits of it.
It's funny that you say that because now
I know I could never pull you away
because I love as an athlete to step
away with perfection and you would shoot
a group that was like perfect and I knew
that we were close to being done for the
day and I'd be like,
all right,
let's end on that.
And you're like,
no way dude,
I'm doing another one.
But then.
But then if you make one negative shot
in that group,
you were pissed again.
Which I can understand too because I'm
so competitive that way.
But I also love that feeling that you're
talking about.
It's awesome sometimes to have that and
it's important and that's what I was
trying to like work with you on is it
doesn't get better than what you just
did.
You're on a high.
Let's,
I want you to like step away thinking
about your trip all night.
So tomorrow,
you know,
you visualize it long enough.
I'm the way I think is tomorrow you're
more likely to be able to duplicate.
I don't like to go.
I don't ever like to go to bed on a
negative.
Right.
So that's actually what I was trying to
do,
but you know,
we're not good enough friends where I
can be like,
listen,
give me your.
Well,
I don't know.
I guess I did take some stuff away from
probably some of the releases that I was
using.
He won't let me use in house.
Well,
this is very geeky stuff.
So for people that are listening to
this,
they didn't understand,
but because there's so many different
aspects of archery,
there's where you're standing,
what your posture is,
how you're,
how you're focusing,
what you're looking
at,
what are your concentrating on.
Because of that,
there is.
There's a tendency to anticipate the
shot and it becomes sort of overwhelming
because you're managing all these
different things.
So what a lot of people try to
concentrate now in the world of archery
is getting what you call it,
a surprise shot.
Meaning that this is just for the people
at home,
obviously not for you,
meaning that when you pull back,
the thing that you concentrating on is
just focusing on the target.
All of your technique as far as keeping
the bulb balanced and level and keeping
it onto all that stuff is something
you've already worked on.
All you're working on now is pulling
through the shot so you don't think
about executing the shot like ready go,
and when you think of that ready go that
pressing that button,
you have a tendency or possibility of
punching it,
of hitting it wrong,
of tweaking and twisting,
and we talked about that today because
it's in a lot of ways,
it's like a fight.
You know that when a fighter trains for
a fight,
you're training for something that is
going to be a moment that's like months
away from now.
So all of this work and effort then
comes to fruition in this one moment.
Fighter number one,
are you ready?
Fire number two.
Oh,
you're ready.
Fight.
Holy Shit.
Here it is.
It's happening,
but at least in a fight you're,
you know,
you've got a few rounds.
You can kind of settle in after the
first minute or so.
You can relax and get into the groove of
everything in archery.
Oftentimes that all that training and
preparation,
whether it's for a tournament or even
more critically,
if you're hunting,
it comes down to that one moment in that
moment sometimes can be completely
overwhelming because that moment,
although your practice has been constant
and diligent,
that moment is entirely alien.
This moment didn't exist during any of
the practice.
There was never the elevated heart rate.
There's never the freakout.
There's never the massive consequences
if you make an error,
everything has to be in place,
and those,
those things are what make a discipline
so rewarding.
When you actually pull it off.
All of those things like knowing that
there's so many different factors
involved and then this alien moment,
so those factors involve all the
discipline factors.
You have to drill them into a point
where they become a part of you.
They become like ingrained in your
genetics.
They become a part of your DNA so that
in that one insane heart pounding
moment,
you can execute it flawlessly and the
best way to do it,
which I'm learning from you,
is by figuring out how to do it with a
surprise shot.
So that way you take out that the
anticipation aspect of it.
Yeah,
it's less you think about it,
the more likely it is for things to
happen,
you know you have to be so focused on
the process that the prize happens
without your expectation.
The really interesting part about what
I've learned as a competitive archer is
it's the fastest buzz kill of any sport
I've ever had,
and what I mean by that is there's times
where you're standing on the line,
you realize,
okay,
archer number one,
one Arrow,
archer,
number two,
one Arrow closest to center decides the
gold medal match.
You literally let go and you're,
you know,
you're sitting there,
you know shit and pickles.
Your heart rate's beaten out,
your neck.
You know you're trying not to.
I actually had this,
I've had this feeling go both ways,
but you let that Arrow go and you,
you have so much adrenaline that you can
barely manage it and then you're,
you shoot and you see the shadow of that
Arrow hit out like out of the gold to
where you know you lost and it's
instantly gone.
You have,
you're not nervous,
you're sweating or shaking.
You just knew you blew it and it's like
wiped so fast.
It's really,
really strange that the release of one
product of an art form can just,
you instantly know that you screwed up
and you know,
and I've been that way as a hunter too,
where you get nervous and all of a
sudden that shot happens and then you
almost can't.
You know,
for some people they make the shot and
then they get like that.
But sometimes you make that shot and
it's amazing how fast it's just gone and
it's such a rewarding thing when you can
take that ball of just emotion and just
say,
I got this and you fricking clamped down
on it and then you see that Arrow going
to the gold and it's just like,
it's such a reward.
Like for me,
that's what I think for you and your
mentality,
me and mine,
you get so much reward for that.
That for me,
I never really worried about it.
I never worried about a trophy or metal
or for that matter than checks never
really mattered either when I was
younger I needed them.
But you know,
I've just came to the realization that,
you know,
every trophy I have at home is
tarnished.
You know,
they need cleaning,
you know,
they just wilt away.
But what imprints I have in my mind of
moments like that's what pulls me
through as a person and it's positive or
that I can reflect on,
you know,
I know that what's satisfying to me and
I feel so content with life is these
small little goals and accomplishments
that I've had where I've controlled
myself,
not the situation.
I was in a gold medal match in Poland
and
they had the,
the gold medal match in this square,
like in the square of the main town.
You're shooting from the,
from the beach into the main square of
the town.
And our match was first and I was the
first archer.
So I stepped up.
We were in a team round and there was so
many people.
I raised my bow,
I pulled back,
I was going into my shot.
And as I'm looking through my scope at
the target,
about four people's heads come,
like looking in like this because there
are people lined all the way down and
this is 70 meters.
So everyone's evidently was shuffling to
try to get to see the archer.
Not Realizing in like,
okay,
there's an arrow going over your head.
So I'm going from like mentally having a
sight picture that I'm not nervous about
to all of a sudden thinking if I shoot
someone in the face,
I don't want to spend the rest of my
life.
And uh,
Poland,
Polish prison and I remember like
someone like keep cleaning the line,
getting the people to back.
No,
it was just like they did.
I don't think they really thought that
people were going to come in.
And I remember I drew back and I was so,
I mean you've seen me shoot in my
element.
It's very smooth.
So then all of a sudden there was like,
my front arm was like,
you know,
I got into that tremor mode.
Like,
you know what you have when you,
when the anxiety sets in.
And I remember I shot and they're like,
you know,
they called 10 and I came off the line
and my other teammate that was with me,
he goes,
what the hell,
dude?
Why are you shaking so bad?
If he's like,
what the hell,
dude,
you almost miss what's up with you,
like as we're passing one another and I
go,
you'll see a fricken pulls back and he
goes,
what the f?
So that next round my gift,
freaking people out of the way,
like I had people's faces in my scope.
That's a youtube video waiting to
happen.
Somebody catching one of the temple
leaning into the path.
That's just so ridiculous.
Don't want one to 10 if anybody doesn't
it,
if you don't know,
like when you're looking through a site
of a,
um,
uh,
on archer and oboe,
archery sites have very small.
So you're looking at a very narrow
window.
So for these people to actually be in
your site,
they had to be extremely close to the
path of the era.
It's a one.
Well,
the Arrow was arguing over there melon,
but
because they were between me and the
target.
So crazy though.
It was very crazy.
Um,
yeah.
I was like,
what is this?
Did what I did at the pool today?
Throwing
safety of that.
Yeah,
it's easy when you're concentrating all
the other things you.
It weirds me out.
I've been at.
I've been at places where I'm practicing
and you're like shooting and someone
else's at this club and you like go down
to pull your Arrow and then all of a
sudden you're like sitting there like
pulling the arrows and it's like.
And you're like,
Yo,
what's up?
Oh God.
Oh,
I'm just saying.
I mean even at that other targets like,
okay,
well yeah,
you know,
how many Joe Rogan pool shots I've seen
I might
want to be on the receiving end of that
certainly can happen.
You know,
what you've got set up is,
is really cool.
That giant long range at your house.
So you could practice like in your yard
like that.
Like there's a video that you put up.
John set up my bow.
I got this bowl from hoyt.
John set it up perfect.
And he took these crazy shots and one of
them we took was 122 yards.
And um,
to,
to be able to do that and to have like
this big open space like that.
In your yard,
it's got to be fucking awesome.
It's weak.
Cool.
Yeah.
Actually,
um,
when we bought my house,
my wife Sharon,
she knew that we wanted to move out to a
farm because we're.
When I.
Before I moved to Iowa
so that could get more deer tags.
You laugh about that.
That's hilarious.
Fuck moves to a state so they can get
more deer tags.
You can get an extra dear.
Doesn't
guarantee you right now.
Campaigns could get to elk tags.
If he crossed the state line,
I'll guarantee it.
He would do it.
He loves Oregon.
He travels a lot.
Anyway.
He might see I get three buck tags.
Actually three different situation
though,
like a white tail hunting and I was just
so different.
And plus it's,
is for folks who aren't aware if it's
like a tradition,
it's a,
it's an American thing,
like a white tail.
Hunting is probably the biggest hunting
pastime in America.
More people hunt white tails.
More people spend more time hunting,
white tails than anything.
And it's also like probably some of the
best meat you're ever going to eat in
your life.
Oh yeah.
I've been crushing mind.
I'm making.
Yeah,
I love.
That's why I was so surprised when you
said you don't,
you didn't see like cooking as an art.
I actually went,
when I go someplace nice,
I'm,
I take pictures of my food because to me
I see it that way.
And actually I cook some backstraps the
other night and you know,
I cook some backstrap so like,
you know,
Cook some vegetables and like a coconut
oil or something and then,
you know,
I like slice through that tenderloin and
like kind of folded them all down and
then like stacked my little half strap
up and Kinda lean them against there.
And I was just like looking at it like
why would people not want to do this?
Like why would people not want to be
able to do this for themselves to make a
nice meal and make a nice meal.
And obviously it's something that
is a reward of hard work,
work
and dedication that I've put in through
the year.
You know,
my saying,
one saying that I made on my TV during
the first few seasons is I'm,
I'm in target archery to become a better
hunter and I'm a better hunter because
I'm a target archer.
I got into professional archery 100
percent because I wanted to be more
proficient and ethical knowing that I
was a bow hunter and I kind of had the.
I was actually the same type of feeling.
I was,
I was only 10 but it or I mean when I
started competing I started hunting when
I was 10,
so there was like six or seven years
there where I wasn't competing.
But I remember having one hunt where I
felt so much anxiety and I like blue is
shot and I just completely missed and I
couldn't explain why.
And it was at that moment that I'm like,
you know what,
if I'm going to do this,
I need to be able to be ethical at it.
So at that point I was kind of looking
for a way to become better.
And I was actually,
it was right before I was supposed to
leave for my first football camps or
college,
I was driving down a road and there was
a sign on the road that said,
um,
three d archery shoots and it was just
an Arrow pointing down and I pulled in,
I had like my hunting bow in the back of
my truck,
you know,
kind of drive in and I see all these
people like shooting on this practice
range.
And then I see like groups of four going
into this course to like shoot and it
was all foam animal targets with scoring
rings on them.
And you step up to the line,
you look at the target,
you try to figure out how far it is
without having a range finder.
And then you make a shot.
And depending on,
you know,
all the scoring is within the ethical
kill zone of the animal.
So after I think,
I think it was 15 targets,
it was a 40 target course after 15
targets.
I didn't have a single Arrow left in my
quiver.
I had lost all of them and it was like a
wake up call.
It was the first time that I had ever
felt defeated at something.
It was the first time that I had a very
clear wakeup call of maybe you're not
good enough to be doing this,
you know,
and for me that was a trigger as a
competitor.
I think the standout athletes in any
sport are the ones that take those
moments very personal and change the
direction to make it their best or
either realized I'm either going to be
good at this or I need to find something
else to be good at,
you know,
to focus all your energy to.
And one thing led to another.
I went to an archery shop were I saw a
lot of guys with shirts on that said
like the name of a shop.
So I knew they were like kind of local
shooters representing this store.
So the next day I was in that store and
I said,
hey,
I want to get better.
I know a lot of guys here,
we're shooting and a lot of those guys
were in the range and I just started
asking questions.
A lot of people didn't want to help,
which is why I really want to help the
archery world.
It's my way of giving back because there
were people that didn't want to help me,
but then I remember the guy came in and
said,
are my arrows done?
And the guy behind the counter said,
let me check in the back,
and he kind of walked past me and he
goes,
come here kid.
And uh,
because I had hung out in that store for
about four days,
just kind of watching and looking
around.
I didn't really have any importance.
So he takes me in the back room and he
says,
you got to build these guys arrows for
me because I forgot to do them.
And I said,
I don't know how to build arrows.
And he goes,
okay,
you take this feather,
you put it in this clamp,
put glue right down this feather,
like this.
Put the Arrow in this Jig.
You push down on it.
Then you turn the wheel,
go to the next Arrow after you get to
the end,
take the clamp off,
put another feather in,
you know,
and he literally gave me the thing.
So I was in there like trying to figure
out how to do this.
Even work there.
No,
I was there like,
like literally stalking people in the
range.
I was like the weird guy in the corner
with like the hunting bow that was
probably my dad's hand me down.
I'm like stocking all the shooters and
about an hour later I came out with,
you know,
this guy's arrows that he probably paid
100 bucks for and some like snot nosed
kid that had never even built them,
built them for the guy.
And so he goes,
all right,
good job.
And he goes here,
now go do these.
And two weeks later I remember telling
my dad,
Hey,
I think I'm gonna.
Um,
I'm not going to do that.
The football thing.
And he's like,
what do you mean?
I said,
I got offered a job at this archery
shop.
I'm going to do it.
And my dad's like,
so you're not going to play college
football and get a get a,
um,
an education,
you're going to work at an archery shop.
And he goes,
what's this archery shop pay?
And I said,
for 10 an hour.
Yeah,
that was my dad's been so good.
My both my parents have been so
supportive on everything in life.
But that was the one time where he
looked me in the face and just said,
this is a really stupid decision.
But Hey,
I mean,
you know,
it's,
I just think it's a great story because
it shows that if someone's willing to
commit to a dream,
then as long as you're able to put in
the work and stay focused on it,
there's so many people that make
businesses out of dreams are,
you know,
careers out of sports that you would
never even consider.
We'll just think of that story.
Now you're traveling all over the world
coaching international teams and
archery.
I mean,
it's a crazy story.
It really stop.
Think about it.
It's really weird.
You know,
I have some very.
I have some friends that are very
successful according to the business
world and there's times where I'm with
those people and then they're
introducing me to like a senator or
governor,
and then they're like,
well,
John,
you know,
it's like,
Hey,
this is my personal friend John and I'm
with the president of the university or
something.
And they're like,
so John,
what do you do?
And it's one of these,
you want to be able to say,
Oh,
I have an mba or you know,
yeah,
do,
um,
rocket science stuff,
but it's like a,
I'm an archer.
Yeah.
I shoot a bow for living and they're
just like,
really?
I'm a slingshot master.
Yeah,
exactly.
But then you start,
you start explaining what you're
actually doing and you realize this is
a,
it's a really big world and it's,
there's such great people there,
you know,
I have,
I literally.
It's really nice to be able to say I
don't have any regrets in life because
I'm in an industry that I love.
I'm doing something that I really,
really love and they're such good people
around it.
And all you have to do is get up every
morning when the alarm goes off.
Mine goes off pretty early and then just
put in the work and,
you know,
I just think it's so cool to know that
there's opportunity like that and
there's a different path,
a path that maybe perhaps other people
hadn't considered.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
And just,
you know,
it's such a great country to live in to
here in the states because you can take
something that no one really might not
believe in yourself.
And if you apply the work to it,
you can make it happen.
And in traveling through all the
different parts of the world that I've
traveled,
I've gone to places where you just,
you know,
you really wish you could give some of
those people a chance because you can
tell that they have such heart and such
desire,
but they don't have opportunity.
And that's sad to me.
That's,
that's really sad that there's not
opportunity everywhere.
And then you come here and you see
someone that has potential or
opportunity,
but they're lazy and they won't put in
the work.
They don't have the desperation,
they don't have the desire,
they don't have the drive,
they don't.
They don't.
You know?
I think a lot of times for some people
when they're young,
it's not enforced early on that when you
work hard at something,
it's really rewarding.
When it's over and it's difficult to
work hard at something,
it's difficult to get your ass out of
bed.
It's difficult to force yourself to get
up off the couch.
It's difficult,
but once you do it,
it's always good.
It always feels good and even if you do
something and it doesn't work out well,
like even if you are practicing archery
in the shots,
don't go well.
It's silly.
You're involved
in the discipline has given you
something to concentrate on and that'll
translate that energy and momentum will
translate to the rest of your life.
If you're working to improve at
something,
whether it's archery or Jujitsu or
anything when you working to improve,
improve on it.
I firmly believe that that motivation
and that momentum of improvement applies
to the rest of your life and it's one of
the things that people love about any
particular discipline is the,
the aspects of it and the qualities of
it that sort of transfer onto your
everyday life.
You know,
it's weird because until you and I
communicated some on the phone when I
worked for an archery company and I was
just a sales guy making calls.
I never got to see faces.
All ever heard was voices.
So voices for me are always triggers
because for 10 years I was just making
calls when you and I first talked on the
phone and I like heard your voice
directly.
Like from my device I actually realized
I haven't even told you this,
but I when I work out or when I shoot
and a lot of times when I'm just working
in my building,
I've comprised like about five hours of
a MP3.
That's nothing but motivational sayings
that I've heard someone say whether it's
and I,
that's all I play.
It's my ambient sound and you are on
there twice about just almost like what
you just talked about,
just a positive.
It was just a positive rant that you had
about all people have to do is make a
step in a direction and you might,
you might look in the mirror one time
and you don't like what's there,
but you know,
you have the opportunity to turn around
and go a different way.
And one thing that I really try to drive
to people because there's times you talk
to someone and you know that they're
down in the dumps.
You know,
any one thing I tell people is,
you know,
motivation gets you going.
Commitment keeps you going.
You know,
it's,
it's no different than the new year's
resolution.
I fricking hate that.
I hate if there's any time a,
I don't want to go to the gym.
It's two weeks after New Year's because
it's like this swarm of people and all
to me,
there's people in there were like,
you know what?
Good for them.
You know,
they're,
they're not in shape.
Good for them to come here.
But then it's so disappointing when it's
like two days and they're gone.
Yup.
And you know,
if you're,
if you're at that stage and you're at
the point where you're like,
you know what,
I want to change myself physically.
It's funny how many
people won't even.
It's funny how many people are going to
the gym to work out,
but they'll circle the gym parking lot
like 10 times because they want the
first row to open up.
Your work is far away from the front
door as you can and warm up by walking.
You skip,
skip to the loo.
Well,
I think a lot of people need a life
coach.
I think this is what I'm the conclusion.
One of the things that I'm coming to in
life is that,
um,
people need to either find a way to
motivate themselves through all the
different stuff that's available online.
I mean,
there's a million different websites and
instagram pages and lots of youtube
videos that show some motivation and
they can help you.
But we,
human beings learn from each other.
And I think most of the cultures in the
past,
not trying to glorify the past and say
they had it nailed and we don't,
but most of them were entitled knit
groups and the emulated the behavior and
the patterns of the successful members
of that group.
The leaders of that tribe.
That's where traditions and came from.
That's where skills were passed on and
that's where ethics and that's where
certain philosophies were passed down
from generation to generation.
These were the most beneficial to the
community as a whole to the individual,
to the culture,
whatever the whatever it is.
This world that we're living in today,
we're almost in a lot of ways,
like you were saying,
people with so much opportunity but to
lazy.
We're almost in a lot of ways just
lacking in a pattern,
a correct pattern and a coach or a
mentor or a person who is ahead of you,
but honest like ahead of you as far as
like maybe been alive longer or maybe
had more experiences,
but very honest about the difference
between you and them.
Because a lot of people think that you,
you see some.
Like we're talking about today,
this is a ridiculous analogy,
but when I was on MTV,
we're talking about downtown Julie Brown
because I was singing on the line and I
remember thinking while you were saying
that,
like you,
you go downtown,
Julie Brown was probably on MTV back
when you were unhappy.
And I was like,
yeah,
but I was a peon.
Like she wouldn't know who I was.
I was on one of,
you know,
x amount of Comedians on the MTV half
hour comedy hour.
Like I couldn't probably couldn't even
talk to her,
say hi to her.
And then I remember thinking like I put
myself in that state of mind that I had
back when I was 23 or whatever I was
when I was on that show and I felt like
insignificant and like,
well that's downtown Julie Brown.
And then I realized like now that that's
nonsense.
Like now I know that's nonsense,
but in my head thinking about that time
I felt like I did when I was 23.
That like,
yeah,
that was your first reply.
You're like,
yeah,
but I was just a p on that.
And then all of a sudden,
I think once you thought about first few
seconds you're like,
you know what,
f that,
well it's so ridiculous.
But I did think that way back then.
I think a lot of other people think that
way now.
You know,
and whether it's a someone who's an
aspiring archer that looks at your
accomplishments and then looks at you
back when you were this stalker kid
hanging around a bowshot yeah.
In comparison to how they are.
And I think that that's a big,
that's a big help to people to hear a
story like that and to know that now you
travel all over the world and you coach
international teams and to see someone
it admit that I think is very important
to see someone discussed that I think is
very important to a lot of us because we
don't really.
Most people don't have fucking mentors
and most people aren't even involved in
like a discipline that tests them in
that manner.
We're involved.
A lot of people are involved in
education,
right?
You go through high school,
you go to college,
get a degree,
you're studying,
you're practicing.
But how much of that what you're doing
has the aspects of the obsession with a
discipline like archery or like Jujitsu
or something along those lines.
You're not getting the same intensity
and focus.
You're reluctant to do the work.
You're doing it because you have to
because you got to get a degree because
you got to get a job because you don't
want to be a loser and so you're
pursuing these things with a lack of
passion and then you enter into the
workforce.
Hopefully you're doing what you love.
Most of the time people are not.
Most of the time people are doing what
they think is a good job that they can
get by with and so they're committed to
this path of not being excited,
not being obsessed,
and then not challenging themselves and
not rising above and not gathering up
some of the possible lessons that you
can and it could be anything.
It could be anything.
If you want to make knives,
if you love making jackets,
if you like painting,
it doesn't.
There's no one particular thing that it
should be for you.
You just have to find out whatever
starts that spark in you.
For you.
It was archery.
For me,
it was standup comedy,
you know,
or martial arts,
it could be,
it could really be anything,
but I think we need things like that.
If people don't have things like that,
if they just work and then they go home
and they watch TV and they work and they
go home and watch tv,
you're not,
you're not fucking living life at level
10,
you're not going to hit it.
You're never gonna feel that.
And I'm not saying you're gonna be at
level 10 every day,
but there's going to be some moments
like when you were talking about,
you know,
being on the line,
wha to archers,
this is the for one shot,
for the gold medal and alert that,
that feeling,
those,
those feelings are integral to being a
human being.
The feelings of being challenged and of
learning what you're capable of and what
you're not capable of through
those challenges.
Absolutely.
And the thing is too,
you have to be able,
when you've made that decision,
the next thing that you should come to
terms with is say,
you know what?
I'm going to push myself further and
I've ever pushed myself and I know damn
good and well there's going to be a
block.
There's gonna be resistance.
I heard in a podcast for me long ago,
you talked about the book,
the war of art.
I bought it,
Steven Pressfield.
I bought it.
So you know,
it talks about resistance and actually
you know,
with you learning this new release for
your archery,
I told you before you even made your
first shot,
there is going to be a point where
you're not going to like this and you
need to know right now that we're going
to push through it.
So a lot of times when people make that
determination and that decision in life,
have,
you know what?
I'm going to go to the gym.
I'm going to get ready.
You need to also think you know what?
There's going to be.
I'm going to have a voice in my head
that's going to tell me this is too hard
and I'm going to have a point of
resistance,
but I'm telling myself right now when I
get that,
that's my opportunity to go further than
I've ever had in the past.
I know right now that when I get to that
I am pushing through it.
If you're only focused on one particular
goal and not seeing the obvious
distractions or things that are going
to,
that you know are going to be in that
path and mentally build,
build up yourself to know when I get to
that resistance,
I am driving through.
You know,
I listen to that podcast with Steve
[inaudible] and he talked about.
He knew he was ready to beat his habits
and when he was in there and they're
like telling him that he should be
going.
He's like,
no,
I want.
Like,
he probably knew deep down inside that
if he left,
he was.
That was,
it was gonna be an opportunity for him
to fail.
So he had already made up his mind that
he was going through that.
And so many people in life just don't
push that one time and then they never
really see how far they can go.
You know,
I heard like,
um,
one time I heard Les Brown say,
you know,
would you rather go through life?
I'm aiming too high and miss or aiming
too low and hit.
I mean,
I would rather aim high and fall short
and still be further ahead then aiming
too low and hitting exactly a low goal.
You know,
I think you have to be willing to fail
and get good at it.
I lost way more tournaments than I've
ever won.
And some of the people that like
question why I'm at where I'm at in
archery that are,
well,
we never won that much.
You know what?
I'm probably lost more than anybody.
That's good.
But I dang sure know that it made me a
better person.
And then when I lost,
I was at the tournament the next week
making sure that I worked on whatever it
was that caused me to lose.
You know,
I think I remember a guy one time
saying,
you know,
you haven't really figured out how to
win yet,
but,
and that's critical for an athlete.
Well,
it's critical that that moment that
happens in any competition where you're
worried about the event,
you're worried about the outcome and
that worry can overwhelm your abilities.
Yup.
Yeah,
absolutely.
And when you get to that point,
you have to be willing to dig deep down
and say,
you know what?
This is what I've worked for.
I knew this was coming.
You know,
if it,
if there wasn't nervousness and the
possibility of defeat or victory,
then there probably wouldn't be any
sense of inner accomplishment to it.
You've literally done everything you can
to get to that moment.
That's a defining moment.
So which way are you going to go,
you know?
Then you have a decision to make.
And for me,
my victories were so much sweeter
because I had failed a lot before that
and it got to the point where I remember
being in a match one time and I had
taken like several second thirds leading
up to that and I remember getting there
and I just,
I closed my eyes on that last Arrow and
I just am like,
I'm freaking sick.
Have blown it,
screw that.
I'm not doing it again.
I'm going to make a good shot.
Visual rocky movie.
Yeah.
And then.
So I just closed my eyes
and made
the shot.
And then when I made it,
the victory seems so much sweeter
because I had pushed through adversity
to get there.
You know?
I think that's,
that's what I love about archery is
that,
you know,
one day you're so good and then the next
day you know,
you see flaws and you see mistake.
What's a long rabbit hole too?
That's the weirdest thing about archery.
You wouldn't think it's such a long
rabbit hole.
There's so much to learn.
So many different places to go.
And there's so many people that your
watch,
you watch TV.
I've,
I've taken to,
I watch hunting shows much to the
Chagrin of my family.
I think it's Hilarious,
but some of them are so bad.
They're so,
they're such bad production.
Like if you want to learn bad
television,
like say if you're a person out there
that's aspiring to do a TV show,
there's some,
there's some hunting shows out there
that look like they were made by blind
people that were drunk and the animals,
like they,
they,
especially the archery shows they
fucking miss more than they hit them.
I mean if someone from like if wanted to
make an argument against the ethical use
of archery for hunting,
all they need to do and where to go
watch some of those fucking shows.
But it's this.
I think it's,
you know,
it's a difficult thing to do and some
people kind of half asset and some of
those people that do have acid,
they're on television.
Well,
and that brings up a really good point
because I know a lot of people that
probably are listening that you either
know myself or know that you're a
hunting advocate and a conservationist
like myself.
We owe it to ourselves as an art,
you know,
as a hunting community to realize that
there's a big opposition pushing back
and we have a responsibility to
represent ourselves ethically and also
appreciate other people's feelings and
you know,
appreciate that there are people that
might not like it and you really have an
opportunity to either do something
that's going to really piss them off.
Or if you're going to maybe do something
to where it'll at least let them keep an
open mind.
Now.
Well,
the best way to do that I think is have
conversations about it.
Oh yeah.
I mean,
I can't tell you how many facebook
messages and twitter messages I've
gotten from people that have told me
that they had a particular view,
a negative view about hunting and until
they listen to like maybe a podcast with
Steve Rinella or Cameron Hanes or Jim
shockey,
and they realize like,
oh,
this is not what I think it is.
Not only is it not what I think it is,
you must do something to control these
animal populations.
And the one thing,
I've said this before,
but I'm gonna.
Say it again to anybody that thinks
there's no reason to ever kill wild
animals.
I have two words for you.
Feral pigs.
You can't.
You better do something because if you
don't do something,
they will fucking overwhelmed the earth.
What about people?
Man?
People are overwhelming.
Earth team that.
Yeah,
I like people.
You can have sex with them,
you can talk to them and you go to the
movies with them.
They make cars.
I'm a big fan of Pete,
except people that make parking lots.
They're making some narrow parking.
Listen.
Oh,
foreign.
Okay.
Somewhere in the.
Somewhere in the last 10 years,
whoever was working for like American
and United Airlines that made economy
plus and then took the big dump on the
regular economy seats for someone
finally fired those people and then they
started designing parking lots because
fricking you can't park your junk in
anything anymore.
They never have an obvious way to like
get to the Strip mall.
That's right next door.
They make you like exit the Fricken Pac
man exit or like you have to go around
all the ghosts and shit to like finally
get to the one way to get out and then
turn and go down to get into the next
one.
Well they definitely try to shove
too many spots in places like,
uh,
I was somewhere recently.
Oh Santa Barbara where it's real nice,
but there's not that many people.
And one of the things I noticed when I
was there,
it was like,
well how the parking spots are the nice
and wide because they're not overwhelmed
by the same amount of people.
There's only like a 100,000 people in
all of Santa Barbara.
It's like an easier way to get around
down there.
Yeah.
Like that Cam and there's too many.
God.
Damn.
I don't want to remember.
You ready to move Jamie's thumbs up from
Jamie.
What's that?
We're moving to Santa Barbara.
Fuck it.
Let's do that.
Do you need a person to like you need a
full time range manager?
They need to build a range.
That's the next step.
If I get deeper and deeper with this
amount of open up an archery shop.
I think so for sure.
I think,
uh,
an archery school would be the way to
go.
Honestly.
I really think that there were a lot of
different martial arts schools and I've
been involved in a bunch of them and I
think that a teaching martial arts is
gigantic,
but one of the things that's a problem
with archery and most particularly with
bow hunting is the learning curve is
extremely steep and it's not obvious at
all as to where to start.
The learning curve to start archery is
just go to an archery store,
go to a shop.
But I mean,
I've had experience with shops that
didn't know what they were doing and
went there and I got bad advice from
them and I saw people that really didn't
exactly know what they were doing and
they were telling me,
Oh,
you don't need that.
Oh you don't need this.
And there's so many people out there
that probably would be interested in,
in archery.
And I know there's a lot of people that
are interested in hunting as well.
They just don't know where to start.
And I think having like classes in a
liquor shop is probably a really good
idea and probably something I'm going to
get into in the future.
Well I want to see that.
Yeah,
no I wouldn't let them in,
but I would have to a grand open.
Alright man you're in.
But I would have to most certainly have
people that were there that were really
good,
that could teach classes and teach
people how to do it.
You know,
like we were showing you show me the
video of your son hunting alligators.
And I said it right as you were saying.
I was like,
look at his form,
like your kid is like,
it's perfect form like a world champion
archer,
like the ways God has his posture,
the way he released and when you know
we're,
we're watching that.
I was thinking,
well,
here's a kid that has learned from the
beginning how to do it correctly.
So when you look at him as opposed to
that picture that you sent me of the
archer that's on television,
that as a,
uh,
an arrow that he's pulling back his
string is deep,
tucked into his face were for sure.
When you're pulling your string back and
it's digging into your face,
the,
the pressure of your face on that string
is going to change the path of the hour.
You should never supposed to dig it into
your face.
Like this guy has it.
Then you look down,
his Arrow is not even attached to the
string.
It's like hanging off and he doesn't
even know it.
It is the most.
And this guy is on television and that
fucking picture was used for an ad.
The picture was on an ad,
which means they took the picture,
somebody looked at it and they were so
careless that they weren't good enough.
Keep going.
We got it,
nailed it,
and they took that and they put it on
television.
I'm ordered to put it in a magazine or
what have you.
But when you see someone who started
from the beginning,
like your son with perfect form it.
How old was he in?
At like 10.
Yeah,
he started when he was nine.
So in that picture,
what would that video with the alligator
tab,
when you see that as opposed to someone
who's been doing it wrong their whole
life.
You realize the importance of original
technique,
like having it like the original
lessons.
The first lesson is you get imprinting
correctly,
yo.
Yeah.
And that's a big part of what I'm doing.
Can I plug the fuck?
Yeah.
Well your,
your show,
which is called knock on TV.
It's on a sport.
What's not departments channel
sportsmans channel.
And they're both owned by the same
people.
Now the outdoor channel and the
sportsman channel are both owned by the
same people.
And then,
you know,
the youtube site,
knock on archery,
there's a lot of,
if you go through there and if you're
not a hunter,
then move past that because there's a
lot of how to stuff and that's the
direction that I'm really going to be
going.
The whole focus on this brand.
Um,
knock on which I think I had,
I think I have a hat on.
Um,
you know,
it's,
it was a brand intended for people that
aren't really necessarily wanting to say
I'm a hunter,
but I'm an archer and so much of what
this show is geared around and it took a
long time for me to convince the network
for me to dedicate.
You know,
right now I have three segments that
are,
how to be better with your form when the
dead center segment.
Then the field recon segment is how to
be better in the field as an hunter,
you know,
some type of a technique.
And then I have the third segment called
knocked and ready to rock,
which last year was literally how to buy
a bow and completely set up the boat,
start to finish throughout the whole.
And there's a video of that.
Oh,
it's over an hour long.
It's on Youtube,
which is a very difficult time consuming
and involved process.
Yep.
And then this year the knocked and ready
to rock segment is all about learning to
build your own arrows.
But as I move forward through the
seasons and through the,
through the Youtube Channel,
I'm going to continue to try to work on
building all these fundamentals to
become a good shooter.
And Harry and my wife,
they both started out with no experience
at all.
And it's funny how if you show the basic
fundamentals and you're taught right
from the very beginning,
how easy you can get to perfect form.
It's when you go into it with like,
you know,
I always say women and kids are way
easier to teach.
And then guys,
because there's not the macho factor,
you know,
guys are like,
Shit Dude,
I know how to grab care.
Give me that.
I'll show you how to do it.
Also do being a loser.
Yup.
Whereas
people who are not worried about,
man,
if I fuck this up,
damn dude,
I'm a loser in this cause of winter.
Like there's a lot of people that don't
like learning things because they don't
want to fuck
up.
You know,
and I think when you,
you teach a,
a woman or a young person,
they have less ego.
They don't think of themselves as being
this shit yet.
Oh,
well there were women don't just say,
just don't have as many ego problems has
been do in that regard.
Well there's two.
There's two t,
you know,
I've,
I've looked a lot into sports psychology
and I won the first time I talked to
you.
One of the things where I was really
hoping you could help me with and if
anyone's listening out there that's like
a sports psychologist.
I actually,
I have a,
I have a big add problem.
I'm very.
But it also has been a huge part of my
success as an archer because I zone
things out.
There's times where I've been in
competitions,
people come up to me and say,
Hey,
sorry,
I bumped you with the camera or
whatever.
It's like when.
Because I like,
I don't like,
you're so tunnel visioned on stuff.
So you see heads in those tunnels.
Yeah.
The head's kind of was a distraction.
That was my adderall.
But yeah,
I've,
I've really wondered,
you know,
is is a d,
d or You know that.
Is that like an asset to get in the zone
faster?
But yeah,
we talked about that and my,
my issue is what is add,
you know,
I'm not exactly sure that everyone who
has add is really has a disorder,
a lot of that.
Right.
I think a lot of is a style of thinking
or way of thinking.
You know right now,
like my dad's a psychologist and it's
amazing to me how many people will,
you know,
I've got friends that will like go to
the shrink for a 30 minute session.
Then they're like,
oh,
I got some adderall.
Do to get add really bad when I got,
when I got diagnosed with mine,
I went for three different days and
almost did like a psychological
evaluation.
I mean it was like questioning,
questioning,
and I remember like reading through this
thing that,
that uh,
that a true psychologist did to diagnose
what I had.
And I remember one of the lines said it
was like one of the beginning lines.
It's like John has always been a fairly
normal boy.
He never had a problem soiling his
linens or something like that.
It was.
That sounds like someone became a serial
killer.
John has always been a normal boy until
we found the one hand sticking out of
the dirt in the backyard.
We never suspected anything.
That's kind of what it was like.
But,
but it's a d and D is add recognized a
hundred percent.
Like is it a universally recognized?
Like there's an issue with add?
I would say.
So they argue,
they argue that it's the case against
add.
How about that Google that they shot?
They argue that there's more,
there's more people coming,
you know,
that are saying they have add and I
think because doctors are so quick to
prescribe nowadays,
but what does it,
what does it mean?
It means attention deficit disorder.
So what is exactly that mean?
Well,
for me,
sometimes
people are talking to maybe when I'm so
zoned out on something else,
I never hear it.
You know,
there's just constant distraction.
There's constant distraction.
If I'm tuned into you then you know,
a lot of times like,
you know,
I'll be focused on something and my wife
like has to snap at me like a dog see,
but that to me is not attention deficit
disorder.
That's not attention deficit it.
Oh,
that's extreme attention on one thing.
Just an unwillingness to engage with
distractions,
but then there's times what's weird
about it is then there's times where
you're trying to focus on something and
it's like every stimuli comes into play.
One of those things that you're trying
to focus on,
is it ever anything that you're really
interested in or is it just some shit
you have to do,
like fix a pipe or you know,
certainly there's times where people are
talking to you and you really don't want
to listen to them.
That's the.
I have a feeling that's what attention
deficit disorder is.
People are bored as fuck or that is what
every casino.
There's this wide range of the way
people think and the way people address
situations like you couldn't even see it
in your children.
Like have my middle child is very
outgoing and very loud and silly and
she'll talk to anybody but my youngest
child,
she.
If she doesn't know you,
she ain't saying shit.
I know.
Say Hi to her and she was like,
whatever dude,
she'll hide behind me.
I can talk to this guy.
Like she just has her own style of
engaging with people and they both also
have their own very distinct likes and
dislikes.
As far as like the kind of TV shows they
like or the kind of toys they like or
the kind of art that they do and I just
think that that same variety applies to
things that people are interested in and
not interested in in life.
And we take these fucking kids,
man,
and this is a big part of the problem
with education.
There's a lot of different jobs out
there and the path for a guy who wants
to be a professional archer versus the
path for a guy wants to be an audio
engineer.
These are very different paths and they
involve very different amounts of data,
different,
different kinds of data,
different stimuli.
And we take people and especially when
they're young,
we make them pay attention to shit they
don't give a fuck about and I don't
think it's good for them.
And I think we see like when I was in
high school they always said,
oh,
he doesn't pay attention.
He's got no pr.
Put something in front of me that I care
about and that's all I pay attention to.
So it's not that I'm a fucking Ne'er do
well,
but you,
you make me feel like I am made me feel
like I'm a loser because I don't give a
fuck about math or Spanish history.
Sorry,
it's not ringing my 13 year old head.
I'm thinking about tits right now and I
have time for Spanish history.
I don't give a fuck,
but you might talk to me about pirates
and all of a sudden for whatever reason
that spark gets lead and now I'm
interested and now I'm obsessed with
pirates and I want to read books about
pirates and I want to talk about pirates
is sorts of different things that people
get excited about and interested in.
But the problem I think,
or one of the problems with formalized
education and are some for some strange
reason,
our need to diagnose certain styles of
thinking and certain styles of
approaching life as problematic as add
or he's got,
you know,
he's got adhd.
Oh,
he's just,
he can't stop.
He's in a fucking classroom.
They're teaching nonsense.
He's sitting on a plastic chair.
He wants to run through the fucking
wall.
It's everything.
I could do,
I have a neighbor and sometimes it's got
corners me,
okay.
And he'll tell me some stupid shit about
his son's basketball game or some other
shit and I literally want to run up a
tree.
I just want to and I don't have add.
I'm not,
I'm not unwilling Adhd,
I'm fucking bored man.
And you're kidnapping me with this
stupid goddamn conversation.
And I'm like Yay,
look at the time,
got to go.
So I told him,
you know,
if you're going to get some time on that
bench.
And that's how I felt when I was in
school.
I felt a lot of that in school and I
think that that's a lot of what's going
on.
We're all interested in different shit
and formalized education in a lot of
circles and a lot of schools.
It's just too limited for some of the
kids in class.
I remember Harry,
his first football team,
I'm thinking he was like nine or 10 and
one of the kid shows up with like a big
can of monster and he's drinking it in
the.
And we were trying to control the kid
and I went over to mom and I said like,
you know,
and it was every day,
how old is this kid?
He was 10.
All My.
And I remember going over and the mom
said,
the mom goes,
yeah,
we just have such a problem control.
And the thing is it was eight in the
morning for a football game.
And she goes,
we just,
he just never listened.
I mean the doctor says he has add and
I'm like,
you just gave him a green monster at
eight in the morning.
He's 10 and he had like a double can of
monster.
I'm talking the big ones.
How much do you think he weighed?
A hundred pounds.
Cheeses.
That's.
I could be wrong,
but that's more than two adult size
servings could be wrong,
but I think I know the problem.
Yeah.
It might be your kids on crank.
I mean that's crank.
That's like extreme doses of caffeine
and sugar and sugar in those things.
And you don't even know what else.
Really.
Yeah.
And you know what man,
they gotta stop selling you some Shit
and saying it's more than one serving
five that you can't do that anymore.
You got to stop doing that.
If it's in one package and it's like a
drink,
that's a fucking serving.
Stop saying it
to servant.
Yeah.
Unless it's like a box of like
something.
You know that you're going to cook.
If it's a box that's multiple surveys,
don't tell me this bottle of waters to
fricking service.
Well that's fine.
Well,
he'd say it well you could say that.
No,
that's fine.
Because there's no.
There's no negative consequences and
drinking a bottle of water.
It's universally agreed that an eight
ounce bottle of water or it's not going
to hurt anybody,
but one of those fucking monster energy
drinks,
or my trainer had a protein bar the
other day.
It was like a small one to men.
It was only like maybe three inches
long.
It was a small protein bar.
And he goes,
oh,
I gotta get my protein bar.
Go your candy bar.
I'm fucking with him.
I go,
Dude,
you're eating candy.
He goes,
no man.
I go,
how many grams of sugar in that?
And he goes,
nine.
I go,
really?
how many servings in each bar goes,
no way.
I go check.
He goes,
fuck.
I go,
that's 18 grams of sugar in that little
tiny thing.
It's a candy.
Yeah,
absolutely.
I coached that with teams actually
because when I competed,
the one thing that I think was that I
found really,
really helpful is to be able to travel
and keep yourself in your same daily
routine with your rest and your diet and
more importantly your garbage intake
because people will go to a tournament
and then they'll pop in and they'll grab
like,
you know,
a power bar,
like the chocolate covered power bar.
And then they go to a tournament and
they're like having a snack and then all
of a sudden like two targets that either
like,
I don't know what's up,
I'm kind of like bouncing all over the
place and I'm thinking,
you're on your own.
You just had 40 grams of sugar.
And they're like,
when?
And I go,
well,
you just say that,
um,
marathon bar,
you know,
19 grams of sugar per serving.
Yeah,
double it.
You know,
you just like totally had a full blown
insulin drop,
you know.
And you do have one too.
You know,
I've been on this crazy diet now for two
months and I stepped off of the other
day.
I had a cheeseburger and a chocolate
shake.
Ooh,
wait,
wasn't worth it.
It wasn't worth it.
But it was,
it was worth,
it was worth something.
It was worth something while I was
eating it.
It was glorious.
It was a wonderful cheeseburger with
blue cheese and bacon.
It was very good.
And the chocolate shake,
it was pretty God damn good.
it was a chocolate malt.
In fact,
pretty God damn good but good Lord
because I haven't been eating that way.
The crash after it was over,
it was devastating.
Like I could barely stay awake an hour
later because my insulin level,
just my whole body was just like,
what did you do after months?
Two months of eating clean.
You just took a shit in your mouth.
And I recognized that that had probably
been been in normal thing for me for
most of my life.
If I'd eaten a cheeseburger and a shake
within an hour afterwards,
I just was crashed.
I was just done.
But that's most people,
the way they eat all the time,
they just get used to that terrible
feeling.
When I.
When I give seminars,
you know,
a lot of times you have a lunch break
and I pay attention to the people when
they hit the lunch break.
I pay attention to like what some people
are eating because you can tell a lot by
a person,
by what they're throwing.
If you've got an option of something
good or something crap.
There's some people that just like go
right for the crap.
Then there's some people that go for the
good stuff.
As soon as like your session starts back
up,
and I'm sure you've done this where you
give like speeches or seminars after
meals,
there's always like for people that are
like out and they can't help it,
right?
Because they ate a bunch of garbage and
they had this huge insulin dump and you
know,
they've their bodies like trying to
fight off all that and then they crash
and a lot of times I'll like wake people
up and I'll say,
okay,
I was waiting for that to happen because
now is what I want to talk about the
importance of nutrition during
performance because the reason several
people in here can't stay awake right
now is because of what they did during
their lunch break.
A lot of,
a lot of events,
sports related events that are like all
day events.
They have breaks.
Archery always had a break at noon.
I never wanted to be hungry at the
break.
I tried to continually pick and hydrate
throughout the whole event just like I
do at home during the day so that I
wasn't starving.
You see competitors that are leading the
pack and they run to the fricking
concession stand and they want to like
pound two or three burgers because they
know that they're not going to get to
eat til 5:00 and then all of a sudden
their scores just start to peter out and
they start making mistakes and then all
of a sudden towards the end they come
back again and they're saying like,
Hey,
I just had that fricking though several
ends.
I just struggled and it's like,
how do you think?
Yeah.
Well,
at the time I wasn't like telling all my
competitors online.
I saw that cover
well until you try to live clean,
until you try to eat clean and you don't
eat cheeseburgers and shakes.
You don't understand how much of an
impact it really has because I think
people associate how they feel with just
normalcy.
They think that,
well,
this is just what happens.
You know,
at the end of the day,
I get tired,
man.
I need naps.
When I started drawing this primal diet,
the MERC system diet and I started,
I brought my body into a state of
ketosis.
Yep.
Was the first time ever that in between
meals.
I didn't have that crash.
Why didn't feel terrible where like I
could go six,
seven hours and not feel bad at all
because your body,
when it hits that state is starting to
burn off the fat and so your body has a
supply of fat,
so it just starts converting the fat in
your body to energy.
It's amazing.
It's amazing that so few people eat and
live like this.
Yeah.
That was a.
That was really interesting because the
one thing I asked you was I said,
what's really the difference between
that and the Adkins?
Right.
More fats and that was,
to me,
it made.
Then,
you know,
where the Atkins,
there's a lot more focused on the
protein.
You know,
I get people that are uneducated on
eating clean,
you know,
we look at what we,
you and I just ate for lunch.
I mean we like knocked back and avocado,
like nothing.
Some people are afraid of anomaly ocado
because they say it's fattening.
I mean talk about not knowing what's up.
Yeah,
they don't understand what dietary fats
and the importance of certain amounts of
healthy fats,
of getting the amount of oils and fats
that your body needs.
Healthy oils super important and avocado
oil and Avocados in general,
one of the most healthy fats you can
consume,
super,
super good for you.
You know,
and getting the right amount of
nutrients in your body has just such a
massive effect on how the whole goddamn
thing works.
And again,
I go back to the mentor thing and the
life coach thing because until you have
talked to someone that you trust that
that's done it and is there,
you know,
until you know some guy who's a
competitive marathon or something like
that.
And he says,
listen,
you know,
if you do this,
your body will work better.
You got to trust me.
You got to trust me and try to clean up
your diet and try to,
you know,
just if most people just cut out just
one thing at a time,
they would see a big difference.
I actually have a thing that I call
having,
um,
I've got a ton of success stories of
hunters that were motivated by posts
that I made with like food or,
you know,
they just see a post that I do and
they're like,
I really,
I'm just tired of where I'm at.
As,
you know,
billy bob the bow hunter or you know,
I'm tired of where,
where I'm at archery.
I've never been in it 10 years and I've
never made progress.
What do I need to do?
You know,
I'll get some photos of them in.
A lot of times I notice that they're out
of shape and I'm like,
listen,
if you're shooting on a line and you
look down and you can't see your feet
because,
you know,
a big part of my shot routine is,
is the first step is really your feet.
You know,
your stance.
I mean like imagine martial arts,
you're,
you know,
you're trying to talk someone about
their stance.
I can't even see their feet.
Well it's like,
okay,
well we need to address another problem
as well,
you know,
you might not want to hear this but we
need to address this problem.
And for me when I started down that
path,
because I had about three years of my
life where I,
you know,
it's funny how when it comes to like the
path of an Arrow or the path of life,
all it takes is the smallest movement to
get you going a certain direction and
then all sudden before you know it,
you're like so far off the course and
you're like,
how the hell did I get here?
And,
and I had a point in my career,
I was that way.
I was like,
you know,
I remember I had to,
I put on like a pair of 38 underwear and
I was like,
what the hell?
You know,
I used to wear like 30,
38 pants.
Now I'm in a 38 freaking.
And then I look at my legs because,
you know,
I've got a good story about big bird,
but I always like,
I've got big bird legs,
you know,
and I'm thinking frick,
that's how round my waist is,
as long as that fricking leg,
that's how big around I am.
So what I started doing was just having.
And every time I ordered my normal meal
at a restaurant,
if it comes out and there's a burger,
I took half the bun and I just like.
And then half the fries fricking slit
them off and I gave them to the lady and
said,
can you take that?
And I would literally eat half the carbs
that was on my plate.
I just have everything as soon as it
came out.
So I was in my normal routine in life.
If Sharon and I went to applebee's or
whatever and I ordered my normal little
meal.
If it was a carb or junk,
whatever they gave me as a portion,
I halved it.
And I mean just that.
And then getting rid of like soda and
all of a sudden it was just like zoom in
a matter of months.
You've just completely like change your
directional path and once you've done
the amount of calories and once you get
to that point,
you're motivated by what you're seeing.
And then it's like,
I'm going to have that again.
Like normally I'm used to having this,
And you know,
there's times where I might feel like
bread,
like I told you that for the most part I
don't like,
you know,
I feel really good when I'm not eating
starch or carbs.
I feel way better that way.
However,
certain carbs or I think really critical
for times where,
you know,
there's times where I'm needing to write
or I'm needing to speak and I kinda just
feel fuzzy in the head.
And for me it sometimes I think it's
like your cognitive is like craving some
brain foods so we should try some
ketones to.
I'm going to get you some exemptions.
Ketones for digging,
trying your,
your dietary routine.
It's
good.
Exonerations ketones have a big effect
on mental function is very,
very healthy for you too.
It's all,
it's not,
not junk,
not stimulants,
you know,
just just healthy foods.
You know,
one of the things,
one of the ways that,
uh,
I got to know Cameron Hanes is um,
because uh,
in being on a few hunts and going into
the mountains and experiencing what it's
like just to hike at high altitude,
just really underestimated the amount of
stress that it takes on your body,
how difficult it is to do.
And so then I started researching
fitness and fitness and hunting.
I'm like,
there's got to be someone out there
that's like really into it.
And then I found cam,
just a fitness fucking nut does ultra
marathons and all that jazz.
And that's how cam and I became friends
is by looking at his,
his sort of style of getting ready for
the mountains.
Like pretty much all of what he does
with his weight training,
whether it's just running,
running mountains.
It's preparing him to be a better
hunter.
And I don't think many people that view
hunting considered that they think of
hunting as being a fat guy who's beer
waiting for a deer to pass by so he
could shoot it in the Dick.
You know what I mean?
That's,
that's.
That's how a lot of people look at
hunting.
They look at as a bunch of cruel
assholes or that dentist guy who goes
over to Africa and shoots a line and
fucks it up.
That's how a lot of people look at
hunting and that's one of the reasons
why hunting has a bad rap,
especially in terms of its benefit and
as a tool for conservation.
People will say,
well,
that's.
That's bullshit.
The only reason why people call it a
conservation tool because it gives them
an excuse to kill animals.
Most of the money,
most of the money to preserve wetlands,
to preserve wildlife habitat.
Most of that money is a direct result of
hunting mostly lately.
Totally.
That's a fact.
It's an undeniable fact.
So all these people out there that are
calling themselves conservationists that
never donate and then they'll say
something mean and rude about hunting
and even eat a cheeseburger after they
say it.
Like there's a lot of fucking crazy
intellectual dishonesty out there when
it comes to this subject and also in
terms of what we should or shouldn't do
in terms of being the stewards of the
earth.
Like we were talking about like wild
pigs.
If you don't think that we should do
something to control the population of
wild pigs,
it's because you've never been around
wild pigs.
They have two,
three litters a year.
They'll have three or four babies every
litter,
litter and they fucking keep going and
get more than that.
How many of you they get and what is it
like,
hey eggs,
I'm guessing seven to 10 in the litter
and how many liters a year?
At least two,
right?
Yeah.
I think it's a,
what is it?
Every three months I can chuck them out.
Well,
they can.
Chuck went out and six months after
being born,
which is saying,
oh yeah,
yeah,
it's there.
I mean,
it's,
it's amazing how one or two pigs turns
into an absolute problem really fast and
even even at your house,
you know,
people,
there's people that give me slack if I,
you know,
I posted that video of that coyote I
shot and then you know about the wolf
thing,
but people have a problem with that and
it's like,
dude,
we were in your yard and your wife comes
out and there's like two Qa to coyotes
in the yard,
like scoping out your chicken house.
And then when she took the kids to
school,
she ends up telling us,
yeah,
there's a coyote running down the road
with the fricking rooster hanging out of
it's mouth.
Yeah,
they're common.
I mean,
they're like,
you have to,
you have to control some of that.
And I have to control Predator
populations because nothing else does.
And white tails.
I'm telling you,
I'm frank.
Zane,
he was a three time Mr Olympia frank
used to do are you still does?
He still does,
but frank and arnold used to do archery
as kind of an rnr,
you know,
from their bodybuilding.
That was kind of there.
There's in their stress relief was
shooting and um,
when I went to the Arnold and competed a
frank and Anne frank and Arnold ended up
coming in to have like a,
an old cow,
like a competition like from the old
days,
so they into the hall to like each of
them shoot.
Well,
what Arnold didn't know was frank was so
competitive that frank actually talked
to the coordinator of the event and he
called her and said who are there any
really good archers coming that can
coach.
So she asked around and ended up
connecting frank to me.
So when frank and I talked,
I was like a big fan of them because I
was a fitness guy for my stress relief
and he wanted coaching because he goes,
when Arnold Nice shoot together,
I don't want them to think that I've
practiced but I want to fricking beat
him.
So I actually like worked with them a
little bit and he did end up,
you know,
he ended up shooting and then frank and
I became friends and he's,
you know,
he's an animal he's from.
He's down from San Francisco,
South San Francisco.
I think,
and he never really talked negative
about me when he knew that I was a
hunter and stuff,
but I could tell it wasn't necessarily
something that he favored,
but I
will absolutely.
But he,
he wasn't against it.
He wasn't like dead set against it.
I think he just isn't interested in.
Right.
So I pick them up at the airport and
we're driving back and he said,
so do you like hunt deer all the time?
And I said,
yeah,
I have them all the time.
And he's like,
he's like,
well,
how Kinda,
how do you,
how do you feel about it?
And I said,
you have to do it.
And he's just like,
really?
And he never said anything negative,
but I remember we were three miles from
my house in a fricking deer comes across
the road and we're like in my little
Hyundai accent and I fricking smoke this
thing.
And he's like,
he's just like,
oh shit.
Like,
he's like,
he's never seen like a fricking animals
smashed the car.
And um,
and he's just like,
that was a freaking deal.
We just hit a deer.
And I said,
yeah dude,
imagine if 850,000 people in the state
of Wisconsin weren't out hunting a year.
Eight hundred and $50,000.
Is that how many?
Yeah,
between Bowen gun owners,
you can look it up.
I was in Wisconsin for opening season
not last year,
but the year before last and the morning
light is like a war just started.
It was like,
remember when we used to watch like
shocking all,
like when the shock and all happen.
That's what it sounds like.
Well,
we talked about Michigan on the podcast
before that in last year or every year,
50,000 car accidents involving deer a
year just in Michigan alone.
And so people that think,
well,
there's no other way to take care of
that.
This is what people have to understand.
Unless you want to bring in wolves and
guess what?
You don't want to bring in wolves,
wolves in your neighborhood.
You don't want to look that in the face.
Yeah.
Well you did.
You know,
I've,
I've talked.
That story's crazy.
I was telling a friend of mine about it,
the,
uh,
the story of you,
you were in Alberta and you shot elk and
these wolves
circled the elk.
How many,
how many wolves were there?
Well,
at first there was just the one,
the one came in and you know,
the one came in on us and I,
and I,
and that's what I do want to say off the
beginning.
One thing that I always do as a hunter
is I always buy or Predator tag if it's
available,
if I know that I can get that I can buy
a tag for coyotes or wolves.
I always have one in my pocket because
you do see,
you know,
they're out there and they're out there
way more now and this.
And this is an exact reason why he got
to do it because literally we had an elk
down and next thing you know,
we're out there kind of,
you know,
getting it ready to like,
to cut it up and stuff and get it out of
there and all sudden this big wolf comes
through,
you know,
comes in.
And I had spotted it and we weren't
really being noisy,
so I ended up shooting that wolf and it
kind of went off and you know,
with a bow there's no noise.
So what we didn't realize was there was
a pack there and that,
that was actually,
it was an Alpha female is because of the
size of it.
I mean you saw the size of it is as big
as me and it actually went off and then
we kinda thought,
oh,
was freaky.
Freaky will.
Then about 20 minutes later all of a
sudden we see another one and we see
another one and we're kinda like,
holy crap.
So we start moving into this draw.
And one of them was like making a noise,
almost like it was injured or something.
I was whimpering.
So we're like,
what is the deal?
So we were on high ground with the elk
and then we started moving down into
this ravine because we saw the,
the wolves down in there.
And next thing you know,
we get down in there and I start looking
around and there's like hair on the
trees.
There's like,
I mean,
it looked like that movie into the gray,
the gray,
that's exactly what it looked like.
Liam Neeson.
There was like frick and Harry turds
everywhere.
It was just,
there was like beds,
there was hair rubbed on the trees and I
start looking around,
there's like holes dug in and I'm like,
I literally look at my two buddies that
were there with me and I said right in
their fricking den,
like,
you know,
and I think we had that elk was not too
far,
you know,
our elk wasn't too far when you shot an
elk that they probably thought of as
there's.
Oh they definitely thought of it was
there.
So yeah,
they,
they definitely thought that was theirs.
So then once we're down there,
all of a sudden we hear this.
How were like down there,
we hear this how,
and it was definitely an Alpha because
an Alphas the how.
It literally turns your blood instantly
cold if you're right in on a true wolf
howl.
It's,
I mean it's like so freaking low and
deep and it's just like chills your
blood,
what you realize.
It's not a game.
Yeah.
Then I realized I'm like,
we're in their fricking Dan and you
know,
I'm kind of looking down.
I'm like,
okay,
well I shot an elk.
Then I shot that.
I've got two arrows left.
So,
and you know,
both my guides kind of had,
you know,
once we said,
oh there's wolves.
They like grabbed a gun.
We kind of went down in there to see
what was up.
Well now this happens and next thing
after that Alpha sounded off,
it was like,
and I mean 12,
I think it was 12,
sounded off all the way around us.
We're in a,
we're,
we're literally down.
Anyone who's been in Alberta,
you know,
that the farm land is level and then it
falls into the river system.
So we're literally,
they have the high ground,
there's a dozen wolves and we're in the
middle and we're like,
what the crap.
So I just,
I'm like get you back to a tree.
So we kinda all spin around and we're
sitting there and next thing you know
here comes to dogs on a full blown.
I'm talking like full blown like this
running,
coming and I mean it turned into chaos.
There was like bullets flying.
I mean there's freaking arrows skipping
off junk.
And we ended up shooting both of those
wolves dead and there's a few gunfire
going off while I'm down to like one
Arrow left and I told the guy,
I said how many bullets you got?
And he goes,
well I didn't,
I,
you know,
I just grabbed the gun to a couple of
bullets.
Like I didn't know where this was all
going down.
So count,
we're kind of like we need to get out of
here.
So we started backing up and next thing
you know,
they,
the Alpha sounded off again and they all
reported this time there's only two or
two less.
So next thing I know,
I'm like kind of we're trying to back
out.
So when you say,
hold on a second,
you say they reported there.
So there's,
they know that two were dead.
Yeah.
So all of them are howling.
I'm certain that the first.
How was the Alpha male pretty much
saying in is everyone in position
because then they all like.
Yes,
yes.
All the way around.
Then all of a sudden the to come,
all hell breaks loose.
Then we're like the alpha sounds again,
but he's in a different location.
He was actually to my left like right
here and it really close and I mean it's
thick in there.
You've been there,
you know how thick it gets.
So then they sound awful.
Now this time there's two less,
so
I'm kind of looking because I know this
wolf that sounded was and I know it's
the Alpha so I like grabbed my boa and I
start kinda creeping over there and as
soon as I get to where I can see he's
like fricking standing right there.
And how far our
30 yards
wolf can cover jamie.
Pull up that picture from Joe's
instagram.
Like it was about a week ago.
You found those pictures of those
wolves?
Yeah.
I forget who the photographer was.
There got some amazing photographs or.
Yeah,
it was.
It was like not the most recent one that
was on that dead Moose.
But it was from national geographic.
That was actually a bison.
Those from yesterday.
That's right.
Yesterday or the day before.
Look at that.
That right there.
That is exactly the face that I saw in
the.
Anybody was head on.
He wasn't broad side,
but that face where he was literally
looking at me like that.
And I mean you're in a fight or flight
like I'm in.
Totally in a fight or flight.
I had one arrow left on my string.
I fricking grabbed my bow.
I literally,
I like,
I just,
I kinda looked at him.
I knew at that moment it was like he was
coming.
Yeah.
That's like fricken Deja Vu,
right?
The twitter,
the instagram page.
Jamie
do go back up a little bit is c j I m
underscore photography and if you go to
that guy's instagram page has got
amazing photographs just.
And he's out there with them.
There was another one that I had and
it's just right before that,
Jamie,
the.
Before that Wolf picture,
there was another wolf picture.
That one.
Look at that one man,
he's got snow all over his face and his
teeth are.
That's cool.
Yeah,
that's a cool picture.
Like to me that's pretty cool.
Those are amazing.
They're amazing.
And the one thing people underestimate
about hunters is our respect for
animals.
I love him.
Why did you kill?
I freaking,
I totally respect him.
I love him,
but I can tell you that other picture
right there when you have that looking
at you in the face.
I mean I knew it was like freaking do or
die and I,
I literally looked at that thing and I
said out loud,
I said I'm going to shoot you in the F
and face because you don't swear.
Yeah,
sorry.
It's cute.
And
my boy might listen.
Remember I drew back.
Oh,
like I literally drew back and I
anchored and that came into my peep and
means for people don't know.
There's like a little circle that you
look at through the string.
We line lining up with the site.
So I was literally lining up the shot,
lining up the shot and as soon as I kind
of brought my shot down to where that
wolf was,
there was nothing there.
He bolted.
No,
I think he just like,
yeah,
like Ninja.
Well he if there that wise and that big
in that old,
they've got to know what they mean.
Smart.
We had to have known that you killed the
elk and they had to have known that you
killed those other two wolves which
chased you.
That went after this to try and get the
ELC.
I think he came in to to think,
okay,
we've.
You called a fight.
We responded,
now he's like sizing up.
Okay,
I've lost.
Here's what I've lost.
I want to know what I'm going against.
He kinda came in and he freaking looked
at all
and then that was it.
Good thing they can count for you.
Who you only had two hours left here.
Yeah.
Two hours.
Two bullets.
Bullets.
That guy pick up and picked up.
Three.
It was bone chilling.
I'm,
I mean I have,
you and I both have friends that are
grizzlies cats.
I mean,
cats are notorious for stocking hunters
too,
because I mean they are the ultimate
hunter,
but grizzlies and wolves,
I mean there you have to be on guard
that,
you know,
there's places now we're,
grizzlies are strongly becoming such a
problem when it comes to,
you know,
they have to be controlled.
They're just starting to get to be too
many for,
especially for the food source.
Well there's people that worry about
them being wiped out and I read this
article about it recently and it was
just so filled with misunderstanding or
misinformation and we're talking about
wiping out grizzlies that if they did
open up back to grizzlies,
grizzlies back to hunting again,
they will be wiped out.
People don't understand how it works.
There's a lot meant a certain amount of
tags that get distributed because
wildlife biologist deemed that there's
too many of them and then it's
problematic for all the other animals
that live in the area.
You have to understand like when they
try to do,
when they put tag limits on white tail
deer or would they put tag limits on
wolves?
They do it because they've deemed that
there's an issue and there's obviously
people want to hunt deer,
but there's also an issue,
like we were talking about the state of
Pennsylvania.
There's some areas,
I don't know if it's still the case,
but there were some areas in
Pennsylvania where they brought in
hunter's year round,
no tag limits.
They were like,
just please come on down and shoot.
And it was on Michael Waddell,
uh,
his show.
Oh yeah.
T bone was there.
There was a shot like three or four deer
in a day and it was in the middle of
summer.
It's just went down there and shot deer
because there's just so many of them.
And they were shooting them in like a
residential area.
They were in a tree stand in like this
dude's fucking yard.
And it's overwhelmed with deers.
I think I,
I met a guy that was literally begging
me to come.
He said there's a deer season in the
residential areas I think in New Jersey.
And he said there's like so many deer in
people's backyards and the timber.
So he just said it's like there's just
so many that they're issuing a lot of
urban tags and they are wanting to.
Yeah.
And they have to.
And they have.
Did you see the bears fighting in far
rockaway?
New Jersey.
Did you see that video?
Yeah,
bring up that video to no bullshit.
Bonafide seven foot 400 plus pound
bear's going to war in a residential
community.
Knocking over fucking mailboxes and
garbage cans.
Roll it out into the street for flying.
Biting each other.
Look at the size of these fuckers.
But are they there?
Try to pet them or anything?
Yeah,
they should just be friends.
But look at these guys going at it.
These are big fucking bears too.
Big Boars the size of these guys.
And so we kind of move.
Is that.
What was the,
what was that a judo?
Throw his shitty Jujitsu.
Looking at.
He's reaching for a back leg.
It's like more than the answer.
Trying to ankle pick.
It went in for a back leg.
Well this goes on for a long time too.
In the guy who's filming it is filming
it from his car.
I guess he's got his hand out the window
and so they go crashing through the
bushes.
They go tumbling down to the street.
They take out some mailboxes.
I mean there's a mailbox.
Good Dude.
These fuckers are big man.
They're big ass bears.
Those are really big
and they,
they keep going back.
See this one guy wants the garbage and
that's where it is.
Funny.
Have a lady just came out to go
shopping.
Well I fucking easily could happen.
That's how people die.
Oh yeah.
This is lady got killed in Florida last
year by one of these fuckers.
Yeah,
they're,
they're serious.
They mean,
I mean,
you're not bear barriers.
What a lot of people don't realize too.
I every year I go up,
you know,
you always catch,
you catch flack for being a bear hunter.
But I go up to British Columbia every
year and bear hunt and during and it's
all spot and stalk there.
It's all fair chase.
Um,
but during the course of a six day hunt,
I remember one year I saw 82 bears on a
six day hunt.
That's insane.
I mean in some of the barriers you might
see twice,
but there was so many barriers and it's
like,
you know what,
you have to manage that.
It's healthy for them to.
Otherwise this happens and you want to
watch this in your yard.
Well,
this is what could happen and what's
interesting is Jamie and I,
we were laughing because we found this
fucking poster,
this billboard that said they're all
cecil and it's a bear and a lion hugging
each other and it said,
stop the New Jersey Bear Hunt.
Like there are people out there that are
emotionally wreck there.
There are children there.
They're an emotional wreck there.
A child who doesn't understand that
nature is a ruthless,
vicious,
beautiful,
majestic thing and wildlife biologists
were the ones who know the best you.
You see these crazy emotional people
that get so wrapped up in this idea that
these things are.
These animals are like people.
They have this fucking picture of this
bear and this lion hugging each other
and the bear has tiers and the lion is
tears.
Look at this.
They're hugging each other.
It says they are a band.
The bear hunt,
they are all cecil saved,
New Jersey bears.com.
You guys were out of your fucking mind.
Wow.
These bears didn't exist.
They didn't exist and they were in a
movie.
They would be a monster.
Be some based living in the woods.
That fucking eats eats baby deer right
out of the vagina of the deer.
When they pull them out and they
literally catch a deer that's giving
birth to a and they pull them
out of each other.
They eat cubs on a regular basis.
There's so much cannibalism and the bear
community.
It could be.
I'm thinking,
well,
they equal rights.
Tell me that fucking story that you were
telling me yesterday about the grizzly
bear that got into the shed or got into
the cabin.
Oh yeah,
and just the sheer power.
I actually have a.
my,
my like wilderness father,
his name is burt.
He's up up there where I hunt and BC.
He has stories of the wilderness.
He'd be the ultimate character for you
to have on and he's like a real life.
Grizzly Adams.
He's got stories,
but there was a bear that kept
destroying the camps and the cabins.
They ended up,
they ended up like just kind of calling
the bear earl big earl or something and
they would come to the camps.
He would come in and they would have
like a huge big door,
you know,
and they would nail in,
nine,
10 inch spikes through the doorframe in
three spots down the sides.
And then through the top they'd nail 10
inch spikes,
pound them through the logs,
have a log home to hold the doorframe
in.
Well,
they came to camp and they figured,
well this is going to keep him out
because he was blowing through all the
windows.
Every year he'd blow through the
windows,
so they boarded the windows up and they
had this door.
So evidently he got mad.
They could see where he was really mad
about how they boarded the door,
the windows up.
So he literally grabbed the door and the
whole door and we'll.
The whole frame with the door was like
freaking laying off to the side of the
cabin with 10 inch spikes bent on 90
degree angles and there was one claw
there.
He had evidently reached in with two
claws and freaking hook the backside of
that doorframe and ripped a fricken door
out of a log home and pulled one of his
own closet and pulled his claw.
That's how they knew they got the bear
because they ended up getting a permit
to get the bear and he had nine clause.
Wow.
So he fricking through that to the side.
When in the cabin he licked the fricken
oven clean,
but he could still smell that there's
like Greece somewhere inside there that
he like wanted to get to.
So the whole fricken.
The whole stove was smashed about this
high off the ground,
so a couple inches a couple inches off
the ground.
He literally just got on it and squish
that fricking a fullblown stove just
like we would a pop can under our foot
to like squirt some extra grease up the
side of that big Oreo cookie that he
thought it was.
Oh my and licked it clean,
we'll it gets better.
So there was curtains over the sink and
the Cabinet and the curtains were all
gone.
And,
and um,
the other thing too,
I think there was like there was two big
five gallon things of like cooking oil
that were in the camp.
So burt told me that there was like one
claw mark in the cooking oil and then
the fricken things like a Capri Sun,
he had freaked out,
popped a hole in these five gallon
things,
a cooking oil and freaking squirt them
dry like a,
like an old capri sun through those to
the side we'll,
the curtains were gone to because burt
thinks because of cooking,
like the grease and crap that got on the
curtains.
He liked freaking they were gone.
Yeah.
Well at the time they didn't know.
They just,
you know,
I'm his wife Mary Jane was like,
What happened to the curtains?
And he's like I have no idea.
But he had lived in there.
So I mean he had like piled the couch up
and I mean he like lived in that cabin.
Will there.
The bear did a full blown 10 foot
fricking grizzly mountain grizzly,
so then they went down to the next camp
which was 20 miles away and I didn't
tell you this part,
so they get in there and it's just an
absolute freaking wreck.
It looks like a life size mouse home,
just crap everywhere.
So Mary Jane's like cut a snow shovel
and she's like scooping all this
freaking shit off the ground and there
was all these like material
dingleberry's in and she's like,
what are those dingleberry things?
And burt goes,
that's all the balls off the curtains
from Griz camp the frick and buried like
eight.
The curtains in the other camp.
Once he destroyed,
he kept walking down the road 20 miles
to the next brick and cabin.
Destroyed that one and freaking shit.
Only miles.
Yeah.
Oh yeah,
he was,
he was the king of the mountain.
Oh yeah.
They have a huge range,
but yeah,
he like,
you know,
fricking slung dingleberry juice and 10
gallons of fricking oil all across the
next can.
Just to prove a point might have been
kind of diarrhea.
Bear gets after 10 gallons of oil,
just drink oil and eat curtains was
probably about the same kind I get after
like six chicken mcnuggets.
It's hard out there for a bear to hard
world.
It is this a crazy animal.
It's such a majestic.
We're super lucky that they're alive.
We're super lucky that they're around.
And that's the difference between,
I think,
um,
people who were like really hardcore
animal rights activists and people who
are wildlife biologists and
conservationists.
They both agree that bears are amazing
and that's where I think that these
people are,
they have a misconception.
They think that hunter's want to kill
animals and they're,
they're vicious and they're mean and
cruel and they have little dicks and uh,
some of them do.
I'm sure.
I'm sure someone small for you if you
admitted that well,
like small,
but you're a giant guy like six,
five.
It could be.
That could be it.
Maybe it's just small compared to
everything else.
I hope so.
I hope so too for you.
I mean,
you got to admit your problem if you're
going to move on,
right?
So you get better at archery is how you
get better at dealing with your Dick.
But this but both.
My point was that like both love bears.
Oh yeah.
They just,
they just don't want them to be a
problem.
So when you're looking at what this bear
did,
that cabin you said Woo.
Cam is in his name.
Rude.
So nothing's his neighborhood.
How about that?
I just said it that it's all.
If people live out there and the bear
comes in their house,
it's not that the bear came into his own
house,
it's a fucking person's house.
And if you don't think that way then
you're,
you're a problem.
You're your problem.
The bears are fucking bears.
All right?
And if you don't differentiate the
difference between,
uh,
the value of a person and controlling
populations of bear,
well you're a ridiculous person.
You,
you,
you're not looking at this thing
correctly.
No one saying the bear should be wiped
out.
But when you talk about an animal that
can,
from a stove,
flatness,
stove and pull a door out of the frame
with nine foot long spikes surround,
I mean nine inch,
nine inch,
nine foot.
How crazy that some kind of nails,
nails,
nails as big as the band,
nine inch long spikes.
You're talking about an insane animal
that if you don't control their
populations,
they're going to decimate everything.
They're gonna.
They're gonna debt.
The only thing that's saving them is
them,
them eating cubs.
That's the only thing that controls the
population of them.
If they're not,
if they're no.
Huh?
Yeah.
The only thing controlling the
population is the food chain.
And you know,
I told you this the other day,
I,
I feel like as a hunter,
I love what I've got to witness as a
hunter because I feel like I've spent,
I've spent way more time enjoying the
creations of the wild because I've been
out there
really out there.
Yeah.
I'm like,
how else would you have gotten a chance
to see wolves in that environment that
you saw them?
I mean,
that's a confrontational.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean,
yeah,
I wouldn't prefer to be in the middle of
a freaking wolf attack to see them,
but you see things like I told you the
time we're like,
you know,
we're the time were a freaking bull
moose,
like probably about the size of the one
that you've got over there.
You know,
literally watched this fricking grizzly
square off to this bull Moose and hit
it.
The grizzly literally just hit the
fricken top back part of a full blown
Mousse and just broke it.
And it's like dinnertime snapped.
It's back.
Yes.
Snapped it.
I mean,
just the sheer power.
Yeah.
Where was this up in BC.
Wow.
I mean,
you look,
how far away was it from you?
It was a ways off.
I mean,
it was like a binocular watch,
but still there's things like that.
There's things like,
you know,
you talked about how um,
the rivets up in Alberta where they have
the bear camp,
you know,
you saw like a boar.
Maybe they were telling you the story I
saw bore and the south fighting.
Okay.
Going at it.
Yeah.
Well,
I've seen,
and I told you this and I actually,
I shot the bore,
but I spotted a big bear and a field and
I was hunting and it was spot and stalk
and as I'm starting to stock all sudden
the sow comes out and starts freaking
like posture and to the,
to the mail and then all heck broke
loose just like that.
That's what it was like.
And I mean I'm within 100 yards of it.
I mean it's ferociously loud.
And then after they like break up,
the board goes running to this huge.
You've seen the timber up there,
the timbers gigantic.
Then a couple stories,
high fricking jumps on this tree and
starts going and I mean I'm talking like
full speed,
full speed.
I mean it's like if it's an incredible
chase and fight,
he freaking hits this tree and he's
fricking going up at like bark is just
ripping out and the,
the black female is going right behind
him.
And at the time I still didn't realize
what's up until I.
until he gets almost to the top and I
see two colored cubs up there and he's
free,
I mean like branches or coming off like
nothing is stopping.
This dude,
he's fricking going and right before he
gets to the cubs,
the frick and female launches and grabs
the ham hock and just let's go the tree
and just fricking let's both of them and
let's the weight frick and bring them
down and just Ooh,
you hear like boom.
And then all heck breaks loose.
They go up into the timber and it's just
like,
you know,
a crazy fight.
We were in a similar situation when
there was a mother with her cubs and
then the board came in looking to kill
and eat the cubs.
Yep.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
And we talked about there's argument to
why I haven't seen the evidence on,
you know,
you feel like it's just was Rinella said
that there's recent evidence that shows
that these bears are looking to eat
these things like almost immediately
when they come out of hibernate because
of ease of riot.
Yeah,
because they're just food I've,
I personally think because they always
tend to be more aggressive on the cubs
from what I've experienced the further
into may then the rug,
right?
The closer you get to run,
the more likely,
you know,
I kinda think those boards might have
bred one or two styles.
They're Horny,
I mean so horny and then they,
they're wanting another one and they
know that's the only thing that's going
to trigger to for them to come back in.
But I,
you know,
after that fight broke up in the sow,
she ended up standing guard.
She kind of called her cubs down and
they hauled will,
that big bore ended up coming out and he
was,
you know,
it was like a seven foot chocolate and
that's the one I got,
you know.
So,
you know,
some people might be like,
oh,
he was trying to kill the babies and
then you know,
next thing you know,
I got it.
So I kind of feel like I did babies.
You're constantly definitely
conservationists in that
and that people also don't realize that
you eat bears too.
People have been eating bears forever
and it tastes good.
Yup.
You know,
they think the.
You only eat deer and elk and everything
else is trophy hunting,
you know?
Yeah.
It's,
it's amazing.
To me the,
the,
just the beauties that I've seen,
I've been,
I love sitting in a white tail stand and
I spent a lot of time in a white tail
stand just sitting quiet and you know,
for me it's,
it's like meditation because it is so
quiet at times.
There's like sometimes I've heard like
birds and noises where I'm like,
I've literally never ever hurt.
Like what is that?
Like I've never heard that.
And I.
One of the coolest things that I've
experienced is I've been in the timber
during the fall or there's just colors,
like,
like a painting,
just colors,
you know,
you know how it is in the Midwest and
there's days when like the first fall
snap really happens when I believe trees
just decided to let go.
I did.
Have you ever watched any of the Harry
Potter movies you ever see that move?
That tree that just like fricking cleans
itself off and then all of a sudden he
just decides,
well,
I've been in the timber where it was
like the trees are almost communicating
and everyone just said let go.
And literally the like someone just
moved a fresh canvas,
just all the colors of fall just let go
and you literally watched the whole
color of fall go to the ground and it's
bare
who can say they've seen that?
Pretty rare.
It is amazing to see these cycles of
nature,
the see them in person and I think
that's one of the things that a lot of
people are missing by living in cities.
There's a lot of really cool shit that
you could see out in the woods.
There's so much.
So much of it is just like inherently
fascinating or like it appeals to us
some sort of a primal way.
You remember that Squirrel I sent you
the other day?
Yeah,
I got.
that was crazy.
I mean,
I was out for a little walk and I came
across a really nice buck and awesome
buck,
literally dead and eaten by coyotes and
it was a deer that I know was,
you know,
I'd seen earlier in the season and it
was perfectly healthy and next thing I
know a month later here it is dead.
Just a decade carcass eaten.
What do you think happened?
You think the coyote is captured it?
Are you tired from the Rut?
It's hard to say.
I think,
you know,
I think with any type of animal,
especially when the males have such a
limited time to breed,
they've really exert themselves.
I mean it's like,
it's like looking.
I've seen books that literally look
like,
like that.
You got that fighter that fought Kimbo
or whatever,
you know,
$5,000.
I literally seen them,
I've seen them walking in there like a
fricking fully skins Zombie just because
they've just been running.
They came too much.
Yeah.
They don't look like that a few times I
heard
you get,
you get tired,
man.
Yeah.
And I think when they get that run down,
it's no different than me when I'm
traveling a lot,
especially when I'm skipping time zones
and I really have a hard time getting
into a sleep pattern and a recovery
pattern.
You just get sick,
you get the flu,
you know,
you get some fricking stupid little bug
that's on an airplane from some guy like
three seats over that's coughing,
you know,
I think he just where your immune system
down and you're vulnerable.
And then when winter comes in and it's,
it's a fricking,
you know,
it's tough on.
So they don't eat for days sometimes.
Oh yeah.
Days.
I remember it after it.
I saw a book one time.
He was just,
I mean I see him like as far as I could
see with the binoculars over here.
And then I,
you know,
30 minutes later it seem as far as I
could see with binoculars go through
this creek bottom in this creek bottom.
And I was actually sitting on this like
Pond Dam and about 11 in the morning.
Here he comes.
He's just like,
fricking,
he's just walking with the Zombie walk,
like he's trying to find a scent trail
of a dough that's in estrus and he's
just been breeding for weeks and I
remember he was just freaking comment in
any literally just comes running any
hits the pond and he's sitting in the
pond like with just as head sitting out
and he's like,
and then he comes up out and he's just
like,
he goes like
shakes and he's gone again.
It's just like,
holy crap,
this poor dude is just like running this
like marathon of the Rut and well
there's so much competition.
Oh yes.
Well that's part of what ramps them all
up.
This is so many other deer there.
Yeah,
yeah.
I mean,
and it's,
you know,
so to watch so many die that way.
Well I found that,
but that buck that day and then
two minutes later I'm walking through
the forest like,
oh,
here's a cute little squirrel.
You know,
I see this girl like any,
like Kinda like,
he's like looking at me on side of this
tree.
Like,
is this person going to hurt me?
And all of a sudden like fricking boom,
this like red tail hawk,
just fricking pounds of this thing.
And I'm like looking around like,
what the heck?
And then the Hawk looks at me and starts
to fly and then drops a squirrel and I.
and that's the.
I went over and here's this girl with
like to talent marks one through.
It's either through its mouth and one
like.
Did you put that picture on?
No,
I can,
I can send it to Jamie though if you put
it on your instagram page because crazy
picture.
Yeah.
It's a weird thing to see.
Yeah,
it's,
you know,
nature's nature is interesting,
but it's,
you know,
I'm a conservationist.
I'm a,
I'm a huge supporter to the boone and
Crockett club.
I've,
you know,
I've uh,
really tried to become,
you know,
I've,
I've done what it takes to become a
professional member now of the Boone and
Crockett club and you know,
I'm really focused on trying to give
more back on the conservation side
because there are so many important
things that these organizations do for
wildlife.
As much as people want to say they,
you know,
I've,
I've just never seen an,
an anti hunting community
come anywhere where I'm at and put in
time establishing habitat and actually
doing things that grow the population
and you know,
I plant food and I probably leave 5,000
bucks a year worth of food in my dirt to
like help grow deer and like help my
dear,
don't,
don't you think though that there's a
lot of people that have opinions about,
uh,
about animals and about wildlife that
really spend very little time with
animals and in wildlife they have this
very convenient idea.
Like,
like when I,
I told a friend of mine the number,
the more we discussed on the podcast
earlier about Michigan having 50,000 car
accidents a year and he was like,
you're lying.
I'm like,
dude,
Google it.
And he looked at it and he just sat,
like literally looked at his phone and
sat like,
plop down.
Holy Shit.
I go,
you're not there.
If you're there you would know like
it's,
it's overwhelming because his opinion or
his point of view was that these hunters
are just these people that are just
assholes that liked to shoot animals,
like they do need to do this,
like they need to do this and you might
not think it,
but you just.
No Way.
You have a survey of the whole world or
the whole country.
You just don't.
And if you did,
I bet you'd have a different pace.
Have you seen some of the numbers,
like what allstate insurance posts about
how many vehicle deaths and like dollars
and vehicle collisions are,
are just with white tail deer with one
insurance company?
Let's find out.
I have it on my laptop.
If you want me to grab Jamie could pull
it up.
I'm sure it's on Google.
It just google.
How many car accidents involve dear
nationwide?
Yup.
I bet if Michigan has 50,000.
Yeah,
mind blowing the even the number of
deaths would is
well in campaigns is hometown.
Some guy just died,
some guy hit a deer and then the guy in
front of them died because.
Or the guy behind him,
the guy hit a deer when flying through
the air,
175 to 200 fatalities every year and
10,000 injuries.
There's approximately one point 5
million deer related car accidents
annually.
I'm going to say that again.
There are one point 5 million deer
related car accidents annually.
You didn't know that,
did you?
Nope.
Over $1,000,000,000 in vehicle damage
and 175 to 200 fate totalities as well
as 10,000 injuries.
Oh my God.
And
200 deaths in 2012,
it said 200 deaths.
$4,000,000,000
year.
Yup.
Fucking Christ.
Exactly.
And a lot of people don't know that the
continent is large and that.
You know what?
Let me ask you this.
It's funny.
People,
people whine and cry about how much
insurance goes up.
How much do you think it would go up if
we didn't help that?
Well also
does that have about health insurance?
Because it ticks and lyme lyme disease.
Oh yeah.
There was this end.
Just your injuries.
More people going in for hitting one.
Yeah,
absolutely.
My Dad,
my dad actually,
he,
he always wanted to have his teeth
perfect and I remember he wore braces
for a long time to get his teeth fixed
and like no sooner than he had them done
and was wearing a retainer and my dad's
like,
he's got a truck at home,
like a big truck,
but he never drives it because he
always,
he liked,
drove a little bitty Honda and fricking
hit a deer.
He hit a buck like a month after getting
like finally the dentist saying,
you don't have to wear your retainer.
He hit a buck.
The horns stuck through his windshield
and the horn stopped on a steering wheel
and the body came in and hit him in the
face.
Oh my God.
And he had to like get.
He literally is fake teeth in the front.
Wow.
Ha.
So
Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
I had no idea that one point $5 million
I told you.
That's crazy.
That's a way better statistic.
50,000 in Michigan.
Yeah.
That's nothing.
I mean,
well wow,
that's a lot.
It's a lot.
But in the,
in the whole scheme of things,
you know,
my wife,
my wife's from Rangeland,
um,
and she had never hunted her family,
never have.
I mean,
they're just,
they have no idea about that stuff.
It's,
you know,
they,
they have no relation to hunting.
Right.
So when she came over,
she was,
you know,
she knew I hunted and she was open
minded to it because I,
I showed her numbers like this.
I said,
okay,
I understand you don't understand it,
so let's talk about some of this stuff.
Do you realize this?
Do you know that at our house if you
drive around,
you're gonna see a deer from your car,
like almost anytime you're driving
around our area after dark or waiting to
see how many dead deer on the side of
the road during the first three weeks in
November,
driving down the highway in Iowa.
You know what I mean?
So she kept an open mind and she
realized really quick.
We couldn't grow a garden,
you know,
in Wisconsin,
they were like eaten us all the time.
I mean,
they were everywhere and she's just
like,
you know what,
I get it.
I never saw this.
I didn't see this much stuff in in
England.
We didn't have it.
That's why we weren't hunting there.
It's not because people aren't
necessarily hunters.
It wasn't in some areas it isn't a
needed conservation.
It is here.
That's the reality.
Imagine if you could see all one point
$5 million car accidents in like a scene
one after the other.
Bang,
Bang.
Because you've got to think there's
three and 65 days.
Use Twenty four days in a 24 hours in a
day.
So if you could look at all the footage
that's accumulated every year in one
giant loop,
the highlight reel of car accidents,
you couldn't watch it in a year.
Well you couldn't.
Well you would watch two people die.
Two or 200 people die too,
but just the sheer volume would kind of
wake people up.
If you could watch the sheer volume.
If they put together a movie that was
three hours long,
that was just all the car accidents in
the last six months with deere,
people would go,
oh my God,
we're at war.
We're at war,
and they're attacking cars.
They're literally suicide bombing cars
to jumping out in the street and taking
out drivers.
Well,
for over three hours you would see
someone die every minute.
Yeah.
In that compile.
You just see boom,
boom,
smash hook to the face of antlers to the
neck.
It was over and over and over again.
You'd have a lot more candidates for
that.
LSD.
A trial for.
I mean there'd be some serious
traumatic.
Sorry.
Mgma.
MGMA trial.
Yeah.
That would flip people over in the end.
Listen,
we gotta get the fuck out of here.
It's 4:00.
Oh yeah,
you did the shoot and just we just bang
through three hours.
How about this buddy?
Thanks Jamie.
Thanks for coming down here and thank
you very much for all the coaching,
man.
It's been amazing.
I've learned so much from you and
anybody that's into archery.
I encourage you.
Go to a knock on archery,
on Youtube and knock on TV and um,
knock on TV on twitter.
I put that already up on my twitter page
and there's the television show that is
on the sportsmans channel.
John Dudley.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Thanks everybody.
Try Archery.
You'll like it.
I will be back tomorrow with the great
dom I rera sale.