Male.
Hey everybody,
the Joe Rogan experience podcast is a guy
is in need of a new way of saying that
because it's fucking tired of it.
Goddammit Patrick Turner,
the coming distractions. Yeah. Here,
here's some shit you should do with
your money if you want to help the show.
It doesn't really help us.
I mean it sort of helps us.
It helps the people who pay us.
So it helps us indirectly.
One thing we can promise you, when we, uh,
have any sort of sponsorship on the show,
it is 100% of product that I believe
in. There's, there's no like,
we'll never bullshit you. So anything
that we have that sponsors a show,
you can guarantee that what we are
saying first of all is 100% of what we
believe. And the, if we find out that
it's incorrect in any way, shape or form,
we will go back and correct it. There's
a, the last thing I want, that's a little,
that's not subtle enough.
The last thing I want is for anyone to
get ripped off ever from anything that
I'm associated with.
So everything we sell you,
whether it's the supplements from
on it or Ting, uh, we believe in,
what is Ting Ting is if you go to
rogan.ting.com you will be able to get a
better understanding of it. And you also
save 50 bucks on your first ting device.
They have a bunch of cool smartphones,
including the Samsung Galaxy s three.
I only saw amazing your day.
Don't do it. Don't know. Tim,
why don't you hook Brian
Redman up of the phone?
I think we need his technical advice
because I just love me like the bigger
pictures.
Maybe like going on browser,
big screen.
I've been using this nexus seven thing
here and it has the android operating
system on it. And so now I'm like, man,
I wish I could use this as a phone. Yeah.
Because I kind of want to see the
Internet. Is it on the Internet?
It's a Wifi only. So I use my
iPhone five to teeth are at to,
do they make any ones like that that
are um, by the way, it's tethered.
You're fuck,
there is
um, the, um, did they
make them that small?
That actually or is it the note is
the only one that's smaller than that.
It is a smaller, they don't make something
that size. That's a phone though. No,
I don't think so.
But I think us cellular Wifi,
I saw somebody use one of those
notes on the other day. This girl,
this little girl had this humongous phone.
It was like,
it looked like the old days when people
had boombox is on your shoulders.
But they're cool man. I'm telling you,
I get mad phone envy, technology envy.
Whenever I see that screen. Um, they
don't, sorry, Tim doesn't have that.
But they have the galaxy s three.
That's why I want to get it yesterday.
And I walk into a huge too.
That's like a medium,
a medium ground between the note and the,
some of the other Google smart phones.
Um,
but the,
what's great about Ting is the way
they've set up their business and the,
the idea behind it is you can still run
a good business and make money and not
have to rip people off.
Not have to get people involved in these
crazy contracts where you can't get out
of it unless you pay money. I think
that's disgusting. I really do.
I think it's a crazy,
horrible situation where when you,
when you order service,
especially from some gigantic
multibillion dollar companies, you know,
when you're ordering service,
when you don't want the service anymore,
you should be able to say, I don't want
your service anymore. Thank you very much.
And boom, it goes away. It shouldn't
be you have to pay them money.
But that's how it is with
most major providers.
And Ting doesn't have it set
up like that thing. Also, I,
I misspoke when I said that, um, you, um,
that you're,
you're,
you're minutes go into the next
month if you don't use them,
it's actually better than that.
They actually knocked you down on your
bill and then they credit you the next
month. So it's like they
actually charge you less money.
This is not even that they
give you more minutes,
you less so they take away
like you have a credit. Say,
if you have a plan and you,
your,
your plan is to use x amount of minutes
for x amount of dollars per month.
If you use less than that, they
will actually bill you less. I see.
They'll credit your next month.
Right? It's, I mean overpaid on us.
It's a great company and they use sprint.
So it's a major networks network backbone
without the contracts and all the
other craziness that goes along with,
uh, using cells for cell phone service.
It's really nuts. So we support
Tang. They're a cool company.
And if you go to rogan.ting.com you
can save 50 bucks of one of their many
Badass android devices. It's
really, if you're into technology,
it's fucking fascinating stuff.
We're also brought to you by
[inaudible] dot com that's, Oh,
Anne and I tea makers of Alpha brain.
What are you doing Bryan?
You scan the shit out of me.
I got to put too much Alpha brain
and my system for your sound effects.
What is Alpha brain? It's um,
it's most certainly is no miracle.
Okay. It's not if you're a
really dumb person. I'm so sorry.
But there's nothing you can do.
But what it can do for you is what really,
essentially all nutrients can
improve the way your body functions.
It's what your body needs to run.
And we live in a world where most of
us don't eat enough of the proper food.
We don't eat enough healthy
green leafy vegetables.
That's like one of the main ones. Um,
all sorts of different vegetables.
We don't drink enough
water. We, you know, we,
we took a lot of stupid
shit into our bodies.
So the fix that first before you start
taking any supplements before you just,
you know,
eat fucking two cheeseburgers and then
go take some shroom tech and want to work
out. It's not like that you should
take care of your body first.
That's number one.
Eat as much healthy food as possible.
Give yourself some cheat days, man. Give
yourself some days where you fuck off.
But for the most part, try to eat
healthy. You will feel better for sure.
And more importantly,
your mind will function better.
There's essential nutrients that your
mind needs to function at its optimal
level.
And what we've done with Alpha brain is
isolate those nutrients and give them to
you in the purest, most effective form
possible there is behind it. However,
I am way too stupid to be describing
that science because I really have no
education in any of these subjects and
it's really nonsense and Jibberish that
I've just memorize for people
far more intelligent than myself.
If you go to [inaudible] dot com
it'll all be explained to you.
There is Alpha brain, which is the
one that, uh, I, I talk about so much.
It's the one that I take before every
comedy show. I take it before podcasts.
It's, um, it's,
it's most certainly has a positive
effect on the mental function.
And I have so many of my friends addicted
to it. It's a some fascinating shit.
But if it doesn't work for you,
you get 100% of your money back.
Our first order of 30 pills and you
don't even have to return the product.
Just say this didn't work for me,
and then you get your money back.
Nobody wants you to be ripped off.
And if you use a code name Brogan,
you will save 10% off any and all orders
of all supplements that are available
through on it, including hemp force
protein, the hemp based protein,
which is legal and won't, you won't test
positive for marijuana. Don't sweat it.
It's not what it is. It's really, it's
a weird little loophole where it's like,
it's very similar to the marijuana plant,
but it does,
it's not psychoactive so you can eat
it and it's really healthy for you. Um,
hemp protein is really healthy. It's
what they use for fiber, for clothes,
like camp clothes.
But it's illegal to grow in America,
but you can buy it. But you got
to buy it with cash from Canada.
It's fucking squirrely set up
folks. So we get hemp prone, uh,
protein, the finest hemp hearts from
Canada. It's really hard to do it.
It's annoying because it takes jobs away
from US farmers, if I'm on it, could,
we would love to have a farm here in
America and grow hemp and hire people and
employ them. But we can't. We can't
because we have a corrupt government.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it's just,
it's just been around for so
long in this stupid wonky,
transparent bullshit form that we,
for whatever reason,
are stuck there and unless
less people talk about it,
it's going to stay that way.
And this is the problem folks.
It's nonsense that Hamsa legal,
it's nonsense.
It's not even related to the marijuana
as a psychoactive drug debate,
which is also nonsense grown people
telling you what the fuck to do.
But because of that nonsense, you can't
buy hemp very cheap. It's expensive stuff.
Use a code name broken,
save 10% we also have kettle bells.
We have a battle ropes, all different
things to get you fit in a functional way.
Uh, and by the way, all this
stuff is stuff that I use myself.
All of it is stuff that I've learned from
strength and conditioning coaches from
a guys that train people
for Jujitsu or MMA.
It's all like the best exercises to
a really sort of for functional form,
for functional strength, for strength,
where your whole body moves as one unit.
You know, these kettlebell
exercises, it's a, you're not this,
you're not isolating any
muscle groups really.
It's like you're using your entire
body and when you do that, it's like,
first of all, you feel great. It's great
to have like a body that works well.
It's great to be able to
move things. It's, I mean,
just forget the superficial way that
you would look. Just, it's great.
It's nice to have a
functional body that looking,
pick things up if you need the moved.
You know what I mean?
People don't think about it that way.
Where you essentially,
your body is like a race car. You could
choose how much horsepower to put in it.
Oh, I have to do is lift weights. If you
lift weights, you get more horsepower.
It's that simple. Brian,
Dj Brian on the mix.
Anyway. Um, we also have
BLENDTEC blenders coming in.
They should either be in today or
tomorrow. I think they're in already.
They're fucking fantastic. There's the
blenders that we saw we use on an iPhone.
We just decided to start selling them
like they're the best blenders. Yes,
they're awesome. They they, yeah. Though
I use a Vitamix, which is equally good.
Excellent, excellent blender.
But, uh, most of the consensus
was that blend texts.
I wonder if you could
blend a Vitamix with this,
break it up first, but I bet you could
just try one that pointed the blades,
couldn't blend the blades. Right. I
don't know what the fuck would happen.
Should it be chaos,
uh, on a.com folks and
also, uh, Jesus Christ, uh,
audible was the last one. I
love audible. audible.com if a,
let me pull up the euro URL real quick.
Lot of people are saying thank you for
introducing them to the Steve Martin Book,
uh, born standing up. Uh,
uh, they loved it. Yeah.
Because Steve Martin reads it and so it's
like listening to like a play on that.
It's great. I highly recommend it.
I like audible for like road trips.
I'll put it on my iPhone and just like
Bluetooth it over and listened to us.
People talk and fall asleep
while I'm driving. Yeah.
I'm a huge fan of books on tape.
Uh, when I used to use them,
a lot of road gigs, whenever to have
these long road gigs, it'd be painful.
I going to drive like three hours
up to Maine or something like that.
Back then they were all cassettes, but
I, I got into it and it's like, man,
it changes a boring drive
and does something wrong.
Really exciting. Okay. All right. That
was a mistake. These are ridiculous.
You look a little try. This is the
way it was supposed to sound like,
that's like a little car that's better.
That's way better.
Um,
they're all w,
but it was trying to say is that when
you're on a long boring ass drive or any
kind of commute, plane flight, whatever,
it can literally turn something that's
seemingly meaningless into an educational
experience and inspirational experience.
I mean,
that's the beauty of books on tape or
could just be like really educational,
you know? Um, I mean,
it's, uh, to me it's a,
it's an awesome resource that a
lot of people don't take. Pardon.
And,
uh,
it allows you to make productive
time and enjoyable time out of time.
That sucks. That fucking dumb ass commute
you have to do every day. You know,
when you, when you listen to an
excellent book on tape, man, it's a,
it really is. Um, to me it's,
it's a total game changer.
It makes it enjoyable. You actually get
home, you're like, how you feel? Great.
It just so fired up. You know, I've
sometimes gone home and, uh, you know,
taking the CD out and listen to a
book on tape in my house, you know,
and you could do that if you have an
iPhone hook up to your car too. I just,
I'll just continue it.
I get got rope 10. Um,
if you go to Joe Rogan,
Duh,
it's the wrong fucking URL.
audible.com backslash, uh, something
that didn't help at all.
Bull backs.
I think it's Joe Rogan.
Let's see. It's that, or it's, Joe
was trying to leave it hit a bump.
They say so it's not that.
Yeah.
I'm trying to look up Alison Shudi.
Yeah. Okay. It's Joe. That's what it is.
It's audible.com. Forward slash. Joe,
if you do it, you, uh, if you go there,
you can try audible free for 30
days and get a free audio book.
So it's an awesome resource.
Audible is one of the best sites
in the world when it comes to this.
It's like the,
the most prominent site in the world when
it comes and they've been around for a
long time
and the onset of Opiod,
Anthony shows when you were on there,
they have like back episodes of when
you ran or an opiate Anthony. So like,
like you can listen to it. Ari should
fear and us and everyone on, on,
on the opn yet they'd, they also have
a your cd's on here and shit like that.
So it's a good way to buy your stuff.
Yeah, it's just, it's a cool service.
It's a cool service that we
would like to set up. Uh,
I really enjoy the audio books and,
and you know,
of course shows like opie and Anthony,
great to be able to get to and
comedy cds and stuff like that.
It's just a huge variety
of things. But the, the
beautiful thing is if you go
to audible.com four slash Joe,
you could try it out free for 30 days
and get a free audio book,
right? Is that what it is? Yeah.
Something along those lines. Uh,
yes. That is exactly what it is.
All Right Ladies and gentlemen,
let's fucking get this show rolling.
This is the lamest
commercials we've ever done.
We need a little fire under our asses,
ladies and gentlemen.
The Great Alex Gray is here.
We're going to get the bottom of
some shit and figure some things out.
Good
experience,
Joe Rogan podcast all day.
If there is a man that is on more
dorm room walls than you,
it might be frank Frazetta but it's
only like if you count all time,
you know,
if you think about it like if as far as
like the 70s and eighties those poster
years, Frank Frazetta put in
some God damn numbers. You know,
that guy that he had some amazing stuff,
but you sir are right up there and
you are as far as like the psychedelic
community goes,
you're the only guy that I've ever
seen that I've looked at your work.
And I'm like, wow, that guy actually
like captured some of that. You, you,
you've actually grabbed some
of it and you've, uh, it's,
it's v for someone who has
an experienced,
uh,
a really intense psychedelic
breakthrough sort of a moment. They,
they, I don't know if they would
connect with your art work the same way.
It's beautiful. It's striking.
It's amazing and unique. But it's,
what's amazing to me about it
is that when I see your stuff,
it's like you've really captured
something somehow or another,
the, the, the unremembered bubble.
You remembered it enough or you
channeled it enough or whatever,
but you nail stuff,
man. Mean you're, that,
that one that you were just showing
the Hologram. Oh yeah. What is,
what is the cause one of my faves?
Yeah, it's one of my favorites.
The, uh, the, the Bardo
being, and then the, uh,
diamond being at, let's
say they angles here. Yeah.
There's a diamond being,
there's a bar that
there's the,
uh,
jewel being so see how they kind of like,
they,
uh,
it's like you have a little trans
dimensional portal and in a postcard.
Wow. That's amazing. That's beautiful.
That one right there, that one that,
that's yeah, that's totally damped. Yeah.
You nailed body who has had the
trip to me and experience, uh,
recognizes it.
And that's what's really fascinating
because it's impossible to actually
translate that trans dimensional
realm that enter dimensional,
uh, uh, infinitude.
And yet as crude as it is a
painting that's an authentic,
uh, transmission from that stain
will communicate to people.
And it astonishes me that,
uh,
I meet brothers and sisters all over
the world that say the same thing,
that they've been there, they've seen
that, they know where I'm painting from.
Have you ever had a thought in your
mind or a dream where somehow no,
other than the dream,
this has happened to me several times in
my life where an image, a really weird,
bizarre,
random image was recognized to me to
mean something or have some significant,
uh, play some significant part of
my life, whether it's some friends,
I know a place that I live, but it
would be imagery. It was really weird.
It like I looked at that imagery,
whatever it was,
it's strange geometric pattern and it
represented to me very clearly like this
aspect of my life, but only in a dream
form. It's visual poetry and I re,
I remember so many times it's going,
I got to wake up and I
got to write this down,
but I couldn't even write it down because
the shape was constantly moving in my
mind. Yeah. You know, it
had like, I was like, no,
but if I could just draw this image
with bill, that's what you did,
exactly what you drew that. Yeah. It's
kind of a compression of, of that.
That's for you. Of course. Thank you.
Yeah, you nailed man. Whatever it is
right there. Boom. The one
with the stripes, Holy Shit.
The skulls and the stripes.
That's insane, man. That's like,
that's as close to what a
real trip feels like as,
as possible.
And that's for anybody who has ever
had any sort of psychedelic experience.
That's the crazy thing about it at all.
After all rather is that it is possible.
It's hard to believe that it's possible.
Wouldn't you know,
I wanted to, um, give to you, uh,
the fourth book in America. Uh, you're,
you will be the fourth now.
This is,
you'll be the fourth person
to have seen, uh, this book,
which we just got an hour ago.
My wife and daughter and I saw it.
It was delivered to her door and we,
and we drove right over here. Wow.
So this is t you a brand new,
it won't be out in the United States for
another month and a half or something
like that. Wow. It is a net of being.
Wow. This is awesome. Thank
you very much. That's cool.
Wow.
This is incredible. I can't wait to go
through it. I'm going to set it down,
but I've been a fan of
your work for years, man.
I've got a big a piece of yours.
Um,
hanging up in my isolation tank room,
I have several of them.
I have a disco ball and
that isolation tank, no,
I think that's what it needs and really
take it over the edge. Um, the, um, uh,
the cosmic Christ,
it's another one of my favorites.
It's when did you start
doing this kind of art? I,
how long have you been doing this?
Oh,
let's see.
When I was at 21,
I had a kind of a crisis I think.
And I wasn't sure that I really wanted
to live any longer because I was really,
uh, um, I was really depressed.
And so,
and of course I did not believe
there was a spiritual reality at all.
And even though my,
my friends had a,
had a trip before me,
I never did because I was so miserable.
I just thought I'd go to hell
and who needs infinite hell?
And so anyway, at some point, uh,
I prayed to a god that I
didn't really believe existed.
And, uh, uh, that if you do exist, then I,
uh, I need a sign or, you
know, I'm through and,
and so within 24 hours,
I,
I'm saying goodbye to my
professor, uh, at art school.
And it was the last day of school,
like August 30th or something or, or, uh,
didn't, no, no, no. It was
like May 30th, May 30th. And,
and around the corner drives us a VW at,
and it's Sa,
the Scow, Alison who, uh, uh,
invites us to her graduate now it's kind
of like the end of school party and her
sister's in town. And so, uh,
so this professor picks me up later
that night and we go to this party.
And on the way he says,
I've got in this bottle,
some Kahlua and LSD.
And I said,
you know what? Basically, what the fuck?
And so I drank about half of it and,
uh, I got to the door and the
gout drinks the other half.
And I sit on her couch for the entire
journey almost. And, uh,
just sit there kind of weirdly inside
myself on one of her sculptures,
a couch with a,
with a soft figurine of a self portrait.
And so,
um,
when I closed my eyes inside,
and I've never had a trip like this sense,
but I was in the dark,
I could see I was in the dark,
but I was going toward the light because
there was this curling kind of mother
of Pearl,
like conch shell thing.
And I was like a tunnel with a light
coming just from around the side.
And, uh, and it was awesome because
it was, that was it. Of course,
this was God.
This was the light was God.
And I knew that even if I was in the dark,
I was going toward the light.
And I saw that all the
shades of gray connect,
both those opposites. And so I
changed my name to gray right then.
And so my art has always been kind of
trying to integrate the spectrum of
reality into a more holistic picture of,
uh,
the trans dimensional,
the visionary and the Trans transcendental
because the transcendental aren't
traditions, you know, the, all the
sacred arts of all the different world,
visionary cultures.
Cause all,
all religion comes from
the mystical experience.
And that's a visionary experience.
And you see it through all the, uh,
the mosques are beautifully worn,
a mentally patterned from the same
visionary mindscape that a Dmt user would
recognize.
And the same thing goes for the great
Christian masterpieces and all through a
world religion,
there are these waves that
have crystallized into these
visionary experiences of
angels, of demons, of all kinds
of worlds. And they're really,
uh, uh, it's,
it's the thing that connects all the
world religions is sacred art, you know?
And so we started thinking like,
wow,
there's needs to be a new kind of sacred
art that integrates this visionary
dimension of where all, all cultures, uh,
emanate from this vision at
the true visionary cultures.
Aminay from us. You, she see it in the
Shapebos, you see it in, uh, the, uh,
the we chose way.
You see it in so many of face,
uh,
patterns.
Isn't it a fascinating thing that art
is such an integral part of religion,
but it's not really discussed that way.
Religion is all about
ideology for most people.
But if you really stop and think
about it, the, the Christian artwork,
the Hindu artwork,
why do we care about,
we listened to the music or
watch the dance. You know, it's,
it's the way that people connect together.
It's a fascinating aspect though,
a really underappreciated aspect. The
aspect of religious art having influence.
Cause especially when you're stopping and
you're thinking about back when people
had no other transmissions, there was
no broadcast images. There's no video,
there was no photographs.
You literally had nothing or
incredibly stunning religious heart.
You know, that's it. You know,
there was nowhere else to go to see
iconography and was probably the most
impactful thing a person
could see back then.
Cause there'd be all this other
art. But the other art, you know,
whether it's a painting of a tree
or whatever the fuck it is, it's,
it's not going to be Jesus,
you know,
and someone who can paint an
incredibly detailed Jesus.
And if you stop and think about the time
in which these people were doing this,
you know, this is a, an
incredibly, like the,
like the access to
information was almost nil.
So this to them must have been
hugely impactful. The actual,
because you could see it and
it wasn't just a thought,
it wasn't just you talking about,
you can actually see this painting.
There are benchmarks in the evolution of
human consciousness as what they are so
strange that it's not really talked about
as being completely connected because
it's the underground mycelium of
visionary culture that unite everyone.
And that's what the religion
of the 21st century is,
I think is just your creativity,
you know,
and it's your way that you connect
with God however it is. And it's, uh,
it comes out.
You can look at the art,
you can see how the arts could
unite all world religions.
It's trans dimensional,
you know,
or Trans Trans Denominational
and tries to match now,
you know,
and that's what we're building at Kozum.
Even,
uh,
Scientology has lava exploding out
of a mountain and across with like
a crazy star thing in the
middle of it. Yeah. You know,
they have their own shit to deal Mormons.
The Mormons have religious artwork.
Oh Wow. They have temples and they're
quite extraordinary. So thank you.
And the, and the stories
themselves are works of art. No,
they are all religious.
Yes.
All the stories of all the founders
and mystics come from this visionary
experience. They have. I
think Joseph Smith though,
it's been pretty much proven
that it was a con man. Well,
he claimed to have a mystical experience.
That's what ignited the excitement,
the religious fervor of people.
He was also monitored, you know, and
there are a lot of people who hated him.
Obviously. He wished martyred
at like the Bob Gotten martyred,
the behind the Great Behi. Now there's,
I'm not familiar with that story.
Oh my God.
You know,
it's not the church of the sub genius
Bob. It's the, uh, it's the, uh,
founder of the Behi religion.
And where's that from? Uh,
unfortunately I ran
and I believe, and, uh,
they, so he was, uh, considered
a heretic and it was the,
I believe later 19th century
when he received the,
uh, understanding that there is a unity
of all world religions that we should
consort with people of all
religions. And that, uh,
that religion comes in waves of revelation
and he argued for the equality of,
uh, uh, women and men and the, uh,
the friendship of all
races. And so this, uh,
the understanding of how, uh, some
of the religions had failed us,
but not pointing out negatives,
but just positing, uh,
what could be as a higher
vision of a world religion.
It's fascinating to me that even
religions that are clearly made up,
like we're someone that sat out
to try to create a religion,
you can call it a cult or what have you,
but there's ones that they've done that
where even though you know that someone
invented it, it's still has a
positive impact on those people. Yeah.
So it's almost like even creating a
fake religion if done the right way,
imparts an important,
there's a problem of,
I think there's a problem with that is
really, yeah. Yeah. Well I definitely,
yeah, stuff based on false hoods
are not really religion. To me.
The, the, uh, the, the real
religion, uh, has to do with contact,
direct contact with God and that's,
that's then it comes out
through these stories and, uh,
the validity of any of the world
religions is through the direct contact.
But I know people that are Mormons that
have benefited tremendously from being
Mormon. I mean, I know some really
nice, friendly people and a lot of
that is attributed to their faith,
which brings them to these churches and
these communities. But that, you know,
that thing was created by a 14 year old
boy who said he found golden tablets
that were the last work of Jesus.
That is something that
was created by [inaudible]
bullshit. While it seems to be helping
those people, it might've been a dream.
Just like when you see picture images
that are spelling out something to you,
um, to him as a, as,
or a liar or a visionary
was, uh, you know,
given this owl chemical symbol,
it United the symbolism of Alchemy,
of Christianity and of native Americans.
Now this is a unique synthesis. This is
what Joseph Smith did. Yeah. Joseph, well,
I con of graphically,
right? The Chameleon,
the tablets that you could go
back to Hermes, Trismus justice,
the emerald tablet, or you could
look at the, uh, the tablets of the,
um, did Jewish, you know, Moses
tablets you could look at.
So there's a, uh, the Rosetta stone,
all of these written in stone is,
it's a very powerful symbol.
Okay. So, uh, and the,
the chameleon that, uh, doesn't, um, uh,
burn, you know, it's the,
it's an alchemical symbol. So
to us, the, the iconography,
the icon of a written and tablet is almost
like all sort of like profound ideas
will come in that form or many will come
in that form because it represents like
almost in our DNA a represents
something of significance.
Wow. Those, um,
those aligned with this vision,
this higher vision,
granted an American,
this was like one of the earliest,
um,
religions along with spiritualism,
born in America.
Now there's a differentiation
because you have your Middle Eastern,
which is mostly everything comes out
of there and you go a little, uh, uh,
to the side and to India.
And, uh, uh, this, this is it.
It didn't happen over here
to our knowledge. Of course,
the native people were wise beyond anyone,
but no one was listening to them.
No one took them seriously
because they were all heathens.
And so they were murdered. We
move, we move to an awesome,
awesome place upstate Hudson valley,
the town of Wappinger and the
WAPA venture people 400 years ago,
people,
the east side of the river,
all the way down to Manhattan or you know,
loosely federated tribes.
And you knew that, that cause
you're from Jersey. The, uh,
the Hudson River used to
be called the [inaudible].
Connie took before Henry Hudson.
Whoa. The mall he, Connie took,
that's way cooler. Ah, listen to what
it means. Listen to what it means,
that, uh, the great flow
that goes both ways.
Ooh, because it's a tie. It's a
tidal river. It's a moon river.
It is polled back and forth all
the way up to whoppin chair.
Why would they want to change that name?
So beautiful?
Because Henry Hudson put his
big Dick, uh, in history.
Henry Hudson changes himself.
Well, he got a chance. Well,
he did establish the
white, uh, folk in there.
And there were a few friendly exchanges
between Hudson and the wappinger.
Some of the very first encounters with
native people where the Wappinger with
the, uh, with Hudson and he
reports on it. And there was a,
there was an unfortunate incident
where, uh, his men had killed, uh,
some, uh, you know, just in fear. And, uh,
they kind of were forgiving for one
night and I think they all got drunk.
And then,
uh,
then like a war ensued
over a hundred years,
the entire tribe was like wiped out.
Oh my God.
And it was the genocide of a people
practically at Nais fragmented,
uh, this, uh, beautiful people.
It was over a hundred years. Oh
man, it was relentless. And uh,
and so the last time were driven out,
uh,
like the Cyo to trail the
trail of tree of tears.
And I heard like clay at here,
this native American brother came to
us after we acquired this land and want
banter because he felt it was always
wholly to the WAPA. Pinchers and uh,
so, you know, we put a big, uh,
Karen to honor the wappinger spirit.
And um,
he,
he talked about what happened to the wop
wappinger and how they were walked out
like through Ohio. They
had to march, you know,
and uh,
as they were going through Ohio,
they passed right down high
street from where I was born.
You're a burden on high street. That's
where I'm from. No, no, in Columbus,
Ohio where I'm from.
Yeah.
And so I put a self portrait,
like as one of my crazy ass art projects,
you know,
really early on I used to
work for a billboard, the
billboard place, and I said,
please let me do this. It's a dead bored
anyway, you know, nobody cares. You know,
it's on high street. And it was a, a self
portrait, but with half my hair shaved.
And uh, so, but it was a huge, um,
billboard kind of thing. But with his head
with very ambiguous like what is that?
And, uh, so high street
was the trail of tears.
And at that point,
Evan said that number of the Delaware
Indians began to absorb the brothers and
sisters of the Wappingers so
that they found a solace there.
And there was something very interesting
about the Delaware Indians was that
they had a particular kind of haircut,
uh,
that was only for the warriors
in order to keep their, uh,
their bow out of the hair.
It was a cut in half side, uh, you know,
was shaved bald and the other half was
long. Here's the, a, a billboard actually.
Yeah, that's, I'm from a
Worthington. Holy Crap.
Hey neighbor, how you do it? Well,
people are from Columbus. It's funny.
Yeah. We've run into so many people from
Ohio, Maynard's from Ohio I guess too.
Yeah, that's a, that's wild man. So you
didn't even know that when you did it.
Hell No. I had to move to
wappinger to find that out.
That's crazy. Wow. What
a what a sad, sad story.
And you know,
we uh,
we spend so little time thinking about
the culture of the people that lived here
before us.
It's so fascinating that we to on foot,
we want to honor them and um,
you know,
just say what,
what remarkable and a wonderful
people that they were.
Could you imagine mean if you have,
I mean I'm sure you have a match
because you live in this property.
If you thought about what it must have
been like to live there as them before
the white man arrived,
it must have been amazing there.
It must've been like avatar except no
flying dragons notail sex about a lot of
it was like,
I mean they were literally living off
the land and they knew how to do it and
they were sustainable and they had great
reverence for the land. They lived off.
You mean the, they were missing a lot
of inventions that western Manhattan.
But man, I bet. I bet they were pretty
fucking happy. For the most part.
There's a, I was in Disneyland
yesterday, man. It's a dis.
There is a disturbing trend of people
getting so fat that they have to be
wheeled around. Did you see South Park
last week? Did the whole thing about that?
You will go crazy, dude, I will
go crazy because it was weird.
It was weird. It was. It wasn't. There
were injuries. You weren't injured people.
They were just, or if they were
fucking injured, it was from being fat.
These people were enormous and they
were pushing them around these other,
there was a these little scooter things
taking them everywhere. I guess the,
the morbidly obese have not had
a proper vehicle in the past.
Perhaps it's a tab out vehicle they give
up. They just give up on life like fog.
I'm just going to scoot around. There's
so many of them, man. I mean it wasn't,
it was, I don't remember
seeing this when I was younger.
I don't remember seeing these numbers of
morbidly obese people on motor scooters
where they literally have
stopped walking like that. That's
too painful or they're too big to walk.
What,
what has numbed people to the point where,
uh,
that is an acceptable behavior?
Is it the kind of crap that fast food has,
uh,
uh, gone to or, uh, you
know, as part of it?
What do you think?
Uh,
there's,
there's certainly an issue with the
human body becoming addicted to unhealthy
foods. The look, me, myself, I
struggle with cheeseburgers and fries.
I love them. They're so delicious, but
I know it's like, it's super unhealthy,
but I try to limit it and then I put
a really healthy food in between that.
Some people don't do that.
They don't, and if you don't,
you can get caught up in this
addiction cycle was shit food.
Yeah.
I mean if you're,
if you know everybody who does that
artery read that, uh, old report,
you know, the change didn't. Yeah.
Yeah. Um, that's, that's a certainly a
good thing to read. But I mean, it's,
it's just, it's, it is weird.
The numb numbness is a good way
to describe it because it's just,
you just keep eating and you don't see it.
You know, you don't freak out. You know,
it's like somehow slowly but surely,
he just get to this insane point and
well, I mean, I love Walt Disney.
He said to me is an extraordinary
artist. And, and look at the,
uh,
amazing industry that's grown up
around and then the breakthroughs and,
and a motion picture technology,
all kinds of things that nature films,
you know, they, they used to
really, uh, deeply, uh, and, uh,
ubi works. Uh, they finally
are acknowledging his, uh,
you know, authorship basically it Mickey
mouse and things like that. So it's,
I think that they're an awesome
organization that has tried to, uh,
growing in a,
in a beautiful way and is a way,
a kind of the most generous a
representation of the Cherry on top of,
uh, American culture or something.
At the same time, you know, you like,
you really wonder like, well, well,
what does it actually mean? What is,
what is the religion of Disney as him
teaching us? Is it something about,
um, uh, passive observation
of reality, uh, and uh,
to,
uh,
kind of delight us with spectacles of our,
sort of delusional
understanding of certain things?
Or is it actually playing a,
an important kind of moral, um,
role? And I think that for
the most part, you know,
it's been a very benign to very positive,
uh,
organization I think. And as a,
and as art, it's unparalleled.
You know,
they do have some amazing cartoons. Stop
and think about it like a, the sorcerer,
what was the, uh, the first one
called Asia antisocial. My premise,
amazing, amazing piece of work. And if
you really stop and think about the time
in which that was released, I mean,
there was nothing like it before.
It was so groundbreaking.
It's hard for people to really understand.
Was This 1930s? Is that what that was?
Yeah, the look, the rides are amazing.
My kids have an awesome time. I love
Disneyland. That's not what I, I've just,
I'm freaking out about humans.
The first of all,
the fact that Disneyland is so packed,
it's crazy. So many human beings
in one area. It's incredible.
But, but you know what it's like,
it's like Faca for Americans. I mean,
is there anything else more Mac out
like in American wall of American?
Maybe but not really know
Disneyland is the spot.
Maybe a Disney world and Disneyland.
Yeah, those two. Yeah, maybe sea world,
but not even. No, no. Disney land.
It's like really where it's at.
Yeah.
It's incredible how,
and you know it was really kind of cool
about it was there's so many people
there. I mean it is insane. I never
saw one person raise their voice.
I didn't see one person get angry
with their kids. I didn't see,
I mean for as much as we like to talk
about the negative aspects of humans and
man lately on this podcast,
it's really been a bummer.
We've been having a lot of people like,
like reporters telling us about corruption
and the Congress people running for
Congress that are telling us about how
fucked up these new bills that are being
passed.
I mean you just over and over again you
keep hearing negative shit and we're
guilty of it too.
We were discussing it,
but when you go to Disneyland you
like all these people get along great.
Like look what's going on here.
They personally own positive vision.
Us a positive ability for all of us and
have always emphasized creativity as a
and the imagination as something
that is really important.
It's uh, it's amazing that they can
get that many people to be friendly.
You never hear about a gang fight
breaking out at Disneyland. No.
That's what kind of makes me mad though
with all those protestors though,
an Anaheim who are trying to
march to march towards that.
I kind of don't like that. I kind of
like, there's a lot of kids there,
you know? Why don't you just
get away from that? Yeah.
I think they were trying to do that,
I think is that we get the maximum amount
of attention. Fuck with that. You know,
like if my kids there and you start
doing bringing that to my kids, fuck you.
You know?
Okay.
You shouldn't say fuck you because all
they're trying to do was called light to
the fact that the kid was murdered by
a cob. Yeah. But you know what I mean?
Like don't bring it to her to that.
Why would you bring protests where
people are dressed up in military towards
kids? Well, I don't think when
they first started doing it,
there was no one dressed up in military.
That's how that happened
when they arrived.
So I think there's a little
bit of confusion there on
your part there, buddy now.
But I think just people
would just choose Anaheim,
but some things are that
are pouring then rides, man.
Some things are more important than rods
and getting people to pay attention.
Kids are more important than everything.
All tech kits or hey listen to this.
Don't think this is hurting the kids.
I think there's only reason the only
violence was being thrown at the
protestors. The protestors,
as far as I know,
didn't or weren't accused
of doing anything violent.
It was the police that
were showing up with,
unfortunately if that shooting rubber
bullets like we saw with Amber Lyon when
she was on the podcast, they
shot rubber bullets. I it.
But unfortunately you know how
there's going to be people,
especially like homeless people that
are joining these kinds of protests.
Just to be like fuck the police.
Cause I've, I saw it at, okay Brian,
what's a ship?
The thing where everyone sat outside
by Wall Street and occupy La.
When I went there I was like,
there's like a bunch of drunks,
a little different like this
and this was a community.
This particular instance in Anaheim
was a community responding to a murder.
It was violent. You know, they brought,
there was violence in Anaheim. It could,
there shouldn't be violence anywhere in
your kids. That's what I'm saying. Oh,
can I see what you're saying?
But I think in this case,
if somebody's trying to do violence,
they weren't violent.
The cops were violent towards
them. That's the accusation. Right?
As far as I understand it, you know
the, what we saw with that. Amber,
why just protests?
I don't know why he did eat it.
You thought about yourself innocent boy.
Why?
Because I was thinking about
how awesome Disneyland wise,
and I was like that when it was on the
last episode. I remember thinking that.
It is amazing.
But what I found fascinating about when,
one of the things that made me
smile when I was there, it was,
it really is amazing how well
people can get along if sort of,
gee, if the right kind of vibes
are generated and Disneyland,
it's like the exact right kind of vibe.
The only thing that
sucks is lines and lines.
Everybody just kind of laughs and jokes
around and kids play with each other.
That's not that big a deal. Hey
Man, that outlines very well.
Some kids complain and they say,
look,
we're going to have a great time when we
get on the Rod. It's going to be fine.
It's,
it's amazing how well people can get
along in that sort of environment.
People can say, well that's unrealistic.
Well, no, it's not unrealistic.
It's like we all cried
to get along, you know, instead
of think that, you know,
stepping outside of a place
like that, which I, you know,
say it one way or the other seems
a little more sacred to people. Uh,
and that may seem humorous in some ways,
but it's uh,
because it's focused positive. Yeah. Uh,
it's family oriented,
it a nondenominational and can be enjoyed.
And uh, you know, by, by anyone.
Yeah. It's a positive place. It's
fun. It's a fun place. But, and it is,
is sacred in that respect. It's
for, for children. It's such an a,
it's like a little religious experience
almost. Yeah. It's fun. I mean, it's like,
you see, it seems so much fun. See fairies
in places you see, you get a
taste of the visionary experience.
That's what they're trying to
create. It's a fully dynamic, uh,
pull you into a new way of seeing
reality kind of reorienting
experience. Yes. It's,
you know, it's like, oh,
well we just want the temples to be like
this because they're so exciting and
they're so fun and they're, some are
a little too threatening, but summer,
you know, sit depending
on the age, you know,
and so you learn and you can grow and
you can go and visit these things and
enjoy them with your children.
It's a wonderful thing. We need,
the pool is very psychedelic.
Have you been on the Winnie the Pooh ride?
Oh my goodness. Winnie
the Pooh is, first of all,
it's fascinating because my daughter,
she's only four and the
Winnie the Pooh was like,
have you get buckled down in this
thing and it's a slow ass ride.
So when w when it's over, she looks, when
she goes, why do we have seatbelts on?
She was like,
this is ridiculous.
Like a four year old is like you
don't need seat belts for this.
This is so stupid. Like why did
they make us it down? Um, but you,
you go through it and it's
all Winnie tripping. Okay.
Cause they do, they do it in
the guise of him falling asleep.
So when he is sitting there and then when
he ghost is doing flips like over him
and flips over him,
then we enter into this next room,
which is supposed to
represent Winnie's dreams.
And it saw neon tiggers knocked him over
and honeys everywhere and he's like,
this dreams amazing.
And he's literally in heaven.
I mean he's in this wonderful
psychedelic heaven where this like tiger,
who's neon colored completely like,
yeah, whole thing is white, you know,
lights. It happened in Dumbo
and it happened. Look, when you,
when you go through it,
when Winnie the Pooh has his,
has his psychedelic trip, like right
when he goes through and he falls asleep.
It's so obvious that like
acid based. Yeah. Yeah.
As mushrooms or something
there he starts tripping.
That's cool.
And then when he comes out of this dream,
you know, when he comes out of this, uh,
this, this falling asleep experience,
you see the next crazy room.
We look at this.
We need the pull is tripping his brains
off. This is a DMT trip. Look at this.
Look at pink Tigger neon paint.
Take a look at this.
About the fucker with giant orange,
orange heads and green arms
and honeys floating everywhere.
What is more psychedelic than this?
Look at this.
What the fuck are they trying to say?
This happens when you sleep.
It was just how many,
when you look at this,
if there's anything that's a psychedelic
trip, it is Goddamn Winnie the Pooh.
That should be the next thing. Kids
taking mushrooms and getting on the way.
The pool ride.
I bet you would freak the fuck out.
Just a pot cooking on this thing.
It's amazing.
That's great. Isn't that amazing? Wow.
That is clearly a psychedelic now.
So this is a walkthrough.
No, no, no, you're strapped in to,
my daughter was trying to express,
wow.
I tried to stretch a little bit
like a intestines or something.
Like you're being in his
imagination. Yes. Yeah.
And then the pimps you out at the end.
Yeah.
Normal. Yeah. Yeah.
No of the human animal
fusion is an archetype that's
tens of thousands of years.
What do you, uh, what do you think
that is? What's the human animal?
Anthropomorphic being there.
They were standing up. Yeah.
Like human beings kind of,
and like your association with them was
person to person in a way, but they,
they represent the character
of that creature, you know,
in a more humanoid,
anthropomorphic talking kind of way.
So that spirit in a
sense can speak to you.
Like you could be in contact
with other animal spirits,
but they would communicate to you and
in a certain language that you could
understand.
And so always,
I think the Schamens had been able to
have relations with these spirit beings.
And some of the earliest
cave art actually, uh,
of male figures are so cold sourcers
like the sourcer of Troy Fair.
And, uh, it is a, a horned, uh,
kind of deer type, uh,
being that is also, uh,
a man. Clearly I've got a penis. And, uh,
and so it's a fusion,
uh,
images of it online. Oh yeah. Right.
Can you find that the sourcer of Troy,
t, r I. S and then two,
or why us Frere. T. F. R.
E. R. E. S.
Don't guess,
if you didn't get the name
of Troy for air,
um, what do you think that is?
So you think that these are real,
real beings of these people were coming
in contact with through psychedelic
experiences.
It, it's possible, you know, and that, um,
or it's a portrait of the sourcer,
uh,
that is an integration of,
of yeah.
Of Human and animal qualities.
Now this is an enhanced,
uh, version of, it looks very similar
to that, but it's on the side of a cave.
And so they would,
um,
go into the code. The real one, Brian,
that's what they did is they traced it
so he could see what it actually looks
now. That's still amazing,
isn't it? So, so that whole arm,
there you go. So the archetype, wow,
that's the real one. Yeah. That's amazing.
That is amazing. It tells you quite
a few things. It tells you, uh, the
Shamonic, uh, you know, um,
x Ray Vision,
that is an ancient kind of quality of
vision that sometimes you appear to be
able to see through to the lifeline
are to the underlayment of the fabric,
of the body, of the physical
body to it, another kind of body.
But here it's mostly the fusion of the
human and animal archetype can see he's
got a Johnson
down there and I love his eyes.
Yeah. Yeah, I know. Isn't he awesome?
Completely awesome. Oh yeah. Yeah.
I got that business.
I got you like Matt Tail.
Yeah. He's like letting you
know. Yeah. Right. I know, but
he's not hard. So he's not,
no, no. Exactly. He's not needed. Yeah,
I can look behind. What
a strange, very strange.
What is, what is that getting out
sweet duty? That's a weird little,
it looks like a little mushroom.
Maybe it does. Maybe it is.
It's at mushroom up his ass. Could be
most of them coming out of his ass.
That's controlling his mind. Wow. I'm
sorry. How old, uh, can
you look at check the date?
I think it's at least 16,000,
16,000 years old. Yeah. They,
you know,
the most stable civilizations.
I think we're from the earliest a work
of art that I know of is this amazing
picture. I'm sure you've seen
it, of this goddess that, uh,
made out of mammoth ivory and it
looks like Dolly Parton or something.
It's an amazing, uh, you know,
buck some goddess and
it's so, uh, archetypal
it 40,000 years ago. Okay.
So they were still,
uh,
having these figurines like the Venus of
Willendorf and things like that tens of
thousands of years later.
Now there isn't a civilization on earth
that was more stable than the goddess
worshiping cultures. They were
agricultural. They were stable,
sustainable relationships with nature.
Is it just that human beings get to a
certain level of technological proficiency
and then they just start to fuck
each other up really easily.
And that's when things go wrong.
Well,
I think that there was a
remarkable breakthrough in
human consciousness that led
to, uh, a cerebral, uh, kind of,
uh,
you know,
fire of intelligence that led people to
begin to write and to write in such a
way that,
that they could commune with the Gods.
The earliest books were all
religious texts, you know,
6,000 years ago, you know, the
vedic hymns can the rig Veda,
you and you know, that's got
references to Soma. The, uh,
the most ancient of these, uh, uh,
psychedelic Brahma better than Indra.
Exactly. And connects us with the,
uh, immortality and, and uh, infinite,
no one knows by the way, what's so
my, it was correct. Exactly true. Now,
a lot of different people have
different consents, uh, conjectures,
I have no idea, but it
was clearly a kind of, um,
NT agentic a sacrament that allowed
people access to the realm of the divine.
One of the things that Mckenna said,
Terrence Mckenna.
So that was so fascinating to me.
And so when,
when you really stop and think about
the history of human culture and
psychedelic usages,
how could something that was so powerful
where they talked about it with great
reverence and their scripts,
how could that have gone away?
How could people forgotten what that
is? I mean, that's, it's amazing. Well,
we're very distractible
and, uh, we are not certain about the, um,
kind of, um, the game that we're in.
Is it an ego game or is,
uh,
or does love when the day, and, uh,
can you find your own
personal connection with,
uh, the creative source, you know, and,
uh,
if,
if your life is an opportunity for your
soul to read the tea leaves of your
reality and,
uh,
see whether it's in alignment with
your heart's purpose, you know,
uh, I mean, that's,
that's one of the other great reasons
that entheogens or sacraments or
meditation or Yoga and
meditation or any of,
uh,
many different ways of
accessing the imaginal realms.
I mean, making art is,
uh, that to me. And,
uh,
so as a spiritual practice,
thank you.
As a spiritual practice,
I think it has a much
in common with prayer.
If your artwork is in service of love
and truth and goodness and beauty,
and that would birth a new kind
of sacred art as well as these,
the access,
the now verifiable and repeatable access
to the visionary dimensions provided
by, uh, entheogens, which has
happened in numerous cultures,
including the Greek culture.
We have the foundation of Eastern
civilization and the vedic hymns,
uh, mentioning a psychedelic. Then
we look at the Greek tradition,
uh,
and the Eleusinian mysteries,
also a 1200 year old
rubbish. And that's er, uh,
and civilization really pretty long
time actually for civilizations and very
profoundly important. And all the
philosophers that we're familiar with,
Plato and Aristotle and Socrates would
have been initiates and the Eleusinian
mysteries. And so, uh,
these great thinkers that
form the foundation of,
of Western civilization had to haul,
uh,
taken a psychedelic and
uh, enabled them to, um,
commune with the Gods and with the ideals.
That's why Socrates whole
platonic forms or you know,
that he talks about the ideal realms,
uh,
that he describes are him clearly
and contact with a visionary reality.
One of the most famous tales about
Socrates is he walking across this square
like he did every day and he
stopped in the middle of the square.
He just like started talking
and arguing with this.
Um, Damon, he called it
his Damon and this was his,
this visionary being that he
communed with and had a day long,
24 hour exchange with in the
middle of the public square watts.
Yes.
He was crazy.
He was high as fuck.
It was crazy.
He might have just come back
from the Eleusinian mysteries,
ran to arrest him today. If
someone did that, they would,
but they knew he was frickin
sock gritty's they already knew,
give him space. And of course,
well, you know how he wound up,
you know, he was martyred. He, you know,
they didn't want him around, you know,
he corruption of the youth. And
uh, so he had to drink this poison.
Did he have sex with
a bunch of young boys?
It wasn't that also part of
his thing. What was, uh, uh,
I, you know, you could say,
where's the verification?
Right.
And where's the notion that that wasn't a,
uh,
something that was mutual and wears?
Just say that some of the gay, uh,
artists weren't the greatest and
art history, like Michelangelo,
like Leonardo,
does their gay nes suddenly make them bad?
I don't care if they did. Fuck, no,
I certainly does. But you know, it,
you know, might be an interesting
sidebar about history. Well,
that's what I was getting at.
Like what was it,
what was different about life back then?
That was like a really common thing
that men will have sex with young boys.
And even if it was a,
um,
a mutual thing where
it comes into question,
that's when obviously when you talking
about like really young people that you
can't really have a
mutual, you know, if you,
if you look at the ideals
that Socrates spoke of
truth and goodness and beauty and being
in contact with the ideal realms where
you commune with these, uh, you know,
angels and you get
communication from the highest,
you don't, uh, go about messing
like that. That happens at the,
at the kind of a perversion of,
you know,
what the intention of God is,
I believe.
But in terms of, of, uh,
reaching, uh, you know,
like he, he was, uh, just, he
was interested in what was just,
you know, he wasn't interested
in, in, uh, molestation.
So you feel that those are just false
charges against him or do you tap the
Austria is just tower he's going for, if,
you know,
what we like to do is trash all of our
heroes to make them as low as possible so
that you have no hope about
human character. And I think
that's shame. I have not.
I did not look at it that way.
When I heard this read this, I, I,
I kept hearing about this and many,
many civilizations.
I mean obviously the Greeks are famous
for the Romans were famous for it as well,
and my point was merely that was
sexuality viewed as a completely different
thing. I've been, the way we
view it today, I'll play. Yeah.
I think it's more that there was going
a molestation thing, I think are,
we're very repressed whether
we believe it or not,
and I'm not saying you should
start having sex with young people,
but we are incredibly repressed when
it comes to sexuality I suppose.
And I wonder if back then it was
just the ideal was different.
The, the, the, the literally the way you
thought of life was different and it's,
I think it's very hard for people.
I think you're right. Yeah.
I think it's very hard for people
to wrap their heads around that,
especially if it comes to something
as controversial as, oh my goodness,
it's still, you have to be a check.
Look at different, if you're,
if you're on an anthropology
article, uh, kind of, um,
fan and you really look at
different world cultures while yes,
you can see they've all got one head,
two arms,
two legs in general,
and have two sexes and uh,
come in a variety of colors and uh,
things.
But there are many different cultural
practices that work uniquely for each
little niche of a human
civilization or culture.
And it's astonishing
really. Yeah, it's, it's,
it's different in different Crinod
I'm sorry, in different times,
you know,
oh,
we believed this then and then now we
don't do blood letting so much anymore.
You know, what haven't
we done? Well, um, how,
how fascinating are you,
uh,
by the Maya and the Mayan culture and
there if there was ever a culture like so
severely obviously impacted by
psychedelics. It's really true.
It's like the whole culture.
I went to Chichen Eatsa,
I had a really, uh, educated, uh, guide.
It was a guy who was a local professor
who took us around and you know,
he taught like more openly than
I've ever heard anybody talk.
Cause I didn't even ask him.
Started talking about the psychedelic
drug rituals that they have and where they
would have of an explained
was a chocolate and mushrooms.
I don't know what it was. I believe
it was [inaudible] he froze the flesh
of the gods and they mixed the
chocolate and the mushrooms,
which has done to this day.
It's delicious.
Chocolate is so good for you too
by the way. I end. Yeah. Yeah.
Never had people who will never ever be
like raw cocoa, raw chocolate. Especially.
It's so, it's super high in
antioxidants. Like, you know, like,
well it was suicide but it has
also gotten, uh, the, uh, the,
I think the greatest endorsement
from the scientific community.
The Johns Hopkins Study.
Yes.
It corners and Ron Griffiss and
it confirming basically the same,
uh, uh, discovery from the Good Friday.
Cause maybe you can talk some sense into
my friend Brian then because my friend
Brian has done mushrooms a bunch of times
and he doesn't see any transformative
nature to the drug.
You think she's just taking go?
I think the first time
you, you, uh, take it,
it definitely opens up something in
your brain and makes you look at things
different.
But that will always stay open.
But I don't think anytime I
take mushrooms from now on it,
it might be something positive and
I'm on my gain something from it.
But it only like a week or
two later I'm back. You know,
I'm not like thinking about that one trip
I did two weeks ago and how much it's
changed my life. I'm more like, all right,
what's going on? You know, moving on,
you know,
like it's never
have and you haven't properly integrated
it then my friend because uh, and,
and actually,
uh,
dousing of one's consciousness into the
infinite is well worth considering about
how it relates to your everyday
reality. And, uh, what,
what does it say? You know, what is
the nature of consciousness? Who went,
who are you ultimately, and what, uh,
what does God want a view basically.
Yeah.
And I believe that your, you know,
your entire life is, uh, is uh,
basically, uh, an expression of
that. You know, it's a natural thing.
That's why we call,
you know,
art our religion or
creativity in any form is,
uh,
this sacred thing.
And because it's an expression of ourself,
this unique lens through which
the creative spirit passes,
not him.
Nah,
it's a wizard of Oz on mushrooms
with pink Floyd sinked up.
It's not like that, but that's the
cartoon level, man. That is like, I mean,
if you have any interest in this,
don't trip again until you read Stan
[inaudible] work. He's not reading shit.
Well, you see, if you, if you want to get
the most out of an experience like that,
a real opportunity to drop into infinite
love where you and God become one,
uh, you know, you beat your own
God self. It is possible. But,
uh,
in Roland Griffiths study,
it was a those who,
um,
actually we're interested in
contact with spiritual reality,
uh, who had an intention, uh,
about it spiritually inclined. People, uh,
were the ones who were
opened up 65% of the time.
Now each of them thought it was a positive
experience. Not all of them, you know,
got all the way to the mystical
experience, but the mystical experiences,
something pretty well defined.
And once a person actually
has that experience,
it's um,
it's affirmative.
It's so affirmative that you
reorient your life to relate to it.
And it may not change your outer
appearance of, of your life,
but it may empower it in some
way with hope and you know,
new kind of creative dreams that,
you know,
where's your creative flow coming from?
It's not just cashflow, it's got to be,
you know, connected with, um, whatever
you feel like your creative spirit is. I,
you know,
I have no problem with the word God,
but a lot of people
have trouble with that.
But I think that it's a legitimate way
of thinking of your relationship with a
spiritual reality.
Just to play devil's
advocate and you know,
only so that we could answer the
question. When you, when you, you,
you talk about these people that wanted
to have this experience and then had the
65% of them,
I mean,
how much of what we're talking about is
real and when you go into it with good
intentions to have some sort
of a visionary experience,
how much of it is your imagination?
How much of it is your
imagination acting with a,
a hallucinogenic drug to produce this
euphoric state that you think is visionary
contact or some sort of spiritual contact?
And how much of it could just be your
imagination mixed with drugs and this is
what you were looking for.
So your imagination created it for you.
And I'm not saying that that
is bad or good because I don't,
I have a feeling as I get older,
this makes more and more sense.
Even though it's harder
and harder to talk about,
I have a feeling that things
are neither real nor not real.
I have a feeling that the, the way we try
to define things in such simple terms,
it, I don't, I don't necessarily think
that the imagination is not real.
I think the imagination has
some sort of weird impact.
The mine detention and the creativity has
some sort of a weird impact on reality
of course. So that's what that is
the evolutionary edge of reality.
That creative spirit
is evolution in action.
Is that weirdly defined when you use
the word God, weirdly defined eye,
that's God's paintbrush. You
know, w who created all this,
not you are or me. You know, how much of,
of all of the spectacle of reality
did we really have a part in creating,
right? You know, but when you say
it, when you're saying, God, I,
I completely agree with you
that that is the most, uh,
the most beautiful way to God.
And probably the most,
if there is some sort of an overwhelming
power to this creative force,
they all describe the,
this sacred a reality as a
creative force. And uh, it,
uh, at the first moment, you
know, and it's the declaration,
let there be light.
Let there be, you know,
it's that it's the positive
affirmation of the creation, you know,
like what is it,
13.7 billion years ago,
there was an affirmation that took
place and where the living result of it,
the evolutionary wave has brought us
to this moment and it's an awesome,
awesome thing if you really
look at it, you know, you know,
4 billion years of evolution
on earth practically and,
and from blue green algae to human
beings gibbering at each other on a radio
podcast,
holy and we are to the future just like
Amoebas are absolutely no question about
a tiny,
one of my question was when I said does,
does it weirdly define it to use the
word God because the word God to a lot of
people does not mean that too. A lot of
people, and probably most of the world,
the world,
the word God means a deity who created
the earth and did it with certain
intentions and has rules that you have
to follow or there will be repercussions.
It's a completely different kind of God
than what you're describing. Well, it's,
it's, um, if one would
give themselves the,
the pleasure of being introduced
to the various faces of God,
you know, it's that, uh, to uh,
expand their mind beyond
the any dog don't,
uh,
really submit to the authority of any
religious dogma until you've examined
reality and it has to jive
with science. You know, your,
we have awesome tools now for actually
analyzing reality and measure shit.
So don't leave that out or, or
discounted or anything like that. And,
and uh,
so it has to have a sense of justice,
all the rest of the things
that religion has always had.
And that's why if we enacted our
creative spirits in the service of love,
and that's what happens at Disneyland,
you see that,
that there's a lot of love
and families to come what may,
and they yell at each other and they
don't get along and they're bitter and
whatnot,
but maybe for a few hours they can suspend
themselves and just delight in being
together. Uh, having a
visionary experience. It's,
it's a kind of a drop down visionary
experience that takes you outside of
yourself.
You get pulled in,
you lose your ego for a moment and join
in a collective imaginal experience.
And by the way,
ladies and gentlemen,
if you're playing the Joe Rogan experience
drinking game and you drink every
time someone says the word
experience today, you're dead.
You're not going to make it. Don't play
this shot. Stop it. Don't play this game.
Um, my, my just point was
that the word God has already,
it's like so many people.
I absolutely agree that,
that your concept of God must evolve.
It can't be stuck in a fundamentalist,
a definition.
Just like our definition
of religion as Bob Jesse,
my dear friend who, uh,
council on spiritual practices,
he said, Alex, you know,
there's a, a, a primary
religious experience
and then there's everything
else, you know. And,
and so the primary religious experience
was this contact with the divine.
And, uh, that was at
the heart, the mystic.
Every one of these world,
we said eastern and Western civilization
started with psychedelic reality.
Okay. Then look through all
the major world religions.
They all started with this visionary
experience. You know, uh, uh,
Moses sees a burning Bush with the
guy next to them have seen at burning.
I don't think so. It was his
neurons that were burning. He was,
he was ignited with this voice of God.
And with this experience of this fire,
not unlike Joseph Smith's fire,
a fire,
which is a visionary fire and know that
Jerusalem scholars have recently started
attributing that to a
psychedelic experience. Oh, well,
there's actually science behind it.
Apparently. The acacia tree, Aha. DMT
that Bush the Acacia Bushes, very
common in that area. The burning Bush.
He talks to God.
He finds out how eventually shit,
the DMT trip was the foundation
of this, uh, uh, Jewish.
I'm completely messiah.
Nothing like nothing. What
was the man growing out there?
Man? It's going down.
It's a good question.
Was that the growing on the sacred calf
that they were worshiping because like,
hey man, we eat the stuff, the goose
poop. You knew? Well, yeah. I mean,
no question. That was, uh, not, not that,
just that cows were worshiped because
of that. There was a sacker. They were,
you know, the, they,
they didn't eat them because they were
worshiping them because they created
these, these mushrooms that would let
them communicate with God. Exactly.
There can be no clearer when you're
talking about poor people in India,
there could be no clear example
of an entheogenic being a,
a connection to God that
then you literally don't
kill these animals that you
could use for food. You literally
start, but you do milk them and it,
and it's of interdependent,
kind of symbiotic,
um, positivity, you know,
for each one. And there's a,
a friendship not to develops between
the creature world and the human world,
this sense of comradery
with the creature world.
But in her case,
the actual creature in Disneyland,
we don't experience these creatures
all the time. We live in the cities.
We forget about our
connection with the creatures.
And so a trip to Disneyland may
remind you, even if, uh, you know,
in a anthropomorphized way,
um,
but they have really been working on
that too. They'll go down a, you know,
an open, uh, as zoo, uh,
element and try to try to care for
animals because they're part of the human
story.
The,
the animals are branches
on the evolutionary tree
that we're in relationship
with in this mighty evolutionary patchwork
that is the mycelium of consciousness
on the earth that's runs
through everybody. It is
pretty fascinating that we,
I mean, humans for the most part, think of
animals. You think of your dog, your cat,
and then some shit that's in a cage
somewhere that you can go stare at or
something that you can watch on the DVD.
But it really is fascinating when you
stop and think about the vast majority of
animals on this planet are not
us. Like, this is not our planet.
We are on this thing.
We've just figured out how to build these
really stunning structures that keep
them out for the most part.
But he has, like, there's,
they've been spawning
coyotes in Manhattan lately.
They've had several coyote
spottings in Manhattan. Wonderful.
Schamens coyotes are, yeah. So the cat
eaters, that's what they are. Yeah.
And rat eaters may be, and they're
coming in for help. You know,
and it's interesting to see
who thrives and who, uh,
declines in the animal populations
in these really difficult times.
I'm afraid we're going through
mostly caused by humans.
And as far as like the polluting,
of course,
the heating up of the
atmosphere and the, and the, um,
political suicide and, and,
and, you know, it's like,
I feel like,
uh,
it's the mighty mission of art to try
and uplift humanity beyond itself.
Destruction.
You know,
this is why all creators need to
really consider the ethical, um,
Stan that they're taking
in their culture and, uh,
not just, uh, be like
soldiers of fortune. Uh,
if you're selling your soul that cheaply,
you know,
if you're not taking people to some kind
of creative source and positive force
that is at the heart of
their own creative spirit.
If you're not trying to ignite and uplift
a people souls, what are you doing?
Why are you doing it? What about people
that would just try to be entertaining?
Is that uplifting someone's
soul? I mean, it should be IP.
Is it always at the expense of someone or
we, are we always making fun of people?
Is that the highest that we can reach
for in terms of our, of our, uh, I mean,
it doesn't hurt to disarm are kind of,
uh,
pompousness, you know, to
try and knock down everybody.
I think that there's positivity
in that, you know, so that
we're, you know, less, uh,
less pompous.
Uh,
some of my favorite humor is people
getting shit on cars. I so do I,
and we love the drama Kinison
and, oh, he's amazing. And, uh,
my friend Joey d is just yell at
people for serving them ranch dressing.
It's very negative, but it's hilarious.
It stirs things up. Well, you know,
we split off fiction. It's, it's,
it's like watching a movie with
fake violence in it. You know,
it's like watching people get
killed by Werewolf's. You know,
it doesn't really freak me out because
there's no where Wilson, it's not real.
I enjoy it. It's fun. It's
just a silly created piece of
art. It's a ride, you know,
and it's, you know, it's obviously
it's, somebody has expenses.
That guy who fucked up and
went in the basement, that
guy gets it, you know? Yeah.
But it still, I still enjoy
it. What does it feed in them?
What does that feed in comedy?
What is it?
What does it feed in the human soul?
Well,
it gives the human soul and escape for
a short amount of time and get some to
think about how ridiculous
something that someone just said,
even if it's really negative,
how preposterous and ridiculous it is,
especially done in the form
of standup comedy. And uh,
for me,
I just enjoy it as an art form.
I enjoy offensive comedy as an art form.
Like I enjoy Andrew dice clay.
I think he's hilarious. I treat him
like I treat a band that I enjoy.
I like what they're doing.
It's fun for me or you not zip.
It's a work of art.
It's certainly not if I wanted to talk
to him as a human being and that was what
his point of view on life represented.
No,
he's saying a bunch of shit that is really
silly and he's doing it to, you know,
in this character, cause he's knows it's
funny, he knows what he's doing. He's no,
he knows how to make
you laugh and it's not,
there's a big difference between that
and it representing his life philosophy,
representing who he is, the person. It's
art, you know, stand up philosophers.
Yeah, we do. And we don't. We
also just need comedy. You know,
there's plenty of philosophizing
going on in this podcast. You know,
if I applied this amount of
philosophy to my standup, I'd fucking,
no one would show up that people
would go to sleep after a while.
They built to come to command someone's
attention for an hour and 10 minutes.
You have to be funny and you have to
work on being funny and it's like you,
you can't have,
there's a certain amount of philosophy
that people will upset except,
and certain amount that if you try to
get a point across, you have to throw in,
you know, you, you really have to
explain people where you're coming from.
But the beautiful thing about the
podcast is when I was younger,
I always thought that like one day I would
have like a message, like as a comic,
you know the,
my comedy was so juvenile and ridiculous
and it's a lot of it is about sex and
stupid shit and I was like,
well someday I'll, I'll,
I'll evolve my comedy to the point
where it's like it's got like a message
because I admired certain
comics that had that.
But then as I got older and especially
as I started doing the podcast,
that became less and
less interesting to me.
Like I don't want to hear your
point of view through stand up.
It's just the same way.
I don't want to hear a complex
idea described through a song.
I want you to tell me,
tell me what you're really thinking.
And they explained to me over with
all the words possible in the most
descriptive and intricate and
objective and subjective way possible.
I want you to explain it
to me with your own work.
And you do that just through standup.
It's eliminated medium.
It's not what it's for. It's
for. It's for cracking jokes.
It's for making people laugh or if
it it's, it's at someone's expense.
The way I feel like it's tough shit.
You should be able to take the hit if
you're not looking at this instead of
feeling so serious about it.
Not only that,
I don't think it's good to enforce the
idea that people should be so fucking
sensitive when it comes to
people communicating about them.
I think there's far too many people that
get butthurt too easy in this country
and this world and this in this universe.
I think we have to be able to make fun
of things and you have to be able to
laugh at your own self. Right?
And when you, when you say, oh,
is it someone else's expense?
Sometimes they need that shit sound.
Some people are ridiculous.
All right.
Some people will look for every fucking
opportunity to cry or be negative or
whine about shit or do something stupid.
And those people,
I think it's culturally, it's important
to knock them down. It's important.
It's important to all laugh together
and it's important for them because if
they're doing ridiculous behavior and
you highlight that ridiculous behavior,
it benefits them because now
they get a chance to see that,
oh everybody thinks I'm a fucking dummy.
That's part of how we evolve consciousness
by becoming conscious of something
that appears to be a wrongdoing.
And if they can't accept that they,
all they're doing is dragging their
heels behind the evolution train.
That's what they're doing.
They're kicking at the dirt
trying to slow down the train.
They don't want to evolve themselves.
So they don't want to have anything.
Cause if you're making fun
of them unjustly, guess what?
It won't be funny if there's no
work, there's no truth. Your words,
it won't spontaneously make people laugh
because you've spoken a truth that no
one will say. And it scares the
crap out of people. You know,
like when Bill Hicks would let loose on
things, you know, it was like, oh my God,
can he say that? He said that, you know?
And every time he would say something,
you know, it was like, oh, oh my God, I
didn't know I was going there and there.
And it was a genius,
you know, of, of uh, uh,
carving territory. But he also,
if he, even if he painted hell,
he painted a little bit of heaven
too. And I love that about him. Yeah,
he really did. He had some great points
that weren't necessarily even funny,
but he wanted to make them when he,
when he was doing certain bits and,
but he was so interesting that
he carried it anyway. You know,
he had this like thing that
he wrote down, uh, look, uh,
the bill Hicks rules for standup or
something like that. I forget what it was,
but one of them was,
I'm paraphrasing
it that you didn't always have
to be funny. Just be interesting.
Like there's sometimes you,
you, you use the funny,
you get the funding there and then
you could tell him something that is
entertaining for a brief moment. Just
not necessarily funny. You know, it's a,
it's a tricky thing to do in stand up,
especially at not be preachy.
That's where shit gets annoying for
people to go see a comedian and they get
really preaching. Yeah. Yeah.
Because it's the intoxicant of the stage,
you know,
you're allowing people to have a massive
amount of control over the influence
that they have on you
to stand up on top with,
with a big spotlight on you and an echoey
voice and you know, magnified voice.
All of that is ridiculous.
So because you're in this situation there,
there comes a time where a lot of
people do things just because they want,
they want people to think they're smart,
they do things just because this is going
to get a big impact. This is going to,
and then they got to start getting
really preaching. And that's what it is.
It becomes disingenuous. You lose
this connection with the comic Ma.
I saw a lovely Tom on do something
extraordinary, you know, like,
uh,
signs of intelligent life on earth or
something like that or that was very good.
And, uh, even, you know, even though, uh,
it came out of love and self reflection
and that kind of thing is really rare
and I'm, all I'm doing is saying all
of culture is necessary and every,
the freedom of expression as as a
guaranteed absolute, I think in the,
uh,
and it's the only way that the creative
spirit can feel free enough to do
anything and to explore, uh,
and evolve into territory.
But if you're going to
then call it something like
sacred art or if you're going
to try and reintroduce,
cause my wife and I had these mystical
experiences and what are you going to do
then? Oh, I think I'm just going
to make art about the marketplace.
Cause that's the only thing that's
going on these days. You know?
Or maybe I should do some kind of vulgar,
uh,
transgressive thing to really
make a spectacle and things are,
or maybe I should, uh,
critique corporate, uh,
vacuity or something like that.
No, the mystical experience.
That's the most important thing.
And throughout history, uh,
see the reason that Bob,
Jesse said,
I don't give the fundamentalists
the word religion.
It's, you know, then, then, okay,
you can't evolve that concept. It's
too important to concept to let go of.
And uh,
so you have to evolve it.
You have to take it on and say,
okay,
there was a primary religious experience
that was the mystical experience that
was the visionary experience
that contacted, uh,
such as the Moses moment or
these various kinds of things.
Those things recur and
they continue. And, uh,
so there is a contact with a sacred
reality. And if we look at love,
just people still believe in
love and they feel it from Ah,
they're kids and thinks now that
means love is a cosmic force,
God or Creator,
whatever name you want to say,
or just the big bang
brought us. And in a, uh,
if anybody looks at, uh, the, uh,
amount of intelligence that it
goes to create a cell, you know,
Dr. Hoffman, Albert Hoffman, uh,
discover of LSD use to, uh, talk about,
do you think it would be possible for the
parts of a cathedral to be laid out on
a football field and to assemble
themselves into a cathedral?
Now, uh, you think of the unlikelihood
of that even given the, you know,
like an infinite time and you know
that it takes intelligence to build a
cathedral.
And he said a self reproducing cell is
much more difficult to construct than a
cathedral. And it is done in such a, um,
my microscopic way that,
uh,
you have to,
I a good scientist would
simply infer that, uh, the,
uh, intelligence, uh,
that constructed the
universe is at work in,
in so many systems that we see around us.
And uh,
you would even if you,
part of your small mind is absorbed with
the daily bullshit that comes floating
by you're a screen and you get upset
about it and you get hooked into your
emotions and all that stuff
on the background reality.
If you could just lean away
from the bullshit and, uh,
tap into the infinite,
that is always there.
The divine creative spirit
that really turns people on.
That's the thing that people want to
experience. The ecstasy of creation,
you know,
and when you're even gardening or when
you're cooking a new kind of soup,
or you're being creative, you're
happier. You're not thinking about the,
the thing that she said you are,
the,
or the thing that he did or,
or how terrible the world is
or anything like that. You're,
you've transcended the
chatter of the mind,
Bruh.
You know,
briefly and entered a creative flow that
is an intuitive flow that is just a,
just a plane of consciousness, higher, uh,
than the most of the current,
uh,
video screens that people are tapped into.
So if you could just begin to lean away
from that mental stuff and back into
the, the, the creation that brought
us here, then you'd see like,
wow, okay, things aren't really
so fucked up actually, you know?
Okay.
So we blow it.
Look at the magnificence of this,
um,
intelligent,
uh,
evolution to a point where we have,
even though we don't know what
reality is and it, and it,
this part of the imagination and
consciousness, these are great mysteries.
That's, you know, that we
are God speaking to God.
We're consciousness.
Uh,
speaking to consciousness
is the way that I see you.
You're tapped into so many networks.
You're part of a wider intelligence that
in circles the globe and that listens
avidly for your independent,
uh,
advocacy for points of view that
are very marginalized in society.
It's an extremely important stand to
take as a cultural hero to many that you,
uh, uh, we'll acknowledge certain
things that are not popular,
but you feel it's important to say.
So your work comes from a place of the
heart and a place of justice and a place
of a kind of righteous understanding
of the multiple dimensions that we all
dwell within.
Well, it also, my,
my point of view comes from a person that
feels that like how I know myself and
my, uh, tendencies to,
to get in bad patterns in my own life
and how I've overcome that and how I've
sort of molded my mind and changed
the way I thought about just reality,
my interactions with human beings,
all these things.
I know that I'm not unique
in my ability to do that.
I know that a lot of people have done
that. I can do that and are doing that.
And one of the things that's
been the most positive, uh,
benefit of this podcast for sure is
running into so many people that have said
that listening to these conversations and,
and,
and taking in these
different points of view,
these well-considered points of view has,
have actually benefited their lives,
changed their lives. People are eating
healthy. Isn't that awesome? Exercising?
Yeah.
It's direct to transformation.
It's, it's the, um,
I guess the fourth quadrant of how,
uh,
art and a podcast as a work of art.
Yeah.
It's not only visually
beautiful, but, uh, you know, uh,
Brian's been weaving in the sound effects
and that it's a work of art that's not
art. Don't tell him that.
Sorry. Okay. Okay. But doing,
I don't want to inflate anyway,
but I'm saying
hour. We'll just be none of that.
Don't, don't, don't, don't encourage
them. Oh, you son of a bitch.
He's got the Shaman's rattle. That
is the Shaman's rattle. Right?
Is it shaman or Shaman? Uh, I've,
I've used both at varying times.
Yeah. It's a tricky one.
It's like Bahrain, Bahrain.
Um, so you're, you're, you,
this gentleman who you quoted
about the use of the word religion,
don't give it up to the fundamentalists
who feel the same way about the word God.
It's like, don't give it to people
that have a narrow definition of it,
just use it, use it.
Even though there is a
standard definition that a lot of people
sort of think, oh, your religious,
are you a Christian sir?
Do you believe Jesus is your savior?
And then things get strange.
Well that,
yeah,
the ideology can in small in
us and it absolutely does.
And so, uh, the real religion,
the primary religious experience
is direct contact of self with God.
Now that is still valid and important.
And then the ability to let go and
reach these strange realms of higher
consciousness that are available with
and without help from any sort of
entheogens. Absolutely. Prayer and
meditation alone as the Royal Road,
you know, uh, the mine is very variable.
It's very variable in its frequencies.
It's very variable in where
you can take it. And, uh, my,
my own experiments with
a [inaudible] experience,
a part of my life is isolation tanks.
A huge part of my,
my development as a human,
that's a fabulous kind
of late 20th century, uh,
uh, addition to spiritual
practices. And unfortunately really,
really, uh, found it.
And he was one of the psychedelic
fathers of, um, this, I,
I see,
by the way, I should say something about
Lilly, but just came out today. They're,
they're showing me on Twitter.
It's going crazy to ketamine
used to cure depression. Wow.
They're saying that it's one of
the most effective, cute uses of a,
a cures for depression.
They've vibraphone really
simply one dose.
One dose has an impact at Saint John.
They were saying that for sure,
but, uh, you know, uh, I don't,
I don't know exactly what they're
claiming all he have vitamin B,
vitamin,
fabulous proponent of ketamine.
My God, I, well, you know, ketamine
has an interesting kind of, um,
shadow side to you that I've
seen. Uh, it's very dumb, yeah.
For people. And I, uh,
I never saw that in the classic hose
and agendas that were psilocybin or,
um,
even LSD or DMT.
They're not really addictive in the,
in the, uh, kind of strict sense.
So Ketamine is one of those
interesting new substances.
Uh,
it was extensively studied and the 60s
and the Vietnam War and used actually as
a battlefield and Dickerman and uh,
then a small amounts of it snorted or
smoked and various things like that take
people into these dimensional,
I,
it's kind of like a catapult for your
consciousness. It goes flinging out, uh,
if you're laying down, uh, uh, into, uh,
what seems like a very rapid motion
of your consciousness going very fast,
even though you're laying
down and over a texture,
a kind of a vast texture. And, uh, we,
we had these kind of
openings into the void, uh,
that were very profound and
very, uh, heart opening in a way.
It is a, um, a horrible club drug though.
It's used very sparingly and it
should be treated with great respect.
I know, but yeah, I never heard a, uh,
like I had a number of, of
friends. I never got into it,
frankly, you know, I d uh,
we were injected with it I think a couple
of times, like back in the 70s. And,
uh, it was, uh, you know, it
was an available thing and, uh,
and a psychiatrist gave us
that experience and it was, um,
it was profound.
My friend Todd Mccormick,
do you know Todd marijuana activists?
Very interesting guy.
He got injected by John Lilly himself
with ketamine in Lily's isolation tank and
he went deep and he was, he's kind of
freaking out in the town. So Lilly shoots,
he shoots ketamine into himself, gets
it another tank and goes and visits him.
Whoa.
Yeah.
What that is,
that is high tech shamanism is high
tech shamanism that, uh, you know,
hey,
I ventured into the coincidence control
here that I'm not familiar with and
it's, I'm really freaking out. And, uh,
so I mean, he might've even, uh, had to,
uh,
you know,
pay a little something to his
buddies who run the machines,
uh, to, uh, get his friend back.
What would you, what happened?
What a piece of your consciousness
would you have to give up? Oh, uh, no.
It was just like a, hey,
hey, I'll give you my sex.
I'll give you my sex. Yeah. Those
change from male to female. Really?
John Willy,
he changed from male to female. I believe
he did it. Whoa, Whoa, Whoa, whoa.
So you're saying that my friend Todd
McCormack in his irresponsible use of
ketamine now, so now you just said, well,
I don't mean it. I'm just fantasizing.
Is that like a dude that dude,
did he do that? I don't think
it had anything to do with
your friend at all. Okay.
Uh, it was for him, I'm sure, and
have a creative evolutionary step.
So Ketamine,
essentially,
he marched toward the divine
feminine and embraced it.
That's interesting.
Well,
a lot of people believe that that is
the number one problem with the world is
the expression of the fact of
the divine feminine. Absolutely.
The fact he was Austrian exists in the
intelligent life form that is evolving
past pass through the, the,
the actual form of the,
that we recognize matter in,
into a nuclear haves. Like what,
what else was he then,
if, if people are profits,
if people are profits
of something,
he was a prophet of transformation and
the use of all technology available for
accessing the human bio computer
and a coincidence control.
Right. And so he really
believed in a spiritual reality,
but it was a completely informed by a
Rica and all the rest of the systems that
he was familiar with.
But I think a very legitimate,
and one of the most densely
detailed descriptions from, uh, uh,
you know,
uh,
this trans dimensional
realm that we currently have
and his incredible invention
of the isolation all night.
God was such a brilliant,
brilliant invention. Yeah.
He was trying to figure out
how to separate the mind
from the sensory input of
the body and he couldn't get there with
meditation, couldn't get there with yoga.
He couldn't, couldn't quite get there.
He was always conscious of his body.
So he figured out how to do this in the
first sensory deprivation tank was like
a scuba tank or you had like a,
a helmet,
scuba helmet and you would
float like from your neck.
They use that in an altered states, you
know, to uh, describe initially the first,
it was pretty chronological
in that respect.
They started off with that sort of a once,
right.
And then went to the horizontal once
they figured out how to use salt in it.
But his old ones, he used to have
like waste evacuation systems. Yeah.
Well he would shit and Piss
in the tank for a long, long
time. You know, the uh, you know,
because he was interested in long
term immersion. Yeah. And uh,
this was basically a replication of
something that had been done for many
centuries. I'm sure you're
familiar with it. You know,
the young teat practice and a Tibetan
Buddhism is all about the dark retreat.
You go into the dark and uh, yes, uh, uh,
you know,
all these things that he talks about
that you're still dealing with gravity,
blah, blah, blah. Uh, but
the intention is the same,
to remove all distractions and
to be surrounded by darkness.
Well, I wouldn't even call it a
distraction to be awake. Um, you know,
and you could lose consciousness of
your body so much and are able to access
your imagination.
Now,
Ibn Arabi thought that at,
and he was a Sufi mystic.
Uh, my favorite, uh,
your favorite Sufi missed tab 10 wow.
Room.
He wouldn't be right next to have cars,
you know,
but Eben and Robbie was the most scholarly
and he called the imagination your
angel.
That is the place where God meets God.
And so, uh, that,
that is the visionary
mystical experience that,
uh, runs through all world
religions and he details it.
And there are celestial hierarchies that,
uh,
Plotinus describes in exactly the
same way they had a cross cultural,
although they were writing it at
different times. It wasn't dissemination.
It was all direct knowledge.
And, uh, so these were,
these were people that were getting
it from the highest, uh, command.
And it came through there.
Um,
it came through their unique
lens of their language.
And so they each had unique prayers to
be in contact with this creative force.
And,
uh,
he really did emphasize the
sacredness of the divine feminine.
And he's, yes, no [inaudible]
been a rock. And, uh,
so the great mystics, I've quite often
done the same thing, you know, I mean,
what do we have more art of a
goddess sculptures, you know,
the goddess is the symbol of
beauty as symbol of love, uh,
for humanity. And although it gets
perverted and things like that,
if you step back and just look at
the flow of art history, you know,
back from the 40,000 years ago to today,
what is celebrated the beauty of
the divine feminine and a worshiped,
really, really, truly new age. Shamanism,
the creation of this sensory deprivation
tank is the creation of something that
allows you to take this practice of
solitude and darkness to a completely new
level and literally remove the body,
remove the body from the equation. And,
uh, Lily Korea, you're still aware
of the smell and you're still aware,
but it's much less. Not really cause
all factory sense is only detect change.
As long as you don't Fart in the tank,
you're not aware of the smell because you
won't be aware of anything. Yeah. Your,
your, your nose will stop receiving any
changes in see the one you've got? Yeah.
It's a, it's is created by this
guy, a crash from the float lab.
A float lab is in Venice and it's
the best place in the country. Wrong.
He's a really mad scientist
when it comes to it.
There's the filtration
systems that he uses or the,
the highest standard and he's pushing
for like an industry standard to try to
get people to start taking these things
seriously as far as like how you can
clean the water to make sure that
you could use them commercially. Yes.
We know lots about,
have you,
have you been to Munich and to the float?
Uh,
experienced though? I've never been
to Munich and, well maybe I have,
well it was in Germany. I forgot where I
was actually. Sorry. It was for a fight.
What happens is you go
into this huge tank,
it's like a king size bed,
but bigger of water and
eight inches deep I guess.
And so you lay down and it's the salt
and it's really warm and nice and it goes
down to a very, you know, like ultra
marine blue doesn't go totally plaque.
Oh. And there's, and you can close
your eyes and most of the end,
and it doesn't change at all and it's,
it's just the most pleasant,
uh, an amazing, uh,
it relaxation kind of experience.
And he's woven it into the German
businessman. Now they, you know,
on lunch hour they'll come in and say,
wow
man, I really need to unwind. And it's,
let's just like a half hour
later they're like, whoa.
It's just like they were meditating.
It does wonders for me,
especially after I do Jujitsu classes
and I'm exhausted and strained out.
They'd like, it lengthens your
body, like your, your, your muscles.
They contract and tighten it up.
And what I mean by lengthen is,
is they relax and sort of extend the,
they relax and pull away.
Like it,
everything feels like it sort of just
takes a big deep breath like all of your
tissue. Like Ah, ah, it relieves
so much tension. It's it,
by the way, it also, it
benefits your body. Um,
it's one of the best sources of
magnesium because I'm at the magnesium is
entering your body through
the Epsom salts and your skin.
It's actually very healthy for you.
Very interesting. We know the, uh,
the filtration system that they
had was unique and patented.
John Daly's no, the one
in Germany, in German.
And they were, they saw themselves
as continuing to work. You know,
John's obvious, you know, uh,
invention and uh,
uh,
move it forward also in a
similar way to your friend, uh,
is doing out there in Venice.
That sounds like a great idea though,
to have just a really light blue
so you can even open your eyes.
And just the idea of doing it for
as a short term relaxation thing,
that would be very pleasant.
It's, it's extremely uplifting.
And probably the caller has something
to do with it. You know, I love blue,
like a for professional pool.
They found out that the color,
they'll a light blue,
a light calming blue,
like a blue sky is like the best
color for seeing objects around it.
As far as like seeing edges, the edges
of the ball and things like that.
That light blue is what it
really just a appeals to the eye.
I use these two things. It was green,
it was green for the longest time,
but now they uh, they go with light
blue. That that feeling. Yeah,
the feeling of floating also,
um,
the release of all the input that's
coming in from the body allows you to take
in information better.
And what crash has been working on over
at the float lab is what he calls a
cellular influenced device.
And the idea behind it is it is a screen
that is fits in front of your, your,
your visual peripheral,
like from here to here.
And it is the lowest emission of
light that's physically possible.
So you literally don't see the
edges of the, the television at all.
You see nothing other than
whatever is being broadcast.
They figured out how tuned that in.
It took him years to figure this out.
And he has these speakers that are in
the water literally on either side of
right here.
They're all,
it's all sealed up and so
they're underwater and you're
in this thing and first
of all, the sound moves, the
water, it pulsates the water.
So you feel the sound, you feel his
toes. He, yeah, you do whatever you want.
I mean, would crash is trying to do
is get people to start coding, uh,
documentaries
and uh,
instructionals to it cause he thinks it
will speed up learning by a staggering
amount.
That's a remarkable it to
immediate kinesthetic. Um, yeah.
Uh, kind of taking it on a
cellular level in farming your,
your cells all over.
And also the retention is
just far stronger and greater
because the fact there's
no distractions while it's going
on. It's the same as, I mean,
in theory this all needs to be tested.
But I can tell you that as far as just
your sheer horsepower for concentration,
to me, there's never been anything like
it in my life other than psychedelic
experiences. But I consider it a very
psychedelic experience. And you know,
probably came to him in that state
and it was used to study that a thing.
That's how the Shama and say, you know,
like, uh, the plants told us, you know,
it was like the,
uh,
he was one of the first really a
scientist to do deep studies with Lsd.
I find that fascinating and I find
that so hard to believe. Uh, I don't,
I also find it amazing how few scientists
today openly discussed psychedelic
experiences and are enthusiastic. They'll
be ostracized. Isn't that amazing?
It's sad. The same reason
that more artists don't talk
about it either. It's, uh,
it's, they're not mutually
exclusive. You know,
that people have to understand
that silly behavior, yes.
Can Be attributed to the recreational
drugs or recreational drug use at a one
that's not what we're talking about.
And B,
just because someone is involved in
something that other people were using
recreational doesn't mean there's not
some massive benefit to it that can be
discussed by scientists on, uh,
you know, a really scholarly level.
There's something going on that can
truly benefit humanity by harnessing a
substance that most certainly help
people access their expanded states of
awareness. Now that is what Dr. Hoffman
wanted. And I quote him at length,
uh,
on his hundred and first birthday,
he wrote the most remarkable thing
about the promise of the entheogenic
sacraments and about how he hoped,
because he always felt tremendously
guilty for anyone who had, uh,
you know, uh, taken a wrong turn
or not been a, you know, headed,
it had catalyze there
a predisposition to a,
to a psychotic state. Borderline
personality should avoid it entirely.
People who have a history of mental
illness, you know, without, uh,
professional, uh, use, they should
avoid these things for sure.
But sometimes people take them. And so
it, it haunted him horribly. And he, he,
he was never an advocate, but he,
at the end of his life, really,
you know, he kind of
told people about it. He,
he on stage would say that, you know, I,
I sent the size did in
1938, uh, we tested it
on animals. Nothing happened, you
know, and then five years later,
you know, in, uh, April, he,
he starts to hear a voice that asks
him to resynthesize this particular
molecule. Now he sent the sizes
thousands and thousands of molecules,
but he said,
never before had he heard that voice
calling him to do a particular thing.
So he did it. And, uh, then, uh,
April 19th, when he finally, uh,
basically dosed himself in 1943,
um,
at four 20, really? Yeah. Have Four,
19 at 4:20 PM pm, he, uh,
in his journal, he writes a, that
was his, uh, that's when he took it.
And, uh, the origin of four 20, no,
no, it's not. It makes sense. No,
it isn't. But it's an interesting
coincidence. Yeah. And, uh,
so I mean,
it ha,
it may have had some
sequential elegance in his own,
uh,
journal writing.
It wasn't randomly that he chose that
time to do it because it was an experiment
that he was wondering about.
But he,
but he brewed up the tiniest
amount that any, uh, you know,
that is for sure not active by
any substance known to humanity.
Uh, if you take 250
million, 70 gram, you know,
nothing happens with anything that's,
that's like, uh, uh, what do they call it?
Homeopathy, you know,
it's that kind of dosage.
But little did he know that he had
stumbled upon the most potent psychoactive
substance of all times. You
know, it's, uh, you know,
Co many times, uh, more potent
and powerful than any other,
a sacrament in those
tiny mouths. And so, um,
he was catapulted into a, uh, uh, a
kind of chaos. He thought he was dying,
of course. So, you know, and, and he just
didn't want to die in the lab. We would,
you want it to just go
home, you know, to die.
And so he was freaking out feeling for
sure he had poisoned himself and he and
his assistant rode their bicycles back.
And of course,
that's why they call it bicycle
day, you know, uh, four 19.
And uh, that he made it home and
then they called, it was April 19th,
April 19th. It was 1943 at four 20. Yes.
Yes. That there was, uh, uh, I,
I did a painting and it's in the net of
being book. You need to bet the lottery.
We need to call, put some
numbers on. Well, you know
what happened that same day?
Probably around the same time. Well, well,
there was a Warsaw ghetto uprising
that happened in the wake of the Nazis
wanting to burn down the war.
So ghetto Warsaw ghetto,
and it never happened before.
There was a spike in the novelty,
a curve that day that was off the charts.
And,
uh, they, it, it led to a siege. It
never happened and never happened since.
Whoa. What the fuck is up with that?
The number. Isn't that interesting?
Isn't that interesting? Do you do, does
that make sense? It's a synchronicity.
That's just a interesting, the, you
know, something I've been noticing a,
and I can't explain it at all,
but it's just one of those mystery things.
Like you were saying, like in your dream,
you see these various things, you know,
they're, they're saying something, they're
all, it's almost like God is a Punster,
you know,
and putting visionable rebus says
us for this is a visual language,
you know,
in front of us.
Have you ever looked into all this
stuff that's going on right now in,
in physics where all these uh,
different scientists are proposing?
The idea that we're living inside of a
simulation and it's becoming more and
more prominent today.
I got a new thing,
technology review.com a new thing
published by Mit and this was a sent to me
through Twitter. So of course I
had to investigate it because I,
I'm inundated by this shit.
Like,
literally every day there's some new study
or new proposal about the world being
some sort of the universe, the reality
being some sort of a simulation.
When you see shit like the number four
20 coming up over and over again for 19
and four 20. Do you
ever stop and go, well,
maybe that's just the way it was written.
It's the cosmic code.
It's the cosmic wink,
you know,
there are so many correspondences.
Uh, I feel like the, uh,
what did, what happened to psychedelic
culture after that time, uh,
you know, was, uh, there, there came
a time of tremendous repression,
but first there was scientific study.
So they actually established the true
merits of these substances prior to them
becoming illegal,
illegal for political reasons,
by the way, you know? Hmm. Uh, not,
not for,
not and it,
and I think it's anti American because
America is all about freedom of religion
and freedom of point of view. And
as Terence Mckenna says, you know,
there's nothing ever been a key.
I deuced against them except that
they give people funny ideas. Yeah.
Well,
your definition of America,
much like a definition of God is not the
popular one as far as the rest of the
world.
And I think [inaudible] represents,
I think of it I'll get with Terry Monster.
Exactly. It's Americorp's,
that's what I call it.
AMERICORP's is that what
America has become, right?
It's a living death that being perpetrated
on the world and it's because of of
this, uh, uh, you know,
cause out, you know,
of this hole to the
military industrial complex.
Eisenhower warned us about
it. She was going to say that.
Yeah. And so, so, you know,
there are various reformers in
government that are trying, you know,
really trying to shift things, but
they're massive forces, you know,
they are cons as the gnostics would say,
you know,
that are kind of dragging their
heels in the evolutionary bell curve.
They haven't gotten the message that
we're all a unity and that we need to now
think about how we can
best preserve the life web,
not how we can destroy it and make profits
for a few years while we watched the
weather, uh, go haywire.
There's never before been
a clear indication that the
people who are in charge
are not, they're not tuned into
the Internet. The they, they,
they came about this way.
They created this way long before there
was an internet and this is how it's
always been done. And now that
it's being exposed all around them,
they're still clinging to this archaic
notion of non connection, right?
This archaic notion that
all of your actions,
all of your deeds and all of our thoughts
and feelings aren't all connected in
some sort of a strange way that
we need to recognize a dress end.
We need to move forward with that as,
as an ideal that we are
all connected then. Yes,
absolutely not happening. Cover it and we
have to recover it. It's a spoil banks.
It's not happening with the
Federal Reserve or whoever
the fuck is in charge of
sending us to Afghanistan. Right. Whoever
wants to us to actually put, you know,
yeah. Well that was a, that was an
obvious and huge mistake. There's even a,
uh, a page in there called remembering
nine 11 before it happened.
You know, now I think that
it's pretty remarkable, uh,
kind of thing that, that, uh,
happened era of course, who,
but a spook would do something
like that. Nine 11. That's a joke.
Okay. Emergency, you know,
that's a spook that to Joe mean like the,
like the nine 11 is the code word for
emergency right now outside of America.
Question Mark.
You know,
like that's a reference
that only an American would,
uh, would play with because, uh, okay.
So then we have all the explosive
evidence about what happened that day.
Now, uh, you know, the burning of
the right stock and all of that.
Have we forgotten history? You know,
that's a massive distraction to, uh,
you know,
uh,
stop the everybody from paying attention
to Enron and go into some place that
never attacked us. That's, this
is your point. The Iraq war,
what was that based on?
But a lot of lies and
Afghanistan the same way that,
uh,
there a need to sell weaponry
and to spend money on these,
uh, you know, uh,
these mercenaries in order to,
uh, satisfy a certain hunger.
And this a hunger is the shadow is the
set seti and energy that dwells in the
desert and is,
uh,
and we are living off of what we
need to become is a solar powered,
uh,
humanity.
We are still struggling with set and
Horace who fought an epic battle thousands
of years ago in the deserts of
Egypt and continue it today.
The soul of humanity has to go
toward the light and find new energy,
uh, means to, uh,
to bring us out of our
dependence, our addictions to, uh,
the destructive web of, uh, this, uh,
kind of oil Gorky that we're enmeshed in.
So it's your opinion that,
uh,
September levels with some sort of a
false flag event and it wasn't just
incompetence or,
uh,
an attack that was capitalized on by
people with nefarious ideas that it was
instead plant. Um, or you would
only, I would don't, yeah,
I entertain that possibility.
And I think that the entire
affair needs to be examined.
But why I was setting that
up and to controversial
elements that many scientists
bring up. Not, you know, like
artists, you know, our people's,
an engineer has all those,
all those people who analyze the actual
material and the polling of building
seven as the smoking gun. But, you know,
you can go down that and look at it.
I think it should be
examined. But the, uh,
what I find fascinating about the entire
thing is the nest of synchronicities
that, uh, artists, uh, where,
uh, exhibiting on, uh,
that day, uh, there was, uh,
a man who had a studio,
an artist who had a studio in a tower.
One,
a number of artists had studios
actually in the twin towers. And,
um, his name was Michael
Richards, actually.
He was a black artist and he
was a sculptor and remarkable,
wonderful work. You hate himself?
Well, he was, uh, he, he was, uh,
he was an awesome, uh, that
was a bad joke. Yeah. Yeah.
Now he's has no relationship
to that, uh, uh,
fella and just happened to
have the same name. And, uh,
so,
uh,
his entire body of work was
destroyed practically, uh,
when the plane hit the twin towers.
And,
um, so a couple months later, uh,
some of his friends discover,
and this a museum in South Carolina that
they have one of his pieces once been
discovered. And, uh,
it was a self portrait,
um, and, uh, at Saint Sebastian,
you know, but instead of arrows going
through the body, they were airplanes.
Wow. Okay. Whoa,
whoa.
Saint Sebastian and the tar
baby is what it's called.
Wow.
Okay.
Now that is a fact.
Now, uh, I did a painting
like an eight, 1989.
I was,
it was a vision I had the day our daughter
was born and it became the painting
Gaya. Now, what's interesting, you
can look in that book, Netapp being,
we were in the World Trade
Center September 10th, 2001.
Wow. And, uh, I, I put my
tag in there actually. And,
uh, in the guy a painting,
there happened to be, um,
two airplanes. And, uh, there, uh,
there's also the twin towers.
There's someone who looks
strangely like George Bush.
He's embracing a terrorist and a disease.
Dick.
And, uh, I had no idea it
was used in the Beastie boys.
It'll communication album,
which by the way, has, uh, uh,
I, I can't stand it. Uh, the, the
most famous hit from that, uh,
from that album was a sabotage.
I tell you it now y'all, it was
sabotage, right? And, you know,
and so there are numerous things planted
into the collective consciousness you
could say. But then the, the, uh,
the comic book of Superman that
came out September 12th, actually,
uh, had the twin towers surrounded in
smoke and how copters were around it.
And the first panel panel one,
there was a hip hop group.
Everybody remembers this thing was
released that week after nine 11, uh,
there was this hip hop
group, the Coo who, uh,
had two members there and they were with
kind of like punchers and in back of
them,
the twin towers exploding now,
uh, they were prevented from releasing
it because it was September 12th.
They said, Whoa, Whoa, Whoa,
whoa. No, no, no, no, no, no.
But September 11th in Boston,
where's it's released live from
New York, this, uh, particular, um,
place, uh, this band in Boston, uh,
and it had the twin towers
surrounded in flame.
So you think that this, these people
who are creating this art that are,
are remembering these images that they're
pulling this from some collective from
the [inaudible], I mean,
uh, close encounters, right?
Remember that moment when they all
go into the artists, uh, you know,
room where there, oh, this one drew it
and that one sculpted it. And that one,
you know,
they all got blazed with something and,
and it, it, and it's such
a fascinating narrative,
synchronicities that I
believe it's unprecedented.
Well, you, you're,
your point of view on just reality itself
has got to be so much different than
the average person's. How often
do you bring up this? I mean,
this is a very controversial and strange
thing to say. You know what I mean?
It's a very
requirements saying that
it, that you know, uh,
that my painting or various other things,
uh,
necessarily lead to the truth,
but they point towards something
strange. Very strange. I mean,
anybody body examining the evidence,
it wasn't premeditated. It,
it's remembering nine 11
before it happened. Right.
What w what I was saying was this is a,
you just the way you have
to sort of lay this out.
How many times have you
had this conversation with
someone that you could see
him go,
oh, okay. Yeah. Looking at the time,
show the evidence though.
Show Michael Richard Sculpture,
which we do in this book. Matt
have been and show, show the,
um, uh, the folks that, um,
DC weren't, weren't fond of it,
so I didn't reproduce their thing,
but people can go onto
the internet and find it.
There's many Niecy what
does that DC comics,
they didn't want the superman panel
reproduced in a thing like that.
But you can talk about it and you
can say exactly what happened.
And just to pointing it out,
you have a sense of the uncanny.
There's a que se uh, and uh, uh,
right. They couldn't release that thing
would, that's the real image. Yeah.
That's it. No, that's not the real image.
That was what they fabricated
and wire to release that week.
But we're prevented by every good
sense, you know, to say good grief,
we cannot be doing it.
Doesn't mean,
is that the real image of nine 11
[inaudible] from there? Yeah. Yeah.
That was the CD cover.
That was the angle. Yeah.
So I mean this is a smoking
gun of some kind of, of uh,
regulatory breakthrough.
That was a terrible thing.
It was a terrible thing but it,
but it leaked through the
consciousness of humanity.
So you see the power of art as prophecy
and you see the power of art as what
could it point us toward?
We want to see a sacred possibility.
We went to look at our highest potential,
not look at the destructive.
We want to take that power of art and
plant seeds of liberation in the minds of,
of people,
not this kind of negative world of
self destructive nihilist a culture and
behavior.
My point of view or what I
was trying to get at was, um,
when you go into this sort
of a definition of things,
it's a fairy fantastical
and amazing sort of a,
a concept that there is some sort of
frequency that we're tuning into and were
getting warnings from, from, you know,
future events that we'll
have a big ripple in time.
How has this normally received
when you talk to people,
I mean you're a very unusual guy.
How many people can you
talk to about this stuff?
I think it's unsettling to
most people because, uh,
it's,
I haven't heard it spoken up,
but I hate just happened to be one of
the people that got blazed with a vision.
I had forgotten about it entirely. I,
you know, I knew I had painted some, oh,
this was the dark possibility of
humanity and this is the light.
This is the nature, you know,
and this is what we have to in,
here's Al Gore with some basket of
fruits and things in the guy, guy, guy.
Can you pull it up?
The guy at painting.
And how long did you do
this before September?
It was a 1989.
It was,
I had the vision in 1988 the day our
daughter was born. You know, how powerful,
you know, your child being
born is, it impacts you.
So as we had been up for
three days anyway, and, uh,
and I had to leave my wife,
they kind of kicked me out and I had
to go do an illustration project,
but as I was going over the
Brooklyn Bridge, I had this
vision, you know, and this,
it was probably the division, you know,
I've Manhattan and the vocoder sound that,
you know, but, but I had
this, uh, this dip titch uh,
kind of think there's a better
one on Alex grey.com. But the, uh,
but that's basically it. The, uh,
the world tree as the great mother
and the stress, uh, that humanity,
uh, is, uh, causing food. The twin towers
and little planes. That's fucking trippy.
Yeah. So 1989. And, uh, uh, there was,
somebody bought it and, and
of course it was in the, uh,
the El communication album. And, and, uh,
and then I published it in 1990
and the Sacred Mirror book,
my first book that came out then. And
so that was in there. And, and, uh,
um, uh, after nine 11,
some people sent me emails and
showed me the picture again and I,
I hadn't remembered any of that at all.
That's amazing.
That's really,
really freaky.
When you think about these
ideas and these blips in these,
these signals and whatever it is that
you tune into when you become creative,
you know, when, when you think about the,
the impact that the work that
comes out of it has on people,
what do you think ultimately we're
doing here as humans are evolving?
Aren't cognitive
process.
Absolutely.
You can't help but be transformative as
technology and destruction of anything
to do with that. Is there cars?
It's accelerating the, uh, you know,
the shaft or change to the
need for change and to grow.
It's almost like we're threatening suicide
unless we can think about. Absolutely.
And you should together,
I'm gonna blow my brains out.
The Waking Up is happening a lot through
the interconnectedness of the web of
technology. Technology had to
happen after an industrial period.
All of it has been an
evolving intelligence that
is finally beginning to see
it's cosmic origins in this story of,
uh,
of the universe that we've
been discovering and, uh,
and the Hubble telescope that shows
us the vast ness of space in the
understanding of dark energy
now that connects everything,
the clusters of galaxies
that had to exist,
that the earth is a rare, uh, kind of,
I think of it as the, uh, as this, um,
owl chemical, um, balancing act.
Well, it's, it's, it's, it's, you know,
the Olympic that goes around the sort of,
um,
whatever the alchemists puts
into his retort or into his,
into his flask. This flask, uh,
then is heated and it has a special
temperature that brings the interior to
transformation. And it goes
through a lot of different stages.
But I think of the earth and its
sir surrounding geomagnetic field.
The geomagnetic field is our limbic.
It's our al chemical epic.
Now you'll look at the Mars and it no
longer has a magnetic field around it.
And so everything has died.
And so this magnetic field that surrounds
the earth is our protection from the
solar, uh, flares and
the solar heat, the sun.
And it gives that beautiful kind
of a Rara, uh, that happens.
And so just at this
particular, uh, orbit, uh,
where are we in relationship
with our guru, the sun?
And we have this attraction, you
know, but what is attraction?
It's the bending of space time and
you're at a particular circulation,
but that circulation has the Olympic
of the geomagnetic field around it.
The US,
what the experiment of life can unfold
takes billions and billions of years to
grow an intelligence that can
start to recognize its own source.
That's astonishing.
That's a great epic journey of the
evolution of human consciousness.
And that's what's really going on.
Don't read the Times.
Read Aternity is, as Emerson said,
you know, it's a great quote.
Do you ever see [inaudible] uh, album
cover live scenes from New York City?
Cha Cha, there it is. Yeah, it's,
there it is released nine 11.
Yeah. And has the twin towers on
fire on an apple. That's crazy.
The, um, the future.
How do you, uh, how do you think
this is all gonna play out? I mean,
obviously you believe that you expressing
yourself with love and using art and
finding creativity elevates the human
experience as do I think there's something
incredible about seeing great art in
any form, whether it's great music,
great paintings or whatever it is.
There's something about seeing someone
really tap into whatever it is that is
going on. When you're being creative,
whatever it is that you're really,
when you're really accessing the
imagination that elevates us. It does.
You see that as an integral
part of this experience,
of this transformative experience
that human beings are going through.
But where do you see it
going? Like, what do you,
what do you see wakening
to our own? Yeah, I'm
creative spirit,
our own unique lens into the infinite
one that we all are and reflection stuff.
Uh, we're, uh, you know,
ultimately humanity has a great future.
And if you look at the evolutionary
bell curve of what's possible for human
consciousness and love,
uh Huh.
And how primitive it still seems that
humanity is in terms of their ability to
love one another.
You know,
we've had great teachers from
all over the world, you know,
teach us the same thing.
The wisdom masters say repeatedly
to love each other, you know,
and uh,
not to kill each other.
And it's something that is so
simple and so true and so beautiful.
And,
uh,
this is the affirmation of the
intelligence that built ourselves.
We have to tap into the, you know, we,
we recently had the
guest, Paul Stamets, uh,
visit cause him a couple of weeks
ago at our fourth summer. Him,
what you're referring to is the chapel of
sacred mirrors in New York. Absolutely.
At the chapel of sacred
mayors in Wappinger. Uh,
actually we had the great Miko Eco or
Eco Miko cow mycologist ECO mycologist,
Paul Stamets, who's written
extensively about, uh,
the power of fungus and the,
uh,
he's one of the world's
experts in medicinal. And, um,
uh, just the, uh, the
power of these things too.
Like he uses them to soak
up oil spills, the, uh,
oyster mushrooms and things like that
have been used to draw hydrocarbons,
uh, out of, uh, uh, water
that's been polluted with them.
And Chernobyl.
And the 30 mile radius around Chernobyl,
there are funguses growing
mushrooms growing that are hot.
They're radiation,
uh,
filled because the mycelium that they
fruit from has been drawing all of the
radiation from the soil in order for
life to come back to the forest there,
the deepest oldest plant on earth and
human beings themselves diverged from the
fungus over 650 million years ago.
So we have this connection,
this web of connectedness and obviously,
uh, uh, a connection with the
intelligence of the mushroom and, uh,
and Paul at far from
being a Terrence, uh, um,
sort of endorsing of
the, uh, uh, you know,
exogenous kind of, uh, um,
fertilization of the earth with the spore.
He believes it was homegrown and
he believes that we're exporting.
Uh,
so I love that kind of can do earth
based consciousness that evolved in this
alembic.
And for those who
don't understand what you meant by
that, what would you, you met for the,
the story is a Mckenna believes that it's
possible that mushrooms came from the
vacuum of space.
It rise on asteroids as well.
It's the theory of Panspermia,
which is we know amino acids and certain
things are transferred and there are
asteroids here from other planets
that have land the media rights.
And that is also one of the theories about
what happened to Mars as well. Right?
And that's how they lost
their environment. It was
an asteroid will impact
possible. And certainly we,
uh, the human, uh, or the,
the great chain of being in great
chain of evolution that, uh,
was impacted on the earth. Certainly,
uh, there's a belief that they media,
right. Uh, you know,
basically ended the era of the
dinosaurs and these little rat,
like things that were our
ancestors were able to, uh,
become more dominant as a species and
evolve due to the territorial kind of
disputes being over with these
large lizard people. Yeah,
that really was a nice,
nice break for us really.
And it had to happen.
But yeah,
we have big brother Jupiter out there
watching our back and it's taking the
heat, you know, he's
the bouncer of the, uh,
whole cosmos a or Arab
middle solar system.
And so only at a certain
level surrounded by a living,
kind of a lambic and
shielded by a particulars,
a kind of a planetary brother was
life of this kind even possible.
Think of how many billions of
galaxies it might take. We,
well, we certainly are probably
the only, you know, Earth,
planetary consciousness in the
universe. Obviously, you know,
we're a unique little neighborhood.
When you say Earth,
planetary consciousness in the universe,
what do you mean by that? Well,
there's no other earth right where
it, where the earth, this planet,
we're the only ones.
We're the only ones it evolves uniquely.
Darwin showed that on every
little, uh, uh, cov or,
or things,
things evolve a little bit differently.
So wherever else life exists,
if it does,
uh, uh, in a quite quite likely debt,
does it, most scientists would agree that,
but, um, uh,
is we have a unique jewel.
We've been gifted with it from
billions of years of evolution.
Don't fucking below it. That's
the most important thing. Yeah.
It's a w w we are saying if people don't
understand it is that Jupiter has a
massive amount of gravity. It's enormous
and it absorbs asteroidal impacts,
sucks them all up. It's like
the body guard for the earth.
It's amazing. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. It's, it's,
it's truly unique situation as far
as what we've studied in the cosmos.
But I might be further evidence.
There's a simulation. I'm like, yeah,
which is awesome. Well, you know, my
experience, uh, with, with Alison,
just to inform that
one, uh, our first, um,
kind of breakthrough,
um,
psychedelic experience that
changed both of our works.
It happened about a year after we first
met him, like our first anniversary,
June 3rd, say, uh, uh, 1976.
And we both melted down into these kind
of Tour Royito fountains and trains of
light and every other being
in thing in the universe,
which one of these balls of light as like
a soul. But it was, you know, like, uh,
uh,
an amazing kind of tourists.
It was like a tornado flow and uh,
this thing felt much more
alive and real than our kind
of material world reality.
It felt like this is what's
really going on. It's,
it's eternally and infinitely
light and we are projecting our,
uh, kind of souls into
experiences to have, uh,
um,
in reaching educational opportunities
and try to wake up to God sent us here to
wake up to God, you know, to the
core of our being, to our God self.
That's why this painting that's on the
cover of the net being is called God self
because it's a symbol of our
interconnectedness with all other gods.
Selves is every other being and thing.
And the network has access to this
great vast intelligence of the,
there's no other reason
that we could be here
when you believe that and think
that and then see what's going on.
Like with everybody saber rattling
about going to war with Iran. Well,
what do you,
how does that mean?
I feel very sad, you know, because, uh,
really it's about a breakout the piece,
Monkees,
you know, don't destroy
each other and don't, uh,
don't poison the web that sustains you.
That is only logical and by toxifying
both the consciousness of humanity by,
uh,
you know,
in training people's minds with a limiting
self images instead of accessing our
unity as a human species
and expand beyond that.
If you can feel,
even though you may hate your neighbor,
you now you may have
a gripe here or there,
but ultimately you
connected with loved ones.
Love brought us all here.
Love is the highest expression
of the cosmos. You know,
Albert Hoffman said that
the highest refinement of
light in the universe is love
because it took a solar battery
like our son to give birth to uh,
uh,
a planet earth.
And it took the evolutionary train
billions of years to get here to a point
where a consciousness,
a brain was capable of having
the experience of love,
which was the common source of everyone,
the love that brought us all here
to recognize it in each other,
to honor it and each other through all
different ways until we celebrate that
amazing experience and to try and,
you know, turn the ship around.
Now folks, you know,
don't go over the edge.
Don't commit suicide, do
something harder. You know?
Why is it more impossible
as the occupy folks said,
to imagine the end of capitalism then?
Or Why is it more,
uh, easy to imagine the apocalypse
than the end of capitalism?
Yeah.
You think the,
that capitalism is the big problem and
it's not just putting hard of morals,
it's part of it. Yes. All of that. Because
it's not a god centered consciousness.
We've wandered away,
you know,
is it possible though to have a god
centered consciousness and produce all the
shit that we produced to make all the
laptops we make to make all the cars we
make? You know what Steven
Chops was and to my friend.
Yeah.
Who's in a yelling at his employees.
Yes.
She's ended up making Chinese
people worked for $50 a month.
He was into a lot of shit there was,
but look at the nucleus of where those
things that you were just celebrating
came from. Well, he made
it his, it was from his LSD
experiences.
He credited that with being
a tremendous opening for him,
uh, and informing his, uh,
breakthroughs in
technology and Kary Mullis,
the Nobel Prize winning a molecular
biologist has said exactly the same thing.
And many people's lives have
been ruined by these things,
but many other people's lives
have been saved. My own, um, the,
the Francis Crick story, is that true?
You Go, yeah, this is a true, well,
you know, it, it is a
congested me. It is a, uh, uh,
it was released after his death,
right.
Cause he by threat of deaths had such,
and so now you could say,
oh,
now somebody just trying to hijack
that breakthrough of the imagination.
But then you go back to when it happened
and you realize that actually he was a
psychedelic advocate and he had, um, uh,
like many of his scientist
friends experimented with
these substances which were
supposed to catalyze the
creative imagination.
So he had read the papers and he
had access to these things. And, uh,
so, uh, he, there was no
stigma about it. In fact,
the first life magazine stuff about
psychedelics was extremely positive and
there was no stigma about it than what,
and he'd come out and say it initially.
Oh, because by the time,
uh, that it was a, yeah,
you would think you would think,
but he might not want to
Sally his breakthrough by,
uh, by, by, by putting
anything between, uh,
the breakthrough insight and the, you
know, then what are you talking about?
What, you know, based on a drug induced
hallucination. But, you know, I mean,
that's how the benzene ring was
discovered. It was in a dream, you know,
and,
uh,
so great discoveries come through
the visionary imagination.
Isn't the Hell Day cargo the idea of
science in the first place? There you go.
It was a dream that,
uh,
I think the exact quote was the science
and nature will be conquered by using
measurement. There you go. Well
that was a really important thing,
but conquered gives it, yeah, I
think I probably use that. That's,
but that is an aggressive
stance that, that uh, the,
um, the male species has,
has, uh, promoted because
it's very self serving.
And I think that, uh, if, you know,
part of,
uh,
what we're doing at this
point and as evolving, uh,
human beings is trying to create a new
model of possibility for humanity and in
a realm of sometimes for some
people diminishing expectations.
So the,
uh,
Paul Stamets a point of view of how
mushrooms can save the world and how
mycelium is actually a
network of intelligence that
connects us with the plant
realm and that we can take advantage
of by tapping into the nervous system.
That's a humanity diverged from
over 650 million years ago.
Now that's tapping into
cosmic intelligence.
Do you follow Mckenna's stoned ape theory?
I feel like that's the way a lot of people
and even responsible anthropologists.
Thank that.
There's some something to it because
they certainly would have encountered the
psilocybin mushrooms and who can say
that it didn't play a part and catalyzing
the growth of human consciousness. Now
it was Leary's or I'm in Lilly. Oh,
both leary and Lilly ideas was that it,
uh,
that these substances could advance in
the evolution of human consciousness.
Now you look at the Uni Oda Veggie
Vegetal, which is the, uh, first,
uh, psychedelic church for white
people, I guess in the United States.
Um,
and part of the mission of the UDV,
which is a church that
originated in Brazil, you know,
the heart of the Amazon from the
green mantle of the earth. Uh,
the green emerald comes these great
wisdom traditions that are spreading
throughout the world with
Iowasca and people are waking
up to the mind of nature,
um, uh, through these plants, sacraments
that have been used for centuries,
for thousands of years actually.
And um,
more and more anthropologists are saying,
well, they were seeing visions and the,
and the place,
we know that the bog people used to
smoke cannabis and cannabis has been
humanities friend for a long time.
Now neuroscientists just to,
and,
and I'll hand the floor over.
A neuroscientist in quoted in scientific
American said most neuroscientists
would agree that everything
that we experience is a
figment of our imagination.
Most neurosciences would agree with this.
That's what she said.
She might be crazy.
She might be,
but she had an entire issue of scientific
American optical illusions that it's a
yearly publication.
And so yeah,
she argues for this idea of
the plasticity of the mind.
And when you take these a dimensional
shift, you know, I'm like,
you're changing the radio
station with your, um,
kind of dimensional shifting that some,
uh,
psychonauts are able to do your,
you're tapping into different wavelengths
so you literally change reality.
Absolutely.
Literally can change reality.
Reality is reality is low dimensional
reality is code dimensional.
It's not like you, you know, you are,
this conversation changes
reality in this dimension,
but they'd also has a resonance
with another dimension.
So it's essentially what we
were talking about earlier.
That's neither real nor not real
and that, exactly. There you go.
It's a combination of
imagination and reality.
One of the things that always struck me
about imagination is how it's sort of a
marginalized, like the idea
of all that. Timmy, he's got
a vivid imagination, right?
You know, there's,
there's something to that.
But the reality is that
every physical thing,
including this building that we're in,
including this chair
that you're sitting in,
the microphone that
you're talking through,
all of it was created through the
imagination. So it did not exist.
It was thought up through
the imagination then became,
it manifested itself in a physical form.
And we've become basically numb to
the spectacle of the creation that has
unfolded before us.
And if we could remove our blinders
and notice the awesomeness, you know,
in the lean away from the Jibber Jabber,
you know,
we could be more at peace and maybe
recognized that the same beautiful,
uh, true and good stuff that flows through
your heart is flowing through mine.
Well,
if it is possible,
I believe that conversations
like this are what move, uh,
the consciousness of the people who
listen to this and the people who consider
these thoughts and the
things that you've said it,
it does move things in a better direction
and moves it in the better direction
for those people that are listening.
And I think if there's any one way,
we really can't change this world,
it's to change the way people
who are open minded view it.
If you're open and you,
you,
you introduce a positive new
idea into someone's mind,
you know that that can change them
and benefit them in a positive way.
So if you really want to change the world,
you already just did it.
You just did it with this conversation.
You're awesome. Chow and you're awesome
too, man. You, I love you too many. Your,
your work is amazing.
And for folks who want to stay
up on everything you're doing,
they can follow you on Twitter.
It's Alex. Great. Kozum c o s m um,
gray. Why not a y? Um, and uh, if
they want to, what is your website?
Well,
the most important thing that's going
on is really the chapel sacred marriage
project. We're creating our
first sacred structure, right
sample.
We're building it up there.
And it is an incredibly
important time for us. Uh,
if you look@alexgrey.com at
all, uh, well, let's see.
And theone is really the, uh,
the, um, the thing that we're,
we're working on now.
And that is this new sanctuary
for visionary art. And,
uh,
it is a multi denominational or trans
denominational acknowledgment of the power
of the creative spirit.
And it's occurring in architecture now.
And it's a place to house, uh, the,
uh, this thing. It's something else.
And an I were shown in a dream.
And, uh, she is the cofounder
of the chapel sacred mirrors.
She inspired the Sacred Mirror series.
She named the sacred mirrors.
So the honoring of the divine feminine
is really at the center of my life and
she turned my life around with her love.
And so that kind of love
is, uh, and the creative,
um,
evolutionary spirit that goes through
everybody is kind of what we celebrate at
Kozum. And, uh, so people
do a lot of creative. Um,
you know, there's art church.
We just had an awesome,
our church with other visionary artists.
It's happening around the world.
Visionary artists or like providing
cultural alternatives, you know,
where a likeminded people,
we call them the love tribe because you
find them all over the world, you know,
who've awakened to something beyond,
you know,
the stress full politically charged,
uh,
national boundaries and
they're global citizens. They,
they are tapped into the world centric
intelligence that could help lead us to a
planetary civilization. And they, by the
way, probably didn't exist 50 years ago.
Yeah. So that's the big jump. Yeah.
It's one of the things when people want
to talk about how bad everything is,
they're not aware of how good it is to,
yeah.
So chapel of secret
mirrors is a chocolate,
what does the [inaudible] dot Org Alex
grey.com has just been a re a revised by
our dear friends falling and Scotty
beautiful. And, uh, so, uh, there,
there will be updates about
[inaudible] and, uh, it, it, uh,
incredibly important step
for our community and,
and uh, for visionary
art. We hope. Listen man,
you just rocked a lot of
people's worlds today, Huh?
He threw a monkey wrench into the
gears of reality for a lot of folks.
I think that was awesome.
Thank you very much for doing this.
Anytime you want to do it again,
I would love to. That was,
it was just too much fun.
All right. Thank you brother.
Thanks to audible.com for
sponsoring this podcast. And again,
if you go to audible.com
forward slash Joe,
you can try audible for free for 30
days and get a free audio book and a,
as Brian said, and I've said the Steve
Martin one, uh, on doing standup, it's,
what is it called? The standard
[inaudible] standing on standing up.
It's fucking amazing, man.
It's read by Steve Martin.
If I wanted to just introduce
you to something that would, uh,
get you to really appreciate the impact of
audio books, that's my, uh, personal, uh,
idea. Uh, that's, uh,
Brian's as well. It's, um,
it's a great choice. Give it a shot. But
there's a million books on there. I mean,
I don't know how many there are, but
that's an incredible amount of, uh,
interesting books on CD
or on audio rather. Uh,
an MP three form that you can listen to
pretty much anywhere and it just makes
commutes and it makes
otherwise meaningless time.
It makes it educational and inspirational
and, uh, an awesome website.
audible.com forward slash Joe,
go there and get your free
30 days of audio books.
You son of a bitch. All right.
We're also brought to you by ting.
Ting is, uh, the, the mobile company
that, uh, we've started working with.
Um, no contracts. The way
works is if your money,
if you don't use all your minutes, you're
actually credited for the next month.
You got, you actually, they drop your
bill down and you're, you're credited.
So it's a beautiful company and
they use the sprint backbone.
So it's excellent
service. It's a, you know,
a great a line of phones that
they use mostly android phones,
but they also have some a right,
if you're,
if you're one of those old school dudes
resisting change in you and to flip
phones, they even have those things. So go
and check that out, you freaks. And, uh,
also thanks to [inaudible]
dot com for sponsoring our
podcasts. Go to O. N. N. I. T.
I checked, I can't find the blenders
online, so I guess they're not there yet,
but just to let you know
the blenders on that way,
you dirty bitches and a kettle
bells are there. We have a,
an awesome supply of kettle
bells in various, um,
various weights and sizes. And we also
have packages. And, uh, we have the,
the battle ropes in as well,
which, uh, there's videos.
Explain how to use them and
what to do with them. It's,
it's a awesome way to work out your entire
body. If you use a code name, Rogan,
you will save 10% off any and
all the supplements can't do.
You can't use that with kettle
bells and battle ropes though,
because Shit's expensive to
send through the mail. Yo,
we're sending you giant chunks of
the earth, giant metal with handles,
but it's manly as fuck and
really good for your body.
So go check it out. Um, desk squad. Dot
TV. You're out of shirts, right? Nope.
All in stock. I'll bitches.
They're back. So any of the, uh,
psychotic kitty cat shirts
that Brian has produced,
they original Brian Red Band works of art
as well. By the way, ladies, gentlemen,
uh,
you can get them@desksquad.tv and all.
Also be informed as to when, um, uh,
tickets are available for,
uh,
shows that Brian May be doing with the
other folks that are involved in what is
called the death squad. Um, including, uh,
the, the end of the world show with honey,
honey, Joey Diaz, Doug, Stan hope and
myself at the Wiltern December 21st, 2012.
Um, the tickets are
available right now. No,
there's not going to be any
end of the world, folks. Okay?
Everything's going to be
beautiful. And if you go to a, uh,
twitter.com forward slash Joe Rogan
and search through my timeline,
you can see the,
there's Presale for today and tomorrow
and the password is tickets. All right.
You freaks. That's it for this week
cause I got to go to Brazil and, um, uh,
I won't be back until next week,
but next week we have five podcasts
and it's going to be fucking awesome.
So we'll see you then. Thank you
Alex. Great. Thank you. Joe Rogan.
Beautiful.
Yeah.