And we're live,
so it was nice to take a break,
man.
Taking a break from anything is a good
move.
It's really is.
Take just a few days off the podcast.
Get all excited to come back and do it.
Yeah.
Little refresher.
A little refresher.
So,
um,
what's up brother?
How are you?
Good to see you.
I'm good man.
We going on there.
Oh,
this is my shirt that uh,
talks about how George Washington was
alive today.
They throw him in jail because he was
smoking weed and murdering.
Yeah.
He,
he grew pot,
right?
Yeah.
And he was pretty open about it.
He talked about how they should sow that
seed everywhere.
It's like,
it's amazing.
It's a miracle plant.
Makes me feel good.
It's good for good for clothes.
Could paper.
Did they smoke it though?
Did the founding fathers smoke it?
You know,
there's not like a lot of direct
reports.
I don't think about them actually
smoking it,
but if they hadn't figured that out,
they're pretty savvy.
I think they got that down.
I wondered though,
because if you were like growing
something and you were using it for one
thing,
like say if you were growing Kale and
you were eating it,
you wouldn't be like,
let's smoke this shit.
Like live your whole life and not know
the Kale could get you to God's front
door.
You don't think that smell though,
you know,
they're just like,
miss that smell,
this herb.
They would have eaten it.
Have made a tea out of it.
They would have done something isn't it?
Doesn't have to be cooked though.
In order to be psychoactive.
I'm the worst pothead ever.
I should know this.
I'm like such a pot advocate.
I should know.
Like if you're going to get in trouble
and you eat a bunch of your pot,
do you get high up?
I don't really.
I'm pretty sure you don't.
Wow.
Yeah.
I think that's one of the reasons why
people really enjoy a juice pot.
Apparently the health benefits of
juicing pot,
of taking the fresh non dried leaves and
doing it like wheat grass juice is
incredible.
It's supposed to be really good for you.
I believe that.
Yeah.
Yeah,
and it smell.
It doesn't smell like something you want
to eat,
you know,
like if you smell pot it's like it's
aromatic.
It's a beautiful plant.
A flag of tea.
Yeah.
That was out in the wild data probably.
Fuck you up.
I think it's a fat issue though.
That's why they always do it with
butter,
you know?
I think it's a or the oils I should
know.
Goddammit.
Well we got it.
People get so mad when you don't know
things.
Pothead Carter's going to get revoked.
Research.
Well,
I definitely know it can get you high.
I'll vouch for that.
But no,
I don't think.
I just still think eating it raw can.
But um,
um,
people get so pissed off if you were
wrong about anything in these long
rambling shit.
Talking sessions.
No vetting of information.
Two thousand 16 man.
Enough.
Enough of your misinformation and I
don't know,
I don't know if it but it does it.
It is amazing though that all these guys
used it for so many different things and
somehow along the line,
just a couple hundred years later,
it became demonized and got people
locked up in jail.
Very Declaration of independence written
on the plant that got made illegal and
one of the drafts,
yeah,
one of the drafts is written on hemp
paper and papers the best.
Have you ever had him paper before?
Now it's insanely durable.
It's really weird.
It's such a weird plant.
There's a weird thing about marijuana is
have you ever held a stock a marijuana
tree stock?
Now it's incredible because it feels
like styrofoam in in,
in terms of like how light it is,
but it's really hard like oak.
It's bizarre.
It's a fucking alien plant.
It really is.
If you stop and think about all the
things that that one plant provides,
it has a full amino acid profile,
but almost like a meat only.
There's only a few other plants I
believe keenwah and a couple others are
similar in that they have a full amino
acid profile.
You can make oil that you could.
You could heat your house with it,
you could build a house with it with
hempcrete.
Ever seen that hempcrete stuff,
but I've heard my God,
they make concrete with hemp and
apparently has antimicrobial properties
where it makes it really an effective
building method and places that have a
lot of mold,
like high mold content,
like high moisture content.
It's insanely durable.
It apparently will last forever.
It's really light.
This is hempcrete.
This is the shit you make this with.
Hemp has massive installation
properties.
Yeah.
Energy efficient.
It really is like an alien gift.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
Just went down and said,
here you go,
humans for so many things.
Have you seen all the stuff they're
doing with cbd oil and children that
have epilepsy?
I have been following that closely.
Fucking wipes it out.
You know,
another thing apparently there's really
good for children that have epilepsy is
going into ketosis.
Akita genic diet apparently like high
fat,
high fat content foods low a low simple
carbohydrate foods.
Yeah.
Apparently has a radical effect on
children with epilepsy.
It makes sense.
You know,
I mean a lot of what the brain is brain
is mostly made up of fat,
you know,
and I think a lot of times we don't pay
attention to the raw materials that our
body's made up of.
You know,
like your brain is made up of largely
fatty content and it's shown in a lot of
different studies that fat is good for
the brain.
So these issues that are coming from the
brain,
maybe there's an issue with some of the
raw material,
maybe you just supply it more of what
it's made of.
Yeah,
that's probably.
That makes sense.
And also what makes sense to me is that
that's what people ate for thousands and
thousands of years.
They just ate plants that grew out of
the ground,
like normal stuff and meats and fishes
and whatever.
They could get a fishes the fish and you
know,
and whatever they could catch and eat.
They didn't have spaghetti,
you know,
they didn't have all this stuff that we
fucking love now.
Bread bread is awesome.
Goddammit.
Bread is why is it so bad for you?
Well really,
I mean there's a lot of people who argue
that the bread is only bad for you
because of how we prepare it.
We allow the heat to dry,
which has it developed this heightened
layer,
this kind of protective layer so that
the seed could survive,
you know,
conditions where it wasn't going
directly into the soil,
you know,
seeds or have evolved to survive.
And the way that we prepare it,
it's not germinated,
sprouted.
So that hard layer is what makes it
really hard to digest.
Or if you get like a sprouted bread,
you know,
a lot of people say that the health
benefits are pretty good and all,
and a lot of the negative is mitigated.
That's interesting.
And that's what I eat most of the time.
And he did Zucchini bread,
which is a sprouted bread,
which,
uh,
not nearly is delicious now.
It's definitely not.
Definitely not.
The other one that's supposedly good is
sour dough bread because sourdough,
they use,
uh,
it's,
you know,
they have a culture in there that's
fermenting,
that's what's actually causing it to be
sour.
And that's partially digesting some of
that,
uh,
the hard parts of the wheat to digest.
So it's almost coming to you like pre
digest it a little bit by the bacteria
that makes it sour.
So it's a lot easier on your stomach.
Yeah,
I'd heard that.
Right.
Like for even there's some gluten free
versions of sourdough bread,
[inaudible],
which is a apparently even better.
I have something I haven't,
I haven't done anything with it.
There's a lot of.
The problem is,
is that when your stomach gets
inflammation,
it doesn't just go locally in your
stomach.
Then it creates these proinflammatory
cytokines which go cross the blood clot
in the bloodstream into the blood brain
barrier and then you get that Kinda
like,
foggy,
shitty feeling throughout your whole
body.
You know,
I mean,
a lot of people talk about it like leaky
gut,
but when inflammation is there and the
it's a lot easier for it to go systemic.
And so keeping that,
keeping that down to a minimum is really
key for,
you know,
performance.
Yeah.
Pasta Comas are legit for sure.
Fucking real mature.
Like,
my mom used to make this insane lasagna
and you'd eat the Lasagna,
you better know how many plans bitch
is on using your system.
That ricotta.
And
it was so good though,
God dammit.
And um,
I've had gluten free pasta written
recently.
I've been getting into that.
I wished I'm so glad Joey Diaz isn't
here.
He'd be screaming fucking gluten,
but it doesn't give you the same effect.
It's like you get but you don't have
that.
Oh,
like that.
A lot of people associate with a good
meal and feeling of just being,
just sedated.
Like,
oh,
that was great.
You know,
it's,
it's weird how that works until you have
to do something.
Exactly.
It's like,
shit,
I got work to do or have that big lunch.
And you got meetings afterwards and
you're just pounding coffee.
Just like get it together to death
doesn't work.
It doesn't really work that well.
She is the way to go.
Right,
for sure.
If you're in that situation,
you really should be pounding enzymes,
digestive enzymes,
and even additional if you
really have a difficult meal,
you know,
taking some hydrochloric acid along with
the enzymes is going to be great.
But enzymes are,
are key.
You know,
it's,
it's so fascinating for me that for the
longest time when people thought about
food and nutrition,
they f they thought,
well,
he eat a healthy balanced diet and you
know,
that's pretty much it.
That's really all you need.
If you want to be a sensible person,
if you want to really push the fringes
like Jacqueline Lane,
he used to fucking eat a bucket of pills
everyday.
Didn't he?
Didn't,
wasn't Jack Lillian like a crazy
supplement taker guy?
I wouldn't surprise me.
Yeah,
I'm pretty sure he was.
Um,
or uh,
another one is a homeboy.
The guy wants to live forever.
Ray Kurzweil Kurzweil,
he explained to me.
I interviewed him once for this Scifi
show.
It was so fucking cool.
Just me and Ray Kurzweil chilling in his
apartment in San Francisco for like an
hour and a half talking about to life
and possibilities and all the potential
future technologies that are going to
extend our life thousands and thousands
of years.
But that guy,
he doesn't fuck around.
He takes a gigantic bucket of pills
everyday,
which I'm not sure is the right way to
do it,
you know?
I don't know.
Sure.
Is it foods?
Is it foods and supplements?
I think you've got to really just look
at what,
you know,
what you particularly need to know and
just targeted for that.
You know,
I think a lot of things are what you
want,
you know,
a lot of it is just like,
what's going to help your performance?
What's going to help you reach your
goal?
Like what is your goal?
For him,
it's live forever,
so he's probably trying a bunch of
different things,
but he's a little bit frantic about
that.
He's a little concerned that he's not
gonna make it til this technology older
than us.
He's like 70,
70.
But what I was going to get at is that
when they started doing grass fed foods,
like grass fed beef became all the rage
and people start noticing the difference
in the actual size of the stakes,
like if you get a tenderloin or if you
get a New York strip from a grass fed
animal,
it's like can considerably smaller piece
of meat and then the fat looks
different.
The fat is a yellow fat instead of a
white fat.
And then when I started getting into
hunting,
one of the weirder things that I've
found was Steven Rinella told me about
blueberry bears and that the most
delicious meat is these black bears in
Alaska and Canada as well.
Anywhere they have blueberries,
right?
When they're getting ready to get into
hibernation,
they feast on blueberries to the point
where their flesh smells like
blueberries and they're fat becomes
purple.
Like it changes your body.
And it made me think like,
what about fucking twinkies and shit?
You know,
what about Coca Cola?
What is all that doing?
Your fat content?
What is it doing to your body?
You know,
like how much of what you are like if
you ever smell someone that's like
unhealthy,
like give her a date and unhealthy girl
or your own self when you're sick.
Not Me Bro.
Good.
All the time.
Let's.
Yeah,
that'll,
that'll do it.
If you,
if the smell is.
I think that was one of our primal cues.
You sniff somebody and say,
are you healthy?
You know,
how's your,
how's your gut biome?
That's what someone's.
But you know,
like is that.
Yeah,
totally.
But I think um,
you know,
now we're in this paradigm where it's
not just you are what you eat because
that's really true.
Your body is made up of the input that
you eat 100 percent.
That's what makes up your body.
And I think we forget about that,
but.
So we're not only what we eat,
but what we're,
what we eat eight,
you know,
so we're what the animals ate because
their body's made up of what they ate.
And then when you're looking at
vegetables,
I think sometimes people ignore the fact
that the vegetables are drawing these
minerals from the soil.
So what's the soil like?
Is it soil that's been farm forever and
they just put a limited array of
fertilizer on there just enough to get
it to go,
well then maybe you're not getting
enough minerals because the plants don't
have enough minerals.
So I think that's scenario that I'm
really kind of looking keenly on because
the one thing that I've done this year
differently is really started
supplementing with minerals and that's
made a huge difference in my energy
levels.
What are you doing?
I take a fulvic mineral and I take it a
couple of different ways.
What does that mean?
It's a different.
It's like fulvic acid.
It's a type of compound in the soil that
has a really wide array of trace
minerals and so you can get it.
I'm pretty much from the United States.
You can get it from all over the place.
It's really like densely concentrated
old,
old vegetation,
you know,
that is turning,
turning the soil.
Um,
that.
And then Himalayan Sea salt of course is
another great resource.
But the combination of like
intentionally giving those,
I feel like I'm giving my body the
building blocks to make the body to do
what it needs to do.
Like all of our clans and skin and
organs,
it's comprised largely of these elements
and minerals and these different things.
And I feel like sometimes the body's
reaching for spare parts and the garage
is empty.
It's like Duh,
what the hell?
I don't have this mineral that I need to
repair myself.
You know,
because it's not part of what
osteoporosis is.
Yeah.
Your body drawing calcium literally from
your bones.
Yep.
And then we do that naturally.
Another reason why we don't have that
many minerals is we do that naturally
when we run a little bit acidic.
So for drinking coffee and alcohol and
these things are Ph may not change,
but the reason it doesn't change is the
body uses the minerals from things like
the bones,
calcium carbonate,
which is the traditional antacid,
something that buffer the acid.
So it buffers the acid within the body
by utilizing available minerals.
So we get an even a greater mineral
depletion if we're running more acidic,
which is one of the reasons why I think
an alkaline diet is helpful,
but you can kind of hack that by just
taking a lot more minerals so you have
more available to buffer out your acidic
diet,
not that you should be drinking booze
and eating sugar and coffee anyways,
but we're all going to do that.
We're all humans.
So if you're going to do that,
getting more minerals in your diet is
going to be huge.
What do you fuck around with colloidal
minerals?
We take that stuff into that for awhile
and I got some benefits of it,
but uh,
for whatever reason I stopped drinking
them.
Yeah.
You know,
for me it's just fulvic.
There's fulvic acid,
humic acid.
I found that the humic acid a little
heavy,
it weighs on my digestion,
but fulvic acid is a little cleaner.
I feel like I absorb it better.
So every time I'm making a drink,
I get those mountain valley spring
waters and my thing is just a little bit
of Himalayan salt,
maybe two grams and then a little scoop
of the fulvic mineral powder and um,
and drink that and huge difference and
I've given it to a lot of people who
have had some energy issues,
just things not going quite right and,
um,
made a huge difference.
So that's something I'm really kind of
looking at for 2016.
Nice.
Um,
I'm going to get really in the
probiotics is here.
Yeah.
I had a Rhonda Patrick on the podcast
and she was talking to me about these
really powerful probiotics.
So I'm ordering those this week and I'm
going to get started on trying out
different probiotics because I'm a
regular drinker of that Kombucha,
that stuff.
GTS,
Kombucha.
No bullshit.
I drank for a day,
three to four a day every day.
I mean,
I'm constantly restocking on that shit
and it makes a massive difference,
man.
Like having good gut biome having good
thing.
I've been eating a lot of his,
um,
raw sauerkraut and raw fermented beets.
Yeah.
Kimchi and fermented plants and foods,
when you're doing that,
you're.
You're literally taking in raw like
soldiers told to fight off all the other
shit that's going on inside your body.
I think that
absolutely.
The other big key that we all ignore,
you know,
all of us have taken these courses of
antibiotics and there's a recent study
that came out that showed it takes up to
a year for your gut biome to fully
recover from a course of antibiotics,
a single course of antibiotics,
so you're just basically detonating a
nuclear bomb off in your stomach and
these,
this gut flora is responsible for
neurotransmitter production and immune
system production.
All kinds of benefits and it may get
even crazier than that because there's
some animal studies now where they took
the gut biome of a really kind of chill
mouse and a really hyper mouse and they
switched the gut biomes of both of these
mice and their personality
characteristics changed.
So like a lot of what we are may be
related directly to our gut flora.
So paying close attention to that I
think is that minerals is probably the
two most important things you could do.
That's a really insane thing when you
stop and think about it.
It was we,
I think we associate ourselves or we try
to think of ourselves as being some sort
of an independent entity like I may as
well.
I feel good when I have a cup of coffee
and a glass of orange juice.
But the idea that you literally are what
you've put into your body and that it
doesn't just fuel your body,
but it makes your body and your body
changes and varies dependent upon what
you're putting in.
Yeah.
We're like a trillion organisms actually
that just have one over mind so that
everything's not just warring with each
other and and making it like,
I need this,
I need.
We just have one over mine,
but it's really,
you know,
we're king of a trillion
cells and how are we going to be a good
ruler to these?
They're like our loyal subjects.
Like we have a little kingdom in our
body and are we going to be a good
ruler?
Are we going to be a shitty one that
just talks shit to him?
It gives him shit food and,
and you know,
taxes the hell out of them.
Mass too much.
Gives you little.
Well we have one voice where it comes
out of one hole,
but I don't necessarily know.
That's like one thing in there that's
running the show.
That's true because I think we like to
think that it is,
but God dammit shifts loyalty and
direction.
It just,
it's all over the place.
The mind and who you know in quotes you,
when you think of yourself as me,
you know me when you think when you
yourself,
well,
I'm going to do this or I'm going to do
that.
I'm like,
what are you saying?
Like what do you.
What are you saying?
I'm going to lead the troops,
but who are you?
You change all the time,
motherfucker.
You're different whether or not you've
had a nap,
whether you've had a cup of coffee,
whether you're taken your Alpha brain,
you're fucking different all the time.
Like,
cool.
You Bitch.
You're so inconsistent.
Like what's going on in there?
Well,
what's going on there as you're an
ecosystem,
you're,
you're like,
it's like the jungle calling itself a
thing.
The jungles not authoring the jungle is
fucking millions of things all in a
cycle where the big ones are eating the
little ones and then the big ones die
and the little ones absorb it and it's
like this constant ever going thing
that's happening.
The idea of it being like the like a
lighter,
you know,
or like a brick,
you know?
It's not a fucking giant system of all
these and that's the body.
Very true.
Yeah.
I think there's this combination of also
the body and then consciousness and the
mind like all of these three different
things,
which I,
that's how I kind of organize it.
There's the body,
then there's the mind,
ego,
and then there's your consciousness and
those are always different voices.
The body's more like a plant.
It's slow and it doesn't listen to the
mind that which moves,
like instantly the mind can think one
thing and the other thing,
but the body has fortunately has a big
lag.
It's way slower.
Otherwise,
they'd be getting mixed signals all over
the place,
so that inherently creates a conflict
because the mind moves at the speed of
light,
but the body moves slow,
so we have this built in system where
it's a little bit strange like we can
want something for the body,
but it takes a while.
You gotta change the nutrients.
You got to do these different things and
I think that's a frustration point for
people with their bodies because their
mind is so fast and that's what they
identify with and they want the body to
react.
But the body slow bodies like a plan.
Yeah.
Everybody wants that instant fix.
You know,
like you come off of hard drinking over
new years and you look at your gut and
you start pinching your fat and you're
like,
God damn it.
I got to change.
And then it's hard.
Like you wake up and you look at your
clock and like,
fuck,
I don't want to go to the gym.
If I go to sleep right now,
I could sleep for another hour and a
half before I have to go to work or I go
to the gym right now and you know what
you should do,
but your body's like,
come on man,
but then your brain is like,
what are we looking for?
We're looking for success.
We're looking to improve,
we're looking to feel good,
get up you fuck.
But it's,
it's
this conflict.
Constant conflict of trying to improve
and trying to be disciplined and trying
to get it all together.
And then this fucking self sabotage
mechanism that somehow or another,
the vast majority of us have.
Yeah,
the inner bitch bitch.
Yes.
Yeah.
I think one of the most important
things,
and this is what I've really been
focusing on,
is having the ability to do what I call
mental override,
which is just where you just push
manually push that go button all the way
down and just do something that you
know,
you don't want to do because we're so
good at negotiating and justifying and
you know,
having these little arguments with
ourselves and sometimes you just need
that ability to just go,
okay,
we're doing this.
I don't care if you're scared,
that's cool.
You're going to be all right.
Mental override.
We're doing this and you can really use
that ability to choose,
you know,
in so many things.
You can even choose yourself in a better
mood.
You know,
I've experimented with that like you're
in a Shitty,
I'm in a shitty mood and like,
well maybe you just choose to listen to
a song that's not like a shitty mood
song and then you choose to.
You can jump from Lily Pad to Lily Pad,
but you can choose your way out of a lot
of different things if you're willing to
do that.
If you have cultivated that skill to
just push the hammer down and say,
all right,
I'm going to be happier right now.
It's that determinism thing that a lot
of people fall prey to.
It's like all the different
circumstances that have happened in your
life.
All of your own trials and tribulations,
successes and failures,
all these things lead up to who you are
right now and sometimes the momentum of
those things is super hard for people to
break.
It's super hard for if you've always got
up in the morning and smoked a cigarette
and had a cup of coffee,
the one day you get up and you're like,
you know what?
I gotTa stop doing this.
I got to take care of my body.
Got To get off the cigarettes.
I got to figure out a way to have it,
but to to try to cultivate a bunch of
different inspirational things to get
you over that Hump I think is the way
like whether it's people like for me
there's a bunch of people that I call
upon in my mind in my mind,
like when I think of like a incredibly
disciplined top.
Like there's this guy that about on my
podcast before a great guy,
Jocko willink.
Jocko was fucking savage.
Yep.
Right.
He's the man every morning go to the
twitter page.
That motherfucker shows a photo of his
watch and it'll say 4:45 or 4:30 or
4:15.
This fucker is up every day before five
slinging lead,
just fucking lifting weights and he,
he'll show like puddles on the ground
after his workouts and then it'll show
like the sun coming up and he feels like
that gives him an advantage.
But in sending those images out there,
other people,
even people like me that.
I mean I don't necessarily have a
problem with discipline.
I'm a but I don't have the best
discipline.
Sure.
But I mean,
but it's pretty,
it's pretty good.
You know,
I'm pretty healthy but I'm still a fuck
up on occasion because I'm a comedian at
heart.
I mean ultimately is that self-indulgent
personality that goes,
we're doing shots,
you know,
it's always there,
but when you see a guy like that that's
out there fucking going for it like
that,
guys like that,
they,
they breed like a little spark,
you know,
you're not even a little spark,
like a big spark.
So there's a few of those people that I
follow,
a few people that I know,
a few people that have watched their
documentaries or a folder their,
you know,
their workout routines and you just,
you just got to cultivate those things.
Just sort of like,
he cultivate information.
You can have a conversation with no
data,
you can't,
you literally have nothing to talk
about.
If you haven't experienced anything of
you haven't taken any information,
will that information much like food is
fuel for your body,
that information is fuel for your mind,
for your personality and for the way you
view the world.
Like your overall projection or
interpretation of the world itself is
based on how much data you take in,
which is one of the reasons why it's so
important to surround yourself with good
people.
No,
Duh.
I mean people generally move by one of
two forces,
inspiration or desperation.
It's way better to get an get in early
on the inspiration tip,
wait for desperation.
It causing,
oh,
I had a heart attack.
That's why I changed my diet,
or Oh,
I'm going to die,
so now it's time,
but if you can move from inspiration,
you know you're going to be way,
but way better off.
But there's something else too,
which is just the ethos like you know,
and all warrior cultures develop this.
The Samurai had the Bushido,
the spartans had their ethos and it's
something where you just decide
something that just doesn't have.
There's no room for negotiation anymore.
This is not a negotiable item.
You don't need inspiration.
You don't need desperation because it's
no longer on the table for negotiation
and I think that's part of that ability
to just choose something and create your
own ethos.
Like maybe your ethos is I don't smoke
cigarettes anymore and that is my ethos.
It is non negotiable.
Like that is part of my code and
developing something that's so,
so strong that it's not even on the
table for negotiation,
you know,
and I think it's important to use all of
those different facets.
Like for the spartans it was,
you know,
never retreat for the Samurai.
It was always keep on or you know,
whatever their Bushido it was pretty
wide code,
but you know,
and all of those things,
there were these just these things that
wouldn't break.
So when it came time to,
you know,
take the sword to protect your honor
into your own gut.
You know,
how hard that is.
I can't even cut my little finger,
cut my finger.
You mentioned like sticking a sword,
but it was just non negotiable.
Like it was so deeply ingrained and so I
think all of us should spend time
creating our own ethos.
Like what is our ethos?
And don't get too crazy with it.
Like I'm never going to eat sugar.
Come on man.
I mean,
give yourself a little bit of sugar
every now and then.
Don't make that ethos
but create something that's just non
negotiable.
Well,
I think cheat days are really good for
the mind.
Cheat meals are really good for the mind
and that even though it's not good to
take in like an entire pizza in one
setting,
knowing that you allow yourself that
possibility every now and then actually
relaxes the imagination and relaxes the,
the resistance to discipline because I
feel,
at least me personally,
I don't like rules.
I don't like.
I mean one of the reasons why I became
who I am and the path that I chose as
far as like what I chose to do in life
just because I didn't like people
telling me what to do.
I didn't like the idea of school.
I didn't like them telling me I had to
learn this right now for whatever dumb
reasons and when you grow up with this
idea that confirm conforming is bad and
that following orders makes you a robot
and a slave.
Fuck that man.
I'm going to be my own person will be a
free spirit.
I'm going to put tie dye on fucking
hitchhike across the country.
Here you have these ideas that the,
the sort of patterns that everybody else
is following,
they're only following them because
they've been told to and you don't have
to do that,
man.
It's bullshit.
We're all just organisms.
We're all just living on this life
together.
So you kinda get,
get into this mindset where you don't
want to have any rigidity.
You don't want to have any,
uh,
any hard fast rules,
but that's not necessarily empowering to
you as an individual.
One of the things I'm really fond of
saying is that you only appreciate rest
when you've earned it.
Yeah.
Like,
I don't appreciate rest unless I've
fucking busted my ass and those have
worked out hard.
Got All my work done,
got all my shit,
all my.
If I have anything that's fucking with
me in the back of my head,
it,
it haunts me.
You know,
it,
it bothers me and I can appreciate
relaxation.
It does not worth anything anymore.
If I come home from doing nothing and I
sit down in front of the television,
I may enjoy whatever I'm watching.
I might enjoy it because it's good
information or it's good stimulation,
but I'm not going to enjoy that
relaxation.
I'm not gonna.
Enjoy that.
That thing and I've earned it.
Yeah,
I mean you have a natural seeking of
your own kind of balance and I think
that's what's important is having that
compass to say like,
alright,
I've worked this hard and now it's time
to take off and just let the stress go
and I think that's an important line of
delineation something that I struggle
with too because I'll finish a long day
at the office and they'll come back and
I'll work and I'll be constantly.
Even when I'm like with Whitney trying
to watch a movie,
I'm thinking about what I could be doing
instead of just saying,
all right man,
just take this two hours.
Yeah,
really rest.
You're off.
You're off duty man and clock out.
And I think that's an important thing to
kind of restore and yet again,
it's that same thing like taking a
break,
like allow yourself that opportunity to
let the stress go.
You know,
when you've done the work.
But if you're on the other side and
you're just not really doing anything,
you know,
and you're just kind of relaxing and
that's starting to create the stress,
then you got to go to the other side of
the pendulum and kick some serious ass
first before you start worrying about
the rest.
So it's just about like striking that
right balance in your life.
God,
that's so important.
The right balance of so God damn
important because you don't want to be
that fucking psychopath that just burns
everything in front of you and just
hacks at the land trying to achieve
victory because that,
unless you're a fighter,
I think that if you're competing,
if you're fighting like,
well,
I'm a big fan of saying that if you,
if you want to fight,
if this is what you want to do,
it has to be completely singular pursuit
you.
You can't.
I want to fight.
And I also want to open up an organic
peach jam business and I know what I
mean and I also want to start marathon
running and I'm also really involved in
this and that and that and this man,
if you want to be someone who's doing
something so insanely dangerous that
it's probably as far as pursuits in
sport fighting is probably one of the
all time most dangerous things you could
possibly do other than like maybe bmx,
flying those flips,
those guys do have ramps and like ski
jumping,
like the shit that he does when he's
fucking flying down a hill.
Like Jesus Christ.
Like that's insanely dangerous too.
But like a singular pursuit.
Yeah,
I think you can only do it for a few
years.
Like maybe at the most 10 or something
like that.
But I think to,
to be like a fade or a million inco in
his prime,
that motherfucker was probably gone.
I mean he was probably in that zone all
the time,
like Anderson when he was in his prime
other than pussy and food.
I bet that dude was pretty locked in,
you know,
in the few recreational activities,
video games,
what have you,
but you need to achieve that state of
like high revolution excellence.
You almost have to be like unhealthy.
Yeah,
I mean I talked to a really successful
person that I know and he said that he
limits himself always two,
three things.
Like he will not allow himself to focus
on anything more than three things and
that was kind of interesting for me
because I love creating these little
different things and working on these
different projects.
He's like,
for me,
three things is the maximum and that's
what I forceably cut myself off with and
I think that's something good to keep in
mind.
You can only really genuinely work on
three things at a time and maybe when
you're a fighter that just narrows down
even more to just one thing.
Right?
Because you have those disciplines
you're working on,
you're working on the grappling,
discipline,
striking disciplines and maybe those are
your three things.
Wrestling,
striking,
not like nuts.
That's it.
That's all you have time for.
If you're going to be the greatest,
maybe that's why Thailand so good for
those guys.
Just you just pay for sex.
You just take that off the table.
Not even an issue.
Yeah.
Just go to the massage parlor or
whatever you do.
Get your joint worked out.
Yeah,
no doubt.
I know.
I think,
um,
where
everybody's sort of trying to find this
zone that makes them feel the best,
that makes them feel the most satisfied,
the most comfortable,
the least crazy,
the least disappointed.
You just want to find this and
everybody's zone is different.
Like some people,
they don't have this and burning
ambition to succeed.
They don't have lofty goals,
they just want to be happy or they want
to pursue whatever are in they enjoyed
doing.
Maybe it's maybe like painting or
something like that.
They just enjoy creating painting,
you know,
creating a piece of art that someone's
going to look at and it looks kind of
cool.
I think that's really important to not
take what societies when is and make it
your own.
You have your very own wind and that
could be chilling at the beach surfing
and occasionally painting and that's
your win and if somebody else is trying
to tell you,
oh,
you got to do something with your life,
fuck that.
That's just a counter force,
like if you really track what your
mission is and what you love to do,
then do that thing you know and don't
let these other things tell you that
you're not succeeding or try and make
you conform to what society says is
success because that's a bunch of
bullshit.
We each have our own version of that and
I think it's the most important thing we
can do to stay true to that,
but it does seem to me that everybody
needs something.
We were like,
sure,
whatever those things are.
These interests that people have,
they seem to be like vehicles for
happiness,
like the mind almost from being
developed at the time we were monkeys to
what we are now.
The mind has gone through all these
different activities and has gone
through all these trials and
tribulations and the struggles for
survival.
So there's almost like this built in
mechanism in the mind to problem solve
and to deal with things and either to
create like for a lot of people that's a
big one or to achieve or to accomplish
or to get over the hump and when you're
not fighting for your life and you're
not struggling,
those,
those don't get fed and these sort of
genetically ingrained reward systems,
they seem to be like built into the
system of being a person they don't get
addressed.
And I think that's one of the reasons
why a lot of people feel lost.
They feel they feel like depressed and
unsatisfied because what they're
choosing to pursue is not really
interesting to them.
Like there was a threat on my message
board where someone was,
uh,
it was,
it became like a big crazy fucking
argument,
like all threads and all message boards
do.
But it started off interesting where
someone was saying that hard work stupid
and that really what you want to do is
find something you love and then
disciplines no longer required because
you're truly enjoy it.
Which is sort of true.
But sort of not,
because if you really want to achieve
excellence,
you need both.
You need to find something you really
love doing and then you need to figure
out how to discipline yourself to pursue
it to the utmost so that you,
you hone that blade and sharpen it to
it's razor edge.
And if you do not do that,
then you're always going to have this
thing like,
oh man,
I could have been better.
We need resistance.
You know,
we need resistance in our life.
Like the obstacle is,
is what we should go towards.
No matter what that is,
whether we're writing,
you know,
writing itself contains its own
resistance points where it's hard and
you're pushing against that.
Obviously in weight training or
athletics,
it becomes really obvious what that
resistance point is.
You know,
you're actually moving weight or trying
to defeat a person.
But no matter what that is like applying
our force,
the force that is the totality of
ourselves against a resisting force and
overcoming.
I think that's a fundamental craving of
the human nature.
Like that is definitely a key to
happiness.
Whether it's against nature,
against yourself,
against a craft,
against another opponent,
against whatever else.
Like that dynamic,
that push poll is super key.
Yeah,
it really is.
And I think unfortunately for whatever
reason,
when I,
at least when I look at life itself,
I almost think that the evil of the,
it seems like this,
the struggle of the world,
whether it's a struggle for peace,
whether it's a struggle for,
you know,
to alleviate people that are trapped in
poverty,
whatever,
whatever struggle there is.
It seems like those struggles are
almost,
it's almost imperative to have some sort
of a struggle in order for people to
find balance and,
and to find inspiration to do better and
inspiration to,
to push further.
Like I wonder where society would be.
This is kind of sound fucked up,
but where would we be as a culture if it
wasn't for the horrors of war and crime?
Like where would we be?
I got,
as I was driving here today,
I was thinking about,
um,
just how fortunate people are in the
United States in general are most people
are at least,
but that there's parts of the world
right now that are in these horrific,
almost mad max states like Liberia.
I've watched this one documentary on a
vice on Liberia that back in the day
that just cemented in my mind how
fortunate we are because mad max like
the apocalypse,
it exists,
it happens every day.
Just doesn't happen right here.
Knowing that that exists,
does that make you appreciate this more?
And if,
if that didn't exist,
would we,
would we try as hard as we do to try to
keep peace in the world?
Would we try as hard as we do to like
try to be happy and achieve happiness if
we didn't know that there was some
ultimate horrible sadness and evil shit
going on?
Would you appreciate the cool people in
your life if you didn't know that there
was just an army of content out there?
You know?
Yeah.
That's an interesting topic.
I kind of tend to believe that there's
enough internal resistance that will
battle enough of our own demons.
I mean look at how you celebrities
and really wealthy people,
their rate of happiness is no better
than anybody else because even when you
alleviate all of these conditions,
you're battling these internal demons,
like will always find resistance points.
So I think we would be okay because it's
just the way the system is built,
they would come up internally when
everything is right and then we have to
apply that same force to fight that
enemy within our own demons within
rather than having this clear objective
outside.
But it's,
it's almost easier and it's almost like
it has a certain allure to make an enemy
external.
Because then like imagine,
you know,
think back to when the twin towers got
bombed.
Everybody pulled together with this
common enemy.
We all had a mission,
you know,
and everything made sense and that was a
really good external,
you know,
external way to focus our mission.
But when it gets internal,
that's where we just don't have as many
skills.
And that's where the tools,
like the plant medicines and like
meditation and like floating or the
tools you need to navigate and kind of
conquer those waters.
It's not guns and it's not bombs
anymore,
it's these other more subtle mechanisms
which were not nearly as advanced as we
are with the stuff that blows stuff up.
So I think it would just go from these
external battles which have always had
this great allure.
Let's go to war,
you know,
into these internal battles,
which are really actually a lot of times
even harder.
I mean,
not to say that these conditions in war
aren't incredibly challenging and
incredibly difficult.
I mean,
I've heard stories from Tim Kennedy and
all kinds of soldiers and just blow your
mind,
but these internal battles can be super
fucking intense too.
Yeah.
We just don't think of it as being
intense because there's no life or death
consequences.
The consequences are there are
psychological there.
The reality of who you are as opposed to
this image that you're projecting,
the reality to seeing all the sort of
failures and,
and all the different,
um,
sort of mechanisms that you've created
in your mind,
in your,
in your life to deal with all these
personality issues that you might not
have ever addressed.
And then when you take a psychedelic and
you're confronted by this,
like Ari was telling me about one of his
friends that was a dick and they took
him out to,
well,
you know,
already does that true and fest every
year it took him out to the desert and
he just had this literal come to Jesus
moment where it was like,
why do I act like that?
Like,
what is wrong with me?
what,
what is the.
And then he realized he's just unhappy
with his life in his state.
Wake up where he is as far as his
achievements as a standup comedian.
And as a,
you know,
like he's not successful.
At least he,
you know,
he's always struggling with his bills.
And because of that,
um,
he's nervous all the time.
So when he goes on stage,
he doesn't do well and because he's not
happy,
he doesn't have good relationships and
because he doesn't have good
relationships,
he doesn't feel good about himself
because other people don't feel good him
and he acts out almost in a defensive
mechanism like attacks people and acts
Shitty to people in almost a way of sort
of taking away focus from his own
failures,
his own internal disputes.
So he's sort of externalize those in
this weird way and become this
aggressive kind of shitty person.
Like here's a perfect example of that in
my opinion,
in a successful person,
Donald Trump,
right?
I mean,
why is that guy so shitty about
Mexicans?
Why doesn't he have a balanced nuance
perspective?
Why doesn't he understand that you were
insanely lucky?
You Fuck your dad gave you what,
2 million bucks to start a business and
you,
you make it seem like it's no big deal
that your dad loaned you all this money
and you're a self made man.
That's ridiculous.
First of all,
you live in America and you're white.
Okay?
Right away,
you're lucky as fuck.
And then you're involved in this system
that it's allowed you to fail and go
bankrupt and you know,
and skirt away from all your bills then
come back.
But the idea being that here's the guy
that has this insanely successful life
monetarily,
but yet still,
you know,
we'll have these ridiculous short,
shortsighted opinions that he rants and
about and talks about and these,
like these Syrian refugees and he's
like,
you know,
we need to keep out of the country,
keep keep Muslims out of the country.
We need to figure out what the hell's
going on,
like,
what the hell is going on?
Like what you're again,
you're not dealing with units,
you're dealing with massive amounts of
human beings that are all different and
varied.
Like why does he have this sort of
aggressive fuck you,
you're a loser approach.
What,
what is the conflict?
How does,
how does he get out of that and have a
more balanced perspective to deal with
what is really in a lot of people's
eyes,
people that are way more unfortunate
than he is.
Yeah.
And you know,
there's a bias in society to just
appreciate these external success is,
oh,
you're wealthy,
Oh,
you've accomplished this.
But we undervalue those in the victories
over that internal self to get somebody
more conscious,
get somebody more open in their heart,
like those are like shoved to the side.
So everybody's been kissing trump's ass
because of the power that this money
creates in the power of that.
And we may even vote him in as president
in this crazy,
crazy world even though he's completely
ignored probably the most important
thing that any human could do,
which is go inside and have that
accurate self reflection like,
hey,
am I a Douche bag right now?
And one of the best ways to do that is
with the plants or with meditation or
anywhere where you get still and allow
that force of consciousness to actually
take control of the helm of the mind.
Push the ego aside and show you the
truth.
But that's why people are terrified of
it.
That's why trump will never,
you know,
go do Iowaska and the jungle and I'll
never.
Maybe you will.
Maybe he would be amazing.
If you want to.
Man,
I'll hook it up.
I will hook you up.
We'll go down.
It'll be.
Could you imagine
if like in mid cycle he just completely
shifted gears and said,
I had a moment.
I had a revelation and I realized that
what were the direction we're going in?
It's just not right.
Everybody be like,
wait,
you are our only hope.
You're Obi wan Kenobi.
Motherfucker year.
You're Obi wan Kenobi for white people.
Like,
who else is there?
Hillary Clinton,
get the fuck out of here.
There's so many guys that are just not
going to vote for a woman.
Especially a woman who was married to
Bill Clinton,
who looks like a shrew.
It's just not happening.
Oh,
who else?
Bernie Sanders.
Get the fuck out of here.
There's so many people that are not
going to vote for Bernie Sanders.
Especially when you realize that he
wants to literally literally 90 percent.
He wants to tax rich people.
Ninety percent like this.
I thought that was bullshit.
I thought like,
well,
that's not true.
He didn't really say that.
That's probably an exaggeration.
Nope.
He's actually said that and he goes back
to like,
I think it was Roosevelt,
I forgot who it was.
It was an office during the war and
there was at one point in time where
they sort of effectively taxed rich
people at extremely high rates and you
know,
he was talking about the efficiency of
that,
but the idea of taking money from
successful people and just such an
insane disproportionate amount and then
giving it to what the government,
who is the government,
the biggest waster of money to you,
you fuck like lifelong politicians and
people that are for whatever reason,
working government jobs like get outta
here.
You can't just take the money from
people that have achieved that,
but that's not the solution and it's an
ineffective strategy because you can
only tax people on their income.
You can't tax them on their wealth.
Right?
It's all income tax based.
So all of the wealth that's already been
accumulated by all of these people,
you know,
you can't even get that money anyway.
So you're just taxing the people who
finally are getting successful enough to
make the money as well as some of the
people who have residual money,
but it's not going to even achieve
practically pragmatically what he's
trying to do.
He's trying to be Robin Hood,
except he's only taking the new money.
Not the.
Not The existing 90 percent of the
wealth that's all stored up.
It's just a crazy.
It's just crazy all around.
But the,
the unfortunate part is his ideas on
pretty much everything else are pretty
fucking cool.
Yeah.
You know,
so it's like he has this dichotomy and
that's these choices that we get stuck
with your alright,
pretty good over here.
But you're totally completely
incompetent in this one area.
You know,
it's this weird thing,
these weird choices that we have to
make.
Well,
I don't think we get anything other than
that.
When it comes to established people
running for president of United States
of America,
I think in order to get to that
position,
you have to be so compromised.
You have to be so deeply entrenched in
this insanely flawed system that someone
who was really radically outside of it
is looking at it and saying,
Hey,
this whole idea is ridiculous.
Having one person running the whole
thing is preposterous.
It doesn't make any sense.
It might work if there was 50 of us and
even if there was 50 of us,
there'd be like 20 people that don't
like how it's running and but the idea
to do it with three plus million people,
it's insane.
It's insane.
It's insane to have this one guy and
then we watched.
First of all,
Bernie Sanders looks like he's a
thousand years old now.
What the fuck is he going to look like
after four years in office?
I mean,
that guy is going to be dead.
Obama looks like dog shit.
I mean he looks old as fuck right now.
If you compare him to what he looked
like seven years ago,
that is not seven years of aging at some
radically accelerated aging due to
stress and tension and the reality of
the world itself,
the massive grain of his hair.
He just looks tired all the time.
He looks like a different person.
It looks much more frail,
mean he's experiencing some insane
stress and part of that stress is a job
that you're not supposed to do.
No one's supposed to have that job.
You're not so opposed to have the weight
of the world.
You have to sleep in this fucking house
in the park.
And if people around you constantly
earpieces and guns and bulletproof cars,
look at the difference.
Yeah,
it's brutal.
The fucking difference.
We're looking at a photo right now of
Obama from 2009 and Obama from 2014 and
all my God,
I mean he looks like he's 20 years old
plus 20 years older plus and,
and really the tools to help people cope
with that kind of stress or just tools
that aren't really that prevalent and
talked about like what,
what is he doing to help mitigate that,
you know,
is he,
is he going in the float tank,
you know,
is he doing these different things that
you have to do to be able to release
some of that stress and be supported
properly?
Definitely not.
This one's fucked,
man.
This photo is fucked.
We're looking at him from 2008 and 2013.
Oh my God.
The poor bastard.
Wouldn't you love to just have that guy
to sit down with them and go,
tell me what is really going on.
Just tell me,
what is it like when you get in that
fucking office?
Uh,
who are you talking to from Halliburton?
Who,
what,
what dude pops out of a fucking a metal
grate in the ground with steam and fire
and presents to you,
you know,
he like he hands you want to pitch fork
of manifesto of ideas that,
you know,
this military industrial complex wants
you to promote any kind of leadership
position is really crazy.
I think if I was thinking about it
recently in war,
like you know,
you applaud these generals for these
great strategies,
you know,
and,
and sometimes the strategy is you put a
small number of troops in one area to
lead the main core of your enemy army
toward those troops so that you can
trick them and attack their flank or
something like that.
Classic,
like General Strategy.
But really what you're saying is,
all right,
these hundred people,
they're gonna die for sure.
Like they're gonna die for sure.
So who's up?
Who's up for that one?
Okay,
you guys,
you go into die for sure category and
then the rest of the army will come and
we'll kick some ass.
Like what a fucked up that is.
You know,
like knowingly saying that you have no
chance.
Like there's no fight.
There's no like you can run away through
the back hills,
you're going to fucking die.
That's the plan.
So that we can kick more ass over here.
I mean you have to be something of a
sociopath to be able to pull that off.
But again,
that's.
You know what these great general,
these quote unquote great generals have
all had to do is just make these crazy
decisions and being president is a
little bit a part of that too.
You have so many people that they become
like numbers and it's no longer just
each individual like,
how's this going to affect this dude?
This dude who is me living a different
life.
How's it gonna Affect that dude?
And you can't think about like that
because you go crazy if we're going to
do it.
It's just a weird dynamic,
which we're not really prepared for.
You know,
we're prepared for these kinds of tribal
dynamics where,
you know,
we're working,
we know everybody that we're leading.
There's the chief of the tribe,
maybe it's under 150 people.
If you look through anthropological
records,
that's usually how it was.
And that's generally,
you know,
the leader back in the kind of tribal
organization.
But then as it gets massive shit gets
crazy.
Yeah.
I think in war there's the ethos of the
warrior and the warrior ethos is it's a
different reality and I think for a lot
of those guys not talk to this one dude
who's a navy seal and he was explaining
that the way a lot of guys look at it
and him included was that if he died in
combat,
that he would die as a warrior and that
that would,
if he was killed by another warrior,
that is a time honored way to go and
that this is just the way.
And this is the ways pursuing that he's
accepted that way and because he's
accepted that way and all of the
exciting aspects of it,
like one of the things you talked to
people that have been to war about it,
like Jocko says,
it was the greatest time of his life.
You're not supposed to say that,
but I'm glad he does.
I'm glad he's honest about it because
when someone's honest about it,
folks like you and I that are outside of
it,
they go,
oh,
okay.
Well how do I fucking internalize this?
How do I.
How do I absorb this information and
bounce it around in my head and make it
have it make sense to me?
But he's being honest.
He's saying,
look,
this is the life I chose.
This is the path I wanted.
I'm there and I'm very excited and happy
to be there.
I'm happy to lead and I'm happy to be a
warrior.
So if you're going to die,
you know you live,
you die.
Is he wrong?
No,
it's just,
we,
we have this idea that the way we're
living is the only way to live and that
this is the wrong way to live,
but if you want to fucking make Omelets,
you gotta crack eggs,
you want to get into Ramadi,
he gonna have to shoot some bitches.
Yeah,
there's just no way around it.
And then to have that accomplished.
I mean,
I think we could all agree that there's
some bad people in the world in order
to,
to somehow or another keep those bad
from going straight up.
Hitler on us.
There's some ass kicking has to be done
in the current state of humanity the way
it is right now.
Unless we,
uh,
utilize my method from shining happy
jihad.
My 2006 CD where I say we use crop
duster planes,
fucking cover the entire Middle East
with chronic smoke for a couple months.
And even that might not work to do as a
sober up and go back to the old ways.
Unless something radical happens,
it changes humanity.
We're always going to have this struggle
between quote unquote good and evil.
And when you have evil you need,
you need ass kickers.
Yeah.
If you don't have ass kickers,
you got a real fucking problem.
So you need people that have this
warrior ethos,
this mentality to go in there and get
the job done.
And sometimes that means you have to
sacrifice troops or you have to put them
in danger.
You have to.
You have to understand that there's
going to be risks and those risks are
going to be horrific.
The results of those risks are
potentially horrific.
Yeah.
And that's absolutely what you have to
do.
It's actually something that the body
does really well.
You know,
if you think of all the cells,
like many organisms,
think about what happens when you go
into a Cryo tank.
You know when you go into a Cryo tank,
all of the blood rushes to the core of
your body to protect the most vital
parts.
You know,
your organs,
the things that you need for the whole
organism to survive the blood leaves the
extremities,
like the fingers and the toes.
It's like,
fuck it,
sorry,
fingers,
toes.
Yeah,
you gotta go,
but you're on your own,
like if you die you die.
We're going to live,
you know,
by doing that.
And that's kind of the way that these
armies have to go.
So there is certainly a model,
it's just,
I would hate to be that person that
looks out at some garrison of 100 people
and being like,
you're going in this basically suicide
mission,
so the rest of us can do.
It's a brutal thing to do.
But again,
the warrior ethos,
you know,
these people would go,
look at you and probably go,
Whoa,
you know,
like,
this is it,
this is what we're committed to,
the mission,
the mission is greater even than our
lives,
you know?
Yeah.
And there's a lot of people that look at
the way the world works and as far as
conflict and say,
well,
the only reason why we're involved in
these conflicts is because United States
is invaded all these countries and
they've done this and the foreign policy
and it's caused this and that.
And there's probably a lot of truth to
that.
There's probably a lot of truth to that,
but at the end of the day,
there has always in less,
the entire world is brought to the exact
same standards as far as standards of
living as far as access to resources as
far as just peace on earth.
If the entire world is not up to the
same standards,
you always going to have conflict and
you're always gonna.
Have ambitious people.
He always gonna have those pollutants
out there.
You always going to have these dudes
that just decide to just dominate a
country that's smaller than them or take
over an area of the world and then
you're going to have horrific human
rights violations and then you have to
make choices.
Do we allow this country that's doing
this to this smaller country and
subjugating it's people and torturing
the women and won't let girls go to
school and do we allow that to happen?
Or we decide that we're the police
force of the world and it's a.
it's a complicated question because when
you don't do anything,
then evil grows and then it becomes
really powerful and then you get to a
Hitler type situation that can happen.
People think,
well,
that's not gonna happen today.
Jesus Christ.
That was not long ago.
Sure.
It doesn't seem like if you look at
those black and white night,
fuck,
he's got his arm up in the air and
fucking people screaming.
It seems like eons ago.
Nope.
Nineteen forties,
forties,
man.
Love externalizing an enemy and you see
it now.
I mean,
it's actually starting to happen with
all Muslims,
all Muslims.
For some people have become the enemy
because instead of it makes it really
easy to define yourself against an
external force.
Where as I was saying,
it's really difficult to actually go
within and battle those internal forces
where you know,
the real conflict is raging.
It's much easier to say,
oh yeah,
the fuck and Muslims.
Yeah,
let's go get them.
You know,
and that's,
I think a tendency that we've,
all we've all had is just to go fight
these external things in this crazy
video game we call life.
You know,
we like the boss battles and we like
that kind of,
that aspect of the game because it's
very active.
It's very proactive.
You're out there with your hands and
you're swinging and you're shooting and
you're doing things.
Whereas like these,
exactly the internal battles,
you have to have a totally different
strategy.
It's the strategy of actively
surrendering,
like,
okay,
I got to let that go.
I got to let go of that attachment.
I got to see myself and be okay with my
death.
I got to.
It's like a completely reverse side of
the coin where to make progress in that
it's surrender.
Whereas to make progress and more it's
vigor,
you know,
it's like these,
these two dichotomies and I think
ultimately the way the game is best
played because if you're playing on both
sides of the coin,
you know you're playing externally with
vigor and you're playing internally with
that surrender forest and advancing on
both sides.
And that's,
you know,
that is the idea of the warrior poet.
That's the the warrior who can go
externally like Musashi and kick some
ass and then go back to his dojo and
paint colors,
calligraphy,
and tap into his internal thoughts are
in meditation or are all of these
things.
I mean,
that's,
to me the ideal one is not better than
the other.
They're both important,
you know,
just let's expand the opportunities that
we have as humans to play both sides of
this amazing game and
you know,
I think there's parallels to with what
we're talking about about the body.
Then we want things to change quickly,
but the body does not change quickly the
body.
It's sort of a long,
slow process and I think that's what's
going on with society and civilization
itself,
that there's this.
We would like,
we want war to be over.
We want everybody to live at peace.
We want everybody to have a livable wage
and you shouldn't live in poverty and we
got too many.
There's wealth disparity.
We're going to fix it all.
You know it,
it doesn't necessarily work that way.
The debate is going to start changing
people's ideas,
going to change their behavior and their
actions,
and then ultimately we would hope that
we'd get to a better place than we were
today someday.
Just like if we look back at 1200 add
and look at today,
I think we would all agree this is a way
better place.
Yeah,
yeah,
for sure.
I mean the heart of the dark ages where
it's actually literally dark outside,
but,
but also just the practices were
completely fucked.
You know,
think of the inquisition that was,
that was the most ridiculous thing in
history.
You know,
all of these people burned at the stake
for some weird idea that they were,
which witches aren't real?
Well,
it sounds a lot like what's going the
hysteria that's going on today about
Isis,
these ideologies that manifests
themselves and become toxic to all those
around them until people rally against
it or realized the folly of that way and
then change.
They meet that resistance.
They find this horrible thing in the
world and they resist it and they fight
against it and then things get better
and it's kind of like a constant cycle
that's going on that we would like to
end.
We were like,
we would like it to be over now,
please.
We would like to not have conflict,
but we've got a lot of problems.
First of all,
we don't understand each other.
It's fucking what?
How many different languages do you
know?
How many languages are there?
I don't know what the fuck those people
are saying.
I don't even know.
I see.
I have some people that I follow on
twitter that are Russian,
like a Russian fighters,
and they'll occasionally,
they'll tweet something with their crazy
Russian words.
Those Russian letters.
That one looks like a tree house.
Looks like pants,
pants,
treehouse.
What are you trying to say?
What the fuck is that like?
What is he saying?
Don't worry.
Or Hebrew.
You know,
you see people that write in Hebrew.
You're like,
okay,
what does that.
What is this?
This even these aren't even letters or
Chinese or Japanese or Korean or all
fucking Christ.
We see we can't understand each other,
so it's the idea of all of us coming to
these same conclusions and having these
same ideals when the world vary so
radically and drastically as far as
conditions and poverty and you know,
and,
and then you know,
places like North Korea that had just
been under the boot of a dictator since
the jump and they're just stuck.
They're stuck in this insanely shitty
spot.
The idea that your life in Pasadena is
going to be the same as some guy who's
stuck in North Korea who might,
you know,
as mother and father might've grown up
in prison.
I mean,
there's people that are born and raised
in prison camps.
They're,
the world's not even,
it's just,
it's just not an until we get past all
of these conflicts that we see right
now,
it's not going to be even.
It's not going to simply the United
States just stops invading these
countries.
Everything's going to be great.
It's not,
it's not going to.
It's now.
It's not going to fix North Korea,
just not.
It's way more complicated and they don't
know they've lived this way their entire
lives.
Many of them don't even know how it's
going on,
like what's going on in the rest of the
world and they're not.
They're not going to change that
quickly.
It's going to take a long ass time.
They might have to die off.
That might be what's going on with
United States politics as well.
When you're looking at what we're seeing
now with Hillary Clinton and Bernie
Sanders and Donald Trump and ted Cruz.
Get the fuck out of here.
When I'm,
when I'm looking at in my mind is like a
dying campfire so he can kick around a
few embers.
There's like a little something left
here,
but it's eventually going to die off.
I mean,
this is,
uh,
these are this.
There's no teddy Roosevelt's.
There's no JFK.
There's,
there's no fucking real leaders that are
running okay.
I think they'll only come when the
people demand that they come when the
people demand that people have
consciousness or reading them.
But now at this point we're too easily
distracted.
You know,
were they found these little hooks,
these ways to tug and pull at our
emotions and our fears and our different
things that Kinda influence us into
following these different preset paths.
It's like,
I know I'm not big into the whole
conspiracy of the whole thing,
but certainly it's very good marketing
propaganda to hook people into following
certain preset channels that keep the
establishment where it is,
but eventually that will break and I do
think that's one of the reasons why
there has been some intentional
oppression of these mind expanding
consciousness tools that are available
to us because those tend to allow you to
see the see the machine behind the
curtain.
You know,
that lets you see Oz.
You're like,
oh,
I see you pulling that lever bitch.
Like I know I kind of want to know
what's going on.
And that's a dangerous thing when you
have this big establishment that's built
on that.
But I'm really optimistic.
I think that it's going to change
because of the Internet.
I think actually a lot of these things
wouldn't have been allowed to get to
where they are if the Internet had
already been around from the beginning
because whistleblowers have been coming
out information would it spread,
but that same force,
that free spread of information is going
to start,
you know,
taking away all of these different
shenanigans and all of these tricks that
people are going on right now.
We're just kind of tolerating them,
but eventually I'll.
Tolerance will get less and less and I
think that will be an interesting and
exciting
for sure.
Yeah,
I agree.
And I also think that when you look at
the way we conduct politics today,
the way how the debates,
they all stand in the most unnatural way
possible.
You're at a podium,
which never happens in life.
When do you ever talk to a friend?
They stand in front of a podium.
Can you imagine?
Like if your girlfriend said,
hey rob,
come on over man,
I'd really love to have a conversation
with you.
And then behind a podium
and she's like,
there's your podium and this is my
friend margie and Margie is going to act
as our moderator and you're going to
state your point and then I'm going to
state my point.
We're going to have an audience and the
audience is going to cheer or respond in
turn.
Like why is there a fucking audience?
These debates,
why is there's this grand standing
opportunity where you can say what the
United States people deserve.
It's a fair wage.
What we deserve,
what we want,
equal rights,
what we want.
Black lives matter.
And when you say all these things that
make people yes,
yes,
it's,
it's all orchestrated.
It's all artificial and it's all.
It's.
It's the least natural and normal way to
communicate possible.
Normal,
natural way to communicate would be sit
down and have a conversation with these
people and try to figure out what are
your plans,
how are you going to do this?
And then the,
the rest of the world that's watching
this gets to decipher and try to figure
out,
okay,
is this guy makes sense?
Is he full of shit he nobody's talking
about.
Does he have the data that he says he
does?
Does he have the possible resources to
fix these issues and does this plan
makes sense fiscally?
Does it.
Is there their numbers to actually pull
this off or is it bullshit,
but you don't.
You don't get to that when you're.
You're involved in this debate where
there's a guy standing there talking.
There's a whole fucking crowd of people
behind him.
Then these people that are on
spotlights,
they're wearing makeup.
They have notes in front of them like,
what is this?
What is the end?
Does that person have the character and
that character under pressure?
You know,
that's one of the most important things.
Like when there's forces of pressure,
are you going to crumble?
Like even when I'm hiring,
you know,
add on it in the company,
like one of the most important things is
all right,
do you have the skills,
like what exactly what you're talking
about?
Have you done this before?
Are you capable of,
you know,
being a chief technical officer,
what's the code that you've written?
You know,
how have you been able to handle these
situations,
but then there's also like,
how are you going to handle pressure?
You know,
for me,
like that's a really important thing.
So I'll do things informally to kind of
test people out.
Like we'll go do a workout if they're
athletic,
you know,
we'll go do a hard workout and just see
kind of how they handle that external
pressure will go out and get really
drunk and go out drinking and see like,
oh,
when you're drunk,
like does some weird shit come up,
little demons that are hiding in there
that we need to find out about.
And so eventually then you get this
opportunity to see and sometimes I'm
dead wrong,
I've been dead wrong before,
but then at that point you have the
ability to just say,
Oh man,
I was wrong.
Sorry,
this isn't the right fit and you know,
you're out.
But America doesn't have that
opportunity.
Of course you could impeach somebody,
but that's this crazy process.
You know,
it's just this weird thing where you
have all of this false hype and
propaganda.
Then they're there and then they're just
there right now and it's like there's no
accountability at that point.
You don't really know what's going on.
Well,
Clinton was the last person to go
through an impeachment procedure,
right?
I mean they essentially ever get that
far.
I don't know.
I don't know what will impeachment.
We think of impeachment is being removed
from office,
but a peach meant impeachment
essentially is being forced to sit down
and review whether or not you should be
removed from office.
I think they actually get kicked out is
a different phrase,
different term,
but he was and he was on the most
preposterous thing ever.
Getting head like it wasn't.
It didn't have anything to do with how
he was running the country.
It was him lying.
The way he described this encounter with
this woman's mouth and his penis.
You know that it is.
The way he understands that was not
sexual relations.
Yeah.
What the definition of is is.
It was a great line that he had there.
Do you remember that conversation where
they.
They were grilling him and they were.
They were giving him this.
They sat down with them and they were
forcing him to recount what happened and
describe in his,
in his eyes why he felt like he wasn't
lying and he's like,
as as the way it was defined to me,
I do not think that I had sex with that
person and it was this weird fucking
dance they were doing where you're like,
what?
What are we doing here?
Like it's supposed to be about intent.
What is intent?
Like did anything,
did anything happen with that check?
Like can,
can you say that?
Did you guys hook up?
You know,
that's where hookup is like well
defined.
Hook up,
hook up.
As far as it's been explained to me.
I did not hook up with that woman.
And what is hookup?
You got to ask fucker asked to.
Mouth counts
just jerks you off of the Oval Office
desk.
That's nothing.
Nothing.
That's that.
Who Care exactly does care.
That's the crazy.
Well we care because we catch you,
we catch you.
We catch you lying.
Like that's one of the unique things
about a guy like Charlie Sheen because
in a lot of ways charlie sheen really
did sort of pull the curtain back on a
different machine,
the machine of,
of,
of sort of what is it that people have a
real issue with when someone gets caught
doing something like whether it's
smoking crack like Charlie Sheen did or
whether it's getting blown like Clinton
did.
What is it that we really have a problem
with?
I think we really have a problem with
almost more than anything is dishonesty.
And when he was onstage when Clinton.
Well it was a wherever he was,
where he's like,
I did not have sexual relations with
that woman.
When you see him say that and you know
he got his dick suck.
Do you like wait a minute.
Okay,
well what's going on here man?
Cause you,
you're not being honest now and now
we're in a situation where I know that
your horse shitting me and then okay.
And then they're going to tell you that
they caught you,
the girls got address.
Got Your calm on it.
Well hold on now.
I'm not a liar,
I just,
as it's been explained to me is how I
feel,
and then you,
you deal with all this,
you know,
this,
ah,
that feeling like that.
Whereas Charlie Sheen comes out and
goes,
look,
I was smoking rocks,
you know,
I'm a fucking winter.
I'm winning every day.
And I'm like,
all right,
you know,
that's,
that's what I do.
You know,
I,
I'm,
I'm banging hookers and smoking rocks.
You're like,
okay,
I guess we're done.
They kid fucking say anything.
What,
what are you going to say to a guy like
that?
Obviously he's not the president.
He's not running for president,
not in public office.
He's not a leader.
He's just a guy.
But he's a guy that,
you know,
was,
it is refreshing when you hear that.
I think that's what tiger woods should
have done when all that shit came out
and he should just spend like,
look,
I'm fucking tiger woods.
I'm horny.
Like,
it's,
it's me like deal with it,
you know,
instead of being a hard sell to go to
rehab and do these different things like
sex rehab,
like I could,
I could imagine that there might be some
value in that for somebody,
but I really think that's just a way for
people to retreat because of these crazy
societal norms that say we shouldn't
want to bang people.
You know,
it's like this is like the,
the approved bullshit fallback position
that all of us know is bullshit,
but you have to go play this charade,
you know,
and figure it out.
It's just,
I think we got to all start respecting
like the truth about each other.
Like everybody likes to have sex.
Like let's just fucking get over it,
deal with it.
Like it's cool.
Not only that,
but the per,
the type of people that wind up being
president,
the you,
you have to be some insanely confident
achiever and those people generally
genuinely are generally both like to
fuck,
you know.
And that's what the whole jfk thing was
all about.
Jfk was apparently like the biggest
freak of all times.
And when people who knew him,
when they see how much of these stories
are true,
it's up to,
you know,
who knows,
we really don't know.
But what you hear is the ultimate super
freak.
I mean he was just in this time where
the information didn't spread very
quick.
I mean we're just getting it now.
18 when she was in the White House and
he made her blow his friends and stuff
like that.
It was like really freaky.
Like in a pool.
I keep the woman that had an affair with
him.
I think she was like,
he had her suck some guy's Dick who was
secretary of state or something like
that in front of him in a swimming pool.
And she wrote this book like,
like a couple of years ago and it came
out like.
Or these stories were published a couple
of years ago.
It's like,
it takes so long for that information to
come out.
But if Clinton was in office right now,
like queued Lord.
Yeah,
good Lord.
What stories would come out like,
whoa,
crazy.
But if JFK was in office,
he would make Clinton look like a
fucking in in our eyes because
the data didn't get out while he was
alive.
He's a great man and that's how we look
at it.
We look at it.
He's a great man.
That was a,
a huge champion for civil rights and he
was gunned down by a horrible person who
is probably working for the CIA during
his prime.
Then.
I mean,
what about Putin?
He's got it locked down,
don't Russia.
And nobody's fucking with him in the
system.
I mean,
he's murdering people,
allegedly.
Supposedly.
Yeah.
It's a,
it's a weird.
It's a weird thing now where,
you know,
there's such a spotlight on the wrong
shit.
You know,
we get so easily distracted by these,
these things that really don't matter,
you know,
because we've set up this false
paradigm.
People aren't supposed to have sex and
people able to have the most sex in the
world.
The most powerful people,
athletes and presidents are supposed to
be faithful in this monogamous
relationship.
And I think as we look forward into the
future,
I think people are going to start to
understand each other a little bit
better and some of these expectations
are just going to drop.
I mean these were some old control
mechanisms put in by the church.
Like you want someone to be relying on
the church.
Well make them guilty for something that
they will always be guilty for,
something they cannot control,
sexual desires.
Make them guilty for that and make you
the only person to have the cure.
So create a problem that everybody's
going to have and have you be the cure
you.
You can only,
you can absolve them of their sins,
you know,
and it's this old control mechanism that
was put in place,
you know,
maybe partly to keep the society and
this kind of regimen in order,
but also to keep one particular
organization empower and isn't.
It's sort of a byproduct of our lack of
ability to read each other's minds and
truly understand what each other are
thinking.
Like this ability to find the truth and
actually get information.
The ability to disguise that,
to disguise it.
With this false morality and this Norman
Rockwell image that you're trying to
project all that leads to this like
massive confusion as to what the actual
playing field we're on really is,
and when we look at these media created
versions of our world,
whether it's murder she wrote or CSI or
a television show or a movie or a
coldplay song or some distorted version
of human beings that we absorb into our
database.
Well,
people are Clint Eastwood.
People are Charles Bronson know people
with a real clinics would the real
cleanness would as an old man who's been
divorced a shitload of times,
who gets on stage and says a bunch of
Wacky Shit.
We.
He pretends to have Obama sitting next
to him and it does this add.
It means he's doing a fucking ad libbed
speech where he said he didn't even plan
that out.
He just had obama like a fake Obama
sent.
Do you remember that from the
Republican?
Oh my God.
You never saw it?
No.
Oh,
Jamie.
You must.
It's.
It's wonderful because this is the real
clinics with the real clinics would was
the guy who was married to a woman who
made him do a reality show and I love
cleaning,
don't get me wrong,
I'm a fucking giant fan of his movies.
I'm a giant fan of the Spaghetti
Westerns and the unforgiven and no,
but who he is as a man is just a.
just an old man who's a republican and
he,
because of the fact that he's famous,
they allowed him to go on stage at this
convention or whatever the fuck it was
and give this insane speech where he had
a chair next to him and he pretended it
was Obama and he actually like was
standing over him looking down on them
like,
watch this.
This is hilarious.
You go to,
you're going to laugh your ass
ministration hasn't done enough to cure
that and whatever.
Whatever interests they have is not
strong enough and I think possibly now
it may be time for somebody else to come
along and solve the
stand up white people.
Mr. President,
how do you,
how do you handle?
How do you handle promises that you've
made when you were running for election
and how do you handle it?
How do you handle it?
I mean,
what do you say to people or do you
could just.
I know people,
uh,
people were wondering,
you don't.
Well,
I know even some of the people in your
own party who were very disappointed and
we did,
didn't close Gitmo and I thought,
well,
I think get Kale closing Gitmo.
Why close that?
We spent so much money on it,
but
I thought maybe it's an excuse.
What do you mean?
Shut up?
Okay.
It just,
I thought it was just because somebody
had this stupid idea of trying
terrorists and downtown New York City
maybe.
Yeah.
If anybody wants
us,
it's wonderful to watch because
he's,
I'm sure a nice guy.
I don't know.
Cleaning doesn't seem to be a terrible
person,
but just why close get my.
We spent so much money on it.
Well,
why don't fucking keep the gas chambers
open in Germany.
I'm sure they spent money on those two.
What the fuck kind of argument is that
why close Gitmo?
We spent so much money on it.
That is some wacky old man,
republican thinking right there.
Sure.
The.
The idea that
say that will,
what will,
what will.
Yes.
We will work closer with George Martin
glass.
Fuck he talking about.
We're talking about a place where people
are pulled out of school where people
might've went to the wrong meeting.
They might have known someone who knew
somebody and they get locked up,
put in these orange jumpsuits and stuck
in these fucking camps for a decade.
Yeah.
Maybe that's not a good idea to have
that.
You know what works.
I think you brought up a good point when
you said if people could read each
other's minds.
I think Bertrand Russell explored that,
the philosopher and he was saying that,
you know,
initially it would just be whore.
Everybody would retreat to their homes
and be like,
man,
the world's fucking crazy.
But eventually you just get kind of used
to it.
Yeah.
And then you'd be like,
oh,
everybody has these same thoughts and
these same things that are going on in
their head and then everybody could
actually start to track truth.
You know,
and just realize that,
oh,
everybody's thinking about pussy and or
Dick or whatever you're thinking about.
Everybody has these urges,
has these conflicting forces inside
their own heads.
Even weird thoughts,
weird thoughts when you're on this high
place,
that weird thought,
man,
maybe I should just jump off.
You know,
like what happened?
They're like these weird things that all
of us have that we shoved down deep in
some nook and be like,
that's not me.
That's not me.
It's not me.
You all have these fucked up things.
We all have that urge when we see a kid
making a beautiful sandcastle being man
and be funny to just knock that shit
over,
even though we'd never want to do it.
Like we have these crazy parts of
ourselves.
I think that's something that,
you know,
as I've gotten this past year,
I did some pretty the most intense
psychedelic journeys of my life,
which actually I've never talked to you
about.
Um,
but part of it was just reconciling the
fact that we're a lot of things.
We're not just the good thing that we,
that we think we are,
we're kind of everything.
We're all parts where all the good were
all of the bad and we're just a
summation of our choices.
You know,
it's really about like what we choose to
be and harnessing that,
that element of like I'm going to choose
to be someone who loves someone who's
someone who does good and brings out
into the world,
but you know,
we're in that kind of morphic field is
rupert sheldrick would say in that
capability of man is all the evil and
all the good,
you know,
the protector as well as the destroyer.
I mean all of these elements are within
the human psyche.
And really I think the key is just to
reconcile that and to forgive that.
Like,
all right,
yeah,
there's some fucked up animal parts of
me that,
you know,
get a,
get sexually aroused in certain
situations that you shouldn't get
sexually aroused in that get attracted
to violent situations when that's
actually hurting somebody and just
reconcile.
Like I'm going to choose not to indulge
any of those,
but that's a part of humanity,
like the darkness is a part of all of us
and I think that's like a key
recognition and it's enough to just
choose the light,
to choose love and to choose to be who
you want to be.
I think we're also dealing with a world
that is so complex and so fucked up in
so many different ways that to expect
someone to be balanced and perfect and
healthy is kind of insane.
Expect someone to be completely free of
any bizarre thoughts or ideas is
ridiculous because we are a product or
at least we are influenced by the world
that we live in,
right?
In the world that we live in is insanely
chaotic.
Recognizing that and talking to that
about that is a big part of the steps
that's going to take to improve whatever
society is.
However we define it,
whatever civilization is right now,
there's gonna.
There's gonna have to be steps that are
taken in order to make it better and you
got to kind of recognize that you're in
chaos.
Even if we're going to die,
okay,
this is gonna end,
it'll stop and then new people will deal
with the same questions that we're
dealing with now and hopefully we were
honest about our experiences so that
they can gain some information without
having to go through those same mistakes
themselves and that's part of what
inspiration is.
It's part of what reading biographies
were all about.
That's part of what talking to people
that are wise and ancient and you know,
unlike clinics,
would they.
They have some real like,
yeah,
you're like,
Stanley Kripner.
You can talk to some really old people
who are really knowledgeable that have
experienced some bizarre moments in life
and that have come through the other end
with some lessons and I think that
what we're dealing with is a society and
a civilization.
What would human culture is today?
Is this thing that's becoming awake?
It's going,
why are we doing this?
Like when we're looking at what we're
seeing on television in terms of these
debates that we're talking about there,
so preposterous.
Well,
they're there.
They're carrying the momentum of decades
and decades of similar debates that
they.
They feel like this is how they have to
do it.
When you watch the evening news,
what you're watching is the evening news
is the momentum of the decades of
evening news,
the expectations that people have.
If it bleeds,
it leads and these things have always
been this way and it's to change that.
It takes a long ass time,
but if you watch the evening news today
and you watched the evening news from
1930,
it is a fucking different.
Humans are different.
If you watch the way people talk from
then and the way people talk today,
if you.
If you look at movies or music or media,
things have become more complex and more
honest and I think culture is becoming
way more aware of these complexities and
the importance of this.
Honesty in art are attempts to decipher
what it means to be alive.
There are attempts to decipher what it
means to be a person.
What is the most harmonic way?
What where,
where?
How can you get through with harmonious
with the most harmonious way to get
through this experience?
What's the way to make the least amount
of mistakes and create the most amount
of happiness and have the most amount of
friends happy as well,
and what is,
how is there a zero clear way?
No is a trial and error thing that's
going on.
There's a failure and success.
There's a lessons learned sort of thing
that's going on and it's not just going
on with you.
It's not just going on with United
States of America.
It's going on with the entirety of
humans on the planet earth.
There's a learning thing and it's based
on how much data we're taking in and the
data were taken today is radically
increased.
There's so much more data than at any
other time in history that we're almost
overwhelmed by it to the point where you
just want to concentrate on gossip.
He just want to concentrate on fucking
distraction.
Meek mill and drake beefing.
You know what I mean?
It's shit.
That doesn't mean anything,
but why?
Because is this almost in a lot of those
cases,
there's comfort in the simplicity of an
affair.
There's comfort in the simplicity of a
two dudes that are going to fight and be
like,
I was watching some video of the game,
the rapper beaten up some other APP.
First of all to that dude needs to learn
how to fight both of them.
Fucking horrible to watch it's shitty
technique as a commentator.
I was appalled,
but it's,
there's something adorable about
watching some really like clear
conflict,
really obvious stuff.
It's,
it's,
it takes you away from the complexities.
It takes you away from the ambiguity of
the great picture where the great
picture I think is about information.
It's about information and,
and figuring out how to apply that in
good information.
Yeah,
and my,
one of my favorite ways to get
information is just experientially.
And again,
you know,
that's been part of my path is like
figure out,
you know,
go deep within your own psyche and get
that information out,
you know,
not just the external information about
things that are going on in the world
and these new structures that are in
place.
But like learn yourself,
you know,
learn about your own desires and
weaknesses and fears and demons and
these things that'll come up.
You know,
I remember I was in isolation for a
month and I was doing a,
what's called a [inaudible],
which is a kind of a shamonic
technology.
I wanted to try.
I was going to write my book anyway,
so made sense,
but I was basically meditating every
night and with that clarity of
meditating every night,
which is something I don't usually do.
It's,
I'm kind of like feast or famine with
that meditation practice.
But for then I was meditating every
night and it started to shine a light on
a lot of different aspects of myself.
Nope.
No,
no plants involved at all.
Like,
and I started to see,
you know,
even little tendencies that I could,
that I could cure that would come to me
in my own imagination.
Like I remember I was,
I was in a fight with Whitney and I was,
you know,
really,
really mad at her and you know,
I didn't say anything mean or call her a
bitch or anything,
but I would like wasn't returning our
calls.
Right.
And I knew kind of that was like,
that was hurting her for sure,
but I didn't about it like this,
I'm not going to answer that call she
can do with that.
And so I go into my meditation and I
start seeing this,
like this image come up of this gorilla
with these big old horns and she's
taking this stock of stock of roses and
it's hitting Whitney with the stock of
roses,
like the thorny part.
And I'm thinking like,
what the fuck is this?
Why is this in my imagination here as
I'm doing this meditation?
Then I was thinking about it.
I was intentionally not talking to her
because I knew it would hurt her,
you know,
but to me it was like my,
my mind was saying like,
as long as you don't say anything,
you're cool man,
you know,
it's all good,
but just shined a little light and like,
no,
it's not cool under any circumstance to
intentionally hurt somebody you love.
Even if it's just being quiet,
you know,
like that's fucked up too.
So you get these little pieces of
information where now all the sudden,
you know what I thought was like
unacceptable behavior.
Oh you just go quiet.
That's acceptable.
It's not being mean,
you know?
Oh No,
no,
no.
That is mean.
That is kind of fucked up because you're
withdrawing your love and you're hurting
somebody.
So these little like course corrections
that can come from the knowledge of
going within.
I think that's one of the most important
things we can do as well as absorbing
all the knowledge externally.
Like put as much focus on the inside as
the outside.
Well,
most people,
when they get involved in any sort of an
argument with somebody,
they immediately start shoring up their
defense,
you know,
fuck her,
I told her this,
and you have this whole like,
you have these walls set up,
you have your armor meant you have
every,
all your weapons.
If she says anything about that,
I'm going to bring up the time.
She fucking did this.
And that's why it's so frustrating for
people when they have a conversation
about something like,
you know,
hey,
how come you didn't put gas in the car?
You know,
you said you,
you fucking dropped the car off and I'm
fucked.
Now I've got to find a gas station.
Yeah.
Well you know,
you should have done this last week when
my friend came over and you told her
like,
what does that have to do with anything?
Just always built up resentment and the
built in defense and instead of handling
that situation like I remember dating
girls in the past that you could never
talk to them about something because
they would bring up some other shit that
was completely nonrelated and not even
address what you're talking about.
They would just talk about some other
thing that happened a month ago or six
months ago or a year ago.
Like,
oh my God,
like,
I can't.
This is not going to happen.
We can't do this.
You can't.
You can't talk about the like,
what will you need to fucking admit the
fact that you did.
That
has nothing to do with what we're
saying.
Right?
Nothing to do with what we're saying,
but they've got their defense shored up.
They've got their walls up,
they got their weapons and they're ready
to fucking go to war and that's what it
is.
You know?
It's,
and it's so easy to get stuck in these
kinds of mine because the ego wants to
be right.
The Ego wants to be superior.
The Ego's first line always is how dare
you and you want to win.
You want to win too.
Yeah.
If you don't believe that you're beyond
reproach,
even if you don't believe you're
innocent though this is a fucking game
of and you want to figure out how to get
that king knocked over.
You want to get to checkmate.
Yep.
Yeah,
and that's.
It's definitely the sticky little trap.
Whereas when you find yourself in that,
you know,
the solution has actually let the mind
with all of its manifestations go and
just focus back to the heart.
Focus back to those truths,
like the platinum rule that we talked
about like,
oh,
that's another me living a different
life.
Like that's not fucking crushed them and
when and hurt them.
Let's just see what's best for the good
of both of us and like take it back to
that simpler kind of slower truth that
we find like deep within our own
consciousness inside our heart.
And there's also a reality that some
people you got to let go because you're
not on the same path as you and they
will drag you down with that.
You know,
you should have done this and blah,
blah,
blah.
There's some people that were will
always be in conflict,
are always going to be fucking up.
They're always gonna,
not pay their taxes and being this
constant state of fucking chaos.
They're always going to be caught lying.
They're always going to be doing this or
stealing or there's people that are
going to always do something wrong and
you can't keep them in your life because
they have to find their own path.
Even if that is you living another life,
you're not helping them by enabling them
now,
by continuing the cycle of like makeup,
like fight makeup,
fight makeup,
come to some acknowledgement within
denial afterwards,
you you will be caught in their own
conflict and that same sort of thing
where I said that the complexities of
life oftentimes lead us to pay attention
to simple,
stupid shit like you hear Kanye is going
to get divorced from Kim because Ron,
well,
what is that?
It's like you're.
You're looking for some simple stupid,
clearly,
easily defined shit to distract you from
the complexities of the world.
Well,
if you get involved in a friendship with
someone that's really fucked up and,
and you know,
steals from you or just have some
horrible shit going on,
that debt will take away from all the
other stuff that you're doing.
It will become a massive part of your
life and that conflict,
which may you may be completely
innocent.
He might not have anything to do with
it,
but you're trapped with this person that
might have a drug addiction.
Like if you have someone like for
people,
a lot of people that have family members
that are hooked on drugs,
it's insanely,
extremely frustrating because they'll
like,
uh,
I know guys who have stolen from their
own mother to pay for their drug habits.
Yeah.
Could you imagine you have a child and
you raise your child and your child is
stealing from you to pay for drugs and
you're kind of in denial about it and
you,
but you're trapped.
You're in this conflict with this person
and there's almost no way in your mind
to fix it,
to make it better.
And it becomes your life.
You know,
if you have a child and your child
constantly in and out of jail and you
know,
fucking up and doing horrible things,
you,
you become trapped by that relationship
that you have.
You have,
you have a right to your own happiness
and we got to make sure that you protect
that,
you know,
and these people who are living on
compulsion,
it's almost like they've forgotten their
forgone,
their right to choose their ability to
choose their compulsion.
It's compulsion for more drugs.
That's compulsion for more emotional
turbulence.
It's compulsion for needing something
like that.
And those people are naturally like the
hardest to be around because they don't
have that stillness where they can,
you know,
kind of wrangle their ability to choose,
to me like choices,
like breath,
like it's going to happen no matter
what.
We're going to make decisions no matter
what,
just like we're going to breathe no
matter what you know.
But then there's also the ability to
wrangle your choice and decide how you
breathe.
Maybe
deep breath,
you take control and you actually can
maneuver with that choice and actually
start to make reasonable decisions of,
you know,
acting on your own volition rather than
compulsion and getting people around you
who are also able to do that is so key
because then you can actually have some
freedom to make decisions and to build
cool shit or to explore cool things or
have,
you know,
have a lot of fun and those are the
people that I think are going to be the
most beneficial to be around.
Yeah.
And also you build momentum together.
That's the thing about having friends
that are like really happy and fun and
warm and,
and doing what they want to do.
Like when I have friends that are
successful,
it makes me excited about success.
If I have friends that are involved in
good things,
everything's going great.
It gets me excited about doing more
myself,
getting more good shit done,
enjoying life more.
And then when you spend time together
there's all this fun and laughter and
it's like good times.
Whereas if you're involved in these
negative patterns and these patterns of
like constant chaos and mistakes and
deception and Horse Shit and addiction
or whatever the fuck it is,
those patterns seem to just be overwhelm
everything else in life.
Yeah.
One of the most impactful things that I
did last year was I went on that summit
at sea cruise and I thought it was not
going to be that cool,
but what was the most cool part?
There was some great speeches,
some good content.
Is it what is summit?
It's so.
It's like a curated group of
entrepreneurs,
thought leaders,
musicians,
artists,
different people who have.
They've invited to come basically hang
out for a little while and interact and
so there's some speeches and people give
content.
There was the CEO of Uber and a Schmidt,
the ex ceo of Google and there was a
bunch of.
Bob Pittman was there,
gave a great speech and Shep Gordon,
the famous music agent.
So a lot of like bigger names.
They are giving speeches and doing their
thing,
but there's just the general guest lists
with people who were somehow,
you know,
doing something cool,
but what the effect was is having 2,500
people who generally all,
everybody there
had the attitude of we can do anything,
we can totally do anything.
Like anything is possible.
Like just the effect of being surrounded
by 2,500 people who all believed that
anything was possible was just fucking
super inspiring because you never,
you never,
you know,
aggregate that many people who feel like
that those are the anomalies and most
people are like,
oh man,
fml,
this fucking sucks.
You know,
you get a good mix of both of those
things,
the inspiring people and the people who
were kind of bummed out and that's
fucked my life for people going
and so,
but being on the boat like everybody
believing like,
yeah,
anything's possible.
What are we going to create?
How are we going to do this?
What's the social problem?
What's this thing?
Just that alone was worth it,
you know,
to just be like,
man,
that was fucking cool because your mind
takes in all of that.
You kind of like absorb it if that's.
If that's the norm around you.
You know,
like there's a lot of people say that
you're the average of your five best
friends.
Like if that's the norm around you,
you start to believe that even more
strongly to like,
fuck yeah,
it's possible.
Like what do we want to do?
What,
what do we want to create?
Isn't that why being in a really
horrible neighborhood is so insidious,
like being born and raised in a horrible
neighborhood is so insidious because
you're kind of trapped by your
environment a lot of ways,
but that's what one of the things that
people that you know have that pull
yourself up by your bootstraps mentality
don't take into account.
It's like these people,
they don't see that.
Like where are they getting this?
Or you're asking them to build an
insane,
raging fire with nothing but wet trees
and to rocks to bank and stuff like
that.
Pull yourself up by your bootstraps.
I've done it well,
no,
you had a fucking lighter.
Okay,
and you had newspapers and you had dry
wood and you had a fireplace in a
beautiful mansion and you were watching
people build fires your whole life.
You know,
and everybody knew how to build a fire.
So this idea that everyone starts on a
level playing field and you just need to
escape from your environment because
you're ambitious and you know you're,
you only ambitious if you're allowed to
be ambitious like you.
You have to have someone around you that
has some sense of difference that
there's some.
Something can be done that,
that is more,
more pleasurable,
something can be done that is better.
You can improve upon your surrounding
you.
You have to see that if you don't see
that,
you just assume,
well,
this is how we live.
We scratch and claw where like the
chimps in the jungle that steal from
each other and beat each other over the
head.
And then we're going to have to figure
out a way to survive.
And the way to survive is scratch and
claw.
Well,
if you're in,
you know you live in some horrible,
poor neighborhood and that's how it is.
Everybody is survival of the fittest
around you all the time,
all the scratching and clawing and
that's your reality that you have to
adapt.
You have to stay alive that way and
that's the dark ages.
That's the inquisition.
That's like your.
This is the environment you're in.
It's so hard to escape the environment
or to change it.
If you're stuck in a situation like
savior in like some isis occupied city
right now,
like what?
What are you going to do?
Think positive.
What are you going do?
Go to yoga.
The fuck are you going to do you know
you,
you have to.
Reality is a motherfucker and you have
to accept the situation that you're
presented with.
If you,
if you don't,
this idea that you could somehow or
another rise above just simply by
thinking positive and doing the right
thing.
Well no,
your,
your situation is constant conflict.
You involved in that.
Unless you can figure out some sort of a
way to end that across the board with
the entire country.
The entire world,
the,
the planet earth,
all of humanity.
We're always going to have issues.
We're always,
you know,
there are certain circumstances though
where that kind of external pressure,
everything being so fucked up,
we'll crack most people like you're
saying,
but then they'll occasionally be.
These diamonds are formed.
You know,
these people who define themselves
against this horrible resistance around
them and because it was so hard for them
to build the fire,
to use that analogy with their wet ass
newspapers and these two flints and
they've just been striking and striking
and striking when they actually do it.
Their skills that they bring to the
table,
they're the baddest motherfuckers
around.
So occasionally it can create these
masterful human beings that are just
defined in greatness by their struggle
coming up.
And I think we all know a lot of those
people.
You even,
I think at one point said,
you know,
show me the great man that's a son of a
great man because you know that you do
need some of this resistance to really
be as you know,
as magnificent as you can possibly be in
a lot of circumstances.
But yeah,
in general it's hard because while
there'll be one diamond,
there'll be,
you know,
a thousand pieces of crushed call that
it's just the pressure of the
environment is not supportive for the
general population.
It's also like that movie,
um,
was that band movie where they were,
there was that a composer who was trying
to get,
he was the state,
like the farmer's insurance guy who was
a composer and he won like Academy
Awards,
Farmer's insurance guy.
He was a fuck,
I can't remember.
But anyways,
he was like,
he was a composer or like a,
um,
yeah.
And he was basically taking one of his
students and he would,
he would take his students and he was
like the worst coach ever,
like just recently.
So in whiplash,
you know,
it was the most brutal hours insurance
guy.
The guy from Oz.
Yeah,
the screamer.
Yeah.
So he would have,
he died the most brutal methods for his
whole people.
I mean,
they're playing until their fingers were
bloody and he just basically broke
everybody.
He broke everybody.
And what he was waiting for was that one
diamond to emerge,
right.
And a lot of have that kind
of mentality.
Like we'll break them down,
we'll break everybody and then there'll
be this greatness that comes.
Well,
it's really like super rare that that
happens.
And generally like not worth it,
you know,
like why not like have people enjoy
music and lead by inspiration instead of
this.
Let's just fucking break everybody and
hope that that one time you strike the
hammer down,
it doesn't break and the hammer breaks
instead because you've actually struck a
diamond.
It's just kinda like weird ethos that I
think a lot of coaches and a lot of
people have.
My High School basketball coach had that
same thing.
Like he was willing to make the entire
basketball season miserable,
completely miserable in order to try and
get something out of the players,
which never happened.
We lost in the first round of the
playoffs,
no matter how highly ranked we were,
because part of our motivation is just
to get the fucking season over because
we hated him.
Fucking hated him.
So we had like mixed motivations,
effective coach.
And an ineffective and so,
but there is that.
You do create occasional diamonds with
pressure,
but for the most part it just crushes
most people and sometimes those
diamonds,
they become like a guy like Nelson
Mandela,
that sort of elevated entire culture,
right in their King Nelson Mandela,
these different individuals who you know
were defined by this,
by this intensity.
So it's not to say that it's a hopeless
situation.
It can create the greatest of the great,
but it's going to be a real fucking
challenge.
It is,
and for most people,
expecting those folks that are in that
environment to to behave the same way as
people that live in a gated community in
Pasadena,
just it's completely unrealistic in.
And that was the trump point.
It's like,
c'mon man,
like you.
You've had not just a silver spoon.
You've had the entire cutler early line
in your mouth since you were a baby.
You were born with it.
The whole thing is it's,
it's unfair.
It's unfair and uneven.
It's bizarre to me that some folks don't
recognize that,
that they don't see it.
They don't.
They don't look at it like,
wow,
there's,
there's a lot of conflict out there.
There's a lot of different conditions.
They vary.
It vary so much.
Yep.
I think there's also a tendency to say
that,
you know,
to expect people who do,
who are wealthy to just be totally happy
and totally like avid together.
Look at all the advantage you have when
a lot of times you see these people,
they're pretty fucked up,
you know,
but society says,
look,
you've had every opportunity.
You know,
you didn't have to struggle,
you should be fine.
Well,
again,
those internal forces or a motherfucker,
you know,
and if you're not dealing with those
right,
doesn't matter how much money you start
with,
you're going to have problems.
You have all the money to access all the
drugs in the world.
You have all of the ways to escape and
not any of the tools,
you know,
to actually help you overcome those.
So in a lot of cases you see the
children of these really wealthy people
are some of the most fucked up people
you know,
around there.
Just.
Yeah.
It's just a really interesting thing.
Like you'd rather hang with somebody in
a super poor neighborhood
who's just real and down to earth and
mostly they have their shit together way
more than someone living in one of these
mcmansions somewhere.
Well,
they've been forced to deal with
conflict.
They'd be forced to find solutions.
They've had been forced to develop
character.
We define success too much by Zeros,
by numbers,
by yeah.
How much do you have?
How much money do you have?
That's the ultimate goal of success
instead of are you a happy person?
I was listening to this Ted talk and it
was a woman who was a model and she was
talking about how she hit the genetic
lottery.
She was really honest about it.
She's like,
for better or for worse,
you know,
this is what has been my life.
This is,
this is my existence.
And she said that a lot of people have
this idea about what makes you happy.
If my legs were thinner,
I'd be happy.
If my hair was Shinier,
If my face was,
my bone structure was better,
I'd be happy.
She said,
but models in general are some of the
most unhappy,
insecure people on the planet,
and she's like,
I'll tell you,
I am insecure.
Like all my friends are insecure.
They are crazy.
There are all these nutty fucking models
that are dealing with bulemia and
Anorexia and speed and all these
different methods that they use to keep
their body weight down and all the fear
they have of aging and you know,
should I get botox and what treatments
should I be doing?
And they're constantly in this state of
chaos and fear and a lot of it is over
this weird gift that they have that
becomes almost a prison,
a prison to maintain this garden of
beauty that you've been bestowed with
from birth without any work at all.
I mean,
we've all seen people that are just
fucking beautiful.
They just have a written and everyone's
drawn to them genetically.
And why?
Why is that?
Well,
because nature wants you to come in that
person to make people like them because
they have good symmetry and it's really
that simple.
But that poll,
that genetic poll is so overwhelming
that we use it to sell cars and we use
it to sell fucking condos and you know,
anything,
a woman with long legs,
you know,
stepping into a car,
looking at you,
they're here,
makes you want to buy that car for
whatever fucking stupid reason.
And this idea that we have that.
If I have that,
I would be happy.
No,
because look at the people who have it.
How many people who are super wealthy,
how many Wall Street people in Manhattan
right now are ready to jump off a
fucking building?
Their freaking.
They might have 100 million dollars in
the bank.
They might be rich as fuck,
but they're miserable.
They hate.
They're just want to do coke.
And the other thing about people that
are successful is oftentimes what
they're doing is not pleasurable but
the.
But the reward is the numbers.
The reward is having numbers so they
indulge in that reward where they want
to buy versace
and wear a rolex and have a this and a
that and live in that or this and always
keep up with the Jones'.
And always have this quantified results
that they can show success.
Like,
look,
I've got,
you know,
in my day I've achieved blah blah,
blah,
and I've got a all of them,
but who are you and are you happy?
And that's not something that you can
put down on a,
on a ledger,
you can't show that.
You can't have a spreadsheet that shows
your happiness.
Yeah,
I mean I've,
I've been in all different types of
circles from being indigenous places
where they have virtually nothing in
hanging out with local tribes in Africa
and South America and different places
than I've been at.
I was at a birthday party where the
musical lineup was John foggerty
stinging and like some other crazy pan
at a birthday party.
Right.
Who's fucking birthday party present.
Yeah.
I don't know if I should mention her
name,
but yeah,
it was a big hedge fund trader that was
an old family friend.
How much they spend,
who knows?
Countless,
countless millions,
you know,
and not a party on a party for his
birthday.
So I was there and color for sure on the
other way.
They're happier.
That guy's out there,
so it was a weird thing though,
because you know,
he was actually pretty happy.
He's a,
he's a,
he's a hunter and he's a.
he's a cool dude and he was throwing the
party more for his guests than himself,
which made him actually happier.
He was like the happiest person there
because he was like,
let me give you guys this,
this awesome thing,
but the majority of the people there,
you could just feel I got pretty high
before I went because I was by myself
and I could just feel the sadness.
It reminded me of when I walked through
the red light district in Amsterdam or
it was just like the sadness,
like nobody was giving these people like
a real hug.
It was always a,
let me give you a hug and try and take
your money and give you a hug.
Try and take your money.
And they were just so guarded by that
whole paradigm that they've been in.
You know,
there's just these challenges that are
across the board that we have to
recognize in these traps,
like the trap of more money.
The trap of social media,
when you know a girl posts something in
a sexy photos and then looks immediately
refresh,
how many likes,
how many likes this quantification of
how pretty you are,
and then you start to live by that and
then if you get less than that all,
fuck,
I only got 60 likes on that.
Better slot it up.
Maybe I'm getting too old.
Maybe any more botox.
I'll do it as a new treatment of vampire
treatments.
Stab your fucking skin.
Put baby blood in there.
Yeah,
exactly.
So it's just traps and this were things
a lot.
I have a few girls that are follow on
instagram just to look at their but
pictures just to show how many different
ways can you stick your butt out.
How long can you keep doing this?
And there's this one girl,
her entire fucking instagram is her and
her underwear sticking her butt out in
various ways or her at the gym and what
might as well be her underwear.
You know,
jen selter got really famous that way.
That was one of the instagram checks had
like millions of followers just from
showing us photos.
Just ridiculous.
Shell fast.
Yeah.
That just came out and said she is a
real though,
right?
Like she has legs to that go along with
it.
It looks real.
It looks real when they don't have the
legs.
It's like,
wait a minute.
Why is all that weight in your ass?
Anatomically,
it's like having boulder shoulders but
having like little skinny arms.
Why are your shoulder so big?
It doesn't make sense.
Is that her?
Jesus Christ.
What a good kid.
Look at that,
but it's go to go to some better ones
were the ones right next to it in our
dress.
See down below,
down below,
wherever the photo that you were at sea.
Go to the right there.
You all pay up.
Oh good Lord.
She just sticking her ass out and every
photo,
she's got that right.
Kind of little sway back thing,
but girls were like,
look at her face.
Now she's not even that [inaudible].
Guess what girls?
Good enough
here to let you know the ass.
It trumps all those cheek bones,
all the,
all the other stuff that you're worried
about.
I don't know if that's real.
That's a tricky.
That's a tricky trap for her because
she's just obviously,
I don't know obviously,
but there's going to be a seduction is
going to say,
you know,
I define myself by how attractive my ass
is.
Like that's where a lot of she's going.
She's scoring winds and her book based
upon those instagram followers and
likes.
At a certain point she's going to be a
40,
50 year old woman in the ass is going to
sag and it's gone or Kurzwell with
fucking science.
Kurzweil figures it all it permanent
giant ass,
but you know,
I think that that's an issue that
particularly for females is something
that's a problem when you put that much
emphasis on beauty being and it's not
female's fault,
it's society and everybody's fault.
You put that much emphasis on beauty
being one of the defining self worth
characteristics.
Then when that starts to go,
you're in this mad fucking scramble for
as much surgery as possible to restore
this youth rather than appreciating the
gifts that each age bring.
Like each aid should bring more wisdom
and like,
like the older obsolete as like that
that you see down in the jungle that
have fucking magic that they're able to
bring like,
yeah,
I'm not young and beautiful anymore,
but I've lived 65 years.
I'm tuned into my instincts and I can
fucking bring magic.
I can heal with herbs.
I can do these different things.
That's all well and good,
but their instagram pictures of shit.
Version Celta pisses on those.
Go Fuck Yourself.
Old Magic Lady in the jungle.
Look at these yoga pants fixtures.
Fucking yoga pants have revolutionized
the world,
changed everything changed the game when
you could look at a girl naked without
her being naked,
but better than naked because it's all
compressed like it's not.
It's not like you don't see the sloppy
aspects of skin and flesh and tissue and
deposits.
Just that beautiful
pressed in shape and that shape is so
deeply ingrained in the human brain.
The colors of a flower,
you know,
you get your whole legs are all pink.
It's amazing.
It's a bright pink,
a shocking bright pink or white or like,
whoa,
it's a white rose,
right?
Like a total hack in your psyche.
Like the monkeys that have those colored
butts.
Totally freak out the monkeys out.
What the fuck is that?
That boone ass fucking goddamn explosion
of fireworks coming out of their
asshole.
They should be baboons,
yoga pants.
The most popular yoga pants would maybe
be too much.
It was just all flesh color,
just all normal and then just fold
baboons.
It would be too much asking too much.
It's weird.
Also,
shapes,
shapes become insanely attractive.
Like I was looking at pornography the
other day and the girl had a natural
body and it's so weird when you see
natural tits,
big natural tits juggling around.
She had a natural ass.
I was like,
wow,
this is fascinating.
Like these,
these are fat deposits that are very
attractive because they're.
They're really good when you get
pregnant.
If you're pregnant,
you should have wide hips.
The baby comes out easier.
Hip to waist ratio,
hip to waist ratio has been shown by
scientists to have a drug like effect on
heterosexual males.
Like it literally is a drug.
There's a hip to waist ratio.
That's almost like when a man sees a
girl with small ways in a big ass
your your body,
your body just goes,
Eh,
man on deck man on deck.
Like you're going,
you're about to go to war.
Like it's time to be on your toes.
Like there's a drug and that drug is
right there.
It's an ass.
It's an ass and it's a form.
It's a shape.
But if you see someone and she's got the
the back and ass of a Guatemalan
housekeeper,
you know where they have like that
really the like the hat,
the ass to weight ratio is nonexistent,
is a,
a parallel line like the twin towers
from her shoulders down to her hips and
was with,
you know,
there's just a weird sort of body and a
flat ass.
And like for whatever reason that is
completely unattractive,
she sidestep to a wall.
All parts would touch at the same time.
You don't want that.
Well,
it's weird like that.
These shapes have these ingrained the.
They're quantified in our brain,
like you see these girls in their yoga
pants,
like that girl that has the millions of
instagram pages.
If the Guatemalan housekeeper with her
big wide back in her flat ass had the
same poses,
like nobody would care.
We need what we're looking for certain
shapes.
Yeah.
There was even a theory that,
you know,
the reason
why people like cleavage and I don't
know if this theory is accurate,
but that cleavage actually reminds our
brain of what a butt crack looks like.
And so that's one of the reasons why
it's sexually attractive to males.
That shape of those lumps of fat pushed
together in that kind of format is like
a trick into our brain where it's like,
oh,
an ass on the chest.
That makes sense.
Kind of.
But it also makes sense that,
you know,
if the tits are that big,
they're touching together and once you
were released,
those mamas pop that snap on the Bra and
they come out to play.
Whoa.
It's another bizarre one.
Like tits or magic.
They are fucking magical.
Nipples are magic when they get hard,
when you're sucking on a nipple and it
gets erect like that is a magic moment.
There's something exciting about that.
Yup.
It's a fucking cool world we live in.
You know,
I sometimes think like if we were all
just consciousness and more in reality
didn't exist in this world,
didn't exist,
and we were like,
man,
what should we do?
Well,
let's create the fucking coolest video
game ever.
You know,
something that has lots of boss battles
and challenges and different things you
can do and you can have sex and it feels
amazing and you can accumulate things
and you interact with other players.
It's like the most massive multiplayer
online experience possible and like,
yeah,
let's do that.
Oh,
I got an idea.
Let's make it so that you think it's
totally real when you're playing the
game,
you don't know it's a game.
And then it was like,
fuck yeah,
that game is even better.
And I kind of feel like that's really
what we're doing here.
We're in this like the best possible
video game that we could create and it's
so good because we think it's fully real
and it's such a good game that we can
create mini games within the game and
actually play video games in our video
game and those are awesome too.
Know it's like the most crazy thing that
we've done and then we get back,
you know,
and in my believe that,
when we're done with this experience,
we get back and we get to look and go,
wow,
that was a crazy fucking turn.
And then get to decide like,
yeah,
let's go again.
Let's do it.
Let's play in this world,
you know,
earth world.
And maybe there's another world.
I don't know if there is,
but maybe there's another world and you
can say,
Oh man,
that's playing that fucking world.
That world looks fun.
You know,
and there's just this opportunity.
And I think at least even having that
perspective really gets me to appreciate
this even more like,
yeah,
there's struggles,
but every video game is going to have
those struggles.
It's gonna have that thing where you can
barely beat it and it takes you a long
time.
That's like a good game.
It's like it's just challenging enough
where if you apply yourself completely
and you're at the edge of your skill,
you can win.
Otherwise,
if it's too easy,
it's not fun.
You throw that fucking game away real
quick.
Yeah.
Unless you live in the Congo,
then you game sucks and your game,
you're in a level that's really too
hard.
Blows get parasites and malaria and
fucking war lords.
Shit.
This game's dogs playing halo with a
bunch of professionals that just fucking
headshot you all day like I
can't even play.
Yeah,
well,
I'm fascinated by simulation theory.
I'm fascinated by the fact that there's
actual physicists that are bantering and
throwing around this idea that it is
possible that at one time in the future,
in the near future,
perhaps like within the next 20 or 30
years even,
that they're going to be able to create
an artificial reality that's
indistinguishable from the reality we're
currently experiencing.
You are going to be able to enter into a
fake world,
whether it's through some sort of a a
chip that they can put into your mind or
whether it's some sort of a virtual
reality headset that you put on that
allows you to interface with some sort
of computer stimulation.
That's it makes it indistinguishable
from reality.
We're currently experiencing that.
We're going to come to a point in time
where it gets so good you can't tell if
it's really not,
so how do we know if we're not already
in it?
How do we know?
How do we know if that isn't the entire
process?
Being some sort of bizarre fractal thing
like that.
From the time a cell divides into two
cells,
becomes a multicellular organism,
becomes a more complex multicellular
organism,
become sentient,
becomes something that's creative,
become something that's not just
creative,
but can manipulate its environment,
has articulating fingers that change the
atmosphere around it,
changed the physical world in which it
lives,
alter the weather,
alter the structure of the things that
are around them and then gets to the
point where creates an artificial world,
creates a world that's so complex and so
bizarre that it only exists in ones and
zeroes,
but is indistinguishable when you
interface with it,
that when you interface with it there as
well,
is that a real world?
Who's to say it's not?
Who's to say your worlds real?
If you get deep into your world,
if you go deep into the subatomic realm,
what is that?
It's all fucking space and and magic.
When you get into the world of subatomic
particles.
I have tried so hard to understand.
I've watched lectures and listen to
people give speeches about quantum
theory and about the interaction of
subatomic particles.
Particles that are in superposition,
which means they're still and moving at
the same time.
There was one of two possible outcomes.
They blink in and out of existence.
Observance of them is what decides which
one they are.
That's crazy.
Well,
how about the fact that they go away and
we don't know where they go and then
they reemerge somewhere else.
They blink in and out of existence so we
have no explanation for it based on our
current understanding or a current
ability to measure what's happening.
Maybe that'll get more complex and I'll
have some more answers in the future
when they get better at figuring this
stuff out,
but the current understanding of
subatomic particles when they get into
things like superposition is like you're
dealing with magic.
You're dealing with something that
literally if you.
If you.
If it didn't exist and you tried to say,
Hey,
I'm going to create something that
exists and doesn't exist as something
that's moving and still I'm going to
create something that's here and then it
goes away and we don't know where it is
and it comes back in another place.
People would go,
shut the fuck up,
just shut up.
You're talking about nonsense,
but that's not nonsense.
That's subatomic particles.
These are.
This is.
This is a real acceptable aspect of of
the scientific method.
They've gotten down to this,
they've examined this and this is
accepted across the board,
but these people that study it,
well,
what does that even.
How is that more real than this
simulation that someone's created with
the computer that makes you feel like
you really are running from dinosaurs in
Jurassic Park,
you feel the wet leaves under your bare
feet as you're sprinting away from a
fucking raptor.
How did.
How has that more real?
What is real and what is not real?
That's going to get real fuzzy.
That's going to get real strange when
you have to define reality.
When you know that this desk that I'm
hitting on is filled with Adams and
those inside those atoms.
It's mostly space.
We don't understand why there's so much
empty space,
but what is in there like?
Why is it hard?
Like why?
How come when I knock on this?
It's hard,
but when I put my hand through water,
it doesn't water of Adam's to like
what's going on here,
like what,
what is real and what's not real or are
definitions of what's real and what's
not real or what can I put on a scale?
What can I put a ruler across and
measure,
you know,
what,
how am I,
what can I sell you?
What can I put a barcode on and package
it and sell it at whole foods?
What is,
what is real and what's not real?
I think that the way that in my
explorations go in as deep as I possibly
can,
which is where I generally turn first,
is the way that I've understand that
understood it,
is that collectively we did create kind
of a simulation and at least in my own
experiences,
you know,
illuminated in my own imagination
perhaps,
but collectively we did create a
simulation and that simulation was led
by,
you know,
just intent.
The desire to say,
yeah,
let's do this.
Let's have,
let's have a physical manifest.
Let's have things that we can knock our
knuckles on and have this opportunity to
do it collectively as that,
as that unified force,
kind of like the one voice in our body
that collectively makes decisions even
though we have all of these other
organisms all vying for different
things.
Collectively.
There was a yes and then there was like
an intelligence in place led by the
sacred geometry.
That very quantum stuff that makes
things stuff.
Then that artificial intelligence
created the perfect solution for that
initial intent which led and then
ultimately leading us and maybe other
sentient beings who could potentially
create other worlds downstream as well,
you know,
and it could just continue with creating
other and then eventually those sentient
beings that have been created from the
intent and allowing rules like
artificial intelligence or sacred
geometry.
Allowing those rules to create the world
perfectly.
Because if you're actually trying to
program that Shit's too complex.
Not Possible.
But if you have rules in place like all
right,
this artificial intelligence,
we'll figure it out according to these
different laws of evolution and
reproduction will make these things
combined together in certain ways.
And,
and that's,
that's the rules of the system and it
will flourish in a certain way that will
survive until eventually there'll be
other,
you know,
God,
so to speak,
these other sentient beings that then
couldn't create eventually downstream
worlds when their ability to create
artificial intelligence in these other
rules will happen and that can go to
infinity,
you know,
and we may be somewhere in that infinity
of,
you know,
and it just goes on forever and that's
this mind blowing kind of thing where
you're like,
Holy Shit,
you know,
like we could be in a simulation that's
part of a simulation,
going to create another simulation,
you know,
like we're,
we're our own universe in the
multiverse,
creating a micro verse which is a
universe and it's own multiverse and
just,
it just goes on forever.
Just like that.
We're not even high.
We're sober stone cold sober.
These full console owners.
No,
incorrect.
I have a theory about artificial
intelligence.
I think the idea is very flawed.
The premise is flawed.
It is intelligence.
It's not artificial.
What's artificial?
It's created on earth with materials.
Why is it natural?
It's created with come and it's not
natural if it's created with silicon
chips and it doesn't make any sense like
it is intelligence,
but it's intelligence that's not
biological in origin in the sense of
it's not based on the cellular structure
that all biological entities on earth
possess.
Like it's something that's made with
human beings manipulating the raw
materials of the earth and creating
something through programming,
through,
uh,
you know,
where the fuck they make computers.
Whatever processes are involved that
creates this intelligence,
but it's not artificial at all.
It's 100 percent real.
You know,
if you eat,
like my kids have a kitchen set and eat
one of their fake tomatoes,
you're eating a fucking piece of plastic
that's an artificial tomato.
That's hard official.
This is not artificial intelligence.
It's actual intelligence,
but it's intelligence is created by
people that have manipulated the raw
materials of earth and then looked at
their own shortcomings and sort of
modeled this idea of a future being
based on correcting what they see is
wrong with themselves.
But in doing so,
what are we gonna?
What are we going to do to what we are?
I mean that's the big fear of artificial
intelligence is if we create something
better than us,
we have to come to the realization that
we are.
It's so flawed that we cannot be
repaired.
Like the idea of coming in people and
getting them pregnant and then a baby
comes out of their pussy and then
someone comes in that baby and you know
when they become an adult and that the
baby has a baby that comes out of their
pussy and then we see that's the only
way we do it.
That's it.
It's the only way.
It's the way it's been because the
future is the past is no,
it's not.
It's not.
It is a way to get to the point where we
create these beings that are far
superior than the what our biology is
capable of making.
I think you may be right,
but I think we're in this hurry to do it
when I think we should just be like,
man,
this is the fucking golden age.
Genitals aren't going to be around
forever.
Like,
let's enjoy the shit out of this right
now.
Like I really feel like we're in this
transition point where we still have
those base or animal instincts that no
fucking good,
but eventually I think you're right.
We will transition out with whatever
Kinda Kurzweilian ways that we can
transcend death and you know,
have different reproduction done in
different way.
Like those grey aliens with no genitals,
you know,
and these different ideas of,
of a different way to do it.
But you know,
those guys are looking at us like,
man,
that must be fucking fun.
You know,
there's some shitty fights,
but it's fun.
You could still get a muscle car.
They're still legal before they get to
this point where they're just going to
be these fucking automotive.
These cars are going to be all automated
and everything's going to be self
driven.
There's going to be no excitement to
that.
And then there's gonna be no sex.
People are going to figure out a way to
make the same feeling that you get from
sex available on your command.
You know?
Have you ever been in the hospital and
they give you one,
those morphine drips when you.
I got my knees operated on back in the
nineties and it was the real painful
method where they do the Patella tendon
graft,
so they cut a piece of bone out of your
Shin and take a strip out of your
patella tendon and they take a chunk of
the bone and your Shin and they open you
up like a fish and then replace your acl
with this piece of your Patella is
painful as fuck.
And so when you're in the hospital they
immediately put you on this motion
machine and this motion machine.
Your legs sits on this thing and it
constantly bends and straightens.
Bends and straight and spends is right
after the surgery,
like immediately after and then they
give you this morphine button and every
time you hit that bitch
you just get just stoked up with
morphine and it's amazing.
You just sit.
There you go,
Woo.
So the only time I've ever done quote
unquote morphine,
I've known,
I've never experienced like opiates
before.
Other than that,
and it was fucking wild.
I was like,
Ooh,
good thing.
This isn't available all the time,
but we could easily get to a point
sometime in the future where the idea of
going on tinder to try to find someone
to fuck is outrageously stupid.
Why
would you do that when you can just like
how you plug in your phone to recharge
it.
You're going to plug in and
experiencing like the love of the mother
Gaia,
like,
like the swarming fractal.
Love that you get an a dmt experience,
pure.
Just pure pleasure and pure experience
of,
of just understanding and affection and
all of it wrapped up in this warm,
beautiful accepting,
embrace or you know,
I told you this and you went and did
that,
and then I was like,
fuck you and you if I can,
you might fucking cheap my friends.
My friends tell me,
you know,
my friend Cheryl says,
Nah,
I don't want to do it anymore.
You don't have to do it anymore.
And then because of the fact that people
kept doing this over and over and over
again,
our dicks has shrunk and shriveled up
inside of our bodies.
And then we become those gray aliens.
That's what we become.
We ruin our atmosphere to the point
where we have built in sunglasses,
those big goddamn black eyes.
Our heads become huge because we use
telekinesis now.
Uh,
we don't want them to need muscles
because we don't pick anything up
anymore.
And if you look at our muscles in
comparison to a champ,
you know,
look at the,
you've seen those photos are of chimps
with mange hairless champs and like
Jesus Christ will,
they have to have muscles like that.
It's how they get the trend is clear,
you know,
which way we're going.
Great.
He's just now is an opportunity to just
really enjoy the shit out of it because
they know because it's going to go,
you know,
I think at some point,
and you know,
I mean there will be some good aspects
of that,
you know,
I think for sure there'll be generally
some less suffering.
But this is if I had to choose what
level of the video game I want to play,
like I'm going to be here now.
Yeah.
This is,
this is the cool time for me.
And,
and there are ways to do that.
I mean,
I think we think of it technologically,
but I think at the plants as a
technology,
like smoking dmt is a technology.
It's just a way to administer dmt
molecules that don't get broken down
immediately because there's such a flood
that it actually crosses the blood brain
barrier and you have that experience of
swirling guy,
you know,
and it's just like looking at that like
this is tech,
this isn't,
this is drugs,
you know,
this is technology.
It's a weird word though.
Technology,
we think about metal.
Yeah,
we do wires.
But really to me that's a better way to
look at it,
you know,
because drugs carry all these
connotations.
And I was at a cure for this.
It's just this is a technology that
allows this certain element of humanity
to unlock.
It's like a key to a lock and you hit
that right.
It's good.
It's not.
You don't always want to unlock all the
doors either though,
you know,
I mean in my recent experience,
I pushed it,
pushed it to a level where I could
really see like fuck.
Like you could get down into some weird,
weird waters where you're entering a
lot,
you know,
and you don't really know if you're
going to come back,
you know,
and,
and so I,
I definitely,
I announced on my own podcast was like,
look,
I'm done with that
type of exploration of the plants.
I just want to play,
hang out and experience them for fun.
But going intentionally that deep with
them,
you know,
you have to be,
you have to have caution.
Plus it's a predatory universe out
there.
You know,
a lot of these Iowaska shamans and a lot
of these things,
they don't always have your best
interests.
They come from the jungle where the
strong eat the weak.
That's what people gotta realize.
Like in the jungle,
the strongest Jaguar eats all things.
All these Shamans,
their head animal,
most of moons.
Toronto is the Jaguar who eats all
things.
Like you got to realize like a lot of
those motherfuckers you're trying to eat
you like they're trying to eat you.
So be really super careful with it.
But look at it,
you know,
without bias,
look at it like this is a technology,
is this technology going to be useful
for me?
Am I ready to explore this technology?
If so,
do it appropriately and responsibly and
it can be really,
really valuable.
But then no one that technology's no
longer serving you,
isn't it one of those things like we've
been talking about where there's no,
it's not a clear good or bad,
there's not a clear yes or no.
There's not like,
oh,
well if you meet a showman,
he will absolutely be pure.
No,
fuck no,
no,
not at all.
I mean there's just a mixed bag just
like puke.
It's like any human,
is this going to be a good guy or bad
guys can be someone's helpful or not
helpful.
That's why stereotypes are so fucking
problematic.
You know,
if you meet a girl and she's beautiful,
you assume she's dummy,
right?
You know what I mean?
That's the standard,
right?
Because beautiful people don't have to
try as hard as soon as she's taking it
easy and she slacked off.
It's just a lot of people meet these
people from indigenous cultures and say,
oh,
they're indigenous.
One Slash 16th,
native American,
spiritual,
right?
He's got extra magic and he's in
medicine.
Man's.
He made the barefoot.
He may just be trying to fuck everybody
in his village and take your money.
Other people who are genuinely like
Gandalf,
the white wizard where you're like,
fuck,
that's Gandalf.
The white wizard I just encountered and
it's awesome,
but it's just you got to use your
instincts.
You gotta be you gotTa.
Be Keen to the situation and know what
you're getting into because it's a.
it's a crazy wild world that we know
very little about compared to,
you know,
these external technology.
Well also the fact that it's been
suppressed has become such a huge issue
that we have to go to these South
American countries to get it.
It's not like,
look,
if you want to go to get a massage,
you can go to Burke Williams and I
guarantee you they will give you an
excellent massage by a qualified
technician.
No one's going to fucking rob your
wallet.
You know what?
They have established a business and an
ethic.
There's a lot of places like that where
you go and you can,
you know,
you can go and experience a really good
service because it's legal in because we
don't,
we don't.
There's no consequences for engaging in
that action,
but the consequences of the United
States are so extreme that people have
to fly to the fucking jungle to take
something that your own brain produces.
It's.
It's so weird.
It's so weird that there's these
destinations that you have to go to to
explore that your
own fucking pineal gland produces,
and the only reason why is because we
make it illegal here in the United
States.
They should have calabasas IOWASCA
centers.
We should be able to go right down the
street from Kim Kardashians House and
get fucking fueled up,
but we,
we,
we're not there yet and if who knows
what we're ever going to get there.
It seems to me though that that's the
trend it seems.
Yeah,
right.
Definitely in so many different ways.
There's all these ponies in the race.
I was pretty much there with a religious
exemption,
like was that church that just opened up
in Washington?
Don't recommend it.
From what I've seen,
obviously haven't been there,
but again,
there's a very select group that I.
What is the church in Washington?
What is there?
It's a nondenominational IOWASCA church.
So the Church has Santa Diamond.
That church of UDV.
I'm already got religious exemption
approval cream court by the supreme
court twice.
Yeah,
right.
So one more time and you know,
it's fully like everything is going to
be a good.
They're doing full Iowa.
Rick Strassman Ios.
Rick strassman did it with them and he's
like,
they were these golf shirts like they
have like a little outfit and they're
getting blasted with like insanely
powerful IOWASCA and they're singing
songs about Jesus.
Then that's the weird part.
So I'll sing songs about Jesus if you
get me high enough.
So then the church in Washington was
like,
fuck it,
we're going to be nondenominational so
we're not going to sing songs about
Jesus,
we're just going to be a church.
And so we're waiting to kind of see what
happens with that.
But that's,
that's already coming and then
psilocybin is coming for approval as
medicine,
you know,
Johns Hopkins is doing amazing research
on that for both palliative care and a
variety of other thing.
MTMA for posttraumatic stress is coming
online.
Marijuana,
just by sheer sensibility and numbers is
going to be legal at some point.
So like all of these ponies are in the
race and I think they're all going to
come to fruition somewhere in the next
five,
10 years,
while also the information that the
Internet is providing.
Totally.
You can go online today and find all the
different things that marijuana is good
at and then find out the fact that it's
a schedule one drug,
the United States of America and you go,
oh well,
whoever's making the schedules a
criminal and it's real simple.
You've got this plant that you can eat,
you could eat,
you could use it to make a fuel for a
lamp.
He could build a fucking house out of
it.
Like you can make clothes with it,
you can make paper with it.
You can essentially make everything with
it.
You need to get a hemp stock,
you need to get a piece like,
I'm going gonna,
I'm going to order you one.
We'll get some.
If it is a tree grows large,
it gets fat like like a forearm and it
weighs nothing and it's hard as a rock.
It's fucking alien.
It's so weird.
It's not like any other plant that
exists on earth.
It's so strange,
but these laws that are in place,
we're all in place.
Back when information was difficult to
come by back when you had to get it
through these selected media sources
like newspapers or television shows and
everybody was confused.
Everybody was worried they were going to
go crazy like reefer madness and jump
off a building or stab white women
when nobody knew they they didn't know,
and now we do know.
So now that we do know those,
those nonsensical non reality based
perceptions are eroding their roading
right before our eyes.
In the line of it is things like
podcasts.
A lot of his things like Ted talks,
lectures,
people explaining the actual reality of
it,
information,
social media,
stories that are being printed in online
media sources where they explain like
the actual effects of these drugs that
John Hopkins studies where you can,
you can read in New York Times the
benefits of Psilocybin for people who
are experiencing the the end of life
relieving of pressure of people that are
terrified about dying.
People who have had some serious
traumatic abuse in their life and their
being cured of the burden of that with
psychedelic medicines and it's bizarre.
It's bizarre the time that we live in
and that all these things are sort of
sprouting out of the earth.
They've been suppressed and stuffed into
the ground by these people that were
essentially the enemies of information
that they were distributing false
information,
suppressing the real information.
I mean Nixon was the enemy of
information because he sponsored these
studies to show how bad marijuana was
and when it turned out,
the marijuana is actually not bad at
all.
They suppress that information.
He's actually the enemy of data.
He'll like push that data down into the
ground and never released it,
but now it's just just through sheer
truth is popping through the earth and
you're seeing Colorado experiencing
record revenues and taxes and when that
happens,
then all the evil people who quote
unquote the people that are
concentrating solely on numbers on money
now they're involved because you're
talking about a state in Colorado that's
made more money from taxes from
marijuana than they did from alcohol
last year,
which is fucking insane.
But Tulsa Pot people don't mind paying
39 percent taxes if you make it legal
because then what's the joint?
Seven bucks instead of five.
Fuck it.
Let's do it.
Yeah.
No,
seven bucks.
And your blast that off your head for
like the next 10 hours.
Do you understand like how much drinking
costs?
You know if you get a drink at a bar,
like what is.
I don't even know what a drink cost.
10 Bucks.
Okay.
So what?
Two drinks?
20 bucks.
20 bucks worth of pot will fuck you up
for a week.
You get 20 bucks worth of marijuana.
Like if you,
you can smoke like three hits a day for
four or five days in a row on 20 bucks
worth of weed.
Yeah,
no doubt.
I mean it's,
it's a chronicle,
it's economical and it's inescapable
now.
Like they've let the,
the,
that oppression can only work when it's
tight.
When you start to like the
plants growing up through the concrete,
the concrete starts to break off and all
of a sudden it returns the jungle again.
You can't,
you can't keep this stuff down.
And I was actually,
I had dinner with the maps people at my
house,
a little charity dinner and they
presented some of the new data that was
coming out from their recent study on
Mtma.
Unbelievable results for treating PTSD.
So to give it like a quick summary,
posttraumatic stress has a scale and the
scale goes from zero to 1:30.
One 30 is like the most incomprehensible
amount of terrible shit that's happened
to you possible lived in a cage your
whole life,
whatever.
Tortured forever.
Most people have a certain amount,
like five of skift score of five or 10.
There's always been bad shit that's
happened to people,
but like the threshold is somewhere
around 50.
Oh,
anything over 50 year actually
diagnosable with ptsd and in the kind of
medical record as far as I understand
it.
And so in their recent studies,
you know,
they're getting an average of people
with treatment resistant ptsd.
That means the drugs didn't work and
what the drugs showed and it's a
combination of,
I believe Paxil and Zoloft with the drug
showed is they were able with consistent
application to reduce that score like
six to 10 points,
so from like 70 to 60,
so still pretty fucked up.
You're not down like in the normal
range,
which is somewhere around 10,
reduced it from 70 to 60.
With the MTMA assisted psychotherapy,
there's three sessions,
you know,
where they took Mtma three times with a
therapist and it reduced it like 50
points and not only did it reduce it 50
points instead of 10,
it continued to drop over the next three
years that they observe them without any
utilization of mdms.
So it's like instead of this,
this constant treatment,
there's a cure potentially out there.
That's available where three times you
do this thing and of course you know the
psychotherapy isn't to be ignored.
That's an important part of this.
It's Mtma assisted psychotherapy,
not just willy nilly taking the drugs
and hold someone that guide you and
guiding you through into these
situations and it's amazingly powerful
and this is a disease that affects or
disorder rather,
that affects so many millions of people
who are suffering and you just have
something there on the fringe with this
data coming out and pretty soon it
becomes incredibly unethical to keep
this illegal when the data is showing
that much promise.
Like any other pharmaceutical drug that
could be patentable,
that showed that much promise and doing
something fast tracked.
I mean it would be like like that a act
drug which ended up not working,
but when everybody's afraid of aids and
like this may work,
all of a sudden that shit was legal in
like six months because people were
freaked out.
I mean that's what should happen with
Mgma and we'll see if it does.
You know,
because when this data is presented,
it's going to be such a convincing case.
It really becomes unethical not to use
it.
Well,
I think we're also in a world now where
children are growing up and they're
growing up from the time they're a baby.
They have access to the Internet and the
culture that exists today is so
radically than the culture pre 1994 that
the children that are born in 1994 have
now they have.
They're 20 years old,
you know now they're adults and they've
grown up with the Internet from the time
they were babies.
Those are the people that are just not
going to accept the laws that are in
place as they get older and they become
leaders and politicians and they're
going to have a completely different
idea than some of these old wacky fucks
that are just they.
They're operating on a false paradigm
they're operating with,
with bad information and they're the
what,
what's undeniable.
It's concrete and solid to them just
isn't,
well,
bull drugs are bad and it's bad for your
brain.
Like,
I had a conversation with Michio Kaku
once when I was on the opiod,
Anthony Show when I was asking him
about,
uh,
about psychedelic drugs.
I forgot what I was asking them about,
but,
uh,
it was like,
well,
we know scientists,
we're trying to expand our brain.
We don't want to give ourselves brain
damage.
I gave this idea that you would ruin
your brain by doing mushrooms.
Like,
Oh,
well,
you've never done mushrooms,
right?
Have you ever done mushrooms?
No,
I wouldn't do it because I don't want to
ruin my brain.
I want to expand my.
And I was like,
well,
you don't understand what you're saying
that you're,
you're talking about something that you
don't,
you've never experienced.
So you have this idea in your head that
it's bad for you based on what?
Based on propaganda.
But then I realized,
well,
he's in academia,
being an academia,
purdue,
you know,
uh,
doing lectures,
do you use it,
would radically limit his income,
radically limit his exposure if he came
out and started saying,
you know,
hey,
I'm,
I'm really in favor of people trying
drugs and going to the jungle and
fucking hanging out with barefoot dudes
or giving you some toxic frog poison
makes away from that one.
I've done a lot of things and that was
definitely not one that you want to do
the Kambo poison.
But yeah,
I mean the psilocybin has been shown to
have neurogenesis help rebuild the brain
and neurons like what?
Yeah,
that's some crazy shit.
And you know,
if you've experienced DMT,
either an Iowaska or smokable form,
you know,
a lot of times it feels like there's a
thousand little doctors like soldering
and fixing shit in your brain.
You're like,
oh well the end.
It was nice.
The end of my trips always feel like,
like almost like,
you know,
if like if you went theoretically
because we've never done this,
could go to a massage parlor and get a
hand release.
Like they actually rubbed you down first
and they go,
all right,
now let's take care of the problem.
Um,
will dmt feels like you have this wild
exploratory trip.
And then the end of it to me always
feels like they're like,
all right,
well we got to do some maintenance.
So just kick back and look at the pretty
lights were done showing you shit.
We're just going to,
we're going to go deep there and just
try to correct some shit.
Yeah.
You hear the,
you hear in the Eco rose the IOWASCA
songs.
We'll often talk to Dr Ceto,
you know,
Dr Ceto his little doctor.
And so it's like,
it's a paradigm exists in
many cultures and you can feel it
independently,
you know,
like I was feeling that before I
realized like,
Oh,
Dr c dot a little doctor,
you know,
that's what they're,
that's what they're talking about.
His little doctor come here,
you,
you know,
and that's what they're singing to the
plants.
These,
these medicines will.
There's so many people that are dealing
with traumatic brain injuries these
days.
How fascinating would it be if it found
out if they found out or it could prove
that siliciden could alleviate the
problems with traumatic brain injury by
regenerating tissue,
but actually healing the brain?
I mean,
maybe it's not where that is right now.
I mean maybe it hasn't gotten to a
stage,
but between that stem cell treatments
and all sorts of different ways.
There's so many people like when you
lose the ability to see reality
correctly because your brain's not
functioning like either.
You're very Oregon.
It's like having a television that just
doesn't get a good signal anymore.
It's all fucked up.
Well,
it's got to be fixed,
right,
but we can't fix it.
Like right now,
the brain has a very limited ability to
fix itself and there are some strategies
and some different treatments that they
use to help people recover from
traumatic brain injuries and get to some
semblance of normalcy.
But imagine if they got to a point where
they found out that this neurogenesis
capability that we've shown to exist in
silicide and can actually rebuild tissue
and heal brain and run proper studies
like you would with any other
supplementary thing out.
They're like,
all right,
well let's try a micro dose for over the
course of two months.
You know,
like a sub detectable where you're not
like tripping your balls,
but just something like you would a
nutritional supplement.
Let's test that over against placebo for
two months and then measure the results
in the brain.
Well,
the suppression has just eliminated that
option for science to just explore these
hypotheses.
Like what happens if you microdose dmt
in some form over the course of two
months?
Like how does that affect performance?
And a lot of people are doing that now.
They're microdosing on their own and
anecdotally reporting something.
But what we need is a placebo controlled
trial to say like unequivocably,
Oh yeah,
that's what this does.
But it's so hard to get that shit
approved and get the approval material
and get this done that it's.
It's become challenging.
But when that lids off,
it's going to be really,
really fucking cool.
I agree that this is the coolest time to
be alive.
It really is an an amazing,
fascinating time to be alive.
But I wonder if they're going to look
back at us the way we look at champs.
You know,
lily's fucking dummies.
They thought that was an awesome time to
be alive.
I wonder.
I wonder if people always have that way
of looking at things where they just
appreciate what's around them and say,
wow,
this is as good as it's ever been.
This is amazing.
But then one day they'll look back at us
and go with how ridiculous they couldn't
even read minds.
Imagine going through life not being
able to read minds like what a shitty
way to live.
Sort of how we look at people that can't
send emails.
They didn't even have the Internet.
You had to go to a library and read a
book that was written hand.
Like
some guy wrote the a pen.
He had a feather,
a dip it in some coal that they mixed
with oil or whatever the fuck they use
to make ink.
Yeah.
We're going to probably look back at
that someday and maybe even in our
lifetimes.
But I bet there's also those people who
if you took them from the past like
let's say,
you know,
you talked to him Musashi and you're
like,
there's an awesome future,
but you can't use your sword to cut
anybody.
He'd be like,
fuck,
I think I'm good.
You know,
it's like we got all this cool shit.
We got computers and knowledge and you
know,
all these different things.
Travel the world.
We have drones.
You don't even have to be involved and
just have to be like in another room
somewhere else.
He's not going to be into that.
So much is just holding the steel in his
hand and just that's got to meet and so
in every age there's these parts of that
age that are irreplaceable.
I was in Vegas yesterday leaving the
airport early in the morning and you
know,
you're waiting in line at the security
thing to show your id and I looked up
and they had a screen that was giving
instructions and guidelines for using
drones and I was like,
Jesus Christ,
we're living in the future.
Like it,
it,
it almost.
I was waiting for it to be a joke
because if you ever gone through the Las
Vegas airport,
they have these big screens up and
they'll show these sort of humorous
character sketches.
Yeah.
Carrot top.
Trying to carry all his props through
the security and showing what you can't
do.
They have these heavy metal guys that
are taking off these giant spiked risk
bracelets and you know what you have to
like take off to go through security and
so on.
The same screen where they show that
they showed this thing about drones and
I was like,
this seems like some starship troopers.
Shit.
It seems like it doesn't seem real,
but it was real.
They were talking about the Federal
Aviation Administration and the
guidelines and rules for using drones.
Don't let your drone get out of sight.
Don't make your drone go over a certain
amount of feet in the air.
Don't let your drone wandered near
airports.
Don't let your drone get involved in the
path of commercial flights.
I was like,
wow,
this is.
Please use your drone responsibly.
And I'm like,
whoa.
This is bizarre.
Yeah,
like demolition man.
Weird future shit girl.
You see the drone that I almost dropped
on that skier?
No.
Jamie tried to find that there was a
drone that drops out of the sky and
almost completely obliterate ran out of
gas or something.
Ran Out of fucking signal or something
like.
And Paul's like right on the heels of
his skis.
It's wasn't the guy who was piloting it?
No,
he was.
He was like,
it was an actual competition.
So he's skiing ski racer.
Watch this.
Oh my God.
Oh Jesus Christ.
Hold on back that up again.
Oh my God.
Slowmo.
Tom.
That's insane.
That want to fuck that dude.
I'm fucked him up for sure.
Wow.
I wonder if that was like a person in
the audience that wanted to get like a
good video of it or whether that was the
real camera crew.
It's weird.
Well,
there's a thing going on right now where
there's new technology that they haven't
had the ability to form the proper
regulations for yet and they're not
really aware of like what the issues are
like those Goddamn hoverboards,
those things like you see people at the
airport,
at least they were for awhile.
I think they're trying to make that
illegal where they're at the airport and
they're wandering through the terminals
on these hoverboards just scooting along
on these.
These,
if you don't know what a hoverboard is,
it's essentially like a surf or it's
like a skateboard,
but instead of going sideways,
like the way you skate,
you go forward.
Like,
uh,
it's so it's perpendicular and there's
wheels on it and the wheels are like
those,
uh,
those.
What are those things called?
The fucking.
The,
the segway.
The segway.
Thank you.
It's a gyroscope and the gyroscopes sort
of balances you out and you roll around.
They're fun.
My kids have them.
I ride them around the house,
they're really fun,
but now they're starting to have
regulations like they're starting to
say,
hey,
you can't ride these things on the
sidewalks.
You can't.
Okay,
now we're making rules because those
rules didn't exist before.
And people like,
remember when the Wiz Khalifa got
arrested at the airport,
he got arrested the airport because he
wouldn't get off of it.
Really Monitor to around probably
highest fuck tattoos on his face and he
doesn't give a fuck about a hoverboard
and you know,
they arrested him for it.
That doesn't help street credit actually
when you get arrested for robbery,
I mean there's a lot of arrests that
might help a rapper,
but that's maybe not.
Anytime a wrapper gets arrested,
it's good because the thing is they
complain.
These niggas don't know.
I don't know if you should be allowed to
do it,
but I do know when you do do it,
if you know what you're doing,
like very precise with it.
I mean,
it's not an issue,
but I think people have the idea,
the,
the issue is it's automated and you can
potentially like,
like uh,
my daughter I had a slower down and like
settle down,
settle.
She's fucking whizzing around in this
thing like really fast and she's wiped
out a couple of times.
Like she kinda crazy and she's wiped out
and hurt herself and I'm like just going
to just a little too fast and shark,
she's getting to the edge of the ability
to control the thing.
And if someone was doing that in an
airport,
it could be a real problem between those
and drones.
Like these emerging technologies that we
don't necessarily have regulations for
yet.
And I think there's so many people that
are so fragile and they get so scared,
you know,
like they can't,
they haven't kept up with their body so
they can't get out of the way if some
shit happened or like if they did get
hit,
they're going to break for sure.
Like in Santa Monica,
that happens all the time.
We'll be riding our bikes around and
we'll pass them old people and they'll
just curse us.
We're not even close.
Yeah.
Like on the bikes,
we miss them by six feet.
Yeah.
Like fuck.
Because they know they're just in this
kind of like fragile state and so they
kind of panic when there's something on
wheels rolling by.
They don't really
understand them.
Crackers there are made out of crackers.
They fall down.
It's a wrap.
It's over.
Everything over.
Imagine a wiping out on an old lady with
a bike.
If you're whipping along on a mountain
bike and you collided with an 80 year
old lady,
he would just shatter her whole body.
Everything would just snap.
Crackle.
They can't fall down like you can't fall
down.
Imagine you're.
Your body gets to a place where you
cannot fall down if you fall down.
Everything breaks.
Yeah.
That's not a future that I'm hoping for.
I mean fuck.
I wonder how much that can be mitigated
by strength training.
A lot.
Training and mineralization,
you know,
keeping their bone density up,
making sure that you have the spare
parts to replace the ones that you're
losing,
you know,
I think that's,
a big part of it.
Getting the muscles on the frame and
then supporting the bones and making
sure that your body is sturdy enough
because you see the other way if you see
these people is just sturdy is shit and
all different cultures.
Cultures that don't have medicines and
pharmaceuticals.
Like even in the jungle again,
you'll see somebody 75 with a machete,
just kicking ass macho,
big cigarette coming out of his mouth.
Just ha ha.
And then drinks beers at the end of the
day.
You know,
like if you stay that vigorous and
active,
you can,
you know,
and eating very natural foods.
Obviously they don't have another choice
and a lot of those cases you can see the
other side and then you can see this
kind of this other amalgamation which is
gary where you got cracker bones.
Yeah,
that's more,
that's another benefit of being able to
do the work.
Being able to force yourself to do some
things you don't want to do as far as
that like exercise and pushing yourself.
The benefits of that are you have a body
that works way better for way longer,
and if you don't do that,
you get deterioration and you get
atrophy and then you become frail.
You become that old person.
It's screaming at you because you're on
a bike 10 feet away from them.
You can kill me.
Cracker bones.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's a bummer,
man.
It's a bummer.
That's a.
that's another inevitable bummer about
life,
but it's also isn't that part of what's
beautiful about this is that you can't
be that girl with the picks and the
instagram forever,
like why the butt pics are so exciting
is because that but only exists for
about 20 years or so.
We'll start falling blossoms perfectly
right before it falls off into nothing.
You know?
That was the great symbol for the
Samurai was.
That's why they appreciated it because
it flowers and beauty and then falls.
That's life time.
Time will rip US clutching and grabbing
from every attachment that we have.
It always wins.
It's like someone in Jujitsu with the
ultimate squeeze that never gets tired
like we're going to have to tap out at
some point of everything that we love.
Everything that we like,
so might as well just accept that like
it's cool.
Enjoy it while it's here and in a
fractal sense.
Even if you can live forever,
the fucking planet will be here forever,
right?
The Sun will burn out,
the sun is going to run out of energy
and it's going to eventually supernova.
Good luck.
You can't live forever.
There is no forever.
It doesn't exist.
Time always wins.
That time is a motherfucker know.
It is such a motherfucker.
I wrote this piece for Maxim magazine
about how the human body's like sand
castle.
That's one of the cool things about a
sand castle as you're building it and
one of the beautiful things about,
as you know,
it's not gonna last.
If you made a sand castle out of cement,
nobody would be impressed.
So something about a sandcastle where
you,
you've put all this work into it with
the understanding that this is entirely
temporary and that's sort of the same
thing with a human body and I was
comparing old Arnold Schwartzenegger
from the seventies to the Arnold
Schwartzenegger now with the dad bod
when you see them now and his little
skivvies on the beach.
Like Whoa,
what the fuck man,
that's the tide is started to come in,
you know,
and that ocean spray is washing away the
towers and washing away everything until
eventually there's only the memory and
the pictures of that sand castle as it
was.
And that is fucking beautiful.
Like it's not something to be lamented,
like appreciate that shit.
Like it's temporary.
So we fucking love it.
Yup.
You know like that's,
that's a part of the thing.
Yeah.
It's one of the more fascinating aspects
about at all is that it is temporary and
I think that if it wasn't,
if everything,
it's like the way I described it in the
article was like if you,
if it.
That wasn't the case.
It would be like as boring as playing a
video game on God mode.
Never play a quake on God mode.
You can type quake used to be,
you could,
uh,
go to hit the [inaudible] key and go
into the command prompt and you can,
uh,
you could type in God and you would play
on God mode.
In God mode is you were in vulnerable.
Your life would last forever.
It all the weapons you wanted and you
couldn't get hurt.
She just run around shooting things and
as boring as fuck and no consequences
and not worrying at all about your own
mortality.
That would,
it wouldn't be fun.
Like one of the fun things about doing
wild shit is you know you're going to
have to sleep.
You know,
one of the fun things about sex is you
know what's going to end.
You know,
it's hard to get when you get it.
I can't leave her fucking and then it's
over.
Then your tie.
One of the fun things about dragon is a
god damn,
we're going to pay for this.
It's,
it's part of the whole thing is it is
the Yin and Yang.
It is the struggle.
It is,
it's the,
the,
the consequences and it's the reward and
it's all together.
Yeah.
It's the coolest fucking video game that
we all made together,
man.
I'm telling you,
that's really what it is.
And we were born into it,
born into it,
and then we just get to decide how we
want to play,
you know,
decide if we want to level up,
decide if we want to retreat.
We can ultimately decide if we want to
hit the reset button,
but if we hit that reset button,
you know,
and end this game right now,
we'll never get to play this turn again.
You know,
when,
then we get to be this person at this
time on this planet.
I can't say never,
but holds likely.
Most likely.
You never get to do a Redo of this exact
thing.
Maybe something similar,
but so what are you missing out on?
You're missing out on a unique
opportunity to experience something
totally unique in that sense.
And so it's a real shame to do it,
but I think,
you know,
I think taking some of the pressure off
that situation like,
oh okay,
some people may want to hit that reset
button because shit sucks and that's
lamentable and it's an unfortunate
situation because of those things that I
mentioned,
but in my worldview that is just hitting
the reset button on the game and you get
a chance to play,
you know,
some other time
or you come back as well as poisonous
frog is in Topanga Canyon and fuck
people up.
That would be a motherfucker.
I mean,
you know,
with this idea that we always that
reincarnation,
you always come back as a person.
Imagine if not,
imagine if you will,
like you become a person,
a person.
Is that top of the food chain ideally.
Right?
All right.
So when you come back,
you come back as an Amoeba
and you've got to go through the whole
process again.
You had dies an Amoeba,
you come back as a multicell organism,
you die,
you come back as a slug,
death come back as a frog.
Death come back as a bird death.
You're a dog death,
you're a chicken death death,
you go,
it doesn't know,
time doesn't give a fuck no,
and then there's multiple dimensions and
infinite universes.
Now you just keep coming back as new
things,
new things on other planets,
new biological creatures that we haven't
even begun to discover,
like the idea that if you live and die,
you only live in dying.
This one patch of dirt and that your
soul,
if that's a real thing,
your consciousness,
your entity,
your essence only transcends this body
and enters into another one like it.
You know,
in past life who queen or lived in new
people were fucking presidents or kings
like every motherfucker.
It was a president or a king in the
past,
a homeless person sucking dick for
homemade wine and all the fucking.
All the Gypsies are telling you that
Shit.
She's like,
Oh yes,
I see you at a great general like,
motherfucker,
come on,
come on.
How about I was a loser?
I would like to elucidate.
Or Julius Caesar,
the 7,000 Julius Caesar's from fucking
fortunate.
Oh,
I see you.
It was great.
Caesar leading the Roman as well.
People love this.
Love that whole nostalgia.
I was listening to this one,
uh,
African American dude.
It was talking about.
He was talking about the history of
black people.
It's like we were kings.
That's what he said.
Like,
okay,
somebody needs to talk to you because
you can't.
Everybody can't be kings.
Do Kings work.
First of all,
kings are assholes and if you were a
king back then most likely fucking
killed.
A bunch of people were enslaving a bunch
of motherfuckers.
Exactly.
This idea,
we worked things like how many,
how many of you were kings?
Did you go,
I'll get along.
Did y'all have separate kingdoms?
Did you all live in a community of
kingdoms?
Like what the fuck he talking about
Jesus Christ in the past?
No,
we would love that.
We'd love to.
I will.
I'm really curious about that.
Like this longing for nostalgia.
Like what is that?
What people want to look to the past?
And you know,
I dated this girl a long time ago and
she was brutal in the fact that she
always distorted
the past and made,
it sounds so amazing and so incredible.
And so,
you know,
like what you grew up in a broken home.
Your parents were abusive,
alcoholic,
so was like,
you know,
when we're together,
the love was amazing and they were
always together and they always know
they weren't,
they fought,
they threw glasses at each other like
Jesus Christ.
Will you look at the life as what it
actually is in gain those possible
lessons from the actual truth of the
life instead of this romantic fucking
movie,
this strange reese witherspoon movie of
life.
Like somehow,
like people feel like they need that,
who they are.
It's built into like their own pride in
themselves having this thing.
But yeah,
just strip all that shit away.
I mean,
I think that the ego that wants all of
these things,
once that passed and once this,
you got to just strip that little tyrant
and just like take all that armor off,
take all the bullshit off and let it
stand naked in the light of truth.
Just naked as shit out there.
Like,
you know,
get real,
get real with the elements.
I think it has something to do with
movies too,
man.
I think it has something to do with
literature and it's something to do with
our,
our creation of a narrative like our
creation of these uh,
these lives that we read about and
watching films and we sort of apply them
to our database of what's possible.
And then,
you know,
you sort of like look back on some movie
that you saw that was wonderful and it
was amazing,
you know,
some really silly movie and you apply
that to your own past and you sort of
like trying to twist things around.
Especially when you're describing them
to other people.
You want people to think you had the
most amazing life but it never works.
It's sort of like name dropping,
like name dropping has the opposite
effect,
like it doesn't work,
like the idea that you are going to
somehow or another make people like you
more because you know,
you know Harry Belafonte or someone.
I don't know why I said Harold Bell,
where the fuck that came from?
Leonardo Dicaprio.
Really good friends with Leo.
You know,
we go to bars that you immediately think
that guy's a douche bag.
People assume that this,
the machinations behind what they're
saying are completely transparent,
but they're not like people.
Some people are blind to it and ignorant
and that's when name dropping work.
Like oh my God,
you're know Leo,
Blah Blah,
and they're just operating on that short
hamster wheel that's running full speed
and they can't figure out that he's has
some other compulsion that's causing
them to do this.
But then you meet somebody who has a
little bit of that,
you know,
wherewithal and it's just gross.
Like,
Ugh,
what are you doing?
I see what you're trying to do.
That I see these hidden motivations and
I think that's kind of what we're seeing
in politics.
We're seeing across the board,
it's like,
you know,
and so many different little gimmicks
that people play,
like even them saying when I'm president
of the,
they don't fucking believe that when
fucking Jeb Bush,
when present,
he doesn't believe it,
and you can tell you're like our
bullshit belief detectors.
Know that when he's saying he doesn't
believe it,
but you know who does believe it when
conor mcgregor says when they clash them
and I'm not gonna fucking head off he
fuck it believes it was Scottish.
He just fucked up the Irish accent.
Irish accents.
Tough do.
Yeah.
He definitely.
Well,
he in that,
that you know,
that limited world of interacting with
bones and flesh and technique.
Yeah.
He,
he understands it to the point where he
really believes it and says it and I
think although probably believed it too
and some sort of fucked up way believed
him.
Yeah.
I think that's one of the things I think
when anybody's fighting,
it's not only a test of their
physicality,
it's like a test of their belief and all
of that squaring off and all of the
stare downs.
It's like,
how much do you believe you're going to
beat me?
You know,
and most people probably.
Great champions,
they're in that 98.
They're pretty confident.
Connor just shows up straight.
A hundred hundred like denial.
Like you sure you sure?
Congress like,
yeah,
I'm fucking my favorite quotes of
Connor.
And he goes,
I'm number one.
He goes,
number one,
do you think like when they were
replaced,
Chad Mendez replaced Josie Aldo.
He goes,
I'm number one.
Do you think number one gives a fuck who
number two?
And number three is,
let them all come.
Let them.
Oh,
that was a bad Irish accent to.
That was pretty good actually.
I thought it was bad.
Fell in west La,
had deteriorated in the Middle Eastern.
Somewhere in the middle of it.
We're out of time,
man.
We just banged out three hours.
Beautiful.
Believe it or not,
I don't know how that happened.
That's the wonders of conversation or my
brother.
Always.
Good.
Good time.
Definitely.
We're out of time.
You fuckers,
but we'll be back tomorrow.
So,
uh,
thanks.
Happy New Year.
Yeah,
I love you all.
Love you all.
Bye.