Oh,
she like a bag of water.
Okay.
Yes.
Boys.
Yeah.
First of all,
that is a beautiful tell t shirt you're
wearing there.
Mr Sean Newest version of the Master
Cam.
Not out yet.
Accentuates is fucking dope.
Tiger man.
It's like sort of a half dragony tiger
thing going on.
Very Asian with the and k?
Yeah man.
Who's doing your artwork?
I have a couple of guys.
This one I collabed with a guy,
his name's on Instagram,
painted demons and so the two guys I
used,
they're both from tap out back in the
tap out tap out days.
So Justin and this guy painted demons
jettison.
We just get together with the world of
tee shirts.
I love it.
The tap out thing is so strange.
It's like it's like there's a few
companies like that,
right?
Like von Dutch remember?
Yeah.
And then von Dutch.
That became ed hardy.
I want really know,
but you know what I mean?
Right.
The people that would have warned van
dot if they had been five years younger,
we're now wearing ed hardy.
Hardy retarded.
I don't know why it wasn't legit tattoo
artists.
Super legit.
Yeah.
I mean he has.
He's like a famous tat.
I think he's dead.
Is he dead?
Well,
the kind of guys that were like,
they're usually easy.
I used to wear some metal,
but they're usually super killer guys.
Shaved their forearms.
They got the skin,
like a hot dog to use your term.
Jersey shore.
Here's the deal.
I mean we can demonize those guys all
day long and we do and it's funny,
but they're just trying to get laid.
No.
The only reason why we don't.
We wouldn't wear those things if we were
all going.
We're rhinestones because you're looking
to fuck your buddy.
Do they've done studies that when a man
wears jewelry,
Don Ed Hardy,
born in 1945.
He's still alive.
Wow.
That's your sweet ass.
He's alive.
He looks a lot younger there.
No,
that's.
I'm kidding.
That's a different guy with a shitty
shirt.
Is known for those sailor tattoos.
Original sailor tattoos.
Yeah.
He was like one of the.
The great American.
A tattoo artists.
He would make those really cool like,
like his,
his stuff was not realistic looking at
all.
It's like cartoonish.
There is no good and powerful man.
He looks awesome.
He made a bank.
He looks like a closet.
It's just weird that a tattoo artists
like I knew him from the tattoo
magazines.
Yeah,
because before I ever got a tattoo,
I was like really?
Into tattoos.
I'd buy the magazines and check out all
the really cool art wars.
Like Paul booth.
You ever see that guy?
Yeah,
I'm down in New Jersey.
Oh God.
Damn that guy.
That guy.
He won't let you tell him what to draw.
Really?
Yup.
He just got to trust him.
Yep.
He's got his style and his style is like
demonic,
white eyeballs,
black and gray.
Really cool.
Super detailed.
Amazing Tattoos.
Here's.
Look at this fucking guy.
He looks like Paul booth.
He does.
He doesn't look like he's going to take
no for an answer.
I'm using your body as an experiment and
look at that poster.
The back fighting terrorism since 1490.
That's the American Indians.
Native American,
Diana t shirt like that.
Really?
Yeah.
I stopped wearing it.
I felt like I felt like,
what am I,
what is this message?
I'm doing what I'm doing,
what should I.
I might sleep out just because I want to
be 49 sleeved.
I'm 48 and sleeves.
Yeah,
but somehow it fits you.
What?
I'd like tattoos,
man.
If you like tattoos,
it fits you.
I love the artwork,
the art that goes into it.
I love it and as I get older I like
girls that are tattooed on me.
Didn't used to like them.
I used to always love.
I used to be like,
are you crazy?
Damaged Bitch.
I'm like,
wait a minute.
I'm a crazy damage bitch too man.
Guys,
crazy damn website I ever bought,
like subscribe to where I used a credit
card to get access is suicide girls.
That's how much they turned me off.
But that's just pictures,
right?
They don't even know.
Just pictures.
I didn't,
I didn't check off.
I just would look at him and be like,
no,
you jacked off for sure one.
Otherwise why would you give them a
chronic masturbator?
But I that I have youtube or you know,
fucking red tube and all that stuff,
but that there's an attraction to a girl
that covers her back and her arms with
tattoos for some reason because this
girl doesn't give a fuck.
She's,
well,
she knows that this is permanent.
And she's like,
yeah,
whatever.
Drawn me pull up pictures of that Paul
booth stuff because some of his stuff is
insane.
He did.
I'm that dude.
Who a fucking.
Yeah,
look at that kind of shame,
man.
I'm putting that on my body though.
I'm going to need to see the artwork
before you put them.
It's really not.
But he's so good,
dude.
People wait for years.
Hold on.
Back up to that one with the tentacles
please.
Fucking insane.
See,
I would get that.
But it'd be like,
why is Brian doing that?
Well,
why isn't it?
See that's your problem.
Let me tell you what your problem is,
your problem,
and you're worried about what people
think.
Well that shit ain't good for you.
I don't.
I don't know that.
Yeah,
you do.
Definitely.
That's why you don't have a nice car.
And that's why you would.
You were weird.
Shoes at zipped up on the side,
getting a tesla.
Tesla.
I ordered a fucking drive themselves.
I know that.
That I now know craziness.
I got the autopilot to Tom Papa about
it.
Yeah,
well I'm getting one.
I'm picking it up in March 31st.
My,
my buddy Matt,
Matt Lichtenberg,
he's got one and he said he gets on the
highway.
He,
he,
you press a button twice.
I guess it drives itself and he just
starts texting people.
Not,
not for me,
man.
That's just not for me.
I said to the guy,
he explained it to me at the Tesla
dealership and I said I wouldn't use
that.
And he said,
Oh yes,
you will in the future.
Especially you.
And how much traffic here.
That makes sense.
Listen man,
when you have a nice car,
it makes driving a fun experience.
Whereas if you have a look,
there's nothing wrong with just having a
utilitarian car.
You know,
Brock Lesnar,
he used to drive around in like,
it was like a chevy citation,
something like that.
It was like some weird little red
fucking compact car that guy used to get
in that thing and he's what?
All of 300 pounds.
He was a fucking every fucking thicker
than he makes.
He.
He makes me like when I stand next to
him,
like we're not the same species.
It's a totally different kinds of humans
I've ever seen him.
I was like,
maybe this isn't for me.
I'm shaking people's hands before,
like shack,
shake,
shack's hands check as these.
But there's two guys like Shane Corwin
and Lesner.
Both those guys.
You shake their hand,
you go,
okay,
we're not the same thing.
I tried getting hit with one of those
fucking beach on ours for me because I
didn't grow up with any cars.
Like my,
my parents were never in the cars.
So if you don't know the difference,
like sometimes you got to know the
difference,
like you grow up with it.
But yeah,
I didn't grow up with it.
I just didn't grow up with it.
I don't think I've ever driven a fast
car.
I drove a porsche once in traffic and I
couldn't open it up,
so I didn't.
I just don't.
I didn't grow up.
I grew up appreciating what the car was.
He tried to ask him to drive my car,
like,
fuck no.
Take his car up to like little to
hunger.
Like to drive a stick.
I do.
Yeah,
I can.
I started learning on a stick isn't,
I'll let you drive the gt three.
It'll change your life.
He'd be like crazy eyes.
I'm fucking Mr.
d dot.
I'm trying to change your life.
He would ruin your car.
No,
no,
no.
He drives good.
He's a good driver.
But you would,
uh,
you would understand maybe the list at
the beginning of my.
Oh,
the test was really fast.
Super fast.
One of the best cars in the world.
Especially download that APP.
It's still.
Well,
he told me that they can,
like if I,
if I want it faster than they can
upgrade it.
Yeah.
There's like some insane mode.
I don't think you need that though.
Chris alluded to this group.
Two point eight seconds.
Zero to 60 in two point eight seconds.
Crazy.
Of course I don't need a four door sedan
puts in Saint Dan to hit 60 and less
than three seconds end with no sound.
Right?
It's like there's no rumble.
There's no explosions.
Like there are two things I wish I want
to start wearing,
but it's too late for me.
I want that Tattoo.
Get the hand do it.
He might do it,
but he might do something better.
You just got to go to him.
Well,
I also want to where I can't do that.
I can't do that.
Just trust it.
Fucking like snake.
Sorry Bro.
That's what you get.
That's how it works.
Maybe you could say,
look,
my mom was killed by today.
Could you lay off the snakes and he
would just do like bats or is he going
to get what you're going to get a snake.
I mean,
he's a fucking artist essentially.
Not essentially a hundred percent.
Yeah.
And he looks at his art and he says,
you know what man,
people commission me to do pieces and
this is what I want to do.
So I'm just going to say I'm only going
to take that work.
I get it that the southern wrong though.
I mean,
I believe my.
That's how he does it.
I've that.
I'm pretty sure.
I don't think there's no bigger artists
than in southern cal for tattoo artists.
It's the scene man,
for sure.
Oh yeah.
That's a great spot.
If not the best in the world.
I mean it is fucking killers here.
The shamrock yet cartoon.
Yet in Osi got some killers.
There's.
Well there's on d all over the country
right now.
There's a resurgence in tattooing,
like tattooing over the last few decades
has become like a really respected art
form instead of just like,
a lot of them were like Weirdo,
fringe type artists who just were really
into it.
But there's a stigma attached to it,
you know,
there's always a stigma attached to
being tattooed up,
you know?
And now it's not like if you have
tattoos like Aaron Dove,
a dove did this and this was like 50
hours of work,
you know?
And he planned it all out as one sleep.
He did this one too.
He just both really good,
but he's a friend too,
so like I go down there and we hang.
He's cool as fuck.
He's an amazing artist.
You get a close bond with your tattoo
artists.
Like Freddy Negretti,
who's,
who's done all this from shamrock social
club in Hollywood there and you know,
he's,
he grew up rough man.
He started tattooing in prison so he
still rough dude,
but the first hour with them I was like,
God,
this is the worst he was.
I wasn't talking to me,
was kind of me a long time,
but then he opened up and he's my bullet
now.
Man.
Just the straight means just.
Yeah,
it's great.
Maybe he was worried that you were like
a dumb jock type care.
One hundred percent.
You're very deceiving in that way.
Like a lot of people have the wrong idea
of you and they also like people get mad
at you from podcasts.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I know it's fun to hate and I've done it
before,
but you've got to understand and we're,
we,
we play up shit.
Like what do you ramp things up?
You say ridiculous shit.
He knows what he's doing.
He's doing it because it's ridiculous to
say.
Yeah,
I want to act as a natural showman.
It's fun.
It's so much comedy is about
exaggeration sometimes.
A lot of it,
a lot of it is.
I mean,
that's some of the funniest shit.
Yeah,
you know.
But I think tattoos for me is I,
I think,
uh,
one I didn't.
I don't know that I express tattooing.
I don't know that there's anything I,
I can,
I can never make up my mind first of
all,
what I'd want them to be.
Harmony making it too big of a deal.
Like I don't give them what it looks so
good about your arm by itself.
Well,
the must look at this.
Try Haitian.
Even if a separate.
If you have a nice arm,
if you have a big muscle,
you,
your arms fit mean you're fit.
You're a fit guy,
but it's just skin.
Okay.
You go to a great artist and you have
art on your body.
What would I get?
Permanent art or whatever you want.
Well,
you know what,
why don't you guys both get fighter in
the kid tattoos.
Boom.
Send video once we get to 10 million
downloads here to get a tattoo.
That was the deal.
We made that bet.
Wow.
Lucky.
Not On my show.
Tesla.
What do you.
What are you going to get fucking now?
Hey Man.
I'm going to go all out.
I'm going to go balls out and just get
Medusa on my back.
Medusa Medusa big one.
Of course.
He's a god Damn America.
Sorry.
Congress.
You heard of King Kong?
Are you
familiar with big fuck.
You need to know about gorillas pro.
Sorry,
but do you ever see lassie,
Bro?
You know,
flip.
It was not a fish,
right?
Funny I got last year.
Do you know?
It's a big smiley last shitty lassie I
got last year on my back.
It doesn't serone up last year of his
back.
No,
no.
He has a pimple.
It people when he's a kid.
Oh my bed.
It's like,
no,
I don't think so man.
It's a good dad to have his dog,
his,
his dog from when he was a kid passed
away.
I'd like to get something silly.
Maybe a cow.
Ari should fear God.
Keep on trucking.
Tattooed on his body.
It's brilliant hip dude.
I love it.
I love that.
I love that dude.
There's some great tattoos in doc and
there's some terrible tattooed.
Nice Crystal.
It's been nice to have some shitty
tattoos myself in.
GRC could slow down a little bit.
The one on the stomach's a little too
real for me on the stomach and then the
mcgregor above it and he gave up his
abs,
so that's what bothers me.
People have killed themselves for that.
ABS will give up your apps for that.
I could've done without the big crown
being that up his neck tat I like the
straight blast gym.
Gorilla.
And then the crown on top of it.
I think that's my favorite tattoo.
The writing up his back.
I like that.
Well,
that's weird.
And I like symmetry.
Like suicide.
Girls like it or do.
I crashed for like a website that I.
his phone.
Your wife had been cats?
No.
Now I'm going to get her a tattoo that
says mine.
Ooh.
Oh.
Anybody could use that one though.
Yeah,
that's true.
You put council Mylans now.
Mine.
My mind of women don't like that.
They don't like to be owned.
Yeah.
At my or do the at my wedding.
I said twitter ones with tattoos do at
my wedding.
I,
I've made a speech and thank my parents
and everybody and I stopped and I went
and Amanda you are and there was
waiting.
They were praising like I was going to
say something really sweet.
I went to,
man,
you are my property now and that's what
this is about folks.
And everybody started laughing.
Did you get a dowery?
I did not get a doubt right.
There used to be.
You marry your daughter off.
Daughters are so useless.
You gotta you gotta give gifts stuff.
Hey,
you know who cries at weddings?
This guy.
Oh Sweetie.
I tried.
I could not.
I cried my eyes out.
I don't know what it is about weddings.
Divorce.
Divorce is coming.
Yeah,
because you know at my sister's wedding
I was in the wedding and your sister.
But that's what they.
The reason why they used to give away a
dowery was because the woman was thought
of as being less valuable than the man,
right?
Because there's times are tough and
people were dying in war and famine and
fucking sword fights and shit.
So like if you had daughters like the
way you would marry them off to a good
person that you have to give them
something,
give the dude something to marry your
daughter,
so you'd get like,
here's my,
here's a bag full of gold coins,
a ton of cash,
but that was the way that was like super
calm.
Let's bring this shit back.
But it didn't go the other way.
That's what it was fascinating about
modern culture is the divorce is
horrific for men.
Marriage and divorce can often be
horrific for men financially and just
from the limited amount of exchanges
I've had with friends that have been
divorced.
It's fucking horrific.
The amount of money they lose,
especially in California and the amount
of money they have to give off because
you know,
we know a few people that have done
well.
It made good money and then you know,
it doesn't go well when it comes to the
divorce and you find out the sums of
money they have to pay out when you have
to maintain their lifestyle when you
guys were together.
Exactly.
And if you're a fighter.
I'm a fighter friend who went through a
divorce and at the time when he was with
her,
you know,
he's a bad ass making bank.
We'll the career's over,
you know,
it's tough man.
It is tough.
It's just crazy athletes especially.
But it's weird how it switched around
like it used to be that the man would
get a lot out of getting married to the
woman,
so it'd be worth something.
It'd be like a big thing,
like they had to give up a dowery and
now becomes the woman if she decides,
you know,
there's a lot of power in that.
A few,
especially if you marry a rich guy,
you know,
you married some Donald Trump character.
Even if he's got a lock down,
fucking Prenup,
prenup.
Still set son.
Especially if have a kid.
Yeah.
He'll give you a few minutes just to get
the fuck away from this.
If Donald Trump writes you a check for 2
million bucks,
he makes that an a month.
Yeah.
That ain't no to him.
Not even a month.
Yeah.
It makes it in a week when you've got a
billion dollars.
$4,000,
million dollars.
That's insane.
It's kind of crazy.
Apparently he doesn't have that much
money,
but yeah,
he's worth 10,
but they say he's probably worth four.
I read estimates that he,
if you actually look at,
if you take out the debt and everything
and how much he puts into his business,
if you actually looked at what he has,
moneywise is closer to 200 million broke
ass bitch fucking know.
That can be 100 million.
That can be hating on them though.
Is that according to John Oliver and
some other stuff,
I read haters.
It's a tough thing to figure out,
but you can apparently look at his
assets he's not releasing.
You can look at how much it costs.
You can estimate what it would cost to
run those based on employees and
insurance and all that,
and then they have to.
A lot of times I think a lot of
companies,
I mean certainly if they're public,
but I don't know private,
but there are statements,
there are tax,
there are public tax for trump.
Men Struggle is real and people can stay
only 200 mil.
Yeah,
but I don't know.
I just think we don't know.
So we probably should be throwing
numbers rather rich's.
He's rich as fuck.
You know what's hilarious man?
I watched a little bit of the Democrat
Democrat debate.
I usually don't like bates,
but Bernie Sanders sent it home that he
sent it home.
Hillary Clinton.
Dude,
like there's some shit that she couldn't
say nothing about it.
When they were talking about the
pharmaceutical industries and the
banking industry,
the banking industry in particular he
was talking about,
that's what it was.
He was talking about the speeches that
she gives for hundreds of thousands of
dollars and then you know,
he's talking about how many of you like
that?
Why?
Why can't we get the transcripts from
these speeches?
What an amazing speech it must have been
to be worth $250,000
or whatever the fuck it was.
And Hillary was nervous as fuck.
She threw a cough drop in her mouth.
She's sweating and like half fake
smiling.
She can't say anything.
He's like,
you could read the transcripts of all
the times I've performed and did
speeches in front of the banking
industry because there are none.
Damn,
this is a guy who took his.
He took his vacation with his wife and
the Soviet Union.
Yeah,
he's an interesting guy.
He's a very interesting site.
I tweeted out last night,
it's called [inaudible] dot com.
You know,
I'm not too into politics.
We go this and they have like all the
major issues can click multiple choice.
What what you think is major and goes
through all of them and that then it
says who you most likely should vote for
it because your percentage is pretty
dope.
Well,
see my.
My feeling about Hillary is she seems
like business as usual.
Yeah.
Whether she would be good or not.
She's 100 percent businesses usually,
and I think that is the last shit this
country needs right now is this same
system,
so he tried to bring in trump.
I would bring in Bernie or trump for
bringing hillary,
although Bernie,
I'd bring in Bernie because I think that
he would shake shit up culturally,
but it's the best thing though.
See,
but here's the thing.
Here's the thing.
He can't do that.
He can't really pass all that.
You need congress and stuff.
The idea of what he's trying to tax.
It's socialism.
It doesn't.
It's kind of crazy.
It's,
it's.
It defies human nature because human
nature,
when you give people a way to not have
to work for things they do and some.
There's some people that fall upon hard
times.
There's some people that they got a bad
break,
a bum steer in life.
There's a bunch of people that are doing
poorly that it's not their fault,
but there's also a bunch of people that
are just fucking lazy.
Probably the majority,
once you say no,
I don't know what the numbers are.
I've never examined.
Penalize people that produce yes,
and you don't want to tax people to
produce who also create wealth,
but you don't want to tax them 75
percent the way France under Orland is
trying to do and has done.
It just doesn't work out because people
that produce will stop producing.
If I have to work 75 percent of my day
for someone else for the greater good,
hell no.
We've seen how that works in.
Just pick up a history book.
It doesn't work that well.
How will we as Bernie his oldest fuck
his ass ain't gonna make it.
Last question.
Should always be rather than Bernie or
just to ask yourself to what percentage,
what percentage are you willing to give
your power and your money?
Like is it 50 percent duties?
It unfortunately for me,
I have no fucking investment this site
and literally breaks it down.
It's a lot of stuff I didn't know about.
It breaks down very simple.
You just multiple choice and it shows
bone.
This is who believes in the way you do
and this is who you should believes in
the way you do.
Fuck man.
The one I would never think Hillary
Clinton see,
but here's the thing,
she's a centrist.
Can't tell what she really believes in.
That's right away.
She was what she said about Nancy Reagan
and Ronald Reagan.
A fucking liberals are abandoning her
now because she was trying to say that
Ronald Reagan and Nancy Reagan opened up
the conversation about aids during the
eighties.
That is total bullshit.
Not only is it total bullshit,
silence is death is like a campaign
because they weren't talking about it.
They wouldn't talk about aids for
fucking years.
Two years.
I remember it very well and that wasn't
a good administration just because Nancy
died.
Yeah,
she died and I,
I bet she was a nice lady.
You know,
she was really into astrology and she's
married to a president.
That's it.
We're done here.
You don't have to lie about them opening
up some sort of a fucking dialogue with
this country,
but eight,
that's just not what they did.
Hillary's biggest liability is that
people don't trust her.
She's just not based on her.
Based on her history.
That was another thing in the debate.
They said 37 percent.
Yeah,
that was.
That is insane.
Truster only 37 percent trusted women in
your country and there's no women trust
or less and so crazy.
Yeah,
and it needs a stylist.
Here's the.
Here's the fucker.
Here's the biggest thing I have them do.
If she is more like Obama,
if you look at the past six years,
the economy right now is not doing
terribly and this is a guy who believes
probably I'm a little bit more to the
right at least fiscally than someone
like Obama,
but I have to say that,
you know,
I was preaching about how,
under Obama,
if you look at his policies,
the government is going to grow the
government because of a lot of factors.
It's not just Obama,
but if you look at a lot of measures for
how government is grown,
it's kind of stayed exactly flat in the
past six years.
It hasn't grown.
A lot of.
That's because we don't have as big a
tax base and things like that,
but there are a lot of factors that go
into it.
But you know what,
in six years,
it's not like the economist disaster in
by a lot of measures.
The economy's doing really well.
So that's hard for conservatives to
argue with you.
No.
Let me just.
What's the word?
Blind allegiance.
No,
but devil's advocate.
Blind allegiance popped into my head.
I'm like,
why is that word?
I was like,
awesome word though.
But if you look at it from a Republican
point of view,
one thing that can be easily argued,
this is a common cycle of recession and
financial gain.
It happens.
Yeah.
And this is exactly what happens after a
downfall.
The downfall of our economy in 2008.
I don't know shit about finance,
but I've read a bunch of stuff that
people do know shit about and these
cycles are reoccurring cycles.
Like there's always,
as long as the republic stays up and
it's still up and running.
So he goes down and crashes.
People readjust.
Some people find their way,
some people lose their way.
Some people jump off buildings and then
it builds back again.
And that's what's going on right now.
So that's one of the things that they
argued about Clinton's era.
They were saying,
well,
you could say that Bill Clinton was
responsible for all that,
but the,
all the signs seem to indicate that the
cycle is moving in that direction
anyway.
No matter who is the president doesn't
have gone out of my ass for sure,
and I don't know it exactly.
But if trump wins,
if trump wins,
is there going to be chaos?
Chaos.
People are people.
Black people are already freaking the
fuck out that he fights at his fucking
bore,
rushing the stage.
The numbers don't add up for trump.
He doesn't have women,
he doesn't have the minorities.
And I don't think you're right.
Uh,
you'll see I've known.
But look,
you can't take.
It all comes down to him.
I don't really know what I'm saying.
Get the nomination.
Okay.
But all I'm saying is you don't really
know.
And the problem is it's real possible.
It's really just the idea that we've got
this far.
It's insane,
insane.
A lot of Republicans would tell you that
the Republicans,
once again,
because they're not unified,
have committed political suicide.
The pundits that I've listened to will
basically look at these hard numbers and
say,
you know,
the people that you see supporting
trump.
Yeah.
Trump has one,
you know,
but,
but for the most part,
the,
the popular vote isn't there for him.
At the end of the day.
It's going to go to Hillary.
I'll see someone.
I don't think so.
Yeah.
We'll see.
Yeah,
we'll,
we will see.
I think.
Here's the problem.
He hasn't even started to attack her yet
and he's going to attack from Ben Gazi.
She could be indicted.
That's the other thing,
two different cases,
man.
She's indicted.
It's a big issue when we do,
you know about the guy who was the uh,
the computer analysts that put together
her email server.
Fucking got immunity.
He just said he just got immunity
against prosecution apparently so.
So he can know so little about this.
I shouldn't be.
So then he's going to squeal like a
little piggy squeals like a little
piggy.
You got real problems.
But the idea of giving him immunity with
the real.
I know I read that somewhere.
Make sure that I just give him like 300
middle to go away.
She can't.
She doesn't have that kind of money.
She makes good money,
but I'm sure she spends it.
A lack of motherfucker.
The payouts per year from every lane.
They get insane amounts of money.
Really just her in trump.
Well,
insert her speaking monies off the
charts.
What does it,
what does it say?
Scroll down please.
Justice Department grants.
Immunity to staff who set up Clinton
email server.
Yeah,
so it's true.
So what that means is if they did that,
that means that they're thinking about a
case and they're probably planning case.
And if this guy gave up immunity,
that means he's got some serious fucking
information to get a bigger fish.
Who's the bigger fish?
Hillary Clinton that she don't like.
That is crazy because the choices so
poor,
terrible.
Well,
because are the smart people of American
saying,
fuck that job.
Mind Bernie Sanders.
I'm telling you,
I would almost be willing to give up
more money.
He's too old.
Here's the problem.
Here's the problem that I have with the
given up more money though,
is that you're giving up more money to
the government and I don't trust the
government.
That's all.
If I could give up money or if.
If you could,
here's the thing.
If you could have mandated charity for
really wealthy people where you could
give to like I like to give to something
like Justin wren is we're going to fight
for the forgotten.
That's a no brainer.
I give to that one because I know
exactly where the money's going.
That's a beautiful one.
Exactly.
But if you could get like a bunch of
good ones,
you know,
like a good.
Yeah.
You know I probably.
The problem is so much of that money
goes to running the machine that's
supposed to dole out the crew,
including Red Cross.
By the way,
if you look online,
there's a few websites that detail what
percentage of your dollar actually goes
to the charity.
Really listen at one point,
at one point,
the united way,
at one point I remember they had a
special on it.
One cent of every dollar was actually
going to the charity.
The ninety nine cents was going to
running the actual company.
Not only that,
but high salaries.
Ceos like the whole deal.
It becomes a quick wounded warrior
project.
Do you see that?
No.
What I was just rocking the hat the
other day was a huge controversy because
they handled the two guys running it.
We're making a million dollars a year
and they were spending on lavish,
lavish conferences and stuff.
Is that true?
Yes.
It will make it a million dollars a
year.
Yeah.
Both of them and now they're what you
want to talk about the wrong people to
fuck over like that trained killers,
but to be fair,
come back from serving their country and
find out about this shit,
but to be fair to those guys,
but to be fair to the people running the
wounded warrior project,
human beings,
if you're working for a very big company
and you make.
I think they made over $300,
million dollars in donations in one
year.
They had a huge endowment.
It's when you're working all day,
and I'm sure these guys are good people
who are working probably 12 hours a day.
You're going to put a first class ticket
and it might be a red.
I got to sleep.
I,
you know,
I'm doing all this work.
I'm going to spend $500 as opposed to
$300 and it just adds up.
And what happens is if you're doing a
lot of work and you're really good at
it,
they might say,
hey,
you're worth it.
We're going to give you a million
dollars because the board votes that in.
So what I'm saying is that when you have
a,
when you have that much money,
before you give them a free pass,
we should probably know how they got to
that.
Number three.
What I'm saying is anytime you have a
lot of money,
it's going to be spent and people,
and there's not enough accountability.
Human beings are going to behave in a
way.
Well,
they just,
yeah,
it's anonymous.
You're getting more money.
We're all doing the good job here.
We deserve something.
The biggest illusion is that people with
money are happier.
It might be the biggest illusion that
exists in the world today
because everybody really wants to be
happy,
but we really want to figure out how to
get happy and the one thing that we
can't figure out how to do is pay the
bills.
So we're like,
fuck,
if I could just pay my bills,
I'd be happy.
Like that is like one of the prevailing
illusions.
Well there's a certain point where you
make enough money where the bills are
taken care of and that which you're
going to be happy not stressed out about
how long the answer to everything.
Yeah.
It's not the answer to.
It certainly makes you happier to not
have to pay your bills,
but how many people do we know that are
like super successful?
Multimillionaires out of their fucking
mind?
Miserable.
The rich people I know are the most
miserable.
When I think I did a little inventory on
like the Times that I think about what
that brings a smile on my face at the
Times that I remember being the happiest
gay stuff.
Almost always when I'm in a behind a
dumpster with a strong guy,
very dark with the capital area guys are
black,
and very tall.
Hairy guys.
It's even better.
I don't think I've ever seen a black
carry with me.
Yeah,
I've seen like it's their chest.
Hair is like more of like curly,
like Taco meat.
Whether hey man,
how is that racist?
Some Mexican food.
It's okay.
It go to black and Harry said chicken
meat.
That was in trouble.
That's a problem.
You can't say check and even know
chicken's delicious.
Super Diligent.
But can you say Thai chicken?
If it's Tycho can you say black people
might like Thai chicken or you will you
get in trouble?
I don't know.
Subject right.
As soon.
As soon as you toss watermelon.
There were all.
Fuck.
Hey Man,
I love watermelon.
That's a delicious fruit.
You shouldn't bring it up.
It's really dangerous.
It is delicious.
Icing back to me and black eyes.
I've never seen a black guy happy.
I've definitely seen Harry Potter for.
Yeah.
Um,
but it's less common.
Well,
not like Russian dudes like that dude
that center in Abu Dhabi.
Do you know that guy?
That is z and Eddie Bravo.
Uh,
the Eddie Bravo Open.
Is that then the new Ebr,
the one that's in April.
Was that who?
That a crazy giant fucking Russian dude
is those Russians.
Grocer or lost his ship?
Faded his shoulders.
He had to.
It was a nice blend.
I remember when I was fighting about the
winds was like,
oh shit.
I like the shade.
You got it on the shoulders.
It was like a one to two guard on the
shoulders.
Just like a faith.
Yeah.
He's,
he's,
yeah,
he's a Harry.
Fuck.
He was really young too.
Before he didn't.
Before he took care of us.
Chest goes the hairiest motherfucker and
all of MMA.
Dave Herman.
You ever see Dave Herman?
Herman crew.
That shit out of his beard was.
No,
I'm talking about his whole body.
dude.
Dude.
Dave Herman is a fucking sasquatch.
Bring them by the way.
He's in trouble right now,
man.
I was going to say,
still do nuts.
He's nuts.
Here's a video that day released of him
getting fucked up by cops,
man.
Oh Man.
Yeah.
It was like one of those things where
the cop told him to get back in the car
and he's like,
why do I get back in the car?
The car I told you to get back.
It's one of those things where like,
there was an unnecessary altercation
between a person and he goes,
come exact fucking
him up.
And he's a giant,
you know,
very tall.
Herman's the.
I was in a back with him in a corner,
literally maybe hit Mitts for two
minutes and then these planet Gameboy
like old school tetris game,
but it's like two years ago they go,
Dave,
you're up.
Because now they go,
yeah,
puts it down.
Just rolls out there and fights.
It was August and we fought Gonzaga.
Uh,
I think so man in one round.
Oh Shit.
That's what he looks kind of good body.
Good.
Look into shredded set of tits on.
Okay.
I've got some tits.
Here's a talented fuck too,
man.
He just,
for whatever reason,
it was never disciplined.
Yeah,
I didn't totally put it together.
We had that same trainer,
the same striking coach,
and he was saying like when he'd be
like,
dude,
you gotta come in and train,
and he just read that motherfucker is
such a beast man.
So yeah,
my dad,
my dad makes that guy looked like a
girl.
We're that guy.
That guy would slap your dad's kind of
quiet after I talk about my dad,
he was probably smash it down.
I hate to say it now.
You don't know bro?
Most likely.
You don't know.
It's so much before you got to use.
He was like 20 and one just smashed
pitches in Japan.
Some good names to really good names.
Who did he beat?
Oh Man.
The Dave Herman days.
Um,
once he did get to the UFC,
he had that crazy bout with the Abu
Dhabi champion.
Remember that really big guy?
Miller?
A huge dude.
Not Fabiano schermer no.
Who was it really big?
Yeah.
And he's struggling with Netherlands.
Oh yes,
yes,
yes.
Fuck dammit.
I suppose five to.
It's the only fight I've ever turned
down.
I remember that dude.
What the Hell's his name?
Didn't that guy beat Fabricio for doom?
Yes.
To manage.
So you were married?
Huge.
Yeah.
Pull up a Dave Herman's,
him and him and Dave had a fight of the
night here.
He has 500 night serious John Oliver.
I know.
That's how I remembered it before I saw
him.
Bam.
Yeah.
John Oliver.
Dynamo is a serious fucking Jujitsu
phenom,
but for whatever reason it didn't really
pan out in MMA is fucking huge.
And he was also a lot older by the time
he got the click on John Oliver Dynamos.
Um,
yeah.
And it was like,
right about the time they were like
testing for real last to Mike Russell.
Last uh,
Dave Herman that beat James Thompson.
Yeah.
He's,
when I saw him though,
he was 30 because when I saw him was in
2003 in Brazil.
So I guess he was in his twenties at the
time.
He was a beast.
He was Iraqi people,
but it was also confusing for everybody
because he came out of nowhere because
this guy was,
you know,
it was a European guy and all of a
sudden he's a,
he's beaten Brazilians.
He's beaten a lot of like top top guys.
He was like right around the time when
Gunnar Nelson was reckoned people to
know about gunner.
That was the.
That's the only fight I've ever turned
down my UFC career ever.
It was after I lost some Nogueira I
wanted another big fight and like months
went by and they offered me him.
I knew him from Jujitsu,
but I had no idea about them from mma.
I like get the fuck Outta here.
And then Joseph was like,
oh yeah,
cool.
Here's Ben Rothwell.
Alright,
let's do that.
Wow.
Advisors managers.
I came in.
Yeah,
let's do that.
You should call that guy up in the
middle of the night.
He man or that Rothwell fight the.
Let me take you.
Hey Bro,
thanks for that man.
Give me some time to adjust.
I know,
right?
That's not the game I'm in.
So what kind of tattoo are you talking
about when you hit 10 million?
It's going to get that panther down your
neck,
getting something on your neck.
Maybe like a kiss.
Yes.
Ellipse like a lip kiss would.
That'd be sick.
Like a realistic one that I liked that.
I liked that.
Tat that tentacles and now you're
talking nonsense.
Yeah.
You get that.
That's going to be aired.
Towers.
That's 45th.
Yeah.
That's many days.
Five or six days and you have to take
time out like that.
That's a Kenyan mine.
You get your wife to kiss you on the
next one.
Hundred percent.
No to that.
How about if you get one right above
your bean bag?
Been fucking been right above it.
I hold my Dick.
I want it.
I write up about my home,
my dick up and you just tattoo and
understanding people.
People do get their dicks.
They do get their dicks to tests.
They do.
I've been thinking about doing it.
No fuck off.
I want to make it sparkly.
Does it doesn't sparkle enough.
If you were going to get your Dick
Tattooed,
what would you do?
Little barnacles.
Barnacles or warts?
Elephant is around the and make it
black.
Of course their sleeve it out and dark
ink.
If you could possibly be.
Yeah.
Has any guy ever like done that?
Because I know guys get their entire
forums black.
Have you ever seen that?
Like white guys will just really weird.
It's really weird.
Like they have one color,
one color tattoo and I always wondered
if that's a cover up.
Like they maybe had some shitty tattoos.
I always knew it as a cover up.
Like it was a real bad tattoo,
like maybe a girl or something.
So then they just blacked it all out
because you can't cover it up.
There was a famous dude who had that in
a band.
What band was that?
Tim?
Rage against the machine.
Yes,
that's right.
That dude,
his whole arms was like all black.
A lot of times don't like recovering
addicts get like the black band and they
do how many years and then just go black
all the way up to your ankles.
Do I want something on my back?
Like right at the top of my back and
have your shockers.
Oh yeah.
Look at this dude.
I want something over my route that
looks bad ass.
That's very odd.
You take for to kids.
Who is that guy?
He's from rage shoe.
That looks pretty sweet.
Name Jamie.
Tim.
Tim,
see it doesn't have a name.
That's a bad ass.
Yeah,
I like those.
What are those things that's from like
some Japanese symbol about the tadpoles,
tadpoles in the middle.
Is that come?
They'll come on.
It's called Com.
I wouldn't get that common a tornado.
I have to shave my chest in my arms,
but that's what happens when you come
into a garbage disposal and you hit the
button.
It's like a symbol of it.
Hey man,
he looks sweet.
I'm not mad at that at all.
It might be the best one I've seen.
Now they all don't look like that.
Didn't go too deep.
He went like a half sleeve,
like down to the bottom of his bicep.
It's pretty cool.
She's always wearing armor.
Maybe I'll get to six shooters on my
hips.
Your don't do.
They just get one tucked in your lower
back pointing towards your asshole,
but just an arrow.
Fun starts here.
Who are these people to get guns like
fighters do near their porn stars?
Porn.
Dad's pointing down towards their best
tattoos in the game as far as.
Well,
excuse me sir.
Your cheeks are tatted.
This man needs to hit the gym
occasionally.
Yeah.
I don't like his body.
Can have the dad bod and get all those
things.
If you're going to work on a tattoo,
if you're going to,
your body's going to be sleeved out like
that's not even a dad bod.
That's a good luck getting a woman to
fuck you so you can become a dad bod.
Yeah.
It's a Vegan body.
Sorry everybody to.
How dare you.
I dare you started.
I'm going to get a bunch of pictures of
vegans who are shredded.
They're going to be very angry.
You Dude.
You know the girl who has the sexiest
test to me.
Christy mack.
She's got some good ones.
Can I see?
She saw this spot just so bad.
She was in here with war machine before
war machine was out.
Before I tried to kill her.
I listened to some care.
She came here with them.
Yeah.
She took a nap on the couch.
Dead.
Gorgeous.
And person's very pretty,
very pretty.
She's tiny.
She's a tiny girl,
which is what like,
you know,
you hear all the shit that he did to her
and it's horrific.
If it was just a chick,
he's afraid for life.
Right?
He's gone,
he's gone.
But when you see her in real life,
she's so tiny.
You can imagine.
Pretty impersonal has beautiful.
You just can't imagine that a guy like
her with no hair.
Look at that picture.
I liked the reason why I like look at
that picture below.
Wherever the fuck out of the hospital.
Oh Hell No.
I'm talking about clarify though.
People are listed on the side,
bro.
That's the one.
That's the.
Yes one beat up one.
I'm not trying to see if he kicked the
shit out.
She got away.
Yeah.
He was going to get a knife and she
escaped.
She's the hottest chick in the game for
sure.
Well,
she's definitely one of them porno
games.
She's very pretty.
But my point is like,
I can't imagine.
She's like a little kid.
She always took a 100 pounds.
Really?
She's small.
She's tiny man.
She's fucking tiny.
I mean she might weigh 1:10.
Damn.
So she's super tiny,
so war machine,
I mean really fucked her up.
Yeah.
I mean I'm,
I'm not that good at numbers,
but she ain't a big girl.
She's like five slash one.
Maybe.
She's tiny.
She's,
you know,
the idea that he beat the fuck out of
her like that.
It's just so crazy.
I listen to some of that podcast and he
sounded like there's something about
guys ducked real fast like that.
You know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
So for me,
you know,
it's like a firefighter.
You got to realize,
was he nervous?
I was that.
Oh,
I'm sure you know,
he's on the podcast.
He knows a million people are going to
hear it.
I never think of that.
But for some people that's a big.
These also did a lot of stuff.
Yeah,
he's on steroids for sure.
A lot of this stuff,
a lot of stuff.
Had a lot of head trauma with some
serious demons with fighters,
some fighters that there is that
adderall,
like a energy guys have been fighting
for a long time,
but that's from head trauma.
That's what it feels like.
You got erratic behavior.
Breathing is a little bit erratic
sometimes,
so they don't have.
They can't keep it together very long,
but they can't keep it together.
If something's boring,
they can't keep it together as something
is.
If something gets annoying to them,
they don't have a good way of like
staying calm a lot.
A lot of them too.
A lot of them,
I'm one of them,
but a lot of them on our podcast or you
know,
personal conversations,
the jump all over the board,
like they will never finish a story and
come back around to jump all over.
Well,
when you know war machine,
he watched his dad die,
right?
Wasn't that one.
Was super dark demons.
Some tough.
He got arrested when he was really
fucking young.
Cops beat the fuck out of him when he
was like a teenager for nothing.
He tells a story and I,
I,
I tend to believe him,
man.
I tend.
I think that he's definitely made some
fucking horrible choices in life,
no doubt.
But I also think he got fucked life
fucked him.
He got a rough life,
fucked him early enough cards,
fucked him,
and he was around a bunch of other
people that also got fucked and it's
real hard to discern how to what
direction to go through in your life.
I mean,
there's been a gang of people like that
have gone in and out through the UFC
that just did,
don't know.
They've been surrounded with shitheads
and psychos and fucking criminals their
whole life.
They don't know peace in normal,
so that's all.
They still can't try and kill a bitch
though.
You know what he did was horrific,
horrific.
That that's also a breakdown of an
ability to cope at all.
It sounds like he had bouts of madness,
you know?
Well,
he came home.
He came over to her house.
He wasn't supposed to be there.
They were separated though.
He came over to her house and she was
with a guy.
She's a porn star.
Well,
she's hot too,
and guys want to fuck her if he's not
fucking.
Or someone's gonna wanna fuck her.
Yeah.
You look at a slide in the dms because
you come over,
you have to be real sad.
Your ass in front of the girl too,
I don't think.
Yeah,
I don't think he would've been running.
I would have been bad situation.
He had a knife then I'm like,
get her boy.
He probably would've had a knife too.
He's well,
he apparently it was a total surprise.
He didn't expect the guy to beat and he
just saw red and freaked the fuck out.
He's fucking nuts.
He's fucking crazy.
He's nuts.
He's always been nuts,
but he's always been like super cool and
super friendly to me and I mean I was,
I knew he had gotten into crazy fights
with a bunch of porn stars and beat the
fuck out of someone in a bunch of
people,
like three or four people at some porn
party.
Some dude.
But to its off,
they see the wrong shit.
They fuck up.
No,
there's no repercussions.
They can come across a guy like that.
He's going to fuck your world up anyway.
We can be my friend though.
No,
he can't get anybody but he can't be my
friend.
He can't be anybody who's terrible.
Let's talk about it.
But he can't be anybody's friend.
He's in jail forever,
you know,
but he's gonna make friends in there
though.
The point being like there's,
there's certain guys that will just
always fuck up.
It seems well,
but they also,
it's self sabotage,
right?
Like this shitty hand of cards in life
and they play this victim game.
It's like I don't deserve any success.
So they look kind of.
Dave and I were talking about this.
I called Joe because I wanted to lend
somebody money and I just want to
sometimes like I,
I think I have a lot of guilt because
like if you think about how some people
grow up,
they just never even had a chance.
It was just a math fell in my favorite.
Didn't fall in there.
I had parents that loved me,
I had stability.
Some people had the exact opposite and
then we were talking to like guy I
wanted to help and it's just a disaster
and I'm like,
I want to give him money.
I want to help them,
but you get a sense that this guy was
talking about.
He's always going to be that way.
Brands going to be broke.
He's always going to be,
fuck,
I've loaned people money.
I know.
You know how many people pay me back on
to zero?
The thing is,
did you tell me this?
Did you tell me this?
I've been lending people money.
If you lend someone money,
give it.
Don't expect to just give it to.
I tell them,
my father said that I've given it to
people.
Both.
You gave me that advice.
I've got good friends that had been in a
financial crunch and I gave him money.
If it's a legit friend and I know it's
or it's a family member,
I know it's going to help them out.
Fucking tape.
I was too hard.
I was fired for a reason,
so just take it takes time to figure
that out though.
Like when I didn't have any money most
of my life and then all sudden when I
started having money and someone needed
money,
I looked at them as like how I used to
be.
I'm like,
well,
if I help this guy out,
he'll,
he'll get back on his feet and they'll
take care of it,
but they,
none of them did.
Not only that,
they start avoiding you.
Yeah.
Which is really weird.
Hey Mike.
Um,
uh,
you were supposed to pay me after three
months and it's now six months present.
It's,
it's the old saying,
if you were the fastest way to lose a
friend is lending money because,
you know,
I've kind of gotten what was owed me
money for so long that I just don't even
bring it up anymore.
And they'll call me up and he'll like,
it felt good and every time we talk
we'll give me the same song and dance.
But he's about to pay me back and duties
owed me money for years when he's not
really acquaintances now,
but that,
that sealed it.
It's also,
it's a,
it's a mindset,
you know,
a lot of times my experience with that
is that yes,
some people say there are plenty of
stories of people who needed money badly
and they made good and they paid it
back.
Yes.
But,
but most of the time,
for the most part,
the people that I'm talking about,
like you just know,
they like,
man,
you're always from one crisis to
another.
Fuck,
are you doing it?
Doesn't matter the money.
Like I my last fight,
I signed this deal with this company and
I'm going to call them out close friend
who did the deal and never saw the money
and he's a real.
I've known this guy for average super
close friend man and not a financially
I'm fine.
I'm doing better than I've ever done.
Thank God.
And I,
we always had this rift.
He wasn't texting me or calling me back
and I just called him one day from a
random number and I said,
hey man,
it's me.
Fuck the money man.
Your friendship means more than me.
I don't care if I ever get that money,
but let's just move on man.
We're good now.
We're good.
But he's always going to have that
problem knowing that he ripped you off.
That's fine.
I'm cool with that.
You are.
But he's probably,
it's probably makes him feel that,
but at least I know where we're good and
we have open relationship.
Well,
that's nice.
It was very nice of,
you know what I mean?
Um,
I,
I told this dude,
I mean like six months in,
I was annoyed that I didn't get paid
back.
But then I stopped,
you know,
I'm this,
this was one guy.
I mean I could go back over to the Times
that I've been here and it's,
the problem is everybody's got this
scam.
Everybody's got this scheme,
you know,
they want to come to you and if you just
gave me this money,
I'm going to start this business and
that business can make so much money.
And then as soon as my buddy gets in,
he's gonna bring his cousin who has a
connection and we're going to start
this.
I know,
I know that because how many people lent
you money to get to where you're at now?
Did you ask me?
Neither know dove and I'll tell you who
it was after we're off the air.
But Shit,
fuck,
I know.
But devin,
I bought a guest comedian a car.
Um,
we,
we loved this young guy,
this young comedian and both of us,
Jay Leno now,
we loved them,
we loved them.
We thought he was amazing bathroom and
we liked him so much and I was bothered
that how,
how he had no money and he was so smart
and such a good guy and I was just like,
this is bugging me.
And he's taken the bus down to San Diego
and you take the bus around La and he's
got no way.
You can't live in La.
You can't be a comment,
can be living on the bus.
It's going to kill you at the end of the
day.
So I said,
I go,
you know what man,
I got some money and I said to,
I go,
let's buy this guy car.
I got a friend who deals in good cars.
They're not expensive.
Let's get them a reliable fucking Honda
or something.
How much you can spend four grand for
me.
We both spent two or something.
It was not a big deal.
Meanwhile,
long story short,
just bought it for him.
Call me.
Thank you.
All this stuff always brings it up.
He sold it.
When I see him.
No,
he made it.
He made it in the business.
He crushed it.
Yeah.
Real estate.
What had happened?
He never paid you back.
He never.
He,
I,
he.
I said to him,
this is not a loan.
This is what we want to give you and I
will never take money back.
This is I am.
Because he didn't want to take it.
He's like,
what are you doing?
I go,
this is my gift to you because you're
worth it and does it the same way as his
name.
Ron with.
I want to tell your story.
Why wouldn't you tell him?
Tell you.
Yeah.
You don't want him to.
To write it down though.
That he was a broke ass bitch at one
point.
Well,
he,
we all have our.
Let me see what you've never heard of
them.
Never fucking heard of them.
Gave Chris rock a car.
Yeah,
I'd support that choice.
The choice that you just made.
Of course,
once.
You see what I mean?
I knew right away I knew right away.
I was,
I understand why you didn't say the
name.
Yeah,
no need poor.
Do you have wonderful community?
I don't mind helping anyone else.
A lot of fighters to man.
Listen,
I get the struggle of the game.
So anytime they help with tee shirts,
whether they're trying to podcasting
what are.
I got one guy,
Jack May's,
hate to say his name,
but my,
my boy,
he's trying to get a fight on tight man.
He's been doing it forever and my old
manager and super close friend likes
Mcmahon owns tighten when he fight for
living,
man,
this guy's a bcs kids.
So I'm constantly hitting up pine almost
as his fucking manager,
like get this guy a fight man,
because they keep dragging on.
Then someone falls out and he's texting
me like,
dude,
I don't know what to do.
So it,
it.
It's tough man,
because you want to help them but help
them different ways than giving them
money.
That's the way he is worth the effort.
Some people are with you every,
like even some people,
like if somebody asked me for money and
I feel like they are really needed and
they're,
you know,
I,
it's almost worth the money to see them
not be in pain.
Like I'll buy that for my own peace of
mind.
Not a hard fast rule,
you know,
like exactly like most things in under
most situations.
When people need money or they come to
you to borrow money,
they're not going to fucking make it.
It's just,
it's not going to happen.
No.
If they're reaching out to you from God,
but most of those guys,
they're looking for a shortcut.
Yes.
Most of this,
this part of the personality of someone
who keeps coming to people asking for
money.
It's like it's so common that it's the
same kind of guy.
It's like this God that has this
elaborate story that he tells you that
involves some new thing that's going to
happen and when that new thing happens,
it's going to take.
I wish I could record them.
I wish I could record the rules there.
I met with a guy the other day who's a
buddy who I am.
I'm also in business with.
We're meeting on the idea of this
merchandise thing and he pitches this
whole marijuana idea.
To me,
I'm like,
what the fuck is wrong with you man?
Like a business whole business where I'm
like,
dude,
get out of here man.
Just focus on this.
Cornered me at the fucking store one
night about some marijuana business he's
doing and wants me to get involved and
they'll give me equity and the dude,
I'm not doing anything.
I have people call me all the time about
you pitching me ideas for you.
They're just like,
I got this great idea.
I got to speak to Joe Rogan and person.
I know my friend,
but it's just not going to happen.
I could see it all going bad.
I could see it.
I mean immediately you talk this guy,
the guy,
first of all the guy super aggressive
coming up to you,
wants to go into business with you.
It doesn't even know you wanted to go
into business,
to your first sign of craziness and then
you know,
once,
once it all goes about,
dude,
I fucking made this business been if it
wasn't for fucking Mahmoud and have this
pit and you're like,
I didn't even want to be a part of this.
Why am I here?
I got to get out of here and the next
thing you know,
you get this crazy dude.
He hates you.
Nothing worse.
Yeah,
I mean the people that need your help or
need your money in that bad of a way
where they go out of their way to get in
your face about it.
They're looking for like a way to
shortcut the system.
Like the system of making it as a
comedian.
The
system.
Like how many guys have come up to you
and go,
hey man,
you don't be fucking really cool if you
could take me on the road.
Like what?
Like dude,
you don't get spots anywhere.
I can't take you on the road.
You're,
you're not putting in the proper hustle.
And did you ever do that?
Joe Rogan?
Do you ever do that?
Yes.
There's a reason why his ass is asking,
you know,
because I knew there's no short cuts in
man.
There's ways to do it.
I,
I'm friends with all the door guys,
the comedy store,
and these motherfuckers,
they put on their instagram pages.
They're constantly hitting open mic mess
constantly.
There'll be relentless.
You've got to be writing and always
performing.
Speaking of performing,
we're going to be in denver,
March 18th and 19th.
It's my birthday too.
What's happening?
Oh,
I'm glad you asked Joe Rogan.
Um,
we're gonna be doing a live show.
Brendan Schaub,
Brian,
count fighter.
And the kid March 18th,
two shows at comedy works south 19th,
two shows comedy works in Denver.
Performing.
I love it.
This.
It's one of my favorite parts of your
birthday,
dude.
It's my birthday.
Buy Your tickets now.
Where do they go for tickets?
He fat k Dot k dot this bitch out
Denver.
Denver's one of my favorite places on
the planet earth.
Has one of my favorite places.
Did I?
That's where my wife is from and I
always moved back there.
So you want to move down together,
we'll fucking move that.
You could live 20 minutes from the city
and be in the mountains and have a
fucking insane house with a view.
Here's the process.
Drive down to Denver.
Comedy works.
Absolutely not.
It was the only problem if you to leave
and be pissed now to my wife.
My wife grew up in snowshoe.
I'll never move back.
Exactly.
Fuck that.
Snow.
People don't like the snow.
I like it.
I like visiting Dev,
track animals when we go in soon.
Oh,
we'll talk after the police.
Yeah,
we're good.
We're going to um,
the thing got moved to August.
That's important for media.
Frank Castillo.
He's one of the guys who works at the
store and this fucking kid is funny as
shit.
And he's hustling.
He puts up his,
like his instagram posts.
If you look at frank custody,
I think it's just frank Castillo on,
on instagram.
But if his,
uh,
his instagram posts.
So it's constantly post all the
different open mics.
You have to be.
There's too much competition.
Cameron doing.
He's the one open mic night they dealt.
Do Open mic nights that are outside on
someone's roof.
They do them everywhere.
Doesn't matter what you do,
it's how you have to do it.
It doesn't matter.
It's an audience.
I have this friend who was breaking into
comedy,
but this person has a a large online
social media following already and then
break it into standup and we had a
conversation about it and they don't
want to do the open a girl by not saying
he or she.
They're thinking the two good foot.
Well they don't want.
They don't want to do that hard,
that hard work that they should know.
They should also know it's all the same.
Well,
not only that.
How about the fact that you were.
I will do that grind and Brian and I
will go to open mic nights.
Well to this day will show up at an open
mic night.
Well,
we've pumped.
Fucking plan it out.
Yep.
You know.
Well,
I'll do spots.
I do the fucking when red band has an
ice house spot at 10:00
at night and then there's like 30 people
in there.
I'll fucking show.
Well,
I'll,
I'll text him
up.
What's up man?
Because you right,
sometimes you come up with ideas,
fossil,
you're passionate.
I said,
hey,
we need to start doing that.
I'm going to start doing a lot more of
that local stuff.
I'd like to.
How about the hot cafe?
That's fucking great.
Sometimes when I'm doing the um,
the ice house,
like the main room,
Jan will have a show,
the booker level,
a little show in the little room over
there and again at 30,
40 fucking people that,
that room only holds 80,
you know?
So if you got like,
and sometimes like red bag gets like 80
stuffed in there sometimes and it is a
killer fucking crowd just are on top of
you man.
There's like 80 people in that room with
you guys.
That's amazing little room,
right?
Yeah,
I'd have it.
How was it?
How worried is it?
When we started doing our live shows,
I didn't know.
Brian was like,
dude,
I think we're in Portland,
Seattle,
100 people,
eight,
900 people.
And I was nervous.
I'm like,
yeah,
whatever.
It Brian's like,
dude,
you don't realize like,
this is crazy man getting theater.
He's like,
he just jumping in,
can you do,
but listen,
there's no one way to do it and what
you're doing is different because you're
doing that show.
Like you guys were essentially doing
like a dramatic piece.
Yeah.
Yes.
A lot of ad libbing and fucking around.
But you have a show.
You've been like Tom Seger and his wife
Christina Presensky.
They have your mom's house.
They take that on the road and it's
Kinda the same sort of thing.
They have an online like podcasts,
but then they have a real live show,
like an extended brand.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And it becomes fun.
Shit they do.
Yeah.
That's,
I mean that's just the greatest time of
my life,
man.
Pivot to what you want to do.
Stand up on your own.
Like just.
Yeah,
like don't put it.
You're doing it right.
Yeah.
We kick the show off.
I do like the first 10,
15 minutes.
So I absolutely love it man.
So do you think you'll start like
expanding and like putting together an
act and maybe even touring?
Yeah,
I think so too.
Would you could that.
You could totally do.
I think you can do it in the hardest to
a show with the three of us.
How about that fucking come on son.
Fun.
That would be a Brent and get ready to
sell at 3,500
people because it broke and starts doing
it.
That's what it means about that $5,000.
Oh my God.
I'm more happy now.
I'm working.
I get more satisfaction when there's
those live crowds.
That's why I put them on instagram.
So I'm so happy because it's hard to
explain because in the UFC if,
if you have a fight,
right.
And I've never been the main event.
I've been combing events,
I've been in big fights,
but the crowd's not there just to see
you.
They're there to see all fighters.
Right.
But at a fire and a kid,
whether it's 800,
900 people,
he sold out shows.
They're really there to see Brian and
Brendan.
So the love I get from that,
do I have,
I've been seeking it,
looking for it my entire life,
my entire life for this approval.
You know what I'm saying?
For this fucking approval my entire
life.
It's hard for me not to cry,
man.
When I get done with them,
it's hard for me to repeat too.
That's Irvine,
right?
You guys do in Irvine.
Yeah.
Everybody tomorrow night.
I think there's tickets left.
That's a fat room.
I can't wait man.
I get.
It's like the.
It's like superbowl Sunday for me,
man.
It's fun.
Insane.
Now you get it.
I get it.
They don't have.
Thank God brain trauma hasn't kicked in
where I can still fuck dude.
Alpha.
Brain the fuck out of yourself on a
daily.
Eventually they're going to have stem
cells and shoot it in there and you're
going to be a super brainiac.
Hopefully.
Man.
You don't want to get too smart though,
because if you get too smart you,
you'll consider the repercussions of
saying what you're about to say.
I know right now I'm just like,
that fucking dog just go insane stuff.
I keep a certain amount of stupid on
hand just for.
I really do do.
Huh?
There's a certain amount of like if I
wanted to really go fucking sot nom
namaz day and fucking meditate all day.
The problem is I could kind of go there
to.
Those guys aren't funny though.
Are they?
Well,
it's not the kind of funny I do.
I mean people get bruised up fresh.
I kind of comedy people get bruised up.
The thing is if people,
if they don't have a opinion on what
you're doing one way or the other,
you're not doing shit son.
Well I like,
you either want people that you want
more people to like you and hate you,
but you need both.
That's what I like.
We released podcasts.
I get all these hateful things and good
thing like,
perfect ma'am.
We're doing good.
I know what I like.
I know the kind of comedy that I like
and that's the kind of comedy that I
like to do.
Like I don't like.
I don't like calm comedy and chaos.
Like I like,
I like watching people have fun.
Yep.
You know?
And that's,
there's only a couple ways to do that.
And there it's always the subject
matters are always going to be
controversial.
Like,
like I always say,
Joey Dee is my favorite all time comic
because he's a 100 percent
controversial.
His take on everything is always going
to be controversial.
It's always going to be.
That's why you go to a show because you
don't want to hear what the average,
you know,
you want to see outrageous shit man.
Well he's a rock and roll comic.
Yes.
You know you're watching some fucking
rock and roll.
You Watch it.
Some chaos.
That's what I want the best.
That's why when someone has an opinion,
like that's why I don't watch these
shows,
whether it's nfl or UFC where I know
who's paying their bills.
So they don't give a real opinion like,
no bitch tell it like it is.
That's why they wouldn't let you on UFC
tonight.
That's why 100 percent they got rid of.
And what,
why they got rid of.
Because also my,
I'm so sick,
I'm doing so well my own shit with
finding the kid and these live tours.
When they,
they wanted me to drive to Burbank to
film the show and do all this stuff
like,
you have to pay me this much,
man,
this is what I'm worth.
Now.
They're like,
well,
we can get this dude for this.
I'm like,
that.
Good luck getting that,
do that.
Well,
you understand your value.
You know?
I think that is one thing where if I
could give the UFC advice,
what's one thing that I would say is
turn guys loose to turn guys lose.
Why don't beat themselves.
What makes the UFC special?
Because you're looking at baseball.
It's on a downward trend because they
have all these rules and guys can't be
themselves.
We have so many personalities and to
become a fucking cage fighter and you
underwear,
you got to be pretty fucking crazy.
So you get these cool colorful
personalities.
We want that man.
Let that fucking go.
You remember?
Do you remember when Matt Brown got in
trouble for talking about like Rhonda?
I'm not watching list.
The women are naked.
Just some redneck shit.
Fucking
savage.
He,
he had,
uh,
he did a video the other day on
instagram of him with his kid on his lap
and his kids like,
what you like being cute and you know,
little little tiny baby and he's like,
it's hard being hard fucking savages
hold onto to a baby in between dead
lifts and punching people in the Dick
fucking baby dude.
Does he have a fight coming up?
I'm like,
yes,
he was supposed to be scheduled,
but why do I think he pulled out or
something or the FYC I canceled.
Wasn't he supposed to be fighting?
Why do I think he was supposed to be
fighting Damien Maia?
Because he's the last guy to beat
wonderboy.
Yeah,
it was like four or five years ago
though.
What is map Brown's put.
See if we could find that.
I feel like there was a great fight that
was coming up that was super excited for
it and it got canceled.
Do you have any interest coupon whether
Mcgregor's fight Aldo next.
I think there's going to be frank.
I think you fight Frankie Edgar's away
easier sell the Aldo fight.
Aldo comes back and wins and wins in
spectacular fashion,
like say if Aldo in cups wants and have
a rematch because cub swanson,
although went the same way that Frankie
Mcgregor when although jumps out them
hit some of the flying knee two seconds
into the fight and cracks him.
You can't sell Aldo Mcgregor too.
You can sell frankie just like you.
Why not?
Because all he's got to win again.
If he wins again,
see the differences.
You could sell it,
right?
You wouldn't sell it for as much as if
although one.
Okay.
Damien Maia.
Yeah.
It was right,
right.
UFC One 98.
That's in Brazil.
That's overdue.
I'm steep in meal check.
We'll be doing a fight companion because
Joseph will be here.
Fuck,
that is the weekend of my daughter's
birthday.
So I can't go.
Go back to go back to what you were
saying about Mcgregor and Aldo.
Oh.
So although would have to,
he would have to,
I mean redeemed them.
So we'd have to be some.
Something you could sell.
That's like when manny Pacquiao got
knocked dead.
The floyd may where the fight was off,
but then he beats Chris Algieri.
Yeah,
it looks like a fucking demon again.
It starts looking fantastic and go,
okay,
we can see it.
We can see it again.
And then they sold the fight.
But if they tried to go right from the
Juan Manwell Marquez knockout right into
fort.
Maybe with the fight.
Fuck that shit.
That fighter as to when Joe,
that.
That's why like for,
for Misha,
I want Michelle Holly to.
Do you want me show Rhonda?
Really use it for a third time.
Yup.
I do.
I think Misha has a mission.
It's better now.
It'd be interesting to see.
I,
I do that,
but she's the champ.
Me.
She's the fucking champ now.
I think that's because she's lost her
Rhonda twice already and didn't really
come close to being there.
She so she could lose to Amanda Nunez.
Amanda Newman.
I know.
That's why I can't toss them in a Nunez
in there right now because there's only
three bitches who can fight right now
that we're going to pay to see.
Really.
So you have Meesha,
holly,
Rhonda,
right?
probably till November is what they're
saying.
So basically eight months just because a
movies.
Who knows.
I bet.
I bet you heard he's her ass back up now
that Mitch has champ,
right?
I don't know man,
because who knows man.
So let's say one chooses to fight
differently and not engage her and fight
the way she fought.
Holly.
She fights holly and fight smart and
measured bro.
She was getting her ass whupped against
holly until she pulled that out.
She was definitely losing shuffling,
getting whooped though I wouldn't say
she's her face was well taken care of at
the nfl stuff face especially with 35
pound girl and she never got rocked.
Her knees never buckled.
She never like looked like she was going
down as down three to one until she was
definitely down in points,
but nothing holly was doing was carrie.
She was.
Holly was fighting real smart and she
was moving and can completely control
the control of the standup at Michigan
to win this and I was talking to Brian
during the fire went and it's like,
man,
she's always second best because she's
champ.
She's a great champion.
She looks good.
She talks good.
She represents good for.
For Women in the UFC.
I would say all those things.
Great.
Yes.
Yeah.
She's.
She's a champion.
She's a really nice person.
She's great and she's a.
So it's holiday show.
Yeah,
she is.
That's what you want.
Especially that ass from the house.
Respect Brian Caraway.
That's a.
that's.
I was talking about this on the podcast.
I think that nobody talks about that.
That's a real love story.
That's an American love story.
Brian Caraway,
so in her corner and he gets very
romantic.
I think that's a very.
I do.
I'm going to cry.
Let it relax a little bit,
but you won't shut the fuck up.
Nobody gives.
Nobody talks about it.
I do.
I almost cried again.
I almost cried again was when I was
interviewing me.
Yeah,
because she finally did it when she
said,
when I said,
how's that sound?
She goes,
I've been waiting to hear you say those
words for.
So she was going to retire.
How about she was like,
they're not getting my shot.
I'm going to be the fuck.
I was thinking about it.
You know what she's thinking,
what she's doing with her life.
She has,
if,
if let's say,
run it for whatever.
You can't fight til November.
So that's what,
eight months,
right?
Yeah.
Why not do Holly Meesha to.
Well,
you certainly could.
I mean that was the only other fight you
can do,
but the problem with that fight,
his mom's not really a problem with that
fight.
What's the worst that happens?
Holly Wins.
Then you have holly,
Rhonda,
that we want to see.
Really?
That's the biggest blockbuster.
Finding the history,
but I.
Because you've lost that.
You definitely,
but I would like to see it.
The problem is the timeframe,
but I would like to see Ronda versus
Meesha,
but what if me,
she wants to sit it out,
would have me.
She wants to wait for Ronda and she was
trained like a fucking demon for h is
what holly should have done and they
should have just been on this pr fucking
tour to build her celebrity up so high.
So by the time her and Rhonda fight is
the biggest fight in UFC history,
I'm going to get Dan on the phone and
have him hire you.
Well,
you know,
you know what the agreed with that he
wanted.
That's what Dana was saying was he had a
blast out.
People think I don't like Dana.
I'd like Dana,
man.
We just disagree on certain things.
Who gives a fuck?
Well,
but I,
I when I say,
because Dana goes,
yeah,
she should have waited,
but we had a meeting with her manager
choosing me in on the meeting and they
wanted to hurry up and fight,
which I think was a mistake.
He's 100 percent correct.
Well,
100 percent correct financially,
but you gotta respect her as a warrior.
What she wanted to do,
Joel wanted to get in there and people
in a throw down.
People argue that on the title that you
had been a better fighter fuel.
You're an armchair quarterback when
you're talking about Monday morning,
the day of the fight.
She could have one and if she did one,
she would look like even pros and cons.
I mean,
I'm talking about when people say,
ah,
but such a warrior.
Listen,
being a warrior doesn't pay the fucking
bills 20 years from now.
That's true,
but you gotta understand she made a fuck
load of money for that.
She will wait.
She would have made so much more fucking
money.
I would say she's gonna have.
She's gonna have a shot at Rhonda.
It's going to have holly,
I think holly,
but who knows how many.
This is the risk and the risk and MMA
is.
Look when Connor,
if Carter loses to Frankie Edgar,
which is a possibility.
It's a scary fighter.
Conor.
Very,
very strong and so it's so in a way,
if he loses to nate,
now we lose it to Frankie.
That luster.
That time is gone and it's,
it's.
And that's one of the things.
He still has an email right now.
He still that because he lost a fucking
savage at one system.
That's a biggie.
Edgar is a 48 hour storm.
You better have everything.
Chad Mendez the fuck.
He said 48 hours.
Can I get tired?
Never.
He's not getting tired and he's going to
wrestle his ass and he's gonna.
Come at you crazy angles.
His footwork is.
Since this is the problem.
This is smaller.
The problem though,
if connor connects,
which friend he does get hit.
Yeah.
You think in La Conner.
I mean frankie could get knocked out of
Connecticut at 1:45
cutter.
Well,
starch.
Anybody,
anybody be so heavy head by the way.
So we'll cub Swanson and cub Swanson
couldn't connect on forgotten.
Birthed in me.
Frankie just wolverine dim just for
whatever.
It's very,
very possible deviled them.
First of all the know condoms got to
suck a lot of weights,
very hard soccer him and it's a five
round fight and man,
if anybody can grind you into the
ground,
it's,
it's that guy and you're at the Chad
Mendez fight.
Obviously Connor had a knee injury going
into that fight,
but Chad took him down at will,
you know,
and that'll be when frankie gets you
tired.
Man,
he's gonna get in trouble when he did
two cups,
one cub.
Swanson rather was incredible.
I mean he just wore him.
Never seen an ass whooping.
Like really?
It's getting cub cub as far I've seen
everyone in the gym club is the most
talented guy if ever seen in the jail
watches tennis gave or fight insane how
talented that kid is.
So when I saw frankie just dismantling
with whole wheat,
Frankie Edgar,
his,
like you said,
his footwork,
he's,
he's his boxing's great.
Hard to hit.
You know,
whether or not probably,
and I don't know the numbers,
but I would assume I don't think he's a
drawl,
but if snob.
But if you give them a car,
you're good because he's a fucking
drawer.
So what I'm asking is that if you're
connor's manager and if you're connor,
doesn't it make sense to somehow duck
frankie in the interim fight Aldo for
the big money,
easy fight,
but all you see you go.
Unless although winds,
I'm telling you how you're going to sell
all that when he starts them at 16
because he was a champion for 10 years
and also that starching with happen so
quickly.
People go,
I'm in shit because I want to know if
that was a fluke.
That's why I'm interested a little bit
run out,
but Brian,
you could sell it.
You could sell it,
but you're not going to sell it for
nearly as much as you would sell it.
If all the wind something.
I've got to fight all the fights.
Max Holloway.
How about what have you tried some Max
all the way and he fights fight so it
looks like the Aldo of old or he gets
his ass whooped,
but one of those guys emerges and then
you've got the possibility of Max
Holloway having a rematch with connor
connor to a decision.
We need some young blood in Mexico,
a fucking fucker mother.
Some young bloods only like 24,
24 deep and Halloween was fighting.
He was fighting 55,
always 45,
44,
45 fucking free.
He's got a fight coming up though.
Doesn't Max Holloway have a fight?
Aldo UFC 200.
Make it happen.
Why do I feel like he's got a good fight
scheduled like that I'm interested in.
Is He fighting llamas?
You fight and Ricardo Lamas because
llamas just fought.
Diego Diego's only appearance at 45.
He was way too sucked up.
But.
But it maxes on a total winning streak,
isn't what?
What is he?
How about Diego Sanchez beaten Jim
Miller.
He got dale season one season one
winner.
Only guys left,
right?
Yeah,
but Diego is like,
he's still in the hot mix.
That fucking kids an animal.
All he knows.
One thing,
fighting to take a Sanchez.
Watch his fight with Jake ellenberger.
He said,
how about Martin Kampmann?
That's the best one because for two
rounds he's fucking face is hanging off
of his head.
He's nuts and he's just.
And he wins.
The third round,
he went into the fucking third tire
against the guy at camp men who fought
in [inaudible].
80 five.
You know it was a small 85 as diego one
that sees amazing striker too,
but very good striking diego.
One that goddamned third round puts his
arms down and he goes,
come on,
and they started fighting now.
Now you've got them angry one the third
round,
but against Gilbert Melendez.
That's right.
That was fucking scratch dude.
I was doing an analyst's work for espn
and all they want talk about jds and
whoever was on the.
I forget which one it was and I went,
fuck that.
Just hear me out.
Fuck debt.
Fight as a guy who knows fighting you
have.
You have to talk about Diego in Gilbert
Melendez please.
Finally they kind of showed it.
I'm like,
I'm telling you guys are fucking
dropping the ball.
This
is the fight.
That is one where I'd show my kid like,
you want to see what findings about
Insert Gilbert Diego hair.
I'm like ESPN and shit together.
Fuck.
I think it was a jds mark hundreds on
that.
I forget to get the fuck out of my face.
That's like some guys they want to fight
like that,
but they can't find a willing opponent.
But if you can get Diego and Gilbert
together,
kill it.
Like Gilbert.
If you fought smart too,
probably out moved diego for sure.
Let's try it.
But he,
he decides in bags as they should put
those guys.
He's just every car.
Every two months.
Those two fight.
Yeah.
Go every two months.
Not going to step back.
He's going to stand in a phone booth
with you and just bang.
Such a good guy.
Gilbert.
He got.
He got popped for what?
Yeah.
Dammit.
I know that I got older.
You get older.
You need a little help and I,
I,
you know,
I'm torn on this.
I swear to God I'm torn because I know
she's shorter careers.
You gonna see more injuries,
dad bod veto or bums me the fuck out to
see that.
Let me see it.
Bring it up to our TV tour is maybe my
all time favorite fighter watch now.
I like tic Toc.
Overeem.
TRT over.
Okay.
You're right.
Because you were hurting.
Bitch.
Trt over and heads off.
And j.
what's your brock lesnar and that's hard
to top that.
Maybe you want to retire the size
factor.
He's just so big and ridiculous.
He didn't look at it and doing world
class striking.
Yeah,
but fucking Vittorio,
we'll kicked rockhold never throw.
We'll kick it.
Hold Bro.
Kicked Michael Bisping's eye on those
little brown kids.
We can't see his girl is fucking hot.
Well,
that's.
It's hard to tell man.
That could be the shirt sticking out
like that.
He doesn't.
When he fought Chris Weidman,
everyone was saying he's fat in that,
but that might just be the shirt and you
can't really tell these certain
pictures.
You take agree.
I liked the fact that we put that
online.
He doesn't give a fuck.
Look at my gut.
It was a show I just knocked out Dan
Henderson and one round,
but first of all knocked out.
Done Hansen.
Look at my girl.
I'm rubbing her shoulders.
Eat Dixon.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I got a gut,
but I'm fucking rich and Brazilian.
You know what I'm saying?
He's a superstar.
He's a superstar in Brazil,
but really it's like Tom Cruise over
the.
He got hit hardest by the reebok deal.
Dude.
I saw.
I watched a documentary on Rinaldo,
the soccer player.
That's who you want to be in your next
life.
That got really beat his ass.
I don't give a shit.
He's the king of the world.
He's a prince.
I would make out with them.
All right.
Where's Vito Bell floors up there,
man?
That guy's killing it.
How about t our TV tour man.
CRTV tour back in the rockhold days and
the little when he fought a bisping.
Wouldn't you have liked to have seen
what would happen if that guy fought
Weidman?
I would've liked to have.
I still beat him with his wrestling
moves.
Verse Luke rockhold.
Well,
we already saw that once.
Yeah,
he did kick his
face off.
Kicked his face on talking about the
champion rankled.
Now those are back in the day.
I'm talking now dude.
Crtv Torres.
Barely human.
Okay.
That's easy.
The aliens standing because here's the
thing about Ti RTV tour.
You got this freak body with abundance
of fast twitch muscle fibers.
Ridiculous work ethic.
See,
he's still in good shape.
That was him throwing a punch there.
He's still.
I don't know why he's thrown one punch
and dropping his hands like that would
certainly be doorbell for.
Yeah,
it's one punch knocks people out,
but it's weird like,
why would you show this?
This is a weird thing to show because I
don't think he gives a fuck.
Yeah,
I mean,
I guess that's the weirdest thing.
I guess they're working on some moves or
something like that.
Just moving around at the end of the
workout.
You compare that to go to the rockhold
fight.
Vetoer verses Luke rockhold.
By the way,
we might've brought up TRT Vitorin when
we get together about every time our
obsessed with him.
He was a psycho man.
I need me for a loop and this just
shouldn't my fucking world.
Kimbo and Ken shamrock busted for that
coming.
I don't believe it.
That doesn't make any sense.
Them by Lord lead him there.
He's a demon.
Luke rockhold and is all natural.
They're like surfing and just a basic
ass haircut.
Rockhold looks like a school boy there.
He's like,
what?
His fucking face kicked off in Brazil.
Well,
Roger told me 14 hours and get your face
kick though.
He told me he saw him at the weigh ins.
He was like,
what the fuck is this guy on?
He said,
just you could tell just looking at it.
And then Vito whispered in his ear,
afraid.
Well,
his skin,
he's also,
it's training.
I mean it is not just the fact that he
was on trt,
which you most certainly was,
but also the fact that he was training
like a fucking monster.
That's him all sucked up though.
That's at the winds when he's pointing
to is Jesus Waste Bella band there?
Yeah,
for sure.
We see like above that Jesus throw that
we'll kick you out like that's him when
he will kicked rock holding the head.
Look,
look how big he is.
I mean Jesus Christ.
So the reason why I think he's the
scariest,
he's because he's got a massive amount
of experience.
You're talking about the guy who has
been fighting since 97.
He's been training since,
you know,
years before that.
Right.
So he's been around for ever almost 20
years in the game.
He's in his ups and downs at the
highest,
highest level,
at the highest level and he's only like
38 now.
I think he just turned 38 if I get it
correctly,
which is crazy.
Such a nice guy.
Very nice because like the Nice Guy,
very nice guy,
v towards a smart guy too,
you know,
and he speaks very fluent English as
well as uh,
as,
as uh,
as well as a Brazilian Portuguese
rather.
But if you look at his body,
like what you have is this freak body
that also has all this knowledge.
And usually by the time a guy acquires
all that knowledge,
his body starts to fall down.
I had a conversation with Eve Edwards
about it,
you know,
we were talking about like,
eve is super knowledgeable guy.
So many fights.
He's had so many fights
and it's almost like his,
he knows so much now,
but his body just doesn't cooperate like
it did when he was young and wild.
Bummer.
Yeah.
Back in the Aaron Riley days,
ever seen his fights with Erin Wiley and
hook and shoot.
Yep.
And then you see a lot of guys who have
resurgens we were talking about this
like heavy weights and stuff.
Who,
you know,
like Ben Rothwell,
guys like that.
Who victoire I mean,
uh,
um,
fabrizio like,
you'll,
you'll see them when they get to be like
in their thirties.
They,
yeah,
our,
they get into thirties and they're
fighting differently.
That's heavyweights though.
Yeah.
Well wait until January,
have a longer career and later we'll
guys be thinking about coming back.
I think they genuinely don't know how to
move their body as well when they're
younger because there's so much mass.
I think if you look at like little tiny
people,
like one of the things I've noticed
about having kids is you want to like
kids in gymnastics class and the shit
they can do with their body.
It's not just like flexibility.
There's no wait,
there's no mass.
So they're like,
no,
even their body around,
they're rolling around,
they're doing flips and they develop
like an understanding of.
It's also being able to measure like a
Chris Vineyard was explaining to me how
though as you get better and better at
boxing,
you have to move less because you're.
I can measure shots,
so instead of like really moving to the
side like a guy like that,
I'll just literally step back like an
inch gets you to miss and then boom,
we'll experience experience is
priceless.
Men before I fought really Nelson tell
me,
I was like,
dude,
I'm more athletic.
Well,
and he goes,
yeah,
but man,
he has so much experience.
I'm telling you,
it's priceless.
I was like,
yeah,
what the fuck does nate more current?
No.
Build courts.
A perfect example too.
Well,
no,
who the fuck?
They just knock out CB doll baby doll
and I was saying in that fight,
I'm like,
CB can open up and chase him.
That's like,
you can't just open up because the last
thing to go on a guy like nate Marquardt
is and nate mark harking corral and he's
called racked a lot of guys.
He's got a lot of memories.
It's just me and my muscle memory.
He went flying through the air,
like do that bullshit leg kicks.
He try to throw a knee out,
let me try to lead.
I just caught them on the street school
named Mark Karp.
Fuck you was a bad ass.
He was a guy that was super talented but
might've had like a little bit too much
damage by the time he got started
fighting when he was 17 years.
Yeah,
17 doing it and winning coming is
fucking highlight reel knockout of tyron
woodley and strikeforce is one of the
mortal Kombat on one of those.
Asked al Combos.
Oh,
he's a monster.
So talented.
Such a diverse and a lot of traditional
martial arts techniques mixed with some
really good boxing as well.
Extensive martial arts background and
they started fighting.
He was very young.
He was like the first like,
especially in Colorado,
man nate was the shit.
He's I what?
I looked it up because the baddest went
straight to his gym.
You said you'd never seen him lose
around in practice?
Not for a very,
very,
very long time.
Yeah.
It seems like our team is number one
training partner,
wasn't me.
I mean,
yeah,
he's crazy.
That whole connection,
you're going to get
better if you're.
If you're training partner is one of the
greatest ever will use.
Although there's that,
but the word was always at nate was
better.
That's what I've heard.
Nate was a bigger guy and he was
fighting at one 85 last night.
One time I said,
I said,
how do you do against GSP?
And he said,
well that's all I said.
He's so modest.
I go,
what are you going to do?
He's not gonna.
Say anything.
Why would he say anything or underwear?
There's nothing worse than when you
asked the guy something.
He fucking.
I'll do.
I've,
I've fucked a whoever vidor Belfour up
in round one.
Practice them.
I'm rack this.
Well,
there's a lot of guys don't have that.
Right to the worst practice.
Yeah,
there's some good fights coming up,
man.
This what you call Frank Mir.
Mark Hunt.
Yeah.
That's interesting.
Magni.
Hector lumbar scares me for my buddy and
Hector Hector Lombard fan.
He gets a hold of you.
You go for a ride.
He's also a guy that's been a.
He tested positive and he's been around
a long another mindblowing one I know
who saw that surprised.
I'm like,
what would that ass that's artificially
created?
Let her ass.
He I feel like is in the same boat as
his other acumen.
Cuban compile,
compatriot Yoel Romero in that they got
to the UFC a little late in their
career.
People Forget.
Hector lumbar was merck and everybody
over in Bella tour.
Everybody.
He came over from Bella tour like people
forgot.
They forgot and bitches forgot he was
ripping dude's face and I think he's
only five,
nine tiny.
He the fight,
the fight that he might even be fight.
Yeah,
he's 55,
eight,
but the fight is him fighting.
So I like how they do it in inches.
That's five.
Nine,
right?
Yeah.
The fight.
The fucking body.
I've never seen it as no home.
I've never seen in my life.
Then it's the best class I've ever seen.
He can explode on you,
man.
He can explode them.
Anyway,
so the way he knocked out nate,
perfect example that knock on the nate
Marquardt was fucking ferocious.
The angles and the fearlessness in which
he chased nate down in the knockout
power.
When he's on me,
he's fucking terrifying it.
Good luck beating them when he's on.
I want to see him fight Robbie law.
That's a fight.
I want to say.
How old is hector now?
Not Young,
but he's never taken a beating.
Still rolls with that acne.
How about when he,
uh,
how about when he went in and fucking
destroyed?
Paul Horace.
That's when you are 38.
Yeah,
that's when you saw 30.
How fucking scary.
He is.
[inaudible].
It's called Harris,
like couldn't do shit to him.
Hector Lombard before this drug tests
and we don't know how he's going to be
now,
but scary.
Scott won 70.
Who the fuck knows if you draw that
card?
You're like,
ah,
fuck.
That ain't smart.
It's not fun that any one where you're
like,
yeah,
I can ask both.
He's in a different weight class.
He just.
I mean that might be the picture,
but yeah.
Or maybe it's not the picture.
No magnets long and tall though.
Here's a totally different guy.
Dude.
Man.
We did the companion.
Powerful Ellen job and fighting on this
card,
but how about when we did
the,
what's her name?
Remy Nikai.
You remember that draws all into what
might meet your date?
You know what the uh,
what builds?
She?
Um,
she's cute.
She just like weird fetish stuff.
Yeah,
man.
I was into it when exactly.
Sure what it is.
It's one of the proof.
Either way.
It's one of the few times where I read
the captions.
I'm glad I don't speak Japanese market
and suck.
Robin had a baby.
She's got a cute face.
Fuck you.
Don't try to cover this up.
And Leslie Smith,
she had to get her ear sewed back on.
I Love Jessica Jessica.
I blasted her ear and it shot up like a
volcano and she wanted to keep going.
Her fucking ear was hanging off her
head.
She had a hole that you could look deep
into her skull kidded,
man.
I'd never seen anything like it.
Yes,
you want to keep going?
They should want to keep going.
She was upset.
She was sleeping.
Good luck.
Picking knockout of the night or
performance night.
There's gonna be so many knockouts on
that card.
I did the matchups.
Yeah,
I think there's a better picture.
Jamie will.
You can see there.
That's it.
You just had it right there.
Click on that one.
Yeah.
You could see how,
how deep the hole was.
It was a giant hole because the skin
gets so thin from the flower and that
bitch opened up.
What's not that?
It gets thin.
Actually what it is,
the actual cauliflower itself,
it,
it helps rip apart the skin because it's
like having a rock under your skin.
I see that one.
You see that one too?
That's what it looked like.
Oh my God.
You see into her fucking see your brain.
So you.
Do you think while she had it sewed back
on?
She got the colored flower trimmed off?
I would,
I would to trim that shit.
Yeah.
It's going to grow back if you keep
training.
Isn't she a Cesar Gracie?
I think.
I think she's one of them.
Uh,
Cesar Gracie nor cowgirls and fighting
to do it for a living man.
You gotTa love fighting.
She's tough as fuck.
Really?
Picture man.
God dammit girl,
do your thing.
She looks like an anime like doll.
I know she is paid to do that shit.
They think about how fucking tough Josh
Birkman is.
We're talking about Hector Lombard,
Josh Berkman who just fought his last
fight and one at 55 veterans,
fought Lombard and locked it,
sat in the car,
sat there in the pocket is sick.
She went into that fight.
Antibiotics I fucked up.
That's the fight that hector test
positive for it.
Yeah.
That's the fight.
Hector content and Berkman just sat
there and just kinda parried and stayed
pretty much mark less.
I just want to state dangerous.
That's why Lombard,
especially when lumbar started to get a
little tired.
He didn't want to come in because bomb
wing and bombs at you and he can.
You could hit him with a bat.
Yeah.
That motherfucker take a shot.
Well,
he didn't take it too.
He's just tough.
Berchmans been around and he's fought as
heavy as to.
Oh really?
Yeah.
He fought Jeremy Horn once and I don't
know what the fuck.
They had some crazy dispute.
There was some argument when they hated
each other,
he'd been fighting for.
Jeremy Horn is like one of the nicest
guys in the world.
Yeah.
And Jeremy choked him out and spit on
him.
Well,
he was out cold.
I don't know what happened,
but Jeremy's the nicest guy ever.
He's also a fighter,
but I'm telling you like the idea that
Jeremy,
he gets so upset at someone.
It's almost alien to me.
I don't understand it.
Who Does Nate Diaz fight next?
You should fight Robbie lawler at UFC
200 if no,
I would say dose on Joseph's the fight
because I think that Robbie lawler is
too big for him.
If he's going to really fight at one 70,
he should.
I mean,
if he could fight at one 70,
make no mistake about it.
But if you look at like the Rory
Macdonald fight and you look at the,
um,
uh,
a stun gun,
Kim fight,
he could also,
you could easily make an argument and I
think it's not even an argument of fact.
He's a lot better than he was when he
fought Rory Macdonald.
And he's a lot better than he was when
he fought don young.
Kim,
I think his fight,
his last fight in particular,
not just the conor mcgregor fight,
but the fight with Michael Johnson ever
look,
he's on fire.
Nate is comfortable,
he's confident and nate is one of the
slickest dudes when it comes to rolling
with punches.
When kit,
when nate gets hit,
nate gets hit and he goes with shit
going was shit like.
And he's got this like Long Slinky
fucking jab that comes out of nowhere.
You have to give them a super after
being conor mcgregor and he has such
fucking momentum whether he agrees with
what the UFC does,
whatever you have to give that guy.
I think a title shot.
Well the UFC,
I think they have to recognize that he's
a superstar right now.
Nate.
Nate Diaz is a fucking superstar.
Fifty five I think.
Fifty five.
Weight 55 or seven.
But if you give him 70,
just give them more than two weeks.
Notice I,
I mean I think he has a better chance
beating Robbie lawler than he does this
guy.
Rob.
Just a strong man.
I don't,
well,
they'll Sanchez was his last before he
fought.
Michael Johnson,
those lunges leg kick the shit out of
them and horrible and mangled them on
the ground once his leg was all fucked
up.
God damned.
Juggernaut bikes.
Connor.
That's what I think.
No,
come on.
Come on.
You can't do that.
No,
you can't do that.
You can't.
That's Connor's worst matchup supposed
to see anymore.
I don't think it works out well for
Connor.
Come on man.
What if he sleeps?
I'm okay.
Whack.
What if you want to purchase them like
you did all this chaos.
That's possible.
It is possible to go to 1:45
fight Frankie,
and then let's talk about 54.
I think he kind of has to defend his
title,
right?
You can't lose that 70 than fight the
champ at 55 and then go back.
Okay.
Here's my.
Here's a big thing.
Here's a question.
I'm not saying.
I'm asking a question.
We go,
is it possible?
Is it going to take a shit?
Look,
is it possible that conor mcgregor,
because he's
an excellent boxer and he's got that
left hand,
is it possible that we're going to see
people game plan to say,
Hey,
just stay away from that left hand,
and if you do you can just grab them and
grind them into the ground.
I can get shit for that.
In other words,
what do you taught?
It's nothing new.
In other words,
you want to say a question and you just
came up with a question.
My question,
my thought it was right.
Jamie knows everyone knows,
asked you this.
In other words,
do you think that if he gets it,
I guess what I'm really asking is you
spit it out.
What I'm really asking is,
is he.
Is he just really good with that left
hand and if you negate that,
he becomes ordinary,
but he's good.
He's an excellent fighter.
He's amazing.
He's the last one,
78.
You don't just knock out,
although with one punch destroy markers,
image destroyed.
Diego Brandao.
He's destroyed.
Dennis seaver,
he looks like a murderer.
Smash Chad Mendez.
Conor mcgregor is a gangster.
There's no doubt that he just got a
little crazy if you want to.
Anybody.
He went up all the way up to one 72.
Granted,
he fought nate Diaz is not a real one 70
anyway,
but he's a legit one.
50th five.
We can't make 1:45.
Nate can't make 1:45.
You see nate cut down to 55.
He is fucking troll reddit.
So another 10 pounds after that.
That's not gonna happen.
But Connor could make that way.
So you gotta think that nate is a bigger
guy and I'll tell you why.
Connor's still the biggest draw in the
UFC because in everyone should take
notes.
The way he's handled this loss.
He doesn't go into hiding champ.
He's not not doing interviews.
He's not talking shit.
Just what's up?
Yeah.
I took a chance.
I fucking lost man.
I will not apologize.
Took a fucking risk.
Who's fucking next?
Well,
he loaded up on nate.
He tried to take them out with one shot
at a time and you just can't do that.
It's just not that easy.
It's not an easy how it keeps us on
Joe's.
Besides knocking them out,
keeps them away from him.
I feel good question.
Just grabs him.
It's a big,
big problem.
Totally different.
I haven't seen any answer to that.
Totally different animal.
Physically.
He's still sound.
Joe's has these thick ass ankles and
thick as risks.
Thick ass.
He's a thick motherfucker up knocking
him out,
have fun getting kicked in the leg by
him and then grabbed around the was also
his paces in Sadie's breaking dudes.
Especially at 55.
When I watched his fight with pedes,
I was like,
oh,
how's this guy keeping this up?
See that.
That's not the move.
I.
If,
if I'm Connor's manager,
I haven't first take some time off.
He doesn't fight at UFC 200.
He's crazy.
He's fighting UFC $200.
Well why would he not?
When is that?
Because you just bought that fucking
murked you need a break.
Has Do an interviews.
Twenty four slash seven a couple of
times a shot for a take down on the
ground.
Duncan coked out.
Do you think you got a concussion?
Yeah,
he got fucking a one.
Two from fucking Nate Diaz was on
wobbles street.
But is that a congressional fuck?
Your shot a double leg?
I know he did.
But what is technically concussion?
Your brain fucked up and you can double
and then you revert back to old school
ways.
That's when your brain's bruised.
Right?
Right.
Medically,
like
medically,
I think it's when you bruise your brain.
I don't know when will we know that he
got his bell rung.
We know he got rocked,
we saw his legs buckle,
we saw nate beat the piss out of him on
the ground before he choked him.
Right?
So all those count.
So yeah.
So I wonder how much damage he did and I
wonder how much time he really should
take off because it's not the same like
this obviously levels of it.
Like Rhonda getting head kicked by Holly
is like the highest level.
The highest level is getting Gonzaga.
When Gonzaga knocked out,
cro cop,
that was like the height that's going to
take a year period.
He's even better.
Here's even better.
Terry Edom versus Barboza Barboza we'll
carry Adam.
That's the highest level of chaos.
Go and take some time off to the highest
level of the rest of your life,
but either way it see,
we say,
well,
he just got his bell rung.
That's a bring trauma,
but there's levels.
Right,
but what's the UFC $200 for what?
For what?
Why not do another day?
He's going to get paper no matter what.
Also also,
how long has your career,
like just injuries and stuff.
Man,
I don't know.
We need to look at Chad Mendez.
Chad Mendez goes and getting stopped by
connor and then immediately gets knocked
out with one punch by Frankie and showed
like,
like that's not normal for him.
Usually he can take a really good shot.
Yeah man.
So he goes from that to that.
Now was the.
When was the Ricardo Lamas?
Fight was before the conor fight right
before color.
So he fights Ricardo Lamas,
dust him with one punch,
hurts them,
at least with one person that puts them
away.
Flights.
Connor loses that fight,
get stopped and gets really rocked,
Kinda hits them.
It's a big lift and knocked out,
but he kind of just.
He was so tired.
Then he got,
he got,
he got 10 percent and then frankie just
takes them out with one left hook.
Fucking New Jersey son Tom Connors camp.
I'm losing sleep over that guy.
Frankie Edgar.
Mind he said,
best match up if he loses to Frankie.
What?
Where does connor,
what happens to conor at that point?
That's a real good question.
Um,
if he loses the Frankie,
he's got a really figure out how to
regroup.
It depends on how Frankie beats him.
If Frankie takes him down and beat the
fuck out of them on the ground,
and then we've got,
he's got a real problem.
What I'm saying is a lot of sense.
How you,
oh,
that's the blueprint at Brian.
There's everyone knows that type
economy.
Everyone tries to do that.
Then they get fucking knocked out where
everyone knows everyone in this entire
world knows connor's weak point is
grappling with arguments that he hasn't
seen a real grappler.
He's Chad Mendez except for just Chad.
Just go for one round Duffy.
Who was the guy who beat him,
beat him.
Joe Duffy arm triangle though.
That's what I mean.
So what I'm saying is that I'm telling
you,
you're saying nothing new.
No,
I,
no,
I'm just saying that when you see what's
happening in the news,
what you see,
which did.
Fingers ready.
Brendan's a bullying.
Brendan's broken down.
You can.
No,
no,
that's not what this is about.
Pride.
Just hear me
out.
I'm going to take some pain from this.
No one's ever heard this.
What if he brands fight conor?
No.
Hear me out.
I know what I'm saying.
What if I said it when his head is.
If you could just get away with.
All you have to do is stay away from his
left hand.
It's the game.
Not True because he kicks.
Good.
Connor's got his right hands.
Amazing to.
Did you say kicks our rice kicking?
Didn't do a thing tonight.
That Nate Diaz.
Okay.
Yes it did.
He like kicks.
He just,
he didn't throw his kicks are like the
Sanchez is what I'm saying.
They're not like.
You can't say he's a different kind of
kicking in the door.
I can't entertain this conversation.
I don't think it counts as his kicks
are.
All right.
In comparison to a lot of guys,
I feel like that's not your own.
When you fight conor,
you're more worried about his lefthand.
You're not.
You're not worried about getting knocked
out.
Like holly,
you say,
be careful of that round house you're
going to get knocked out with.
Does not just watch out for those leg
kicks with all the watch over the leg
kicks with connor.
You're saying stay away from that left
hand.
Let me tell you yes,
but let me tell you something.
If he kicked you in the face,
he can knock you out that way too and he
can kick in the face,
but he hasn't done it.
It doesn't mean anything.
He's got.
He's got a lethal lefthand for sure,
but when I watched him throw kicks,
we're closer,
so it throws a lot of kicks,
man.
He throws a lot of kicks in.
A lot of times what he's doing and she's
throwing almost disdainful kicks setting
you up.
Well,
he's relaxed with them.
He's just throwing them in there.
He just throws them in there.
He's not like fucking written down and
digging in and Barboza grits down.
Dig.
That's exactly what I'm saying though,
is that the kicks themselves might be
there as a distraction,
but you're not going to have to.
It's not like your coach says,
listen,
those kicks are going to knock you out.
Whereas Barbosa of the Chad Mendez
fight,
because he fucked Chad up with kicks to
the body.
He hits with a heart spinning back kick
to the body front,
kicked him the body a gang of times.
Yeah,
I think he's got a lot of tools.
It's just does he have real world class
tools?
Like here's the most world class striker
right now in MMA.
Wonderboy,
that's the most.
Yes.
Most dynamic and exciting striker in
mma,
what he's doing is he's sport karate but
Moitai skills and wrestling,
takedown defense,
and that combination is fucking
ridiculous and answer just me.
It's crazy.
He's fighting him.
Fight his hands down and can't find a a.
You can't find a sparring partner.
The match him.
Well,
he's.
He was 57 and.
Oh,
I think it was seven.
Yeah.
What the fuck?
This is.
What's crazy?
How crazy is mma where connor loses.
Rhonda loses.
Holly loses like you can't predict it.
Everyone except for that bad
motherfucker.
Pound for pound number one.
Jon Jones.
I was gonna.
Say Demetrius mighty mouse.
Johnson.
Now he's lost though.
I'm talking about that,
but he hasn't.
He hasn't lost since he fought dominick
Cruz.
He lost a decision to dominick.
Cruz still lost.
I'm just saying the guy who has John
Joe,
not even close.
That's true.
John Jones hasn't been well Gustafson
one fucking train for two weeks.
I want to see him in rumble.
I really do.
Me To kind of wrestle.
I think if he fights with Rambo,
I think you'll see John John's take
rumble down maybe second round.
Take them down first.
Here's the good about John is John could
be the nail.
He's not just the hammer.
He can be the nail and it's one of the
things that's really scary about him
because he's so fucking talented,
but he still can take a beating and he
does not give up.
He got his arm basically snapped
backwards by Vito Belfort and they
submitted Vittorio later in the fight.
I mean he.
He tore his entire body on him.
He fought shale son and beat the fuck
out of him and he being the fuck out of
him.
He broke his toe sideways,
twisted it around backwards,
and he didn't even realize it until we
were talking.
He didn't even realize until he had his
belt on and he looks down in the bottom
of his big toe is facing up.
Oh,
that's wild.
Jon Jones.
Now he's lifting and pray.
They're like beating him,
lifting and drinking.
Fucking everything in praying.
He's drinking Fiji Water and doing
squats.
I love it.
That's his instagram.
They show them lifted and was like,
he's changed.
This is brilliant.
Fucking changed.
This is cynical,
Brendan.
Brendan Shop.
Who doesn't believe in movement.
Coaches also doesn't believe Jon Jones
is Cherry.
He does.
He just.
I'm saying,
good luck.
Beaten that dude.
Good luck.
Good luck beating that dude.
And if he's.
If he is super dedicated,
even more,
good luck.
Beaten up.
Hopefully.
Sometimes you need that wildcard for
greatness.
You know,
you need to be a little crazy.
I,
I believe that.
He's a wild motherfucker.
I want my champion a couple of lines
here and my chicken continent.
Dude prostitutes when you did that
interview with him and Daniel Cormier.
We're in the middle.
I,
I the,
the look and Jon Jones.
He's terrifying.
What?
So what happened when the camera wasn't
rolling,
they wouldn't talk to each other before
and they.
And afterwards John was,
they were talking mad shit on the way
out in the parking lot,
but I didn't witness that so I can't
really speak on that.
But before it,
like I had a conversation with Danielle
before.
It's separately,
a quick conversation with John before it
separately just saying what's up,
how's everything,
you know,
just Chit Chat and um,
seeing how,
how he's doing,
you know,
that kind of stuff.
And he's fucking terrifying man.
He's when he's focused,
what the shit.
Some of the shit that he was saying that
Daniel was like,
yeah.
He's like,
he's like,
Daniel's problem is I'm the Alpha and he
wants to be the Alpha,
but he knows he's always going to be my
pussy.
Yeah,
you're always going to be my pussy.
I don't know if they,
Kelly did it.
They didn't put that just alpha.
They took off the pussy.
I each other you can see that they
would,
they should leave and I agree.
That's a mistake.
Did she leave that in saying what Jon
Jones to go full fucking Batman Joker.
Just be the heel.
Dartmouth.
Daniel was pretty intense to man when
Daniel was looking at him.
Sometimes fighters will say things and
you go,
well,
he doesn't really believe that,
but he's saying that Daniel was telling
them,
I am going to do everything in my power.
I'm willing to die to beat you.
I'm willing to die.
John say goes.
You better be willing to.
Tom.
Tom Wasn't shaken by it at all,
but Daniel was super emotional.
It was intense,
man.
It was really,
really,
really excited for that fight.
That is April,
April.
I'm excited for that fight.
I don't think it changes,
but I'm excited for it.
You want to come?
When is it?
Because we might be on tour.
We are Midwest tour in April.
Are you guys on tour?
Why don't you guys both come?
We could,
but we have a show at 23rd and 24th.
Oh,
you have a show that night.
Now we have a show in Oklahoma as well.
What a great move being in Oklahoma.
Well,
I know.
Damn well I don't go to UC events by
Kate.
Can we talk to you in the back?
What are they going to be mad at?
You might take an interview with Eric
who wanted to stand just like Robert
Deniro.
Yeah,
back there.
Why is that?
Flag.
Ah,
Shit.
Yeah.
Shop died.
Who killed them?
We have no idea.
He just seen me.
Sorry.
Dana white onto the end of the day.
What you do for the UFC by talking about
fights.
It hypes up fights.
Yes.
You know,
you to let you gotta let it a little be
a little bit looser because you're
dealing with 500 different fighters.
So there's hundreds of potential
matchups and maybe thousands if you
count them all up.
Right?
And you know,
there's a lot of disagreement is a lot
of debate,
but what you guys do with the fighter
and the kid going to get podcasts for or
FTC Kay,
um,
from my tour schedule guys do is you,
you create interest,
you get people excited,
you discuss things.
It's fun,
it's entertaining.
This is the thing though,
Joe.
It's like who pays our bills?
Not the UFC.
I can say whatever I want to realist
way.
Fox doesn't pay my bills so I'm.
There's no fucking regulator on it and
you're fair and it's rare really
sometimes.
Well I think that what you guys do is
valuable though.
It's what I was trying to say.
It's worth a lot like they can't.
You can't always control the message
that comes out when it comes to
something as exciting and dynamic and
multifaceted as MMA fights.
It was just too much shit going on.
And then when it comes to things like
controversial things like the reebok
deal or you know,
any,
any other kind of a sponsored situation
or anything along those lines where
there's a lot of disagreement.
You gotta you gotTa Kinda like let all
that play out.
Like if you don't let all that play out,
like you're dealing with like a super
dynamic sport and there's so many
different areas to explore in all those
areas.
Create interest.
And I think by limiting the
conversation,
what you do is you limit the amount of
interest because there's going to be
disagreements,
it's going to be people that are pro
this and pro that pro her at pro him.
And if you got a guy like you is
controversial and it says a bunch of
crazy shit,
like all that does is like blossom.
And at the end of the day you're not a
bad guy.
You like mma,
you love the UFC,
you,
you're genuinely intrigued about these
ups.
You just have a controversial point of
view.
But that shouldn't be silenced.
I agree.
And it's also that,
you know,
with the reebok deal
or any of these match ups,
it when you turn on you,
it lets you watch UFC tonight who's
paying their bills.
These guys can't be real dope.
The fighters with the Reebok,
you'll,
they can't come out because they can get
backlash.
Not always.
The first guy where,
yeah,
they're censored.
So I was the first guy where I'm not
censoring so I can stay out is like go,
you're a hater.
I'm not a hater.
I'm one of the first guys that they
can't do anything to me.
There's really nothing to do.
It's awesome.
So they banned me from UFC tonight in a
UFC fight pass.
I don't give a fuck.
I want double the money.
That's why I got banned.
They did it.
There's just for the first time it was a
guy with a voice and no one reeboks not
pay the bills.
Zuph was not Pittsburgh.
Dana's done my goal and make sure you
promote this.
I do it.
Fuck.
It would be a shame if they were,
because it'd be a shame if you stopped
doing it the way you're doing it because
that's what's fun about it.
What's fun about your show is that you
know that if you get Brennan wound up,
he'll start talking some crazy shit.
I do,
and I do an MMA journalist.
They probably wrote three stories
already during the time we've been doing
this podcast.
About three.
Still one about Joe Rogan disrespects
me.
She's asset.
Brian Caraway.
That's probably one of them.
You guys told me something about Fried
Chicken,
fried chicken,
and we bullied you.
Bullied,
and I'm sure there's our county Mac.
Yeah.
Brian Callahan is a wrestling expert,
pushing kids and breaking news.
How you be conor mcgregor wrestling,
not impressed with conor Mcgregor's.
Then someone shows a highlight reel of
conor Mcgregor doing spinning wheel
kicks,
and dropping Chad Mendez.
The Internet is.
I'll get 50 guys.
Call.
Dude.
You were the only one who knew about the
case.
I can tell you when you get like six
people going,
you should never talk about that.
I may hear a piece of shit while you're
going to have both for sure.
I don't really.
I don't read them anymore.
Ever since talking to you,
you're like,
don't read that shit.
If she choose who you communicate with
in his life and one of the things that's
good about criticism and online
criticism as you can learn how other
people view you and you can go,
okay,
yeah,
I see.
That's right.
That's kind of valid.
Maybe I came off Douchey or maybe I
should preface that better or maybe I
should explain myself better,
but then you realize that some of the
people are just trying to hurt your
feelings.
Yes,
and then you have to realize,
well,
what kind of a person just tries to hurt
your feelings.
Losers.
Yes.
That's it.
One hundred percent.
Yeah.
Anybody who's got a.
they're trying to hurt your feelings,
reaching out to big,
Brown,
trying to make you feel bad.
Why are they doing that?
Why?
Why waste all that time?
Like what is their,
their humor involved in what you're
doing or other people enjoying it.
Like is there a method to it?
Were you trying to say,
do you have a message or you just trying
to hurt big browns fan,
but it's also,
you know,
you're doing something right because
he's putting all this positive energy
out and people are like,
fuck man,
I'm going to be done once he lost a
Travis Browne wrong.
Keeping on keeping on anybody.
Like look at Kanye West.
I'm not a Kanye West Fan.
I mean see cut logs.
Music is excellent just for this,
but I think is closer.
Ridiculous,
but the shoes.
But I love the fact that will tweet
something really stupid and these
dummies
albany is feeding frenzy that he tweets
bill cosby's innocent right before.
I mean,
come on,
that's fucking funny.
That's a master manipulator and a
marketing guy,
you know,
I used to always go bad on Kanye and I
and I went out.
I was like,
why is this guy like everybody likes him
and I know people are very intelligent
and speak highly.
So I tend to look at this body of work
that you should just read.
He,
well he,
I think I can take kind of wake county
down but what,
what got to me and I was like this guy
is produced a shitload of music and it's
all different.
So I went and bought every song.
I bought every song he's ever done and I
spent three days listening to every song
like three times and I got the lyrics
right.
So I was like,
all right,
look,
you cannot deny this guy is putting out
crazy amounts of work and it's really
good.
But then I started listening to
interviews that he was giving like long
ones,
long form interviews and I have to say I
came full circle musical gene.
He's got.
But he's also got shit to say that I
agree with like I'm aligned with him.
I think he also trips over his own dick.
He's got arrogant outbursts and you can
relate.
Yes.
For Chicago Black Kid because you grew
up rich and no,
I can relate to an artist who says I'm
not going to limit myself and I'm not
going to censor myself and I'm going to
speak my mind because we live.
He goes,
I feel like people are crazy.
Is it just about your maybach and just
about your status or is it about
something else?
You know,
and he was very eloquent about how I
spoke.
I love what he said on Jimmy Kimmel that
ranty had about being an artist either
watch the fucking great.
So a lot of wood fence on.
I tried to convert Brian and I finally.
Did you own a pair of yeezys?
I just got them for my birthday.
They're so hard to get.
Jamie's just to just got some 200 pairs
of shoes.
He takes pictures of them.
That's cool.
A lot of shoes.
I love Mandy's my favorite,
these new fucking Solomon there.
Like a hiking shoe that's a running
shoe.
Run up hills with these bitches or some
shit.
The tread and those mothers.
That's a dad shoe athletic dad shoe
right there.
Let's a fucking mountain hunter show.
You cut 100 dash.
Yeah,
I've run hills with these motherfuckers.
These things can kill the and those
things like hiking boots.
Right,
but you turned them into a running it
again right here.
Yeah.
Maybe I'll wear those.
Super Right real thin.
Sole.
And you could fuck.
And you feel the ground when we go
hiking.
You can we go hunting a mouse?
You could,
but you wouldn't because you would get
shit in your one unless you were in
place that didn't have taken notice of
Alaska.
You want to hire,
you want to hire ankle.
You want something that protects your
ankle a bit more,
but if you're running hills is what I
use these for fucking me and you and Mr.
Rogen you like shoes for their
effectiveness and what they actually do.
I just liked the way they look.
I just want to find your feet like a,
like a medieval Chinese woman.
If it look good,
the Yeezys I was like,
shit,
they with 13 health,
uh,
twelfth pretty tight for these the other
day at Rei.
And they're like,
Ooh,
Nice Solomons,
like those kind of guys.
Those guys are balls,
deep functional shoes.
The guys who would buy like one of them
water bladders,
the camel backpack,
Campbell,
because those guys will carry a water
bottle.
I liked myself,
man.
I liked my salesman to be opinionated.
Like I like if I'm.
I went to buy boots at Rei for a hunting
trip and I was like,
I'm going to Alaska and I love a guy
who's like,
oh,
well,
um,
let me think about this now.
Is it going to be in the winter?
And I'm.
Yeah,
I'm looking at precipitation right now.
Let me pull up my graph.
Oh my God,
that's my guy.
Sold his soul is a fourth of an inch.
I'm going to say you're going to want
that and that I want.
I want a guy who speaks in graphs and
numbers when I buy a car,
I want to hear the dude get me.
Well,
we got more cabin room in this.
Um,
I'm all about that guy,
the detail and not talked to a guy at
the BMW dealership once we're,
we're discussing something about an m
three and he didn't know Jack Shit.
I almost wanted to get away from him.
Now I'm starting to ask.
Yeah.
I'm like,
does this,
does this one have,
you know,
the act of suspended then?
Yeah,
if you don't know,
like your,
this is like one of the best cars you
guys have ever been taught.
So you're,
yeah,
you're wearing a suit where he'll bmw
for sure.
Tell me about the counting these things
like,
you know,
I know more than you.
I'm a comedian.
When I went to look at my car,
a little private experiment,
I was looking at Audis,
I was looking at a tornado's I was going
to.
Alexis and I did a little thing.
It's a chauvinist thing,
but I've found that women saleswomen uh,
don't,
they're not up on the details like guys,
our guys love numbers,
stats,
pens and all that.
And,
and I,
I found that women would usually go,
you know,
I,
they knew the car,
but they'd be like,
I don't know about the,
that,
that's something that I'd have to ask.
And they know that guys,
you should definitely not.
I go in with all my research so I don't
want this gap in my ear off.
I know what the fuck.
Like when I bought my Prius,
which the lease is up next month.
Thank Baby Jesus.
I bought it just for kid because I was
driving all over California.
Right.
The lease is up,
but when I bought that thing.
So you want to test drive it like,
no bitch,
it's a prius of.
I'll figure it out.
I don't want to take it around the
block.
It's depressing for gas mileage.
Then I got in,
I was like,
I need to figure something out.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
They will go through the book.
Prius a bum.
Yeah.
You drive your Porsche.
Like I'd beat him everywhere.
You drive your pores.
It very carefully.
Only open up when the speed dickhead.
But if you had one of those cars,
you would appreciate what one of those
cars can do.
It's a ride.
It's a piece of art.
Yeah.
When you're driving that thing,
you're driving a finely engineered
machine that's perfectly balanced.
Take lunch and it has this fucking sound
of that flat six in the back.
That's why I don't mind driving my car.
I'm like,
hey man,
don't take corners.
You know what I mean,
guys,
I'm in traffic.
Thanks.
Well,
it doesn't matter who occasionally get
out of traffic and when you do,
it's way more fun to be in his car.
Then you're fucking Grandad,
Grandad,
mobius portion on the road.
I go fucking a.
it's an elite club.
I had of wave to this guy
and give them a thumbs up.
He had a corvette,
zero six.
The new zero six.
The top comes off and so it becomes like
a target and melt your face.
Oh my God.
Crazy fast.
It sounds so fucking nasty.
Nothing sounds better than a fucking
American va.
Something serious.
Do it.
You know,
I think when I think that you're gonna
laugh,
when I think about when you make that
noiSe,
I go,
I wouldn't hear my books on tape as
loudly as we know the difference between
us.
That's literally what I wear my head
when I was like,
ooh,
I couldn't really listen to a book,
a novel that's my wife gets in my car
the other day.
She was,
what the fuck are you listening to?
I was listening to the knock on podcast.
Knock on his,
uh,
archery based podcast by this guy,
john podcast is all right.
Yeah.
He's talks about like,
like fucking super technical shit about
archery.
Love it.
Fuck yeah.
Listen to it every Day.
We still haven't decided if we have a
site in my boat.
No,
no,
no.
We got to get your boat to a range and
um,
we got to get your,
uh,
draw length measured and stuff like do
that.
Super important.
We're going to go out in august is what
we're going to go after.
So what we're going to have is a good
solid two to three months of like
serious preparation and training camp.
What I want is You to be able to shoot
accurately to 20 yards and then what I
want you to do is not shoot anything
outside of 20 yards.
They call me in that amount of time.
I think we can get that done.
I think we can get you to jail.
I'll fuck.
I want to save your time because you're
busy,
man.
You know brIan's not a hunter,
right?
Hey,
no.
Brian [inaudible].
Brian called me dad.
No,
listen,
I told me.
I watched him shoot several deer and he
Is steady on the fucking trigger and he
squeezes.
He doesn't jerk it.
he's got a great shot.
He's got a great aim.
No,
he doesn't.
He doesn't panic.
It makes good shot.
How long you guys going for will
probably go downtown.
Go.
I better.
You know what?
We'll be going to be back.
We'll be back with me.
Just know that you wait by the campfire.
We'll be back with fucking me.
You will kill your cushy life with your
cappuccino.
We'll come back with the fucking meat
and covered in mosquito bites,
but it's worth it.
We're going hard and in Nevada and we're
going into the mountains in Nevada.
We're going to archery hunt for mule
deer.
Yeah.
And so,
uh,
we're going to backpack in there and
we'll be,
we'll be camping and we're going to be
glass and in days I don't care.
But you got this,
you got to five days things.
You gotta do you gotta you gotta we
gotta fIgure out the both thing.
That's a big one.
That's the biggest one.
And we got to like get you hooked up
with a bunch of different kinds of
equipment because with archery,
one of the things that's really
important because you get really close
to them,
you got to know which way the wind's
blowing,
so we got to get.
It's like a little talcum powder bottle
and you squeeze it into the air and it
blows up and then it goes to this
archery podcast.
Matter of fact,
It's too deep for you guys should start
your own podcast about archery.
If you get to like the one percent of
one percent that give a fuck about
archery.
That's the kind of shit I'm into.
I'm into like leveling your second and
third axis.
I'm into multi pin sights on a dovetail
housing.
I'm into.
Do you use a kisser?
Butler?
No kisser button.
Book.
Green arrows.
What's the spine?
How many past your second shot?
200 arrows the other day.
I got problem.
What is it about?
Of course you do.
What is it about with me?
What is it about the tactile experience
of archery that you love?
Like what if I told you I'm just
something wrong with me man.
When I get into something,
It's like that thing is like a fucking
house.
Could be on fire if I'm shooting
bullseyes I'm good.
Yeah.
what it is then the flow.
There's a switch that goes off and then
I'm no longer driving anymore.
Joe,
don't you?
Don't you think if you picked up golf,
you'd be [inaudible].
That's why I didn't ever played golf.
Do I?
Don't think you know our trees.
Your passion.
I think whenever you got into your balls
in,
that's true.
That's true,
but it has to be cool.
And archery is fucking offsite.
Golf pro.
You will lose your life.
my life with pool.
Dude,
let me tell you something.
I have dreams someday I like.
Sometimes I sit around here and I'll do
a bunch of podcasts and I'm like,
ah,
fucking.
You know what I think I'm going to do.
I'm just going to quit everything and
just go play pool on tour kits and tends
to run a few racks of fat joint play
with like meeting fitzsimmons is coming
over the other.
I'm not tomorrow,
wednesday,
thursday,
tomorrow,
tomorrow with fitz simmons.
Come over.
You know what I'm really happy about.
We're going to play pool.
That's makes sense.
I'm going to see him.
we're going to play some play some pool
for sure.
Don't give a fuck.
I feel like.
I know this sounds weird,
but I watched.
I watched videos.
I watched videos on boxing,
footwork and tennis strokes.
It's.
I practice that tennis stroke alone in
my room with you.
I love it,
dude.
I have a release that I put.
I put my archery released.
I have a training tool where it's like a
rope that I pulled back and I hold it
and I'm watching tv.
I'm firing off shots.
I'm clicking this and I'm watching tv.
I'm by myself.
I don't give a fuck.
I'm just sitting there with zen about
it.
Right.
That's intense,
man.
Once you kill an elk with a bow and
arrow,
dude,
the world becomes a totally different
place,
becomes a totally different place
because you realize how,
first of all,
how fucking primal and crazy that is,
and then also getting your food that
way.
You're like,
okay,
I'm ouT of the factory farming system
for like if I could do this every year
I'm out for life.
Like now I'm completely responsible for
all the meat.
I get a shoot.
One animal.
I eat that animal for a year.
Damn.
What do you eat other stuff too?
like I've shot a dog too and I,
you know,
when I get almost as much satisfaction
giving friends,
I love it.
I love.
I love getting that elk.
I ate the shit.
Elk sausage,
homemade.
I got a gang of it at home.
He wants more dried,
dried,
right?
We're calling it.
It's a breakfast sausage.
No summer sausage,
somersaults.
Awesome.
Now I keep.
I keep rolls of it in the frigerator
backfired.
It's fucking delicious.
Thing gets raul though.
No,
no,
no.
It's cooked.
It's cooked skid,
ell,
summer sausage.
But you can cook it.
You could slice it and like quit some
exotics.
Little hot sauce in my mouth while I
have venison sausage that I had made to.
Oh my god.
It's so good.
I had somebody of the day with
breakfast.
You guys just keep telling shit,
man.
You guys keep killing shit and then I'll
take some of the songs to ain't look.
I like giving away almost as much as I
like eating it.
I really did.
Was awesome.
Like duncan sent me a picture.
Him,
his girlfriend and timothy leary's son
were eating elk meat balls from an elca
roundhouse.
Good.
It's delicious.
You don't have to.
I can't get enough of.
Is this kombucha drink three a day now?
Is that a problem?
You know,
I love people think we're doing an ad.
Every time I do something on instagram,
people,
man,
I just fucking love kombucha,
but nOt the bullshit.
Clear can has to be the black 21 and
over to let live on the.
Explain that because people don't know
what you mean.
Well,
the clear cam,
they basIcally produced those so they
could sell in grocery stores because
they have no alcohol content in them.
Very little.
So the black cans or they have more
alcohol content.
How they should be.
How the tea is naturally fermented.
So you want the black canvas is 21?
No,
it's not a black hand.
It's a bottle.
And the difference is the label cost
top.
It's just the plat,
the plastic rim around the bottle top
when you open it as black.
But bro even the bottles are different
on the 21 million.
They're darker and it's.
Yes.
It's something about the fermentation.
Do we have a knife that your samurai
sword over there from the 15 hundreds.
Go ahead and slice that thin real
samurai sword from the 15 hundreds.
Yes it is.
That is a real samurai swords.
Is it aba?
Gave it to me.
Is it opened that bitch up?
But I feel like this is dangerous.
Your ball or friends,
that's kind of shit they give you.
This isn't a.
This isn't 15 hundreds.
They.
Oh yes,
it is.
Shut your fucking pawn stars right now.
Shattering.
Excellent.
Thank you so much.
It's 100 percent,
100 percent real blade itself and
telling me that shit was 49,
99 bright.
They refurbished the handle and make it
all perfect.
But that blade is from the 1500.
The thing looks pretty fucking real.
That's real as fuck a glove and cut that
fucking sausage and stopped jacking off.
People have died by the sword.
Good chance.
if it's that old,
I wonder mean,
you know,
if you think about all the samurai sorts
in the $1,500,
how many hand in this continuous civil
war for about 300 years.
So there's a good chance.
But what I'm thinking is like,
is it like pistols?
Like most people who have pistols never
killed anybody.
True.
You know what I mean?
Like is that what it was like back in
the day with samurai swords or were they
more liberal or gangster shit?
Yeah,
probably take a little bit of that elk
son slice into that bitch.
Oh yeah.
Brian,
the plastic is getting you take a piece
hate back to the kombucha though.
People have tried telling me the
benefits are fake on that.
Just so just say,
it's not that good for you.
It'S all.
It's probiotic,
probiotic,
fermented vegetables and fermented
fermented mushrooms and things on those
lines,
which is essentially what kombucha is.
It's like a fungus is very good for you.
It's very good.
Let's go.
Let's go get you some.
Yeah,
I can eat that.
Fuck you.
It's very good for you.
Probiotics were like super important.
Gut health.
Gut health is,
you know,
it's a great way getting it.
I love kimchi,
man.
I been getting into.
Kim che found a,
you know,
down near the calabasas.
You ever go to that calabasas farmer's
market erewhon.
Well,
the farmer's market is amazing.
They have like low.
Well I'll take you.
I'll take you.
Um,
calabasas farmer's market has these
local,
a kombucha and local kimchis from like
people that run farms like nearby and
then they have their own,
like some spicy.
So it's pretty good.
that's really good.
I love them.
I love it because I don't drink soda.
I don't drink soda forever,
but these replaced that for me are way
healthier.
What kimchi is,
I'm actually fermented cabbage.
It's like a spicy fermented cabbage,
but my point is that it's a really good
source of probiotics.
I've been eating every morning and I
don't know if it's because of that,
but I feel amazing.
Kim.
She's fantastic with brian.
It's really good for you.
Well,
gut health changes everything,
man.
If you listen to some of my podcasts
I've done with rhonda patrick,
she goes deep into gut health and how
important it is for all sorts of aspects
of your personality,
the way you think about things.
It's amazing.
They did that with the rats where they
gave.
They've changed the gut health and the
rat,
like the bacteria and some rats with
healthy bacteria in their gut kept
fighting.
Um,
I guess to get out of the water and
others,
when they change the bacteria in their
gut,
it actually changed the serotonin levels
in their brain because apparently
serotonin is made in the gut as well.
And they just became listless and gave
up around.
Yeah,
it had a bad call.
That bitch ass was stomach ache.
If you can go swimming,
makes sure your gut,
your guts.
Good.
See,
and this is all this all came from an
animal that uh,
I mean I was there that you shot in the
face and the body.
You're shooting in the face though.
Now the phase is a good idea though.
That'd be if you don't do it because you
really,
it's hard to be that accurate when you
shoot a body,
like,
especially in elk,
you have a giant target as much as,
as much as you're practicing.
Let's sort of go over some head shots on
this.
We don't want to do it as taboo.
No guys do it all the time with pigs.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
There's a show called pig man.
Yeah,
pigman is,
it's kind of hilarious that I watched
that show and I go,
god,
if vegans ever fucking found out.
Oops,
I let it out.
There's a show called man.
Okay.
And
this motherfucker is,
he's called pig man because you just
kills pigs.
He's got a ranch and me hunts all over
the world.
Just shot a moose with a bow and arrow.
Pink pigs?
No,
no,
no.
WIld invasive,
cute pink pigs.
My love on my instagram.
The other day it was carrying off a
fallen.
Did you know that hogs carry off fond
and kill a medium?
Yeah.
that was.
That was a wart hog.
No,
it wasn't really.
no.
it was a pig.
There was a american domestic hog.
that's pig.
Man has got a patch on his eye because
he was in a fucking car accident.
He got all fucked up and now he's going
to shoot his bow with his left.
Nice.
Taking the anger from losing his eye on
the pigs.
No,
he's always been a pig murderer.
I mean he looked in.
If you live in Texas,
you got to kill pigs.
It's hard to kill pigs.
Yes.
You got to find them.
First of all.
I mean they're.
They're massively invasive.
There's millions of them.
I mean fucking million just taking
machine data alone.
In Texas alone,
there are millions of wild hogs.
Oh,
it's so bad that Texas,
they opened up a road.
Have they had built a new road and the
night they open it up,
they got liKe 40 car accidents where
people were slamming into pigs.
You know what?
Tim kennedy taught me this.
He said in Texas,
pigs are real.
He gets on horseback and hudson was
spear.
how about the fact that with fucking
helicopters wanted to see something
crazy west.
This pull up pigman and ted nugent hunt
pigs with a helicopter.
They have episodes they call a pork lips
now and they fucking fly around
attendance outside hunting.
You.
No,
it's massacre.
Instead,
it should be illegal not to do.
Yes.
Yeah,
it's a massacre,
but that's what they have to do.
Like,
look,
there are things that you have to do if
you want to,
if everybody has this idea that nature
balances itself out,
but the problem with that idea is in 90
percent of everything that's ever
existed ever is extinct.
Ninety percent.
So all of those fucking animals that
weren't helped along,
like,
you know,
I mean there's,
there's a real big problem with bears
and deer and moose populations because
bear and wolves,
especially to now in the places where
wolves have been reintroduced because
wolves give birth to a litter,
right?
So if a wolf pop,
you know,
if a wolf mom has like six babies,
a moose only has one baby.
So the moose has one baby and then
there's this fucking wolf running around
with six pups.
Well the just do the math,
you know,
they're gonna,
they're gonna slowly but surely start
taking out all of the,
uh,
the game animals.
And that's what's happening in a lot of
states where they've reintroduced wolf
hunting too.
A lot of states now.
And bears.
Oh,
bears have always been hunted.
What?
You have to have like a knife,
kodiak bears,
mountain lions,
you have to hunt things that don't have
a predator because if they don't have a
predator,
the nothing controls.
They're popular.
Great white sharks or what?
Well,
great white sharks try to hit those next
day.
They clean shit up,
dude.
Look at him.
Hang that,
but that's what that says.
If an ad,
there's actual episodes where you could
see going down these little pigs.
That's a.
That was a pork.
Lips was a night on sportsman channel.
They,
yeah,
they kill everything on the pork lips
now,
but they Just leave to point being this
guy's dad pigments.
Dad shoots pigs in the head all the
time.
Not only shoot them execution style,
but way crazier.
What he does is he'll line corn up on
the road like a row of corn,
like maybe like several yards long and
then they get down there because it's a
line.
They get down there to eat in the line
and then he gets their heads lined up so
when it gets to the headline deaf,
he'll shoot through three of them with
one bullet and he's always trying to
kill as many pigs as he can with one
bullet to the head and it's crazy but
it's fucked up.
But theY do have to kill these things.
So like,
look,
if you can kill one by shooting in the
head,
that is the best way to do it.
And some people like,
no,
you sHouldn't do it,
man.
You shouldn't kill.
Well,
okay,
well then they're going to eat
everything.
They're going to eat all the ground
nesting birds.
When you.
First of all,
jane would google how many pigs we
slaughter a day in this country.
That number.
You're talking about domestic.
That's avoidable because you don't have
to have farming,
right?
You don't have to have factory farm and
you to feed that many people.
You do.
My point is that we're talking about two
completely different issues.
My point is if you let these wild hogs
go nuts and just keep breeding,
they're having three litters a year,
sometimes really bad.
And each one of them is like six to
eight fucking babies.
500 hogs and pigs and they run fast for
the fastest shit.
And they know what's going on.
Man.
They're smart.
Wow.
They're here.
These pop pop,
pop.
And they watched their friends explode.
They're not stupid.
Damn.
But I don't know doug.
They're very smart.
It depends on who's run though.
I'm impressed with how fast they run.
It's a wild animal,
brian.
Yeah.
No,
that's terrified for his life,
but the question is if you don't do
this,
okay,
if you don't shoot them,
what do you do?
Do you just let them like what is the
vegan response?
What is the animal rights response?
Build a wall for him.
What do you do?
You've got to can't.
You can't,
but you can't have a white one.
You son of a bitch.
Well,
there's a lot of.
These are domestic pigs that get loose.
I'm so impressed with how fast they run.
They bound.
Yeah,
they're fast as fuck.
And by the way,
this ain't easy to hit these fuckers.
I love how they run and zigzag.
Yeah.
Fuck yeah,
they're smart.
They're trying.
Good shot though.
I forgot.
Not a magnet.
Right?
WeLl you definitely have to be a good
shot.
You're still.
I mean guys miss on the show.
All the halo is a killer.
No,
For real.
I feel like it'd be all right.
Call of duty and shit.
Dude.
Who did?
They have kids now who are 16 years old
because they've been playing for the
against and there were three.
You give them a couple of adjustments.
They're shooting as well as they swat
guy.
They get used to pulling triggers.
Those first person shooter as a
motherfucker.
All these fucks when they go into the
theater shooting,
they'll fucking practice on the kids who
are expert.
They get used
to Leading to get used to doing all
kinds of different things.
on.
This one kid was 16 and he was hitting.
He was,
he was headshots bang,
bang,
and they.
At first it was kind of missing a little
knick game,
a couple of adjustments because it was a
real gun and then in an afternoon he was
shooting as well as the expert.
The expert marksman.
Kids play a little too much.
video games he'd been playing since he
was three.
He was.
He was saying,
that's so insane.
If you think about how what they can do
now in comparison,
like think about what they used to be
able to do 20 years ago,
what they can do now and then what
they're going to be able to do 20 years
video games.
I'm talking about controlled fighters.
Fighters are going to have like an
ability to fight like a virtual reality,
kind of moving their head and seeing the
shots come.
Here's one thing for sure is gonna
happen.
We're going to have some I.
Robot type assassins.
One hundred percent.
We're going to release those on
Afghanistan and we're never going to
have another casualty.
I mean if also going to release so well,
that's the problem.
Yeah.
Suicide bombers now to fucking I robe.
Others walking down to the miami
dolphins stadium.
Oh,
that's the worry.
That one's for frisia chore ahead
technologically,
but for a little bit.
China begs to differ.
Korea.
Well,
I'm going to see that thing come from a
mile away thing.
I think the next generation,
this thing has a battery power on its
back that it stole from a tesla and it's
running around.
We'll go ahead and run behind that thing
and yanked the cord out.
I'm not afraid of.
It's going to know you're running behind
it because it has cameras everywhere.
Just like a tesla looking just like a
test.
That's how tesla.
This is insane though.
This is weird to watch.
I know this thing walking around what
you feel like you just run up and
fucking Bruce Lee kicking it fall over.
It can see you come and I would assume
it has cameras everywhere.
Why wouldn't you put cameras three and
an associate degrees on one of these
fucking things?
It's picking up a box.
Ooh,
it bends over correctly.
Nice posh.
The guys slap and tries to knock them
off.
Balance.
Let me spinning back.
Kick that.
Let me fucking yank him from the back.
I'll just.
I'll just sand chai trip.
I'm just get them into the collar tie.
Just fuck.
Let me go and get those legs out.
This is the future.
Hope.
Hopefully it's a little more
aerodynamic.
This guy keeps fucking with the robot
flux.
This steve jobs came around that it's
going to chase after the package.
She's.
Why doesn't he get mad at the guy with a
stick and he slapped the guy with the.
A kind of what?
I'm looking for,
robot.
Well,
if you guys paid attention to this go
thing.
No.
Well,
for the first time google's ai has been
able to beat the best go players in the
world that we're talking about.
Your role up behind him and fucking push
his.
Sorry ass over to.
Let's see.
Get back to q robot now.
I it gets bad,
but I'm yanking cord that once it gets
down to this,
almost fake,
that the way it's getting up.
Whoa.
I don't like that.
It looks like it looks like robocop in
1988 skinny.
It doesn't even bother defending itself.
This is just the prototype,
right?
When we're looking at something that's
going to one day be like a brendan
schaub or brian count,
you're not even to be able to tell,
so anyway,
the google artificial intelligence,
the ai for the first time,
it's been able to beat the best player
in the world,
a human being at go and go,
which is exponentially more difficult
than chess.
It's a super complicated game aNd not
only these these ai systems to say this
google ai system,
able to beat the best player in the
world,
but it's doing it and some really
creative ways that are freaking people
out because they're trying to figure out
how these,
these fucking games,
how these artificial intelligence
programs are learning these games so
well.
They thought it Was going to be years
before one could be to player,
like a real world class top of the food
chain at dartmouth for not knowing this
game.
I'm not knowingly said,
dog,
you could make up the rules and I'd be
like,
okay,
I've.
I've played.
I was playing a sorry with my kids the
other day and they were totally making
up roll.
I could tell.
I was like,
definitely not go to reach for the
fucking instructions.
She grabs my hand.
oh daddy this at the beginning.
Creative getting creative.
our kids are gonna.
Grow up with.
I started that new tesla suv because
will smith's son had it at erewhon.
He's got a name dropper that erewhon
okay,
we get it.
You're in calabasas.
I got to spend that karate kid money
somewhere.
That's word god damn right.
I'm going to start a cult someday.
Yes or no.
Oh,
wellsmith.
Either one.
Him his son.
Anyone like that?
Anyone to disappeared and he also
doesn't see a difference in women and
men's clothing because when I read,
well there is no gender.
It's not real.
It doesn't even know that you know that
gender says this as no more.
Cte will.
Smith will all bathrooms should just do
this.
Look,
I'll tell you that much.
Oh,
you want equal rights?
Good.
And show the bathroom.
Yeah,
share the bad.
A good looking kid though.
I don't see man clothes and woman
closed.
Well,
you need to get classes because they're
very different.
Girls wear skirts,
pitch combat boots and shit.
Go and put some high heels on.
welcome.
Listen,
if I was in this fucking kid's position,
I'd be saying way more stupid shit.
I'd be way weirder doing way more crazy
shit.
Anybody,
anybody in that life like growing up
with your parents?
You grew up like a little prince.
I got good grades,
but even weirder because your dad is a
professional.
Make believer.
Your dad is like just a guy who's really
good at pretending and he's world
renowned.
Everywhere you go.
You're flying on private jets.
Mom too.
She's famous as fuck.
Did you see chris rock's bit about that
classic,
about jayda?
What did,
what did he say?
He say he's like jada pinkett protesting
at the oscars.
Is main testing outside of beyonce?
Is posy not invited?
I was not invited.
That great joke.
Perfect actor for almoSt fucking it up
though.
Like,
are you chimed in the middle of me?
Sorry.
I was trying to get for the timing.
Uh,
who was the other guy?
The other black actor who,
who,
who tweeted hey rianna act.
I mean,
hey janet,
act better.
I was like,
oh geez man,
I can't.
Oh,
did they really?
Yeah,
that's good.
Do you want to get favor with the
academy?
That's the way to go.
What did you think about that whole
oscar?
So white.
Well,
you want my answer?
Yes please.
More wrestling or whenever something.
Yeah.
Whatever.
Something bothers me.
I'm usually kind of Write about it in a
way like where I go,
why I know the message is important and
I obviously am not prejudice and I want
everybody to be equal.
I think I resent when people cram it
down my throat and try to shame me or
scold me,
which I felt like the outskirts.
We're doing a little bit.
They did it.
They did a good job,
I think of kind of taking the piss out
of it,
you know,
making it,
come on,
we're off,
blah blah blah.
Chris rock did a good job with what he
had.
But um,
I always feel like when,
when,
when joe biden tAlked about consent and
when a lady gaga got up and sang that
song about victims of sexual abuse,
like,
I get it,
I'm with you.
I'm not pro rape but rape someone
because of a lady gaga song,
like you not to re.
Matter of fact,
it made me more angry,
know what to write.
I feel like that's what I,
you know,
you feel like you're being manipulated
and demonized you.
not only that,
it's a,
it's a manipulation where I already
agree with you,
so it's all racism is bad for telling me
something.
I don't know.
Sexual assault,
it's bad takes.
Lady gaga told me that because I was
about to go.
Right.
Thank god you stand.
You know what?
But it's not real.
It's social virtue.
It's virtue signaling.
Michael shermer calls.
But let me be devil's advocate for a
second.
that definitely devil's advocate.
You that.
Can you advocate,
I can advocate for the devil.
Uh,
there iS,
there.
I do understand the idea that if you are
sam smith and you say,
hey,
this is for all the lgbt people out
there or if you are lady gaga,
lgbt,
lgbt.
what?
I forgot the gate house tear by all I
see guys don't see gay.
No,
I have to exclude that.
You see women's clothing,
men's clothing.
Don't do it.
I'm just so colorblind.
I don't know if you guys or girls or
boys.
Do you have a front hole or front?
Let me check.
There it is.
But uh,
what was I saying?
Something really profound,
but,
but this is my thing.
Job,
just while you're thinking,
I'll tell you what will,
what will we do?
I think you were getting.
You were saying that.
I don't know what you're saying.
If someone says something there,
I do think that there is a place to say,
hey,
if you are a victim out there,
if you're a transgender kid and you were
thinking about killing yourself,
there is value.
There's value to seeing really cool
people,
actors that you look up to saying,
hey dude,
it's okay.
You're not a freak or it's okay to be
who you are because that's the truth of
who you are and feel empowered.
Like I get that.
I can't wait until it's no longer an
issue so then we can start
figuring out which one of these
transgender people are just dummies that
happened to be transgender.
which one of these gay people are just
dummies and happened to be gay.
Like there's a lot of that where people
get free rides just because from a
marginalized group,
it's not just that they're annoying and
they're a part of this whole thing,
like a hundred percent.
A lot of the real de is just coming from
dummies that support a great cause and
they get.
They have a big problem with the whole
social justice warrior movement is it?
A lot of it is just really fucked up
socially,
socially retarded people and those
people,
those people have found an area in which
if you,
if you support this area,
you can be the biggest con in the world
supporting that area.
You could be fucking horrendous to
people,
rude to people,
try to destroy people's lives as long as
you're doing within the confines and the
parameters of that cost and I don't buy
it because I think that those are just
terrible people.
Meeting those people are will people
that found a good cause to be specific?
Specific.
I don't know.
You can call them terrible people.
I think people like that are Way less
interested in the actual cause.
They're way more Interested in power.
You said that you see people who,
the,
you know,
whether they're in greenpeace,
whatever,
they just are not satisfied with winning
a victory.
They are more interested in never
demonizing and controlling.
Another group of.
I also think going back to the oscars,
yes,
there is no black people nominated.
Could it just be that all the white
people had great movies that year?
Maybe the blood in the.
They never got the major roles,
which is an issue,
but it just so happens this year.
All the great movies,
all the great actors happen to be white,
so you just chalk it up as race.
It's a clever move though,
because we're to hollywood.
there's such pussies that once you do
have protests like this and say oscars
so white,
they're gonna fucking panic now.
Black.
Oh well everyone,
what they're.
What?
They're going to like the type of movies
that are going to get made.
They're going to try to make movies for
highly perry's like,
no,
that's not gonna work,
but that they're going to try to make
really diversity oriented movies.
Of course.
Yeah,
it's,
but it's,
it's all artificial.
So this is like an adolescent stage,
so we'll get to that stage and then
It'll just be quality.
Like there's no denying denzel
washington's one of the greatest actors
of all time.
you don't give a fuck if he's black.
He's white.
He's fucking spectacular.
Robert downey jr.
When he went blackface.
Still great.
Don't remember that.
shouldn't even talk.
You can't do that today.
You're creating controversy.
Tropic thunder.
If you tried to do that today,
you could do it.
He kept saying he was trying to forgot.
he did that and he was really amazing
because you can't do that to never go
full retard.
some of the greatest lines and
everything.
And then he moved.
It was brilliant.
funny fucking movie,
man.
Great man.
Eddie bravo and I were just.
We were just talking about on the
companion.
yeah,
that's right.
You can use so good.
I've talked about that movie like 10
times over.
The last two is a spectacular movie that
you couldn't make it.
All I'm saying is it doesn't matter if
robert junior plays black guy,
white guy.
he's a brilliant man.
Still play a chinese guy.
Could you still.
Do you remember when they used to.
What was the charlie chan?
Charlie chan was a white guy that they
pretend this child things you could and
I'll tell you something else.
He dressed up like a native american and
we instagrammed a picture for this
sketch.
We're doing all these social justice
from that and I answered some of them.
I was like,
listen man,
it's a misappropriation.
Do I hope you know how ridiculous you
look like,
bitch,
you got a tesla.
What are you talking about?
You're not a real indian.
Yeah,
I saw there was one of the kardashians
had a photo of her like in some native
american outfit,
like a pocahontas type outfit for
halloween.
It's hot.
Probably hot as fuck.
Just just fucking all the hate standing
up,
standing up for any reason to stay.
Fucking hate americans do not understand
what cultural misappropriation is.
You don't because you have whIte
privilege.
The k,
first of all,
you should just shut the fuck up and
listen.
This is a big thing,
a big thing that they like to do.
If someone of color speaking,
shut the fuck up and listen.
wow.
I am noble and I am progressive and I
want you to shut the fuck up and listen.
That's a big thing if some.
If a woman is talking about women's
issues,
how about we shut the fuck up guys?
How about you guys?
You men to shut the fuck up.
But the thing is posted the indian
video.
You don't even know the context.
So for you to jump on there and be like,
this is offensive bitch.
Your wife.
It was the traditional garb.
It actually was very historically
accurate.
It's fake as fuck.
Do you ever listen to the character?
Do you ever watch the youtube videos
from the,
uh,
the amazing atheist?
No.
Amazing atheist is great.
He's been on the podcast before too.
He's fucking great.
His videos are amazing and because he's
amazing,
but he had one the other day about how
feminists hate when you use the phrase,
not all men because they want you to
somehow or another be guilty for the
actions of all men.
So if guy say,
whoa,
whoa.
Not all men rape.
Like I don't rape.
Stop saying all,
stop categorizing.
All met,
which is fair.
Which is totally fair,
but he does this whole thing on this
article at some woman who's a crazy
feminist,
who by the way I went to her page,
I'm blocked.
I love what I don't even know I'm
blocked in their twitter things.
Know that you,
you use these block programs that
anybody who might have any remotely
controversial view really.
She's insular,
probably blocked to herself,
but his fucking video on it is
sensational.
He does such a good job of covering all
the points.
He's self deprecating.
Yeah.
It's a really good fucking points.
And he's got a boat.
I've been on a binge watch some of his
videos lately.
He's actually,
I'll watch them,
but this one like just skewers this,
the feminist ideology that you're
supposed to just feel guilty for the
actions of men that have done horrible
things when you haven't done a goddamn
thing,
but it's like what it is.
They
have this,
uh,
this ability to demonize and they don't
want to lose it.
You know,
they can call up and they use to use
fake statistics like one in four women
like that.
Was that Christine Summers on your
podcast,
but exponentially genders,
that gender study guy from Arizona,
I think a or a woman was from Arizona
was I want to said that and she didn't
have any.
It was a shotty experiment.
It was bullshit and it's also the
redefined with sexual assault and rape
isn't to include regret.
That's right.
Which is our alcohol.
If you've had sex while inebriated
college band in that,
they've kind of abandoned that by the
way,
but feminists were riding that hard to
the point where feminists wrote a blog
about it,
like if you have had sex while drunk,
you've raped somebody.
I remember like theY were saying,
women don't have sex with your man if
you're a man's drunk because he can't
consent.
Like,
listen,
can I just sign a paper?
we could suck my dick when I'm drunk.
Yeah.
Is there anyone I can just text you can
set right now.
Trust me.
We're gonna Be okay.
Plus b,
I am ready to go.
I will say whatever you want.
I would like to find the guy that has
ever sued or taken a woman to court or
tried to call the cops because he was
drunk.
He had a girl fucked him.
I want to for a second how I want to
find a job.
My friend there was a story.
A guy wrote an article I remember about
10 years ago in the New York times.
Neat was talking about being a battered
male and his girl,
but it does happen though.
Of course it does,
but he went to the cops three times and
the cops were like this.
They were like,
uh,
man up.
They were like,
they were like,
they would all snickers this in New York
city.
Yeah.
Go New York.
Bullied by.
Funny is.
That was one of the subjects that the
amazing atheist is named tj.
One of the things that he brought up was
that he used to work with this woman
who's to sexually assault them.
They can teach us like a big sort of
like outside of doing his youtube videos
is kind of an introverted guy a little
bit and he worked at this place and this
woman who was an older woman and she was
his boss,
she was always grabbing his ass and
fucking with them.
She's a funny when it happens to a guy
happens a girl.
It's terrible for a guy to me.
It's hilarious.
He wants to get off bro.
Hey,
sugar tits once you get over here.
to me,
that's hilarious.
I know there was nothing she could do to
him that I would press your heart son.
Yeah,
I don't.
I'm confused.
We'll deal with it bro.
Up,
confused.
There's so much confusion with so many
of these subjects.
When I was 14 of an older woman took
advantage of me.
I would have been a.
Okay.
Yeah,
but if she was your boss and she was
gross.
If she was your boss and she was gross
and I think he was.
Well,
I think it was a young guy.
Suck it up.
Yeah,
but you're a different guy too.
Like if you're like an emotionally less
introverted.
Yeah,
more introverted,
a little different for women,
men guys stronger.
The guy could be inside your body.
It's a thousand dollars.
Not going to hold them,
no doubt,
but it's like saying murderer is,
is really bad,
so don't go.
I mean
if someone punches someone that's no big
deal,
but it is like getting knocked out as
not as bad as getting stabbed and
murdered,
but it's still not good for you.
So like his position of being sexually
assaulted by a woman is not as bad as an
ally.
That's reversed.
It's fucked up and it is weird,
but it's hilarious to meet with him at
night,
dreading going into work and be locked
in a fucking sugar dick and just paratha
them nonstop.
What's even more funny as you being
callous about this with a mouthful of
elk,
she would've downed mocking this guy.
How dare you take.
It's fucking funny.
Come on pussy.
It is.
It is weird.
And the other thing that's weird is
like,
I don't have any sympathy for these
fucking 16 year old kids were the
teacher blows them when they get in gang
bangs.
The teacher in school this,
you'll be fine hills.
Where was my dick psa?
THe real problem was one pussy that
falls in love with her.
That's the real problem.
No,
that's what happened.
He fucks it up for everyone.
He ruins the gang,
starts telling it Baby fucking out of.
He's like,
I like.
I liked the courts too.
it's just this hot ass teacher.
Just poor kid.
You've terrorized him pretty right.
One of the teachers.
There's a whole list site dedicated to
hot teachers that have fucked their
kids.
Really?
Yeah.
My warlock.
So I had nothing.
I can't remember a single hot teacher
that I had it all through my years out
of kindergarten,
first grade,
ms dot yarrow smoke show.
There was a dude that was a handsome guy
that was a spanish teacher.
And I think he was like,
oh my god,
what?
Whoa,
she's hot.
It's free.
That woman right now,
hope I will pay her bills.
She doing what does it say?
Where's she going to 17?
Can we get rid of.
He was 17,
between 14 and 17 for whatever.
Free on bail,
but was tried for oil oral.
When a new guy in print.
I'm brett bail.
Sugar free on bail was blowing them.
More people copying freak.
Look,
there's some girls.
Oh well.
A little thick.
Not too.
I like to go get these fucking school is
dirty bitch school.
They're gorgeous.
God damn it.
Oh yeah.
There's a lot of hotlines.
That one's free them.
Well,
you know also a lot of these guys,
they're like really good at producing
older women.
Young hands.
She's 25 year old.
Had sex with 18 year old.
I don't see a problem with either.
If he's 18,
18,
18 year old male student.
Illegal.
She's a spanish teacher.
Incentive.
10 sentences 18,
but a lot.
Preventing teachers from having sexual
relationships with students regardless
of their age.
Whatever.
Quit your job or guilty or guilty
though.
It's all good.
Yeah,
for sure.
It's not teaching spanish and still suck
is seven years older than him.
He's probably given that good 18 year
old dick just cardio for day one of a
believer.
He's trying his spanish.
Ola.
Do you imagine you remember things that
you would do when you were like a young
teenage?
We couldn't even believe you were doing
them while you were doing them.
Is this real life like the first time I
had an actual sexual relationship with a
girlfriend I remember like we would be
having sex and be like,
is this what I really get to have sex?
When I was 16 I had ever had sex with an
older girl and I was like,
I was like,
this is unbelievable and I would come
and stay hard.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
But you get used to it.
You get used to.
It's like,
yeah,
we're going to have sex.
Just like anything normal comes normal.
You know?
There's only one time in my entire life
where my ears rang when I came and that
was when I was in high school.
My girlfriend at the time blew me on a
porch.
We're at a port.
She blew me.
I changed the shape of her head.
Her head became like one of those that
they've had their fucking head clamp,
the one of those skull shaping jeans.
She looked like doug came and my ears
were ultimate orgasm and I remember
thinking,
whoa,
is this going to happen every time where
you're like,
are you okay to this day?
I'm 48 years old.
This happened probably when I was 16.
To this day.
I think,
man,
if I just don't jerk off for a couple of
weeks,
maybe I can get back.
You're trying to get back to the super
soaker.
Don't have the willpower.
You want them to be young forever.
Gluten.
I,
I can get on that primal diet.
No,
no,
no.
I'm not going to stop shooting loads.
I guess I'm just not.
Now you know what the problem is?
It becomes too confusing.
It's like the same way I feel about
exercise.
Like if someone said,
I'll give you 10 million bucks people
exercise for you.
I couldn't do it.
I go,
you can fucking keep your 10 million
bucks.
I'm not going to have a year of
suffering just for some money that I'm
miserable.
I can't do it.
And I feel the same way about jerking
off.
I think that a lot of ways jerking off
is like a type of exercise because it
exercises your reproductive system so
it's not constantly ramped up.
You know?
I've always felt like there's a lot of
confusion that comes with being a horse.
These guys on the couch and fucking tell
him,
man,
ants exercise.
Do it by the fucking job exercise.
So good for you.
I told you,
mom,
you gotta come,
you gotta get it out of your body.
Because if you don't,
it pulls up and then your body starts
getting desperate and lowers your
testosterone.
Not only that,
your mind starts getting desperate and
you start getting like,
like I remember I went on a dry spell
when I was just out of high school.
I was a fucking complete total loser
from 17 to 18 graduating year.
Dude,
I was a fucking loser.
I didn't have not been going on.
No money couldn't get.
I had no money at all.
I was,
I was girl,
didn't give a fuck about taekwondo,
just we'll kicking and jacket was doing.
And I was so sad.
I couldn't get my clip,
not get lazy,
so for ever and when I did get laid,
I finally did get laid after six months.
I didn't even stick it in.
I like barely got.
Yep.
And I just got a fucking loser.
I am,
but our.
I remember that desperate feeling,
like the desperate nature of it and then
I started regularly beating off.
That's when I started regularly beating
off was I was just like.
I had a girlfriend when I was 16.
I swear to god.
I got laid before I beat off and people
think that's a lie.
It is not weird though.
I didn't start beating off when I was
five and I'm not kidding.
I wish I knew about nobody talked to me,
which I figured out like,
oh,
you get some vaseline.
You.
Ooh,
not me.
As a kid.
I used to rub it into the bed.
That's all I have.
Waterproof dick looks,
freshly waxed gleam,
fucking lots the moisture and I remember
being maybe fifth or sixth grade and
just having a boner in my sweats.
Just be like,
oh,
I like,
it really had no idea.
I was hiking and I made a day sad,
just fucking jerk me,
but happened to me now when I'm fucking,
I'm hiking and I'm thinking about
something dirty and all of a sudden
somebody walks by me right now I'm going
to be a lone guy off trail with a heart.
They say,
guys,
think of sex,
something like every three seconds.
So girls do too.
There's a lot of free girls out there to
bitch.
But I'm my point being like,
one of the problems was I wasn't jerking
off so desperate and so that's crazy.
I was desperate.
Uber aggressive to smelled of
desperation.
I'm sure girls could smell it.
It was a loser.
I was a loser.
I was living with my parents.
I didn't have a future stone wheel.
I'd won the state championships like one
year,
the first one when I was 18.
So I had no real accomplishments.
You know,
I remember those days.
That was your last.
So who was the girl who was like,
I'll suck your dick.
Joe.
Well,
she,
um,
she's had sex with me.
I don't think she blew me.
She jerked me off a couple times for.
We actually had sex.
Sex.
Where'd you meet her?
Local local girl.
She was just randomly.
Yeah,
her name was donna.
Nice.
Because,
because now kids can go on instagram.
Facebook,
right.
So much easier.
It's so much easier to get chicks now.
More dangerous.
It's way more dangerous,
but back in the day,
especially when you're a kid,
it was just,
you know,
he met the girl and it's whatever.
You to have a girl that hurt piece boy,
they put a red flag on her and made her
walk around with a flag like people
knew.
People knew when people had things.
Tinder's like a weird.
It's fucking hot girls.
Hot girls and go.
I liked that guy dem.
God damn son.
Yeah.
If you want to get laid today and you're
a guy,
all you have to do is have a phone and
you have to be like not totally
disgusting or have really low standards
or be 49 with two kids and wife.
What?
A little bit of a roadblock.
You got to learn about russians.
Yeah.
But then then,
you know,
you go to Russia,
I go on vacation and you come back,
or Costa Rica or to Thailand,
maybe try and get your dick sucked.
You know when you don't want wanna,
try not to say just good luck.
They just do it.
Just,
it's what they do.
It's cultural.
You can't be rude.
You are misappropriating,
blowjob culture from other countries or
third world,
wherever they drunk indigenous people.
Got to say all the key buzzwords.
So yeah,
I've,
I don't know what you're talking about,
but I believe one day,
one day,
one day we'll all be single and free.
Oldest fucking girls.
We shouldn't get a time,
dude.
That'd be three of us.
The checklist.
Hey,
that house or wrinkles girls come on.
Oh,
well there's gonna be some.
There's going to be some massive
breakthroughs within the next.
I know.
So I know there's a massive
breakthrough.
The same guy who came up with regena
keen is working on right now that's
going to regenerate collagen in your
body in a crazy way.
Whether it's going to eliminate
wrinkles,
come on,
will never age.
When you're going to age,
you're gonna fucking die.
You're just going to look good when
you're dead.
That's awesome.
Yeah,
but if you can keep your muscles
structure and then they shoot that
fucking shit in your body.
That regenerates collagen.
How long we think in.
Well,
you don't know because there's all sorts
of different things they're constantly
working on,
so what we're talking about is what they
have in 2016.
What they have in 2016 will be
unrecognizable in 2026 because it'll be
on such a higher level.
It's all exponential because every
single invention in every single
technological breakthrough and every
single medical breakthrough,
they all converged together and they all
build on each other and new
technological breakthroughs,
make new medical breakthroughs,
possible.
New understanding of the body makes new
new designs and new things,
and then then there's going to be all
sorts of different.
Like they just came up with some fucking
lens that they're installing in people
that is allowing people that weren't
able to see before and now they can see
new stem cell operations.
Oh my god,
they're doing what they're doing now is
just the tip of the iceberg.
We could just stay alive if humans.
I mean as a,
as a,
as a race can stay alive for the next
thousand years.
Well,
we won't be.
We'll date this machinery,
this,
this is this biological machinery that
we let them help the next to come up
with some shit or not guys got about 50
in the next.
I really want to be on a planet where
everyone can breed and no one dies.
Well,
not only that,
follow this.
What if you can download all the
information.
I killed people like pigs.
So what does that say about
accomplishment?
If you could download like how to be
everything you want it to be.
If you could take approach.
You see that recently I haven't seen
that.
No.
Oh my god.
To pull that up,
jamie.
What scientists have figured out a way.
They are very confident that they were
going,
they're going to be able to download
skills into your brain.
Like the fucking matrix fucks us.
They're going to be able to download
information and skills into your special
anymore.
Well,
not,
not always.
No one special.
No one's going to look any different
there.
Everyone's going to look like fucking
john siena.
I don't want to be be around for that.
What is that size for risks,
but I have to believe that there's a
reason why they're being nudged in that
direction.
Scientists discover how to upload
knowledge to your brain.
This poor girl is the Guinea pig strap
in folks,
strap in mean we're just.
We're just at the beginning of this
thing.
This is.
This is not man.
Everything that's in the matrix is all
going to be true.
Artificial reality,
whether or not it's going to take over
the world like the matrix.
We're all going to be locked into some
fucking machine and feeds off your
spine.
That's probably not going to happen,
but what is definitely going to happen
is virtual reality is going to be
indistinguishable from regular reality.
I always leave scared when we do these
podcasts.
Why don't we?
It's not scary,
but it's fascinating.
It's fascinating,
but here's the thing.
Here's why it shouldn't be scared
because anybody who's ever lived,
ever at any time you can go back to,
you know,
go back to rome and grab in julius
caesar and take him to 2016.
He would be like,
you gotta be fucking shit made fruit guy
who lived the best life in the world
hundreds of years ago or a thousand
years ago would be nothing in comparison
to you if you had to go back.
Okay.
If you had to go back and you had to
live like in leonardo da vinci's town,
you'd want to fucking climb up on top of
a windmill and jump the fuck off.
He'd be like,
what?
I'm going to eat this shitty bread and
we're all gonna.
We're all,
we're all gonna die of polio.
Already ready for that?
Yeah.
Get ready for the smallpox epidemic.
Anything.
Anything anytime or rats in town.
Everybody has to run flag fucking fleas.
Yeah,
I mean you gotta figure out a way to
know that you didn't even know that it
was,
that they didn't know anything.
Those witches curses and shit.
They didn't know what the fuck was going
on.
Or you could go back.
Awesome.
You could,
will you if you knew what you know now.
Yeah,
that's true.
I started drawing.
Human beings will evolve with their
tasks.
So like,
oh shit.
You heard a shot,
you know what you would do?
You would go back and start,
you know one day have a thing called a
microwave oven.
And they'd say he's a which led him on
fire.
Yeah.
They might kill me.
Satisfying.
Fought with swords too.
And you had to be a bad ass that I don't
know if it was a big man and favors the
fastest guy sorta no joke.
So it's definitely don't favorite big
person to favor someone is strong enough
to swing the sword as fast as possible.
Public await that.
You like any like a point of diminishing
returns to its sword fighting.
It's pretty final sword fighting.
It's not so fine.
You don't walk away from a bloody no.
Yo.
What's interesting is musashi was a big
man.
Me and my issue was not small men.
Thick.
Well for.
It's hard to tell because you know,
they.
What they measured,
I mean I think they probably didn't use
inches.
I mean,
I don't know what the fuck they use
described as being,
I think like thick though,
like big,
big sore.
You know,
we had a president,
I forget which president,
but he was five foot four and he weighed
a hundred pounds.
Was it taft?
I think it might've been tapped.
No tea.
No,
not if it was big was a big job,
a big fat guy.
Because when I made saying there's no
fat presidents,
people sent me pictures.
So I was reading this book with my kid
the other day was all about presidents
and weird facts about presidents,
but one of the guys was a hundred
pounds,
so he's half my size.
Tiny little.
That's like a hobbit running the
fucking.
That's like christina.
Yeah.
Well,
well she's probably got 1:10.
He definitely smallest us president.
He's five for 100 pounds.
Smallest us president.
W was it james madison?
That's right,
man.
I didn't even know he was president
until I was reading my daughter's book.
Madison,
one of the authors of the many
presidents.
Can you name?
I can name maybe five,
maybe five,
maybe five to 10.
Who is our third?
Who is our third president?
Some douchebag.
Jefferson,
okay.
How about lincoln?
Was he 16?
George Washington was number one.
Who's number two?
Nobody gives a fuck because nobody cares
about number two losers.
Alexander hamilton doesn't work that
way.
It doesn't work that way.
He's gonna lose at hamilton.
He was a winner.
It was a new president.
James madison.
Wait,
it was the Alexander Hamilton and
jefferson Washington.
Hamilton majors person.
You know who we really dismiss for one
term presidents.
Yeah.
Wasn't hamilton the guy that was
terrible.
He was getting all his fucking friends
jobs and he was really,
really corrupt and literally wound up
saying,
I'm not fit for this job.
No,
you're right.
It wasn't hamilton.
It was someone else.
Find out who,
whose.
Whose quote was that I was not fit for
this job.
So one of the presidents,
harding harding was considered,
I think it was.
It was considered the worst president
because he was very handsome.
He's very good looking.
I think it was warren harding,
and he was very handsome,
but he was a bad president.
He just was not a very smart guy.
I think he looked really presidential.
How about,
hey,
I heard jfk was just a fuck and ladies.
Men three weird.
You really heard that?
Oh yeah.
Hey,
hey.
This is breaking news along with taking
mcgregor down.
Jfk gets some bitch.
You ever seen his medical records and
health would a physical wreck?
He was.
Okay.
Yeah,
it was Andrew Jackson.
What john was.
Jackson jackson was a guy who
essentially was considered,
first of all,
he'd seen a lot of battle.
He killed a lot of native americans.
No,
no,
no.
This is the wrong quote,
is the wrong quote.
That's not.
Andrew.
Jackson was talking about being a great
general and not being.
Not being a great president.
He had been shot on tool and he had a
hole in his in his lung that would
perforate jfk.
Jfk had gonorrhea and all sorts of
horrible back problems.
He what was his.
It was on so many drugs.
Look it up.
The New York times ran a whole thing.
I couldn't believe his medical status.
This back issue from partying or what?
He had a.
I think it was a congenital fuck this
fucking dude.
Fuck dude.
He will know.
He went to celebrate this.
He wore a brace.
He wore a body brace under his suit moto
and he had to be in pools.
It was.
He had some kind of degenerative
disease.
I think back when you threw out
gonorrhea and herpes and he was treated
for gonorrhea is dot treated for them.
If you look at his medical records,
it's pretty unbelievable.
When they treated you for gonorrhea,
did they even get it back then?
I mean they just started a runny nose,
barely penicillin thing.
I mean,
what kind of fucking what kind of like
lab tests they do back then?
It's pretty easy to cure with
antibiotics.
Who knows what?
Yeah,
yeah.
Well diseases are weird man,
because occasionally diseases come along
with it and not exactly sure what you
have and they have to ask where you
been,
where'd you go?
And then they have to try to sort of
narrow it down and test for a bunch of
different things.
They say,
this is an urban myth,
but the guy emailed this story to me
where the curl comes,
goes to the doctor,
she's got a rash on her face.
Dr.
Like,
what is going on here?
I couldn't figure out the sample comes
up and goes,
um,
can I ask you a question?
Go what?
And he goes,
you have necrosis on your,
on your face.
You have a bacteria that you get from
dead bodies.
We've been around dead bodies because.
No.
And he said,
where'd you go?
She goes,
I was in Ireland.
What did you hook up with?
Anybody who said,
yeah,
guy in a bar.
He goes,
do you have his number?
Yeah,
yeah,
blah,
blah.
It turns out the guy worked in a morgue
and he was fucking bodies.
She sucked as zombie dick.
Okay,
but is this.
And she sucked his dick and got.
And that's it that I was told that's an
urban myth,
but this is what the guy emailed me and
told me the story of jesus christ.
Because story,
if it's a well,
why don't let's go further.
Then she started time traveling and went
back to the time before she did it and
then it became two of her and the two of
her plotted to take over the world.
He just making shit up at this point
possible.
You know,
we don't know if a story that's such a
good store,
but it's kind of google these things get
on your damn phone.
It makes sense.
Or they hold it far away from you so we
could use our.
My eyes are so bad now.
They're so good at this distance.
They're perfect,
but then you're right here.
I can always like.
Yeah,
lucky.
I don't have to read my own fingerprints
on here.
It was just a pink blush.
Stories kind of legit though.
Makes sense.
I'm sorta,
sorta makes sense.
I could see it happening.
It makes sense that dead bodies would
have bacteria on them that would be
eating the dead body and if you had any
sort of an infection or cut on the south
or you didn't wash and it got into your
system.
Sure.
That makes sense.
Very cox dead body.
Oh,
a lot of people.
Yeah.
That's been a real problem many times in
funeral homes.
I told you my acting teacher right when
he came out,
his mother died.
He told his story.
His mother dies.
Fucking goes to see her body in the
morgue and the guys coming out and
putting his pants on sweating and he
looked at the guy and the guy looked at
him and he goes,
you fuck my mother.
He didn't say it,
but he knew it.
He never said anything.
The guy just ran out,
beat the fuck out.
Like I just went,
fuck that.
Why didn't he go check his mom's box?
He did.
Well,
I don't know if you checked our box,
check the box to take that asset.
Pulled out my kit kit.
I'd have to kill someone.
That's another way.
I don't think you do.
I don't think you'd do jail time for
that.
You would get a fine for it.
Oh no.
Jail side.
No,
no,
no.
You.
You're going to jail.
It's a.
There's a law about mishandling a dead
body,
but it's really.
There you go.
So the legend,
the legend.
Yeah.
Been told over and over again.
There you go.
Scroll down and see if there's any
possibility.
See,
scroll down.
Blah,
blah,
blah.
Oh,
these are the same emails over and over
and the girl got herpes from whatever
reason.
Started fucking making stuff up.
There's certain things that are like
supposed to be urban mess,
but you find out their true charles
manson endorsing trump is not.
Is not following a.
Who cares?
The charles manson endorses.
You know what's weird?
The trump guys who are putting fucking
ss style bands around their arms.
Have you seen a show?
These idiots are taken bumper stickers,
trump bumper stickers,
and they're wrapping them around their
arms like hitler.
Armbands bad look.
White people just get so wacky.
Fucking white people.
White people are a lot like the economy,
the economy,
cyclical white people on an upswing
right now.
They're on the upswing.
Ups.
Everything was all good.
Yeah.
Look at these guys.
Dip shits not good.
These guys have fucking bumper stickers
around their arm like trump is the new
hitler and it's kinda macho is.
No.
Oh my god.
It's not a bumper sticker.
Some real is mostly false facts.
She found this on snopes without even
knowing.
It was just two guys,
two young women were photographed
wearing nazi style.
All right.
Okay.
You know what?
They probably wanted us to talk to them.
Okay.
What's false?
Hold on.
Scroll down.
The two men were legitimate trump
supporters and the use of nazi armbands
express their genuine political beliefs.
So they really did it well.
What were they doing when they show me
around?
It doesn't mean they're nazis.
Well,
were they doing just fox news?
A tweet that supported the republican
presidential Donald Trump spot in
Florida rally,
but blah,
blah,
blah.
Not dissimilar.
Okay,
but what is it?
What?
What's,
what's really going on and scroll down.
So what are they saying?
The art band was one of many invoked of
nazi imagery.
We,
we,
we photoshop.
But what is it saying?
What does it say?
How is it not true?
However,
it appeared that the initial tweet was
sent with that much verification as to
whether trump armbands were legitimate
campaign memorabilia.
Sported you,
you,
you know,
chronically on.
Ironically,
ironically,
by dutiful supporters of the gop
presidential hopeful not long after the
image hit twitter,
hard users began pointing out that the
trump supporters looked awfully
familiar.
So who are they?
Other jokes.
They're comedians.
Oh,
they're comics.
They keep showing up.
Political prankster.
Fuck it.
They wouldn't go.
They go.
When they got us,
they got us.
Well now we know play.
People were sending that late today and
I was like,
what do you see when you see when they
grew a fucking dinosaur leg on a
chicken,
a real dinosaur like no park is gonna
fucking come and I will be the first
one.
There will be the first one there to see
all sympathetic american consumer.
You'll be there with fresh,
a new hair.
Do synthetic dna.
You're going to have create your own
animal from your own imagination.
Scientists have grown dinosaur legs on
chicken for the first time.
What in the fuck?
What the fuck?
How about you guys?
Cure cancer?
Yeah.
How about you figuring out a way to get
salt at the ocean?
You assholes.
Stop making dinosaurs.
It's all part of it.
Help you help the ozone funds with a
dinosaur.
It's all part of it is all part of it,
right?
We shouldn't expect these guys to make
better cell phones.
They have a different field of study
about that life.
The chickens out about that,
bro.
I ain't about that book about the
chicken eggs on some pitch.
It's so rare that someone's job.
Dude,
I'll tell you,
when you watched chickens eat,
you realize they're just dinosaurs.
They're just little bit little
dinosaurs.
They can't kill you,
so they just deal with it when they can
make dick cells.
How many,
how big do you think guys are?
How much bigger there?
No one is going to have a little dick
anymore,
that's for sure.
That's for sure.
No one's just going to say you going to
get.
How big is your dick going to get and
how many guys,
guys,
guys get weird without having surgeries
like just inject my dig and if you can
jean dope or whatever it is.
For crispr crispr,
crispr is bad ass going to be at least a
foot long and girls pussies are going to
grow.
I had a whole bit about this,
but the bet if they did come up with big
dick pills,
like those commercials that ron jeremy
used to sell three in the morning,
if it was real pills,
those pills really did make your dick
bigger.
It would be about 30 seconds before the
first guy died of an overdose.
I might because no one's taken one pill
over there.
How many gives me a stroke?
The problem is dick should be so big.
The vagina's would grow too because
people would still have to breed and
they would evolve and have to adapt.
I said they would turn into giant flying
squirrel pussy people.
They're just people that are jews with
big dicks that haven't been shopping.
Cart's going to be chasing these girls
to the top of cliffs and the women would
just leap to safety like squirrel
squirrel.
Like imagine what kind of weird shapes
people are gonna come into like now.
What we're dealing with now is people
that are starting to explore the
possibility of modifying their body with
tattoos and piercings or weird shit.
But once you can change the shape,
yeah.
You know you're going to lose the
funnier loose.
You know the people.
That's not good.
We'll have variety though.
Just because everybody has a different
idea of what's beautiful.
Everybody has a different idea of what
they want.
Someone's going to want to be.
The whole is going to be like,
no,
I to know I want to be five foot one.
Man.
I like to keep this.
I want to keep these
pits and small day.
Madison,
you'll have less people who are longing
for something.
Right?
You'll have if you have an ability and
the money,
if it's fake,
but they'll still be people left out
because it's going to cost money.
You're going to ask you.
You feel me?
Like reading,
you know like it used to be a long time
ago that reading was a luxury that very
few people could read,
but now have couldn't afford books.
Right now.
Pretty much everybody could read.
Anybody could get books,
and not only that,
you can get so much off the internet
that's free.
You can get your access to information
today is better than it's ever been
before.
Fuck,
your access to changing your body will
follow a similar,
doesn't mean happier and it doesn't mean
that will be more fulfilled,
I would imagine.
I think the responsibility to creating
your own fulfillment will still remain
and they can make artificial happiness.
Got damage.
Problem is we like went on drugs,
right?
Yeah.
Well the problem is what is happened is
really based on just.
You know what I'm talking about ecstasy
all day.
If you were just rolling all day,
but no negative repercussions can't get
shit done,
art wouldn't be created.
Right?
Art,
when you get your dick sucked while
you're on ecstasy on her son.
How about you fly like an eagle?
You guys are fucking god.
Oh my god.
It's crisper.
Yeah,
that's the new god because we're
controlling our own evolution.
I wonder,
man,
I wonder what it's gonna look like.
I mean,
it's going to change.
It's not going to just.
No one's ever going to go,
hey everybody,
let's go camping.
Let's stop all this.
Right?
We're not going to do that.
Those dudes that had grown dinosaur legs
and chickens,
that's the satisfaction.
Satisfaction,
you get from overcoming the impossible,
almost as good as learning kung fu in
the matrix,
but if,
but if someone can take the shortcut,
don't you think the math is that they
can take the shortcut,
then I can put the work in.
I don't know.
What I'm saying is that there may be
shortcuts in certain in certain areas,
but we'll still have challenges and you
know,
hope you're right,
brian.
Yeah.
So,
so if you're really good at something,
if you're really good at whatever you
want to be,
I wonder if you know,
you know,
like for example,
like what I like about tennis,
what you like about archery,
what you like about boxing,
whatever it is,
is it the repetition and the state of
puts you in and the slow attrition of,
of a skillset is immensely satisfying.
Right?
I wonder if you could just do it right
away.
I wonder if all the fun goes away.
It doesn't snow more mystery,
but mr.
Learning because when you're hitting a
ball really well or you're boxing really
well one day and you know,
you go back.
Yeah.
And you go today,
I hit it,
and if you don't have something to
compare that to,
I think what happens is you end up being
generally copacetic and and I wonder
what it says about downloads.
Skateboarding,
just a fake ass dude skateboarding like
I think who you are right now is based
on what our ideas are right now about
what people want and what people need
and what makes us happy.
And one of the things that makes us
happy is overcoming adversity.
Trying to figure out puzzles,
trying to set goals and accomplishing
them.
Setting goals and accomplishing them is
one of the biggest sources of happiness.
One of the things that people say,
if you really want to be happy,
you should have projects and she'd set
goals and she'd try to accomplish those.
And for whatever reason it's probably
just some deep seated evolutionary
reason and it's something that's in our
dna.
We have this desire to achieve things
and when we do achieve them,
it gives us this feeling of happiness.
And if you don't do that,
like the most regretful,
sorrowful depressed people,
rarely set goals and rarely achieve
those set goals for whatever reason.
Now whether or not the creek and they
hate on others who are trying to achieve
that.
So what is what we're doing kind of is
like some sort of a weird balancing act
with our ancient primate minds,
right?
So our ancient primate mines which
wanted to survive,
they wanted to gather food,
they wanted to figure out things like
how do I catch this fish?
How do I,
how do I start a fire?
And all these different desires that we
had to both breed,
protect our territory,
overcome,
and they manifest themselves as like
rewards and these human rewards are in
our system.
And we,
we intrinsically linked those rewards
and in this system to life.
And this is the only way to live and
this is the way we live because we've
always lived like this.
But if we can completely remove
ourselves from the biological process,
completely remove ourselves from the
lust and the greed and the what,
what do we become?
And is that actually a better way to
live?
Maybe it's a good question,
but.
But I,
but I think that you have to add,
you have to add another dimension to
what you said,
which is yes,
there,
there is that evolutionary notion of
reward that creates a feeling of,
for example,
safety and whatever it might be.
Right?
But I wonder also if the other reason
that we seem to have this need to get
better at something like just say the
violin or whatever it might be.
I,
I think that there's another thing that
happens to you when you get really good
at something.
When you develop this a deep skill,
I think you get a better understanding
of you.
Like you go,
you come closer to who you truly are in
your essence.
The notion that when you do something
for the sake of its own doing,
which would be considered play,
that that's how you would define
probably play.
That's when you are the most authentic
and truly yourself.
And I feel like human beings not only
having nostalgia like a built in
nostalgia to try to find who they were
originally.
But I think also it's just my general
idea that I wonder if,
because the internet is bringing us all
together and we're getting a deeper
understanding of what it is to be each
other in one way or another,
and we're going to end pretty soon if
you can download not only information
but what it's like to be joe rogan into
my brain.
Well,
if that's bringing us all together then,
then I wonder if the.
The end goal is something in the area of
deep self knowledge and deep knowledge,
deep human knowledge sort of this
creating this,
this neural net.
So we're all.
Sorry for the,
for the word one.
You know that that seems to be the two
thing that that spiritual dimension,
that thing that's hard to measure has
always existed in human beings.
We,
we somehow always want.
And I think it's where religion comes
from,
where inspiration comes from.
We seem to always want to reach beyond
ourselves.
What is that?
It's always going to be there no matter
what I was going to be there.
I think it's going to be there for
operating inside of the biological
parameters that we currently have to
operate on.
You say,
if we can get out of this,
think history will be taken away.
If what?
If?
What if they can eliminate greed,
would agree the the,
the instinct of greed can be located in
our genome and can be eliminated.
Well,
greed,
exactly.
Mighty might be valuable.
Great.
Jealousy,
might be valuable to greet also may be
great.
Also be that that primordial need to
amass as much food and as much what?
Safety and as much power so that you
stay alive.
That's the one thing we know is that
human beings across the board what love
one thing above all and that is
immortality.
Well,
what I'm thinking is a lot of our ideas,
a lot of our ideas of what was valuable
and what we want and what we need and
what is just part of life.
A lot of those ideas are only based on
the current model of human.
Exactly.
That exists when they start manipulating
shit and downloading new thoughts in
your mind and do you want to go like
fucking meditate in a in an ashram for
10 years and sweep up and just home all
day in the corner,
or how about they just press a button
and shoot some shit straightened to your
brain and you could read minds.
You're going to take that.
You're going to take like instant
enlightenment.
You're going to take the ability to
transcend all of our biological
impulses,
including the dumb ones like self doubt
and fear and hate and jealousy like
this.
Exactly,
exactly.
Yeah.
That's the real thing.
Even if you can even like ray kurzweil
who created this sort of movement of
curve,
chris wireless,
the notion that,
all right,
we all say we're going to die.
We all know human beings have one goal.
It's to stay alive forever.
It's why we do great work and we want it
to live on.
We have children.
That's why we were so attached to our
children,
if not necessarily true,
because we do because we enjoy it.
While we're doing that to 100 percent of
you have kids thinking going to live on,
I don't think you make.
You don't make a painting.
No.
This will go on forever.
You have this idea in your head and you
wanna express yourself.
Yeah,
I,
I agree with you on that,
but I just think that overall,
if you looked at the general overall
over arching sort of desire,
a need in a human being,
it's probably we all want to live
forever.
We don't want to die.
I think it's just a fear of death,
desire,
follow this.
Uh,
so if,
if we can download our essence,
if I could download everything that's in
your brain,
your memories and your paradigm,
your paradigm or whatever the words are
a.
And then I could put that into a
computer,
a or a robot.
Then you kind of keep living forever in
a way.
Right?
So what does that say about when you
change,
like whatever you are,
if they download you and put you in a
computer,
they're going to have all your flaws,
or is it going to be filled with all
your insecurities going to be?
Is it going to be a liar,
imagined the computer becomes a liar.
Imagine if the computer or develops its
own insecurities and starts coming.
It changes who you are and starts going
down its own weird emotional paths.
Those are programmed in.
No,
most likely you're going to program
something where when you going to be,
they're going to probably have to
differentiate between what you are and
what you love and what your memories are
and all the negative stuff.
Well,
you,
you're part of what makes you great and
your essence,
in my opinion,
for all three of us,
and I don't know jamie well enough,
but I'm sure and his is our reaction.
It part of what a bit part of our
personalities,
in my opinion,
is a reaction to our shortcomings is the
compensation,
the measures we've taken to compensate
for our,
uh,
limitations would not just that your
experiences,
the,
the trials and tribulations,
this failures and successes,
the struggle,
the struggle defines your personality.
You show me a guy who doesn't do
anything and I'll show you a guy who
can't do anything,
right?
Yes.
Could you show me a guy who's
accomplished all or a woman who's
accomplished all sorts of things.
She can continue to accomplish things
because she knows how to get shit done,
but she's also learned how to fail and
be anyone who's successful has failed so
many times.
Well,
that's where wisdom comes from.
Wisdom is the acknowledgement not only
of your limitations,
but wisdom is also knowing what to do
with those limitations until they
fucking strap you to that machine and
shoved those fucking genius thoughts
right into your dome.
So that the same as being high though
all the time.
Isn't that the same as keeping the dmt
trip going forever?
Well,
the dmt trip removes reality as we know
it.
That's where it gets weird.
So another dinette dimension,
right?
Well,
we don't know that.
It certainly feels like that.
It could just be hallucinations.
It could all be going on in your head
and said what you get because they have
ever done you get from it.
I didn't do it on my own for no reason.
What you.
What you get from it is something that
is exactly the same.
Like someone say like maybe it's all in
your head when you trip.
Maybe it's not really happening.
Okay.
May be however,
the experience is exactly the same.
If you really are going into another
dimension,
you really are experiencing love in its
purest form and forgiveness and just 100
percent wisdom like all the bullshit and
all the flaws of your thinking and all
of the ridiculous aspects of the world
around you revealed in some wonderful
dance by gestures who are giving you the
finger and a never ending complex
geometric pattern.
Even if it's not real.
It's still the same experience.
Like if you really do go to that
dimension and you really do experience
these in incredibly enlightened being
and they really do instill upon your
wisdom and you really
do hold onto a few grains of sand that
slips through your fingers.
Hold onto a little bit of it while
you're there.
You got handfuls,
but you just hold onto a little bit.
It's still the same experiences.
Shit's real son.
Yeah.
It's a little bit like,
you know what changed?
The way I argue is that somebody said,
look,
you may think that that person's point
of view is shitty or you don't have
respect for it,
or they're there.
Maybe they're acting crazy to them.
Those feelings and emotions are very
real.
So if you start the argument by saying
like,
that's why if you look at like political
discussions as country,
it's hilarious.
You get gun rights advocates and you
have gun control.
The first thing they do is they go,
you're a gun nut,
and the other ones go,
you're a bleeding heart liberal pussy.
You start the argument there and guess
what?
You're.
There's,
there's no.
Nobody's having a conversation anymore
because you just said,
I don't like you atheists and religious
people,
religious people,
feminazis male,
mrs.
You'll never have a marriage between the
religious people who are very religious
and people who are strictly scientific
because what happens is instead of
saying that religious person is
religious and he gains inspiration and a
feeling that's very important to that
person and they're going to guard that
feeling because it makes them feel good
about the world.
If you come in as an atheist or a
scientist and say,
everything about you is bullshit.
Oh,
that's a big fairytale.
You just shut down the debate.
You just broke that bridge.
You're never gonna.
See anything.
You're not going to see that person for
who they are.
Never going to understand even if what
they're experiencing or what they
believe in,
what the faith is not real.
They still can get a tangible benefits
summit and it can impact their life and
so with Israel in a way,
isn't it?
Well,
it is something that they believe in to
the point where it benefits them and it
can create beautiful things.
Great pieces of work,
art,
whatever it might be.
That's my argument about ben carson.
Ben carson might be a wacky dude who
doesn't believe in evolution is you had
some crazy ideas,
but I like him as much as any of the
other people that are running for
president or dude,
he's not just smart dude.
One of the best neurosurgeons ever.
Okay.
Not only that,
he's really like measured and relaxed
and calm always because he never gets
too high or too emotional.
Like yelling at someone the other day,
go home and get a job.
This is gonna be our president,
go home and get a job and all the
fucking white dudes with golf shirts on.
He doesn't have his eye.
Whereas his idea,
his where his ideas for his id.
I'm hoping that once he becomes
president because it's going to become
president,
then he lets it go.
Because what ben carson said about trump
that I thought was really fascinating.
He says he's remarkably reasonable when
he's not on camera,
and so what?
Jeff ross told me that too,
because ben's endorsing them now.
Yeah.
I don't think he's a dumb guy and I
think a lot of it's worth.
I think you may see if he becomes
president,
two things.
One is he probably comes,
he's not an idea was so therefore he's
not an ideologue,
so he's going to do this.
I think he will approach everything as a
problem to be solved,
which is not a bad thing.
Secondly,
don't be surprised if he surrounds
himself with very competent,
smart people who know more than he does,
uh,
that those are the two silver silver
linings.
I can see trump,
uh,
coming to the pin holes on the.
I don't like the guy.
He breaks the system because the system
of special interest groups and the need
for this,
this,
the campaign financing.
When you get a guy like him who doesn't,
he really can't buy him.
He doesn't benefit.
He has a problem with campaign finance
reform is that sit with citizens united.
That supreme court decision giving money
to a political campaign is in the
exercise of free speech and it was
considered constitutional.
So it's very difficult to get big money
out.
But what I do think will happen,
and you're seeing it already with people
like bernie sanders and even Donald
Trump,
is that we as citizens will go,
man,
you have big,
deep pockets,
deep political pockets,
and so you must be a little corrupt.
At least I ain't voting for you when
there's transparency.
So things like crowdpac where you can go
and find exactly who's financing people
crowdpac which my friend steve hilton.
It's good thing you go and check out.
I mean they've got their website,
has all of the various campaign funds,
all the,
you know,
the people that are influencing all the
special interest groups.
Love it.
Tight move.
We got to get the fuck out of here.
Thirty five,
40.
Come see us in denver through,
through.
We flew through three.
I really did.
This is a good one.
Comedy store tonight.
Comedy store to point out that both of
you bitches peed twice.
I never got up.
Why your strong,
strong piece?
I have portrayed it from doing the show.
I drank four cups of coffee.
Sat there and a bottle of kombucha.
You're gay.
I'm not bragging.
Just probably I could hold up a lot of
March 18th.
March 19th.
It's my bed.
I say I'm bragging about my ability to
hold him piss.
It's things like a baby cam.
Logan.
Logan will be at the comedy store
tonight.
Tonight.
Feel von brent earns.
That's for a good cause,
right?
Whereas the spinal cord.
Spinal cord.
The spinal cord injury.
So come by.
How much of the money goes towards it
while we were all literally all
beautiful but mine.
I'll get mine.
You get all your money but to all your
money now just kept loving job.
We'll do it for charity.
So that's the night at 8:00.
Right.
And theo vaughn,
guy brent earns hilarious guy.
Brian count hilarious.
And I can do my best.
Um,
and that's it.
Alright,
we'll be back tomorrow with greg
fitzsimmons and also thursday night.
I'll be at the improv for greg
fitzsimmons st patrick's day
extravaganza.
We'll be talking about that tomorrow
too.
Alright.
Thank you everybody.
Love you guys.
Bye.
And 20 million downloads.