And we're live Tony Hinchcliffe.
Hello Jake. The fucking snake.
I can't believe it, man. I've got
to do this. What do you know, Joe?
Have you ever heard of that before? I've
heard it a couple of times. I've heard,
Hey Joe, I heard you shot your old lady
down a few times as well. There you go.
I gotta tell you, man, I watched a
documentary last night and it's fantastic.
I appreciate it. It is. If that
thing doesn't bring tears to you, I,
you need to go to a doctor.
You're not human man. No doubt.
That is Dallas is a fucking
Saint. He really is hard headed,
you know? Uh, without it, I'd never
made it. Yeah. Cause um, you know,
was junkies and way like a lie a
lot. You know, and alcoholics do too.
But it was a tough, tough road
man. And he guided me through it.
He's never gazing, never gave
up. And I can never think of,
I mean,
not for what he's done for me and given
me all my life back and not only my life
and my family. I got my kids back
her, they're all digging me now.
I'm a great grandfather. Would
probably be the best grand. Yeah.
Father ever as you know. I'm just
saying because it's true. Anybody,
I'll pick anybody up man.
I mean the detailing of your recovery
though and him taking you into the,
what does he call his house? That
house? The, the accountability house.
Accountability crib. Yeah. Yeah. I
mean he's a special guy. It really is.
You got to, can understand. I mean,
no man in his right mind would bring one
much less two drunks into their home.
You know,
you got to expect tragedy and there's
going to be something come bad out of
this. And uh, he was able to
hold us together, man. I mean,
there were a couple of brief,
brief moments that though that kinda
escalated and got kind of stupid, but um,
you wouldn't give up man.
Well, I got to know Dallas when
he came on the podcast and one,
one thing that you get about him is this
guy, he, he's not just about himself.
Like he is really about
helping people out.
He gets a buzz off helping people and,
which is to me is just so amazing.
And I've picked that up off of him.
I searched people out now in the crowd
that are having a hard time walking or
you see something going on or they're
overweight and you go like, man, you know,
I'm so and so and it gets me in
using the name Jake the snake.
I can talk to him. Hey,
you ever thought about um,
trying some DDP yoga man because it
works and if you've never done it,
DDP yoga is without a doubt.
The number one thing out there
for getting healthy man, it
makes your body healthy, makes your
mind healthy, you know? And uh,
for him to be out there,
he's just a soldier. Yeah.
He really pushes all day long
man. And uh, here's a guy that,
that they could be handling
in a totally different way,
but he still picks up the phone and call
somebody and thinks them for buying the
program. Yeah, the hell does that. Right.
What does that he does cause he wants
to know. And the next thing you know,
he's been on a 25 minute phone call
and they're sending him photos over the
before and then he wants to look at it
and after picturing and six months from
now, the stories, he's got a million
of them. We put success stories.
We played a video when he was in of a
gentleman who was a paratrooper. Yeah,
guy could barely walk. I mean he had
done a bunch of paratroop missions,
you know, parachuting out of
planes and landing on his knees.
His knees are destroyed, legs
are destroyed, backs destroyed.
Everything's fucked up. But he
starts out barely can stand,
barely can walk. Two canes. Yeah,
two canes. By the end of the video,
this guy's running, he's wanting,
he's doing full yoga poses and it's
these animal incremental steps,
incremental steps, but he kept
getting better, kept getting better,
kept getting better. And that is, it's
so symbolic of like your journey in life.
If you just decided to give up
and decide to just fuck the world.
I'm just going to just eat and drink
myself into olivion. You have been there.
You can talk.
I stayed there a long time man. But then
you turn it around. But that's, that's,
I fucking love that and
love stories like that.
But it's a one in a million shot man.
Unless you have a diamond
Dallas page in your corner.
Because it wasn't only about Dallas
helping me, it was the whole crew. Right.
See Dallas, you know he came up
with the idea, him and Steve,
you as a business manager,
whatever. And they said, look,
you know we're going to
bring you back through this.
We want to film the whole thing.
I'm like [inaudible] I don't know about
that cause I got burnt bad in the film
here. Walk back, you know, and they just
cut me a new one, man. They lied to me.
And anyway, it happens.
Film, this whole thing.
And at the end of it, if we put
it together and you don't like it,
we'll never go out. Really?
You're going to give me that ride.
You're going to invest this
money and this time, because we,
I stayed there for three and a half
years cause he took me that long to get
clean. That's amazing. You know,
I couldn't go in for six months.
I've done that. I can get him going
for four months. I've done that. Hell,
the time I went in for four months,
man, I'd go across the stage.
You get my diploma so to speak,
from finishing this course and
being in rehab for four months,
I go out the other side, pick up
a pay phone and call my dealer.
He meets me outside the damn door, man
with big rock, you know, in a stim.
Thank you. I made it, but that's
the insanity. The disease.
The disease will let you sit in a place
for three or four months and not touch.
You won't even come knocking on your
door because it knows right now you're
locked into your going to do this,
but it's over there doing pushups in
the corner, man, waiting on your ass.
Soon as you get away from
these idiots over here,
they're teaching you bad habits. Jake. A,
I'm going to get you where you need to
be and that was the thing of being there
for that long period of time. What was
the feeling like when you did slip up?
Because you [inaudible] a couple of
times. Four or five times. I did. Yeah.
It was horrible.
I wanted to die because not only
did I feel like I let myself down,
I'll blow him down and that really sucked
because here's a guy is opened up his
wallet and said, you can live with
me. Don't worry about your damn bills.
I'll take care of them. Excuse me.
Oh damn damn sure in now. You know,
you don't have to talk twice
to me about this scramble.
Y'all moving in with your brother.
If you go pay all my bills, man,
when I get healthy. But I never even
thought it was going to take three years.
Wow. Let's see. He would take, you know,
like if he had to go do a con
or go do some music, you know,
go to go do a movie or something. He
had people that work for DVP yoga,
specifically Garrett and in a
young kid named Dylan, who I,
I really got the kid messed up, you know,
because he had to share a room with
me. I don't wear clothes. Okay.
And I guess he looked kind
of freaky. You know, here's,
here's this old wrestler that I idolized
for years and I've seen his junk,
all gray hair and everything,
but his joke is seeing the snake and the
bags gently bent over picking something
up right there by his bed. I had no idea
my asshole was in his mouth. But uh,
yeah, Dylan, he lived through some
horrible things and Karen did too.
But Dallas always made sure I've
taken care of, you know, he,
whatever he had to do, the first thing
you had to do was take care of Jake.
And he put me first. I
didn't expect that we would.
The solidarity in the, the
comradery that you guys all have,
you razor Ramon as well, when you
guys are all in that house together,
like the experiences that you guys
shared working together and then still in
life, you know, you guys have
a bond that's very, very, it's,
it's very hard for most people. Yeah.
You know, it's like, it's
like guys that are, you know,
in the service together and there's
just something that becomes,
they become brothers and one man.
No. And that with Dallas, you know,
the thing about him was he's
never went down that addiction,
that addiction road.
I used to run nightclubs but he never
became an alcoholic. He's a freak.
Piss on him. Screw him. You've
got a better car than I did. Okay.
I get that then I like my
cars. My cards now are awesome.
My life is so good too.
To go from hell cause
that's where I was at man.
You have no idea what it's like to wake
up and be angry that you woke up cause
you didn't want you want,
you want it to be over.
And there's been so many years that were
like that for me that I wouldn't go out
shopping and this was 3:00 AM I
didn't want anybody to see me.
Cause I had gotten to the point that I
hated myself so much and I'm begging God
to die. Uh, when I would
hear another wrestler died,
I'd get angry at God and curse him for
not taking me. Instead, when Piper died,
we were just talking about Rodney
before the show started. Man,
I was so pissed off that he got to go
before I did. And that's just wrong,
man. I mean, even when I tried to
Odie a couple of times, you know,
really tried, I took a
hundred value. Jesus Christ,
10 milligram value woke up and all
I've done is PUCO myself and I said,
what a fucking loser you are. You can't
even die, right? You're a piece of shit.
What kind of mind says that
it's, mine is given up.
The torture that people put themselves
through an addict, people will get,
he had the wrong idea about this
shit, man. They think, yeah,
they're out there getting fucked up,
man. They're happy. No, we're not. No,
we're not happy. We're
not enjoying getting high.
I quit enjoying getting high 30 years ago,
but the problem was I couldn't
live without it. I mean,
I would feel like my heart was
going to burst. I couldn't breathe.
I was scared to go anywhere.
Shit. It was horrible.
Was it everything or anything?
Like what, what, what was drawn?
What was pulling you, what drug
or what out? What was it? Booze.
For me it was more, I was
at more everything. I,
I'm lucky I didn't get to
in the heroin, you know,
I probably wouldn't have beat that one,
but uh, yeah I would because that's,
this is what I'm meant to
be doing right now, but to,
to go through 25, 30
years of doing cocaine,
it's amazing. You know,
I think Vince McMahon for affording me
my addiction because without it I'd be in
prison somewhere cause I would have
killed somebody from my drug. No,
I without a doubt I would've,
you know, knifed him, whatever,
man you got that guys got an eight ball
watch this done life meant nothing to
me, man. And it gets to a point where
you put yourself in such a dark hole.
There is no light, none at all.
And it takes somebody that special.
You couldn't have sent me to
rehab right then and worked. God,
I'd have been out in the in minutes
even when Dallas offered me to,
to pay the whole trip. And uh,
you'll move in with him with feed
you the best damn food on the planet.
We're going to get you healthy real to
get the bullshit out of your system.
I'm like, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm going to last about a week now
because I knew me and I'm like, dude,
if I'm making a week, I'm
going to be doing good.
Cause it's a time I couldn't
do 24 hours not doing cocaine.
Wow. If you wanted me to get up out
of bed, pray me some go. Okay. Wow.
That's where I was at
because life was too ugly
to want to go out there.
When did it start?
Did it start when you pro wrestling
career started or was it going on before
then? No, uh, the cocaine and alcohol,
alcohol was always there. I mean I
started drinking when I was 11 or 12.
Whoa. My, uh, grandfather was an alcoholic
drug addict slash drug addict cause
it started with an oil field accident.
He got his legs crushed and he
refused to have his legs cut off.
So he stayed in the for 18
months. Well, back in the 1920s,
the way that they fixed you was let
it heal then rebreak it, you know,
that's what they did.
They didn't put Mars and metal
in there to straighten it out.
They'd let it heal. Then they'd
rebreak break in a different way. Oh.
And they kept him a deck,
kept him on morphine for year and
a half was the end of the year.
And had they patted him
on the back. See ya,
he had a little itch going
out there, didn't he? Yeah,
he could walk. So it worked.
But it took your mind until
you're hooked up on morphine,
which back then it wasn't like today
you can get on any corner. Right.
He went to alcohol. I remember in
the 60s, which is 40 years later,
they not trusted him to come
to the doctor's office. Well,
they didn't trust him to take the
pill, the pill, the pill being,
Oh my God, what's it called?
Keep me from drinking, um,
and abuse, you know,
he'd taken an abuse bill,
you're not going to drink
about, he said he did. I mean,
I've drank on an abuse when it's been
like two days since I'd had the pill and I
have a drink or you have no idea how
scary that shit is because immediately you
start throwing up and you start
pissing and shitting your pants.
It happens that quick.
And then you have to start with the
sweats and all this and you'll wind up on
the floor doing the heebie jeebies man,
that sounds strong and abuse as well.
They didn't even trust him to
take the pill. They said, no, no.
You take a taxi to the doctor's office
and we'll give you a shot cause we know
you're not gonna take that bill.
So he'd do that every morning and he'd
go outside and get in the same taxi.
And because we lived in a dry County,
he would take that same taxi over to the
next County and get a fifth of whiskey
trained yet before he got home.
Now the rest of his day spent
shitty in Buchanan. Wow.
But yet tomorrow he don't do the same
thing. Oh my God, that's the hell.
You know, I was doing the, you
know, doing the Coke and stuff. Man,
I'm hating myself the whole time I do it.
I'm not getting high anymore
and I can't put it down.
I can't turn away from it.
Cause there's hope in that.
What's the hope for no more pain?
So just that it numbed no more shame.
That's what it numbed me is a shame.
You know? Shame is something
you put on yourself. You know,
you can't shame me, man.
I have to do it myself.
The man who was their man in, because
I'd went through some ugly shit as a kid,
being sexually molested, my
sister being molested too.
And then my sister kidnapped and murdered
and we got all these things thrown in
there and I was hating myself. I
didn't protect my sister better,
you know, and just, you know, life
happens. What do you do with it?
That's one of the things that
Dallas preaches, you know, is about,
he got all this stuff out there,
man, he's going to come at you.
I just want you to do with his accounts.
You know, you don't deflect it. No,
you bring it to you, you chew it
up, you spit it out, he slept,
sift through the bullshit and you go
on, there's something I couldn't do
cause then you got personal
with me and I would lock down.
I'd shut up cause that's
how I handle things.
I just didn't talk about it. When
you've been sexually molested,
I'm very is no good moment
and that screwed my head
up and it still messes with
my head. I desperately,
desperately want that.
A relationship with a
woman. No true relationship.
Finally it's 63 what goes.
I did have relationships before that I
was constantly sabotaging them because I
didn't trust women.
That goes, the last one,
she raped me and beat me and threatened
me and told her she had my dad killed me
because you know,
my dad was seven foot and weighed 425
pounds so he could get the job done.
But I just wanted my
dad to be proud of me.
So all these things are factoring in,
keeping them quiet while the wife beats
me and has me do her and then beats me
afterwards. Dude, sex ain't sex.
If you're doing it like that,
they're called rape and then shit
screws your head up for life.
Now what do you do with it? Well,
is it cute? I hid that shit man.
I stuffed it away. I didn't talk
about that. Are you kidding me?
When do you remember the first time
talking about it to a high school buddy of
mine? He said you're so fucking lucky man.
You're your stepmother's
still fucking hot. She was on,
she's 22 years old cause my father's
a child molester for Christ's sake.
Of course she was hot but it wasn't
hot to me because that's my mom.
No. And then the BDS afterwards
was, that fucking confuses you.
You got all this shit going man.
So you start looking for a way out.
And for me as a kid,
my grandfather would get drunk and forget
where he hit his liquor cause he had
to hide it from her grandmother
cause she knew what he was,
she had dealt with it for 50 years.
So every time she found a bottle on
the farm, she break it and that's it.
So you'd hide it, the chicken
house, different places.
Well me and my buddies
from across the street,
we'd go out and find it getting
12 years old, 11 years old.
Then we got smart and started selling
into the other neighborhood. Kids,
you know, make a buck. That was my
beginning of drinking man. And uh,
you know, as time goes on man,
you start smoking weed, uh,
in the pills. What else is next?
Cause I'm still not forgetting,
I'm still remembering this shit.
And you go out and you'd try to have
a good time with people and then you
realize something's different than
you because drugs it put you to sleep.
Wake me up, downers.
Wake me up. The counsel. I wired
you gave me five Percocet, brother.
I'll break a case of beer
and dance all night for you.
Really go out and have three or four
wrestling matches. Let's go to the ed.
If I take it this way,
whenever miss my neck up in 89
[inaudible] here's a guitar.
When I wanted to go to the gym, my
regimen was to wake up, go downstairs,
starts coffee maker, take two
men, 10 milligram Percocet,
don't them my mouth. Chew him up
and wash him down with the coffee,
then hit the gym. Jesus. I loved
it because I was on fire man.
Plus the purchase that made me a little
gnarly made me want to punch it in.
Really? So you get a good
workout and from Percocet,
that's how screwed up my wiring is.
That is so you don't get any drug and
they'll tell you their wirings fluff.
Yeah. Things that make you go to sleep.
Wake me up. Things that wake you up,
put me to sleep. So the,
the pain of pro-wrestling,
which is probably one of the most brutal
professions that a person can embark
and write. And think about all the days
that you were on the road. All the many,
many matches,
all that physical pain probably
justified the drugs even more.
I didn't even care. He didn't care
about the pattern. I, I don't, I,
I felt no pain. I wrestled
none afterwards. No,
I was wrestling in guy in
Louisiana. Ernie the cat lad.
You remember him playing for
the AFL San Diego chargers.
He's in the hall of fame, put ball
in wrestling. He was six, nine,
three 50 bad-ass on the
pitch, man, you know,
but back then they had chatbox and he had
like 15 knee surgeries and that was in
his career.
But we were wrestling and my bone came
out of my arm compound fracture and he
goes, kid your arm. I'm like, yeah, I
see it. Just come on. And he's like,
why get away from me and I,
I'm trying to get to him and he starts
puking on me like, mother fucker,
you puking on me. You're our man.
You're on his fucking bone, dude.
I'm like, your daughter. Come
on us, finished the match.
Fuck you. I'm getting out already, man.
He could pick up a bunch
of shit, man. Yeah.
You finish off your opponent by
having him hernia. Yeah. Yeah. Wow.
Is nasty smelling shit to me. But I was
fine. They got back in the locker room.
No, I was sitting there
and I was, I was saying,
this is a strange thing
that I blow on the bone.
It feels cold not blowing
that boom. Oh wow. Whoa.
15 minutes later I'm in
the shower. Holy fuck.
Oh the fuck bone. You felt
it. The adrenaline's gone.
You've been in the ring and you know what
that's like. The adrenaline is going,
nothing hurts. It feels good. Invite.
You know what I would've thought that
you would look at the bone and go, Ooh,
I've got to handle this now. Why
did you wrestle fucked up? No, no.
Wrestled straight, no straight part
much. You know, and I been going through,
uh, withdrawals at the time, but uh, no,
I didn't drink or either shit before,
before match and I didn't like it,
but I did it that way because it's my,
and, uh,
my thing is another wrestler
to take care of my opponent.
I noticed that after if I have like
a fun set or something like that.
Doing standup comedy that I
like to have. Like if it went,
if I tried something new
and it w it went extra good,
I like to have an extra
drink or two that night.
Would it be like that for you in
wrestling? Would you get more messed up?
It was like Madison square garden or
no, I'm just kidding.
Until I went to sleep because sleep
was such a premium back then. You know,
back in, back in my day, we were wrestling
seven days a week, seven days a week.
Well except for Saturday and Sunday.
Then we wrestled twice on Saturday,
twice on Sunday. Jesus,
like you might do the LA Coliseum at two
o'clock in the rental car and drive to
San Diego scene the seven o'clock wow.
The next day you might be an Omaha at two
o'clock then you'd be in Des Moines at
seven o'clock and you're driving all
this in between. You know, you fly,
you drive, boom. Well with me,
it made it even worse cause I got to
drag that fucking snake everywhere.
80 pound box of shit, right?
Be like having to carry this
around with a bad back over there.
Hey folks out there. Pray for
him, man, he's over there.
Who and moving back here.
He's making fun of young Jamie
and Jamie is a minor in frack.
It's very difficult to talk about
injuries when you were on changes.
Totally threw me under the bus. So
let me, before when I first got here,
he's like, I pulled my back the other day,
but I don't want to mention
it in front of Jake the snake,
cause it's embarrassing. He should be
embarrassed towards man. He tore his man,
giant sneezed in toward his band jars.