Three.
Two,
one.
Happy New Year.
Tom Pub.
Yeah.
Happy you get.
Thank you for the gift.
You're welcome.
I've always wanted one of these.
It's amazing.
Really.
It is.
I got two things that I really don't
want today.
One was herpes.
No yeezys
you'll love him.
Jamie thinks,
oh love.
He got me here and I said,
take these bags.
These are yours.
Do you keep him?
Hey,
he came back and brought me the right
size.
He had cysts first.
He brought me to the Bronx.
What's wrong with them?
That they're fucking preposterous.
Let me see him.
Your um,
Brendan Chop.
They're the perfect thing because
they're in,
this looks like something from the
nineties yeah,
like some kind of shoe from the 90s.
Now what level of outrage would there be
if I started wearing these to run the
mountains?
What if they were really comfortable and
you like them?
I know what's going on.
So you think that if I put him on,
I would all of a sudden love them and I
would get it.
Those are street.
Maybe.
Are Those for the street?
Does he have like a bird?
He'll worthy of wake up extra hook in
the back of the heel?
Yeah.
Like why is it go like a normal heel?
Like here's a normal heels,
right?
Those flat flush,
it's flat.
It's like goes out at an angle on those
two.
That does too.
Is the boost.
It's the style of shoe.
It's the bottom.
It's what it's of the Adidas.
Is it the style or is it the uh,
the shape?
Is it the style or is it the feel that
you really like the feel?
Bubba won't both.
Honestly both.
But these were really comfortable shoes.
The boost is super comfortable.
Is this a adidas made shoe?
Is that,
yep.
Oh,
so didas makes,
yeah.
And there's just no adidas logo on
there.
So it's hard to tell that he's starting
to like them starting to warm up while I
weird how they have this like military
style number.
Yup.
Thing on the side.
Like some fucking Korean missile
quit.
Is there,
I couldn't tell you what it stands for.
I've seen it.
Multiple things.
It could just be supply or could you
come up?
It could be an acronym for something.
I don't know.
Yeah,
they look like they're from the nineties
enjoy them.
Thank you sir.
Why an accordion?
Like what is,
are you a monkey?
No,
the guy that has the accordion,
the monkey dance monkey dance is,
I love the sound of the accordion and I
just,
uh,
I saw it and I just wanted to bring
something to the new studio.
I like how you have a lot of weird shit
here.
And this is weird that somebody loved
this sound so much that they decided
let's make an instrument out of it.
Yeah.
Are there like real complicated ones?
Those are like big to people play them
and orchestras and shit.
No,
I don't think they made it into the
orchestra and so it's never been like a
really respected piece of musical
instrument design at Co.
New Orleans Buckwheat,
Zydeco.
You ever hear that?
Sure.
Yeah.
Back like,
Oh papa poke a lot of Polish.
Booka Zam fear master of the Pan Flute.
Of course.
What happened to that poor bastard?
Like he had a whole marketing team
behind me.
Like,
dude,
no one's done this.
No one's done this,
but we're going to do this.
You can master the Pan Flute,
Dvds,
cds,
vhs tapes.
We're going to sell it all.
There's literally no competition.
There's nothing you can do that your Zam
Fair.
He's the Tony Hawk of the Pan Flute,
right and areas.
Give me some volume with the sky.
Beautiful music,
radio and TV.
Look at the chest hair and the change.
What?
Gold chain around the world.
20 million records.
What is
Zam fear that he will get book Tom in
his magnificent,
he looks like a guy that works on the
jelly.
That is
very forgettable sound.
It's a recorder.
It's for like window of the things you
learn when you're in fourth grade and
they teach them music.
Yeah,
that goofy flu like thing.
I never,
I never paid attention to the recorder
because they gave me the recorder and
I'll go,
well how come I don't see this bands
the fuck outta here.
I'm not going to spend some time
learning an instrument that no one place
you had to though need to carry it in
your sock.
You remember you had to put it in your
sock.
They didn't even have cases.
They just give you a good get old tube
sock from your dad and put it in there
he go be cancer.
Right.
No,
makes a case for the fucking recorder.
Now you have to put in your dad's sock
and it didn't make any sense either that
it was,
oh,
he's got it tall,
but he plays a flute.
Right?
Well it said Pan flute when I typed it
in,
but,
oh,
flute rock.
Well,
he's a bad motherfucker.
Yeah.
JETHRO tull.
He's winning crazy looking dude.
He looks like he lives in a hollowed out
tree.
Right?
He does.
Oh my God.
Scurries out when you walk by on the
trail.
I know.
Has anybody else figured out how to use
the flute in rock and roll music besides
Jethro Tull?
I haven't spent some flute.
There's been a
but not like him right now where it's
not worth hard of it.
The lead.
He's the lead guy.
Isn't that weird how like a band will
come along and they'll just figure out
how to do something that no one's
figured out.
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly.
Now we're going to do this.
Yeah,
we're just going to throw a flute in the
mix and then everybody's like,
okay,
I like it.
Hey,
it kind of works.
Should we get a flute?
I was,
uh,
I was doing this show last weekend and
this guy had an oboe.
He was like the in San Francisco.
He's one of the,
like the oboist in the world and he's
playing,
this instrument is very melancholy,
just beautiful.
But it really
was occurring to me like,
why,
who built this,
who thought this sound was so important
when they decided we're going to make an
instrument so we can re recreate this
feeling and this sound for all those
instruments and the stuff.
She gave me a pen and a paper and told
me to draw an Oba,
I'd be fucked.
Yeah.
I,
it was not what I thought it was.
I was like,
Oh,
before he pulled up a picture of it,
let me think of what it looks like.
Well,
I want to think,
and I'm thinking of a trombone,
I'm thinking of a thing,
but it's definitely not.
That was way bigger.
Yeah.
We'll kind of pull it up.
Let me see what the elbow is straight
out.
It looks like a flute.
Yeah,
it's straight.
It looks almost like a clarinet.
Clarinet.
That's what I'm thinking.
Not a flute that looks more clarinet was
pretty bad ass
oboe and pop that's in waterworld not
done moving.
Right.
That's an example of world's a terrible
moving water.
World's a terrible movie,
but they have a damn good themed show at
universal.
It's very good.
It's really good.
But it's amazing.
It's like nobody watched that fucking
movie and it was a gigantic flop,
but still in 2018 they put on a Jamun
live show kicks ass waterworld so
everybody's like,
wait,
wait.
What the fuck is this based on?
This is some sort of dystopian world
where like everybody is drowning,
right?
Yeah.
The water is risen to the top of
everything.
And then these baddies and good people
and and then this done people that are
risking their lives is explosions of
file flying jet skis.
I went to see what my salary is.
Great.
We got fucking drenched by the way.
If you're going to go to see this good
seats don't go during the cold that it
doesn't matter.
Good or bad seats,
man,
that shit goes up into the 15th 16th
rose.
I look at that.
That is a good production value.
It's great cause it's like a play,
but it's fun to watch.
That's it's very enjoyable.
That's all Kevin Costner had to do was
just do this.
He didn't have to make that check.
Antic movie.
That movie just hopper.
That movie was a,
I had some friends that worked on it.
There were stunt people and they were
just talking about the amount of money
that like whenever you feel me,
anything involving water,
like you're fine.
Everything is insanely expensive.
Right?
Camera's here.
It's all under water,
but he's water.
It's wet,
everything's wet.
It's like,
yeah,
it was crazy and it sucked.
Aw,
it did suck.
I tried to watch it actually.
Basically fucking terrible movie.
It's a cool idea that like the seas have
risen and there you've got to either
have to live on this boat.
Yeah.
But like he's in like a fight for his
life and shit and he's going to fucking
cigar in his mouth and they love those
movies.
Yeah.
And they have weird like comedic guys
and then Dennis Hopper is kind of looks
cool,
but it's kind of weird.
I see like these guys are about to shoot
him and he's got a cigar in his mouth.
Like,
look,
everybody's dirty,
but it's wet out.
It's like,
it's like the water.
You fuck dirty,
stinky bitch.
Just there's water everywhere.
That's a great point.
Why are they filthy places a tub?
It's because it's a rip off of Mad Max.
Yeah.
Max.
The dystopian Mad Max movie was made at
a place with no fucking water here in
the desert and a reason to be dirty.
Fucking plagiarists just jump in the
water.
He's fighting for his life and he's got
a cigar in his mouth.
Spit the Cigarro Yukon.
You're going to get shot.
Jesus.
Jesus Christ.
I did like that boat though.
That was a pretty cool boat that he
could control.
The whole thing is kind of,
it's bad,
but it's not nearly as bad as the
postman.
The Post Osman was another dystopian
movie that was a colossal failure
starring Kevin Costner.
But Kevin Costner,
who I'm not,
I'm not shitting on Kevin Costner,
was huge.
Kevin Costner Fan.
I love that guy.
But he,
he was in a couple of stinkers to kind
of shark tanked him for a long time.
The Postman from 1997 is one of the
worst in the history of bad.
So bad that I will get high and watch it
occasionally just for the fucking Yuck.
I mean,
never even seen this one.
Oh yeah.
In the field.
That's CBT.
Ribisi whatever's,
yeah,
whatever.
Giovanni Ribisi you get kicked in the
head there and um,
in this movie,
like who is he?
Kevin Costner has to deliver the
letters.
It's like this big in the future.
There's no PA post office anymore,
so he's gotta be like the post man,
but they're trying to kill them book.
They're going to fucking get him.
He's got to run across the bridge.
He's like,
I've got lettuce.
It's got the mail.
What are you doing the fuck you doing
with these letters?
I'll go to bring them.
It's important.
We communicate.
It's just all because of dances with
wolves was so good.
And I tried to like re do it.
No,
this is not nothing like dances with
wolves.
Get them back in the woods.
I think this is based on a novel,
if I remember correctly.
See if that movie the postman is based
on a novel.
I think it's based on a science fixture
or future fiction novel.
If I remember correctly.
I never even heard of that movie.
Oh,
it's so bad.
Great.
Yeah,
it is man at a book.
Okay.
Yeah.
So yeah,
it's,
it's crazy.
It's about,
I think it might be like post nuclear
war or something.
Who's trying to stop them?
People don't like mail.
Guess what year it takes place in hope.
Let me guess.
that's great.
The other day we were looking at,
um,
uh,
blade runner.
Blade runner is 2019.
Oh really?
Original one was 2019.
Wow.
Next year flying cars robusto off.
Not so well.
We might make it a book loan fast.
The thing is whatever does happen will
happen so fast.
We'll wish for something like blade
runner where there's some sort of
intermediate world where the technology
and the people coexist,
right?
Because we're just to be,
yeah,
we're just
going to be plugged into it like the
Matrix.
It's just going to be slow and then all
of a sudden it's going to be just,
if you go back to 1994 which is
essentially when most people started
logging on to,
you've got mail.
Yeah.
That's 24 years ago.
Okay.
That's not a long time nets at tiny
brief little moment in human history and
in 24 years,
the world's radically changed the way it
gets information completely.
Completely right now,
go 24 years from now,
it's probably going to be accelerated 10
fold from that point.
The moment artificial intelligence
happens to moment,
autonomous cars started happening.
The moment the boring company actually
has tunnels going through the bottom of
La and all of it's going to be fucking
bananas.
I had a guy from a tesla energy at my
house yesterday and uh,
they bought solar city,
so it's no longer this solar company.
They're now tesla energy,
Tesla energies now of a car,
the trucks,
the batteries,
the power wall generators and the solar
and this,
this guy comes in like he's from the
future.
He is dressed like a future guy in this
like black fitted thing,
these kind of like those shoes but in
white and he just kind of comes in.
He's really sharp and like really clear
and just goes through the thing.
He's probably an adderall and her thing
is that,
uh,
they're going to put a solar on the
roofs and then you have your power wall.
You're still connected to the grid
because you've got to,
they have to for political reasons,
but their whole thing,
they want to create tesla neighborhoods
where everybody starts feeding off of
each other.
They're just completely autonomous.
Tesla neighborhoods.
That's a good point.
Where you just said though about that
it's politically motivated that the
reason why they have to stay on the
grid,
it's the only reason.
It's the only way.
They don't need it,
but in order to get things passed,
they can like have that big battery and
you're in your house.
They wouldn't let that happen unless,
because that really would mean that
you're completely cut off.
And the politicians just like,
no,
that's not happening.
Isn't that crazy?
Because
that's a more efficient way to do it.
You're getting the power from the sun.
It's cleaner,
it's better for everybody.
And yet they're still like,
no,
we want to keep these jobs,
keep the system.
We want to slow down progress.
We know we don't want everybody to have
to radically readjust.
Yeah.
And the,
and the costs are for energy or just
going up so quickly that in like three
years,
what you pay in southern California,
he's almost going to double.
So it's three years.
Really?
Yeah.
Wow.
Cause there's a,
they have to reach benchmarks by 2020
did you see what Tesla did in Puerto
Rico?
No,
it do.
I remember him saying he was going to do
this and then there was no news coverage
about it,
but their whole infrastructure was wiped
out during the hurricane.
Like completely that old electric shot.
He had all these power walls,
they're giant batteries about the size
of the flag and they just store all of
this energy like a year's worth of
energy you can store.
And they were about to be shipped to
customers here in the u s who bought
them,
who want them in their house.
You know his backup generators basically
they're supposed to ship in January.
They're not shipping now until April
because he decided these people in
Puerto Rico need energy,
took all of those power walls,
ship them to Puerto Rico and has built
this new infrastructure for Puerto Rico.
Hospitals are running on Tesla,
schools are running on Tesla.
Uh,
neighborhoods are running on it.
And it was this quiet little story like
nobody,
this is a kick ass company that went in
and literally is saving this island.
No Sin.
Fuck Oprah.
We need Elan Musk to run for president.
Tired of people saying Oprah the last
couple of days have been hell for crazy.
I love Oprah.
Don't get me wrong.
I think she's a wonderful woman.
I think she's a powerful force of good
and positive energy.
But Jane,
no,
Eli.
But she also brought us doctor Oz and
the secret we have to remember with this
lady has done,
she has to be held accountable.
I forgive her,
but I mean cut the shit.
The secret is a particularly egregious
offense.
What you don't,
you just,
if you don't believe,
you don't believe who believe.
I want to be rich.
I just am rich.
I imagine myself flying.
I can fly.
I will beat my wings until I take off
what's up.
Yeah,
it was one of the more confused I want
us to disturb,
disturbing.
But it was confusing when that was
taking hold with people.
When I had friends that were telling me
that the secret is real and that they
imagine they were going to fulfill these
childhood dreams that they had had about
whatever,
being a fucking astronaut,
whatever it would be.
And there's a couple people that I knew,
they were trying to tell me that the
secret was going to be the thing and
that they had a vision board and they
had photographs.
They put pictures up of the things that
they want,
like them in front of large crowds and
shit.
And I'm like,
Oh boy,
this is the front of large crowds.
This is so not how it works.
Yeah.
But there is a kernel of it that works.
Yup.
Causative thinking,
you wanting something,
you envisioning it,
but that's a little component and just
how you live your life.
It's not just sitting in your,
you know what it's like and wishing it.
So
it's like saying,
I am going to be a bodybuilder because I
drink water.
Yeah.
It's like,
no,
you okay.
Ah Geez.
Where do I start?
You?
You should drink water and it will help
you if you want to be a bodybuilder.
But I've talked to all these
bodybuilders and the one thing they have
in common is all drank water.
And they knew that if they drank water,
they would be giant.
There'd be giant,
huge people.
It's all you've got to go.
Okay,
but did they also perform reps to
failure?
Did they also take steroids?
Did they also do these exercises?
Squats,
dead lifts,
curls,
you know,
did they do all that stuff too?
Yes,
but that but the water,
why aren't you believe her?
This is what it's like cause cause
they're saying like no,
these people,
they believe that they can do these
things.
Yeah.
They,
they,
they had this vision and they focus on
this vision and it came to fruition.
Yeah.
You know what they also did?
They also busted their fucking ass and
got lucky and we're in a business or
career that they had some talent in and
figured out what that career is and
figured out how to navigate the very
weird waters of social interaction and
skill acquisition and success and
failure and learn from your failure and
luck.
Yeah.
That's a big problem is you're dealing
with complete sampling bias.
You're,
you're only asking people that are in
the mansions.
Tom Papa,
how did you do it?
I mean I see you here,
you have this place.
It's as big as the White House.
You have a giant lawn.
Did judge always know this was going to
be your reality?
I saw it and I just put it on my vision
board.
Obviously it doesn't stick around and
be,
didn't it became a fad because all these
people,
well at some point that's take the board
down.
Well and unfortunately some people died
because they,
um,
there was a story I was reading about
oprah unfortunately where this woman had
terminal cancer and she,
she had stage three breast cancer and
just decided that through the secret she
was going to imagine herself a healthy
person and you know,
she eventually want them dying from it
because she,
she didn't get treatment.
The IAA I know,
I mean she,
she stopped traditional.
She stopped conventional medical
treatment.
But what part of,
so how far do you go with positive
thinking?
Cause I see you as a fellow that,
uh,
has goals and I would think positive
thinking plays into your life.
So what does that even mean?
Really?
Like do I think positive?
I,
I think in a positive way.
I try to be positive.
I try,
but when you're trying to accomplish
something,
whether you're trying to,
you know,
get better at something,
like say if you're playing a game,
like what if let's like golf,
like say take up golf and you want to be
a really good golfer.
Like you start thinking about golf,
like how do I get better at golf?
You have to learn if to pay attention to
instructional videos,
you have to maybe seek out coaching.
You have to play some games and lose,
you have to choke under pressure.
You have to examine the mental game.
Like what is wrong with my mental
process when I approach a shot?
What is wrong with this?
What is wrong with it?
And then become obsessed with the,
the idea of succeeding in that.
And I think that that can apply to
everything.
So yeah,
I mean I certainly believe in positive
thinking,
but this,
that was like mystic nonsense.
No,
that tips over and it discounts all the
other stuff that you have to do.
There's something to the law of
attraction.
It is,
but it is one component to this gigantic
sort of spectrum of factors that have to
be taken into consideration when you're
trying to succeed at something.
Yeah.
Positive thinking is one of them.
Yeah,
but it's also the understanding of how
to eliminate laziness,
how to discipline yourself,
how to write down goals,
how to,
how to make incremental steps towards
improvement,
how to recognize failure is not just the
end of all your hard work,
but in fact the beginning of a new
breakthrough because you understand like
how to never do this wrong,
wrong,
the wrong way again,
and the consequences of doing things
wrong.
It's like there's a lot of,
yeah,
there's a lot of factors in getting
better and succeeding at things and they
boiled it down to the easiest one,
which is dreaming.
Right,
right.
Exactly.
And that's why it's sold.
But Oprah sold it.
I mean,
she was,
she was one of the big ones,
manage.
She was fucking 50 years old at the
time.
I mean,
this is not a young woman who was
selling this.
How old is open now?
75 89 no,
she just ran a marathon in four hours.
Did she?
Really?
67 63 so we ran a marathon.
Yeah.
So let's,
let's think of when the secret came out.
I want to say that was like 2006 six
2004 2006 so 12 years ago she was so she
was 50 years old.
How the fuck did you not know when
you're 50 years old,
they're worth $1 billion that that's not
how it works.
But it's Hocus pocus.
Yeah,
it's not hocus pocus.
and to sell that to people is crazy.
And that's a book that's sold.
I think I was reading it sold somewhere
in the neighborhood of 20 million
copies.
Wow.
Is that what it tells you on?
Geez,
that's crazy.
Well,
you want an easy way.
You want something that's easy.
Everybody wants,
you're in trouble,
you're feeling whatever and they want
something to come.
Something come and help me.
I mean that's where religion comes from.
It's just please,
there's that thing inside of us is like,
ah,
I want to believe if I believe,
is that enough?
It is a lot like that.
Yeah.
There was one of trump's spiritual
advisors was,
uh,
he's got some spiritual advisors,
some woman who was,
uh,
telling people to send her money.
There was a set,
send her money for January.
There was some,
so some whole article about it,
but it's basically essentially the same
thing.
It's like the idea is that,
what is she saying?
Donald spiritual advisor.
Paula white suggest people send her
there January salary or face
consequences from God.
Is that true?
She's attractive too.
It's interesting.
Is that true?
Yeah.
Look at her.
Pam.
I'll give you money.
What do I got to do?
What am I going to do?
Paula?
How much do you need?
I don't know if that's a good picture.
Maybe she just looks good when she's
screaming and she looks good.
But um,
yeah,
I would love for some really,
I would love for the day where there's
some real powerful spiritual,
uh,
individual who doesn't ask for money.
You will that sound who doesn't,
who?
Real power.
Powerful or spiritual individual.
It's a huckster.
I know.
That's what I mean.
Like,
it would be so great if some like,
so you listen to some people,
like I watched,
I was doing some Gig and there was this
black preacher and he was out on stage
and he's talking and it was like he's
really entertaining and he's,
and he had a couple of Nice things that
he was saying and then please send me
your money.
And that is,
looks like,
imagine if a guy showed up.
Well there is,
there's plenty of those people on
instagram who don't ask for doe.
Yeah,
they're not.
They're just trying to be okay.
Like Gary Vee for instance.
Gary v's whole thing is about hustling.
Gary v's like the anti secret.
He's hand tie the secret in,
in,
in.
You look at like what Gary Vee does.
Gary Vee is all about,
I was sick for several days,
so I was fighting some can all last
week.
Yeah,
I got it.
I got the flu,
I got the flu.
Uh,
I thought it had it.
Um,
like I left here.
so I'll,
I'll,
I'm diverting,
but let me,
let me just get back to this Gary v
thing.
But what guys,
I do want to talk colds,
those book.
So I don't know if he's the best
example.
He sells books,
but he's not asking for money.
I mean,
he's actually,
and he's actually a guy who was,
he's experienced some success as an
entrepreneur.
And I listened to people,
how do I say this without being mean?
There's a lot of people that are giving
advice online because people react well
to it because they're,
they're giving advice because when they
give advice,
people respond to it and they say,
this is amazing.
And they'll,
they'll blanket and they'll,
they'll give them positive feedback and
love,
but their advice is at least a certain
percent of it is just nonsense.
They're just talking,
right.
They're just trying to say things
they've heard before or they're trying
to somehow or another put together a
sentence that sounds like you'll get
some likes.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
There's a lot of guys,
you just got to surround yourself with
positive people to crystally.
It makes fun of those people in a
hilarious way.
He's great.
Or is it about Comedians who do it?
Oh,
just not just comedians who do it,
but just people do it.
But here's the thing.
Sometimes people will say things that
are real and are really inspirational.
Yes,
and that's great too.
It's just knowing,
knowing horseshit.
Yes.
You got to know Horse Shit.
Know a lot of people don't know where
the Horse Shit is.
This secret is horse shit.
See that's the problem.
Gary v is inspirational and
motivational.
I guarantee you there's a lot of people
out there that have done things in their
life that they might not have done
because of Gary v because he's a hustler
because he's really got a lot of energy
and he's like,
just fucking put down your phone.
You know,
go out there and get things done.
Sleep an hour less sleep,
a fucking hour left.
And it'll just tell you like,
do this,
sell that,
go.
And it gives you practical advice about
how to get started and get things done.
It's like the opposite of the secret.
Is this what seminars?
I'm sure Gary does shows at that.
It sounds like Tony Robbins,
he just sort of,
but he's more like,
I mean Tony Robbins,
he younger,
more energetic hustler character
crystal.
He lives in the same play.
This give you some volume.
Pardon?
It says you could do anything you put
your mind to accept.
Most things is perseverance.
He's got an ego to shut down the town,
stopping,
remaining focused,
never quitting.
So funny.
Meanwhile he does all those things as
well.
This is from his last special.
Meanwhile it works really funny.
The funny thing is Chris actually does
work hard.
I literally,
well yeah,
that's,
that's the kind of,
yeah.
I mean Kevin Hart now has moved into
that realm.
He has so many people listen to them and
all of a sudden they just,
you know,
he's,
I love him.
He's hilarious.
He's a really good guy.
I've known him for a long time,
but now he's got so many followers and
he has so many people listening that
he's starting to do that.
It's,
he's not just telling jokes,
he's doing crunches and telling you that
you've got to believe in.
And I said to my daughter,
my daughter was like,
is he a comedian?
She asked if she was showing the thing.
I said,
yeah,
he's really funny.
I saw that this is a different thing.
I said,
do you think I can make videos that just
tell people to live better with David
like that?
No,
Dad.
Well,
I'm guilty of that too.
I've done that too,
but if it's just,
there's things that you know that you've
experienced and that you've done,
you want people to know about,
but it's not everything I say.
The problem with some people k all day,
you're inspiring people.
That's all you fucking do,
right?
All you do,
right.
All you do is give out advice.
Yeah,
that's it.
What do you do?
Do you just advice give no,
there's it.
There's a thing about,
there's a thing about Kevin,
there's a thing about you that you
watched somebody,
they're interesting.
You like them and they're getting shit
done and you're like,
I'll take advice from this guy.
I will.
I'll,
I'll hear what he has to say.
There is that element.
It's when it becomes bullshit.
Bullshit.
When it becomes,
no,
you have to listen to me because I have
all the answers,
right.
And God talks to me and that kind of
stuff.
Well,
there's songs that,
there's love songs that you hear that
hit you
and you go,
wow.
Like why is that?
Why does that resonate so,
so much?
Why is it so profound?
And then there's songs we were like,
shut this stupid fucking nonsense down.
Right?
Yeah.
It's like there's this pop musicy
plastic hollow,
empty bullshit that also has a lot of
those same words in it,
right?
Like what is the difference?
And that millions of people like,
yeah,
but they're dumb as fuck.
Well that's,
but it's the same thing.
You've got all these people that is
still buy into the Horse Shit.
Yeah.
There is a big herd of people out there
that you can,
if you just start doing,
if Chris just stopping and convenient
started posting videos like that all the
time.
Oh,
he would kick out.
Just get followers.
Well,
if he really wanted to,
if deleah really wanted to be an
inspirational guy,
he's a handsome fella.
He's got a great voice.
He's got a lot of energy.
He's,
he's,
you know,
he's dynamic.
He could do that.
It.
Yep.
He could do something like that if you
want me to.
Kevin,
the same thing.
The thing is though,
Chris can do other things.
A lot of these inspirational fucks,
they really can't do things right.
They're not doing anything right.
They're not producing any great works.
They're not,
they're not doing any interesting art.
They're not creating any interesting
music.
They're not making any funny comedy.
What they're doing is just trying to
like,
you know,
there's a lot of people out there that
don't think they can do it,
but you can.
It's in you.
It's a flower that must be watered with
the love of the gods and like,
yeah,
oh,
you can't,
there's so many of them.
They're overwhelming.
They are,
but so their business is not getting
money from you necessarily.
Their business is in you paying
attention to them and then as you pay
attention to them and to their social
media,
their social media page grows and then
they can do like speeches at these.
Have you seen no self help conferences?
Some people go on boats,
they get,
they go go on a cruise ship and the ship
is just giving different kinds of
advice.
Yeah.
Peaches and everyone get in here,
we're going to have a session and see
and he,
you know,
and it does help people,
like there are people that they do help.
Yes,
true.
Some of it works.
I mean if you're,
if you're lost and you're just,
you don't know what's going on and
you're been a loser for a while and you
take a couple of his tips.
Yeah.
And you start working and writing shit
down and go in and have some self
confidence,
it can help your life.
But there's some of these guys that all
they're doing is just trying to like
figure out a way to give people advice
when they've never done shit themselves.
Yeah.
And that did not,
it's not worth listening to,
but yet they're there and they're there,
but it's the way it,
but is that any worse than an open miker
right.
Is it,
I mean,
if someone now,
but I want to do is,
I'm sorry if someone says,
what I want to do is I want to become a
motivational speaker.
I want to really help people.
I want to really touch people,
but right now I kinda suck at it.
It's like you don't,
you don't just start out as Tony
Robbins.
No,
that's right.
Yeah.
You're just starting and it's like a
trainer.
It's like a bright boxing trainers never
really want to fight.
It could just be like an old guy who's
just some of those guys.
Most of them in fact a former fighters.
But are they?
Yeah.
It's very rare that someone's a boxing
tracking sales guy.
What?
Freddie Roach.
Yeah.
It was a good boxer.
He's a famous professional.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
He's got Parkinson's because of it.
Oh really?
Yeah.
He's got trauma related Parkinson's
disease from his time in the,
in the ring Angelo Dundee.
He fought,
um,
uh,
shit.
Uh,
what the fuck's his day name?
The Puerto Rican guy.
Hagler Hector Camacho.
Camacho.
Yeah.
He fought Camacho.
He fought a lot like big name guys.
Wow.
He,
he was a big deal.
Like in terms of like journeymen
fighters.
Freddie,
Freddie Roach was and his,
his brother Pepper Roach is also a known
guy in the world of boxing.
Yeah.
Freddie was legit legit guy.
He was a legit pro.
Are there trainers that just train
people that they just became trainers
and boxers?
They definitely have some experience.
Usually they have some amateur fights or
they,
it's very,
very rare that someone becomes,
I respected boxing trainer without
having any competition experience just
doesn't seem to make any sense.
Some of them,
they realize early on that they're
better at coaching than they are
competing.
Whether it's because of physical
dynamics or whether it's uh,
you know,
they just don't like getting hit,
they know the limits or some people just
are really good at teaching others.
Yeah,
that's a,
that's a weird thing too.
And the world of Jujitsu,
it's very common because a,
in Jujitsu there's a lot of people that
get really good at understanding and um,
like one of the guys,
it's going to be here next week.
John Danaher is world famous for it.
Yeah.
He's very famous for being like one of
the greatest coaches in Jujitsu of all
time,
but as boy,
as far as I know,
very little experience in terms of
actual competition.
Oh yeah.
But he's as he's kosher.
Yeah.
Unparalleled.
He's like universally regarded as one of
the great coaches alive.
That's impressive.
Yeah.
I got my 12 year old,
a uh,
a heavy bag Christmas.
Yeah.
You should,
uh,
just wrapping her hands.
He's got gloves.
Teach.
Get someone to teach her how to do it
correctly.
Yeah.
My Buddy Matt is coming over to,
oh,
he's a trainer.
He worked on their Angelo Dundee for
awhile and open his own gym.
My good buddy Matt Bay Monte and he's
going to come my teacher on Thursday.
That's good.
Yeah,
it's pretty cool.
It's a good way to get out aggression
too.
That's why he got it for,
she would just get angry.
She'd be doing schoolwork and be like,
this is bullshit.
And I'm like,
and she's like,
I want to be,
I want to punch something.
She started like punching pillows once
in a while.
So now we got her a bag.
You're,
what,
how much of you is Italian?
Um,
all of it's Italian except
for my one grandfather was German.
Angry people.
The Germans or the talented 10th Bolt
Sicilian Italian Sicilian is the
dominant part is a little temporary.
People are jeans.
Yeah.
Fucking feed knuckle sandwiches to
people.
Really tough.
She's just like this beautiful 12 year
old girl.
Just wants to punch my sister's that way
too.
I stopped dating Italian girls when I
was 21 last time.
Girl I dated.
He took a swing at me.
I was like,
that.
I'm good.
Did you?
Yeah.
Did you deserve it?
Nope.
But I saw it coming.
I was like,
this is,
I can't believe this is happening.
She's actually trying to punch me.
She's going to punch where they just can
make a bunch of me.
Like I saw her shoulder pull back.
I'm like,
there's no way this is actually
happening.
Yeah.
No.
It gets fighting at the time.
So I was used to people punching me.
So as she's pulling her shoulder back
and Mike,
this camp,
we were really happening.
I don't believe this is happening.
Oh my God,
it's happening.
It's not content.
It's funny,
but I think she just wanted attention.
I don't think she actually,
I think she's pretty sure that it wasn't
going to land.
You know that if she threw a punch at me
that I was just going to,
cause it's just really wanted to hurt
me.
She fucking hit me when I wasn't
looking.
You know?
That's what people do.
They don't just look right at you and
you motherfucker.
But then again,
when people are in the height of some
sort of fucking Sicilian love rage.
Right,
exactly.
You don't want to mess with that
screaming and the yelling and the
throwing things around.
That's also very east coast.
Oh yeah.
I've talked about this ad Nauseum,
but I really believe that that's the
echoes of those fucking barbarians that
came over on boats from Europe.
Yeah.
And didn't even know what America looked
like.
No.
Did he knew to have a photo to look at
and these fucking cave people pulled up
on rafts and start a fucking,
immediately they started baking bread,
rolling up pasta bagging.
Hey,
I got bread for both of you.
You brought up.
Oh,
you too.
You have to lows.
You're an animal,
Tom.
Papa God amongst man.
There you go.
This is for you.
Do you,
do you need,
I've never given you the bread.
I never give Jamie the brand.
I'm like he's probably gonna appreciate
it.
How long will this stay?
Good.
Because Sunday's my cheat day.
Sunday.
Yeah,
you'll be good.
And where are we or should I just use
days?
Pawn my cheat day or move it to today.
If you keep it in paper,
it'll wait.
We'll have to toast it out to eat it
today is the best way to eat it today or
tomorrow?
Actually tomorrow.
Thursday.
Better.
Yeah.
Why is it better?
Cause it just came out.
Ooh.
So it's not good right away.
It is.
It's if you want that warm.
It is,
but really it's,
it gets even better a day after,
you know,
that's the case with tuna.
I did not know that.
I always thought that if you bought
Sushi,
you're supposed to get fresh Sushi and
just pulled it out of the wire.
They're going to slice it up for you
right now.
But no.
If you go to like a real master Sushi
maker,
that Sushi sits.
Oh,
really?
Yeah.
For how long?
Fucking week.
Sometimes.
I know just the tutor.
I watched some documentary on some Sushi
master.
Oh,
the hero?
No,
it wasn't that.
It wasn't that guy,
but that guy.
That's a great one too.
It's really good.
I was like,
somebody's,
what we're talking about is a g row was
that I tased him hero or zero euro.
Jiro or a euro.
How do you say it though?
Do you know?
But it's spelled with a j.
Let's say Jiro.
Jiro dreams of Sushi.
I was like,
I'm not going to watch a fucking
documentary on a Chi.
Makes Sushi fish a fish to the rice up.
You're done,
dude.
Yeah.
Okay.
Give me some edamame.
Miami would kick this.
He started saying like some complicated
casserole that you're putting together,
you know?
Yeah,
but wow.
You Watch it and go,
oh,
okay.
I'm ignorant.
This guy's an artist.
Yeah.
There's way more to this.
Oh my God.
His whole soul is in it and it comes
out.
Yeah.
Amazing.
He's tiny ass little restaurant.
That's about the size of this room.
No interest in getting bigger.
Nope,
no franchising.
Nope.
Just doing this so well that people are
going to,
are going to come.
There's something to that man.
Oh,
it's the best.
I'm doing one thing really well.
Like God,
it's the best.
There's something,
there's definitely something to that.
There's something to especially like
the,
the mindset of every day trying to learn
how to make that egg dish perfect.
That one egg dish that one guy said he'd
worked on for a year.
It's crazy.
A fucking year.
And the eggs,
all that just completely doing it over
and over and over.
My bread thing is not I,
it's probably like you're both thing,
the bread thing.
It's like you do just start to like
focus on this one thing and trying to do
it well and you just start to get,
it becomes a part of you.
You're starting to put yourself into it.
It's not just making bread,
it's there.
It is a practice.
It is something that for a couple of
years I've just kind of gone down that
wormhole.
Yeah,
it's a good thing.
The worm.
Yeah.
Doing that one thing I really,
I feel like that sometimes with with
standup it's like we've all these other
things that are always going on and
pulling us in different directions and
stuff and it's like if you could just
focus purely on just if that was the
only,
if you weren't taking any phone calls on
anything else,
you weren't podcasts and you weren't
writing scripts,
you weren't appearing on whatever,
like would that make a difference?
Like would you be yes and no because I
think that we're,
it requires a certain amount of
dedication and a certain amount of time
on stage,
but I think it also requires certain
amount of living.
I think you need to do other things and
although podcasting seems like a job and
a distraction,
one thing it is unquestionably is
exploration.
It's an exploration of ideas,
right?
At an unprecedented level.
Like you're,
you're exploring ideas without looking
at your phone,
without talk.
You just,
you and I are talking to three hours.
When does that ever happen in life?
Yeah.
No it doesn't.
There's a lot of ideas that I come up
with through stand up or in standup that
came out of podcasts.
Oh,
sure.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Your mind's active.
Yeah.
So I think that that writing similar
writings,
oh yeah.
Same kind of a thing.
Yeah.
But I also think doing stuff is
important too.
Not just the actual sit down talking
part of your podcast,
but actually going places,
being active.
You have to experience things.
You have to watch documentaries.
You have to go to a museum,
you have to go see things.
He got to go talk to people.
You've got to go on adventures.
Got To go travel.
It's filling up the,
well,
yeah.
This,
you have to think of your brain almost
like your crossfit,
not crossfit.
Uh,
what's that?
What's that word?
Where you a
cross training?
I guess that's what I'm looking for when
you're doing a bunch of different kinds
of multitasking that will,
no,
no.
Different types of athletic,
athletic activities that will enhance
your sport if you play hockey,
right.
You don't just do hockey.
You also are involved in the box jumps.
You're doing a lot of,
uh,
you know,
sprinting up hill,
it's a good way to look at it.
Yeah.
These all these things enhance this one
activity and it's not just all you have
to do is just skate all day and you'll
become the best skater while you may be,
or you could get better at the motions
of skating by strengthening your legs
with weightlifting or doing this and you
can accelerate your curve by doing yoga
or you could,
you know,
I think that that there's something to
that with comedy,
at least for,
yeah,
no,
I agree.
I mean,
when I'm really actively writing other
stuff,
whether it's scripts or whatever,
uh,
my writing for standup improves does.
Yeah.
And reading,
by the way,
reading,
writing stuff,
it all feeds the act.
When you,
when you then shift your focus over
here,
back to the act,
you're better because of that stuff.
But I do sometimes think like the Sushi
guy,
like,
but what if the output was only geared
towards that?
The input I get doing all that stuff.
But would there be a difference?
Maybe.
I mean,
maybe there's something to that.
I don't know.
I don't know anybody who does that way
though.
Well,
maybe at him.
Yeah.
But Regan plays golf and drinks and does
a lot of other shit,
but he's not creating other art.
He's not writing scripts.
He's not,
he also doesn't.
Right,
right,
right.
He writes like cutting his head and then
it goes on stage and works on stuff.
Right?
Yeah.
Which I'm torn on.
I mean,
I know it's,
it's a very effective,
some people do it amazingly well and
that's how they've created incredible
works of art.
But I never give that advice.
Whenever anyone asks me,
I say,
you should do both.
You should write down things and you
should write on a computer.
You should.
Right.
Or however you like to write,
but you should also fuck around on
stage.
You should do both.
Yeah.
That's what I think.
No,
I do too.
I can't just show up on stage and hope
it's going to happen.
Well,
here's some ideas that I've had that
I'll like literally like have in my car
and then I'll bounce them around by
myself a little bit and not having ever
written them down.
I'll go onstage and then it'll just
catch fire and it will become a bit,
and there's some bits that have made it
to specials that I've never even written
down.
I just knew how to do them because I did
them a bunch of times.
And most of them,
not though,
most of them not,
or at least I always feel like I'll
bring an idea up on stage that hasn't
been written down yet.
There's something there,
there's something going on,
but then I bring it back to the shop and
we'll play with it.
And then,
then it becomes this back and forth.
Yeah.
Like,
here's what one example,
this is a bit that I,
I bounced around,
I was thinking about in the car and then
I brought it onto stage in a completed
form and it never really changed.
It's a bit about,
uh,
big foot.
I said,
here's what you don't find.
When you go looking for bigfoot black
people,
like you're more likely to find big
foot.
Then you are black people looking for
bigfoot and just fine hordes of
unfuckable white dudes out camping.
That's what she fine.
That's,
that's how it goes.
Looking for bigfoot.
You're not,
you don't find it's not African American
pastime and that that bit came out in
the car.
I made myself laugh and then it never
changed.
It just became that.
I don't think I ever wrote it down
anywhere.
Hated it into my 2014 comedy central
special.
That's a little,
but that's rare.
Those are the rare ones.
It is rare,
but man,
it'd be nice if they were all came that
way.
Yeah.
It's been a few.
They're usually,
for some reason they're one liners to
like that.
He's so funny.
It's just complete.
Yeah.
Some of them are just,
they just formed themselves complete.
It's just a bowser best too.
When you makes you laugh.
Yeah,
like there's things that you've just
thinking your head.
Yeah.
That's pretty funny.
There's a funny thing and then you bring
it up on stage and it becomes really
funny,
but when it really just truly makes you
laugh,
then you,
it's such a,
that's great.
Yeah,
it is great.
When there's
thing that he just clicks to the point
where you just start giggling,
get the fuck out of here.
Yeah.
Those are my favorite kind of jokes
keep.
Yeah,
because it's,
that's what,
that's why you started making people
laugh as a kid in the first place was
just having fun.
And sometimes as an adult you've got all
this other stuff in your head.
It's like you do have to kind of remind
yourself,
this is fun.
This is silly shit.
They should be giggle enjoyable,
you know?
Yeah.
It should be.
Yeah,
it should be.
Sometimes it can be,
feel like,
you know,
because it out of writing,
the other stuff that does come out of
writing,
writing can be a grind.
Writing is insular.
It's by yourself.
You're just in there alone doing,
it's not this joyful place.
Most of the time you're not,
you're not writing like,
but it's not painful.
So painful.
But it's,
but it is a practice that is different
than just being with your buddies.
Talking about big foot.
Yes.
Yeah.
No.
Yeah,
that's,
those are the fun ones,
right?
The big foot ones are the ones that come
out of nowhere with no effort and they
kill and like,
I got this for free.
It's like got some crazy scape or the
not worried about damaging cars and work
on it for a hundred years.
Yeah.
No writing's not painful,
but there is a thing,
there is a mental part where you,
if you're,
if you're ever like put it down for a
while and don't do it,
it's like you gotta get your head back
into the space of doing it.
That could be a little painful.
It's that hard.
I don't know.
It is,
but I don't know if you ever read,
um,
Steven Pressfield's book the war of art.
No,
it's excellent.
It's so good that I bought stacks of it
and I used to hand it out to people on
the podcast.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Because I think most people like when
you say it,
like if someone says like what's the
difference between guys who get things
done and guys who go don't get things
done.
Yeah,
this sounds so stupid simple.
But the people that get things done do
things.
You actually do it.
They sit down and do it and there's
something about the people that don't
get things done that stops them from
doing that.
Like what is it?
And pressfield calls it resistance.
And what he says is that you have to,
you have to overcome resistance because
that's where professionals do you sit
down because you,
you have affirmed that you are a pro and
you sit down and you go over what you
are going to do.
This is what I do.
I A professional I've,
right,
right.
And I'm going to sit down and I'm going
to write and I'm going to summon the
Muse and the Muse,
any,
whether the muse is a real thing or not
and he treats it as it's as it's a real
thing.
And the concept is that you are going to
summon this thing that you call upon to
endow you with creativity and that doing
the work by doing the work.
Yeah.
And then that overcoming this resistance
is the war of art and um,
yeah,
that's what is the resistance then?
That's the question.
It's my negative thoughts really.
What's,
it's not just negative thoughts.
It's resisting work.
It's,
it's not negative in this.
It's like,
it's weird.
You're like,
something's po stopping you from
succeeding.
Something stopping you from,
from pushing forward and putting down
those ideas
you want the easy,
you want to just sit on the couch.
Like in my office,
I have a couch and I have a desk and the
couch,
I said,
you know,
nothing gets done.
Nothing gets done on the couch.
Really.
It's,
it's,
it's about sitting there.
There was this great a quote from this
Israeli writer who I,
every time I'd say the quote I say,
I always forget what his name was and I
should know it because he used the
quotes so often,
but he says that writing and the job of
being a writer is the same as being a
shopkeeper and it's your job to go and
open the shop every day and some days
nothing happens.
Some day you're just sitting in the shop
like an idiot behind the desk and
nobody's there and then some days the
shop is buzzing with action and activity
and people in and out and stuff is
happening.
But all of those days when it's really
busy and active does not happen unless
you opened the shop every day.
It's such an easy way for my brain to
kind of think of it.
That's a brilliant way of putting it.
Just go and sit down at the place where
you do the work and start doing the
work.
He may not be great.
That's not up to you.
If it's going to be great,
it's up to you whether or not you sit
down and start working.
Have you ever,
I read Stephen King's on writing.
Yeah,
that's great.
That was a good one.
Those are my two go to books when I'm
feeling like I need something to
recharge.
Jan would be a good one to go back to.
And you know,
I read that one like a long time ago and
uh,
his just thing of you just like what
you're saying,
you just have to do it.
You just have to do,
right.
Yeah.
I mean there's,
there's days that I'll go and I'll write
for fucking hours and literally get
nothing out of it.
There's nothing there.
Nothing,
nothing.
It's all bullshit and then nothing.
And if you judge yourself by that,
you'd go like,
Hey,
I'm a fucking terrible writer.
Yeah.
Stink.
And then one day you'll just sit down
and then you have your next 10 minutes.
You're like,
oh boy,
there's something here.
I got here,
I got something here.
I got it.
Sparks.
Yeah,
because you showed up.
Speaking of sparks.
Did you hear about this fucking bird
that they found that starts fires?
No.
They found a hawk that picks up burning
embers and sticks that are on fire and s
flies them across rivers and creeks to
start the fires on the other side so
that it could force a game animals to
run away.
Wow.
Brilliant.
Took of this.
Birds of prey are starting fires,
deliberately kites and foulk.
I didn't know kite was a bird.
Kites and Falcons are intentionally
dropping smoldering twigs to smoke out
mice and insects in Australia.
Jesus Christ.
Geez.
Louise.
Researchers of compile the study of
reports of wild bird spreading fires.
They believe the birds carry these
burning twigs to unburnt parts of the
Bush and the birds dropped them in a bid
to smoke out,
pray,
blah,
blah.
They also smoke three packs a day.
What does it say?
The researchers said birds.
Could you see the third force capable of
starting bushfires?
That's incredible.
There's,
it's clever.
Yeah,
there's so,
there's so irresponsible.
He's fuck,
I don't give a shit about fires and they
fly away like,
wow,
fly where fire isn't.
I got a mouse.
All neighborhoods burnt down,
but he got a mouse snacks,
cheese,
Douche bags.
Did you see that chicken that the
researchers created that accidentally
somehow or another through when they put
it together,
um,
had the face of a dinosaur.
Have you seen this?
No.
Yeah,
we'll see if you can find that on my,
it's on my twitter,
but they made,
they made chicken.
Don't know what the fuck they did.
Read it.
I briefly read the article.
I'm like these motherfuckers and then I
ran away but he got scared.
He had to face is chicken as the face of
the fucking dinosaur.
Get teeth.
It's a chicken with the dinosaurs face.
So who got the dinosaur stuff?
Pull it up.
Who got the dinosaur DNA and put it in
that oh no gross face of a dinosaur.
What?
What's earth dude?
I've been telling people forever because
of the fact that I keep chickens now.
Chickens are fucking monsters.
They are monsters.
They give good eggs though they do have
good eggs.
But we have this idea of them as being
these cute little cuddly little fluffy
things that lay eggs.
And just peck around now they're fucking
monsters.
Doesn't even pull up the,
uh,
the,
the top of the article.
Jamie go to the top of and make it
larger so I could read it there.
So,
so what it says,
blah,
blah.
Group of dinosaurs.
The idea,
I keep going,
uh,
to understand how one change the other
team has been tampering with the
molecular process,
um,
that make up a beacon chickens.
By doing so,
they've managed to create a chicken
embryo with a dinosaur likes snout and a
palette similar to that of feathered
dinosaurs like Velossa raptor.
They're making raptors.
The results are published in the journal
evolution.
The team's aim was to understand how the
bird beak evolved because the beak is
such a vital part of birds and bird
anatomy.
It's been crucial for their success to
10,000 or more.
More species occupy a wide range of
habitats and many have specialized beaks
to help them survive.
So it mess the mess with them.
The neck,
molecular makeup of the beak.
Yeah.
And he made a fucking dinosaur phase
chicken.
How long?
I'll be good when they're running
around.
That will be great when they're at the
petting zoo.
I bet they would have better.
I bet they would have better eggs
because like my chicken's eggs are
significantly better when I let them
loose and they go fuck up.
Like my,
like they'll eat mice and they'll eat
worms,
bugs,
bugs and then I'll get these dark yolks.
Like the last couple of days they've
been running around my yard all day.
So really?
Yeah.
So the exit I'll collect tonight or
tomorrow will be dark orange,
but when they're sedentary,
they're lazy.
They're just in the cage.
Um,
well they have it.
They have a very large coupe.
The coupe is right.
The coop is essentially for the 19
chicken,
seven 17 now a of them died.
chickens I have,
it's basically the size of this room.
So they all good space.
They got plenty of room to wander around
and plenty of food.
But they like when you ever see
vegetarian raise chicken and vegetables
that they don't want that.
Oh no,
that's just that.
They'll eat that if that's all you give
them.
But they won't eat,
they won't eat things like bugs.
And worms.
That's most of it.
But mice more than anything.
Mice,
they found a mouse.
They fight for it.
It's one of the few things that they
will fight for real?
Yeah.
One,
we'll grab the mouse and they will just
chase each other and try to fuck that
mouse up.
How are those eggs?
Amazing.
It's hard to tell like who's laying the
eggs.
What do you do with all the exit eggs?
This is a lot of them out to people.
You can have some new ones in bags.
Yeah,
sure.
I'll take some,
excuse me,
some eggs.
I got to meet for you to come out of
elk.
I got songs I really started to crave to
this year.
Oh yeah,
I know.
Alright.
Eh,
that's a good serve it up.
Could he for the meet?
Me and my,
my dog are so happy with the hell comes
out.
Yeah,
I showed you a picture.
Did they send you a shot of Mike?
You cooking?
I was cooking up the ground alk and the
dog is just like,
we're doing this right?
Yeah.
Grass fed butter and ground elk,
garlic salt.
It's really good.
With the eggs to and mix it up and eggs.
That's exactly what I do.
Remember.
We put it on a little bit of the sour
dough bread.
Now you're thinking,
damn,
take the sourdough.
You put a lot of butter on it.
Just use it as the base and put that on
top of it and then just cut it and eat
it.
We need a friend with a vineyard.
Ooh,
we had a friend who makes his own wine.
Yeah,
it would be great.
We live in the right state for it.
Oh,
I know.
I know a guy who does it.
You do?
Ah,
I don't know.
I never had his wine.
He gave me a bottle.
What the fuck happened to it?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
It's a buddy of mine I can drink and
he's in the real estate business.
I drank a lot of wines.
Second half of the year.
Yeah,
a lot.
Too much.
I started reading fashion time.
No,
but I'm not drinking for January.
The whole month off sober January.
My friend was,
my friend was like,
I'm just going to,
uh,
I'm not,
we went out on the second and he's like,
no,
I'm not.
I'm not drinking for the month of
January.
And I was like,
that sounds good.
I'm going to do that to not thinking.
And uh,
it's been a week and I'm like,
this is stupid.
Which makes me think maybe it's not a
bad thing.
I've never taken a whole month off since
I started drinking as a kid.
You got to do sober October.
That's the move sober October.
Yeah.
We all do it.
I dunno if everybody's going to do it
this year.
I doubt we're going to get burke do it
again.
Bert was in a part do with that frothy
panic.
What time November rolled around.
I was holy Shit.
Look in his face.
You know where he was.
Um,
he was getting his,
uh,
his jollies he was going on instagram
feeds of people that were clearly losing
their fucking mind.
Like,
oh
no,
you'd send them to me like comedians or
other fucking minds.
He'd send them like a Cha,
just just check out her instagram story.
I'm like,
you son of a bitch.
And I go there.
I'm like,
oh my God,
what have you done?
Oh,
not when I'm not drinking.
Just crazy.
Just being crazy.
It's been crazy.
There are some people out there and I
know I don't want to out them,
so I'll tell you off the air,
there are some people you find out about
their instagram story and you go,
oh,
there's a hidden little gem here online.
Instagram is such a great tell for
people.
I was going to work with this guy and I
was like,
I asked my other friend,
they said,
do you know him?
Like,
is he,
this is just a,
he's a director,
was like,
do you know this game?
And uh,
he's like,
well,
I don't want to say anything.
I'm like,
what?
She,
she's just look at his instagram.
I was like,
oh,
what a,
what an old man thing that I didn't
think to do that.
So just go on the instagram.
You're like,
oh,
there were train wreck,
train wreck.
Just seeing them posting all their
insanity inspirational stuff.
Now this was just pure bad chick
teaching you partying.
You know how to be the fully actualized
person.
I don't mean Shit.
I'm Kevin,
by the way.
I mean Kevin is he,
he's one of those guys that get shit
done.
Like he's Kevin,
Kevin Hart when I was saying like Kevin
Hart's thing.
No,
he's,
he legitimately get things done and also
legitimately gets a thrill out of
helping people get motivated.
Exactly.
He does runs where he brings hundreds of
people out running with them and say you
do like a five k and everybody yacht
show up.
I know.
And everybody will run with Kevin Hart.
He's legit.
Hey,
how far do you run when you run with
your dog?
No more than,
well,
Marshall doesn't like to,
he gets to the point of the end of the
run.
He's only a year old,
like two miles is about.
Yes,
we're,
you know,
push a pretty good pace in the hill and
the hill.
Very steep hills at two and I don't
bring any water for him.
Oh No,
no.
So at two miles,
that's all I want to push them because
at the end his fucking tongue is bright
red and he's like two miles up hills is,
that's a lot.
It's great.
He's great for the rest of the day.
Yeah.
The rest of the day he's like,
hey man,
chill best.
He's such a good dog.
Bad.
I love golden retrievers.
They're so good.
Yeah,
they are great dogs.
They're so food oriented though.
Sometimes to the point of being
annoying,
so it was my lab.
Yeah.
Labs are two,
same thing.
Just a lot of dogs are like that.
Yeah.
If they're active,
they're hungry.
Yeah.
Metabolism is quick and they want to eat
to make just yet.
The good news is they're really easy to
train with food because they love food
so much.
Just give them like little treats and
he's this dog that I,
that I have Marshall,
he's the best I've ever had as far as
like listening to sit and stay and lie
down
and stuff like that.
And when I go running with him,
I don't worry about him.
He stays close to me.
That's cool.
He runs and then I'll like,
he'll,
he's ahead of me and I go,
hey man,
slow down.
And they'll just stop and wait for me
and then I'll come up to them.
Then it'll start running again.
It's great.
I've never,
uh,
taken her off leash like that and I feel
like it'd be a blast.
The only thing I worry about is
rattlesnakes.
Yeah.
That's,
that's an issue because I don't think he
knows exactly what a rattlesnake is.
I bet the instinct would kick in if he
didn't get surprised by it.
There were the war instincts.
I'm worried about it.
The wrong ones,
which are to get clothes.
Oh,
you think and get bit,
it's think they'd be like all in ancient
Dna of hearing that rattle.
Like Ah,
three dogs that were bit by
rattlesnakes.
Oh really?
Yeah,
because they went after it.
Yeah.
One,
one of them got bit,
I brought him to the doctor and I'm
like,
I think he got bit by a rattlesnake and
the veterinarians like,
Oh,
you gonna play me as I'm going to play
the sad song.
And the veterinary,
they're fine.
He lived the,
but the veterinarian was like,
um,
everything seems okay.
Am I,
I don't know man.
I'm pretty sure the snake got him and he
goes,
well,
you know,
if,
uh,
if he's acting funny later,
let me know.
So I bring them home.
Our laters face swells up like a fucking
basketball.
It just took a while for it to kick in.
I thought I was doing the right thing by
getting him to the vet in time.
I'm like,
I'm gonna just get them there right
away.
I'm in the car,
you know,
I just beat the clock.
Yeah.
And it took a while for the venom to
like sink into his house.
It took over an hour because I was at
the mention hour.
Yeah.
Because I was at the veterinarian's
office,
um,
within,
he got bit,
I had them there within 35,
40 minutes.
And then the vet,
the vet's looking at items like,
I don't see any marks.
I don't see any blood.
There's no like clear,
uh,
he might have gotten missed or the,
the thing might not have gotten even a
minimum,
maybe got lucky.
So I take him home,
his face just like boom,
it happens.
Their face swells up.
Oh,
it's brutal.
Yeah.
And then it costs thousands of dollars.
It's very expensive.
The antivenom,
they use the antivenom.
It's really expensive just to inject
that.
It's thousands of dollars.
Yeah.
Which is really bad for people that are
poor,
you know,
if you don't have any money to pay for
that and your dog,
it's bit,
it's a fucking tremendous stress.
Oh Man.
Yeah.
Would they survive?
I mean,
if it's,
that dose was five.
Yeah.
If some dogs,
dogs don't.
Yeah.
But some dogs die from it for sure.
Uh,
it's,
it's really bad for them.
I don't have a place to run my dog like
that.
We've got like all streets around this,
so it's like,
hey,
you got to drive them somewhere,
man.
Take him to a Runyon Canyon or
something.
Can you take him off leash in those
places?
It's not.
The problem is you never know what kind
of dogs are going to run into,
or coyotes or angry moms.
Yeah,
that's true too.
Yeah.
It was a lot of people like that.
If you
can go places that are less populated,
those are the best for off-leash type
activities.
She would be so happy,
but she's a lab too sweet dogs and wants
to run and they're not,
they're not like the kind of dogs.
It's not like you're taking a press
Kenario hundred and 20 pounds.
Yeah.
Demon dog.
No,
but nothing loose because she's sweet.
Yeah.
Demon dog.
What was the name of that dog?
Presta Kenario.
He never seen my mouse there tanks.
They're these huge fucking muscular
canary.
I'm looking,
there's a,
a guy who was breeding some that I know
is making these Brenda ones.
They look so crazy.
They're like the ultimate guard dog.
Little dinosaur being the size of the
thing.
Oh,
it's like a mastiff.
Yeah.
Super aggressive.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Oh,
quick on that black one above it.
That will be that gray top [inaudible]
shoulders.
He's going to fuck you with that big
Dick.
God,
giant Horse Dickies.
Got His doggy legs.
Oh my God.
Are these are,
these are round.
Yeah,
man.
They're,
they're real.
They're not dinosaurs.
They have these like people have these.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
I know.
Some people have.
Um,
my friend mark has two of them.
Yeah,
that is scary.
So enormous dark there.
Apparently very good loyal watchdog.
So they are,
they're nice to have a family.
Well,
it's all in.
Who breeds them?
Look at the one where the dogs on a
leash.
Polen are there like a fucking,
she's filled on that thing.
Blow.
What a nightmare.
If that was chasing after you,
fuck,
fuck.
What are you doing?
A dog comes at you and it's going to
wants to bite you.
Just punch it and give him your arm.
Just giving me your arm.
No.
A dog's going to attack you if you know
for sure.
If you have the time you feed him,
your arm stabbed the shit out of him
while he's grabbing your arm.
You then nick.
Oh yeah.
Well,
if you don't have a weapon,
you're fucked.
So why don't you carry a weapon?
Should have a weapon.
Always.
I should always have a weapon.
Yes.
You never know when you get to attack.
No weapon.
Oh really?
Hi.
Hey.
I see.
I told you,
you carry out a show tack by a Goddamn
Dog.
It's a dog knife.
Never know.
Nice coyotes.
Mountain lions.
I was,
what do you do when you,
when you,
why he got put it in your bag,
your teeth like a pirate.
Damn.
Check.
Tsa Pre.
No,
I don't bring it with me when I travel.
I just opening boxes today.
I'm only kidding.
Oh,
you don't carry that all the time,
asshole.
I had open boxes.
A lot of people do.
Don't you think there's a lot of people
out there and next to you at the seven
11 that have,
uh,
and yeah,
they're carrying shit.
Oh yeah.
I know a guy who used to carry a gun on
his ankle.
He might still do it,
I don't want to say his name,
but he was the guy he used to fight for
the UFC.
He a gun on him and he's huge.
He's a giant man.
Right?
He carried a gun on his ankle.
He carried one in the small of his back.
He carried a knife in his front pocket
on both sides.
He had two knives that he carried all
the time and he carried his shoulder
holster just to go to the store.
Everywhere he went.
Everywhere he went,
he was a locked and loaded like he was
the wrong guy to fuck with in every
single possible way.
260 pounds and enormous trained black
belt.
She FC champion loaded to the hilt
carrying knives and guns all over his
persona.
Like the cool part about that,
which I always like in the movies is
when you're done with your day and
you're just unloading all that stuff on
your dresser,
you know when your client take,
have a strap on thing or that thing.
That always seems,
I love that part of being a man of just
having all the stuff you got to unload
to them.
Go to like beyond keys and y hippie like
gun machete,
others guns.
Right.
Exactly.
Cause anybody to carry brass knuckles
anymore.
Those out.
They must've made me.
Yeah,
why not?
Yeah.
It's not a thing anymore.
Not like,
I wonder if those are legal.
That was something you'd hear about when
we were kids.
Oh,
they got brass knuckles cause bugs bunny
had him.
That's the only place we were hearing
stuff with children.
You don't hear about brass knuckles at
all and the yeah.
Now words are what?
Hurt.
Get Your Aa,
get you some brass knuckles shape or her
with words.
Words are violence.
Give me some brass knuckles machine.
Yeah,
the old day Shane.
the old day.
Shane.
Why did they talk like that back then?
Train.
Cause that's the way he spoke back then.
Shea,
you had that coffee just sitting there
for longest time.
It's still hot in port.
No,
I had a bunch.
You had a little bit of it.
Yeah.
I love coffee.
You do addicted Brennan Shab told me
that he drinks 12 cups of coffee a day
and that he's been throwing up a lot
lately.
And it's because of the coffee because
all the acid in the stomach.
Yeah.
Just coffee.
Give you acid.
Is that what it does?
Yeah,
it's acidic.
putting the beans,
all that jazz.
And that fucks with your stomach.
Yeah.
If you're drinking,
how many?
1212 yeah.
It was drinking 12 cups of coffee a day.
Yeah,
that's an addiction.
Music for him,
for his stomach.
I said that's a big time.
Addiction.
Cops
can make
coffee is highly acidic and it can
stimulate the hyper section.
Secretion of gastric acid.
Caffeinated coffee has been shown to
increase the city acidity to a greater
degree than either regular coffee or
caffeine alone.
So decaffeinated coffee is more acidic
than anything,
which is caffeine and coffee.
Stimulate
gastric acid secretion and decaffeinated
coffee raises serum gastrin levels.
That's disgusting.
That back to your wine guy.
Um,
let's see.
Oh,
it's fine.
The guy that's hook up with a guy,
I do know one guy,
maynard Maynard,
maynard Keenan from tool.
He's a friend of mine.
He's actually,
he has a vineyard,
like a real vineyard in Arizona.
That's right.
It's not in calc.
He makes great one.
Oh yeah.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
Well he's an artist.
He's a weird motherfucker.
Super,
super smart guy and makes wine the same
way.
He makes music.
Like he,
they made it tool album and one of the
songs was,
was they,
they wrote a song to the FIBONACCI
sequence.
What did,
what did you just pull up the vineyard?
I do see us.
Dot.
Yeah.
Um,
he wrote a song to the FIBONACCI
sequence had been not cheesy.
A fibonacci sequence is a mathematical
sequence.
The way it works is like it goes like
zero and the next number is one.
Um,
and the next time was two and then two
plus one which is three.
And then uh,
then it keeps going like in this,
in this mathematical progression.
And that's how they had the chord
progression.
Had the chord progression link up to the
FIBONACCI sequence.
Just for fun.
It's just a fucking maniac.
But that same sort of attention to
detail and obsessing the,
you know the intricacies of things.
He's an applied that to his wine.
Amazing.
It's really good.
What's the label?
A do ceus vineyards could do see us.
Yeah.
He has an Austin Maria too.
He has a small restaurant.
Yeah.
Jeez that's crazy.
That sounds good.
Yeah I think it gave me the food that
fuck oh really guy.
Oh that's where the flu k till he told
me just got over the flu.
I'm like Oh shit head.
Cause I was hanging out with him in
Vegas and I think that's right when I
started to catch it and then I had like
a little bit of a cough and then it got
a little worse and then I really did
myself in,
in the sauna.
I crank the sauna up the 210 degrees.
Oh relations.
Uh,
apparently too high for people.
How,
how high you supposed to go?
One 76 to one nineties apparently people
like anyway to 20,
I went to,
I was at two 10 for about an hour.
Not an hour.
But how long do you stay in there to 10
for?
I was in to 10 for at least 20 minutes.
1515 minutes.
You know what?
I don't know how long I did it at two
10.
How long has that most of the day?
A bunch of times.
Um,
to get the right benefits,
you're supposed to 20 minutes at 176
degrees.
It at least twice a week is like what
they recommend.
But sometimes you can get to four times
a week.
You're a lot better.
Off,
what's the main thing it does for you?
It increases a bunch of things.
First of all,
does something called,
it makes your body produce something
called heat shock proteins,
which are the,
which radically reduce inflammation.
It's similar in a lot of ways to cold
shock proteins that you would get from a
cryogenic chamber treatments.
Uh,
but can I ask a question,
which we showed them question,
but uh,
why is inflammation,
why is anti-inflammatory?
Why,
why is it bad to be inflamed?
Well,
I mean,
I know it sounds kind of that's the root
of almost all diseases.
It is big,
big,
big cause of a lot.
Well that was one of the things about
this study.
I think it was a Norwegian study on the
song and they showed a decrease in
mortality,
a 40% decrease in mortality,
uh,
amongst all causes from people that use
the sauna,
I think three times or four times a
week.
What?
Yeah.
Meaning 40% decrease in stroke,
heart attack,
all these different various factors.
And they think that that's attributed to
the heat shock proteins.
Doctor Rhonda,
Patrick Healy.
Yeah.
She's the one who got me into it.
She's a frequent guest and the podcasts
and super genius and a San Francisco.
Yeah.
Oh,
that's cool.
Yeah.
That's nice.
The coolest.
She's very cool.
She,
we were just talking about,
she was on the Kardashians.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Jamie was telling me,
which you're talking about the
Kardashians.
That doesn't make sense to them.
How not to be inflamed.
That's great.
Your lips are inflamed.
Are you sure you're not eating anything
weird?
No aggressor and what's going on with
your butt?
Your Butt is inflamed.
It are you.
Are you guys not getting in the Sauna?
If Kim Carney ash and gotten the sauna,
she probably starts sweating like,
you know,
like when you bake something,
like if you have like a slow cook pork
roast or something like that and you see
all juicy of juice come pop in,
all the top of it,
it's putting a tray under to catch the
drippings.
Yeah.
Because you think about all squeezing
all that fat that they pull out of the
sides and then suck in and they pumped
that stuff in the butt to make the but
extra big.
And then you put that button,
the oven and that'll just get juicy.
Goody,
goody and Z.
I'll tell you what that is some good
eating is right.
Yeah.
Boil it down.
So the heat,
the heat proteins,
heat shock proteins.
Yeah.
A cyto keens help you with inflammation.
Yes.
It helps your body fight off
inflammation and so it doesn't in a
natural way,
instead of like nonsteroidal anti
inflammatories like Ibuprofen,
things along those lines,
which are really bad for your gut
health.
Really bad for you.
Like they say that Ibuprofen should be
taken rare.
Rarely if ever.
Really.
Yeah.
It's apparently terrible for your body.
Can cause strokes and it also is really
bad for your,
your gut flora.
I had a buddy,
my friend Cameron Hanes is a ultra
marathon runner.
He runs,
he's crazy.
200 plus miles and he's nutty fucking
things taking Ibuprofen on a daily
basis.
And um,
got off of it after he listened to the
Rhonda Patrick podcasts and all of his
joint pain went away and his joint pain
was literally being caused.
He thought it was being caused by all is
running.
It was being caused by his taking of the
nonsteroidal antiinflammatories which
increased his body's inflammation
levels.
Yes.
Which is crazy because it damages your
gut bacteria because it's fucking
poison.
He's taking 800 milligrams this shit
every day.
She body freaks out.
I was telling him like,
dude,
you're significantly increasing your
risk for stroke.
And I sent him all these studies and
findings on Ibuprofen.
So he stops,
he gets off of it.
All of his joint pain goes away.
No,
literally causing joint pain.
So how has your gut connected to
inflammation?
Inflammation,
which is one of the reasons why people
tell you not to eat bread.
It's why people tell you not to eat
sugar.
Refined carbohydrates cause
inflammation.
And one of the ways that cause it
through the gut leakage and what we say
inflamed.
What is inflamed?
That's a good point.
Let's
pull that up in a way that a car
describe it.
What is that?
Inflammation.
What is inflammation?
Sorry.
If you're going over style from the need
to know about inflammation,
inflammation is a defense mechanism in
the body.
The immune system recognizes damage
cells.
Oh,
these fucking cops with the pop up on
the immune system recognizes damage
cells,
irritants and pathogens.
And it begins the healing process.
When something harmful or irritating
effects,
part of your body is a biological
response to try to remove it.
The signs and symptoms of inflammation
can be uncomfortable,
but or to show that the body is trying
to heal itself.
So if you're in a constant state of
inflammation because you're constantly
taking in foods that your body is
reacting to in a very adverse way,
that is what causes a lot of diseases on
peep in people.
And it also causes your body to your
feeding certain aspects of gut bacteria,
you know,
that are just,
it's you're just not healthy.
And so you're putting,
so the body is actually the same way
they would fight a disease,
is fighting these foods that come in
exactly these medicines or whatever.
Yes.
Foreign things.
Exactly.
A big thing with food's a big thing with
alcohol.
You see people with puffy faces,
they get it like permanently pumped up
and they're all soft,
fucking inflamed,
everything's inflamed.
Gut sticks out,
their guts inflamed.
And is it yourselves?
Is it your arteries and everything?
Everything is just pull up the rest of
the things.
Just kind of go back to that often the
fluid.
Um,
yeah.
Okay.
Chronic inflammation can eventually
cause severe t several diseases and
conditions,
including some cancers and rheumatoid
arthritis,
infections,
wounds in any kind of tissue,
uh,
would not be able to heal itself without
an inflammatory response.
So inflammation is a part of the body's
immune system.
So what you're doing is you're,
you're in a constant state of damage
when you're eating shitty food.
So if you're constantly eating sugar and
drinking sodas and fucking corn syrup,
all that bullshit.
Yeah.
You're putting these weird chemicals in
your body and your body's freaking out.
So,
yeah,
this is,
they're not just making a distinction
between,
um,
inflammation that comes from like a
bruising or injury where your body's
trying to heal itself versus something
that's happening internally,
right from,
from your consumption of shitty foods.
But there's this whole crazy many
inflammatory causing foods that people
eat on a daily basis.
And we just think of it as food,
Pizza,
pizza's delicious,
right.
Fucking full of inflammation causing
bullshit.
Why?
It's uh,
well,
um,
first of cheeses,
the bread,
the bread's,
which is unfortunately what you make,
but I think that your bread is sour
dough bread,
which is different because sour dough
bread apparently has less complex
gluten's in it because,
right,
right.
Yeah.
I have friends,
I have friends that,
uh,
that,
have gluten issues that can eat my
bread,
not a to access,
but it doesn't bother them the way they
were processed bread about Islam.
There's something about sour dough bread
that ha,
it's different.
No.
Commercial Yeast,
the gluten structure is a little,
a little,
a weaker.
Yeah.
Well,
there's a great documentary that I
watched recently called what's with
wheat and it was all about how they
changed wheat,
um,
to make higher yield,
uh,
wi which w you could grow more wheat and
a shorter area and have a higher yield
and that the,
the gluten's in that wheat are much
more,
they're much more dense and complex then
the natural wheat that we used to eat
and 150 plus years ago.
Right.
This bread that you're going to eat,
it comes from this great,
um,
mill in a Utah that is pure organic
small crops.
So you won't have a problem with this.
So it's like heirloom wheat,
is that what they call it?
I don't even know.
That was a thing until maynard.
Yes.
Who told me about that is they use
heirloom wheat in his pasta and he makes
it as lost around.
Interesting.
It's easier for people to Digest.
Yeah.
It's,
you know,
it's a little more expensive and a
little harder to get,
but it's a,
it makes a difference in the flavor is
so much better.
Yeah.
Bye.
And Pasta when I rarely eat pasta,
but I do eat it.
I buy it from Italy and they have
heirloom pasta in Italy and just you
don't feel as fucking gross after you
eat it.
Yeah.
It's not like that brick that,
yeah,
that punch in the gut that just fucking
like you ate a bag of rocks.
So what is the,
so the sauna,
if you're eating all this stuff probably
help and
you're putting in there and you're the,
it would help,
but you're also dealing with your gut
biome,
right?
You're,
you're,
you're forcing your body to your eating
foods that are going to encourage the
growth of certain types of gut bacteria.
Right.
That live off of sugars and live off of,
a friend of mine got the gastro surgery,
Yo and uh,
she was diabetic and she had the gastro
thing done and her diabetes leveled out
and she said it was,
the doctor says because of the bacteria,
because the something that they did and
taking something out.
Does this make sense at all?
Yeah.
Well,
she probably had a terrible diet.
Yeah,
probably.
Which is also probably one of the
reasons why she was so big.
Right.
And you know that there's different
kinds of bacteria.
There's different types of diabetes,
right?
There's diabetes that has caused
entirely by diet and this diabetes that
is genetic and the type of diabetes that
is caused by diet is reversible.
It happens with a lot of people that
wind up going on,
you know,
calorie restricted diets.
Right.
Reduce the amount of sugar they take in.
And a Dean del Rey,
Dean del Ray was a diabetic.
Yeah,
he went to a doctor and the doctor he
was,
he had a real candy problem.
He's eating candy constantly.
Oh really?
Yeah.
It was hooked on sugar.
He talked to him now he's like sure is
the fucking devil,
man.
Yeah,
he dropped,
he dropped a lot of weight.
He dropped a lot of weight and got
really fit.
Yeah.
He looks great.
The Gym all the time now really high.
It looks very healthy.
Like Dean's never looked better now man,
I don't eat that.
Yeah,
he's like sugars,
the fucking devil,
man.
He's not wrong.
No,
he's not wrong at all.
I mean is great.
Every now and then it's like a lot of
things,
a little treat,
you know,
Tiramisu after a nice meal.
That's what it used to look like.
Wow.
Yeah.
Look,
he looks inflamed.
That face looks inflamed.
That thing right there,
it says,
people ask me,
how do I do it?
How do you not get tempted to eat sugar?
I keep photos like this around the house
to constantly remind me,
never again.
Fat Dean.
Fuck.
Sugar healthy.
See that's inspiration right there.
Yeah,
yeah.
Well,
yeah,
you've got a picture of yourself when
you're almost dying of a disease.
It's very,
very common for people to eat too much
sugar for long periods of time and then
go to a doctor and the doctor tells me,
you have diabetes.
Right?
It's very common and especially in
America.
Totally brought on just by your diet.
Yeah.
Your body's just freaking out.
You're constantly making it processed.
Sugar insulins jacked up,
spiked all the time,
and everything's fucking haywire in your
system and your body's like,
hey,
shithead.
Stopped with the skittles that's
supposed to eat like this.
You dumb fuck you lard ass.
What about intermittent fasting?
I do that.
You do?
Yeah.
I kind
of liked this idea.
I love it.
Yeah.
I eat a for 10 hours a day and some
people say you should do eight hours
every day.
16.
Yeah,
every day.
Well I take a couple of days off a week.
Jimmy Kimmel or Jimmy Kimmel did you
read?
Uh,
wouldn't eat on.
He would eat like 500 calories on Monday
and Thursday and just like real cat with
fasting basically on those days and then
eat whatever he wanted on the other
days.
And that's how,
that's how we lost all of his weight.
So for two days a week eats like have
severely restricted amount of calories
and the rest of the week you can eat
whatever he wants.
Yeah,
that seems crazy.
Doesn't it seem crazy?
He said it was,
it's a tricking your body into a
tricking your body.
And it was so the metabolism was like
kicking in and I don't know what the
specifics were,
but that's what he did when he dropped
all that weight.
He wasn't exercising and that's what he
did.
He Monday,
Mondays and Thursdays.
I wasn't exercising.
He hates it now.
He exercises and his fit that way and it
doesn't restrict his calories as much
cause he's physically doing something.
But uh,
I like the idea of not eating a day.
That whole,
when people say I hate exercise,
it's like people saying,
I hate brushing my teeth.
Like shut the fuck up.
What are you a baby?
Just meaning she's just,
I don't want to brush my teeth and hate
Aa.
It's a no,
that's back to the couch.
I got breathe heavy.
Yeah.
Eh,
he just fucking do it.
Shit you don't like to do.
It's like,
I know water.
Right.
How the fuck do you expect a jokester
come baby?
Right.
And I like it just come into my head.
Come on,
come on.
Just wait.
You wait in my head
muscles from a pill.
His name is ty,
the comedian.
Uh,
uh,
you're a crazy person.
Oh Man.
Oh Kevin Meeney the Great Kevin,
what did he die?
Oh,
I think his heart,
he was just on his laptop and in his
living room and just,
just had a hard,
yeah,
I think so.
Fuck God,
he was funny.
But he would wind up like,
you were just like a crazy person.
Right.
It's not right.
We're big pants.
Pee Fall Dude.
I saw Kevin Means
19 days funny.
Me and my friend Diane Derosa Nice.
She was a friend of mine from high
school.
Yeah.
We went to see,
um,
we went to see him at catch a rising
star in Cambridge
and this is like,
I think maybe I had done an open Mike
night or maybe I hadn't even gone on
stage yet,
but I want to see him and I paid to see
him.
It's great.
The comedy,
any crushed so hard that I could,
I could,
I was,
it was unimaginable to me.
I couldn't imagine so it could be that
funny.
So funny.
Cause he was in his prime then and it
was uh,
you know,
maybe 180,
200 seat rooms.
Yeah.
You know,
just killing ceiling pow and he's on
fire.
No escape.
He was on fire.
That's not right.
Okay.
Right.
And then I opened for him like a
caroline's when I was first starting and
just watching him just like destroy any
breaks into that coffee song.
I remember he would do the book coffee
song,
this song,
this uh,
uh,
all the coffee in Brazil or something
like that.
He just,
he's just killing talking about it and
then all of a sudden he's doing this
musical number.
Like this is a mattress.
Oh,
he just saw the coffee and all the
coffee in Brazil.
I think it's up
that he got comfortable.
He could do whatever he wanted to.
He would set spot.
There's a spot that some comedians can
hit them in the fucking bow tie.
This is first tonight.
Show them women call me.
Plucky
you'd have to see it to really,
it also,
you'd have to be there in 1988,
you know,
to realize like how crazy what he was
doing was,
it was so weird.
But he got stuck.
He got stuck.
He went from being a fucking murderer on
top of the world.
Uncle buck healing in every place.
But he got stuck with his act.
We had like the same act for the longest
time and that act like it didn't work
anymore.
Well this is cut back to what I was
talking about.
It's a bit of taking your eye off the
ball and like doing other things.
He started doing uncle buck.
He started doing some movies and the
Nino at that time,
those people weren't so conscious that
you had to keep your act alive.
You know what I mean?
And you know you take five years off the
road and then try and come back.
It's,
it's not easily done.
No.
Did you take that much time off?
I don't know.
I'm just ballparking but I mean,
you know,
his interests were other places at that
time.
He was doing tv shows and doing all that
other stuff.
It's hard.
You don't progress because you're not
just in it doing that stand up all the
time.
Well everyone was told back then in
particular that you had to do something
else.
That stand up was a vehicle that got you
to the big game and the big game was a
television show or a movie.
Like when I got news radio,
one of the producers of news radio said
to me like,
why are you still doing standup?
Yeah,
you're an actor now,
right?
Yeah,
sure.
On TV.
I was what?
Yeah.
And I remember thinking like,
Oh my God,
I got to get to a comedy club right now
for this makes any sense.
I know the fuck you talking about.
I mean,
the way we think is you do that stuff so
more people come to see your show so you
can keep doing your shows.
That's why you do that stuff.
It's not the other way around.
But they,
that generation saw it as the standup
was not something that you buy,
but also to be fair,
they didn't have theater shows and other
avenues weren't kind of carved out where
they would,
could see stand up as being a special
thing.
They were just in these hard ass clubs
doing six shows a weekend and it's true.
And they were like,
get me Outta here.
When did theater shows start kicking in
for people?
For the main,
for like just regular good comics,
not,
you know,
fairly recently.
Really?
Yeah.
Who Was it?
Who else was doing theaters before?
Like you know in those days?
Well there was Kevin meaney.
If Kevin Meeney was peaking now he would
be running off and starting to do
theater shows.
But back then it was just comedy clubs
and then television.
Yeah.
But some people did big places cause I
saw people in big places.
Like what kind of places?
Like Ah,
there was theaters,
there's definitely rock clubs.
There was some of it,
but there wasn't like an active touring.
When was the first time,
man,
I'm trying to remember the first time I
did a theater.
Not that long ago.
I bet.
Shit,
it wasn't like part of the touring
business.
I mean you had guys that were big,
they were doing it,
but it wasn't like,
you know,
you couldn't have a guy that instead of
headlining at a club could just go off
and do
another little theater.
It was different.
They were like comedy was,
you know,
it was also a slump,
like,
like all the clubs were closing
years.
20 years.
How many 15 years ago that started
happening.
Yeah.
That sounds about right.
Sounds about right lump,
right.
There was a comedy.
Yeah.
When I started in 93 the comedy had had
fallen on it.
Sas.
Oh,
you had,
you started right when it hit right at
the end of it,
because I started at the tail end of the
boom.
The boom was like 84 and when he started
in [inaudible] 88 okay.
And when I started,
it's like people like,
ah,
you started about four years to like
kid.
All right.
Hey.
Yeah.
But there was still plenty of work.
Yeah,
there's a lot.
When I shut up clubs at 93 it was over.
There were a get discouraged.
No,
cause it was good for me because all the
guys' wedding,
yeah.
Everyone was quitting.
And I was there.
I was working for free.
I wasn't looking to make money.
I was just doing it.
Yeah.
So all of a sudden I was able to just,
if you had a car and would drive the
headline or a club you could get on
stage.
Well there was also this weird attitude
that some people would have that land,
like they were getting screwed because
the work was going away.
Yeah.
Like you were getting screwed.
Like what?
And I remember thinking like,
wow,
what a way of looking
at things that as that you are
personally getting screwed.
Yeah.
Because this entire industry was
oversaturated with a bunch of hacks.
Hacks.
Yeah.
Real has someone was talking about is
there going to be a bus now?
Because there's been so much comedy out
there and stuff.
It's not a dearth of shitty comedy now.
There's a lot of comedy,
but it's a lot of good comedy that's
progressing and moving forward.
The art for a lot of booming different
voices,
there's a lot going on.
It's not,
there was a bust back then for a reason.
People had 40 minutes of material and
they just pounded people with it
relentlessly and they never wrote and
they never were traveling constantly.
It was shitty.
Yeah.
And there was a lot of these formula
guys that would go,
uh,
you know,
they would just have some fucking like
really obvious premise and they would
work at like a comedian,
say they had a way of talking him like
her comedian.
What is this mutual of Omaha's wild
kingdom playing out in my kitchen.
Yeah.
Cause you said it was really funny for a
while.
Something's happening now.
We're French comics are getting exposed
for stealing American comedy verbatim
now and,
and,
and translating to fringe like,
and there was a video that came out
today that showed Dave Chappelle and
then some French comic ripping them off,
Jerry Seinfeld and then some French
comic rick ripping them off or ripping
them off with the same hand motions.
The same doing his act in French,
just doing exact and French as if they
were the only human beings who spoke
both English and French.
This was something that we had heard
about forever from the Montreal Comedy
Festival.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Because the Montreal comedy festival,
not the people that perform there,
but we would perform in Montreal and we
would talk to guys who were comics
that's,
that spoke English and French.
Right.
And a lot of the guys that spoke French,
sometimes they would tell you they did
French shows.
Yeah,
I go,
I was,
I like,
that's weird.
Like you do French shows,
an English shows and they go,
it's interesting,
but there's,
there's a bunch of comics that are
famous only in the French speaking world
of touring comedy and they just steal
from American comics and just say their
stuff in French.
I go,
no,
there's,
oh yeah,
it's blatant.
Well,
and there's,
there's a handful of comedians that were
making a living turing,
so three years just stealing
everybody's,
I love having you here.
It is here.
I love how they steal from the biggest
guys.
So stupid.
Yeah.
I mean literally this is a whole kit
while they're getting a guy from 2004 so
this is there going,
God,
this is like a Hashtag.
Me Too.
It's hilarious.
Copied comic mix.
Yeah.
85 or 86 to 2005 well that's Gad.
Do you know him?
Yeah.
How do you know him?
He,
they call him the Jerry Seinfeld of wow.
Of a France.
Well he took that shit literally.
He's good.
He's good friends with Jerry.
Yeah.
Well stealing Jerry Shit.
Oh Man.
Yeah.
It's uh,
it's interesting.
And they're using a Hashtag copy comic
in Hashtag copy comic mix did,
this is like French speaking comedians
who don't do this.
It was like enough is enough.
You fucks and they're mad and they're
coming out with all,
yeah.
Maybe.
Maybe
there is a real thing.
I was thinking the other day,
I heard you talking with,
uh,
I think it was Neil Brennan.
Yeah.
Then you were talking about a Jannie.
Richard.
Jenny.
Yeah.
Who I love Jenny too.
One of the greats and then I was
underrated comedian of all time.
I think.
So.
Great.
But then when you listened to his stuff,
the it is very much of the time,
I think are all comedy is very much of
the time.
Sure.
It really like even our stuff from,
you know,
15 years ago,
it was of that moment.
And like you listen to Jenny and he's,
uh,
he's so funny and so,
but he's definitely have that ear.
Like if I were to try and turn my 15
year old onto to him,
it wouldn't fly.
I don't know.
I think if you,
if you made your 15 year old listen to a
steaming pile of me.
Yeah,
yeah.
15 year old boy or girl parts of it.
Girl.
Yeah.
Parts of it.
But I mean it's,
and it's not,
this isn't a knock,
I think.
No,
you're saying,
you know what I mean?
We,
it's just,
comedy is very much of the given take of
the culture and what's happening and
there's some stuff holds up and some
stuff because like,
because Richard is the first guy to do
the lobster and their tank,
uh,
sandy wasn't even,
he wasn't even,
there was a guy in Boston that was
doing,
and even before him,
oh,
really?
Named Don Galvin,
who had all Gavin hilarious bit about a
lobster and a tank.
Oh really?
Gavin's like the king.
He was,
he was a monster.
I'm a monster.
But see what happens is he breaks that,
he breaks that code like Righty,
comes up with that bit and then 15 years
later we've seen shades of it.
So then by the time my kid here is that,
it's like,
oh,
that old thing.
And they don't realize at that moment
when Don Gavin comes up with that on his
way into the club,
it's genius,
right?
Yeah,
no,
yeah,
for sure.
And there was a bunch of people had
similar premises back then.
Yeah.
You know,
was there was a bunch of bits about game
shows,
you know,
there was a bunch,
a bunch of bits.
Right.
There's a lot of different bits that
people just had their own take on these
individual things.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
Gavin,
so funny.
Oh,
he was a monster.
Yeah.
He's one of those guys that left Boston.
No.
Yeah,
Boston was a s a dirty mistress.
She fucking catch you around.
Yeah.
Crushed your dreams.
It was so good there that they stayed,
stayed and have long careers though,
right?
Yep.
But they should have been monsters.
Yeah.
Like dawn Gavin should be,
in my opinion,
he should be right up there with all the
greats.
People should know him the same way they
know Robin Williams and all these other
standup comics that are huge.
Maybe even bigger.
Such a natural,
such a natural.
So good.
Especially at the time,
oh my God.
In 88 when I first started,
Oh really?
He would show up half cocked,
drinking hand,
go on stage and just crush to the point
where you just like you couldn't,
he couldn't believe how good his timing
was.
Yeah.
And he had that,
that fucking Boston we had talking about
that Irish there right now when I
vacation I went to Puerto Rico.
I loved it.
But fucking so many Puerto Ricans,
I don't even know how they afford it.
So expensive.
And I'm a vegetarian and I hey meet and
shit.
But
it's like the timing of it was,
everything was a throwaway and the tag
was a throwaway to another tag.
You were laughing at Shit you couldn't
believe you were hearing and so
brilliant.
And then it really becomes,
you know,
there's certain stuff like I'll see like
the old,
I was watching old Jack Benny on
youtube,
like [inaudible] and some of it really
is as funny as sitcoms that are out
today.
Really?
Yes.
Some of it isn't.
It nails it,
but most of it is,
like I said,
it's,
it just kind of dates itself.
I was watching an ad for these Jackie
gleason dvds.
Jackie gleason had a show.
Yeah.
I didn't know you had a show and the
honeymooners was a part of that show.
Ah,
it was like a sketch.
Yeah.
So it was a variety show and that
they're there,
um,
playing this ad for a DVD,
for the variety show.
So my wife walks into the kitchen,
I'm watching this on TV shows,
what the fuck are you watching?
And I'm like,
look at this.
This is like a time machine.
Like you get to watch what people
thought was amazing in 1960 or whatever
this was.
Yeah.
Look at that that way.
He goes,
Jackie gleason show Jackie gleason show.
Yeah.
Look,
there's the honeymooners at the bottom.
Joe The bartender.
Wow.
Fenwick Babbitt.
Reggie Venn gleason the third.
What the fuck?
Just doing a whole bunch of character.
They called him the greatest.
He called himself the greatest CBS TV
fast.
Wow.
How weird.
Yeah.
That was his show.
Eight to nine o'clock on Saturdays
brought to you by schick smaller.
Let's see if he can find a clip it.
Oh,
the bat.
So weird to watch,
man.
They all smoked.
They were constantly smoking like while
they're on the set,
they would like light up and they're
doing their sketches and they had like a
cigarette in their hand while they're
doing sketches.
A lot of them were a sponsored by the
cigarettes.
Oh,
that makes sense.
That makes sense.
Jack Benny show,
they would stop and just start talking
about it.
Due to the nature of the rare,
rare kinescope recordings utilized in
this tape.
Picture quality will vary in comparison
to modern video technology.
However,
it becomes the historical significance
of the subject matter.
They are included.
Very nice.
Look,
this is it,
man.
This is the beginning of television
comedy.
Damn.
Look at what it was.
Looks like American scene.
Yeah.
Wow.
It's basically a poster.
You're just pushing it on a poster to
see what year this is Jamie?
52 62 62 so this is right around the
time or he was in the hustler.
Oh Man.
Was that the best?
Look at this.
Look at that giant pack of Marlboro
cigarettes.
Why?
What does she say?
But back it up a little bit so I can
hear what she said about Marlborough.
Give me some volume and back it up.
The music.
So great.
I love this stuff.
New York Shit.
Hey,
the entertainment capital of the world.
You get a lot to live with a moral rule
now in green.
I bet those cows would love to come back
and do some fucking meet two speeches.
Imagine what kind of meat to shit was
happening back then.
Those were cave people
aren't Connie,
right?
Fun Art Carney was with him.
Wow.
Played Norton Tammy's mirror and his
orchestra and a way we've got front of a
live audience.
Boy,
there was nothing to look forward to
back then.
I mean a couple of times and then before
you know it,
your wife was pregnant and you had a
bunch of kids and yeah,
just paying your bills.
Give me a goddamn laugh.
Look at this.
These gals running around.
It's just,
yeah,
you'd have a little,
uh,
this is showbiz.
I mean,
this came from,
you know,
now how you do the shit back,
but do you think Jackie gleason got to
bang any of these checks?
Absolutely.
[inaudible] 60 to [inaudible] 62 I the
greatest,
but I mean,
you probably could barely get it up.
He was chain smoking chain,
smoking,
drinking,
long,
big drinker hammered all the time.
Big Time drinker.
And by this time it's probably deep into
his forties,
right?
There's probably,
yeah.
Grossly unhealthy.
Yeah.
How Sony was.
How old do you think Jackie gleason
wasn't?
62 here he comes.
Yeah,
we have that face.
Wow.
He was the greatest,
but certainly was an original.
Oh Man.
Yeah.
Did it energy.
Fuck,
look at him.
Energy Pinky ring.
When we hear some scheduling laws
getting laughs,
he hasn't opened his mouth.
I got 38 more weeks to go.
38 weeks for this coffee is bigly.
Okay.
Thank you.
How sweet it is.
It tastes it.
Yes,
and she walks away.
We keep might not be long enough.
Probably a sponsor.
That was the joke.
Cattlemen.
We've got a long show.
We want to get it all in.
So jam I little traveling music,
any dances,
hook it back.
There was no hipaa places back then.
Wow.
This is the it all year.
You had the dance yet to sing.
You had to tell jokes,
but it's weird to watch.
So it was her.
Wouldn't you love to go back in time and
bang some hot lady from 1962
I bet it was different back then.
Yeah.
Wild.
When was birth control?
When a birth control come out?
Sixties so I feel like that's where
people changed what they are because
back then there was this mad desire.
Right.
But there was also insane consequences
if you had sex with somebody,
like,
oh,
we met him again.
You're going to get mad of a person.
Yeah,
like this,
this,
this drive,
this poll,
this cyclone of lust.
It leads you to this one person.
Ramifications,
not just ramifications,
but life changing,
life altering results in consequences.
Right.
Then the bill comes in,
you have the sexual revolution.
He was started bagging everywhere.
Weirdness.
Women were in control of their own
destiny.
Yeah,
but just w what changed what it means to
have sex.
It's we,
it became this weirdness.
It became for pleasure.
Yeah.
It wasn't just to,
yeah.
I mean it was always for pleasure,
but it's always for pleasure.
But the odds of that pleasure biting you
in the ass,
like,
and people must have just assumed you're
going to have a few babies mamas by the
time we got to a certain age.
Right.
But as a woman,
if you had a baby out of wedlock,
you were ostracized.
Yeah.
You were seen as,
you know,
bad news.
That is crazy.
Right?
Yeah.
You were seeing the guy who wasn't,
there was nothing,
no reflection on Amie.
He wasn't even in the picture.
She's just like a whore.
Fuck what a shit deal for women.
That is.
Yeah.
It's pretty bad.
But there's some people that argue that
the pill and that changing the nature of
sexual intercourse change the way women
interact with men,
which changed the way women sort of like
view themselves.
Yeah.
This is not necessarily all positive.
I was found out to be confusing argument
and well,
the,
the argument being that with,
um,
like that it's natural for a woman to be
very selective about who she had sex
with and that it's natural for a woman
to,
you know,
want a guy who's getting his shit
together and all these different factors
in place before she allows demand to
procreate with her,
but that the pill comes along and then
all of a sudden women could just have
one night stands and they could be like
the chicks from sex and the city and uh,
you know,
just bang up a storm and have no
consequences but like a guy.
Yeah.
But this led to like a deeply
unfulfilling narrative.
Never a lot of women sort of found
themselves repeating.
I said it's a very tortured conversation
because I'm not a woman because I don't
know what their actual,
yeah.
Doesn't know.
But that's also,
that also can be set of men.
I mean just that,
just that scenario,
just to have sex,
just to,
just to keep banging and have no
emotional connection.
I know guy friends,
it ended up in a very lonely place
because of that,
you know?
Well,
think of this way,
right?
If you're 20 and that's the case.
Yeah.
Everybody's like,
oh,
he's having a good time.
Right?
If you're 60 yeah.
And that's the case.
Like,
aw,
that poor bastard.
Yeah.
Well he does get hookers.
Brings him back to his mansion and it
seems to do coke and they dance.
It's like,
do you remember?
Oh,
commit.
I love the picture of a 60 year old guy
just dancing in a lonely place.
Jack Nicholson was hair all fucked up
the whole bed.
Had a delic first plan la with a robe.
Yeah.
It's so funny.
Fucking dude.
John Luca vivace.
Yeah,
that guy is hilarious.
It's great.
You know this guy is,
no,
he's in good shape.
Well,
he's,
he got rid of that Gal and got a couple
more since then,
but he's 50 years old and he's like the
super millionaire and he makes these
videos.
Oh my God.
Damn.
And Girls Dancing,
uh,
on yachts and shit.
He's like,
he's got an ankle bracelet,
Tattoo.
Like he's got writing around his ankle
that he apparently like taped over.
So then he wears like ankle bracelets to
cover the fact that he's got this weird
ankle like writing tattoos.
See that Blau old is this guy.
He's 50.
He's in great shape.
He's in pretty good shape.
Oh Dude.
Is His instagram is hilarious.
His feed is all like him dancing and
doing weird shit,
but he's got like writing all over his
body.
He's a very strange character.
This is a strange cat,
but he's become from these videos.
It's enormous.
Um,
social media,
celebrity type care.
Oh really?
Yeah.
What's his name?
John Luca.
Vivace.
John Luca Valachi party man.
He's like the most interesting man in
the world.
He's a Dj too.
He does like international DJ stuff.
So he flies around his private jet all
over the world.
And of course he does probably banging
tannins,
doing coke,
dancing,
sad existence.
But is he happy?
I don't think so.
Look at those girls.
How could you be happy?
That's the thing.
It's like
that's sad if he's 50 and not sad if
he's 20 it's this weird.
Well yeah,
it's always your own shit.
It's all your own projection,
you know?
I mean he seems like he's doing me like
he's pretty happy.
It's like he's dancing and back flips
into the water.
There it is right there.
Yeah.
She's got weird writing all over his
body.
He's also showing his dick roof thing
that yeah,
the young fellows do.
Yeah.
You show the bones.
It's not like a sound good look Dick
route.
Look,
it's so crazy.
Like I know what you're doing man.
Stop.
So like walk me through the Captain
America one click on the captain America
one this like he tries too hard
sometimes and some of them are just
really weird.
Like this one.
First of all,
look out tanny is how's,
he doesn't not,
doesn't have a skin cancer is fucking
amazing.
This
dancing like captain America,
he's got a shield and a head thing.
Wow.
6 million.
(720) 300-0840 views.
Like
it's crazy stupid.
Like so people watch that and watch any
hit movie this year.
So
there's um,
you never know what's going to hit kids.
There's this fucking show that my seven
year old loves.
Yeah.
And the show's called haters back off
and there's this girl named Miranda
something or another.
She's a youtube sensation.
Miranda sings.
Yeah.
She's a youtube sensation for doing
stuff like really badly on purpose and
pretending that she's,
you know,
she's killing it and she's got this
Netflix show that I watched with them
and it's,
the fucking show is not a bad show.
It's an interesting show.
It's weird.
It's almost like a female Napoleon
dynamite type situation,
you know?
But she's talented.
But my daughter who's seven loves it and
she does a Miranda impression
thing.
Hilarious about like whatever.
She's nailed it.
Split some of the shows,
like she had this one about being famous
and about like refreshing.
I constantly refreshing her page to find
out how many likes and thumbs up and
thumbs down.
She goes.
Super depressing.
Oh really?
She was crying,
her mother screaming at her,
telling her how selfish she is and the
whole thing is like,
it was really weird.
She just lives in studio city.
It's just like a actress in the valley.
She was balling out of control.
Now she out everywhere.
She does live shows what kind of live
show.
She comes out and sings like Miranda got
all these young girls just pack the
place.
Yeah.
There's weird is weird money in these
things.
She's funny.
She's,
she's very like,
that's very like question marks kind of
old school.
He has his big cartoon lips,
you know,
she puts the lipstick all the way around
the limb on the outside of the lips.
Yeah.
It's um,
yeah.
My kids were imitating her for awhile.
5 million instagram followers.
It's pictures of spaghetti in her budget
stuff.
It's so weird and her making weird
faces.
You guys,
you guys.
But meanwhile she's nailing it with
seven year olds because really a seven
year old,
she was sick from school yesterday.
She watched it all day.
She fucking loves it.
I was on the tonight show once with a
miley cyrus.
This was like,
I dunno,
eight years ago or something.
And she's so famous.
She,
the point where she was just completely
huge,
you know,
and I uh,
my kids came along because they wanted
to meet her and my kids were little.
And uh,
I was like,
wow,
she's really nailing it.
She's like huge and show business and
stuff.
And then my kids come back,
we take a picture and she's like,
yeah,
okay.
Yeah.
And she had to like squat down to take
pictures with these two little people.
I was like,
that's the price he has to pay.
What ticket for a whole day he'll be
squatting down and taking pictures with
little people.
It's bad for the lower back.
All the squatting and posing.
We were talking about,
um,
the other,
by the way,
a bunch of people got mad that cause we
were,
we were talking about that Logan Paul
Guy who had taken a photo or videos with
dead people,
the math side,
the way we were discussing the Logan
Paul thing,
people were saying,
I defended him.
I don't think I defended him.
Did I?
I don't think I did.
I don't remember.
We were high as fuck.
It was me and a red band wearing NASA
outfits.
Don't take it seriously by the way.
And uh,
I read into it more.
I didn't know exactly what he did,
but I run into more,
apparently he was mocking the body's
like there's people's,
like their hands were bloated and blue
and he was making fun of it all.
And so he's a bad guy apparently the
super cut of like everything he did and
he did a bunch of other things on top of
that.
Apparently it's this thing and aware of,
well he's a creep.
He's trying to be outrageous,
trying to get attention.
Totally.
And it was working.
He's got a ton of people.
This is the same thing though,
right?
It's like these people that you're like,
what?
What did they do?
How do they have,
he's got what you find.
He's got how many millions of this and
that and know exactly that the guy's
brother.
Cause the other one who lives next to a
friend of mine bought a $7 million
house,
20 years old,
but I $7 million house.
Yeah.
Kill calabasas killing it.
No,
he's one of those people that love him
and hate him equally.
He has.
But even the people that hate him still
have to see what he's doing.
It's like that kind of thing.
Yeah.
It's super confusing.
It's celebrity.
It's just that so that,
you know,
and he's outrageous I guess.
I don't know anything about them.
It's also just access like everyone has
access to youtube.
So what youtube is now is like a
television show that you keep in your
pocket.
Yeah.
You can just constantly,
yeah,
they're like,
there's a video that I posted yesterday
of a poor bastard.
This fucking guy raised a squirrel that
he kinda the cute little squarely on the
rehabilitated it.
And they got the little squirrel,
squirrel.
We're gonna,
everything's gonna be fine.
He's like putting it back into nature.
It's time.
It's about time.
Little Guy.
And he puts a little squirrel on the
tree and he's like,
you just,
you go back your way.
Good luck where you live now.
And he's got the squirrel on the tree
for all of 15 seconds and the cat comes
along and Jackson with ridiculous speed.
I'm gonna hear the volume.
This is my favorite part.
It's the screaming.
Here we go.
Oh,
that cat,
that cat was on that fucker so fast.
But cat climbs up.
The tree,
grabs him and just takes off.
Just ran with him in his mouth.
And that's like you.
It's more than you do in that with a
cat.
Like if you had a cat in your mouth,
they,
the cat would be smaller in your mouth
in that hamster.
Right?
Squirrel would be,
that's how big the fucking cat.
So raw.
Here it is.
Oh,
that's a wrap,
son.
Almost a million people saw it.
Cats don't give up.
They don't give a fuck.
My cat's a killer.
Oh Dude.
They're ruthless.
Ruthless.
Ruthless just kills everything and
anything they can.
Yeah.
If you ever seen the numbers for how
many things cats kill in North America?
No Bill Yin's of birds.
Billions,
billions,
billions of mammals and billions of
birds.
What's so gangsters?
They kill them and don't even eat them.
No,
they just kill him.
Yeah.
They like the sport tastes.
Food,
foods,
easy.
Cats that live in the wild or indoor
pets are allowed to roam outdoors.
Killed between 1.4 billion to as many as
3.7 billion birds in the continental US
each year says a new study that
escalates a decade's old debate over
feline threat to native animals and it
shows his cute little cat with the
burdens mouth.
They're monsters.
Yeah,
and just brings him and drops him in my
kids' beds.
Like this question,
people also ask to cats,
kill birds.
I keep leaving my birds and they're
dead.
Fluffy would never do that,
sweetie.
Flat fees.
I didn't see a feather in its full well
there.
You know Mike?
Yeah,
my cat drops road and all in my
children's hair while they sleep
in her bed.
Oh my God.
Dropped a rat in my daughter's bathroom
with a leak in her shower cap.
Really to mark his territory.
Now the rat was just scared shitless and
was running.
We couldn't still behind the toilet and
stuff and we finally got it out.
I might to the next day it goes to put
on a shower cap and it's just filled
with p rat rat pee.
Ah,
you could fucking die from the
disgusting.
You know that you can get leprosy from
armadillos.
No,
of course.
I don't know that it's one of the few,
one of the few ways that a human can
contract leprosy from an animal
leprosies apparently is 95% of us are
immune to leprosy.
But you can get leprosy from Armadillo.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
So if you eat an Armadillo,
cook the shit out of it.
Folks wear rubber gloves.
How armadillos can spread leprosy.
That's a dinosaur too,
isn't it?
That tank,
like creatures are the only mammals
besides us known to carry leprosy.
Oh my Lord.
Yeah.
Apparently though those things taste
pretty good.
People,
uh,
people eat armadillos speak to.
Yeah.
They opened him up and it's kind of a
fatty meat grill it and uh,
yeah,
people marinate it and grill it and
talking your head.
I mean why is a lobster delicious and
that things gross because it walks on
the road cause he's,
he its beady eyes at night when you're
driving to vegas capable.
Why is it dear delicious then?
Cause deers walking the road to they're
not as delicious dear.
Yeah.
I don't like dear so much.
Jerry.
You,
you like to cooking it right?
Yeah,
probably not.
How come you eat and elk?
That's a deer elk.
It's a giant elk.
A giant elk is a giant deer.
What is different though?
Well maybe in fairness,
I haven't had deer in a long time when I
didn't know how to cook.
Well also it's how people take care of
it as a big issue.
There's things called tarsal glands that
exists,
um,
on the deer's legs that are particularly
active when they're horny,
which is when a lot of times when you
hunt them,
which is called the Rut and those Tarsa
Glenn's,
if they're not handled correctly while
you're skinning the deer,
you can leak some of that stuff on the
meat and it'll greatly taint the way the
meat tastes.
Maybe I had some of that.
There's that.
And then there's also people don't take
care of it.
Like from the moment they kill it and
like how long does it take before it's
actually cooled down and dressed?
And this was like in New Jersey,
I'm sure nothing was being done
correctly.
Problems,
nothing was done right.
And that's where I was born.
It's done right there.
Born and raised.
I know exactly who killed it will party
an ease and any born in,
uh,
I was born in passaic.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
New Jersey.
Deers.
It probably is a ton of them.
Oh yeah,
they were really,
I mean it's really
there every week.
Well,
New Jersey has an interesting situation
now because the new governor has decided
to stop bear hunting.
Yeah.
New Jersey,
New Jersey has the highest population of
Brown bear per capita in the country.
Cheese New Jersey does,
which people don't,
that doesn't make sense to them.
Bears.
You're like,
wait a minute.
Yeah.
You say bear and New Jersey,
New Jersey has enormous bear population.
A huge am I the way we're talking about
it over the holidays,
my sister,
my sister had a,
uh,
her dog was going crazy,
um,
at the woodpile and my sister went and
put a big tarp over it.
The next day the dog is going crazy
again at the top at the woodpile and
she's like,
why is he going so,
so nuts?
And she goes outside to get the dog and
the a big ass bear comes out from under
the tarp.
This just a New Jersey just starts like
coming out.
She was so thankful that she didn't just
like poke her head under there.
Well,
we've played videos.
These two giant bears battling it out in
far rockaway where they tackle over each
other and they're slamming to these
garbage pails and garbage goes flying.
They knock over a,
um,
a mailbox and they go right out into
traffic and first flying all over the
drunk fight.
Yeah.
They're fighting for garbage.
It was the fight for access to these
areas where these people drop their
garbage off.
Like turf.
Yeah.
It's,
and this new governor,
because Chris away,
Chris,
Chris Christie,
such a Slob,
like people hated him so much and he was
the Republican,
so they hired this ultra liberal social
justice warrior type new governor who's
decided he has his ideological
opposition to the bear hunt.
Even though the bear hunt in New Jersey
is like really strictly controlled by
wildlife biologist.
They've done it to try to keep the
populations healthy.
And there was also the situation that
happened in rutgers a couple of years
ago where a kid was killed by a bear.
Oh really?
Yeah.
One of the students at rutgers.
Sad.
[inaudible] students was a wandering
through the woods with his friends and
they got fucking attacked by a bear and
a bear killed one of the kids.
Oh my God.
A picture of it before it killed him to,
this happened that the stress factory
right next door in the parking lot.
Um,
Vinnie brand was there.
She was doing and he had the phone and
everything.
He was doing probably phone calls to the
bear's den
here.
We got your daughter down here.
She's really drunk,
sir.
So the wildlife biologist put a number
like,
you know,
the bears can be healthy and conflicts
with people can be reduced if we have,
you know,
the bears reduced to shutting them out.
Like it's not an issue of,
uh,
they're in danger.
Ranger not endangered in any way,
shape or form.
It's the opposite.
They're over abundant.
And,
but this is a problem with people with
when it comes to bears or what my friend
Steve Rinella likes to call charismatic
megafauna and their people look at
animals and they anthropomorphize them
and start thinking of them as being Yogi
and booboo and our little friends that
live in the forest,
they don't realize like these are no,
these are animals,
man.
You,
you have to,
you can't have animals there.
Giant predators and close proximity to
human beings without monitoring and
having wildlife biologists,
stoic,
calm,
objective people who really understand
animals tell you exactly how many there
should be in this area and when it
becomes a problem.
Right.
And so they're going to have an issue in
New Jersey the same way they're going to
have an issue in British Columbia.
They outlawed Grizzly bear hunting and
British Columbia this year for the exact
same reason.
Oh really?
And they did it in British Columbia
because they're not endangered.
No,
no,
no.
It was a ton of them.
Ton of them.
Not only do they not endangered,
but the people that voted on it are the
people that live in Vancouver where
there are new grizzly bears.
But Vancouver,
even though it's the population center
of a British Columbia,
it's where all the people live.
It's by no means representative of what
most of British Columbia looks like.
It's a British Columbia's woods forest.
And those people have to deal with
fucking grizzly bears,
grizzly bears.
So they said they're not allowed to hunt
them at all and a lot of them anymore
now.
And so also it's a big part of their
economy because there's a lot of these
people that made a living by guiding
people on these grizzly bear hunts.
Uh,
and it's gonna also devastate the
economy when it comes to their moose and
elk hunting populations too.
Because a lot of people went there to
moose hunt,
elk hunt and deer hunt,
but the bears.
So why did the populations are going to
go up.
The bears are going to start eating more
moose and elk and deer.
So what's their reason?
Animal rights activists have been
infiltrated the government and these
people that are like leaning left and
have sort of a delusional perception of
what wildlife is.
They've decided to push these laws
through that people didn't vote on.
By the way,
this is not like something,
there was this giant statewide vote and
people decided to end grizzly bear
hunts.
Well,
what's crazy about the Jersey thing is
it he just gotten an office and the bear
problems this years it's been a problem,
but that's while you're hunting.
Well,
I think that people are doing it for the
right reasons.
I think they're wrong,
but they're doing it for the right
reasons.
They're doing it because they think that
hunting's cruel and they're doing it
because they think that these are trophy
hunts and that people that there's no,
there was no merit to it,
but what they don't understand is you're
probably going to have to hire people to
kill these bears anyway,
which is what we do in California.
You know,
California Mountain Lion hunting was
outlawed in the 1990s but since then
they spent millions of dollars killing
mountain lions every year.
Oh really?
Not millions every year.
But what they sell downs overall,
a crew to go get a send out professional
hunters with dogs usually to go after
problem mountain lions and the ones that
go after,
almost all of them have pets and their
stomach.
Oh really?
That's what they eat.
I hey dogs.
Really?
Yeah.
It's a big part of their diet.
We can,
we have to control.
I mean it's fucked up.
Yeah.
Well No,
we're,
we're in their world.
Yes.
But it's not their world anymore.
Just like it's not,
you know,
this isn't where the fucking dinosaurs
live either stupid or we build homes all
through here.
Change.
Yeah.
And right now we live here and I'm more
concerned about us than I am with a God
damn mountain lions in there.
They just ate fluffy mountain lions.
You say fluffy.
You fuck.
Are there a lot of mountain lions?
Like is it the number is big or
California has good numbers.
Yeah.
My friend works at to hone ranch and
they have it to hone ranch just outside
of Bakersfield,
which you went about an hour and a half
from here.
And they have a,
um,
what it was called trail camera.
That's a post out in front of a,
um,
a,
a pond and out of this one pond they got
pictures of 16 different mountain lines.
Wow.
Do you ever run into him when you go up
and no,
Ron,
your runs.
I've seen mountain lions twice in my
life.
One I saw in Colorado and one I saw in
Santa Barbara,
I saw one in Montecito in a car.
I was driving,
it was driving,
it was,
it had tunes on,
it was listening to Miley Cyrus.
I was in the car and I saw this thing
and I thought it was a coyote.
It was running across the road and know,
Oh look at its tail.
I saw this big thick bouncy tail.
And I'm like,
oh my God,
it's a cat.
And I realized a,
Geez,
it was weird.
It's weird,
but I'm looking at something for a
second,
two seconds maximum,
right.
What I'll find the cat.
What do you got,
Jamie?
Oh,
Jesus Christ wildlife camera catches
uncolored mountain lion roaming the
Hollywood hills.
I'm like,
God,
that looks the size of that fucker.
That is like,
yeah,
that's like from Africa and this is just
a couple of months ago was October 31st
that's right by pauly shore's house.
It is pauly shore.
Pauly shore.
It turns into that at night when no
one's watching it,
so I held the light twice down.
Hardly working.
Most of the time it's just,
that's crazy.
That's like something you'd see on
Safari.
It's a big one too.
Boy.
Look at the muscles and the fucker.
This is,
this is a halloween 2017 yeah,
craze.
That is our uncolored mountain lions
had,
it means they don't even know where this
one game for.
Oh my God.
I mean that's the Hollywood hills.
That's like right next to people's
homes.
Well,
I stick my dog to a dog park up there.
A dog park.
That's a awful laurel one.
There's a dog park,
a at the top of Laurel,
like right when you go dead.
If you coming up over studio city,
when you go down,
there's a dog park out there.
If you go to the right and one of the,
they had a big sign there that said,
be on the lookout for mountain lions.
If mountain lions attack you fight back.
And I'm like,
God,
no,
fuck am I looking at here?
She's,
I just want to go for a run.
I'm just here to Hollywood,
my dog taking my dog to the park and
sort of see some girls and throw the
ball around.
That's
a lot of that is just because of our
attitude about these animals and that's
also why you see very few deer in
California.
So there's like pros and cons.
The pro is you very rarely get in
accidents with deer like Eww,
that's so uncommon in California.
That's true.
And it's because of mountain lions.
I always figured they just weren't a
indigenous to the area.
Oh No,
they're everywhere.
They used to be way more of them when I
first moved here.
Really?
Yeah,
man.
When I moved,
I moved to the valley in 94 and I see
deer all the time.
All the time.
You seem in the Hollywood hills all the
time.
I've never seen a deer here.
I see.
I saw him a couple of days ago out in
thousand oaks area here.
Yeah,
but they're very rare in California.
Anywhere else like this?
Like if you're in long island.
Oh yeah.
Highland is a giant problem with deer
everywhere.
Everywhere.
Higher snipers go take care of them.
She,
they do.
They're all over New Jersey.
They felt like a pass everywhere.
It's like mosquitoes because they don't
have any predators like mountain lions
or coyotes or very,
very few coyotes.
And the natural order is why we don't
see him.
Well,
it's because here they've kind of got a
point.
And that point is you can let the
mountain lines take care of the
population.
And then when the mountain lions come
into a problem,
when they've come problem that you can
get something called the depredation
permit,
which a woman got in the Malibu
mountains because she ran an Alpaca farm
and these mountain lion one mountain
lion killed like I think 10 or 11
alpacas and a goat.
Oh my God.
In one session and one session.
And it was the same thing.
It's like we were talking about cats
with house cats.
They just canceled.
It just killed him.
[inaudible] me.
She had a good old time.
Oh,
I'll pack a pen,
couldn't help himself,
Jack and all of them,
but when this woman got a depredation
permit to kill the mountain line,
she got a ton of death threats from
people.
They were saying,
you fucking bitch.
I'll kill you.
You touch that cat.
And then she's like,
fuck this.
I'm not doing anything.
She,
she felt very exposed.
People who were,
she were,
they knew where her farm was.
Jeez.
Yeah.
It's scary.
She fuck.
Yeah.
People get really nutty,
man.
When it comes to animals,
they get a week,
but it's certain animals,
right?
Like these people have this weird thing
about that squirrel and then the cat
came along,
killed that fucking scroll.
Guess what bitch?
You've been feeding that cat,
right?
That's yours.
You made that monster and you let that
thing roam around outside,
which is just,
you're asking for it to kill everything
it runs into.
That's what they do.
It's what they do.
Yeah.
And it's probably super charged up about
it too because he gets to do it all the
time and the pride in front of it's
family to do it for the family.
That's what they like the most.
Yeah.
That cat did that in front of you
because that's what he wants you to see.
Right.
They look at me.
Oh,
it's scary.
It is.
Hey,
I saw the tank.
You want to try it some day?
What do you wanna try it?
I don't know.
When can I?
Um,
well,
we'll work something out.
We'll come up with a a time where you
can come in.
We should have,
I should have had you come in early
today.
You could done it before the podcast.
Oh really?
Yeah.
How long do you go in there?
I like to do at least an hour.
Last time I did a,
just a couple days ago that did two
hours,
just floating there for an hour and it's
climbing.
Relax,
listen to music or silence.
I silent your silence.
I'd log it like that.
Yeah,
I'd like to try it.
we'll do it next time for sure.
That'd be cool.
For sure.
This facility is amazing.
It's pretty crazy,
right?
It's so great.
I figured fuck it.
Why not?
Right.
So great.
To me it was one of those things where,
Oh look,
all right,
if I could just do whatever I wanted to
do,
what would I do right?
Then I go,
wait a minute.
I think I could do whatever I want to
hear.
Like I should just do it.
It's really great Jamie.
So she saw me a gym membership.
I'm going to start working on,
you know,
did you get a key fob?
Yeah,
it's pretty Shim equipment actually
comes this week.
It's,
it's,
it's insane.
It was just like a whole,
it's like a gym.
It
can we,
I have an apartment.
Well it would be a real gym next week
cause rogue athletics is outfitting it.
Like a real gem.
That'd be a rowing machine.
There's going to be an Airdyne bike is
going to be a squat cage and she's full
range of kettlebells and fucking steel
plates and that.
Yeah,
they're doing the whole thing.
Fuck
is awesome.
Well,
you can go to the gym and get annoyed or
it could just work out here.
Why not?
Yeah.
Just come on by.
What's the sauna?
The Sauna and then in a house.
Yes.
You could for sure.
Yeah.
If you have the room for it and they
have varying sizes of Saunas that they
did a big one.
Yeah.
That is pretty quite honestly that,
that one's too big for me.
I mean I've only gone in Indian by
myself.
Yeah.
But,
uh,
you could have couple people in there in
that one.
So the idea of that one was,
what was that room?
It was like a closet before that we
turned it into a sauna.
Yeah.
Right.
Um,
we just decided like this is a spot like
that.
Why?
Okay.
Put it there.
Can you just run that size?
Oh really?
And apparently they make them all sorts
of different sizes,
so they do.
Yeah.
And uh,
it fit perfect,
dude.
Here's the thing.
I've been dealing with,
um,
tendinitis in my elbow and it was,
it's really been kind of annoying.
It's really been Bob 10 to nine.
This is a weird one man.
And have you ever gotten it before?
No.
I have a,
what they called Golf Golfer's elbow,
the inside where tennis elbows,
the outside.
It's been annoying me for a few months
now and uh,
it comes from a overdoing chin up.
So I was doing too many chin ups and I
was being a meathead where I was just
pushing through,
you know,
like it would start to annoy me and I
would just keep going.
Right.
But one session in the sauna
significantly reduced like the pain in
it.
And then the second session did the same
thing and then I did it again yesterday
and I'm like,
I barely feel that tendinitis now for
real.
Yeah.
And so just getting the inflammation
out.
Yeah,
I think it has a,
I think it just has an overall effect on
inflammation throughout your whole body.
You know?
It's pretty cool.
Yeah.
You got a spare set onto where you can
climb in today?
I'm going in right after the show.
No.
What does this one James?
Like a personal infrared.
These are like probably 1500 bucks I
think,
or less.
You just throw it in your house and they
also make,
um,
were you,
uh,
you lie down in them.
That's ridiculous.
They have one.
I was lie down in it like a suit and a
use.
Zip it up.
Up to your neck.
Let's see that one with the blue down
there with that lined lying down is keep
going.
Scroll down.
That one with the blue.
You're your cursor's,
right?
Yeah,
that,
that's ridiculous.
Yeah.
You climb like gold.
It's like the old brady bunch of cafes.
He gets up your body and it's apparently
really good for you.
Really?
You look like she looks like the
Blueberry and Willy Wonka.
That's her pussy.
Pussy pussies.
Oh my God.
It's on fire.
She's on fire.
It looks chic.
I like a nice sauna.
It's great hot.
I don't like the steam so much.
Hmm.
Uh,
I think there's benefits
steam too,
but the real benefit of the sauna is the
fact that you can get to 176 degrees in
a dry heat.
Your body can tolerate it.
But if you got to 176 degrees and steam
your fucking Nipples,
a burn on fire,
right.
That you'd feel the wet because you
basically be poaching yourself.
Right.
My friend really believes in the steam
steam.
He's a big drinker and he steams every
morning and it just all comes out of,
it's how I've been.
Please.
That's dying.
Big drinkers are all just ways of
managing the big drinking.
Yeah.
He just got steam it out.
I'm all right.
I think Sano will probably help more if
he could figure out a way to not.
I mean,
I think he's probably getting some
benefit from like being in the steam,
but I bet sauna would be even better for
him.
And it's again the same thing.
Reducing inflammation.
Yeah.
I'd like to be less puffy from
inflammation.
Russians love it.
Five time champion.
Timo cow.
Conan had become adept at enduring the
tournament's 110 degrees Celsius.
203 Fahrenheit heat lasting over 16
minutes.
She 2003 but he died,
didn't he?
Next guy that the guy who we're
competing,
they
have poses a competition,
right?
Yeah.
World's Sauna Championship.
Oh my God,
what the Fuck is wrong with people?
Come on.
I'm a the very best at cooking myself,
but not dying.
16 minutes.
That's not long.
230 degrees.
Let me tell you something,
man.
I was at 210 degrees.
I can't even fucking imagine someone
going 20 degrees hotter than that like
my nipples were hurting and I was like,
why my nipple so hard?
Why they were so sore.
Why did you do that watch?
I cranked it up and then I came in here
to do my ads and when I did the ads,
I left it on too long.
I just got super hot.
That's my jam.
It says that this one guy goes in for
bursts of 130 to 140 degrees Celsius.
I just looked that up.
That's 284 degrees Fahrenheit,
four minute bursts,
todd,
280 degrees,
four minute bursts,
so he's essentially doing like the
opposite of the crowd.
Janet Chamber,
right?
It says you can get what's called
hyperthermia.
If you do this in a bad way,
this heavy bathers in favor of the
hottest temperatures always wear felt
caps and slippers because the wooden
surfaces tend to get very high.
God,
that sounds adorable.
Felt the haves and slippery the going in
like Robin Hood,
Robin Hood Cook things at two 50 yeah,
all the time.
No.
Yeah.
A lot of times when you cook like a
potato Wa one 50 pull it out of the
oven.
I cook at elk steak.
I'll cook it at two 50 and I put an
internal thermometer and when it gets to
125 degrees and I pull it,
yeah,
Jack the temperature up and I see,
or the outside,
it's time to eat.
Three 20 it says one 60 Fahrenheit is
three 20 for short spells.
320 degrees.
Ooh,
so these people,
aren't they?
This is a whole nother psychosis.
This isn't bound inflammation.
This is not just what people do.
Always leave it,
just leave it.
You can't leave it alone.
We had a good thing going.
People that tattoo their eyeballs.
Yeah.
Why wasn't good enough to write.
You only live once and your forehead.
You have to Tatiana,
I balls black.
He couldn't stop.
You have to be like towed from x men.
Why do you have to do that?
Why are you putting things into your
eyeballs?
No one wants you to do that,
but people can't help it.
They can't leave things alone.
If they get one piercing in their face,
they want to get the cheek piercings and
knows purely this guy got his fucking
eyeballs turned blue like you remember
when you were a kid?
No one had their face tattooed.
Nobody.
No one.
And now look at this and another one.
Yeah,
full eyeball Tattoo Solace and says,
oh my God,
your soul is Bro.
Hey Bro,
your solo.
So you've got an umbrella like Mary
poppins and she stupid.
Fuck,
it's got an umbrella.
And what does that a microphone.
Is it a microphone or a razor blade?
What do you do when your kids start
asking have
to do those on their face to anywhere
they say what they want to be peers.
Do they want to?
I th I,
I have two full sleeves.
Uh,
I would be a massive hypocrite if I told
them not to get tattoos,
but I would definitely tell them,
you really should think about the fact
that you're going to keep the skin for
your rest of your life.
Like,
don't,
you know,
if you want to get a tattoo,
it should mean something.
Don't get anything done that's cheap.
Go real artists.
Think about it.
Yeah.
You know?
He can't control them,
I guess.
No,
I don't think.
Not only do I think you can't control
them,
but I think if you try to control them,
you're going to do the opposite.
Nose piercing,
nose piercing seems easy.
He'd get it taken out.
You put it back in.
It's no big deal.
I would rather nose piercing that
forehead tattoo,
but they're so beautiful and feed a loca
rather than your forehead,
eh?
Yeah.
I think,
uh,
my younger one was like,
I like a little nose.
Like,
well,
no,
it's like the little.in the nose kind of
thing.
I was like,
I could be worse things in this life.
I doesn't really make me that angry,
but she's so perfect just like I get it.
Oh,
don't do that.
People like decorating themselves
though.
Then we were buying something.
This was when we were in New York and
we're just walking around and then I was
buying something in the woman at the
register was tons of piercings on her
nose and her ears and like,
you know,
like 50 on her ear.
And I said,
uh,
I said,
how did the nose one?
Did you nose piercing hurt?
This is right off our conversation.
Oh yes.
It really did hurt.
It was so painful and they had to do it
twice and then it got infected and it
was just a terrible thing.
I've got staff and gang grandy.
Yeah.
And this isn't even my nose anymore.
I'm looking at my daughter,
like say,
let's see what can happen.
It's just like,
I still want it.
No,
you can't stop them.
People like decorate and themselves and
I know it's a weird thing.
I have a bad one.
Not I have,
I have three.
I have a really bad one on my leg.
What is it?
It's,
I'm a wizard.
Is it?
Yeah.
You want to say it?
We'll show you.
This was my first tattoo.
It was a guy in New Jersey.
I just picked it up.
The wars.
He
was rough.
He said got a candy cane in his hand.
Well it the original one on the wall.
He was watering a pot plant.
Hold on,
let me get that.
He was watering a pot plant and I was
like,
I can't do that.
That's reckless.
Hold on a second.
You know what's really funny?
Pull the microphone down so I can see
your face here.
Alright,
here we go.
Look at everybody.
You know what's really funny?
Uh,
so when we did the show for your buddy
that helps the Congo pygmies,
Justin,
Justin on the back of his book.
It's exactly my tattoo.
His him that him hat with his beard.
It all comes full circle.
I showed it to him that night when we
did the show.
He was pretty freaked out.
Yeah.
He just sent me a text saying he's going
to kill him.
He's going to climb Mount Kilimanjaro.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
I liked meeting that guy.
That was great.
That was the best part.
But he's,
the chest is even one of the nicest
guys.
Love that guy.
But do things for him.
Oh my God.
He's just a,
just a gem of a human being.
I just wanted to hang with him all
night.
It was from this podcast.
We've built more than 20 different wells
in the Congo.
He's built,
they built hundreds of wells there now.
It's amazing just because of this
podcast alone,
more than 20 wells were build.
They're awesome.
Awesome.
He's such a good guy.
And just one of those people like
instantly you just kind of,
you could tell.
Yeah,
yeah.
He's a saint.
Yeah.
Like,
like legitimately like a saint.
Yeah.
His book is pretty great and he's a
fucking cage fighter and now how does
that,
yeah.
Yeah.
So that'd be a nice guy.
No,
he was really cool.
But I wish I had a picture of the book.
It literally is my shitty tattoo is,
is him.
How many other ones you got?
I've got two more cup.
Went up here and went up here.
Those are good.
This was,
and this was,
this was like a shitty spot.
Tore it too.
It was kind of like a coward way on your
calf.
It's just like there is that.
Yeah,
that's my tattoo.
He's holding the thing.
Yeah.
He's got a spear that he got from the
pygmies and he's wearing a hat they made
out of leaves.
Justin looks like my shitty tattoo.
What's on your raw shoulders?
Uh,
my wife's name is on here and uh,
over here is like the sun with this
quote from Walt Whitman on it.
These are the,
these are the days that must happen to
you from Ode to the song of the open
road by Walt Whitman.
These are the days that must happen.
These are the days that must happen to
you.
You shall not,
you shall not gather,
uh,
rich's,
you'll scatter with a lavish hand.
All that you earn and achieve.
You shall not settle in one place,
but we'll leave.
Uh,
but we'll leave to the silent leaders
and laughing at those.
You leave behind.
Um,
basically go out.
These are the days that must happen to
you.
Be Fearless.
Go,
go,
just go,
go be fearless.
Go stay in the harbor.
Don't stay in one place.
Don't stay in the harbor.
Go and keep touch with friends from back
home.
Yeah.
I've got a real tight group from a grade
school,
high school.
Did some of them not leave,
not go anywhere.
And you,
you were around them and you just,
you get to see what that's like.
Um,
a little bit.
Yeah.
It's a weird way of living.
It is a weird way of living and I get
nostalgic sometimes because I see,
I go back that same place,
you know,
where I was a kid and uh,
and the one hand it seems like,
you know,
you could have made that choice.
You could stay and easy.
It's just stay there and be at the same
spot and do the same thing and there's
something very appealing and calm about
it.
But it wasn't my nature.
I couldn't do it.
Yeah.
There's always something appealing about
something that other people are doing
though,
isn't it?
Yeah,
for sure.
You think about your own situations and
the weirdness of your own existence and
you go,
ah,
I want to be great if I just fucking
cabinet maker and
Belgium.
Yeah,
exactly.
He has his coffee in the morning.
He just makes his cabinets,
goes to the same cafe every evening and
has a beer and he gets embedded nine and
his,
him and his dog.
Perfect.
Sitting at the bar.
I love his cabinets.
Yeah.
And he's like,
Oh,
this is hell.
I live show is kind of jokes.
It happened to me around the world since
I started baking this bread.
When I'm on the road,
I'll go see these bakers.
Like if there's someone really good in a
town that I'm in and just go talk to
him.
He's so big.
He's just like,
like
if you were a martial artist,
she'd go train with them.
Yeah.
I go and I go and check out how they
make their bread and and see what
they're doing.
Hey,
I'm Tom Papa.
A little sour dough.
Yeah.
Like,
Hey,
you know,
I'll,
I'll tweet out.
Then I'm going to come.
And then they'll,
they'll bring me back and yeah,
it's great.
So what do,
did sign the good bakers in towns or a
website that you go to?
No,
you just like,
you know,
through instagram and stuff,
you start to see the ones that you
really like and who they follow and you
just start to see like who's doing the
same kind of a thing,
you know,
because it's a certain,
it's a very natural way of doing it.
So it's not like just like a big
commercial bakery that's just,
you know,
cranking stuff out.
Like there's people that are real
artists that are doing this stuff all
around the country,
all around the world.
Right.
So,
but it's funny because I'll come in and
be like all bright eyed and this is
amazing.
So you're a baker and you just come in
here and make this stuff and you,
I mean,
how great is it that you feed the
community and everyone really loves what
you do and you put your heart and soul
into it and they look at you like,
I'm up at two o'clock every day so I'm
in a living hell flower.
I can't stay up past eight you know what
I mean?
It is.
It's always like,
it's always the other thing with seems
to know what do you have to get up
early,
right?
Yeah,
man.
Because you know you walk in and want a
sticky bun on your way to work at seven
o'clock someone was up making that at
four so you can so it could be ready for
you at seven there's no way around that.
There's no way around that shit.
Yeah.
Those bagels,
someone's in there cranking than out in
the middle of the night.
There's a good bit,
there's a good,
a little bakery down the street from
here.
In fact,
I don't,
I don't like to eat sweets very often,
but they have these fucking chocolate
croissants that is so ridiculous.
The pastry part is so buttery and flaky
and then the chocolate part is so rich,
so good.
I can't even,
I can't get coffee there cause if I get
coffee there,
I will get one of those fucking things
and I'll feel like shit.
I know you'd tell it like it an hour
later you're just like,
what?
But while you're eating and it's heaven,
it's so rich chewiness to the,
there's a combination of the fleeky
buttery pastry in the,
the richness of the chocolate and the
sweetness and then you're drinking your
coffee at the same time.
You're like,
this is perfect.
I didn't,
I don't need anything but this.
Fuck diabetes and not worry about
diabetes.
I wonder about life.
I want to live.
Yeah,
that's living man.
It is the good stuff.
It's not,
it's not bad man.
It's just,
it's not good for you.
It's not anything in excess.
Right.
When I found the little treat once in a
while there's a company called no foods,
k,
n,
O,
w,
and they make waffles,
chocolate chip waffles,
and they make syrup with low glycemic
index,
very little sugar in the waffle
variation and it tastes good.
What do you mean they come like premade?
Like
put them in the toaster.
The lead.
They're frozen like an Eggo kind of a
thing.
Yeah,
but they don't last very long,
so you have to like eat them.
You have to thaw them out pretty
quickly.
Eight grams of fiber,
12 grams of protein,
four grams net carbs.
Whoa.
On sign for grants.
Right Bitch.
And I'm putting butter on those
motherfuckers.
And then they have their own syrup,
no syrup as very little as well.
Uh,
that looks perfect,
dude.
I'm telling you.
They are smart people that are healthy,
that figured out a way to make,
look at that.
Wow.
I had that yesterday.
Felt great,
worked out afterwards.
I feel like a fucking champ.
Didn't feel shitty at all.
Like,
look at that.
You felt like there's no way I can eat
that.
There's no way.
There's no way you got to get them
online or do you get them in a store?
I ordered them online.
Yeah.
And then they,
uh,
they're very nice.
They found out.
They come and they sent me a box of
shit.
What a treat and that we have some of
their cookies here too.
He tried.
We try one of their cookies before you
leave.
Tom.
Papa needs some of those.
Yeah,
man.
There's some stuff that you can eat that
people have figured out how to do.
Ozone stores,
places where they sound.
Oh Wow.
There's a bunch of places where people
have figured out how to make food that
tastes really good.
That doesn't fuck you up.
Yes,
of course.
Be Honest.
Let's be on the United States of
America.
Let's be honest.
Yes.
It doesn't taste as good as that
chocolate croissant.
Well,
no,
it just doesn't.
Well,
no damn good.
But you can have that damn go four times
a week probably.
Yeah.
You could have it every day,
but there's something about knowing that
you're eating shit and you're like,
I don't care.
Now this is part of it.
It's part of the part of the thrill.
Thrill and joy during the holidays.
Oh yeah.
When we had Christmas cookies on the
counter for like two straight weeks,
just walking through eating.
I'm like chips.
Like I don't care.
It's Christmas cookie time.
That's heaven.
You know what I have the other night.
It's a good time.
Pumpkin Pie with cool whip Pumpkin Pie.
No one's even pretending cool webs good
for no.
No one even knows what the fuck.
Cool.
We're pretending it's a food.
It's just like some weird fucking thick
stuff that's white.
Yeah.
Oh,
that's good.
Where'd the Pumpkin Pie come from?
I don't even know.
I didn't even ask.
It was my mother in Law's house.
Oh Man.
I didn't ask a goddamn question.
That's wolf.
That fucker down.
Something about warm Pumpkin Pie too.
I'm like,
God,
it's so good.
Pumpkin pies.
So I fasted yesterday.
I didn't eat anything really.
The whole day.
Yeah,
I had a lot of Broccoli.
I had some water.
Coffee,
coffee.
Yeah.
I had probably four cups of coffee and
uh,
I didn't feel bad.
I didn't,
I felt pretty good when I woke up this
morning.
I was starving.
Yeah,
but once your body,
if you can figure out how to do it for
45 hours,
48 hours,
your body will kick into a state of
burning fat body of,
we will kick in.
No state of Ketosis.
48 hours straight.
Yes.
It depends on the person.
Some people,
it's quicker depending on if you're fat
adapted.
If it's even quicker than that,
but I know when I'm in that state
because my appetite kind of goes away.
Yeah.
That's what,
it was weird.
I was like,
why aren't I starving right now?
Yeah.
Well that's one good thing about when I
was sick.
Last few days.
I hardly at anything really sucks.
Succeed.
Also can look myself in the mirror.
I'm like snot coming down but looking
ripped me.
I'm gone.
My cheeks are sucked in.
My eyeballs are dark.
Uh,
there's something that girls,
do you guys ever do they do this post
where they look at you like this?
Yeah.
Photos I know have there,
but here's my ass,
my ass in my face.
When did that start happening?
At the same time,
there was no photos like that for the
fucking seventies and eighties people
just,
Oh you,
we weren't wasted.
They had to with no film.
They had chance to come up with that
children.
Fucking grown ass children look at my
ass.
Something about turning sideways.
I know.
It's so creepy.
Turning sideways,
looking over their shoulder like hold
on.
You know you're taking a picture,
right,
and you chose to stand some super
illogical way where your ass is facing
the camera and not your face.
Like you're looking over your shoulder.
This is how you chose to take a picture.
This is so crazy.
It is completely insane,
but it's super common.
Yeah,
no,
it's,
yeah,
it's kids do it.
Yeah.
Here he goes,
that this Gal.
Yeah,
that's common.
that's it.
Oh,
11 simple poses that will make you look
more attractive on the link.
Please.
I need to learn these.
Yeah.
I need that.
I want to look more attractive and I do.
We go turn your torso a or the body from
the waist instead of turning your neck.
I turned my neck.
I look at you like this.
I stand.
This is how I,
whoa.
I like that.
That's a stunning dunning.
I'd like to just turn my neck and I do
quick to like this.
I'm going to start some shit.
I'm definitely turning my tour.
Stand straight.
Some spacing.
Your posture by keeping your hand on
your waist.
How?
Yes cetera.
Oh,
how skinny she looks interesting.
I think the goods on the right looks
great.
That's a good one.
I find an issue with that.
Okay.
Fingers should be properly visible.
When you place your hands on the waist,
don't hide your hands.
Show your hand.
Does that make you look better?
No.
The girl on the left that just looks
fucking better.
Stupid.
The girl on the left is hot as the sun
doesn't make any sense.
Nobody gives a fuck if she even has
hands cross your legs or standing in a
way that will make them look angular and
creates space in the posture of the
lower body.
Uh Huh.
That girl needs a sandwich.
I'm not into those.
Lean towards the camera instead of away
from it.
Yeah.
That's what I do.
I lean towards the camera.
I'm like,
hello,
how are you taking like this?
Trying,
this is like the fucking rules.
Um,
a word.
Keep your arms away from your body when
your arm is properly visible in the
photo.
What?
Keep it not like this,
but like this.
Ah,
you don't want terrible website.
He said it's terrible.
I'm getting great advice.
You fuck off.
We're going to look amazing.
How about when you take selfies?
I can't get a good selfie for like life.
Depends on it.
Okay.
This tilt your head forward to look up a
bit to look sharp and slimmer.
That's true.
I want to look sharp,
dude.
How about sharp?
Ooh,
that's good to look sharp.
How about this?
Now just show me your at the same time
and you got something
like Yoga.
Yeah,
right.
Okay.
Don't slouch and sit but create angles.
You're sitting down.
Goals,
goals.
Let's look at that girl's back like how
is she even doing that?
It's all about just like the extra cyst
podcast.
I should have been doing this during the
podcast the whole time.
What's the next one?
Don't sprawl your legs while sitting on
the ground.
Oh,
see,
so she touches the knees together.
Don't sprawl.
Don't sprawl your legs.
Um,
listen honey,
don't mask whatever.
While we're trying to take a picture,
I'll go back to that.
We didn't say that girl is beautiful.
She can do whatever the fuck she wants
with her legs.
No one's going to complain.
She could have them legs like fully
spread wide and people like,
ah,
hey,
you want to get some coffee or
something?
And we want to do,
do you want to take over my company?
Lower your forehead a bit.
Well make up your mind.
Lean forward.
Hello.
Are you with our head for it then?
I'm not leaning forward anymore.
Oh right.
Hook up a little to make your eyes look
even bigger and more expressive.
Oh,
okay.
No,
that girl's hot as fuck.
That girl.
Look hot no matter what she did.
Yeah,
just be hotter.
be hotter.
Oh,
just put weight on the back leg while
posing and hence,
oh and hence creating an angular pose
and hence that,
that girls like,
but she looks like she's saying,
what the fuck did you ask me to do?
Okay.
What,
what did you that is not part of my job
description.
That is not what I was hired for and I'm
barefoot for fucking some strange
reason.
I'm barefoot and angry looking.
What did you say?
White man,
mother fucker.
I was reading a thing yesterday that had
sleep patterns of successful people.
Um,
Richard Branson,
Bill Gates,
people like that,
right?
Obama,
most of them six hours of sleep at
night?
Yeah,
most between like the 12 one o'clock to
like six,
seven o'clock in the morning.
I think there's a balance between
productivity and health and if you want
to get more done,
I would say that's probably the way to
go.
But I don't think those people were
pillars of health for fitness and
exercise is really hard and you know,
and really tax your body.
You need more.
I think you need eight.
You need eight.
I do eight.
You do eight?
I feel way better when I get eight.
He has six is six does not seem like a
lot cause this all the different people.
Nikola Tesla got to,
yeah,
but he's too busy.
Bang and pigeons.
He's crazy.
He was banging super,
super genius.
Who was in love with a pigeon?
What?
Yeah.
I never heard that.
He had a love affair with the pigeon.
Winston Churchill got like a hundred
hours of sleep at night.
Da Vinci and he was just drunk all the
time.
Are those,
are those dots mean hours?
It's when they slept,
he slept every four hours,
like a 20 minute nap.
Who did something similar to that then?
She did that.
Yeah.
That's what those little blue lines are
when they were sleeping.
That's crazy.
And Winston Churchill just slept like a
bear because he was drunk.
He drank like crazy.
Richard Branson seems like he's getting,
let's say six.
Yeah,
12 to six that sounds kind of
reasonable.
That's reasonable.
But six is early to get up for me while
if he's one of those gets shit done.
Donald Trump,
three hours,
one to four,
one to four come on.
That's not real be true.
Is that real based on speed one,
you know,
that was the speculation about trump,
um,
from uh,
an article that was posted a while back
was that he had a prescription for
amphetamines and like the 90s,
and someone had prescribed him,
see what you could find that um,
trump prescribed speed for diet and he
stayed
on it for like eight years.
Really?
Yeah.
It's been my understanding when you talk
to people that love adderall and,
and those sorts of things,
that you become incredibly productive
when you're on that stuff.
And if you're one of those people that
gets used to being incredibly productive
and stuff like eliminating that,
it's very hard.
See,
1993,
Harry hunts unauthorized biography on
trump.
Last tycoon corroborated the rumors and
went one step further.
The Diet drugs with trump took in pill
form,
not only curbed his appetite,
but gave him a feeling of euphoria and
unlimited energy.
The Medical Literature,
Warren,
that some potentially dangerous side
effect could result from long term
usage.
They included anxiety,
insomnia,
and delusions of grand jury.
What?
According to several trump organization
insiders,
donald exhibited all these ominous
symptoms of Diet,
drug use,
and then some the supposed drug trump
took back then was tenuous.
Dos Pan a drug with speed like effects.
It's not unlike dexedrine.
These rumors say trump stopped seeing
doctor Greenberg decades ago,
but according to one source to our
source,
the Donald Trump of today is on a diet
drug called fen term mean and has been
since at least April of 2014 he does not
look like he's on a diet.
Phen phen phen phen phen to mean first
gain,
no tr notoriety us under the name phen
phen a miracle combination of
phentermine and fenfluramine another
established anti obesity drugs.
The only problem was that patients
taking the drug,
b camera b began reporting damage to
their hearts and lungs.
Apparently the combination destroyed
patients body's ability to regulate the
amount of Serotonin phentermine on its
own.
However,
it's still prescribed and while the US
National Library of medicine notes that
most people take phentermine for a month
or so at a time since the drug is
addictive,
trump has supposedly been taking
continuously for over two years.
Well listen,
when people get used to taking pills and
speed in particular,
they get used to that ramped up life.
They can't,
they can't.
It's very hard.
It's just very hard to just go cold
Turkey and be that guy who just dull
now.
Yeah.
Right.
Exactly.
From Superhero he had while he was on
the campaign trail,
like constantly speaking against and
could never shut the fuck up.
It was really impressive.
I mean it was nonstop.
Right?
72 year old man.
73 but it doesn't it make sense.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Yeah.
Hillary was fall.
Oh very nice.
I knew hillary was talking stuff too.
She was on a pro vigil.
What's that?
Pro Vigil is a drug that was first
invented.
They were trying to make a drug that was
actually
a performance enhancing drug and then
they had to come up with a reason for
taking it,
cause he can't just say,
hey,
we made a pharmaceutical drug that
enhances your,
uh,
your,
your energy levels.
So they came up with narcolepsy.
Oh yeah,
I've taken it.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
It's great if you have to drive
somewhere and you're tired because it
doesn't give you,
it doesn't make you speedy.
And I don't think it makes you any
smarter or faster thinking or anything
like that.
But it definitely keeps you awake.
It gives you like a little elevated
sense of energy.
Yeah.
It doesn't sound so bad,
but yeah.
I mean you'd have to take something to
keep up those.
I mean,
you know,
just touring and stuff,
what that takes out of you and watch
the,
how they just were nonstop and he was
probably on diet pills.
Interesting.
And then get skinnier.
I knew a gal got on that phen phen
stuff.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Back in the 90s she was beautiful,
but she was Chubby.
She just had a bad diet.
And you know,
just like the booze and she's probably
20 something or something right now.
And uh,
got on the fen phen and I hadn't seen
her in forever.
I haven't seen her in probably like a
year.
And then I ran into her and I was like,
Holy Shit.
Like what happened?
And you lost balls.
And she was like 120 pounds and slim and
gorgeous.
And I was like,
that is crazy.
So what did,
yeah,
but that it's our fucking weather and
like messing her body up and you know,
like,
like heart palpitations and shit and
then,
you know,
a year later she was bigger than ever.
She's,
well,
I mean if you think about like taking an
Ibuprofen,
if like,
if that messes you up,
these drugs,
the impact is huge.
Oh yeah,
man.
Well I know so many people that are on
adderall.
Yeah,
I was just going to say,
have you ever tried to enter wrong?
Never meet me there to have it,
but I want to,
I know,
me too.
I want to try it.
Jamie's going to bring in something from
me.
You take it,
a dealer may or may not sell it to
children.
Know what God pill from a friend of mine
that I wanted,
I never even used it.
Oh.
And I still just have it.
Yeah.
Now all this stuff really works.
You ever,
you ever take a um,
ambien?
No,
I sleep easy.
I do too.
I got no problem sleep.
I was doing a show in the Middle East
one so my doctor gave me Ambien.
He's like,
if he need help with Justin your time.
I didn't ask for it.
He just gave it to me and uh,
I don't really take anything really,
but I took it.
It was,
I mean it just works.
You just like pretty awake and then you
just feel sleep just kind of coming over
you like,
like an ocean wave and it,
I mean do you feel when you woke up?
Not Good.
A little druggy.
Yeah.
Fucked up.
It wasn't like I woke up like,
oh I'm good to go be kind of tired and
then just go to the gym.
Yes,
exactly.
I'm just not into that drugged up
feeling now.
It's all cause they need,
then it becomes a whole cat and mouse
trying to adjust it.
And I had a buddy who was going,
I had a buddy who's going through a
divorce and couldn't sleep at all.
So he was taking two of those fucking
things at night and everybody was urging
them.
They were like,
man,
don't take that much.
Yeah,
I think this is,
this stuff is not good for you.
I'm always afraid you won't be able to.
Yeah.
You're not gonna be able to sleep
normally
or you don't wake up.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Take it and night-night choking middle
of the night and just
had cheese.
You're in the middle.
Some crazy dream about being in a
gunfight with the cops.
That's the thing about barrel ambien.
People do things and they're asleep.
Yeah.
Got Buy ice cream.
I had a bit about it in my act about a
friend of mine who made a Turkey.
He got up in the middle of the night,
preheated the oven,
went to the store,
bought a Turkey,
came home,
made stuffing,
mashed potatoes and gravy,
cooked it,
ate it,
went back to sleep.
Got Up in the morning and call the
police.
Someone broke into her house and made a
Turkey.
They're like,
what the fuck is wrong with you?
You fat piece of Shit.
They come to grips with your food
problem.
It's a real story.
He didn't remember doing any of it.
No.
He made a Turkey.
Went to the store,
dude.
Yeah,
like bought a Turkey,
dealt with someone at the register,
bought a fucking Turkey,
drove his car.
Oh my God.
That's so crazy.
Yeah.
People are weird,
man.
I'm surprised.
No one's like killed someone.
All they have,
they have.
Yeah.
People have.
People have murdered people on it and
there was one guy that's Jesus.
He,
I want to say he killed someone in his
family with a crowbar.
Oh boy.
It was like some crazy story where he
was on Ambien and he drove to someone's
house and killed him with a crowbar and
then drove home.
We had no idea even did it.
Oh my God.
Well,
people react to different things in
different ways.
You can never predict exactly how
someone's going to react to like heavy
duty pharmaceutic.
That's what I was worried about.
I'm like,
I'm not taking this on the flight.
Who knows what I'm going to do?
Recount all of the fucking ocean.
How high up?
I just wake up in prison.
You don't know why
did I get here?
You know what you did?
Don't haven't watched the video of,
you kind of have some businessman
cat in the hat hat on,
beating someone to death with a nine
iron,
mixing the drink cart.
Go and try and get at the pilot.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
Does having the fly hood a nightmare and
hasn't been around that long,
right?
Like this is 2013 I suppose.
Just trying to look up.
There's something called the sleep
homicidal sleepwalking defense that's
been used
at least since 1987 she's like,
it goes back farther than that and
here's the wikipedia on it.
Wow.
Sleepwalking defense.
Homicidal some,
some NAM bullism,
but on an or sleep walking sleepwalking
murderer.
The act of killing someone during an
episode of sleepwalking.
Oh Man.
See,
that's the thing.
Like if you're going to kill somebody,
wouldn't even be like even sleep.
But he was acquitted of killing the
murder of his mother in,
in 1987 after using the sleep,
walked in defense.
So let me just pause right there.
I would love to believe this man.
However,
I have a wonderful mother in law.
She's a lovely lady,
but I have friends whose mother-in-law's
or straight cons.
It's a real thing.
It's a real thing and it just so convey
at this guy,
he didn't kill his children.
You know,
he didn't know his wife drive to his
buddy's house and kills best friend.
What does it say there reportedly got up
from his bed,
still asleep and drove roughly 23
kilometers to his in laws house,
broken,
assaulted his father in law,
Denis would,
and stabbed his mother-in-law to death.
Wow.
Good on you for all this.
He managed to drive himself to the
police station side from a few isolated
events and next thing he could recall
was being in the police station asking
for help,
saying,
I think I've killed some people.
My hands.
Whoa.
Wow.
Well,
that's what I would do too.
If was going to go,
pretend you've got to plan this out.
Something a blew up for you.
I don't know what it was crazy,
but you guys gotta help me.
Yeah.
Like if you know for sure you're going
to kill them.
Like there's no way I can not kill this
person.
I need a fucking rock solid excuse.
Yeah.
What does this non Bellambi Elysium
but I'm and,
and then he had a wonderful
thanksgiving.
So ever since that Oh man.
Stay married after that.
How's that work?
Yeah.
Probably maybe invite you probably
quietly is grateful.
Yeah.
The Dad pulls you aside and slips your
20s
than me.
Butter,
which some people do have weird
sleepwalking things though.
Sleep while I did as a kid.
Did you
[inaudible] like around kindergarten?
I would,
uh,
I would come out into like the living
room,
just screaming and crying.
Woe
and not have any recollection?
No,
none.
I did have recurring nightmares that I
remember the one very clear one was um,
it was a blackness,
you know,
sometimes when you're sleeping and then
you can feel the,
the black,
this,
the space was just very big and you felt
very small in it.
And uh,
there would be rumbling real mum,
mum,
mum.
And it would build on the momentum
recording,
bum,
bum bum.
And uh,
and I would feel kind of pulled back a
little bit and it got a silent okay.
And uh,
and then the terrorists have two tanks
would slowly come into the periphery on
the left and the right of a mum,
mum,
the,
and you see like the governor of the
tank and the tanks would slowly start
going towards each other from the left
and the right.
And then they would fall down this hole
and you'd get that feeling of falling.
And then sometimes I'd see the face of
it.
My father,
sometimes I have dreams of falling off
of things.
Yeah.
What's that supposed to mean?
That means that you're going to get
money.
Powerful.
Is that good?
Sometimes I do though.
Sometimes I have dreams where I'm like
catching myself like I'm on a tree.
This tree,
hang on.
Yeah.
What am I doing on the edge of this
building?
What am I doing on that cliff?
You get back to the same spot.
Get back to the same spot.
So I wouldn't connect the dream to the
sleep walking,
but what do you think it is?
I mean,
I don't know.
It could have been connected.
Dude,
you're a doctor.
Is that,
I remember one time I was at my friends
sleeping over my friend's house and the
next morning they were like,
Tommy can't sleep here anymore because I
did it at their house where they just
asleep and then you got some kids
screaming in the middle of screaming in
the middle of then crying and screaming
in the middle of the living room.
I've had kids do that at my house.
You have?
Yeah.
You pick them up being,
are you okay?
Yeah,
we'll let him to the bed.
You know?
It's the one kids too,
man.
It's so hard.
People don't have kids to understand
this.
But like,
yeah,
it's when I,
I'm sorry this before,
but when I was on planes before I would
be bummed out if a kid was crying was
fucking great.
There's a lot of fun fucking loud,
stupid kid.
Quiet your kid up.
Yup.
But now I'm like,
aww,
poor little kid.
Yeah.
Like it doesn't it that you don't even
hear it,
but it doesn't bother me.
No.
Like I'm upset,
I can't sleep.
It's like a little kid.
Yeah.
Once you hit so different,
once you have it
hopefully and the parents,
you,
uh,
I have empathy for the parents.
Like you're like,
oh,
I've been there when you're going
through that thing is just so rough and
it,
but it really is an instinct.
Like there is,
there is no,
like when you hear a baby crying and
plain,
there's not that thing.
When you had,
when you were younger,
this is just like get it Outta here.
Yeah.
That's a weird thing that people do
have.
Like,
I've seen it before were like young boys
in particular do not like babies.
No,
they don't like kids.
And they're around.
I'm like,
Oh yeah.
They'll roll their eyes and it's like to
them instinct.
Yeah.
And then once you have them,
you would just like,
but it's funny when you see like teenage
boys around them,
especially ones that haven't been raised
around kids.
Maybe it's the instinct that they're
going to have to,
uh,
one day take care of one of those.
Yeah.
And the party is going to end.
They're going to track,
be trapped.
The part is going
to end in a,
it's funny because like there are these
chapters,
it's like this is all coming full circle
to what we're talking about with like
Richard Branson on a boat,
getting his dick sucked,
doing coke.
But,
but here's the thing,
there's a cycle.
And if you hang in there long enough
becomes cool again.
Like if you're hammered and you're 20
and you're out there,
how it a party,
it's kind of silly and it's fun.
But if you're hammered and you're 60,
it's kind of sad.
Yeah.
But if you're hammered and your 90 it's
funny again.
Yeah,
absolutely.
It's kind of,
Hey,
you're a 90 year old drunk.
I goddamn about you all just suck my
Dick,
which by the way,
apparently the latest in the sexual
harassment Olympics,
the latest a entry is Stan Lee from
marvel comics.
Really?
Yeah.
He's 95 years old.
He lives in some giant mansion and he
has a bunch of nurses and he's trying to
get them all the blown.
Of course now he says it's a shake down.
He says they're all,
they're all just trying to get money
from him.
Uh,
may very well be the case.
She or it may well very well be the case
that he is like a lot of 95 year old
dudes with 20 million bucks in the bank
and about six months to live.
Just getting it on.
Lydia,
do you try?
You'd go for it.
He swing those fucking dice.
Come on.
Seven
Stanley,
if he really can,
if you know what I mean.
If you're worth what,
hold on,
go back to that.
What does it say now?
He,
okay.
He bought someone.
Then it was revealed that someone had
bought an $850,000 condo in his name
without his knowledge.
And that was last week.
I don't know if you're at oh no.
What happened?
Follow police report after discovering
that someone had stolen $300,000 from
him.
Well,
using a forged check and then it was a
reveal that someone bought an $850,000
condo in his name without his knowledge
of fact.
It came to light when his team did a
full audit of his accounts following the
forged check.
Whether this is any way related.
Okay.
So he might be being honest.
This might be in reaction to shake down
the shakedown,
but this guy has so much money that
someone bought an $850,000 condo in his
name and he didn't learn about it until
they were going over the books.
Well,
he didn't.
Yeah.
He didn't learn about it until they
found a $300,000 stolen cheque.
Yeah,
that's a baller.
Yeah.
Stanley,
you all went out of control.
Hero out that kicked fucking ass
superhero.
Yeah.
I'd like to think that he's not the guy
who's trying to tell these maids to suck
his dick.
Naw,
I doubt it.
I like to think that.
Me Too.
I want some heroes left.
A couple of those guys,
but hang in there guys.
One more time.
Let's wrap this bitch up.
What's bringing home?
Tell these people where you're going to
be performing your wonderful standup
comedy.
I'm heading out on tour.
Joe,
where are you going,
Tom?
I'm going to Raleigh,
North Carolina.
Oh,
you're going to Charlie?
Good Nights.
No,
I'm playing a theater.
Oh,
someone's Hashtag Boleyn Duke something
energy center or something.
The Duke fucking Energy Center and then
I'm going to Va Hill,
California.
Where's that?
I'm going to,
I'm all over the place.
Where's Va Ho?
I don't know.
North of here.
Everything's north of here.
They'll tell you how to go.
Yes.
Yeah.
GPS It book.
Just go to Tom,
papa.com all my tags,
right?
Hello?
Okay,
Tom,
it's always a pleasure,
sir.
You too,
buddy.
Already seeing wonderful guests.
I always enjoy this very much.
Me Too.
I'm going to come back.
I'll bring some fresh underpants.
So dawn,
the sun,
we'll be back tomorrow with journalists,
Dan Harris,
and he's going to get in the tank first.
He's got a meditation APP and I guess a
book,
maybe just an APP night.
He's wacky.
Kids today.
Don't even read anymore.
All right,
we'll be back.
Bye Bye.
Perfect.
Just as I have to be perfect.