Hello Freak bitches.
People are really reluctant to give up
fun shit like lying and driving their
car fast like those two things.
People are gonna have a hard time with
you,
like actually getting into the,
into their mind,
seeing their actual mind and being able
to do that so we can know without a
doubt whether or not someone's guilty or
innocent.
But my question to you is if you could
get inside someone's mind and it was
like that really super.
I'm a suggestive guy they were talking
about earlier that just confessed all
the horrific demonic possession stuff
and eating babies.
What if it's like getting to that guy's
mind?
What if you can't tell?
Well,
be the case that,
that worries me,
and this is perhaps an inept segue to
politics,
but the um,
in people's minds,
what you get,
you get someone talking long enough,
you know their minds.
I mean they,
they,
they can only conceal what they're about
a only so.
Well,
and you can because you're a super smart
wizard type.
No,
but Jamie,
I don't know,
but I don't know if he's a mind reader,
but the question is what will people
care,
you know,
it's like if you,
if you have,
we don't even need a lie detector.
If you have someone who's openly line,
right,
who,
who just gets caught in lies again and
again,
you could see it too,
you feel it,
right?
But people don't seem to care right in,
at least in the political process.
And I'm thinking in this case of trump
where you have someone who is in,
in some cases line or just changing his
mind in such an incoherent way that,
um,
it's the functional equivalent of line.
I mean,
it's someone who becomes totally
unpredictable.
He has a stance that is a on Tuesday and
it's be on Wednesday.
And when the discrepancy is pointed out,
he tells her to go fuck yourself.
Right?
So it's just,
there's just no,
there is no accountability to his,
his own states of consciousness that
he's going to be held to.
And the people who love him don't seem
to care.
They actually,
in as far as I can tell,
I don't know so many of these people
personally,
but from based on social media and
seeing a few articles where someone has
explained why they love trump.
People view this as a kind of this sort
of this dishonesty,
what is,
in my view,
both dishonesty and a kind of a kind of
theatrical hucksterism.
I started sort of person who's who's
pretending to be many things that he
probably hasn't.
They see it as a new kind of
authenticity,
right?
Like this guy,
he's just letting it rip.
He doesn't care what what is true.
He doesn't care what your expectations
for coherence are.
He's just going to tell you to fuck
yourself every which way.
And this is the new way of being honest,
right?
This is a new form of into integrity.
It's amazing to watch.
It was.
It's getting.
It has been.
I'm someone who actually,
I remember on my own podcast,
I think I was talking to Paul Bloom,
this psychologist who's,
who's great and we had taught.
We got into politics and this is at
least a year ago,
but at that point I said,
there's no way we're going to be talking
about trump in a year.
I mean,
this is kind of completely flame out,
and I was.
This is A.
I don't tend to make predictions,
but this was a clear moment that I
remember making a prediction,
which is now obviously false,
but I just couldn't imagine it that this
was where people were going to find this
compelling enough to for for him to be
on the,
on the cusp of getting elected.
It's.
It is terrifying.
Have you taught,
have you taught this issue to death on
your podcast or.
I guess we kind of have.
Well,
I think this is how everybody feels.
Everybody feels like you're supposed to
be like with their person,
whether it's Bernie or whether it's for
Hillary or whether you're a trump
supporter or whatever it is,
like you have to be all in,
but if you look at the choices that
we're given,
the.
None of these kids really be described
as ideal.
No,
no.
Like Hillary Clinton.
You could want a woman in the White
House and you want to want to show
everyone that a woman can do that job
just as well as a man and she's got the
most experience.
She certainly has the most experience
dealing with foreign governments and she
certainly has the most experience in
politics,
can make an easy,
but she's also involved in to criminal
investigations.
She had an observer and her bathroom
squirrely stuff going on like,
no,
she's.
She's terrible.
In many ways.
She was gay marriage,
2013 and then wouldn't admit the change
of mind either.
She's a politician,
she's a brilliant woman,
but she's also set in her ways and a
politician,
a politician to the end and part of
being a politician has been a fucking
huckster.
You got to be able to get those people
to see your side and the way you do that
is to talk like this.
You can't talk like a normal person
needs a speech coach.
They all do.
He's terrible to.
Trump's not even good at it and he
kicked their asses.
I know,
but who knows,
but her voice or she.
She has a kind of,
to use the sexist trope,
she has a shrill voice when you,
when you get her
in front of a mic and there's a crowd
and she thinks she's talking over the
crowd,
which he doesn't have to do because
she's in front of a mic.
The sound you get is just,
it's his.
She's yelling when she doesn't need to
yell at someone.
Someone has to teach her how to dial
that back.
What you just did is called
mansplaining.
I'm explaining to the men and her crew
who should,
who should talk some sense into her,
but she is,
she's a,
she's a bad candidate,
right?
I have no doubt that she's
very smart and she's well informed and
she's qualified and she is absolutely
who I will vote for,
given the choices.
Um,
but you know,
I totally understand people's with her.
She's a liar.
She's an opportunist.
She's just almost preternaturally and
authentic.
I mean,
she's just like,
she will just focus group every third
sentence and you feel that from her.
Right?
And,
and this is all true.
And yet,
I also believe that people who say I've
never met her,
but people who know her and I've met her
say that,
you know,
behind closed doors,
one on one,
she's incredibly impressive and,
and great.
Um,
but that doesn't translate into her
candidacy.
She probably thinks she has to do it.
Old School,
you know,
I mean,
the way she's doing it,
but she,
I mean,
the thing is,
she's,
when you look at the,
what's worked,
what worries me?
So I went on facebook the other day and
I've said very little about this,
but I've made enough noise is sort that
I just made that people understand that
I,
that I'm,
you know,
for Clinton,
despite all my reservations about her,
um,
and when I got on my own facebook page,
which you have to assume is filtered by
the people who are following me on
facebook and,
and already liked me in some sense,
just like a thousand comments of pure
pain.
I mean,
no one loves hillary.
No one,
no one said,
oh,
thank God someone's,
someone's smart is for Hillary.
It was all just Bernie people and trump
people flaming me for,
for,
for the,
the most tepid possible endorsement of
Clinton.
All I said was,
listen,
I understand,
you know,
Clinton is a liar and she's,
and she's an opportunist and she's,
um,
I,
I completely get your reservations about
her,
but at least she's grown up,
right?
And
she's going to be the candidate.
It's not going to be sanders facilities
at the moment.
Now is the moment to put your political
idealism behind you if you're a sanders
person and recognize that there is a
vast difference between Clinton and
trump and no itch.
No,
she's not going to change the system,
but she's also not going to run
civilization off a cliff.
Right?
And I didn't,
I forget how I said it on facebook,
but it was just the most.
It was just,
it really was a lesser of two evils
argument.
And it just,
it was,
um,
it's amazing to see how energized and
passionate people are in defensive trump
and sanders.
And there's almost none of that for
Clinton.
It's like people are just sheepishly
saying that they do just divulging that
they will vote for Clinton.
Um,
but they are,
they may be somewhere that I haven't
noticed.
Someone loves,
absolutely loves Clinton,
but it's just,
it's.
She does not have her defenders the way
these guys do.
Have you seen the man enough to vote for
her campaign?
No.
It's with like hipster dudes with
tattoos and beards that are going to
vote for Hillary.
You know,
I hope it's fake because it's so
brilliant.
I hope it's not real.
Is it fake?
Is it?
Thank God.
It's so good though,
because it's not that fake.
It's pretty good.
Like you could almost see.
So wait a minute.
I mean,
this is not bad for
her,
right?
This is.
No,
no,
no.
It's not bad for.
Just funny that someone would make a
joke,
political ad that you have to be man
enough to vote for Hillary.
Like there's guys out there that would
buy that.
They would,
they would,
they do it.
It's a scary time because it doesn't
seem like anybody that you would want to
be president wants to be president.
And so we're left with,
all right,
what do you pick?
It's like as if we're going to play the
super bowl with three of the shittiest
teams we could find.
We're just going to go get some drunk
high school kids,
get some inmates with club feet.
We're just going to throw whoever we're
going to have the worst game ever.
And this was what this game is.
It's not a good game.
This is not a game where you've got like
a John F Kennedy versus a Lyndon Johnson
or it's not.
It's not like like powerful characters.
It's trump I guess is a really powerful
character,
but in more ways like a showman
what he's doing,
he's like,
he's putting on a great show and he's
going to win probably because he's
putting on such a great show and people
like a great show.
But I do
think I'm now have among the people who
think something new,
we're witnessing witnessing something
new with trump.
It's not just the same old thing where
the process is so onerous that it's
selecting for the kind of narcissist or
thick skin person who is willing to
submit to the process.
And then there are many,
the,
most of the good people just aren't
going to put up with this.
I mean,
yes,
there's that too.
But there's,
um,
there's some,
there's a,
it's a moment among
the electorate where it's like,
it's fun.
It's an antistatic.
There's an ant,
there's enough of an antiestablishment
mood and vote.
Now is it happening with,
with sanders to,
um,
where people just want to jam a stick in
the wheel of the system just to see what
happens.
So it's like,
well,
this is the main gripe against Hillary
really is that she is politics as usual.
She's not going to change the system,
right?
People want to change the system,
but they're not really thinking about
the implications of radically changing
the system.
And in the case of trump,
um,
I may hear or someone who is,
who was advertising his lack of
qualifications for the office in every
way that he can,
like,
he,
like there's,
there is no,
I mean,
I'm not even,
I'm not even bothered by his racism or
his misogyny or his demagoguery or is
bully.
I mean,
all of that I'm willing to guess is an
act right.
That he's decided that that's somehow
pandering his base.
And he's actually,
in truth,
he doesn't have a racist bone in his
body.
Say I'm willing to,
to believe that I'm out.
I don't know why I would think that's
plausible,
but it's,
it's,
uh,
you know,
I have a hunch that he's far more
liberal than he seems and it's just
pandering.
But the thing that,
that
can't be true is there's no way he's
actually brilliant and well informed
about all the issues and saying the
things he's saying.
He's not pretending to be as uninformed
and as incoherent and as irresponsible
as he's seeming.
Um,
because you wouldn't withhold
information that will make you a better
leader.
Well,
it's just,
it's.
Yeah.
And it's just,
well,
it's just the vacuum busyness of his
speech.
It's like he's,
he'll say that he'll say the same thing
three times in a row and it was
meaningless the first time,
right?
He'll say,
it's going to be amazing.
It's going to be very,
very amazing.
Trust me,
it's going to be so amazing.
And he does.
He does this with everything.
If you look at the transcripts of his
speeches and the fact that he can't,
he has never so far as I've seen,
he has never once strung together a
string of sentences that was
even interesting.
Right?
But he'd be like,
he's,
he's never.
He just,
there's never a moment where I read or I
say,
Oh,
this guy is smarter and better informed
than I realized that that moment never
comes.
Or I keep expecting to see that happen.
Um,
and it's a little bit like my head is
this image of like,
imagine you have an urn right way and
you just keep pulling things out of it
and all you pull out of it as junk,
right?
You pull chicken bones and broken
marbles and gum and,
and it's,
it's still possible that you,
that if you root around in that earned
long enough,
you're going to find the hope diamond.
I mean,
in each round that you pull something
out that really has no logical
implication for the next thing you might
pull out of a the earn.
But mines aren't like that when I see
what this guy says,
he does not say anything that a well
informed,
intelligent person would say.
And it's just an ideas are connected,
right?
So you can't,
um,
you can't fake this stuff.
You can't,
you can't fake being this,
this uninformed and you can't fake being
really well informed and he's just,
I mean,
we just look at one policy that he wants
the,
the um,
uh,
you know,
the rounding up of illegal aliens,
right around 11 million illegal aliens.
Now this,
this gets stated as,
yeah,
we're going to round them up and send
them back to Mexico.
Um,
and what worries me is no one seems to
care about that.
If you just look at the implications of
doing this,
it has this one policy claim alone is so
impractical and unethical.
It's just what are we talking about
here?
You're talking about like your,
your gardener,
your housekeeper or the person that
works at the carwash,
the person who picks the that you buy in
the market is going to get a knock on
the door in the middle of the night by
the Gestapo and get sent back to.
The vast majority of these people are,
are,
are law abiding.
People are just working at jobs that
Americans by and large don't want to do.
And many of them have kids who were
American citizens,
right?
And somebody to say someone's got kids
under the age of 10 who are American
citizens and what you're going to send
that person back to Mexico and you're
going to do this by the hundreds of
thousands and millions.
It's just that one point alone held in
isolation from all of the other things.
He said.
The crazy things like climate change is
a hoax concocted by the Chinese to
destroy our manufacturing base.
And um,
you know,
the fact that he likes Putin,
I mean,
everything else he said,
write this one policy,
claim alone should be enough to
disqualify a person's candidacy.
It's so crazy with the moment you look
at it,
and yet no one seems to care.
In fact,
he is just,
it's just more energizing to the people
who already like him.
I know that he said that he wanted to
build a wall,
but I didn't know that he wanted to get
rid of the illegal aliens,
round them up and around them up and do
one with them,
send them back to their country is so
crazy.
That's such a crazy idea.
And it's so brutal.
The idea that,
I mean,
it's like a,
it's a sub human thing.
The only reason why people would come to
America as because they felt they felt
like it would make their life better.
So people take a big risk.
It's not an easy way to do it if you're
poor,
you don't have any qualifications for
any unusual job.
I mean,
you're trying to get across to Mexico,
but everybody who does it does it
because they want to improve their life,
you know,
and the idea that one group of people
shouldn't be able to do it in one group
should just because they were born in
the right side of some strange line that
is only a couple hundred years old.
But,
uh,
but I actually,
no,
I'll go further in meeting him in the
middle,
whereas I think we should be able to
defend our borders,
right?
So it is,
I don't have a good argument for having
a porous border that we can't figure out
how to defend and we don't know who's
coming into the country.
Right.
So,
so I think building the wall is almost
certainly a stupid idea among his many
stupid ideas,
but I think it would be great to know
who's coming in the country and have a,
a purely legal process by which that
happened.
I mean,
ultimately that's got to be the goal.
Right?
And we are,
we're in perfectly doing that.
And um,
so I don't have an argument for open
borders or porous borders,
but the question is,
what do you do with 11 or 12 million
people who are already here doing jobs
we want them to do that help our
society,
uh,
and the vast majority of them are law
abiding people who as you say,
or just trying to have better lives,
uh,
the idea that you're going to break up
families and send people back by the
millions and the idea that you're going
to devote your law enforcement resources
to doing this when you have real
terrorism and real crime to s to deal
with.
It's just pure insanity.
Right?
And,
and,
and also totally unethical and yet he
doesn't get any points docked for this
aspiration.
I mean,
it's just,
it's one of the things around which
people are rallying.
But the climate change thing is also
insane and dangerous.
Well,
he was a birther,
right?
Yeah,
right.
He was one of the original birthers.
He was saying that Obama's birth
certificate was bullshit.
He was born in Kenya,
right?
Wasn't he one of those guys?
Oh yeah,
he was,
um,
I would love it if funding that for a
while.
I would love to,
if he got into office and just said,
listen folks,
I am nothing like this person.
I pretended to be to win the presidency.
I just wanted to show you that you can
be manipulated and get it together.
Then at peaches punk to all.
So I'm going to hire some people who
actually know how to run things and
we'll say that's the,
the,
the smart people who are voting for him
think.
And this is,
I think an actual,
a crazy position.
But they,
they think that he is just pandering to
the idiots who he needs to pander to,
to get into office.
So He's,
he's not disavowing the white
supremacists votes,
you know,
with the,
the Alacrity that you would if you were
a decent human being and you found out
that David Duke supported you.
Um,
uh,
because he needs to.
He just,
he needs those votes and he knows that,
that most of the people in his base
aren't going to care and he can just
kind of move on in the news cycle.
Um,
and he's doing this on all these issues
where he looked where smart people see
that he looks like a buffoon and,
and they,
and they are treating him as a,
the people who don't like him or
treating him as a comic figure who he
can't really believe that stuff.
He's not really,
he's too sophisticated to really believe
that stuff.
So He's just pandering.
Um,
I mean,
one is people aren't seeing if that's
true,
just how unethical and weird that is
right here.
The guy has no compunction about lying
and demonizing people.
Like let's say he,
let's say he thinks that that Clinton
really isn't guilty,
but Bill Clinton isn't really guilty of,
of a rape.
Right?
And now he's calling him a rapist.
Right now.
At the time he was saying he wasn't a
rapist and he's just being defamed.
And this is outrageous.
He was taking,
he was taking the side of a friend who,
you know,
he invited to his wedding,
but now he's,
he's calling him a rapist,
right?
In a sexual Predator who's,
who've harmed women's rights more than
anyone.
I'm so,
which is true,
right?
So,
so there's,
there's no version of the truth here
that makes trump look at all acceptable
as a person.
It's like either he knew he was a rapist
and was defending him because he was
just cozying up to power at that point.
Right.
Didn't care that he's a rapist or now
he,
he knows he's,
he's still the guy who thinks he wasn't
a rapist,
but now he just,
for purely opportunistic reasons,
he's,
he's willing to call a guy a rapist who
he knows isn't,
um,
they're both horrible.
Right?
And it's not like there's new evidence
has come forward in the intervening
years that would have changed his mind
about what happened in,
in Clinton's presidency.
So He's,
um,
uh,
but I think people think that he's got
to be much more sophisticated than he
is.
And that if he got into office,
he would just be a totally sober and
presidential person.
There's just no reason to believe that
it,
if he thinks climate change is a hoax
and that we should pull out of the Paris
accord,
then what your ramp up coal production
and we're going to bring back the coal
jobs.
I mean,
this is what he's saying,
right?
There's no reason to think he doesn't
believe this at this point.
Um,
that's just,
you know,
it is a disastrous thing for a president
to think.
The only,
um,
fascinating versions of this that I've
been hearing from people that I respect
are that the idea that he is like,
uh,
the political version of the asteroid
that killed the dinosaurs.
Like he's going to come down and smash
it and it's going to be so chaotic that
they're going to be forced to reform the
system.
And people are gonna respond in turn,
like the way people are responding
against factory farming and more people
are going Vegan,
like that kind of a thing.
They're going to see it and they gonna
respond in turn.
That is such a.
So it's like he's going to toss the
apple cart up in the air,
he's just going to fuck this whole goofy
system up and then we'll be able to
rebuild after trump has dismantled all
the,
all the different special interest
groups and lobbyists and all the people
that we really would like to get out of
the system.
We really don't like the.
The fact that they're such insane
amounts of influence that big
corporations and lobbyists have had on
the way.
Laws get passed that.
This might be the way to do it.
You have some wild man.
Everyone's fired.
You have fired.
You have fire Jetson.
It's like a character like he's coming
in.
His hair's plastic is all fired up.
He's a billionaire.
He made all his own money,
sort of dad gave him some money,
but you turned it into a lot of money.
Point being he doesn't need anybody's
money.
The truth is probably lying about the
amount of money has he is,
but he's a baller for sure though,
right?
At the very least,
he's got to be worth some cash.
Yeah.
I made.
It could be a big difference between
what he's claiming and what is in fact
true,
but he's,
he's a many
pieces here when people assume that
because he's a successful businessman,
he must understand the economy,
right?
Which is no necessary connection there,
There's a lot of rich people who are
totally confused about economics and
you,
most economists don't have a lot of
money,
so there's no real connection there.
But the,
um,
the,
uh,
I mean,
so what you're describing is
I kind of just random like,
like you're just,
let's just,
let's just smash the window and then see
what
happens,
right?
What I'm going to light a fire to this,
this place and,
and see what happens.
And that's um,
it almost any process by which you would
change the system is more intelligent
than that,
you know,
and,
and it's also not value in how much harm
one bad president could do,
right?
Like there's no,
I think even,
I haven't tested this,
but I'm imagining that even trump
supporters would answer this question
the way I would hope,
which is like if,
if I had a crystal ball that could tell
you,
we can't tell you who's going to be
president,
but it tells you how it works out for
the next president.
So like if I,
if I look in the crystal ball and it
says the next president of United States
is a disaster,
right?
Just,
it's like the worst president we've ever
had.
It just think of,
you know,
just just failures of governance and,
and the toxic influence of narcissism
and Hubris that comes along just like
once every thousand years.
Right.
Just,
just disaster.
I think,
you know,
even if you're a trump supporter,
which candidate that was like only trump
is,
is likely to screw things up that badly.
It's not.
Clinton is going to,
is going to be almost perfectly
predictable.
She's going to be a politician,
she's gonna.
She's going to be basically centrist on
a lot of the,
on foreign policy and domestic policy.
You know,
she's going to be liberal on social
issues,
um,
she is not going to
try to dismantle NATO and to get into a
war with North Korea or get into an
alliance with Putin or image.
There's,
she's not going to do something insane.
Um,
and so alliance with Putin.
Yeah.
He said basically only favorable things
about Putin.
They're homeless.
They're tight,
so she get get.
Uh,
hopefully we'll,
we'll see pictures with both of them on
horseback shirtless and out of the red
shirt on.
He'll probably keep your shirt on.
I don't see them as being the shirtless
guy.
I know.
Yeah.
When,
when you just look at the landscape
between Bernie and Hillary in him and
uh,
you know,
to me it looks like the last gasps of a
dying system.
So.
But that's representative government
system for that is a lot of people are
saying that things like that,
but they're not hearing just how
nihilistic that is if.
True.
Right.
It's like there's so much stuff we have
to get right and there's so much.
And the only tool to get it right is,
is having your,
your mind actually understand what's
going on in the world and how to
manipulate the world in the direction
you want it to go.
So you have to understand like what,
whether or not climate change is true,
your beliefs about it have to be
representative of that truth,
right?
So like let's say,
you know,
let's say it's,
let's say I'm mistaken and there's,
you know,
there is no human caused climate change
is not a problem.
And every moment spent thinking about
it,
worrying about it,
correcting for it is just a waste of
time.
That's just throwing out the wealth of
the world,
right?
Um,
that would be a terrible thing,
right?
So it really matters who's right about
that and the fact that we have a
president or a candidate who is coming
in saying,
this is all bullshit,
you know,
in,
in defiance of all of the science is,
uh,
and it's true,
but it's on every other problem.
He doesn't know anything about it.
I guarantee you he doesn't know the
difference between Sunni and Shia Islam
or which countries are Sunni
predominantly in which are Shia
predominantly,
and I mean,
I'm sure he's going to do.
I don't know what he's going to cram for
this final exam.
I'm sure before one of those debates
he's going to get someone's gonna sit
down with him and give him some bullet
points he's got to have in his head,
but his head is just not in this game.
It's never been in this game.
It's obvious from everything he says and
that's what that is.
Something you can't say about Clinton,
right?
For all of her flaws as a person,
I don't care how much you hate her as a
person.
She understands what's going on in the
world and that's.
That difference is so enormous.
Forget about all the other character
flaws of this guy who is just obviously
going to.
I mean he,
he's,
but are we attached to much to this idea
of one person being the figurehead?
We figure it out.
Someone has to be the decider.
If we all woke up today,
if everybody woke up and there was just
no government,
there was nothing more.
I'll just.
What happened?
I don't know,
but we've got to figure out how to run
this thing.
Well,
we had no,
no previous understanding of government.
Would you think anybody would say,
we need one dude to just run this whole
giant continent filled with 300 million
people?
Most likely if we woke up and we had
technology like we have today,
we have the ability to communicate like
we have today with social media and
whatever.
We would probably say we need to like
figure this out amongst each other and
find the people that have the most
qualified for each one of these
positions and start running our
government that way.
Well that that's what we're attempting
to do,
but it's just,
and I totally agree with you that it is
astonishing that out of a nation of 300
million people,
these are the choices you would think
you would think it'd be starting from
your basic,
you know,
your zero set point of just,
now we're going to reboot civilization.
Um,
you would think that if you had this
kind of process,
each candidate would be more impressive
than the next.
I,
you,
you'd be like,
I can't believe each,
each person who came to the podium like
James.
So yeah,
it'd be like,
it'd be like the dunk contest for the
NBA.
I'd be like,
oh my God,
I could just,
when you thought you saw the best dunk
in your life,
you know,
the next guy comes along and it would be
that.
It would be that on every topic,
right?
It'd be like you'd be talking about the
science of climate change.
It'll be talking about the,
the actual dynamics of the war on
terror.
You to topics that,
that seem to have no relationship where
you would have to be.
You'd be amazed that anyone could be an
expert in all of them.
You would find someone who is an expert,
a functional expert in all of them.
Agility,
winter dude.
Yeah.
But,
and,
but someone who is also ethically wise
who wasn't just wasn't obviously an
asshole.
And who,
who,
who had a,
a mature relationship to changing his or
her mind.
Right.
So like the whole bit about flip
flopping and not,
you know,
being someone who could honestly
represent changes of mind in,
across a political career.
Right.
This is nowhere written.
That is a good thing to believe today,
what you believe 20 years ago.
In fact that they do that on every
topic.
It means basically you haven't been in
dialogue with the world,
but there's something,
it's so taboo to change your mind that
either you have to lie about it or you
have to pretend it was a,
it was always that way or it's just a,
a,
I'm an assistant.
Yet the system is,
is broken in that respect.
But given the choices,
you know,
and when you have a choice between
someone who is for all her flaws,
been in the game for long enough to be
really well informed and capable of
compromise and capable of,
uh,
not just just,
um,
breaking,
the entire machine.
Um,
and you have someone who's just,
he could just kind of stepped off the
set of his reality TV show and then lied
about everything and,
and elbowed his way onto your television
set and never left because,
you know,
CNN couldn't figure out how to give the
mic to someone else.
Um,
it's a,
it's amazing.
Well,
he's a product of attention because they
realize that there's the heated race,
right?
The heated race.
This guy was really famous and in a
heated race,
this guy would say some crazy stuff and
so they would tune into them so
everybody had to do an intro.
So I,
because of him saying crazy stuff,
he accelerated the amount they were
talking about them.
So they're constantly talking about him
and barely talking about other people.
And.
But he's created a worm hole in our
political process now where there's
nothing so crazy that could disqualify
him among the people who like him to.
So he can just keep it just like nuclear
bombs of craziness that the press can't
ignore that the,
every time they think,
okay,
this is the crazy.
He said that's going to harm his
candidacy,
so let's shine a light on it.
It just helps him know he could just,
he could,
you know,
he could.
He could get on twitter right now and
say,
you know who I'd like to.
I'd like Nicki Minaj and,
and it would work for him.
It would work for them.
You would use a tweet storm of a billion
people who say,
I'd like to fuck Nikki Minaj to go get
her,
and it's insanity.
That's where we are.
But in a sense,
if w w we,
we do admit that this is a fucked up
system.
It's not ideal.
It should definitely be reworked and
it's so hard to rework.
Wouldn't the best way to rework it?
A trump asteroid just slams right into
the White House.
Boom.
Blows the whole thing sky high.
Who knows what terrible things have to
happen,
but maybe that would be enough.
The thing is we have those,
those asteroids are coming anyway.
So when you look at like nine slash 11
was an asteroid,
right?
So it's like a or,
or a superbug that,
that becomes a pandemic,
that these are things that are coming
and we need people who are in touch
with,
with reality to deal with them,
right?
So like the moment someone advertises
their,
not only their ignorance,
but the fact that they don't care that
they're ignorant and they do this again
and again,
they keep doubling down that person.
It's like if you put that person at the
helm,
what you have done is basically put
chaos at the hill,
right?
It's like this is,
this person's going to believe whatever
he believes,
regardless of the information coming in
and regardless of the consequences,
that's just,
I mean,
it's,
it's worse than having no one in charge.
I mean,
because you're,
you've,
you've put the power in this person's
hands,
right?
So this,
this person is,
everything has to go through this node
in the network that is just like an
information scrambling device,
right?
So like,
know how Matt,
no matter how good the information is
coming in,
you have everything that you've got a
bottleneck here which just screws up the
signal,
right?
Um,
that's what you're doing if you're,
if you're,
if you're hiring someone like this,
who I'm,
I mean,
yeah,
in the best case,
you're what you stated earlier would in
fact be true,
which,
uh,
he'll,
he'll get into the oval office and even
he will be scared about,
of the prospect that he is now
running the better part of human
civilization and he will hire the best
people or some semblance of the
people he can get access to and say,
tell me how to not screw this up.
And that will be a.
and then it'll,
then it'll essentially be business as
usual,
right?
In so far as you've hired,
the best people will be people.
People who are are deeply in this game
already,
right?
You know,
he'll defer to the generals when it
comes time to make war.
Being real.
Really pragmatic about how they pick
politicians and how they push certain
people and decide not to push others.
Do you think that something like trump
completely changes how they move
forward?
Now they realize that this can happen.
Like now that you see that people are so
goofy were so wwe eat out that you can
get this guy,
you know,
this is,
this is where we're at.
We've got a guys.
I told them the wall just got 10 foot
higher.
Yeah.
Everybody gets crazy.
Like how could you say that?
Once they realize that that's possible.
How long before you get like some
motivational speaker type dudes?
How long before they start jumping in
there?
Tony Robbins says,
well we,
that's what we have.
I mean,
this is.
Oh,
this is way worse than Tony Robbins for
president.
Oh yeah.
Way,
way,
way.
Tony Robbins positive dude.
Yeah.
Yeah,
but I'd vote for him.
You know,
Tony Robbins positive guy.
No,
that's not what it means,
but that sort of ability to excite
people to get like one of those
motivational speaker dudes like those
guys.
Whereas a lot of yoga pants and he's
going to,
he's going to be the next president is
going to get us in shape
to be a reality show.
America is a reality show where there
were awesome.
We're the best.
Did you see this press conference he
held?
I think it was yesterday,
no,
I did not know.
There was a very funny moment where the,
there was one journalist,
I didn't recognize who it was,
who gets hooked,
so,
so trump was being very combative with
the press pool and he was,
he was basically,
you know,
shouting them down,
not answering any of the questions and
one journalist,
just a gas said,
is this what is going to be like when
you're president and is this,
how is this going to be like to be in
the White House press corps and deal
with you?
And uh,
and he said,
yes,
this is exactly what's gonna be like.
And,
but you,
you could just see that like the
journalists,
like they,
they,
they turn the camera on the room of
journalists and they like,
they are astonished by what is happening
here.
Like they don't know they're
participating in this process and in
some sense they've created this process.
Um,
but,
uh,
no,
not all of you.
Many of you are enough of us.
Is this what you do?
Is it,
is this what it's going to be covering
you if your president?
Yeah,
let,
let me tell you to have this kind of
take charge in the restroom.
Okay.
Yeah.
It is gonna to be like this David.
If the press writes false stores like
they did with this because you know,
probably half of you are amazed that I
raised all this money.
If the press writes fault like they did
where I wanted to keep a low profile.
I didn't want the credit for raising all
this money for the vets.
I wasn't looking for the credit and by
the way more money is coming in.
I wasn't looking for the credit but I
had no choice but to do this because the
press was saying I didn't raise any
money for them.
Not only that are raised it much of it
was given a long time ago and there is a
vetting process and I think you
understand that,
but when I raised almost $6,000,000 and
probably in the end were raised more
than six because more is going to come
in and is coming in.
But when I raised five point 6 million
as of today,
more is coming in and I.
and,
and this is going to phenomenal groups
and have many
of these people vetting the people that
are getting the money and work you play
at the moment I was referring to
say here is a case where he's probably
almost certainly line about his history
of giving to veterans affairs and says
he gave money very recently after people
started fishing around to see if he
actually had given the money that he
claimed were given to,
to veterans.
Um,
but,
uh,
I mean this is.
What's difficult about this is that,
I mean the PR,
yes there are the press is highly
imperfect and there and also partisan
and there are false stories and there
are exaggerations and they screw people
over.
Yes.
And there are reasons to
not trust the press from time to time,
but the,
in this case you have a,
someone who the,
there is no amount of fact checking and
discuss information of his statements
that,
that forces him to ever acknowledge
anything that he's done wrong and the,
and the lack of acknowledgement to.
He pays no price for it among,
among the people who like him.
And so the press is powerless and then,
and then,
but the net result of like a,
of a press conference like this,
if you're a trump follower,
is he just showed how a biased and and
petty the press pool is.
Um,
and the press do need to just be beaten
up by a strong man who,
who's not gonna stand for their
bullshit.
Uh,
but it's a,
it's a,
um,
I mean if you,
it's unbecoming the very least,
that kind of communication.
It's kind of unbecoming that person that
we expect.
And that's pretty mild compared to his,
you know,
his parody of the,
of the,
um,
the disabled reporter who he saw that
bit where he did like a,
a,
um,
a cerebral palsy imitation at,
at one of his speeches.
He was the.
Yeah.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
He was interviewed by,
I don't happen to know who the.
And it was.
Roberto was.
Oh,
he was making.
He was making fun of somebody with
cerebral palsy.
I mean,
he's done so many
things that you could,
that you would think would be
fundamentally canceling of a person's
political aspirations.
Like you,
you can't even cut Marco Rubio
pretending to be like a just
goofy on someone's cerebral palsy
added at one of his campaign events.
Oh,
right.
One of the things that Ted Cruz was just
that video of him with his family.
The outtakes where they read into that.
Oh,
you didn't see it?
No,
it's a gem.
It's spectacular.
It's him with his mom and he's like,
my mom prays for me often for hours
every day,
and she was like,
she looks at him like,
what the fuck for hours every day.
No,
I don't.
He can't even say that.
And so they have all these really
awkward moments.
Like,
okay,
I'm going to go in for a hug.
I'm going to say I love you.
It's all like weirdly mapped out and
that got online and people were like,
Oh,
Christ,
okay.
See this is,
this is a bad game.
Like you're not even good at this game.
This is you.
You're terrible at this game.
Yeah.
He was objective really terrible.
Well,
that's his,
that's trumped competition.
Well,
the thing that we'll think about cruise
that never even got out,
which was the reason to be scared about
a Cruz presidency,
was his level of religious craziness.
I mean,
no one was even pushing on that because
there was just enough to push on before
he even got to that door and you have to
hold onto those weapons.
But I mean,
it hadn't been.
Had crews been the nominee,
it would have been all about religion.
What's,
what's odd is that that's not a handicap
in 2016 that you can have that and
people consider it an asset.
Well,
the one thing that's
pricing and actually hopeful in trump's
candidacy is the fact that he has,
he has dissected out the religious,
social conservative component of,
of the Republican Party.
So like evangelicals,
for the most part,
we're going for trump over crews when it
was pretty clear to them that trump was
just pretending to be religious and
Minnesota.
So trump gave one speech at,
I think Liberty University where he
spoke.
He said Corinthians two,
um,
and you know,
that's not the way any bible reader
would,
would speak about a second Corinthians.
How would you say it?
Second Corinthians,
that's how you'd say it.
Yeah.
And so,
so he,
so he said Corinthians two,
it's as though this is something he just
opened every,
every night before you went to sleep.
And so it is clear that it was clear to
them that he's,
that he is just,
just miming the language,
you know,
or,
or I'm impersonating a person of faith
and um,
but they don't care really as long as he
does it.
And that's,
that is,
you know,
if you're gonna look for a silver lining
to this,
it,
it shows that it's not,
it's they just want a space where their
religious convictions are not under
attack and they don't really care that
the person in charge share them.
Just if you pretend to share them,
that's good enough.
And that's,
um,
that's better than actually carrying
that.
This person really believe in the
rapture or anything else that is quite
obviously crazy.
Um,
but,
uh,
yeah,
so I don't think any Christian who
voting for trump thinks,
I mean they'll say I'm not going to
judge another man's faith,
right?
Or I'm not.
Who am I to say what's really in his
heart,
right?
They'll say that,
but he's just given.
If you,
if you've been paying attention to who
he's been and,
and if you just look at how he talks
about these things,
I don't think he's any,
any Christian that it.
So I think they're willing to vote for
someone for it now,
for other reasons that are fairly
depressing in their own right.
They're willing to vote for someone
who's,
who doesn't really play the game the way
they do.
You have to believe in God to be
president in 2016.
Right?
Wouldn't you?
Wouldn't you say that?
That has to pretend to believe in God.
But I think with trump,
I think it,
I think the pretense is,
is obvious enough that I don't think
he's fooling the better part of the,
of the people who were voting for him,
who,
who would,
who would say they care about a person
of faith being in the White House.
So I,
if anything,
he might be in one thing.
He might be breaking the barrier on
having an atheist president because I
think he,
it's just nobody.
Nobody thinks he is a person of faith.
I don't think anyone really thinks that.
So he's perfect.
He's made.
It might be our first atheist president
who would help us in that,
in that regard as well.
Another trump media right into the White
House.
You,
I'm starting to sound like a trump
supporter.
Occasionally an asteroid does something
good.
Who would be the ideal president?
I mean like what,
what kind of a person?
I mean,
it would probably be a person who
doesn't seek attention.
Probably be a person that they could be
that.
I mean
the process is even,
even an optimized process will be,
um,
we'll record.
It will require a sacrifice of what
ordinary people want,
most of the time that it will be an
unusual personality who has to get
promoted and you will,
you will be on some metric be,
I mean,
it's almost by definition,
narcissistic to think that you should be
in this role,
right?
Who are you to think that you should be
running a civilization at this moment in
human history?
Um,
and to,
for you to be on it,
for you to honestly stand at the podium
and say,
I'm the guy or the woman,
I am the most qualified.
I should be doing this.
Right?
I can help.
Um,
if you,
if you're going to scrutinize the kind
of personality that could give rise to
those opinions,
it's not you.
Yeah,
there's,
there are some dials you would probably
want to change,
tweak if you,
if you had to be married to this person
or if it's not an optimal personality.
So there's going to be kind of pathology
of power seeking that might be just
intrinsic to it.
But
you want someone who is actually wise
ethically.
I mean,
just,
you're just trying to map that onto
trump,
right?
Just,
he's imagined someone saying thing I
like about trump is that he is so deeply
ethical and wise.
Right?
It's just,
it does not.
I mean,
it's like saying it's because his hair
looks so natural.
Yeah.
I mean there's just no,
um,
it is,
is the antithesis of what he is.
Right.
Um,
the thing I like about trump is that he
is so well informed about the way the
world works,
um,
and where he's not informed.
He recognizes his ignorance so quickly
and he remedies that as fast as
possible.
He,
he,
he seeks out the best experts,
defers to them.
Um,
and uh,
you know,
he's just,
he's mindful of the limits of his
knowledge.
Seo As,
as he is about his expertise and his
expertise is vast.
Right.
You'd want to be able to say that about
a president.
You could not begin to say that about
trump.
Right?
Um,
you could probably say that honestly.
You could probably say that about
Clinton,
right?
Like for Hillary,
for all her defects,
she's very knowledgeable and I'm sure
she will just try it.
Where she,
where she doesn't feel like she's got
the knowledge he's going to try to go
to,
go to the source of the knowledge.
Right.
Just grab the best experts you can find.
Um,
I think she,
I think she will be as aware as you are.
I would be of the consequences of not
knowing what's going on.
Right?
She's just going to want to find out
what's going on.
Whereas this,
I mean all trump has advertised about
himself is that he thinks that bluster
and banality and bullying will win in
every situation.
It's just like,
it's just attitude.
He's the guy is the guy is winging it
and it could not be more obvious that
this guy is winging it on every level.
I mean,
it's like it's just,
it is,
it is
not there.
There'd be no way for him to signal the
fact that he's winging it more clearly
than he is with everything he's doing.
And,
and yet there's no penalty.
Do you think it's possible that in this
age of information,
the way we can communicate with each
other that we're going to experience
these cycles,
these waves,
these in and outs,
these high and low tides of really smart
presidents and really stupid president
and we just people revolt and there's
just.
It's so easy to stay alive is plenty of
students who fill out there and so
they're only willing to vote for other
dme folks,
so the other dme folks get into
position.
They send out the frequency that only
the dummies here and everybody else is
going,
what the fuck is everybody voting for
this guy for what is happening,
and then it makes the smart people
rebound and for years and challenge
themselves a new because they.
They need some sort of an enemy to rally
against to reach their full potential
and that without the low tide you cannot
have the high tide Sam Harris.
That's hopefully.
That's not an analogy that applies to
the maintenance of civilization.
The smell.
Yeah.
The time man.
Maybe at the very least it's a wakeup
call for the establishment.
This silly game that you've been running
have two candidates,
just doesn't work.
Someone can cooperate your candidacy,
get in there,
throw the fucking monkey wrench into the
gear system,
and guess what?
Trump's running for president now.
He's the.
He's the head,
he's the head guy for the Republicans.
How is that even possible?
They don't know.
I met with amazing.
It is a way,
if nothing else,
it has a total wakeup call for the
Republicans.
I mean they are just,
it's June aghast.
Yeah,
it's June.
Everything's decided locked down.
So we have July,
August,
September,
October,
November.
We're that close.
But he's not someone who has been.
Who is aligned with the Republican
platform in most ways.
Right.
So it's like he's been.
Truth is virtually no one knows what his
policies are because he,
he keeps changing his position on things
like taxation.
It's like if there actually is no keys.
He said he's talked to on both sides of,
of,
of core issue,
core Republican issues.
But
I mean,
in many ways he's left of Hillary,
right?
He's,
you know,
he's left of Hillary in terms of being
an isolationist.
Like he's,
you know,
he,
his,
his relationship to war is,
but both extremes.
Like,
he's like,
no,
we're just going to,
we're going to get out of the world's
business,
right?
We're going to be isolationists,
which is deeply anti Republican.
Um,
but I'm going to be the maniac who
you're never going to know who I'm going
to bomb next.
We're going to keep.
We're going to wipe out isis.
We're just straight away,
right?
Did Not,
not a man left standing.
Um,
and I'm not gonna take any shit from
anyone including China and North Korea.
And so he's that.
But we're going to pull back in a huge
way and not be in anyone's business,
right?
He said both of those things.
Um,
uh,
it's,
it's way too interesting way.
We don't want politics to be this
interesting and it's going to be
November is going to be,
if the polls are closed and watching
those debates and,
and,
uh,
waiting for a swing in the polls,
as a result,
it's going to be,
it's going to be way too interesting.
That's gonna be like watching the
superbowl,
those first debates,
you know,
it's going to be 100 million people
watching those debates.
I have a prediction.
I think,
uh,
I think it's entirely possible.
This whole thing was a plot that didn't
work out.
I think he probably came out of the gate
saying crazy shit thinking he would tank
the Republican Party and get his friend
Hillary Clinton into the White House.
Did it.
Well,
she didn't tend to work out.
He kept trying to insult her,
kept trying to make stuff up about
Mexicans and it just kept making them
get better and better and now he's
stuck.
He can't pull out.
That would be.
That would be a great moment and that
would change the system.
Well,
we're going to have to go through
something like this in order for us to
realize that this is crazy,
that a guy can just do this,
can just not really have any interest in
politics.
Until then he should get the Nobel prize
for everything.
If he pulls out at this point and says,
listen,
I'm just took you to the precipice here,
just because I wanted you to recognize
how unstable this situation is.
I mean,
you,
you guys could elect a demagogue who is
actually an incoherent demagogue.
I'm not,
I haven't even been playing an
incoherent authoritarian,
right?
I'm,
uh,
on one hand,
a very liberal,
right and tolerant.
And on the other hand,
I'm like getting ready to be Hitler and
you guys can't figure out who I am and
yet you're still prepared to vote for
me.
I mean,
yeah,
for him to do a postmortem on,
on his punking of,
of the culture,
that would be the best thing to ever
happen.
But I don't think that's,
that's what's happening.
And we need someone like this.
So the,
we realized how silly this whole thing
is.
Do we need.
Some are like,
no,
we need a qualified person to deal with
all of the other hassles and dangers
that are coming our way that have
nothing to do with,
with what we do.
Like that person's not there.
Even if we were doing everything
perfectly,
they would still be this tsunami of risk
and hassle and
waste and,
uh,
just all the rest of the world chaos
that is coming our way.
And it just forget even if we had our,
our house in order,
in every respect,
we still have terrorism and the global
climate change,
you know,
you have,
you've got China and India and what are
they doing in terms of complying with,
with,
um,
climate goals?
Uh,
you have all the things we've been
talking about,
the virtual certainty that there's going
to be a pandemic at the,
the not want to talking about
bioterrorism.
We're talking about just the sheer fact
that in 1919 there was a killer flu and
there's gonna be another killer.
Flew right?
There's just no way.
There's not going to be another killer
flu.
Um,
and we need,
we need people and we need people,
people to smart people to change the,
to optimize the system,
to deal with these kinds of things.
And if we're promoting religious maniacs
and,
and crazy narcissists and uh,
liars,
um,
and ignoramuses and only that,
those people,
how could this end will know this is
just a weird year for leg heavyweight
boxing,
you know,
they have those weird years for Tony.
And then were you were,
you could be the heavyweight champion of
the world.
They went through a period of time
in the early eighties for Tyson,
came around,
was a series of like these champs that
were like,
you know,
sort of like journeymen fighters.
And then Tyson came along.
Maybe that's what it is,
but only with only with heavy weights,
right?
Yeah,
mostly with heavyweights.
Yeah.
And the lighter weights,
they were always bad ass.
But I think that maybe that's what's
going on.
Maybe we need to have this bad season,
get the season out of our way,
realize the danger of having an inept
person in office,
whether it's a liar or a dude who hates
money or,
or,
or trump or whoever it is.
Just go through it and realize how silly
it is that we have it set up this way
still.