And boom,
Danielle liberal friend here we go to
the love and I am loving rather I should
say,
your new podcast,
history on fire.
And it's just wonderful to hear your
soul tree Italian accent,
a waxing politically on the past.
That's because,
uh,
I just never learned to speak English.
Right?
But you do speak.
It's very confusing to me because you do
speak perfect English.
You understand it,
you're very articulate.
Your choice of words is excellent,
but it comes out like,
how come I can do that?
But you can't do that.
Can you try to talk like me if you can
believe it?
I think I do half of the time I'm like,
what accent?
English.
What are you talking about?
I have a horrible year for racks.
I just don't tear it.
Don't hear it.
You know,
when I hear my recording that I go back,
I'm like,
Jesus Christ,
I really speak like that.
But you know what?
A bulky.
Right now you're in my own voicemail.
No,
perfect.
There's no accident data is one of the
great things about doing a podcast is
that it forces you to listen to your
side.
Yeah.
And you can learn a lot about how you
sound.
Yep.
You know,
you really can't.
You learn a lot about little things you
do like,
like the word,
like hats.
That's one thing people say like fucking
way too off a lot.
That's a real problem.
That word like,
like I've tried to shorten it or to
eliminate it,
but it fucking creeps its way in like,
you know,
man,
like it's like this guy like it.
Some people in the problem is if I
fixate on it,
if I fixate on someone saying it like
then it breaks me.
Then I have same thing I was talking
with some guy was really smart and
really brilliant.
They kept saying,
you know,
every four wards,
and I could not follow the conversation
where he was making great points too,
so I was missing out because they're
psychos.
Like,
oh no,
no,
no.
You know,
it's like a fuck.
You go away.
It's a tech.
It gets a,
it's a,
a speech pattern.
It's basically a version of a
[inaudible] or A.
I've always said that that's what people
do with the word fuck.
Sometimes it's a.
it's a use of the word fuck this fucking
guy with this fucking thing.
The fucking.
Yeah.
It's a filler.
That's why I'm super impressed with
people like Sam Harris that talk with no
filler.
They just just that on from.
I don't.
My brain doesn't work like that.
I'm always scrambling for certain words
or trying to wonder if I was.
My vocabulary was better.
Maybe I would be less likely to use
fillers,
but I dunno.
I think he's like,
dude in conversation sometimes you
needed that Mike.
It'll mess up big to just see,
okay,
where do I want to go to wait to next?
You know,
but you don't want to leave an awkward
pose a car,
like throwing something out there.
Just go through the dcs wherever you
want to go next.
Can you also don't want someone to like
jump in thinking you want them to talk
and like you're in the middle of trying
to form the sentence and if
they do jump in then you'll totally lose
it.
So you want to,
um,
just to let them know I'm thing is a
instead of just going,
I've had.
Yeah,
exactly.
And that everybody at least painful that
way because you don't normally,
you give a two and suppose between
somebody starting in somebody's
beginning of the next conversation,
he,
there's no posts.
Everybody's just there waiting for you
to not stop but slow down so that they
can jump in at that age.
Did you see people take a deep breath?
Kind of like Jesus mad.
It's like it's a full contact sport
talking to somebody.
It's just your language is so,
uh,
it's so poetic.
It's a flowing.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Beautiful language that fat is great for
English.
Language is also make sure we're not at
all an empire.
Right?
Is like you tell people,
do this,
get stuff done.
You know,
it's very to the point,
it's weak.
It's to the point,
it's great.
Italian is great for flowery.
Oh Sweetheart,
look at the beautiful bone out there
kind of thing where you just wait,
you said 10,000
words to really say something that could
have been saving five,
but it's the vibe that you create that.
Yeah,
there's a lot of work,
but it's flowing.
Yep.
It's like wine and poetry.
It's like,
Whoa,
it's got this sort of.
Whereas American is just like,
Hey,
what's up?
Fuck face.
It's no,
and I was starting to write in English.
It was so damn hard for me because I was
so used to these long flowy sentence.
That's like De de,
De,
de,
de.
There was these right?
Very musical.
And you know,
any sentence that I would write like
that in English,
I lose half of the readers within three
seconds because that's too many words.
Get to the point,
you know,
what are you trying to say?
And so it's like,
and I taught English sucks.
There's no boy.
There's a reality that is,
you know,
there are ways to express yourself
beautifully,
but it's different.
You need to definitely toned down the
line of the sentences a little shorter.
There are ways to do it,
stealing it,
but for the way,
but he's completely different.
What about the attention spans of people
in Italy versus the people in America?
Because the,
the Italian attention span seems to be
much longer.
There is some of that,
I don't know if he's still through a,
I don't know if it's a genetic thing or
not because I go to their back on
vacation so I don't have the pulse of
the situation anymore the way he used
to.
Um,
he may be a generational thing.
He was that way certainly when I was
growing up,
but there was clearly more attention
span.
But then again that was before a
thousand sinks that we'll use to
distract ourselves time where it's like
somebody's sticking to you,
but I'm like,
ah,
let me send this email.
Well,
yeah,
yeah.
That's great.
Good point.
But you're doing something else at the
same time.
Well,
correct me if I'm wrong,
but like a classical Italian meal,
like in a,
in a restaurant,
like you would sit there for hours.
Yeah.
It's not like America where you're in
and out in 40 now.
Definitely.
Yeah.
There's much more of these as low pace
and a creeping me out the other day.
Um,
whole body.
Marco's give me a call and within about
a minute I was sinking and I,
I love ovarian,
but the vibe for me was like,
okay,
great.
Hi.
What's up now?
What do you want?
And then I realized that he wasn't
calling because he wanted anything.
He just wanted to say what's up and
chat.
And I was like,
oh,
I forgot what it's like to be that way.
It's nice.
I liked it,
you know,
that's a good feeling.
Good.
Or You just,
we're just talking because we like to
talk to each other.
It's not like,
hey,
I need something or you know,
uh,
I'm so used to that conversation now
that everything is for a reason.
It's like we're trying to get stuff
done.
And uh,
it was so refreshing as feeding,
this is beautiful.
I love it.
I miss it.
That's how it should be.
It's nice if you can catch someone
that's on the same vibe,
but when you're like,
hey man,
everything good?
What's going on?
Yeah,
yeah.
I'm just getting some shit done.
What's up?
I just called to say hello like well hi.
Bye.
GotTa go.
I'm running an empire running the empire
of Mike and I mean we do.
We do have a,
I don't know how he got that way,
but we do have intense busy lives.
So sometime that organic or relax.
So let's hang out.
Let's see.
Let's things transpire and play half of
the time it's like,
okay,
it's known at one.
I need to be out of here.
This is my fun time.
So it's 1215 motherfucker.
I'm not having fun yet making it fun
right now because I need to.
It's like you can do that too.
I was listening to this Ted talk on the
nature of happiness and I forget the,
the gentleman who was doing the speaking
but he was um,
he uh,
was.
He had developed an APP and in the APP,
uh,
it would like hit you with reminders and
ask you questions like what are you
doing right now?
Are you enjoying what you're doing right
now is just what you want to do?
And like things along those lines.
And then they would gather data and so
they,
they added all their data from all the
people that use the APP and one of the
things they found was one of the least
conducive things to happiness.
One of the,
one of the indicators that people are
not happy is when your mind is
wandering,
like you just sitting around thinking of
nothing,
just sitting and doing nothing.
And in those moments,
for whatever reason,
people just don't feel good,
right?
They,
their mind will wander to the negative
things,
but when you're in the moment and you're
occupied in something,
whether you're creating something or
whether you're writing something or
whatever you're doing,
like those are the moments where people
feel fulfilled and happy.
No,
definitely in there something to be said
for meditation in that regard of
learning to be in the moment when,
because you know a lot of the times we
can be in the moment when we're doing
something,
but to be in the moment when you're not
doing something,
just like,
let me take a deep breath,
let's be.
Or let's look around.
That's not as easy to do as weird thing.
Yeah.
That's why like our class,
whether it's a martial arts class or a
yoga class is really good for people
because someone's telling you what to
do.
Like,
okay,
now we're going to work on armbars from
the mount.
You know,
I could get to the mount.
Okay.
Shift your hips to the left,
grab the arm pit and Diane and in going
through those steps you have forced to
concentrate on that thing and because
it's so intense,
you're forced to be in that moment and
that for a lot of people is a real.
Not just the physical relief of
exercise,
which is fantastic for the mind,
but the relief of focus and
concentration alleviates a lot of the
bullshit that is like,
that builds up when the mind is
wandering time.
I notice when I do get to,
I finally had a chance to start rolling
again the last month or two,
if that's all fucking good.
Oh my God.
I forgot.
Not only physically,
as you say,
I'll go to fields,
but in that moment,
you know if your mind wanders too much,
the guy's choking.
You guys aren't buying or you can't
wander.
You have to be totally present in what
you're doing and he is just such a
mental break that I thought I had all
these issues when I walk into class and
I walk out of those problems,
you call it those problems.
That's a joke.
Come on.
Big Deal because suddenly you have
lightened up.
You'll go read of this heavy load they
are carrying and there's nothing like
it.
You know,
something that puts you in the moment,
but also your body puts your body,
your mind,
everything.
The gift of perspective.
Yep.
Yeah,
and some people get it from running,
you know,
I know,
I know some people they just love or
like running hills
especially,
you know,
because it's just so difficult and then
when when you reach the top of that
hill,
you have a milestone,
you hit that milestone to get to that
hill and just whatever it is that effort
of doing that,
which is very intensive,
very difficult just when it's over,
just everything else seems like relaxed
bake time.
Even weights.
Yeah,
sure.
Anything,
anything.
Just do something that you have to
concentrate on.
You know,
like if you're lifting something heavy,
like if you're trying to bench press or
squat or something like that,
like while you're doing that,
that is what you're concentrating on.
Amazing though,
that that's what the mind needs
sometimes just one primary singular
thing to focus on and to focus on an
intensely and it's almost cleansing in a
way.
Forces the pipes.
Yeah.
It's kind of like when you have insects
for too long and then you'd wait that
suddenly everything in your brain
switches.
It's like,
oh,
this shit that I felt I had on me or
this tension,
all this stuff that I felt were real
problems.
You just haven't had sex for too many
days in a row.
Haven't had sex for a long time.
Yeah.
I thought you were saying you've had sex
for too long.
I was like know such and such a thing as
doing some sessions,
some session work Myra.
Yeah,
but that's good.
Fuck people up,
man.
I mean,
I,
I
to this day think that that is,
especially for men,
the primary reason why a lot of men
exhibit like really pathetic behavior
because they are trying so hard to get
women to like them and nothing is
working and so they have fallen into
this trap of becoming this like she male
thing this,
this like super feminist,
sort of always a identifying with
women's issues and trying to get women
on your side and it doesn't fucking
work.
No,
like Dave Rubin,
a guy was on the podcast the other day.
He,
uh,
by the way,
great guy,
great podcast.
Had a great time with them,
but he tweeted something the other day
and it was a billboard that some poor
fool had put up and it said,
dear women,
on behalf of all men,
I'm sorry.
She's right.
That the ps two died would be.
I'm really trying to get laid,
really trying so hard at me with someone
touched my deck.
Yeah,
police.
That would have been more honest.
You have to just put that on the
billboard is like with the number at the
ad is like,
Oh,
poor guy.
I got it.
Yeah.
I mean it's like,
not that there's anything wrong with
siding with women if you agree that
they'd been fucked over or looking at
for them out for them or you know,
and sympathizing or empathizing.
That's not the point.
It's just the behavior.
It's.
And it's also an anti masculine behavior
and anti male behavior.
Maybe it's because they identify,
they identify those,
those characteristics with bullies or
people that were mean to them or people
that you know,
caused them pain or frustration,
but it's also like this.
It's traitorous.
You know what I mean?
It's like you're a gender traitor,
like in some ways to me there's that
bullshit dichotomy there where you have
the strong natural asshole that was
older soul kind of doesn't care about
anybody's feeling.
Some days by your strong that's the good
side or use to sweet little sensitive,
but if you say you go,
Hi Dina color and I run and he's like
both them all data suck.
Neither one is a desirable way to beat
you in.
The problem is that in trying to get rid
of the acid male side,
people who have also gotten rid of the
good stuff about being a man about this
thing,
that it.
There'll be a nation,
the stereotypical masculine quality and
it's like,
that's not what we're trying to get rid
of.
That's the good stuff.
You want to keep that.
You want to get rid of.
You know the 79.
It's gender role.
I'm the man I was lucky around and go
back into the kitchen kind of thing.
Yeah,
I can see how that would be less than
ideal,
but they get the lead off.
That doesn't mean get rid of the good
stuff at all.
Exactly the term.
Have you heard the term toxic toxic
masculinity?
That's an adorable term,
but like social justice warriors or
throw around toxic masculinity and the
real problem with men adopting this idea
is that they ignore the negative things
that women have
done because it's not about women.
It's not about men.
It's about nice people.
That's really what it is.
I mean there's feminine qualities that
are beautiful and there's male masculine
qualities that are beautiful and
there's,
there's people on both sides that are
out of their fucking mind and bat shit
crazy and to side with women on every
occasion.
Just because you're a man,
you're saying,
I'm sorry for all men before we.
And my apologies.
That's weak shit.
You know what you're doing.
You need to run hills,
okay,
you need to go to class,
take a yoga class to something but
hadn't gotten laid or get someone to
touch you.
And it's funny cause when you don't come
from a place of need,
suddenly we may like you paying times as
much as before.
There was a period where I did not,
it wasn't running anymore on the typical
script that I've had for most of my life
where it's like,
Whoa,
I want your attention.
Look at that one time thing for me.
Yeah,
there was a period where seeing sap,
but either way where I didn't care.
I'm just like,
if we haven't got.
I haven't got with [inaudible] I'm happy
to,
but I don't want.
Yeah,
you are beautiful lawn.
That's great,
but I don't want anything from you.
And of course the second,
but my brain switched awake suddenly
been like 10 times more than before and
he was like,
okay,
that works.
That's amazing,
isn't it?
It's,
but there's something about being
comfortable in your own skin and just
know constantly acting because you're
trying to impress somebody or you want
somebody to.
Whether it's sex,
whether it is attention,
whether whatever that may be because you
want something from them.
It's like,
this is why I am.
You dig it.
You don't.
I'm still comfortable with who I am.
It makes such a difference when people,
whether today too.
I think also the,
regardless of the words that you choose
and the way that you say them in the
sentences that you structure,
I think people can feel intent and they
can just something about it.
There's an intangible quality to a needy
person that even if they do say the
right things and do it in the right
order,
you know,
some women or some manner like fucking,
not this,
not this dude.
That's why you can read all the books
into wired about the stuff you say.
That's barely half of the game.
You know,
there's a,
it's who you are is not what you say,
what the image you put.
Even because it's painful,
you have to constantly keep up this
image that's not reading you and you
have to say all the right thing is like,
how can I say short?
Yeah.
Or towards
that.
Have you ever paid attention at all to
pick up artists?
Yeah,
and pickup artist game.
They're like,
they'll,
they'll just.
It's hilarious.
I've seen some videos online where
they're actually critiquing people's
approaches and strategies for getting
women to talk to them.
There's like videos on it where a guy
will have a hidden camera and they'll
talk to a girl and then the guys in the
comments will be like interesting.
Like opening great game.
I like how he's doing this like they
have like like moves like it's talking
about like Jujitsu or something or the
way you lean to the right.
Talking to where that call
that's like too much but it's not real.
That's what's crazy about it.
I mean I guess it will work on some
really fucking dumb girls.
That's how it girls will find out like
deep into a relationship like months
later that the guys like heavily in debt
and wanted by the FBI and you know,
beats his mom like you don't find find
that shit out because he got tricked you
with all this,
this strategy and if you can't read that
then you're not going to know that
something's going on.
But that to me is if you ever really bad
the radar and you can get out of people,
then you are dependent on what they say.
Some people are bad radar,
but what they say is a smoke screen,
you know,
and they say maybe real,
maybe in all its people put on a show at
the time and to me it's like,
really?
You didn't feel sitting next to the guy
for 35 cycles that that guy's a freak or
a woman is evil,
or man,
you feel it.
It's not what they say.
It's but it's hard.
It's hard to have sovereignty.
It's hard to have personal sovereignty.
It's hard to be at a place where you
don't need anybody or you're not needy
or when you're around a beautiful girl,
you don't give a fuck.
That's hard,
man.
It's hard.
Most men,
I would say like 99 percent of men when
they're around a really beautiful girl,
they just panic.
They start.
Even if there's no chance that girl's
gonna fuck you.
You're your behavior alters.
It gets weird.
My solution to it's illegal in 49 and a
half state,
but I think that going toward the nine
and a half because it's legally in rural
counties in Nevada,
but going tweens,
sanely halt,
who curse,
calm people down for immense them point
would be like,
okay,
if I want to get laid with seemingly
hall tool when I can mind Nicole,
you are nice to them.
They're nice to you,
done so if you do that,
then in the back of your brain is not
like every time you see a hot woman,
he's like,
I want these as I couldn't.
I couldn't get these any other time in
another way.
You don't have a game and you've kind of
got lady now other ways.
At least you'll go to the nice,
friendly,
who'll courage you've got laid out to
him.
Women.
Then women don't immediately trigger,
I need something from you.
It's like another hot woman.
I was having sex with a woman yesterday,
so what do you know?
It doesn't have that same pressure with,
so that might.
I have a vague feeling that I'm not
going to get a TV program on a doctor
feel recommended.
Just go to Ku.
Kersey make their life better,
but that's my thing.
Well,
I'll tell you right now.
That is the wrong approach.
It ain't about the woman being hot.
It's about love.
Serve.
Sorry to buy your right.
We'll just throw by my ankle.
Your balls will.
They'll rot if you hear that long
enough.
So they get angry and they fall right
off.
Yeah.
I think that the idea of going to a
hooker in America is disgusting idea.
Like that's how we look at it.
And as our culture,
our culture,
our culture looks at prostitution is
something foul and you and I both have
daughters.
We don't want our daughters to become
prostitutes,
but if you know somebody else's daughter
wants to do it.
So you are son.
There are cases where somebody become a
whole car because they are life socks
and they are on.
They are decent.
That,
that's clearly not.
But I've had,
I didn't know a women who have,
uh,
who need to become sex workers who are
speak multiple languages.
Graduated from Ucla,
they have jobs,
they have money,
they have stuck in their ways a day you
have the power and the exchange because
the way they are going to play it is
that they couldn't see their kind of
like dating except that Ip can my
clients.
And so he's like,
I'm leaping around a lot but I get paid
bank for doing that and that's a whole
different kind of,
you know,
not all.
Prostitution is the same.
That's a whole different game that
somebody will come through acquisition
where they are empowered reatard and the
typical street hooker kind of thing.
That's a whole different game.
Yeah.
I've met girls that have done that,
that have actually like had like wealthy
men that they've had sex with and then
they only had like a few of them and
they,
you know,
they fucked him like a couple times a
month and that was there.
That was how they made all their money.
Right.
And they but they didn't like take other
clients on and I was like that is just
weird.
That is weird.
But,
but why is it weird?
Because when you look at like a really
hot woman,
like the Donald Sterling situation,
that old troll looking raised in man,
and he had that girl that,
uh,
the one that ratted them out and made
those recordings.
She was hot.
She was young and hot with a nice body.
Like what do,
what do we think is going on there?
Why do we think he bought her a
multimillion dollar condo and a Bentley
and all that.
Why is it okay to just by people so you
can exchange gold coins.
Can you exchange gold coins is not
paper.
I work Saturday.
Can you buy someone a house?
You just can't give them cash.
I get weird.
Like why is the exchange?
Like when the exchange is actual money,
not something that you can convert to
money,
but the actual money itself,
it becomes an issue.
Like prostitution exists across the
board in many,
many relationships.
I have friends that are married to
prostitutes.
They really are.
They just happened to be monogamous,
but also that they're monogamous
prostitutes.
But these guys are wealthy guys and
there's these women that they're dating
really don't even particularly like them
and they have to buy them things all the
time.
Gosh,
they have to constantly keep the fires
of this.
Uh,
this style of relationship lit that I
find weird is like easy,
easier to just pay for echolook are
gold.
They are each tie but those.
But then,
you know,
the problem is people want
companionship.
They want someone to be there for them.
You're not going to get the by paying
somebody for that.
Sometimes it works.
Yeah,
I dunno.
It's like saying it can never work.
I just think that a lot of people would
be way better off a lot of people if sex
wasn't such a big deal.
Yep.
And I think that is a big part of what's
going on.
Like part of what's going on with,
with campuses,
um,
were there,
they have this massive amount of
attention that's being paid to sexual
assault is very good in a lot of ways.
But your sexual assault,
actual real sexual assault is horrific.
Fucking that's disgusting.
It's fucked up.
And you know,
the idea that my son could do it or that
I could have done it when I was young as
it's terrifying to me and disgusting to
me,
but equally equally true.
The idea of someone being accused of
sexual assault where it really was just
regret that,
you know,
there's a lot of people that are trying
to say that if two people get drunk and
they have sex and then somehow or
another that rape and it's just people
having sex.
There's no violence,
there's no forcing.
There's no,
that's,
that's crazy talk.
And a lot of that comes from the idea,
these puritanical ideas that sex is
somehow a bad thing because if two
people got together and they got drunk
and just cuddled,
no one gives a shit.
Yeah,
that's fine.
But it's like,
where does it end?
Like he would,
okay,
what if you just cuddle and you both
have shorts on and a t shirt and the guy
gets a boner.
Like what happens there?
You know,
is that bad?
Like what if,
what if you're cuddling and the guy and
the girl don't have shirts on,
but they have their pants on,
like what the fuck are we doing?
I don't know if people,
if they're drunk and they hug everyone's
okay,
but if they're drunk and they fuck,
it's a real problem,
right?
Well,
if,
if someone says no and the other person
forces them or does it,
then the problem is of course.
But if it's just two people that drink
and then do something in the other
person wakes up in the morning,
he goes,
I can't believe it.
Fuck that Guy Shit.
And then their friends,
oh my God,
were you drunk when you could not
consent.
That is rape.
It's not rape.
He was drunk too,
right?
Like there was uh,
this,
uh,
I forget what the protest was,
but these guys had these signs that said
regret is not rape and there was this
fucking terrible backlash this.
But that is what it is,
is regret.
Whatever happened to fucking up would
have ever happened to making mistakes.
And also why is it that one gender gets
a g get out of jail free card,
like you got raped.
Whereas every guy that I've ever met has
gotten drunk and had sex with someone
that they regretted.
And then after it's over the like,
oh Jesus Christ,
what did I do?
Oh my God.
And then the girls calling you or you
know,
you see her again,
right?
Yeah.
Nobody think of it that the guy got
raped.
Yeah.
And the guy himself,
he's not going to think that a woman
would think that if a woman got drunk
with a guy,
but then of course you get into this
bill cosby territory where a guy is
purposely getting someone drunk or
purpose of getting someone fucked up.
Well,
of course that's,
that's where it gets weird,
right?
That's,
that's where it all turns into an actual
crime or an actual,
you know,
a,
a negative interaction or verifiable.
Bonafide
assault.
Yeah.
That's different even as the intent is
different thing to another.
Okay.
Whatever.
That's one story that that one is I'm
trying to get you to a vulnerable
position because I want to take
something from you that you don't want
to get you and I'm coercing you into
being sneaky about it and yeah,
that's a different story.
So that's a dark thing that it happened.
It happens.
A lot of women,
man,
a lot.
I've talked to several women who have
been roofied you fuck it up when I was
in high school that I had once,
that was pretty hot girl who was just
passed out drunk and there was two guys
at the party were clearly just moving in
that direction and clear and all about
what was going on.
That was,
there was no ambiguity there.
Dates like that easier trying to rape
somebody that's not.
So I remember just I added my good
Samaritan Day of my life where I just
kind of picked her up,
walking her outside bird throw up
because I was like,
no,
no.
Is like the easiest bad scenario,
right?
Dr.
This is not a pleasant one and he's not
a game to one where everybody's drunk
and it's different.
There's no intent Dz.
Somebody will say,
Oh,
vulnerability,
I'm going after that.
I wonder if anyone's ever done a study
on places that have legalized
prostitution,
whether or more or less sexual assaults
from what I remember.
And I do believe I've seen studies about
it.
I think he was less because Jamie head
to google.
Yes.
Um,
yeah,
I,
I would assume that when it's not
something that's almost impossible to
attain because you think about it like
the average guy who makes a good living,
um,
you know,
maybe occasionally you could afford to
spend $500 on a prostitute or whatever
the Holocaust.
But the idea of getting that prostitute
to be in a sexual relationship with you
voluntarily is almost out of the
question.
Right?
But you,
if you're goofy looking,
dude,
you can pay that girl and she'll fuck
you.
And the weight of that exchange has sort
of been lifted.
I mean,
there's a potential that you could get
addicted to going to prostitutes,
but you can get addicted to go into a
pool hall.
Of course,
you know,
you can get addicted to swimming.
I know people that every morning they
get up and they fucking swim.
They have to swim.
I didn't swim to that.
And if you have the money to like,
there was a,
there was a don winslow it,
I don't know if you ever read that guy.
He's a master.
Don winslow.
Yeah.
No really good.
Right?
Never heard of them.
There's a lot.
He's the guy who did the movie savages.
Um,
what is it?
Savages.
Oliver Stone movie.
Oh yeah.
It was basically,
I don't know.
Was that a good movie?
I haven't seen it to be honest.
I read the book.
The book was good.
Um,
the movie I didn't or anything that made
me want to see it.
So I was like,
Hey,
pass about guys.
Like with the right turn,
he has these wild line.
At one point I forgot which not they
taste,
but he has this line where one guy like,
you know,
she's only with you because of your
money.
And the other note is like,
well,
good thing I have money.
Then it was awesome.
Yeah.
What does that mean?
She's only with you because of this?
Well,
whatever.
With you,
because you're big dick and your broad
shoulders,
so stupid.
What does that mean,
right?
She's only with you because you're more
attractive and more intelligent and more
successful than me.
Oh,
okay.
Well that just diminished me to the
point where I could no longer enjoy the
sexual sexual favors of this young lady
coming.
What does that mean?
People are people that try to diminish
you.
You're only be because of goose kind of
stuff.
They were talking about the sex work.
I find it hilarious when people look
down on it,
kind of like,
oh my God.
I'm like,
do you work the job you have?
Is that a job that you would have?
If nobody pays you,
would you do that same stuff anyway in
99 percent of people would say,
nice because I want to get paid and it's
like playing to exactly our.
You are different from a hooker.
Embrace your inner hooker,
man.
You're doing it for demand it.
That's where it.
Your inner hooker researchers
decriminalize prostitution.
Rhode Island lead to fewer rape and
fewer gonorrhea cases.
My point,
but that's not even legal.
That's just decriminalized,
so that means you can get arrested for
it.
Um,
so.
And stuff on both ends of it actually.
So what's that?
I was finding it on articles on both
ends.
What do you mean by that?
It was going up and down.
There's people saying both clearly
showed that it increases.
Not Statistics clearly show that it
decreases that kind of stuff.
Yeah.
There's studies for whichever side you
really want to pay it.
Really.
It's like the Bible.
You'll see nicotine equipment.
Allies though is not legalized.
What you want is a nice brothel,
nice and clean.
Like a,
you know,
like a beautiful establishment,
like a,
a burke williams spa,
berquist stuff.
Williams of hookers,
Burke Williams,
spa there,
they give you a glass of water with
lemon in it and it's nice and they have
the chimes going and the incense you
walk in,
they're scented candles,
can be a nice massage,
but you know,
they're not supposed to have sex with
you.
See,
that's a problem.
But if you can go to one of those places
and they had sex with you,
you'd be like,
this is what a great exchange.
No,
perfect.
I'm nice to you.
If you've got a bunch of money or nice.
Everybody wins.
It's puritanical.
It totally is.
Because if you really break it down,
why would it be illegal to do something
that you can do for free?
If you can do it for money?
Right?
Why?
I mean if you could do it for free,
why can't you do it for money?
Because everything else you can do like
massage,
like you could give people foot massages
all day.
Exactly.
But the fit's a sexual thing.
Suddenly it's illegal and it's terrible.
They,
I find a dealer.
It's disease,
a puritanical religious crap that we
carry with us from,
you know,
another time.
It just still around
in people's mentality because when you
think about it,
I think it's complete bullshit.
It's,
it works our minds too because it turned
sex into some forbidden dirty act.
Yup.
Now,
I don't know,
it's um,
the,
the whole like pattern of it is very
difficult to break though.
I don't.
I mean,
I think they broke it somewhat in the
sixties,
you know,
summer of love and,
but they were all on acid.
That definitely out that totally.
I mean that is what acid does.
That's what mushrooms do.
That's what DMT does.
That paradigm shifting reset button
where you go,
oh,
well why am I doing it this way?
Why am I doing?
Yeah.
That's where all those songs like love
the one you're with.
All that came from.
It was the free love generation.
It was different,
right?
Yeah.
Isn't that interesting?
Like that's all.
It took.
Just a little bit of drugs and people
went from father knows best to love the
one you're with and like inside of 10
years,
90,
67,
30 feet times music wise,
you listen to what people are really
saying too.
In 1961,
what they are listening to by 1968 and
it feels like 30 on 30 years have gone
by.
It's a nice night than day kind of
thing.
They are like,
how did that even happen in that little
period of time?
It's,
you know,
you'll go from your low motown to Jimi
Hendrix and it doesn't even sound
remotely close.
It's everything.
The clothes,
they start wearing bandanas and bell
bottoms and freaky vests and shirts with
flowers on them.
Like the whole thing just fucking
completely flipped on its head.
Just some drugs these much time.
That's what people don't really truly
comprehend and I didn't truly comprehend
until I got older because when I was a
kid and I was in school,
I.
okay.
I graduated from school in 1985.
That's when I graduated from high
school.
And if you stop and think about that 20
years before that was the height of all
that freaky shit.
Yup.
It was alive and popping in 1965.
That's like,
that's not that long ago,
man.
Nineteen 95 to us like 1995 seems like
the other day,
years ago to think about 1995 just being
freaks and hippies and woodstock and
chaos.
And then the government just threw water
on the whole thing,
put that fire out and everything calmed
down in the seventies and the eighties
that gave everybody coke.
And then Miami vice and Don Johnson
didn't have any socks on and he's
driving around the Testarossa and it all
sort of got to this different place,
like they took the drugs out of the
equation and there was this big void and
no one knew what to do and it just sort
of like had this chaotic bouncing
against the wall thing where it was
trying to find its equilibrium and find
it's harmonious vibration.
Get back to where it would've been,
but inexorably altered because of this
one decade.
Big Time.
I mean even the dogs just mean.
It's not like in the eighties people
were in doing drugs but nasty.
Our dogs go from psychedelics to hard
stuff like crack,
crack.
We're not talking the same drugs.
Here is a very different kind of game.
Amazing.
It's amazing.
It's really amazing when you get older
and you realize that 10 years is
nothing.
It's such a.
like 10 years ago it was 2005.
That is exactly like today.
What was the difference in 2005 and
today,
no iphones.
Other than that,
what's the difference?
We were all online.
Everybody had email,
I mean there was less social media and
things along those lines,
but ultimately is very little difference
between today in 2005.
If you had a 2005 car,
that's a nice car that you could drive
that around and be just like a modern
car,
be November 2015 car.
No different.
Not much difference in the music.
We listen to some music from 2005,
so yeah,
pretty similar.
Big thing,
but yeah,
you can take a song from 2005.
You could totally release it today like
a hit and it'll be a hit today,
but the difference between a hit from
1955 and a hit from 1960 five cents day.
Jesus,
what a difference about which is why to
this day,
people about the 1960 seat there who
love it or hate it.
They have really not medical oncology or
ever seen them.
They're like,
oh thank God for the sixties.
That's where all the coolest stuff
started up.
Anything.
He's very far to find people who are
neutral about it.
This is the differences of the people
that got the drugs and didn't get any
drugs.
People that were getting crew cuts and
fucking goddamn headache.
No,
they never got it.
They didn't understand they missed the
boat.
Yeah.
That's Vietnam.
They didn't.
That's what I put.
It's fascinating to think that the
culture can shift and change so quickly.
That must have been terrifying for the
old guard.
You know,
the people that that were.
I mean you also have to think the,
the,
the ability to communicate about these
things,
about these complex issues didn't exist
back then.
So all you can do is go down to your
local bar and complain or your.
I guess they didn't even have coffee
shops back then,
right?
No coffee shops is who the fuck when,
when there's,
there was like diners.
Huh?
I mean I didn't have like a starbucks,
you know,
that shit didn't even exist,
man.
That's nuts.
When I was a kid,
like you would go to Dunkin donuts and
get coffee,
but that was it.
There was no starbucks and no place like
the mom and pop store wasn't just open
tables where people could sit down and
chat with you and get your coffee,
get out.
I mean it was all local.
Like I remember like if you're a worldly
person in Boston,
you would get the New York Times like
that was to show everybody that you were
world.
If you're a dummy,
you would get the herald and if you
were,
you know,
local,
but you know,
you're on the ball.
You get the Boston Globe guys to deliver
all three of them.
The New York Times.
I was very rare and whenever I would
deliver the New York Times,
the dude always had like a bmw or a Saab
or something like that.
You know?
They always had like some,
some cool car and they lived in a,
a cool house and they just,
they wanted to be more into.
They didn't want to live in New York
necessarily.
Or if they did,
they didn't have the funds to move
there,
but they wanted to be worldly.
They sounded like they had the money.
Yeah.
Well that's.
And that's how you got ahold of the real
news.
That's how you had your finger on the
pulse and you had to be active.
Like I remember,
you know,
like um,
there was this guy that I knew that
would,
you know,
he would read all the papers,
he would read the times,
he'd read the Herald and I would,
I would ask him like,
why,
why do you read all these different
papers?
Want to just pick one and read them.
Just like to really get a sense of
what's going on in the world.
You really got to read all of them.
Like the New York Times will cover some
subjects globally that the Boston Globe
won't.
Boston Herald doesn't give a fuck about
what's happening anywhere but Boston.
And there was like this thing where you
had to kind of like search around to get
a,
a sound like a,
a distant sound of the earth of like
what's actually going on on the planet.
Whereas today it's unavoidable today
actually kind of hide from it.
And
I know you said no spoiler,
I don't want to know about that.
Tell me about the walking dead.
Yeah,
no,
I know.
It's when I was growing up.
Me being in Italy too,
which was even further removed from
several of the newest.
I love basketball and I remember when I
was maybe eight,
nine years old,
I wanted to find out who won the NBA
finals and that was the game on Sunday.
What happened,
and I leaked earlier,
would have to call the one magazine you
need to let Dale dealt with basketball
that would come out once a month and I
would call them and they had talked to
their friend in New York with two of
them are one.
Otherwise I would have had to wait three
weeks until the next day she'll come up
on the MBA finals earlier.
Wow.
That's the word that I know that I grew
up even.
So it's like,
do we even think about today?
You can be on the top of the Malaya and
find the right connection.
You can watch the game live.
It's like that's a whole lot that are
game altogether.
Yeah.
You were reading about basketball that
happened weeks ago and get all excited.
It's like,
I can't believe I'm going to find out.
It's now about came.
It's like when were the first organized
sports?
There was 89 hundredths already late 18
hundreds.
Anyway,
as you start to having a whole bunch and
there's an awesome story about the
devito window football in the United
States,
which was by no means the first sizeable
was before and noticing,
but football is funny because there's
the story that late 89 that it's.
There's no more frontier.
There are no more Indian wars because
everybody's been calling course,
so there was not any more traditional
for kind of per class males to go into
military fight the Indians,
that kind of stuff.
So many of the old guard fell that there
are kids who are growing up to be a
Williams is like what you are into and
killed a few Indians.
What's wrong with you?
You're not a real man.
So they would send them to all the Ivy
League school that were beginning to
papa,
but they felt like,
yeah,
you read the books,
you don't kill anybody.
I don't know about your masculinity.
Really.
So somebody was like,
okay,
we can play this game where they beat
the shit out of each other.
It's great to be these mainly physical
game where they just brutalize each
other.
Then at least,
you know,
it's not as good as bringing home a good
scale for.
But it's something,
you know,
it's like,
it saves their masculinity and stuff and
that's how a lot of.
So if you see the old,
the big football programs of the late 80
[inaudible],
early 99,
they were all ivy Lee's code stuff that
today you'll never,
you know,
Harvard,
Yale,
they had a top football program.
So it is like,
how the hell did that even at a lot of
it was because it was a way to show,
look,
I read the books but I'm still a man.
Okay.
I'd still tough.
Wow,
that's,
that's interesting.
So it was a substitute for war.
Yep.
W much totally makes sense.
I mean that's kind of exactly what it
is.
If you watch a game,
it's,
you know,
you're winning,
you're attacking,
you know,
trying to defend.
You're crossing a boundary which is like
the,
the border to the city,
the gates to the,
to the brothel or to the castle or to
wherever you're trying to break into.
Wow.
No,
and even at these old,
the top schools were ivy league,
upper class,
you know,
super rich people and then one of the
top was carlisle Indian school,
which was the lowest of the low,
like poorest people in the United
States.
Indian kids who got sent there and
boarding schools that nothing to do.
They would play football and so what
they would do is that they will study
the rulebook,
try to figure out what is the.
Nobody's doing that technically is legal
but that you know,
what kind of loophole can we play with?
And they would start using some tactical
that nobody had used.
Kill everybody in the process.
So then the league goes,
okay,
we can them into that NBA is beating
higher to,
so let's change that or what's that
thing?
They do make it illegal.
Like what things weren't.
You know what?
I don't.
I wish I remember.
I read through the list.
There were some,
they were really,
but basically they develop the game of
football in terms of,
you know,
this constant game between the league
and the Indian schools where these guys
use some loophole,
the leak can't seem,
makes it illegal and then the next time
they use a different loophole and that
the consultants have a lot of the rules
of football were shaped to start.
Okay,
those guys do it.
Let's stop it right now.
Interesting.
That's lucky for them.
Black people weren't playing back then.
Didn't change all the rules.
Yeah.
Excellent.
That's what they've done.
Now they just give up.
It's mostly black so you can try.
You can.
You can get really big and white and
block runners or you can get a.
You got good eyesight,
hand eye coordination to throw the ball
at.
Black people could run really fast,
but
it's so rare you get like a super speedy
white guy.
When one comes around he runs like a
black guy to Lariat is fucking
hilarious.
He's funny.
I would just stereotypes change over
time because like eerily you add the
show like ed breaks down many of the
early natural law,
the natural Jewish wait,
so which one or you know,
a lot of the early books were all Irish
or the,
you know,
a lot of Jewish boxers back on a day
bake time.
Well there were people that were fucked
with,
you know,
they were the early immigrants and they
were struggling.
That's what it's always seems to be.
It seems to be the,
the,
the group that is like the most recent
immigrants,
like now we get to,
you get a lot of Russians,
a lot of Russians in both Europe and in
America was so many Russians in mma.
Dagestan of Dagestan people and fucking
completely disproportionate amount of
elite fighters to I really fucking tough
guys from Russia.
Not if you've ever used to.
I mean he's as almost data with TB code,
but if you ever used to toughness
throughout your life,
then client meeting during doesn't seem
like much.
He's got old shampoo protech that a
client meeting Katie has.
Hell exactly.
It's exactly what it is,
is exactly what it is,
and it's also like the hunger that you
have because your life has been like
just filled with despair and struggle
and in a lot of abuse.
So like violence becomes some sort of an
automatic response to reaching out for
abuse.
Uh,
you know,
reaching out in response for the,
the abusive suffered like they have a
chip on your shoulder comes from.
Right,
right.
It's like someone just just waiting for
someone to say some shit because he just
been dealing bottled up.
You have.
It's like please just cross that line.
So I have an excuse to beat the shit out
of fuel right now for a few generations
later.
Your kids are pussies.
Yeah.
Look at her like,
go play football.
Dammit.
What kind of man are you?
But it's weird because like isn't it
kind of a good thing that they become
pussies because that means we've become
civilized and everyone's sort of calmed
down.
It's like this is weird fine line that
we walk because ultimately we would like
to have no violence.
Like ultimately we would love it if you
never had to worry about a threat of
violence,
just go through your entire life.
Never worry about anybody shooting.
You are stabbing,
you are beating you up and that'd be
beautiful.
But along the line you kind of lose out
on a lot of the stuff that comes along
with living a hard life.
Yup.
The character that you develop.
Like everybody that I know that grew up
in a tough neighborhood,
they have a sharpness to them,
you know,
and there's a character that they have
that they possessed that the people that
grew up super cushy and some,
you know,
Connecticut Country Club,
estate type situation,
read the notice and I didn't get to walk
into her to environment,
but he definitely was not a upper class
three Chinese thing.
So to me dealing with gangsters was kind
of normal.
Was like,
you know,
Jessica and stared.
There are clear rules of the game,
you know,
how to deal with them.
And so to see people who don't have that
experience,
when they deal with somebody who is by
nature,
by what kind of gangsters like mafia
guys,
not formally,
no.
Usually not mafia,
more just like,
you know,
people do deal.
People who uh,
you know,
that kind of thing where it's like the
guys who are awesome series our taste of
shoplifting,
we'll just can go into a store and walk
out and they would do it pretty much
professionally where they make a living.
Like,
you know,
stuff like that where he's always like
crossing to do any legal stuff.
Not.
I mean I've met some guys who were
probably more well connected in a more
formal way but not,
that was not the normal thing but normal
thing was guys will do a lot of illegal
stuff where maybe they are not
technically against during a strict
science,
but people who get into a lot of fights.
So you know,
that kind of thing where it's like sort
of outside of the normal rules of
civilized society.
But to me it's like there are clear
rules of what you do with those guys.
Usually if you treat them with respect
and you don't show yourself to be a
wimp,
they treat you fairly well.
There's a.
If you know how to play the game,
if you don't,
you know these guys will test you and if
they smell weakness then they'll clamp
down on you.
And if you only.
If you look down on them,
they will clamp down on you.
You know,
there's a very clear rule of the game
that if you play it right,
you can have very mellow,
pleasant interactions.
But people who don't have that
experience that I see them interact
with,
like don't say that.
You can not say that,
you know,
that's just not good.
I ended well,
that's bad.
Well,
some people have a real issue with
letting people in to their life.
Like you would see that.
Like that was what people always said
about like rap music and one of the big
problems with rap music because these
guys would make it and they would become
legit and then they would let like
gangsters in their life because they
wanted to be seen with these people.
They wanted to be legit.
And then all of a sudden these people
are like completely intertwined in their
life.
Yep.
Apparently that happened with Edward
James Almost when he did that movie.
American May.
Yeah.
That was,
you know,
the story behind that.
Yeah.
That was scared to business.
It was heavy duty movie and the movie
was all about these Mexican gang bangers
and apparently he had become friends
with these guys,
you know,
air quotes friend while filming this
movie and just got way too close and
they just started extorting them and
they started demanding money and you
know,
when they knew where he lived and it
became a real fucking issue.
Yeah.
You are their lunch at that point again,
if they think that there's any weakness
there,
Danielle road,
that's why it's a,
there's a parade authorial aspect to
that game or you need to know how to
play otherwise you're fucked.
And I'm sure he wanted to be down,
you know,
of course doing this movie is going to
play this gangster
Cholo.
But then the movie handle is gay sex in
that,
hey,
you're not supposed to talk.
That was a heavy moment man.
Yeah,
there was a lot of weirdness in that
movie.
It's like what is going on?
Yeah,
that was definitely bad stuff,
but that,
that whole like becoming tight with
gangsters,
like that's a.
that's a common tale.
That's a.
That has repeated itself over and over
and over again with Hollywood actors
that wanted to be like tough guys or
weakness right there because he mailed
that.
You want something from them or that you
look up to them in some way.
Then that's waking.
I see.
They see you putting them down.
That's also a challenge.
So you're kind of screwed if you do one
thing,
you're screwed.
If you do another.
Just sort of a narrow ways.
Not too narrow,
you know there is a way to do it,
but if you step outside of it yet you're
fucked.
Yeah,
and it's.
But it's the same thing is like getting
into fights.
You know,
if you are too aggressive,
you will get into fights because you're
are challenging people and you're
backing them and against the and they
have to fight you back.
But if you are too low,
then people won't respect you and they
see you as a week and they come after
you.
You kind of have to have that boundary
where you are polite to people,
they are nice,
but the message is look on nights
because I chose to decide to cross that
line.
I'm going to fuck you up right now.
And that vibe where it's like you can
bring up the goods when it comes down to
throwing down,
but you don't volunteer at.
You're not as much a guy who was like
trying to get into a fight.
That's what usually people are out for a
fight and to respect them by the way
from.
She was like,
that guy,
I'm not going to pick it up there.
I'm going to pick the next one.
Yeah,
I mean obviously there's a lot of
variables and sometimes run into the
wrong person the wrong time.
But of course,
but there's a parallel with the animal
world.
I mean you think about like dogs,
like certain dogs.
If you're around dogs and you panic and
you run,
they'll chase you and bite you.
It's like instinctive.
They can't,
they almost can't help it.
Whereas if you encounter the dogs or
even some wild animals,
you know,
and they say you have to stand your
ground or yell at them like mountain
lions specially up know they say you're
supposed to look big and make noise.
And then I'm like,
all right,
fuck this,
I'm out of here.
It's too much work,
you know,
they don't want to get injured.
So they,
they,
they're looking for something easy.
But when they knew,
when they sense weakness,
I think it's almost nature,
like nature wants them to go after you
because look at this week,
bitch,
he didn't,
let's just eat fish.
That's what it is.
I remember when I was that kid,
I was probably like 18,
19 years old and I was uh,
I found myself in one the situation or
like what the fuck am I doing here?
Because I basically ended up in the
middle of Togo,
not exactly gangs,
but close to that.
They were about to get into a fight and
that was like west side story type
shined up,
you know,
so he's not reality mafia or blood and
canapes real gangster,
but it's,
you know,
tough guys.
Yeah.
And dealing with some guys and then
decided to group come along and I'm in
the middle.
Then you can really walk our way because
are a beach with Jesus,
do I have to be in the middle of this
shit?
And you know,
they start in this ritualized way where
they start talking sheet and so you can
almost set your clock is like,
okay,
we're two minutes away from the fight.
Right?
It's like they are going through their
dances that they're going to push that
there's got to throw down.
And I remember I was talking with some
of these guys from quote unquote the
other side,
assuming that I was with one side but.
And My vibe with this,
it's like,
look,
if we really want to do this,
okay fine,
let's do this.
But honestly I was thinking I had a date
tonight.
I want to go out with this woman or
Gondola to a movie.
I kind of rather do that than these,
but I don't know.
Maybe you guys.
Do.
You guys have nothing better to do.
I mean if we,
if we don't,
let's fucking do it.
You guys just sitting there having these
long sit down,
have a coffee,
a little spaghetti,
and it was largest because we tie.
The two main guys were kind of building
it up and by the time they turned
around,
nobody wanted to fight.
They were like,
Nah,
you're right.
I kind of want to do this other fuck
days.
I don't feel like they said it will lift
their shirt.
They achieved that.
Are there like,
you know,
perhaps you're right.
Fuck that.
It would change.
Yeah.
Because you know,
nobody has guns,
so it's a chain fire,
that kind of thing.
Jesus,
when know I didn't get to.
I felt like,
okay,
that was one of my better days.
If there's a fire,
I played it because if you.
Again,
if you showed too much fear then you get
squashed,
but if you show too much aggressiveness,
then you invite the fight.
There's also a natural thing when groups
of men meet.
It's almost like it's a tribal thing
that's in our DNA back to when you would
run into people you know,
out in the field and it would turn into
a war,
like almost like an instinctive bonding
thing.
I wonder if that's where like because a
lot of the most heinous atrocities that
human beings have ever created or a
committed rather they've committed in
the process of war right now.
Let me say that during the process of
war,
like people are capable of horrific,
terrifying things that they would never
do ordinarily and then also they say
that when you have like this mob
mentality,
like people will do things like gang
rapes or gang murders,
gang beatings,
lootings,
lighting,
places on fire.
Like the behavior escalates to this
really like insane place.
Yup.
That is very,
very rare for someone to go to on their
own as an individual and I wonder if
that's ingrained in us because of this
long history of war in the human race
that when you get a bunch of men
together and a bunch of men on the other
side,
we just immediately go to fucking
scorched earth.
It's immediately cutting off heads and
lighting bodies on fire and catapulting
them onto rooftops and just,
you know what I mean?
That's like,
I know you went to these three.
Does it read like game of thrones is a
fictionalized docomo.
It's just that some dragon,
the dragon,
but other than that,
it's just most of human history has been
like that and then you get into those
things where maybe you don't want to
start by.
Remember remembered those fuckers.
They got little johnny the other time
and they burned the and so now you're
feeling to get them back.
Exactly.
Then it never ends because it's the.
The other guy started it.
I'm not choosing this game,
but hey,
they started eating.
Then they remembered that you did.
It's like you'll never get out.
I try to explain that to somebody wants.
When I talking about street fights and
it was saying that if you get into a
fight with someone,
you're not just getting to fight.
You're signing a contract that you will
be in conflict with them back and forth
until it's resolved.
It's not as simple as you get in a fight
and it's very rare that people get in a
fight and then after that fights over,
like it's over.
We shake hands and walk away even often
in a contest like a Jujitsu match or
kickboxing mattress and one of those
lines,
after it's over,
people were still upset if they lose and
they still want to get that guy back.
But a fight fight like an actual fight
on the street fight.
Oh my God,
this can go on for like the,
what was the,
uh,
the famous feud in America,
the,
the hatfields and mccoys of great too
wacky families killed each other back
and forth for years.
They just couldn't resolve it.
Now that's why when you,
once you start is a,
you'll bet there,
you know,
but if you've got to go down that way,
then you have to go down all out.
Then you just need to really put an end
to that situation where nobody from the
other side can come natural.
But then,
you know,
warrior talking genocide,
that's not exactly the most pleasant
solution in the world that you want to
get into.
But the reality is that beating somebody
is only postponing the next fight is
kind of like more worldwide in world war
two,
he's a,
they are mad because they got beat and
they are reaching for a chance for
revenge.
And the fruit Stein de Abby did a jump
on it because they're pissed off and
understandably so.
So unless it's a resolve in some way
where everybody can take,
we're done,
right?
And we know we're not saying we're
happy,
but can we leave with the current
compromise,
the staff that we reach after to find
the balance of power.
Can you live with it?
Then it becomes a lot more than.
That's why World War Two,
you know,
damn peanut tone of money into Germany
and much of western new little buddy
building it.
They took away that resentment that
otherwise it would have been there or
like those fuckers who does in this
situation and it ruined our life.
And that's our why.
Our economy sucks.
That's why saying,
you know,
being extra janitor was in that regard,
wasn't just janitor was out of the
goodness of your heart is because you
want to make sure you don't fight world
war three years down the road and that
works.
That's a good alternative to genocide.
Yeah.
Smart people learned how to negotiate
their other.
We're gonna.
Let's just work this out.
Let's figure out a way,
a mutually agreeable way where we can
walk away and have some dignity and
it's.
It's really fascinating.
I've had this conversation with Duncan
wants and it was the first time I ever
thought this,
but I said that the history of the human
race is essentially military history.
That's it.
I've been obsessed with this thought
because
I'm next time I chat with Don Carlina.
That's what I want to bring up and the
one question I want to ask him is
exactly about these.
He's like,
I love what Dan does.
I love a lot of history.
I dig it from so many different angles
and yet why do we always end up talking
about horrible stuff and I do.
It should.
My first two episodes of history and
fire are all about some nest.
Yes.
Sinks and I'm like,
same shit.
Why is it the stuff that we remember?
Why is it that the stuff that makes the
history book is old,
the horrible atrocity massacre war set
people on fire?
Is it that just we don't do anything
else or that it doesn't catch our
attention?
I wish there was a way to also put the
spotlight in history on some more mellow
aspects of people who figured out ways
to live a good life in the middle of all
the shit that was going down.
It seems so much of it is,
as you're saying,
it's all military stuff is all fight war
explored.
The other side.
That's really the big events though.
I mean,
when you look at the history of the
United States,
what are the events that people talk
about?
Well,
arguably the whole slavery,
right?
Arguably that's a war because it's so.
It's a war on these people's
sovereignty.
It's a war on their freedom and there's
a and then a real war breaks out between
the north and the south,
over the rights to this and then the
economic aspects of it,
and then you look at World War One,
of course in World War Two,
so we've got to fight the Nazis and then
we got freedom and all this.
I mean it's the entire country.
The history of this country is war and
then you go back to Europe.
All the history of Europe is all war to
none other than figuring out the
printing press and a bunch of different
cool inventions.
Look,
one of the great podcasts that Dan
Carlin did on history that's not
necessarily about war is riddled with
violence that prophets of doom about
Martin worry about war,
but it is violent,
horrific,
amazing that horrific violence,
but I think a lot of he's
guessing that acorn because there's.
It's a cheap,
easy way to get people attention and so
most of our history,
it's an easy way for us to go down that
path and I do it too,
right?
It's.
I look at 90 percent of the episodes I'm
preparing for history and fired up like,
oh great,
you said other B had enough days that
it's either and I realize,
but why don't we,
and I don't mean we as in.
I mean in general,
there's like people who write history
our way of thinking,
why I'm not denying that part,
that's an important part and we should
look at it,
but why don't we also look at other
things.
It's like what's wrong with the study
and about,
you know,
putting the accent moron stuff about
people dropping acid and having sex
outside of marriage a lot more and
listening to cool music and coming out
with Jimi Hendrix.
And why is that that less than
the Cold War?
Uh,
it's not,
to me that just is,
I mean our many people's life as he
transformed away a lot,
lot as has,
as you know,
sometimes we think was president in the
history in most of our lives.
Who's president these most mildly
important at most.
And there are so many other things that
count for so much more.
But why is it that then when we write
the history,
it's about precedent and our world war
took place when there's so much other
stuff in our lives that count for more,
isn't the,
when we were talking about the sixties
isn't a big part of the sixties or the
Vietnam War and the resistance to the
Vietnam War and that sort of fueled that
sort of crazy hippie behavior because
they realize that these old assholes and
they're shitty stupid ways I'd led us
into the South Pacific and it's crazy
war that nobody wanted.
I mean,
that's a big part,
I think,
of the rebellion of the 19 sixties.
It's almost unavoidable because that's
the worst thing that can happen.
See,
the worst thing that can happen is
someone kills you or kills your loved
ones.
Right?
So when that happens in mass,
you know,
like in war,
well,
that those become the biggest blips on
the social radar.
That's.
Yeah,
you're right.
So I guess just.
Well,
it's kind of seems like it's
unavoidable,
unavoidable.
It seems like,
at least historically,
I'm not saying about for the future,
but war seemed unavoidable because it
was never avoided.
Yeah,
I mean,
it's hard to argue that war is avoidable
when it's never been avoided.
It's like you kind of at a certain point
in time,
you know,
if,
uh,
like if a girl acts like can't all the
time,
she's always screaming and yelling and
clawing and pulling chicks Harris.
And she's like,
I'm not a con,
but you're a con every day because if
you were today,
you were the day before the fucking
keyed three people's cars today.
You threw a fucking bag out the window.
You're,
yeah.
I'm glad you don't feel that way,
but the happiness seems to save me.
I don't understand you.
Okay,
well we're.
People are war like,
no we're not.
We're not.
Uh,
we're not okay,
but human history says you're wrong.
It really does.
Like there's not a single moment in time
in human history where someone somewhere
wasn't killing.
Like,
okay,
let's look at this way.
I believe firmly that if you mean Jamie
all lived together on an island,
we would not kill each other if we had
plenty of food and we didn't.
We didn't argue over resources.
We got along great.
I don't think we would kill each other
assuming that there are at least three
women there.
At least one girl that's got a lot of
endurance.
That could work as well.
That could also do it,
but even if there wasn't right,
we just went,
jerked off in bushes for the rest of our
lives.
If you would,
you would say,
okay,
the odds of us killing each other or
extremely small,
so if there was only three of us on the
planet,
there will be no war right there a bit.
We'd be no war,
but as soon as you get more than three,
as soon as you get more than 10,
like if there was 10 of us,
it was 10 of us will live on an island.
Man.
The odds of somebody getting jacked,
it's.
It goes up.
They start to,
you get to 20.
Ooh.
Things get weird.
Something could happen.
Things get weird habit of his 20th
[inaudible],
17 are guys and three or woman,
someone's going to die at that point.
It's not even a debate.
It's a number thing,
right?
Like you get to a certain certain number
of people and then war becomes
inevitable and there's never been a time
ever in the history of the human race
where someone somewhere wasn't killing
somebody is literally never happened
there.
Not that we know of.
Right.
Well,
you and I need to read the Bible and go
back to the time of Jesus.
Adam and eve never did anything.
Do we?
There they were.
I think there's a certain point in time
where you,
you know,
you go back and people were essentially
dealing with predators and that might've
been the only time where we're killing
each other.
Yup.
We're just constantly worried about
getting eaten.
Right,
exactly.
But even then like,
like giraffes kill each other,
like I didn't know until this year that
giraffes kill each other and all that.
I just found out now,
dude,
you got to see the way they do it.
They do pd each other with their necks.
They use their head like a whip,
you know those,
those weird knobs that they have on
their heads.
They whip each other with those things.
They use their head like literally like
a whip and they.
It's the weirdest thing to pull that
shit up.
Jamie.
They beat.
They beat each other to death though.
Like commonly beat each other.
Zf jobs wound healed until I started
hunting.
I didn't know that deer's kill each
other all the time.
They stab each other all the time,
so fucking horrible.
It's dog eat dog world.
You imagine you grow swords on your head
and just running around stabbing each
other,
but.
But giraffes,
it's so odd to do it because it's a
whipping thing.
Look.
See?
They whip each other.
Look at that.
Look at this thing saying they stand
side decide and they push on each other
and then they whip each other with their
heads.
What have you seen q right now?
He's like,
okay.
I thought they'd do.
It seems like it sped up.
Jamie,
is it sped up?
Wow.
Oh,
it's not sped up.
No,
it is sped up that up.
Yeah.
It's so weird.
This is not sped up.
Okay.
This one's not sped up.
That's more realistic.
I think the first one in the video
series of direct,
what is the name of this video?
A giraffes fighting draft battles,
but they.
They always do it the same way.
They go side to side.
She was like two dudes standing shoulder
to shoulder and then it head butting
each other.
Yeah.
It's so strange man,
and these guys have placed are clean
chimneys one the previous ones wearing
these side to side walk each other and
then they take five cycles where they
are thinking about the next,
but look to get back to the same
position that always get back to the
shoulder to shoulder position.
When they clinch up,
it's just to get back to this side by
side position so they can fucking head
butting each other.
So strange article or.
And they use their head.
They used their head to the body,
see the attack,
the body with those antlers that William
like nubs,
whatever it is,
but they'll go to the same spot over and
over again,
like right to the rib cage.
Can you imagine anything?
Giraffes had actually like deer antlers.
They will just go there.
Would,
but see if you go to the zoo,
you would never imagined.
This takes place now because one of the
cool things about giraffes is that
they're an animal that's so universally
gentle.
Yup.
That you can have babies feed them.
Like my daughter when she was two years
old,
we let her do.
They give you a lettuce and you hold out
the lettuce and the giraffe comes over
with his crazy tongue.
It's like an arm and they reach out
their tongue and wraps it around the
leaves and it pulls it,
but they're so confident in their
behavior around people that they let
babies feed them,
but you get these two motherfuckers
together and they fight over some pussy.
That's what he told her latest,
but it's not.
It's exactly what this is.
That's exactly what the dea,
the deer don't fight.
You know,
deer get together and bachelor groups
when they're not breeding,
when the run is over and they are and
their buddies,
they're all buddies together.
That's like one of the best ways that
people hunt them out of the Rut is to
find bachelor groups and then you're
done with those pitches.
They don't even hang out with.
Soon as they get done fighting.
As soon as they'd done fighting and
fucking and they were like,
let's just hang out guys,
come on,
let's go wander through the countryside.
It's go camp.
Let's go hang out,
tell some stories.
Come on guys.
I know we stabbed each other a couple of
weeks ago,
but that's over bro.
It survive.
I survive because they said they heal up
quick too.
That's another bizarre thing about deer.
So they'll stab each other and they put
these horrible gases in their body and
then like a week later it's completely
sealed up and they're just walking
around like nothing happened.
Was vetting power.
Just they just super,
super high metabolism and probably just.
They only live like seven years.
So I think whatever injuries,
they have seals up quick because there
was this video of this guy.
He went bow hunting and he missed this
deer.
He missed a good spot.
He,
you know,
he missed the vitals that he hit it in
the shoulder,
so the deer got an arrow in his shoulder
and then they found the deer a week
later walking around like nothing.
Just.
I really narrowed that off.
Oh,
it fell out,
fell off the,
the,
the hole in the shoulder healed up.
Just sealed,
sealed itself.
It's like what the fuck,
but achy.
Well,
to just,
they have to be like that.
Yeah.
That wasn't bad.
And their worlds to getting stabbed all
the time by swords of these dudes are
growing on their heads that were
competing for sex and competing for.
That goes back to my point,
if there were giraffe who curse or
digging,
are hookers?
This guy who had said that they get
along well.
The crazy thing about deer is it's not
about like,
it's not just about sex,
it's literally only about sex one time a
year.
You just want to resist.
The pressure is like,
oh,
this is my one chance man.
And I only live seven years.
So I this,
this,
the,
I really everybody live three,
four or five at most.
So most,
if you're in my way,
I'm going to fucking kill you.
I don't know.
Most of them,
they freeze to death.
They freeze to death or starve to death.
Like they'll wear their teeth down to
nothing and they can no longer process
grains.
That's a good way to go.
It happens to a lot of deer,
like a lot of people will kill an old
dear.
And then they opened its mouth up and
they go,
wow.
He would've never made it through the
winter because their teeth are gone.
They still have a very finite resource
with those teeth and at that point
you're really doing them a favor because
that's a way to go by this little
starvation that's fuck it up.
Or they get even worse.
They're on their way to getting starved
and the coyotes find them.
Yeah,
they're weak and then you'll get eaten
alive.
Yes,
asshole first.
That's how they get you outta.
There was a thing that I tweeted today,
Jamie,
you see the thing about there's a
literally a new species that is evolving
before our eyes.
It's a mix of coyotes,
wolves and dogs and domestic dogs.
And that a hybrid of these three is
incredibly successful and it's like the
Koi wolves are coyotes and wolves and
we've known about them for awhile and
that's really a fascinating thing
because it's a larger coyote,
but look at this new species,
new species evolving right before our
eyes and ultra successful mix of wolves,
coyotes and dogs,
so really interesting article,
but it's an actual.
Is this from the economist?
This is actually their mating with each
other and they're creating an actual
species really fast.
Wow.
That's 3:00
PM.
The embedding began up to 200 years ago
is European settlers pushed into
southern Ontario and cleared the
animals' habitat for farming and killed
a large number of wolves that lived
there.
It also allowed coyotes to spread from
the prairies and the white farmers
brought dogs into the region.
Over time,
wolves began meeting with their new
genetically similar neighbors and the
resulting offspring which had been
called the eastern coyote or to some the
Coi wolf now number in the millions.
According to research at North Carolina
State University.
This is really interesting stuff,
man.
That's crazy.
Fifty five pounds now.
Told no 437.
This is cool.
And an analysis of 437 hybrid animals
found that the coyote DNA dominates its
genetic makeup with about one 10th of
its DNA from dogs,
usually from a larger dog such as
Doberman pinchers and German shepherds,
and a quarter from wolves.
Wow.
That's freaky.
Began that building size compared to a
big.
Yeah.
It's just,
it's,
it's fascinating to think how a species
evolved in the first place.
Like how did a wolf become a wolf?
You know,
how did a giraffe become a
giraffe and to see something like this
happening and have a very clear line,
like a genetic line.
Right?
This is what caused.
This is amazing stuff,
man.
It's fucking trippy though.
Sure.
That's always.
Would you wonder about if we're going
wrong,
when you see those Adam,
you know,
you think about wolves and then you some
of the dog species today.
I'm like,
how the fuck did you come about?
You're not suited for anything.
It's like,
and they've been doing it for thousands
of years.
That's a modern dog has been around for
thousands of years and we didn't even
know the original origin,
like there's a lot of speculation.
They believe that the wolves that were
around human beings,
they became,
they became different because they
wanted the people to like them,
so they became the more successful ones
that stayed were the ones that are a
little more timid and more Beta playful.
They did a study on Fox is really
interesting study that they highlighted
in this radio lab podcast,
but they were talking about genetic
diversity and genetic diversity and
foxes were,
they only allowed the foxes that were
timid and um,
and like more more accepting of human be
human touch and to be around humans they
only allowed them to live and they sort
of like bread.
Those let those breed with other ones.
And over like 10 years,
they had completely changed the Fox Dna.
I had completely changed the point with
their ears.
No,
we're no longer pointed.
They flopped.
They didn't stick straight up.
They flop.
Their jaws became more feminine in any
hours.
Yeah.
And their color started changing nuts.
Ten years.
It's like generations maybe for folks
that's or something.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
I mean probably more than three
generations because generation isn't
exactly the entire lifetime.
It's like how long it takes you to breed
into successful.
Maybe might have been a capital offense
or something,
so maybe five.
Regeneration.
Yeah.
It's crazy.
It's not much.
Yeah,
five generations.
There's nothing.
Well,
that's what they're finding now more and
more the more they study life is it life
can evolve and change and shift and
adapt incredibly quickly.
Oh my favorite story of that.
As the Congo,
the Congo used to be like a grassland
savanna and then the climate changed.
It became this really lush rain forest,
but a lot of these animals that were
like savannah animals,
they got trapped right now.
They are stuck.
They're stuck inside this rain forest,
so like there's this BBC documentary on
the Congo and one of the cool things is
seeing this swampy,
crazy rain forest and then seeing these
deer run through the water of the rain
forest,
these antelopes and you're like,
whoa.
Different supposed to be in grasslands
and they're just trapped in this
insanely dense rain forest.
The,
they change a anything like their habits
there.
Anything about their physical features
that was there.
Some of them,
one of them is called a diker and dikers
are very small antelope,
but he can swim underwater for up to 100
yards and it eats
the hell.
What the hell?
No,
what I would picture a hundred yards
underwater.
Underwater.
That's what the fuck it's.
It became something that adapted to that
environment.
They can eat fish,
but they found that deer eat birds.
They didn't know that until really
recently.
And one of the ways they found it,
it was through camera traps because you
know,
they have these camera,
um,
these trail cams that people put up when
they're hunting and that when they put
up these trail cams,
as the trail cams got more and more
sophisticated,
they started using video trail cameras.
And as the video trail cameras started,
they get the data back from them.
They started finding like occasionally
birds,
like deer would eat ground nesting
birds.
Yeah.
Soda need my Ds and they find,
Oh,
told me to beat the shit out of each
other.
That direct birds that are no
certainties in life anymore.
No.
They're all evil.
Those goddamn animals.
The ones that we have anthropomorphize
these beautiful creatures that exist
solely on the power of love.
Yep.
Yeah.
There was a.
They did some sort of a,
a study where they were capturing
certain birds with nets and they had set
the nets up and the birds around the
nets and get caught with the deer would
just walk right up to the birds and the
nuts and just start eating them.
Wow.
Just chewing them alive while they're in
the net.
Just so much more to eating a sentiment
about the era and it.
Because it wasn't like they were just
testing,
like trying that.
Alec is this food though?
They just went right to it.
They like so dear.
Apparently eat ground nesting birds all
the time,
but being at ground nesting bird that
looks like shit.
Let that just bad evolution right there.
Dog Shit.
Life.
What were you thinking at bird delete on
the ground.
That just a bad idea.
Don't you know how to put sticks and
twigs and the trees.
You dumb fuck the other.
That helps a lot.
Like where I live,
there's a regular,
an older list on a monthly basis.
There's like some cute with the little
birds,
Nesting da egg Saracini and devotees.
He got into hall,
could regularly come by us,
reap the shit out of them and I find
pieces of birds everywhere and it's
pretty nasty.
Yeah.
My friend Tom was sitting out on his
back porch who was one of the directors
of news radio back in the day.
Tom's a great guy and he was an in
studio city and he goes,
sit down.
He had this sort of Georgia accent.
I'm sitting on my porch enjoying my
coffee and I see a dove or some sort of
a bird.
Maybe it was a dove sitting on the fence
and then add a nowhere hot comes and
snatches that Burrito and he goes and
part of me felt lucky to see that.
Yeah,
lucky because that doesn't happen every
day,
but it also like made you realize like
it's hard out there for a tough war.
Yes,
and birds eat birds.
That's another fuck up.
That diverse thought of that I saw not
so long ago.
It's coming back home and die.
Yardies bird just yapping
away just making these crazy noise.
I'm like,
what the hell?
And I look up into three and acds one
burgess,
just mad.
Just going there and then I see that
right next to it,
like maybe 10 feet away.
There's this hawk that does another
burden.
He smiles that look exactly like the one
that Seattle lean.
So this one is probably like saying he
was set off a beach which are just
teaching my wife.
That's not right.
It's like I was like,
man,
that's a rough life right there.
Yeah.
Hawks,
Jack,
everybody.
Yup.
Everybody gets jacked.
Except I saw youtube a video for
committing suicide by Eagle.
The site with an eagle's nest and oh no,
not a good idea.
You see these eagle who was just like
minding his business is this big Bald
Eagle.
And then clearly before even the camera,
because the camera,
I guess was set on the nest to capture
whatever was going on there.
You see these eagle just suddenly see
something,
a bus up like ready for the fight and
the next day you've seen is this hawk
coming in,
just fighting with the ego and it lasts
about six seconds as they go.
Just go whack,
whack.
And just the reap the Hawk to pieces
because it's like I'm glad you'll be
told the other birds.
But an eagle is an eagle.
Step away.
You're beginning to overestimate your
skills.
Math got drunk.
Yeah.
Drunk.
So take on an eagle.
It's fermented berries or something.
Fuck it.
A golden days thinking they are all
that.
I'm going to show them right now.
And that did not work.
It's interesting that birds fly in
flocks,
right?
Like Canadian geese and ducks and
sparrows,
but not the ones that eat meat.
No meat.
You're on your own bitch.
Yup.
You know,
there's probably these,
a competition about that flesh.
Somebody eating that meat just changes
the whole dynamic of the situation.
The ones that eat the meat,
a spicket of which after seeing your
instagram picture of your dinner,
I'm like,
I,
I'm going to be knocking on the Oregon
side for you.
Fuck,
I wish I had gone to the.
I have to get some,
but uh,
I have a freezer in the back.
I'll hook you up next time I see you.
I'll bring you some elk stack.
Be Able to love it.
I'll teach you how to cook it too.
It's a little different because there's
very little fat so you have to cook it
quick.
The easiest to.
I'll give you some ground elk.
Is the easiest to cook.
Like elk burgers,
super high protein too.
It's like,
I'm think it's 22 grams of protein per
pound,
which is way more than domestic beef.
Right?
It's like between,
I think the highest is elk and the
second highest is Moose.
Like those are the highest of the,
that type of animal that you can get,
but it's really delicious.
Two minutes.
So good.
I love them.
So good for you too.
And you don't have to feel guilty about
factory farming and all that other.
Exactly,
I mean if you're to eat meat,
might as well.
It's bad that wild and had a good life
and that's it.
Do you know factory farming sucks?
Have you ever seen an eagle in the wild?
Um,
yeah,
yeah.
Wild to see.
Right?
When you see one in real life,
you're like,
God,
this is big.
And South Dakota.
Yeah,
I've seen South Dakota,
there's
a crazy video online from Alaska,
have this kid and his whole family is
there.
Their lawn is covered with bald eagles
and they were throwing out fish.
They had like some salmon,
so they had filleted the salmon and then
they had the bottoms in the ribs and the
heads and all that stuff.
And they were,
they had thrown it out for these eagles
and their fucking lawn is just
overwhelmed with bald eagles.
So we like to think of Bald Eagles is
like spinning something like extremely
endangered and protected.
Alaska is a different story.
Totally different story.
They're protected in some places,
right?
But in Alaska they're not protected.
I mean,
not,
not to not protect,
I should say they're endangered in a lot
of places,
but they're not in danger and Alaska.
They're still protected.
Yeah,
I know.
Like,
look at all these.
No Way.
Yeah.
So what's the name of this video?
Jamie?
It says 1:00
PM on a summer night.
And um,
how was it?
A summer night.
Oh,
you can't see the other one?
I was like,
you and breads.
It's not night just because it's pm.
Look at all these eagles,
man in the.
Those are the ones that aren't black
with a white.
Those are the immature ones,
the young ones and some.
Sometimes those young ones are fucking
enormous man.
Yeah.
They don't want to look smart,
that's for sure.
Now they're all over this guy's lawn and
uh,
they,
they throw like these buckets of fish
out for them,
but they have,
you know,
eagles all over the place up there.
Yeah.
California.
We have some eagles still.
We have Golden Eagles.
They,
they still find them,
but they're just not,
for whatever reason,
not nearly as common as they are up
there in Alaska.
I guess it's also probably because they
have a lot of food up there with all the
salmon salmon runs.
This is just one part of the video.
This video is pretty long,
but see they're,
they're sitting around waiting for this
guy to chuck like fish heads.
For them
it's just an amazing animal.
This animal,
this is flying raptor.
That really is probably exactly like
what the dinosaurs are like.
It's fascinating when they find more and
more evidence that many dinosaurs had
feathers and you think there's really
probably not much difference between
some birds like eagles and some
dinosaurs.
And then they know that some birds,
even birds that lived a fairly recently,
like the terror birds,
they were uh,
these large flightless six foot,
seven foot tall birds just going to go
for the head look at.
Should I get that head?
I want to get that habit,
that fucking do with camera.
So He's thinking about it.
Look at his little baby steps up.
Pussy,
Pussy.
No head for you.
Faggot.
Swooping in and try to do it is this one
is more mature.
Yeah.
He's got a little bit more confidence.
Jack,
you go,
love
it.
Lovely.
Just swoop in and grab it.
Kinda damned.
They're awesome animals.
I'm,
I just,
I,
I find the world of nature to be
unbelievably beautiful and exciting and
crazy,
but for whatever reason,
I'm way more thrilled by the predators.
Yeah,
like the,
like when I see things like this,
when I see like raptors,
that's what excites me.
If I see like some sparrows or something
like that,
this pussy as we kind of related more in
the science of,
you know,
as human beings we have hunting and
gathering has been 95 percent would have
been around a while.
We did.
It's what has been the norm of,
for human beings for the longest period
of time.
Yeah.
But there's just something about
dangerous things.
I want to show you this picture that
certainly sent me a.
This a family friend has um,
uh,
chickens and they caught a bobcat eating
their chicken.
Get this fucker Jamie.
Yeah.
Hold it up to the camera and see if
people could see it.
This is a,
this is like,
I think they live in woodland hills.
Yeah.
They're so far away from here at all.
That's what's today is that now for the
longest time I live closer to the water.
Now that I'm leaving them kind of close
to Glendale,
to the heel,
subpoena ego.
They're all kind of stuff.
It's crazy.
The stuff that you'll find running
around in the middle of houses,
you live everywhere and skunks.
The other day.
I'm yesterday with Katie.
Larry's.
I'm coming back home.
I was teaching a night class,
so I come back home.
It's probably like 10,
30 pm or something.
I arrive,
I'm walking through my garden.
It's pitch black and just maybe 20 feet
to my right a year or just something
good out at me.
Right,
and I don't know.
It completely skipped my rational brain
that there was no thought in my mind.
The next thing I hear is this meanare
heavier growl and I realize,
oh wait,
that's me.
It's me,
that whatever other fucking thing was
there I just pissed off.
Right.
I never know because whatever the other
things was decided.
Okay,
you're fucking crazy or to me.
So I believe it because I added.
I honestly don't think he was anything
big.
I think he was probably like some piece
of record and tried to show that they
are.
They are not really.
I don't think he was anything.
Koons will fight you though because I
would have grabbed if they want you to
come after you,
but they're not and they don't because
they are small so they mind their
business.
Mountain Lion wouldn't and it's very
rare anyway,
so it's probably stupid raccoon or
something.
You probably got too close to his
garbage stash.
Exactly.
He was all trying to.
This was a Bobcat,
this,
this fucking crazy mangy looking creepy
animal and like I said,
this is like real close to where the
studio is and this is a guy had a
chicken coop and this thing figured out
how to get in his chicken coop and was
eating one of his chickens and his coop
and found it creepy looking face on that
fucker.
Out of that.
It looks like a mean bus.
Oh,
he's out there earn,
earn his.
Keep getting any welfare in the form of
giving him shit.
I don't know how big the bobcat's get.
They get like 30 or 40 pounds.
Right?
They're pretty big.
Yeah.
But I would imagine arco yacht out this
bigger,
somewhere around there.
I bet coyotes don't fuck with bobcat's.
Probably not.
Yeah,
but it's too much work.
I mean they probably could kill them if
they got a bunch of them together,
but it probably tastes like shit.
It's probably like chew in a shoe.
Yeah,
exactly.
There's no self than this.
And you know what apparently taste good
is mountain lion.
Really?
Yeah.
I know this guy in Colorado and
Colorado,
they're pretty.
They're good about taking care of them
too.
They have mountain lions seasons and
they try to keep the populations down
and you know,
some people will argue saying that
they're killing too many and this and
that.
You shouldn't kill them,
but there needs to be some sort of a
balance.
Otherwise they start appearing on
people's lawns and killing peoples out
and like California has a real problem
because they don't allow people to hunt
them and they have a lot of.
Coyotes are a lot of mountain lions and
that's one of the reasons where the deer
population in California,
so low it up of course,
and some people like it that way and
they think,
well that's the natural balance,
really shouldn't have that many deer
round.
And ultimately,
I mean I can see that point where it's
probably better to have a lot of
mountain line than it is a lot of lyme
disease ticks and a lot of deers
slamming into cars like you do in places
that don't have high mountain lion
populations,
you know,
like Michigan or something like that
where they have a lot of them.
But I'm focused on my point that we
should eat with lion.
Oh,
they taste good though.
These guys that I know that hunting in
Colorado and I said,
really?
I'm like,
what does it taste like?
And he goes,
it's a lot like pork,
pork loin.
Yeah.
Did you take the backstrap from um,
outline and uh,
you know,
the,
the roast,
it was weird because my solar ray,
that tourists are not excited with you
think of what do you want to eat?
But apparently taste really good.
They said it tastes really good.
Like this one guy that was talking to
one of his favorite meats said it tastes
just like a pork roast.
They make it with like a blueberry
sauce.
I'm a nature school today.
I found out that she had rafts or cons
that birds,
that of goodness.
There's all sorts of things to be
learned here about the wild,
natural world,
you know,
it's just,
it's like I said,
there's something about the predators
that I find just unbelievably
fascinating and I think it's because
they have to,
they have to be so explosive and so
quick and so dangerous in order to get
what they're,
they want to get.
They can't just walk around and chew on
grass and like cows.
Nobody gets excited when they see a cow
because it's just,
even if it wasn't so common,
they're fucking boring.
Like Buffalo,
they're the same.
But at least they have cool hair
executive.
They make some sounds that are.
Yeah,
battlestar.
Cool.
I ended up once in the middle of a herd
of Buffalo in custer state park in South
Dakota
where I took like,
um,
they have,
you know,
the regular roads that you can take with
the card and they have some dirt roads
that you can still take with the car.
So I was kind of off the beaten path and
all of a sudden I find myself in the
middle of like probably 300 buffaloes,
so I kind of stopped the car away there
and they are going everywhere around me.
Right.
There's like one site to the card,
the other in front of me behind me.
And they are big powerful animals,
you know,
you see them,
you're either a,
not to piss them off because they are
solid,
you know,
they don't mess around.
And he was awesome though.
I mean,
once I figured,
okay,
these guys don't want to fuck with me,
they just want to move around me and
they don't care.
He was great because you see the cafs
running after they are beautiful.
They are really also my animals and
yeah,
that's the thing with all wild species.
Salar cooler than all the domesticated
species tend to be dumb Bert and to be a
lot like somebody is going to be food
anyway while you die,
you know you need to be on.
He's like,
when you see a dog and you see a coyote,
they are silent.
You don't hear them make a damn noise.
You see them and you're like,
oh,
is that a dog?
And you know,
30 seconds.
Even though he's not a dog because they
had moved away,
they,
it's a whole different game.
Was good.
Dogs are all done.
Been happier there.
Like who?
Who will be your the way noisier.
It's a sneaky.
Yeah.
The wilder version is always so you
know,
you don't cut it if you're.
If you're not smart in the world,
it's hard to live.
It's a hard life and they have this like
this,
this air about them.
They're just trying to catch something
to sneaking around.
The first time I saw a coyote was in
burbank in 1994 when I first moved here.
I was staying at the Oakwoods,
the Oakwoods,
they have these pre furnished
apartments,
that's where I lived and I was driving
to my place and I saw this dog in the
road and another dog next to him and I
was like,
Oh shit,
that's a wolf.
I realized like,
oh,
that's great.
That's a live thing that I'm realizing
those are wild coyotes and they're just
wandering through Burbank,
like Oh,
strange that they can just exist on the
streets.
I didn't know that.
I figured if you lived in the rural
areas you would encounter them,
but I didn't realize that they had
actually gone deep,
deep,
deep into the cities in search of like
cats and shit.
Big Time I ever.
I found one in my age in my yard and not
so long ago and he was getting a bit too
comfortable.
It was just kind of roaming around
around him as like first year like,
oh,
this is so cool.
I can't believe I'm seeing these.
After awhile you're like,
okay,
to never get too comfortable in my
backyard because you have a kid and I
walked out.
Then the coyotes are moving away and
then I realized,
what the Hell am I doing?
I'm putting a wild animal with his back
against the fence.
That can be a good idea,
but that was my sweet delusional because
my idea of the fence,
like I took a look at me and was like,
you call these offense.
It was like probably a good six foot
fence and he just jumped it in one thing
without even just said these will keep
out at dog.
Those stupid things he will make keep
around but me,
I got something God's going on.
And I was like,
okay,
wild animal.
Our whole different game.
Yeah.
I had a coyote killed one of my
chickens,
hot my friends,
like it was nothing.
Really.
Yeah.
I watched him hop the fence with the
chicken in his mouth.
I was like,
wow.
That was their powerful motherfucker.
Well,
when chickens brewed,
um,
you have to remove them from their
regular nest because they'll sit in the
nesting box that pull their feathers off
and they get sick and they can do it for
like a month and a half at a time.
So what you gotta do is you got to put
them in a small cage for a couple of
days where they have to stand on a rail,
they have to clutch and sit on this rail
and you do that for a couple of days and
then they'll get over the brooding
instincts and get normal again.
It's just this cycle because they're not
having sex.
Oh,
is that what it is?
Because they're not having sex.
Like when you eat an egg.
I didn't know this until really late in
life,
but an egg at the ready for a new piece
of information or let it go.
I thought an egg would become a chicken.
That's how retarded I am.
I thought the only way that it chicken
makes an egg as if she gets fucked by a
rooster and then an egg comes out and
then they sit on the a and it becomes a
chicken and you just got to get the egg
before the chicken hatches.
Then you create.
That's not the case.
That's my understanding of faith.
So please enlighten me.
Now they actually lay eggs all the time
with no males involved whatsoever.
So I have 22 chickens,
I have no males or all females and they
lay usually,
if not an egg a day at the very least an
egg every other day close.
And those eggs will never be chickens.
Never.
So people that are vegetarians that
don't eat eggs,
like you're really silly because it's
animal protein that doesn't hurt
anybody.
These chickens,
they lay these eggs whether you like it
or not.
And if you don't eat them,
they just rot,
right?
You could just,
you know,
but um,
these,
uh,
these chickens,
they would take them when they're
brooding and then I'd put them in this
other box and the other boxes outside of
their coop and it was,
you know,
fairly secure.
But this coyote had figured out how to
tip it over and uh,
got the chicken and he had them in his
mouth and I watched him hold it in his
mouth and run through my yard with his
mouth.
I'm like,
this motherfucker.
And I opened the door thinking like
maybe I would be able to get to him
before he could jump the fence with the
chicken.
Nope,
not even close.
Just leaped over it like it was nothing
that.
Exactly what their ability is amazing.
And a mountain lion a way crazier.
They can just do ridiculous shit.
They can jump like 12 foot fences.
That would freak me out in the wild.
The mountain lion in the fight.
If you don't have any weapons on you,
we are not a good thing.
Yeah.
That's scary.
Shit.
I ain't scared of Shit.
There's a video of this guy hiking and
he's hiking and as he's hiking this
mountain,
I just sitting there staring at him,
watching him and he's on this trail and
he starts making noise and smack and
sticks against the ground.
But it's like that guy probably came
super close to getting eaten up and if
it was smaller,
especially if it was like a small woman.
Yep.
Yeah.
That was a case of not it a few years
ago and Griffith Park and there was some
lady got eaten
by a mountain lion while hiking.
I'm not surprised they're out there.
There's a lot of them there,
you know,
they,
they track quite a few of them,
but I guess when it comes to large,
big predators is probably one of the
best ones to have around because you
know,
they,
they have plenty shit.
They eat right.
They,
they keep away from people for the most
part.
But it is weird that we,
not only do we want to help them,
like they're,
they're setting up these,
they're like bridges that go across the
highway because one of the ways that
Mount Lines di is trying to cross the
highway to tried to cross the 101 and
they get nailed.
Yup.
I say fuck them.
She's stupid.
So stupid.
Let her know to cross traffic.
I'm fucking stupid.
He run into traffic.
It's not a cat that needs to be around
that.
That's nature's way.
A thin the herd.
I mean selection.
Just a lot of them,
you know,
we don't really need to protect them
that much.
They need to spend millions of dollars
building a bridge,
you know?
How about cleanup,
skid row,
that will work on those animals.
There
I was,
um,
I like to go to big bear because,
you know,
he's only four hours away from me or
something,
but he's awesome.
It's like a whole lot.
Their environment is beautiful,
the trees,
everything.
So I like to go out there and the place
where I usually go the,
I was chatting with some neighbors and
they were telling me,
yeah,
you know,
these days bears have stopped coming
around.
I'm like,
why?
What's,
what's up is that coke was a mountain
lion moved into the neighborhood and
even they are freaked out by him to get
into the.
There are like,
I mean the Bayers in big bear or not
this huge black blackberry.
Exactly.
And appeared to this mountain lion is
extra grass even decided the bears
decided let's move to a nicer
neighborhood.
Oh,
so one gangster mountain moved down.
Exactly.
And there's a hiking around and he was
probably 6:00
PM and I'm like,
do I really want to do this at this
time?
This does not seem like the best plan in
the order.
I know a no way.
Phones like this too much.
Yeah.
You got to go with like fucking four
hockey outfit on maybe football series
ads and some chain mail.
They're not going to get you though.
They have things to eat.
There are plenty of things to eat.
Most of the time,
mountain lions don't want to have
anything to do with.
People are sick old ones that they need
food so bad until they're willing to
take a chance on a person of course,
but for the most part,
even if you do like the natural
selection process is probably eliminated
people from their diet because every
mountain lion that chose to eat a person
was killed.
Exactly.
So they somehow or another,
they all,
yeah,
they know,
fuck,
we're bipedal,
but they think they can get away with
it.
Why not?
But the is beautiful as they are.
They are.
They,
they're terrifying and they're ferocious
and everything,
but it would be way more thrilled to see
one of those than I would to see
something that doesn't kill things and
then it's weird.
Right?
Yeah,
and I think
it goes back to the same thing we were
talking about regarding history.
Why is it that we're fascinated with
that and we are,
you know,
there's no denying it and you'd be
bullshit to pretend no,
you know,
I like peace and mellow and I like to
see people shake hands and it's like
there's a beauty to some mellow,
peaceful stuff,
but we dig.
We like you at.
Why do we like fight it?
Why do we what it is,
right?
It's a,
that's the game.
It's in nature.
We like it.
Them on half of it is about the conflict
and the wars and it's all about that
stuff and it's conflict and
consequences.
Like if you were in the ocean and you
saw a,
a big Marlin,
like wow,
that'd be cool.
I'll look at that Marlin.
But if you saw a shark,
eat tomorrowland.
Yeah.
It'd be way more exciting.
You know,
if you see if whale whales are cool to
see their beautiful arc,
but killer whale is way cooler than a
regular way.
There's that.
Something's gonna something exciting and
dramatic is going on shark sharks way
cooler than a regular fish.
Yeah.
There's something about those type of
animals.
Like I would love to go on to Africa and
the safari.
If it wasn't for malaria and Ebola
wasn't for those 57 threesomes would
fucking parasites and all kinds of crazy
shit.
I would love to go to Africa just to,
in the off chance of seeing a alliance
take something down on a safari.
I would love to go and see that.
I'd love to love to witness that.
I wonder how often that that takes
place.
Like when you go on one of those
safaris,
when,
how often you actually see something get
jacked.
Yeah.
Even because just because they are
hunting doesn't mean they're going to be
successful because course a bunch of
times you fail and that's the.
And I think that's part of the
interesting conflict is there's
something's going to happen and the two
sides,
whoever the two sites are trying
opposite seeing.
So there's this conflict of wheel in
somebodies going to get their way and
somebody isn't.
So there's that element of excitement
that almost make you want a bath or
anything like what's going on?
Who's gonna,
who's gonna step up and lead their a
game and succeed and full.
Was that miserably?
It's a.
it's cool when you watch fights,
it's cool.
What do you watch?
Anything.
It's like there's even.
We should not fight.
He was the lie on chasing the Gazelle is
like Ken the gazelle speed.
Leave the light on in the dust and the
just leaving pissed off and hungry.
Or is it going?
There's that question.
There is like,
let's see how they played their cards
when life is on the line,
you know?
Yeah.
And that contemplation of how the
outcome's going to go down.
Like what was that for whatever reason
is one of the most compelling things
that people can watch.
Yep.
It's where were so strange in that
regard that,
that,
that is like one of the most interesting
things for people.
I mean,
that's why the Romans,
I mean when they were feeding the lions
are Christians.
Right?
That's what that was all bound.
It's like to see how long that guy can
last in there.
Just to check these out.
These a nasty story that I did not know
about.
So what happened was after they would
have the beast,
either fight each other or they'll have
the lie on seat Kriesti answer something
than a typical thing is that after the
end of the day when a whole bunch of
these animals have been killed in one
fight or another,
the Roman emperors to kind of look cool
and popular with the crowds,
would then distribute the meat to all
the poor people of Rome.
So the animals killed India in our then
be eaten by all the poorest people in
Rome as a Freebie because you're a poor
person and you're more likely than not a
lot of people in your realm or pretty
close to starving.
A lot of the times nothing.
Get them be thrown away.
You eat right,
you eat the whole animal.
Whatever they give you,
you eat it.
So what does that mean?
That means that among other things that
would end up as we are an exalted in on
the table.
Sometime you get also the interiors of
animals that have just been eating
people.
So through via second hand,
you're also eating people since you're
eating stoma contents of a lie on the
job and got killed in the arena and that
lie and just finished feeding on a
Christiano.
So you're having a Lion Christiane
Burger for yourself.
This is just something you just found
out about three,
four years ago I was doing some research
on gladiators and games and all of that
that I was like.
And I started picking that savings,
a bunch of sources.
I'm like,
okay,
so this is not bullshit.
This is uh,
so is that something they discussed in
the history texts,
like they discussed that people would
talk about accidentally eating.
People are like,
how would they say?
Yeah.
Essentially they were like,
hey,
people ate the whole thing.
There was no,
nothing was thrown away.
The whole thing was.
And I guess I don't know if there were
primary sources that refer to these that
were,
that I forget the exact,
you know,
the smoking guns that say,
yeah,
this is what happened.
But I remember seeing it in an AF
secondary sources to say,
okay,
there's something to that story.
I didn't know there was any history at
all.
If people eating lions.
Yeah,
I mean you wouldn't as a choice,
but if you are a starving plebe and
enroll was nothing else,
and the emperor say,
look,
what a nice guy I am.
I'm giving you lie on star Mark,
please have fun car.
It's that is the civilization that we
always point to when we talk about
excess leading to chaos leading to the
client of civilization.
We always talk about Rome,
but either the United States way more
fucked up and decadent than Rome ever
was.
Except for feeding Christians to the
lions.
Yeah.
Other than that,
if you look at the overall numbers of
death,
there's a lot of shit that we've done to
the environment should do.
We've done.
I mean that just the sheer number of
human beings.
You're dealing with 350.
Was it somewhere?
Three $50 million.
It's a lot.
It's just,
it's crazy that they got to the point
where they were entertaining themselves
by bringing
in gigantic predators.
Like how far is Rome from Africa?
How the fuck did they get lions?
Yeah.
Day will dive a hand thirst trap and
then Dan them I guess a set up a bait on
something they would like.
They would fall in,
in um,
in a big pete where they can climb it
every way out.
And then I don't know exactly how they
get a cage on them and their rapid.
It's,
I'm sure a lot of people died to
provide,
uh,
the lions for Rome and then you ship
them by boat through cc Dan they send up
to Rome and uh,
they did to a level that they see that
the animal population of North Africa
changed completely because of the Roman
games because they were killing
thousands upon thousands of them that
they literally,
they drove some species extinct in north
Africa,
at least in that part.
You know what the fuck?
Yeah.
That's such a massive scale they want to
do for the Games.
And the Roman,
the guys were setting up to the games.
They were kind of like,
remember when pride was on and there was
those wacky Japanese matchmake he'd
wanted.
They would have like,
let's throw the 600 pound,
the Huda case,
the hundred 50 power.
Let's see.
What happens though is that Robin's
matchmakers or like Japanese
matchmakers,
they had those ideas.
It's like,
I wonder what happens if we throw at the
bar.
Let's see what you know.
Let's try it.
We'll do that stuff.
Was there a conversation like that
before them or did they invent these
games?
Put all bleed.
The gladiatorial stuff was ancient in
Greece and some people think about the
Etruscans as well.
There may have been some orange in there
because the story about the gladiators
is that I started out as human sacrifice
that they would do it rather than he
originally.
They probably sacrifice somebody on the
grave of some important person because
the idea was that there was feeding the
spirit of the dead.
Then probably somebody said,
hey,
how about instead of sacrificing me,
I give you entertainment,
so we have a nice big fight.
I got the other prisoner of war.
We go at it.
One of us died.
Doesn't have to be me.
I have at least a shot,
one of us,
the blood will feed the data and the
other one got to walk over live.
We decided bay.
Cool.
It's like we got entertainment on top of
the sacrifice.
That's one of the popular theories.
You think it was the prisoners idea or
do you think it was like some.
I would think they would more likely be
some sadistic rulers idea.
I mean if you will.
Yeah,
there's that one sword into the cage.
That could be.
But at the same time,
if I'm the.
What about be sacrifice and be like,
Hey,
I'm going to make it fun for you guys
just.
But he'd be somebody else.
And uh,
but yeah,
erk is,
it started out probably is a religious
thing and then it evolved into,
oh,
this is fun.
It's corroded religion.
But just that sort of a good time.
Um,
well we always point to the decadence of
the Roman Empire as being like the
pinnacle of their excess.
Right?
That's how we look at it.
But then you go to Disneyland and you
see people on scooters everywhere you go
within themselves.
These gelatinous beanbag
style human beings.
I was just a Disneyland.
I've,
I've.
Every time I go there are more scholars.
There's more and more people just
getting so big that they can't
walk.
Yeah.
That's make it easier for people weed
themselves to that because that's what
we want.
It's had dairy are one of the reasons
why I think he's seen thirsting for many
people in the US to study at all.
When there's this fascination for Rome.
He's because of the parallels are not
that hard to see.
You know,
you see that super powerful civilization
that keeps growing and growing and power
and eventually hit the TPN scale off.
Access gets more and more.
People get healthier life,
so they do get softer and then you are
getting ready for her to fall in the
face of somebody else.
Tougher and stronger will come from a
harsher life was gonna.
You know,
it's the same stuff as the Roman empire,
right?
Eventually,
stop sending your guys to fight your
wars because I don't want my kids to go
to are about.
That's what we did.
It's our heritage,
but I don't want to do that anymore.
Let's hire some poor motherfucker to
fight for us.
In the process,
your civilization gets weak until
eventually the other motherfucker hiding
doesn't want to fight for you anymore.
They turn on you and your civilization
folds.
Never learn.
No.
It's a tough balance between leaving too
harshly where,
yeah,
you'll become this war machine,
but that's a sucky life and leaving to
softly when it's.
It's a real delicate game and I mean,
you know,
it is with your kids.
You want sinks,
easy for them.
You want to make every single as easy as
pleasant as possible,
but if you make it too easy,
you throw them into wimps and suites.
If you make it too hard,
they'll hate your guts because it's
like,
fuck you.
You're needlessly making my life hard.
So it's like that very delicate game of
making field.
People love the,
giving them support Dev when needed,
but then also teaching them how to be
strong and does not happen through
softness.
It doesn't happen through making
everything easy for them.
I've had that conversation many times at
Brian Cowen where he and I were talking
about,
you know,
one of the reasons why,
um,
you know,
Brian lived very strange life,
like he went to boarding school for a
lot of the time.
He grew up all over the world.
He lived in many different countries and
we just faced a lot of adversity because
he couldn't make friends.
He was constantly moving and because of
that he's just really interesting guy
and everyone that we know that's really
interesting had some sort of a fucked up
life.
And yet we don't want our kids to have
fun.
You don't want your kid to be
interesting.
I guess maybe what's that Chinese
proverb with the curse may you live in
interesting.
Exactly.
It's uh,
yeah,
it's,
I,
I wonder if that's the only way to
create someone or to engineer the life
of a human being that's,
that's a,
that has character.
Like there's got to be ways that you
could teach through difficult
tasks or through athletic endeavors.
Like,
I mean,
I,
my life was definitely fucked up up
until the time where I was in high
school,
but all of my,
I think my real character development,
all of who I became like the harder
parts was when I was in a really nice
neighborhood.
I lived in Newton,
which is like a really nice suburb of
Boston,
but it was,
that was when I was doing martial arts.
That's what I was competing.
So I like consciously or purposely did
something really difficult because that
was what I was interested in.
I wasn't thinking,
oh,
this difficult thing will make me a real
interesting man when I grow up and this
will provide me with all this character
development.
That was like,
that was what I really wanted to do.
For whatever reason I was compelled to
it.
And then the byproduct of that was
developed character.
Yeah,
develop the ability to push myself and
discipline.
But I did it without having to go
through horrible neighborhoods.
Nobody.
I mean people will beat me up in the
gym,
but nobody beat me up in the street.
Nobody robbed me.
I didn't get shot or stabbed.
But I developed character in a way
that's similar to what someone would
probably go through if they went through
some bad violent times and I think you
nailed it right there because you're
bidding getting up 17 that's not.
You're going to get that because we're
going to throw you in the street and
you're going to fight every day against
some crazy.
Kate's with nice and you survive.
You are going to be tough.
It's like,
well that's silly though,
but at the same time he's now let's have
you shall tear.
Then I think martial arts in that regard
is perfect.
You know,
combat sports are good age because they
do teach you toughness,
but they're still within a relatively
protected environment.
Nobody's gonna pull out the gun on you.
Nobody's going to will,
you know,
it's,
it's tough buddies,
CBLI stuff.
It's not a battle.
People through the walls and pray for
the best.
So it's a,
it's a nice medium.
And I think the more we make our life
easier,
which we want to,
we do need to engage in seeing that keep
the business alive at least to some
degree.
You're not going to be tough the way the
one guy who survive out of 100 was being
thrown to the wolves,
but at the same time you still have that
muscle.
There is now completely gone because you
are just all about because then now you
end up with people who are very
pleasant,
very nice,
very sweet and complete Williams and
don't have a spine and then it's like,
that's not the solution either.
They have no resilience.
They don't have any experience in
overcoming difficult situations.
I oftentimes think about that when I
think about animals because you know,
I have dogs,
I have cats and my animals have zero.
I mean,
I guess,
I mean they would,
they would kill something if they could,
but they don't.
They're not mean at all.
But if you see a wild animal or an
animal that has to get its own food,
there is so different and the only way
you can get an animal that's team is you
have to provide them with all their food
and then you have to bypass all of their
natural predatory instincts
that every dog has and every cat has.
And there's a way to bypass it.
You just got to give them steady food
and love steady food and loves food and
love.
And in doing that you quote unquote
domesticate them.
Right?
And that's kind of also what's happening
with people.
You know,
what we're doing with human beings is
turning people into these fluffy sort of
kitty cat type people.
Exactly where if everything goes wrong
and you find yourself on a deserted
island,
you can go feral,
try to figure out a way to survive or
eaten raw mussels and chewing on routes
and stuff.
But the reality is what you've become is
a domesticated person.
You know,
if you ever see like liquid,
they catch people,
they find people that have been like
living in the wild by themselves,
like it's only been a few times or are
found like actual wild feral people.
But they represented,
they resemble feral animals.
They don't.
And a lot of ways
that's how you survive.
You know,
it's who does live in the wild and
succeed while Dynamo.
So human being was going to do with
that.
This is going to be along those lines.
It's
but what we value from people,
a lot of what we value is domesticated
people.
Like what I like is people that I go up
to a hug them.
I know they're not going to try to bite
my neck
to avoid a leader that way as well.
Yes.
I tend to enjoy the same thing.
Now it's like anything is a balance and
the balance is not 50 50,
maybe 90 slash 10,
but you still need to have a little of
that other side is always that there's
a.
Once you go a hundred zero,
Daniel really lost something.
You know?
It's like where exactly is that
balancing a desirable place where you
are a strong person by our also pleasant
and sweet and nice and you can do all
the things that we want in a civilized
conversation without you being weak
because that's the other aspect.
When people lack the staff side,
then I don't buy their and cedar because
it's like you are nice because that's
the only thing you can be.
You don't even have the option not to be
nice because you don't know how.
You don't know what it takes to instead
step up and be assertive and extra stuff
you don't have,
so your niceness is not a choice.
You have your cab.
It shows their belly try is.
Whereas if somebody doesn't have to be
that way and chooses to be that way,
then I buy it directly.
Then is legit because you're choosing
that,
right?
If someone is generous because they want
to be generous because they have to be
generous.
Yeah.
It's a strange,
fine line.
What why I was,
why I've been focusing on this and
obsessed with this lately is I've gotten
this weird idea in my head,
not necessarily weird,
but this inescapable thought about human
beings domesticating themselves with
supermarkets and that Sim supermarkets
are in many ways a lot like serving a
cat,
a bowl of cat food every day and that in
removing the equation of having to go
and cut the wheat and pick the
vegetables and kill the animals that you
eat and instead just show up the
supermarket by throwing the cart.
That what we've done is we've developed
a system of domestication and the
supermarket or the fast food restaurant
or whatever,
wherever you're getting your food and a
lot of ways serves the same purpose that
a master does to a pet and that we were
slowly domesticating the human animal in
that way.
I think there's a lot of parallels there
and that's one of the reasons I'll also,
I think why people get angry.
Even people that eat meat when they find
out that people hunt.
Yeah.
I think that they're reacting to this
path that they're on and it's a path of
domestication.
Even if it's a rational.
Even if they eat meat and I've had the
most irrational,
which is people that are strict veggie
vegetarians or vegans,
but they have animals.
They feed meat to say,
yeah,
that doesn't know.
I know it's a lot of this stuff make no
sense.
It doesn't make sense,
but the rationalizations,
I feel like they form such a common
pattern that you almost have to take
into consideration the fact that those.
Those rationalizations may in fact be
natural protective mechanisms for this
domestication process to take place.
Yeah,
and I think that as we become more and
more peaceful and more and more
civilized,
like I would say,
and I think everyone agrees that this is
probably the safest time for human
beings to live ever.
Well,
you're a historian.
You know a lot about history.
Yeah.
You would probably say that,
right?
Yeah.
I mean,
when you look at so much of human
history,
there's always the guys,
but I'm over to Hilo are going to come
up and slow through your family at the
drop of a dime.
So now the fact that most people in many
countries in the water,
in that situation,
it's kind of unique.
That's a.
it's awesome.
It's not something that he.
Most of recorded history,
you can find evidence of.
You don't find any evidence that.
Right?
Like if you think about like a cruise
ship pulling up to your harbor and a
bunch of people get out,
you welcome them now strangers from a
strange land and you're like,
oh,
this is great.
They're going to come over here and
they're going buy my trinkets.
No,
they're going to buy a Poncho,
you know.
Whereas at four they were going to come
with fucking swords and kill your
family.
So do you watch the TV series vikings?
No,
I didn't.
It's pretty bad us.
Really?
Yeah,
I like it.
See,
I,
uh,
I'd never heard anything about it.
Rarely gets good.
Photography is awesome.
This is pretty good.
It's.
And there's these ones scene that I was
watching from the third season where
there's this critical viking standing
outside of batteries.
So you see,
it seemed the distance though the shape
and it's beautiful that you see these
pieces.
DOLLF semi-naked,
Vikings.
We put our trust and they are starting
to scream.
It's acts dive.
It's so hard to tie,
but you know,
it's like about a show.
That's where they're screaming.
It's time and its sword time.
Exactly how it's hammertime.
What about Hammerton?
Excited?
No.
I'm married.
Escaped habitat and the.
That's a lot of fuel,
but he's 30 there.
That's
a lot of human history.
People that have and people that have
not and the have nots show up at the
gates and they are hungry and they are
more motivated than New Yorkers.
They are hungry.
It is amazing that this is one of the
only times that we've ever recorded
where people show up in places where
they don't know anybody in their
welcome.
Yeah.
You're welcome all over the world.
Yeah,
no.
Could.
He said Ryan,
as there are many people who have their
theory that like way,
way,
way in a distant past in the hunting and
gathering time,
people are not more Amandla.
There was less war and then there's the
other camp or that argues.
No,
no.
The hunting and gathering tiny store,
crazy column for the ats.
Just he didn't tap into it often because
there were a few people,
so they don't run into each other that
much and the reality realities,
I don't know,
is that right?
I don't think either one is completely
right in the sense that I don't think he
was at peace and love scenario because
that's not how human beings operate and
I don't think he was a small deal that
totally states can save you from
violence because otherwise everybody's
always killing each other.
I don't necessarily think of that Cedar,
but clear.
I mean we do have evidence that people
bash each other brains forever for a
long time.
Our frequent that was,
that's the question and there are
different schools of thought in that
regard and it's kind of hard to come up.
We took a glues,
events are,
but other than that scenario,
which is so far in the past that we
don't have solid evidence on for match
of the history that we do every courts
about.
Yeah.
People do nasty shit to each other all
the time.
Yeah.
I think Chris is talking about tribal
cultures that live,
you know,
indigenous people that live in the
jungle and shit like that.
I think when it's resource dependent,
I think when there's a lot of resources
and there's plenty of women to fuck.
Yeah,
everybody's.
I Have Ryan also.
He loves those polyamorous society.
He loves it.
Yeah.
He loves those.
The concept of these cultures that
existed that didn't have,
they weren't able to trace lines of male
paternity,
so the entire villages would raise
children,
which exists right now,
and this is some parts of the world,
you know,
I mean that,
that's,
that's how some indigenous cultures
still operate to this day,
but yet there's also indigenous cultures
like the ones in New Guinea,
which,
uh,
the sperm warriors beginning,
which is,
you know,
that story right there.
Remind me later.
I know somebody been fighting,
going on about some.
What's up with disparate warrior.
Awful,
awful.
Pedophilia.
They,
they will take children at a very young
age and make them consume calm.
Yep.
Both in their ass and in their mouth.
And Make God mad.
Yes.
Yeah.
They call you the,
the,
the leave their parents and go stay with
what they call their anus.
Father Jesus.
Yeah.
There's,
Oh God.
And they'd been doing this for thousands
of years.
For whatever reason.
This became a style of living.
Somebody was really into little kids
when they see the doc,
the gods have spoken theses,
how you'll make her yell the message
from upon high,
from now on.
It's not romanticizing,
etc.
But at the same time,
demonizing,
get this,
uh,
and I don't mean these [inaudible] yeah,
dc's fuck it up,
but I mean tribal culture that there's
great stuff there.
There's all full of stuff there.
There's human stuff done,
right?
There's the whole spectrum of it all.
And I do like what chris is doing in
terms of,
I don't know,
it's a historically 100 percent right in
that deBate about are cool or not so
cool.
Ancient tribal societies were,
but I do like the where is going with in
terms of what these,
that we can learn either from the actual
history or from something that sound
cool that may not exactly have that bend
away,
but the gives as an idea because
ultimately what the fuck cares what they
did 10,000
years ago,
but it's about what you can do now that
gives you an idea of what you can do now
to make life better.
I don't care whether it really happened
or not.
If it makes life better now,
I'm happy.
You know?
Good point.
That's a really good point.
Like what?
What is possible now?
Yeah,
and I firmly believe now is the best
time ever.
I mean,
I think we're incredibly lucky to live
right now and as long as we don't hit
some sort of a natural disaster or
someone fucks up and accidentally starts
a nuclear war,
I think it's a great time.
He's not perfect,
but there's no,
there's nothing going to be perfect.
It's what we were talking about,
just the sheer numbers of humans.
You know,
20 people on an eye with three girls.
17 men.
You're going to have death.
Yeah.
Akiva,
I don't think one night goes by without
you here.
China recently,
they changed their one child that day.
Oh yeah.
Like when?
The last few days.
Really?
Yeah.
That can go both ways.
I mean on one end you,
the whole female fantasize was fucked up
and the other end,
a China growing dramatically.
Population that's not exactly a good
thing gator.
So what are they going to do it because
there's only like 15 girls,
right?
I guess actually fucked up this idea
that you would only have men because the
men would be able to take care of you.
Well you,
you guys threw a monkey wrench in your
whole generation.
They sure did.
What?
A fucking cluster.
Yep.
Big time.
Oh,
can you imagine being a guy and you
growIng up there and you're on that
island with 17 dudes and three women are
like,
yeah,
fuck.
I know that's,
that's a shitty deal that I got to be
the worst.
Trying to get laid as a man in China
must be fucking hard.
I can see how that would not be easy or
I would imagine people,
high school universe.
But you know,
a young males would be pretty deep piece
golf.
Condom shares fall after China abandons
one child shares in companies that make.
What does that nappies prems and baby
milk up.
What is it?
Oh,
I guess like baby stuff up on friday
after beijing announces plans to change
family planning laws.
I just don't know how they're going to
engineer their population.
I mean,
this was in response to overpopulation,
that's why they decided to have a one
child policy,
but that's just not good when everybody
wants a man.
Yeah,
exactly.
Is that they didn't think he threw in
that scenario because I mean,
I can see the idea.
You have too many people,
too few resources.
You'll get fuck it up.
You'll kind of do that.
But at the same time now he's like,
okay,
nobody was going to have a baby girl,
so let's all have boys because that's
what I want.
And so there's this dumb dad that I
talked to sometimes he's so it's every
now and then I get stuck talking to him
and he's just like,
he has daughters and he wants sons and
you know,
like,
and like,
dude,
you're fucking daughter's are healthy.
Like what is wrong with you?
I have a friend who is a child that has
severe autism and all these terrible
behavioral disabilities and he's,
he's a mess.
I'm like,
you're lucky.
You're extremely fortunate.
You have healthy children in America.
Yeah.
You hit the goddamn lottery and your
dumb ass is whining that you don't have
a son to play softball with and even in
that light,
because you can't fucking teach a girl
to play softball because it's not girly.
What a of play softball.
Maybe you know the idea that your son is
an extension of you is one of the
stupidest fucking attachments that some
people have.
You're,
it's a human being.
The human being.
You're fortunate enough to be the parent
of this human being,
this idea that you're upset that it's
one gender or another,
just shut the fuck up you monkey.
And that goes back to the stupid
stereotypes of masculine and family.
Know what it means to be a man or a
woman.
It's like,
of course there's genetic stuff and
there's not.
That's a given.
You know,
there's not even an article at
simultaneous in nature,
but then there's also a bunch of feet
that these nurture and these solar rays
and somebody may have a tendency going
one way,
but if you teach them and you can
balance it out in other ways,
you know,
he's like,
to me even the most interesting people
are the ones that I've built that have,
you know,
the stereotypical sensitivity from the
supposed to be female,
but they are always so tough and who the
hell said that being emotionally
sensitive is a only for women or that
being tough is only for men.
I get bored with both people unless you
have both,
unless I can relate to you on multiple
levels.
It's pouring.
It's like can be for sure.
The typical girly girl is like,
jesus,
I'm fearing sick disease killing me.
It's so boring.
But also the typical guy who breaks a
beer bottle off,
he said,
watching affordable.
That's not exactly.
Okay.
That's great for about 10 minutes and
then I'm out.
You know,
it's to me it's like the aveda human
beings that are strong and sensitive.
What the hell is wrong with that idea?
You know,
it's like,
yeah,
this is why one of the biggest problems
growing up as if you're stuck in a
neighborhood,
if you're stuck in the neighborhood and
the people in your neighborhood are all
stupid and there's no one interesting to
draw from.
There's no one to find that you can
relate to.
Like I remember being a kid and uh,
you know,
you have a good friends that you
really enjoy hanging out with and when
they weren't around,
he would hang out with dummies and you'd
be like,
oh my god,
it's so taxing.
If you,
if you have the wrong,
if you just buy a roll of the dice,
find yourself in a neighborhood where
people are prejudiced or ignorant or
aggressively ignorant or aggressive or
prejudice.
You could just have a terrible time.
He just want to stay home and be locked
in your environment.
And I think until the internet came
around,
that was the biggest issue in children
growing up.
You were a subject to your environment
or a victim of your environment.
Sometimes a product of your environment.
That's why even what we're doing it
right now,
the idea that somebody in Sweden can
download and listen to what's happening
that's 30,
I mean shit.
I would have loved to grown up with that
possibility of needing to conversation
so that I'm not traveling to the
immediate reward that is in the few for
where you are born and when you are
raised,
but you'll get access to and then you
realize,
well there are people out there with
different way of thinking other than.
I mean think about even when tv came
around than somebody in the middle of
the United States in a town of 5,000
people suddenly could see people who
look differently or a different
conversation has been the most freeing
thing in the world.
Unless you were black and they were
like,
where the fuck are all the black,
sanford and son?
Yeah.
He like,
what in the fuck there's got jefferson's
finally,
but he said that funny that like in the
19 fifties,
hold the advertise that are sold.
The programmers tilt.
In order to attract people,
we need to make the content as not
controvert like the most uncontroversial
thing possible.
We make it very square.
We make it very safe.
No sex,
no violence will make it not end.
You see,
uh,
what we are attracted to today's one 80
completely.
It's like lost weight,
get all that.
Yeah.
The suppression,
right?
Yeah.
It's like we're the rio that's also
interesting.
Like advertisements,
like advertisements today,
like on the internet,
like podcasts here.
This is a perfect example.
No one has ever,
when I do a podcast ad say don't swear
or don't see something fucked up.
Like I say,
fucked up things.
Sometimes these ads,
because I'm winging it,
is a little long as I'm not saying
something.
When I say fucked up,
things are obviously jokes.
Yeah.
As long as I'm not saying anything
that's actually racist or homophobic or
sexist or anything like that,
people are fine with it and you could
never have one of my ads on a television
show,
no way,
but the people that watched a television
show or the same people that are going
to download a lot of podcasts exactly
like if like someone's listening to
howard stern in the morning,
right,
and they're hearing all this crazy shit
that's the same person that might watch
the big bang theory or america's got
talent at night and it's squeaky clean.
What's the same human being?
Yeah,
exactly,
but for whatever reason they decided
this human being can accept it in this
form but can accept it in that form like
you might.
You might watch something that's totally
squeaky clean and the advertisers are,
but the same person might go to a rated
r movie and watch crazy violence and
death and some fucking horror film.
It's.
It's weird what we decide people can and
cannot be subjected to cannot be exposed
to that.
Especially with nudity.
One kind of nudity,
alto,
my automatically is the highest possible
that because that's gonna fuck up your
brain,
right?
If you see a boob,
but now y'all are going to be screwed
for life.
It's like,
really?
That's what you are scared to show your
kids.
Would you remember vincent gallo know?
What does it mean to send vincent gallo?
That's his name,
right?
Vincent gallo,
the actor,
that's his name,
right?
There's an advancing gal.
He it.
He was a very respected actor,
like a really intense guy and he did
this movie.
He produced it and started in it called,
I think it was called brown bunny and it
was with this chick.
Chloe's va yankee.
I don't know how the fuck you say,
very good actress,
excellent actress,
but they had a real sex scene in the
movie and in this,
in the movie,
she sucks his cock,
like she really blows and he comes in
her face and on her mouth and it's real
and people were fucking furious.
People that went to see the movie hated
him and they were furious and it fucking
tanked his career.
I mean tanked his career.
Never even heard of that.
That's crazy.
Well,
he's done some stuff since then,
but not much and he's done like some
vodka ads,
like some vodka commercials,
but before that he was like,
this guy that was like this go to guy if
you wanted this like really intense
character and he's a very good app and
just like,
you know a guy who just decided,
look,
I'm going to take a crazy channel.
It's like,
look,
we have these quintin tarantino movies
where guys are getting their ears cut
off where they're taking these crazy
chances with violence and pulp fiction
where the guy gets shot in the head and
sprain,
splatter over the back seat and there's
all these racial slurs being thrown
around by white people to black people.
This is all fine,
but a guy getting his cock sucked in a
movie.
You could see like if she dropped down
to our knees and you only saw the back
of her head and she was sucking his
cock,
that will be okay.
That it's fine.
It'll be okay.
I know,
but to see his actual penis in her
actual mouth for whatever reason,
people were like,
no fucking way.
That's it for you,
dude.
We're done.
Yeah,
that's.
Yeah.
I always find it so weird.
Everybody wants their dick sucked.
If you have a dick,
you want it.
Soft is the one universal truth because
even if you're gay,
right?
If you want it,
suck by flies anyway.
If you're straight,
you want to suck back.
Right?
Everybody loves blowjobs.
They're amazing.
It's one of the greatest inventions that
anybody ever figured out was that if
someone's sucks,
your dip,
it feels fantastic.
To watch it in a movie is somehow
horrifically offensive.
I totally consensual.
We're not watching you.
We're watching a totally consensual
sex act in a movie.
Meanwhile,
the same people that were offended
probably watch porn,
right?
Of course,
but as long as the windows are closed
and the shades are shut and the door is
closed and no one can hear them,
then they can pick and jerk off and
they're hypocritical world and they
think it's okay.
I don't remember if I mentioned that to
you before or knowledge because I always
cracks me up so much,
but there was a study neva know in Utah
a few years ago where,
uh,
because the standard way,
the supreme court at the top of the
obscenity laws,
they basically said that it boils down
to the standards of the community of
what the defined obscene or nothin swing
uta.
They were saying,
well,
we are a very conservative community,
so we,
uh,
we want the old,
the old tale chains.
You need to not be able to allow to use
porn.
They cannot sell barn is the number one
thing on the paper view in hotels are
like,
nope,
because the fence the standards of our
community.
So then they did these research and
found out a porn consumption in Utah is
actually way higher than most other
places to find what people say.
I will have people who are completely
different and that's how I find it
affected.
I think about being comfortable in your
skin to me is like,
look,
you like porn race.
It's just accepted.
It's who you are as long as they are not
key people,
as long as you're not doing anything
horrible to other human beings.
Acts.
Don't put forward this image of what you
think you should be when you're not that
person.
If you're not that person,
there's a reason why is not that healthy
for you is not the way you're built to
be.
It's not.
There's something there.
They deal with reality,
you know,
deal with where you're at and if you
want to change yourself,
then take a few baby steps away from
that,
but start accepting the fed that dcs
where you are.
This is what you like.
This is what you don't.
Then if you decide you want to change,
you can work on the address.
You're not going to change dramatically
because you don't change the essence of
who you are,
but you can,
you know,
smooth the edges if you really,
really want,
but that never happened.
Something like that.
You start with realizing what it is that
you are and you stare at it and accept
it for what it is.
You know?
It's interesting too because I think
that a lot of what people are worried
about is other people's perceptions of
them and those same people are shielding
their own reality from other people.
Worried about their perceptions.
They might all be into the same thing.
Exactly.
There's um,
uh,
the podcast center the other day coming
up,
I sent it to the world but a while back
and he was reading through and one thing
that he was cracked up about is like
men,
you have zero filter your toys,
like the staff you say about what you
think,
what.
That's not the kind of theme that boss
people that meet to you though.
That's the kind of stuff that it's a
socially.
Most people who are professors.
Yeah.
Never mind that.
That's a big one.
Your world,
right?
Yeah.
Where does this image of how we are
supposed to be?
And to me it's like that's such
bullshit.
It's like a,
b,
a you on being about that extra freedom
because you have podcasts and because
you can,
you can express yourself through that
and you can actually make money doing
that too.
So it's,
it's you have these other outlets for
expression.
Yeah,
I mean I think I realized I had these,
a really stupid idea for a long time
that I could get a regular gig in
academia as I see it.
He goes by fast surrender and I could
have also the space to do all the other
stuff.
And then I realized this was actually,
I remember beating my office one day
after the realization that most
academics don't like me sync,
sung keen.
Most academics don't like you.
Why not?
Because I'm a student like me.
If they don't like them,
that means oh,
you must be too easy or too something or
sort of fed that.
I get along very well with students and
that's not always the case with them.
That's usually strike against me and
also when I was having this,
oh,
why is it that I didn't like me?
I don't understand.
I kind of step outside and it for my.
And he was,
I mean my office hours,
I'm playing him.
He named me my office and I have around
my neck,
our strap,
the globes that are just used to spar
with one of my students during a break
in my hand is my medical marihuana and
you had a blog he'd but why don't they
just like,
well,
if they like you,
there wouldn't be something we didn't
decide.
What do you expect they are with her and
that's fine.
That's the eighties,
but you can't expect to be just because
you're polite and you opened the door
for people that are,
that's nice,
but you're still if a very different
animal from what they are.
And so of course they are now gonna
embrace you as one of the few guys.
I bet you and daddy asked russell if you
were in the same staff,
get along great.
Sure,
sure.
There's a few.
There's,
there's people out there that are.
No.
Absolutely,
and in fact,
I'm not saying all people,
all academics are all equally.
Steve barring gas,
so that's not the case.
There are some radical people,
but the culture,
the general culture of what you're
supposed to fit in is a,
it's a very steep one.
Do you feel like,
I mean,
you've been a professor for a while.
Do you feel like the,
uh,
the culture is shifting?
The culture outside of academia shifts a
lot faster than the culture inside,
like cooling institutions,
they tend to be the last place to
change.
It's like when everybody else gets to
accept something that maybe they will.
It's kind of like politics,
you know,
whereas like after 99 percent of people
in us will be put on legalization of
marijuana,
then some politician will say,
we'll do this really daring thing and
try to,
you know,
it's not going to start from the inside
at any establishment is built on keeping
the status quo.
So that's nowhere.
So I locked off.
If anything,
a lot of academia I'm seeing,
he's becoming more and more
bureaucratic.
There's more of a do measurable seeings
do stuff that everything can be
accounted for so we don't get sued.
Make sure to do.
There's a lot less flexibility and
allowing people to kind of run the show
as they like it because they're like,
what if somebody runs it the wrong way
and they will get sued,
which sure that is a concern,
but you're also eliminating the
possibility of people doing cool things
in the process and so I don't know.
I don't see,
don't see tremendously good changes in
that regard.
What about the,
the changes in as far as political
correctness or the,
uh,
the ideologies on campus,
they seemed to be more extreme and more
left wing now than they have in any time
in the most recent history,
at least.
Obviously I'm not in school,
but from people that are reporting on it
and professors that I've interviewed,
I know I'm pulling for you,
has done that because honestly I hear
about it a lot.
I read it in the newspapers,
I hear about it from other people
telling me I don't see it.
What do you experience?
You know,
the whole extreme level of political
correctness is not one that I have two
that I witness a lot.
I get to what I do.
I say what I say,
nobody gets pissed off,
nobody yelled at me over.
It tends to be fairly injera guarders,
tila little and I don't see my students
getting offended that I ever seen the
way you would read based on websites and
I'm not saying that that doesn't exist.
I'm sure it does.
I mean it must be based on something.
I just don't think he's quite as either.
I'm extremely lucky for some reason or
he's not quite as pervasive as it sounds
on paper,
but I don't know because you know,
of course all I know is my experience
and that may not be representative of
what's out there.
It's also probably indicative of the
sheer numbers of people that are in
school.
Did you ever see that old bill hicks
bit?
Bill hicks had this really funny bit
about cnn,
about how you.
Every time you turn the news,
murdered death pit bulls and he goes and
then you go look out the window when you
hear a chirp chirp.
He was where the flux all this shit
happened.
But I think just the sheer numbers of
human beings that are in school.
If you're dealing with,
you know,
how many millions of kids are in school,
I don't know how many there are,
but out of those you're going to be able
to cherry pick some extreme examples of
social justice warriors,
political correct thinking,
you know,
progressive thinking,
run a muck.
It's diversity.
Run a mock.
That's what going on.
I think there's a that makes for a story
that got
about or as if you talk about the,
he's the same as wide way like water,
you know,
the extreme out there kind of thing that
makes people emotional involving the
story.
You would report it and people get into
it.
Whereas the fuel really talk about what
a lot of the time happens is not that
glamorous and so yeah,
it's not as a reporter.
Have you had any backlash at all from
doing like controversial podcast cause
you know you don't hold back?
No,
definitely not volunteers,
but I think algae is that probably these
are not the same.
People will listen to podcasts,
care or date.
They brother.
This is so good.
It is.
I was in a history department meeting.
I won't mention the school.
None of that makes a difference because
it's the same scene,
probably 99 percent of them,
but they were talking and this is like
30 people or whatever.
Many people who are historians who
that's what they do.
Right,
and when I mentioned dan carlin hardcore
history,
nobody knew what I was talking about and
fucking kidding me.
He's like,
you are a historian.
That's the number one history podcast
out there is one on the planet podcast
period of any kind.
It's amazing the guys at god at lane
this game in 90 minute or theme like you
didn't even bother checking.
What's that tells me that you're so
locked in a tower out there,
then you have no idea what's.
I was blown away.
I mean even I was surprised and they
have really bad feelings about academia
to begin with and I was.
That was too much.
Even for me.
How is someone in the world of history
not find out about that?
That seems like it's such a
revolutionary way to distribute history.
Yeah,
precisely,
but that tells you how insulated are
days where it's about what's in the
food.
To note on page three,
57 of the monograph that has been read
by four people they may know about,
but that's weird that weird world yet,
but you know that weird world is what
got people to this age today where we
can do things like hardcore history.
I mean that was all created by the
knowledge that was taught through
schools and then dda bidding that
happened,
one of his podcast where you say,
look,
in the past history was a bit more
holistic in nature where goofy story on,
so we're also good storytellers and they
may have not been quite the same level
of researchers,
but they were really good storytellers.
History is moving more and more in the
direction of a good nerds will heat the
lie that are your.
Now you don't have to go to the library
or do it online,
but that are hardcore into research of
primary sources and you need it.
You know,
of course you need that skill because
otherwise you don't have the data to
subpoena.
Good story about that,
but if that's the history that's out
there,
you can have the most accurate history
in the ward and nobody wanted to eat it
because these guys can tell it because
it's dry.
You need a bullet,
you know you need the hardcore
researcher would dig south,
32 beats it in there.
Then you need the ones who can spin it
in a way to that can communicate with
other human beings that people that can
make an mk or they can make it a mean.
Interested can and these are often not
the same people because it requires a
very different balance.
Yeah.
That's a lot of people say about neil
degrasse tyson as well,
that he's a.
He's such a brilliant man,
but a brilliant communicator like that.
His real skill is in making it
entertaining and exciting and an
absorbable upset.
Whereas the the dry lectures that you
might listen to from a physics
professor,
nobody cares.
It's just not get in there for whatever
reason,
but you need that guy.
Sure you need it.
Has that desire acquire that
information.
The problem with academia is that they
have made that guy the only.
That's the measuring stick of what the
historian is.
That's one side of it.
It's an important one and I give you.
That is an important one,
but it cannot be the only one because
there's a reason,
like every single one of the best books
I've ever read,
he's always said eaten by a Jordan
released.
He's never written by a historian
because Jordan is.
They are paid to know how to tell a
story to make it.
You know the reason why you're paid is
because you need to hook a reader in
that doesn't have to read that story
that makes you want to.
Dan.
His background was as a journalist,
you know it's about people who nobody
owes you.
Their attention is you intrigue them and
so they want to pay attention.
That's that skill.
Most of the people who are professional
historians in a traditional sense that
talent is not encourage is not something
you may have it by luck because that's
how you are as a human being,
but it's not something that you are
encouraged to develop.
As part of being a good historian that
seen as I add,
that's popularizing it.
That's.
Yeah.
What's wrong with that?
To be able to make something accessible
to people.
Isn't that funny though?
That will be shunned.
Popularizing something that's as
important as the historical record.
Yup.
It's one of the most important things
for human between human history or for
human beings rather is to understand
history because then you can learn from
the mistakes of the past and then
understand the parallels of what's going
on in the current time.
Like when you look at the roman empire
and you talk about the great excesses
and how that civilization crumbled under
the weight of its own access.
You look at us now,
you go,
well there's some parallels here.
People on scooters and disneyland.
I mean it might not be feeding
christians to the lions,
but I mean there's.
There's definitely some fucking crazy
shit going on right now that they're
going to look back on when when you look
at the average american diet and the
fact that I was in disneyland the other
day and I told you that are on scooters,
but one of the other things is they had
to change the boats out in the pirates
of the caribbean ride if everybody's
still bad because people are too big.
They've done this several times.
They've had to change the boats and they
had to dig a deeper trench on.
It's a small world because over the
years people have gotten heavier and
heavier and they have to accommodate and
they have to take into account the
possibility of 600 pound people.
Wow.
That's what they're doing now because I
saw several 600 plus pound people that
are just overflowing on their scooters
and they also have to help those people
from their scooters onto these rides.
So these rides have to be reinforced in,
in order to take the weight of several
people.
I mean,
a lot of these rides are like you're
supposed to only get two people in the
average to people.
You get two people together,
you know,
maybe 400 pounds for two people,
right?
When they got one person the weigh 600
pounds and so this does this ride's not
really designed for this,
so that's discrimination.
You've discriminated against,
are large,
large citizens to these is the most
disgusting stories that have ever earned
or say I totally to danko was seeded by
podcast is so gross,
but it's sensitive.
My wife had told me what she was working
in hospital.
She said,
oh man,
I got pulled over by a colleague.
They told me this story and it's cowered
by braid ever seeds,
so we'll gladly scoured the brain of
everybody listening right now.
So these capital emptied to the doctor
or they were complaining about how they
keep trying to get pregnant and she's
not getting pregnant and you know,
the woman was like probably a good 500
pounds,
something like that.
Just rolls of fat everywhere.
The whole thing.
And the doctor was like,
okay,
let's see what's up.
Let's see.
What's going on and leave the fat folds
left or right.
Suddenly he realizes,
oh shit,
these people thought they were having
sex,
but based on the rest of you I'm seeing
here between the fat falls,
they weren't exactly having sex.
The guy was fucking different folds
thinking that he was in where he was and
and ben,
they were that he,
Hawaii,
they were not getting pregnant.
They should have let him keep fucking
the fact fold.
You're real close.
Real close.
What they told me that I'm like,
oh my god,
my brain.
I can now get that out of my brain now
forever.
I'd never done that will be a standard
move.
It's just titty fucking fat holds.
It seems.
I'm not shocked at all.
That didn't even make me feel sick
though.
Well,
these to the.
Yeah,
I think has lifted the fat false and
finding the rest of you from all the
failed attempts it seems.
I don't know.
See,
I was thinking that they're going to
find a fetus in there.
I was thinking you were going to say
that they didn't realize that.
Okay.
Yeah.
You waiting.
I can see why.
That's what I was thinking,
you know,
that's,
that's about it I gave you that.
I was someone was that fat.
Think they're going to take care of a
child,
you know,
and the little toddler start running
around like,
how are you gonna?
What are you gonna do to get your
scooter chase him around the park?
Right.
Well you probably stopped then with food
day and night,
they'll sit next to you.
One bit,
200 pounds by the time they're three
years old.
I've talked about this a bunch of times
on the show,
but the,
you know,
at the possibility of overindulging this
thought I've stopped eating sugar and
kind of.
Well I didn't stop but I cut it.
I cut it out completely for two weeks
and then I cut it way back since then.
And I will occasionally,
every few days or so I'll allow myself
one thing like a piece of like this
chili mangoes,
you know,
not angels with Chile that has sugar in
it,
but very,
very little sugar.
I lost like eight pounds from that.
Just doing nothing but that it's not the
same amount.
My energy levels completely different.
Like through the day,
I don't need.
I don't get tired towards the end of the
day anymore.
I just.
It just stayed normal.
It's weird.
That's what our nature is fucked up
because she was dark days,
sold them good and yet it's so
bad for you.
Well,
it's supposed to taste good in the form
of fruit because it comes with the
reward of vitamins and fiber and all
this other good stuff that's in fruit,
but we somehow or another hijack that
extracted it from the food and shoved it
into a liquid that comes in a nice
aluminum can.
You pop the top and you get that corn
syrup right into your heart.
But the average american diet is just
overflowing with sugar and these poor
people are just becoming bigger and
fatter and corn syrup and simple sugars
and they're just overwhelmed with this
excess sugar.
And it's,
that's the.
I think that's the primary issue that
people have when it comes to weight
loss.
Sugars and simple sugars and
carbohydrates and,
and uh,
you know,
a simple carbs like pastas and breads
and all that stuff which converts to
sugar,
alcohol which converts to sugar.
It's all but probably there's also
sitting on your ass forever and never
moving because I mean I see.
I would like when I go back to 8:30,
I see people
bulleit and people's lawns throws them
out of past.
Right?
They're like,
oh,
are you even.
And yet you see them and skinny most.
Yes.
I see what I eat,
what I wouldn't be like really are
hitting half the box of the whole thing
were like easy and I feel actually put
it to good.
I can go forward more.
You know,
it's like,
do they have the same wheat in it lands
where I have no question marks.
It's clearly something is different
there.
You know,
something is not because you cannot.
If it was just the carbs then that
would,
should do it then everybody should be
huge and that's,
that's not the case.
So something is going on.
I mean,
I've seen it even with the like if I
tomatoes in Italy versus tomatoes out
here,
tomatoes in Italy are awesome tasting
and they are feeling,
you know,
you eat some tomatoes,
you feel like that can be a big chunk of
your lunch right there.
I hate tomatoes here.
I feel like I'm drinking water in the
right package.
Do they taste like nothing and they
don't feel me like it's theoretical.
The same fruit,
but clearly something has been done
different in the way they have been
gmos,
man,
I don't fucking know,
but I had no idea why or what.
But clearly the result is different.
Well,
selective breeding.
I mean they've,
they've selectively made these tomatoes
a much more hardy tomato that doesn't
taste very good.
Right?
They've bred out all the juiciness
because they don't last.
Like I have some heirloom tomatoes at
home,
much spot on the other day.
They're already really soft.
I got to eat them tonight,
but I think people are lazy and they
don't go grocery shopping than enough.
And so he's like,
I want to bike domenico today.
The last three weeks from now we're
gonna.
Look,
just as neil and the fact is it's going
to look new,
but you have no thesis.
What's really in the shipping?
The shipping is the big issue.
Like being able to get them across the
country.
You,
of course,
big truck,
but the heirloom tomatoes,
I didn't even know they existed until,
you know,
10 years ago or whatever.
When I first one,
they're fucking delicious.
They are.
That's what a tomato is supposed to be
like.
Heck.
It's like we have this rare to beto.
That's the way it's all right there.
I hope we don't run out of heirloom
tomato seeds.
I would cry.
I would really cry if we get to a point
some day.
I'm hoping that with all these like um,
this is new emphasis on craft
restaurants and craft breweries and
craft,
you know,
people are really into like farm to
table restaurants.
There's a lot.
This is a great one near me and they
have a,
I get eggs there and the eggs of like a
dark orange yolk just like my eggs and
the food is all from a local farm and
they'll tell you like what farm they're
sourcing their be from.
It's a great little restaurant,
but I'm hoping that with that sort of
trend that more and more people embrace
that and then we'll keep the idea alive.
Have you know,
real natural foods co.
Sorry.
No,
you don't.
That's okay.
I was going to say,
but you know in other,
in other ways like things like golden
rice,
like genetically modified rice that is
much higher in protein.
That's helped a lot of people.
Kept a lot of people from starving.
No,
I'm all for people.
Having choices is like that thing I
don't like is when one model become the
the only model that you don't let
anybody else have a choice whether
there's a problem there is.
If it doesn't,
I don't even care which one is winning.
The point is if you start having a one
model lead,
there's a problem there.
So you do have the people who want none
of this shit and we out of the way
toward the opposite,
it's like we're going to saturate the
market so much.
Then we squeeze every other possibility
out.
Both of those are shitty choices.
Like you want to allow as much choice
out there as possible and in a way to
doesn't squash all the other
possibilities.
You know,
what I read recently and I thought I
thought it was really interesting is
that mcdonald's is apparently hurting
like really badly and that their profits
are down radically from like 20 years
ago and that they're thinking that
eventually that model of really shitty
food,
fast food is going to be gone and
they're going to be replaced by things
like in and out burger,
which is delicious.
They cook it to order,
takes a little bit more time,
but it's infinitely better.
Exactly.
And that these five guys,
places like that,
that's the new model and then that's
what you're going to get.
And then the idea is like if you've been
to lax recently,
have you been flying that?
Well,
one of the things you notice if you go
to lax is the restaurant choices have
gotten dramatically better.
Like you can get really good food at the
airport now,
like really cool restaurants.
They're not chains and like with this is
a brilliant idea.
They have a food truck there.
One of the,
uh,
they have a,
it's like a got a truck of face and
then,
you know,
there's a little restaurant behind it,
but the idea is they're gonna give you
food like you would get from a food
truck.
And so they're,
they're establishing this new sort of a,
a place to get which used to be like
you'd get chili's,
you know,
get like
applebee's.
It was like chain restaurants or
mcdonald's,
stuff like that.
But now you get like a really nice
salad.
You can get us a kale salad with real
cucumbers and stuff on it and stuff.
I think people are realizing that just
because this is the only way we've had
before,
but you don't have to have it this way.
No,
I saw this thing on one.
Oh,
anthony bourdain's shows was on san
francisco and one of the guys that runs
this really nice restaurant was going to
open up an all vegetarian healthy food
option,
a very cheap place in the tenderloin,
which is one of the worst places in san
francisco,
and the menu was going to vary between
two and $6.
That's it,
and everything on the menu is between
two and $6 and they had like a really
healthy veggie burger that actually
tasted good,
like more dean eight one,
and it's like,
this is actually,
I would actually go this and they're
going to try to provide healthy semi
fast food for people think that that's a
good idea I think,
and it's not that difficult because a
lot of healthy stuff.
There's the stereotype that all the
other stuff is crazy expensive.
Not all of it is just a method of
digging enough of finding scenes that
can be nutritious ratios and not crazy
expensive because there are those
options is not.
That seemed pull off all.
You need to have a bank in order to hit
the lt or you eat cheaply crop there.
Samo feet.
It's who,
but not completely.
There are options where you can eat
delicious meals that you like to cook.
I've done things to like when they think
about what I just spent and it's nothing
and his fucking deletions and this good
food and there's no trade shows and I'm
like,
what's wrong with that plan?
You know,
why is that?
And I think we'd,
what you were saying earlier also,
that intrigued me.
Something I've been obsessed in a bit.
The distance that goes from people
eating the food to the food to be
introduced.
And I don't mean just how far it
travels,
but even out disconnected.
We are,
I don't care,
even if it comes from three miles from
me,
I mean it's bad there of course,
but I mean through the idea of people
live in,
at least to some degree,
some contact with the food you eat.
So you do have,
whether it's,
you know,
the guy who I had remembered you added
on the show,
the image of the guy that landed the
vertical,
a woods or whatever they call it,
you know,
like that,
uh,
is it looked like a skyscraper where
they bought a bunch of trees all over it
was you.
Why don't these plans now was trying to
figure out how to um,
put on all the rooftops,
put gardens so that people can have
their vegetable gardens even on top of
like four story buildings or something
that there can be the building garden
that everybody goes.
Now I don't know how he's going to work
in terms of what that was.
Mike domenico,
fuck you,
I'm going kill you.
But having that idea where it may not be
old,
you are not self sufficient is not all
of your food,
but you have some contact with the food
that you're indicating.
I think everybody,
should I wait to one degree or another
in powershell it's hard because most
people don't have the space,
the situation to the weight in their
backyard.
But figuring out ways on the cheap to
make that up and figure out ways on an
architectural standpoint on it,
multiple ways to try to make the link
between people and eating food,
the direct ones so that people have a
sense of where food comes from and that
they raise their own food to one degree
or another.
I think that would be awesome.
I don't know how realistic that these
are our practical,
but why not take a few steps in that
direction.
Figure out how we can be done.
Yeah.
I mean everyone who has a backyard
should have a garden.
Yeah.
It's not that difficult to grow
something and just even if you only grow
a meal a month,
just a salad,
just something.
It's something particularly satisfying
about picking a cucumber that you grew.
Chopping it up,
putting in a sal,
cooking a squash that you grew this.
It's.
It's really nice.
And I think it's primal.
I think it,
it connects us in some sort of a way to
shade it a lot more.
You remember all the time and energy
that went into getting this stuff
from these big two.
Then you're like,
ah,
this is a,
there's a story behind it.
My friend remy warren was on the podcast
yesterday and he has a show on the
outdoor channel called a apex predator
and it's all about he follows these
different animals and tries to learn how
they hunt and how they survive and and
one of them was about bears and he had
to,
he tried to forage the way a bear
forages and he was shocked by how little
you could find to eat,
like you know what you're doing.
And we were talking and he was saying,
you look around at all these plants.
Everywhere we look,
we see trees,
bushes and garden,
but none of it you can eat.
Like why do we grow so many plants that
we could just grow food everywhere?
And I was like,
I never even thought about that.
Like instead of palm trees have food,
trees everywhere.
Food.
Could you imagine if everyone,
anywhere you looked,
everywhere you go,
there was grapes growing and tomatoes
and,
and fucking peaches and shit.
Why not?
Exactly.
I agree 110 percent.
With that,
it's like it's we,
we need to work in that direction.
It gets totally possible if there's all
these bushes and trees.
Every,
every city.
Street has bushes and trees and.
But none of them are growing food.
It's weird.
Science.
What does it.
And it's not like those,
like an apple trees,
a beautiful tree.
Like a cherry tree.
That's a beautiful tree though.
Why don't we do.
I don't get it.
I don't go to data.
It's strange.
It's like somewhere along the line we
lost the plot.
Like,
yeah,
growing a bunch of shit we don't need.
That seemed like a really smart concept
is.
Yeah.
That's.
Hold on.
Yeah.
It's very strange.
It's very strange that we don't have
food around us all the time.
Like we have to rely on it getting
shipped in and trucks.
Yep.
Yeah.
I mean seriously,
like any major american city or math or
most cities in the lord,
our [inaudible] fire away.
They are one big blackout away from
everybody turning into the walking dead.
It's,
we're seeing things get really ugly
really quick because noboDy has any idea
how to get food.
Danielle,
ebola,
do we have to end on a low note?
No,
let's piCk up.
Let's go.
We're almost out of time.
That's very little time here.
Left.
What do you got there?
What's the book you got?
Oh,
this is.
I'm doing research.
Uh,
this is a book about caravaggio,
the italian painter I'm doing because I
put up here a bunch of research for
history on fire.
I prepare a lot of research ahead
because otherwise with dan carlin ended
up doing is that you do need to have
this humongous gaps between one episode
and the next to research because he
takes as doing the math the other day
just because I was bored and I figure it
take me to produce a two hour episode
for history and fire.
It takes me probably about 200 hours of
work have shown and research and read
the book and take the notes and do this
and that.
So,
I mean that's a fulltime job.
I can release episodes often if,
uh,
if I'm doing other thIngs.
So what I did is for the last two years
I basically prepare to start history on
fire.
So you knew you were going to do this
for the last couple of years?
I've been working at it,
not all the time,
you know,
while I do another thing and now I can
get to bed,
but I basically prepare eight episodes
so I would have the research ready to
roll,
just need to record data and that's it.
So he buys me a little time.
So I kind of released that these old 76
weeks now until eventually the research
catch up with the ana done carlene
skylar.
But hopefully I'm.
So now I'm researching episode denying
the well I am on steel on episode two is
our,
it's like trying to eventually will
catch up,
which they probably won't be that long
until catch up with me,
but until then by deleveraging episodes
on a relatively often scared or I can
also hook up more people and by that
point they may be more forgiving if I
take longer to do the research.
But it's such an intensive style of
podcasting.
It's really like not just educational,
but it's like you're,
you're,
you're kind of doing a lecture.
It's an audio lecture.
Yeah,
I did when I did that too.
I was really happy with episode one.
I thought kicks ass.
It's good.
It's every single I wanted that I
picture in my mind is coming on.
I did episode two,
I listened to it and I'm like,
this is a b effort.
This is not what I wanted and buy.
I did the whole thing.
I recorded over a few days.
I'm like,
no,
come on iT.
And then I was like,
you know what?
Fucking delete and start over.
Wow.
You deleted it.
Yeah.
That was like,
no,
I don't,
I don't want to do a specialty.
Definitely not at the beginning,
but in general,
you know,
you want to release it and then delete
it.
I just recorded it.
That was,
we're about to put the intro,
the outro,
that kind of thing.
And I was listening and I'm like,
no,
it doesn't have that punch that I want.
And um,
and so I was like,
no,
fuck it.
I'll do it on an outline or like,
how do you.
Yeah,
it's a fairly detailed outline now you
don't want to date because of course
then it doesn't sound natural,
but you and I have a pretty clear of
where we are going and uh,
so if you haven't eaten a quotation that
you need to call it is right there.
If you,
you know exacTly where it's going.
So it's same ice cream,
but then you do it where you can.
It's kind of like if I deliver a lecture
in class,
I'll take a peek at my notes and like,
oh,
that's what I need to go next.
But then you deliver it in a more
natural style.
And so that's a good chunk of notes.
But then of course you don't read the
notes,
you just have them there as a to keep
you on track so that you know where
you're going next.
And I'd be really curious to see if your
accent is the same.
By episode nine.
I honestly duct is going to change
because again,
if I could direct,
you know,
actually I got in trouble because I say
you told your podcast.
I think the first time I was on your
podcast,
that as a joke,
I said,
you know,
I used to speak perfect english.
I just,
I'm using good for women.
Right.
And people took it seriously.
They thought that I really like fucking
pig.
Yeah.
And might affect.
If I could pull that off,
I will actually would do it because it's
still.
If I couldn't go that way,
I wouldn't do it,
but he's really just like,
don't theory.
Well you have a green light to do it
because you're italian.
I started to move to Italy and I started
talking like this.
Then I will be a poser,
poser.
The fact he's also eat would take an
insane amount of work to change because
I don't hear it,
so I would have to really sit down and
just spend four over dwayne and that you
have the most extreme version of a
completely fluent english language that
I've ever heard.
Have anthony bourdain's wife is from
Italy and she has a very strong italian
accent,
but she's way clear than you have been
friends for a long time,
so I know exactly what you're saying,
what you're saying.
But if I didn't know you I'd probably be
like,
what the fuck did he just say that art
is a flow to it though people have zero
problem.
Most people are like,
oh no,
I understand everything you say,
no problem.
And then there are people who have no
idea of what one word I'm saying.
I had the,
I had a friend and I were talking on the
phone and they're like,
oh,
so I'm going to cook tonight and maxine,
what?
WhaT do you want to eat?
And I said,
ah,
I don't know what to say.
I was thinking of making some salomon
and they were like,
what?
Salmaan salmaan sorry,
I.
Oh,
fish.
Okay,
great.
What kind of fish?
Salmaan or like.
Because of course you don't say that's a
moron.
Put two and two together,
but also might on a salad bar and I'm
pronouncing every single ladder.
whereas it english salmon.
Yeah,
exactly.
Thank you.
That one,
but I can get it.
It's like,
and no one says sam edelman.
Yeah,
right.
That's not how you say you were making
up words.
I spell out every single thing because
you need that in every lecture that's
there.
It's meant to be pronounced.
So you read every single them let her in
english.
That's not the case and so that's
confusing.
But there's also some weird things like
two c's or an h,
two r.
YeAh.
And two
l's or a walk or thIngs get weird.
Yep.
That's the phonetic differences between
the way letters like,
like that's a big issue obviously with
portuguese to english too with the
brazilians are the ares or hs and
everything gets very weird when you try
to translate it baCk and forth.
Well that was what I wanted to ask you
earlier,
but I,
I'd actually forgotten when we were
talking about translating,
when you're talking about the difference
between learning english and seeing how
short and abrupt the sentences are as
opposed to like the italian.
How difficult is it when they're
translating ancient historical texts?
It's crazy hard.
Yeah.
It was crazy.
That's why a lot of translations are,
it's an art form,
you know,
some translators are awesome and who
knows if they are really true to the
original language but late do something
amazing and some don't.
It's a I love about achieving,
you know,
when you're ready.
Some translatIons are painful.
I don't give a fuck.
It's like this is boring as hell.
I don't know what they are talking about
and you read the next translation is the
best book I've ever read and he's like,
how can that even be?
But well there's some sort of an
artistic license and the trends,
translations,
that's what it is and that's what it
really kind of has to be taken into
account when you're talking about any
really ancient thing that it's an,
an,
a language you have to take into account
the time that they wrote it,
the way people communicated back then.
Even if you read ancient english stuff
like the way they talked.
I mean even just read the declaration of
independence,
the way people describe things and
communicate.
It's odd.
It is.
It's hard to wrap your head around,
you know,
big time.
Yeah,
it's a translation from one culture to
another one time period to another and
all of those combined like ancient
italian literature,
translating that into modern american
english.
It's gotta be like super bizarre.
Yeah.
You are kind of rewriting it.
It's a.
It's a cooperation between the writer
and the translator and it's a.
That's why when I don't are lots of
books that I read in italian because my
english stock and I couldn't read it
read in english and when I finally got
through to them in english,
I'm like,
well,
that's another book that's completely
different.
There are some similarities,
but it's a whole different style.
There's not even close.
Yeah,
I would think that would be the case.
Absolutely.
With the bible,
they'll like to really understand the
bible.
You hAve to truly understand like
whatever translation.
Again,
like aramaic,
you'd have to like truly understand
ancient hebrew,
but ancient hebrew is like a real
squirrely language anyway.
Right?
Somebody pixi pick secondly the way.
Well as a sweet kind of.
There's a lot of guesswork.
Of course.
Well,
this one of the weirdest ones because
it's also a number.
It's a numerical language,
like the literature is the number one,
they don't have numbers or letters
served as numbers as well,
so it's like words had numerical value,
good luck that I was laying in bed and
there's a bunch of words today,
lIke there's a debate about what
percentage are still
under debate,
right?
And so like what,
what it actually means and what it
doesn't mean,
but imagine if you could learn ancient
hebrew like exactly how they did it.
Then you would understand what they were
trying to say,
but even then you wouldn't understand it
unless you were in the context of the
culture that existed when acute.
You had to know how they thought about
things.
Exactly.
That's why most of the time you have to.
You don't really know what that guy said
to you are these translational sound
bath or.
So I'll go with that one,
but you know,
know which one they meant.
Well,
it's got to be one of the really most
difficult.
one of the most difficult aspects about
history too,
because it was written by people who
decided how they wanted people to
remember the turn of events and exactly
whether or not that's exactly how it
went down.
There are cases where there's like the
egyptian guy who left the record of
like,
oh,
we meet,
we've met the hittites and were kicking
her ass if we wipe them out and the
pharaoh is the best that the jewelry,
the hittite accountant that does not
look like,
how do you,
how do you know what the fuck really
happened?
And we will have this vague sense of
what happened.
We know like facts,
like these people aren't around anymore.
It's just so somebody killed them,
you know?
Well we found this pile of bones and
this is where we think we found troy
because this is a spot like,
fuck man,
there's a ton off guesswork involved in
history.
You know,
we make it sound like it's this super
hard science and you know,
you want to be as scientific as
possible,
but there's a lot of guesswork at the
end of the day.
That's so weird.
It's so weird that we're trying to piece
together the past to understand how we
got here.
Almost like a giant crime scene of the
world.
yep.
We're slowly like brushing fingerprint
dust on things and trying to figure out
where the fucking blood splattered from
and what happened,
what the fuck happened,
and then you have to go over some shit
that people wrote down.
Don't even know what the hell they were
saying.
Get a bunch of scholars.
there's one episode I want to do next
that's.
There's no primary sources is all a
archeology and he's these guy.
I don't know if you'd remember to start
at guided.
They found the ball deep,
perfectly preserved for 5,000
years ago at the ice.
Yeah.
let's see what's.
Yeah,
it's an awesome story because through
archaeology you find out so much.
You can find out what this guy was
eating 5,000
years ago,
what the of this stuff and yet
ultimately you don't know who the hell
he was,
but there's.
It's a nice steady enough to tease you,
but just not enough to actually know all
is up.
Yeah.
It's.
It's amazing though that you can find
something like that preserved.
At least get like a short window into
that time.
Jamie just gave me the two minute mark
so we got a rabbi's up.
It's a old baby.
We just did it three hours.
My friend.
He's so much fun.
Flew by,
flew by love.
If every time a history on fire,
two episodes are available and episode
zero as well.
Right?
Like a little pilot or let everybody
know what's
up.
And uh,
anything else?
Got a book coming out next moment.
So early december.
I have a,
uh,
people can,
if they are interested in and we'll
tweet about it,
we'll let everybody know and a hobby
back in once the book's out to my
brother.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
All right,
my friends.
That's it for this week.
We'll be back next week.
Until then.
See you soon.
Bye.