That's my yoga move Hixon gracie and be
super spiritual.
Nobody does yoga every day.
If you do,
you're a freak.
I had to call Brian.
Count out on that.
Brian,
does yoga every single day has to be a
chick.
Yeah,
there you go.
Not dudes.
Dudes under yoga everyday.
Especially regular dudes.
Unless you look at Yoga Guy.
I mean there's,
there are guys do yoga everyday,
but that's the thing that dude's like to
say I do yoga every day,
you know,
call them on it.
Yeah.
The same to you.
Well,
I do yoga every day.
It keeps you centered.
The Joe Rogan experience podcast is
brought to you by several things.
The one thing that we can promise 100
percent when we do commercials for the
podcast is if we're going to support a
company,
if we're going to have them as a
sponsor,
they have to be cool there.
There has to have a good business model.
They have to,
they have to be something that makes
sense for us.
And uh,
that's one of the reasons we are
sponsored by kerosene games.
And um,
what we decided to do with kerosene
games is to take a chance to endorse a
startup company that is making really
fucking cool video games and they're
making them for the IPAD and the iphone
and now in February will be android
phones as well,
but the,
they're making specifically for that and
they're just really nice,
cool,
fun games.
Whereas a lot of times,
like when you buy video games for the
IPAD,
a lot of times they're a ported over
from the PC whereas kerosene games is
making all their games.
They're making them directly for these.
So with intuitive touchscreen controls
the graphics of bad ass.
And you see Brian is fucking with it
right now.
It's really addictive game.
If you've got,
it's not use a video of someone playing
it is a clone.
Oh no,
that's crazy.
I think.
Yeah,
they were made from the ground up,
see amazing control.
So you already have a video of you
playing it?
No,
this is,
I just go on Youtube.
There's a lot of it,
like if you want to look around,
there's a lot of videos of people
playing this on Youtube.
There's really good reviews and there's,
you know,
there's a lot of tips and secrets of
you're stuck somewhere.
You can just go to youtube and find out
a lot of stuff.
Yeah.
This is like a really high end game.
It's fucking cool to play.
It's really great graphics.
It's,
we live in strange times.
Folks in that little skinny ass piece of
glass and plastic and innards can do
some amazing shit when it comes to
graphics processing.
So the imagery that you can get is
really,
really high resolution and cool and uh,
to just addictive really,
really fucking addictive game.
So if you're looking to get addicted to
games,
we got it for you,
bitch.
It's only two 99 a.
it's cheap.
It's called Blade slinger.
And uh,
like I said,
it's really fun and it's from a cool
company.
They're cool people who were like,
uh,
like dealing with them and we liked
their business model.
That's very reasonable price.
They've invested a lot of money making
this game and they did a great fucking
and for to 99,
it's a bargain.
So go get that shit.
Ain't that shit on your ipad
and thanks to all other people that have
been doing a positive reviews on that
game in the APP store that's really big
for this company if you'd like.
Right.
Like reviews and and you know,
and stuff like that for them because
that just like podcasts,
every time you write a review and rate
it,
it helps them out and it also shows
that,
you know,
this podcast is helping them out and so
that's good for us to be like,
look,
look what we were doing.
Do you guys were helping you out here?
So it helps everybody out.
So
yeah,
it really does.
We appreciate that.
This one of the coolest things of this
podcast is sort of brought about is this
real sense of community that,
I mean we,
we had a community amongst ourselves
before his friends but there's this
whole community of other people that are
like minded that do cool shit like that.
We really appreciate the fuck out of
that.
And that's why one of our other sponsors
is hover.
Hover is the same people that own ting,
which is a great cell phone company that
we endorse because they're,
they,
they have no contracts,
you can cancel anytime you want and they
have high end phones.
It's very reasonably priced and on the
sprint backbone,
well they also have a company called
hover and what they're trying to do with
hover is basically kind of do the same
shit that they do with,
with Tim that trying to give you a great
service,
uh,
with,
with.
It's easy to manage with excellent
software and they're trying to do it
ethically so they make it so that it's
really easy to use.
They have,
they take the hassle of owning and
managing domain names with smart,
easy to use friction free,
powerful domain name management tools.
So lives the way they have it set up.
It's very nice.
They're like a real easy going company.
They're not the,
there's no crazy hard sell.
They don't believe in hiding
functionality or requiring extra payment
for things that should be included in
the domain name management.
Things like who is privacy and Brian,
we were talking about that like that's a
big thing,
like who is privacy you want,
you know,
if you have suck my cock fatty
[inaudible] dot com.
And then someone comes along and was
like who's this sick prick?
And they,
they,
they find out that it's,
you know,
you go to that.
Who is,
who owns that?
Oh well it's brian red band.
He likes fat checks.
Blown them.
Or is it fact dudes?
You know,
who the fuck would call a woman fatty?
That's so rude.
That's not just sexist,
it's,
you're a rude person.
Call one more fatty.
So it's probably gay.
So it was talking about eight guys and
you know,
if that's your thing,
it must be someone's things.
Someone out there must own.
Suck my cock.
Fatty.com.
They must,
it's been thought up already.
They probably sat down and bought every
fucking domain name you could ever come
up with.
So if it's cool,
it's like if you type in a name,
like I said,
like you want a,
you know Joe Rogan farts.com
and it shows you if it's available also
gives you like,
like a bunch of suggestions like that.
So you can kind of like,
oh I didn't even think of that domain
name.
But one of the other cool things is that
there's also domain nowadays a lot of
people buy and they're like,
ah,
I'm just going to sit on this,
but you know,
if somebody offers me this much money
I'll give it to them.
And so they also have that on the
website.
So like you can come here and look at
some websites that you're like wow,
I could buy that for you know this.
But here,
here's a game.
Try to guess how much this.
Here's one.
It's $8,000.
Let's see what the name or what domain.
That $8,000.
Td Crew Dot com.
Somebody selling kidding crew is spelled
with a k $4,000.
We got
what the fuck?
That is really cool software though.
Like say if there is someone who has one
and it's the name of your company and
you can get it for a couple thousand
bucks or whatever it is,
you know,
you.
Yeah,
I mean,
you save yourself a lot of hassle.
So,
uh,
that,
that's cool.
And it's the same sort of thing.
It's a company that they're,
they're trying to do things ethically
and they're trying to do things in a way
that provides you with great service as
well.
And they think that that's possible.
They think that's possible with they're
showing it's possible and it's showing
it's possible with hover as well.
Um,
so if you,
um,
go to a hover.com
forward slash rogen,
what do you do?
Save money off your domain registration?
Yeah.
You save a,
I believe it's 10 percent off your,
uh,
whatever you get.
So it's a,
and I'm just guessing.
Yeah,
well they have that big 10 percent thing
going on with you,
you know?
Yeah,
I'm big on temperature.
If you go to Hubbard.com
forward slash Rogen,
you will get 10 percent off your domain
name registrations.
So Brian is correct.
I,
I'm,
I'm unorganized,
ladies and gentlemen,
I have my notes here and they're fucking
scattered all over the board,
but what I do know what I can tell you,
it's fucking cool company run by cool
people and support them because they're
a,
they're doing things and what we believe
is a,
an ethical way and they're providing a
great service as well.
They know what the fuck they're doing.
We're also brought to you by [inaudible]
dot com.
It's o,
n n I t I wish I didn't have to say that
every week,
but there is a regular on it.com.
There is an o,
n I t dot don't go there and you know
nothing you can do about that.
Bad.
Too Bad.
Like no one makes like an honor song for
you guys.
You like based on like you know things.
Please don't ask for that because I
didn't create it.
I would not play it for the hawks.
The hell you know it would snow.
No one's gonna make good on audit song.
Yeah.
You heard the Olive Garden Buffalo Song.
People did exactly what I just said.
No one's going to make a good song.
Crazy.
Fuck.
Oh,
what are,
uh,
what we all believe to be good.
Everybody has their own sort of level.
Dr Lazar,
by the way,
I think it's bizarre.
Dr Azar as the neurosurgeon is talking
about the benefits of taking Alpha
brain.
Um,
we're,
we're currently rubbing running this
double blind placebo,
uh,
experiment.
You guys had been there for two years,
is they have to take it.
They take it for a year,
which it sounds crazy and it costs a lot
of fucking money.
But what's important is if you go to the
site,
there's a science page on [inaudible]
dot com explains all the different
ingredients that have been shown in
clinical trials to improve memory to,
to the idea is that they improve
cognitive function by providing your
neurotransmitters with all the building
blocks and the nutrients that it needs
in order to think the best.
I'm a,
I'm a huge believer of talked about this
on the podcast and lean times and I've
talked to a lot of people after shows
and they've told me how much it's helped
them and how much it inspired them
because I'm a big believer in it sounds
so obvious,
but I'm a big believer in putting
healthy shit into your body.
I mean occasionally enjoy a cocktail or
two or a fucking steak and cheese sub or
you know,
I mean I'm not a,
I'm not a saint when it comes to that,
but I do eat a lot of nutritious food
and I think it's really important for
you to do the same.
If you want your body to really work at
an optimum level,
in my opinion,
the only way to do it is to feed it
nutrient rich foods like vegetables,
Kale and a lot of green vegetables,
drink a lot of fucking water,
don't just drink a little bit,
drink a lot,
take multivitamins,
and there's other supplements that you
can take that will have a positive
effect on the way your body functions
and,
and to me,
that's what it's all about.
I ain't mad,
I'm all about my brain functioning on
the highest level.
I can get it to my body,
functioning at the highest level I can
get it to and that's what we're all
about it on it.
Everything that we sell is either trying
to improve your immune system or trying
to improve your memory or your
cardiovascular endurance or with hemp
force that has Makkah and raw cocoa.
Your recovery and with antioxidants in
it protect you against free radicals.
We sell coconut oil and killer bee
honey.
Everything we sell,
it's just designed to make your body
performed best.
It's the best shit we can find.
We guarantee you were we.
If we.
If we know about any cooler shit,
we'll try to sell that to.
Well,
I when you search Alex Jones on on it,
like I just tried to search
Joan's going to become a representative
of audit.
Finding a new world order with vitamins.
Is He really?
The government doesn't want you to have
vitamins because the elites are the only
ones who want to have a good memory
and it could laser not find his
name.com.
So he had to run a laser but it was
already taken.
So He'd got the [inaudible] with a z
just like that.
Other kiddies.
Good
move if Dr Lazaro,
but it's like a famous character and
like a Batman comic book or something
like that to change your name to Dr
Lazaro.
There'll be kind of clutch.
But the only other Lasar that I've ever
heard of is that guy,
um,
that was the man who claimed to be an
area 51.
Have you ever heard of him?
Robert Lasar.
Bob was our and he's the guy who claimed
to be a man who was hired to back
engineer Ufos and area 51 and it was
proven that he's at least full of shit
about is education of the Stanton
Freedman,
I believe,
who actually wants to do the podcast
when I get him on who is the probably
the leading guy when it comes to a Ufo
and flying saucers and what,
you know,
what the possibilities of space travel
could be this guys.
But like I think he's like a nuclear
physicist or something wacky and he's
been studying this shit forever,
but he absolutely believes that we've
been visited by ships from other
galaxies and he says there's proof and
we're going to get him on and we're also
working to get Steven Greer on who's the
guy who's the head of the disclosure
project.
We're hoping to get him on it.
It looks like some time in February and
the disclosure project was like a bunch
of different fucking scientists and they
uh,
military people and they all got
together and the all talked about their
ufo experiences in,
in great depth and some of them are very
compelling to really interesting stuff.
And we're going to have him on the
podcast as well.
Bitches.
We move forward.
Get yourself some upgraded coffee.
I'm drinking it right now.
This is bulletproof coffee.
I make this shit with butter.
Ian Edwards.
Do you know what I'm talking about?
Raw butter.
I take raw butter as opposed to what?
Cook butter.
I take butter from grass fed cows and I
blend it with the coffee and something
called mct oil.
That's how you make bulletproof coffee.
You want some next level shit.
Next level.
Just when I think I'm healthy,
she didn't make me feel we're taking
this shit.
No,
you body's good dude.
You know?
How silly would it sound if you talk to
somebody from the 19 twenties gone,
no,
this is grass fed,
but they're like,
you got some other type of butter.
Yeah.
Be Looking at what the fuck you talking
about stupid.
Are you okay?
Do you need to sit there on this rock?
Uh,
if you go to [inaudible] dot com and use
the code named Rogan,
you save 10 percent off any and all
supplements in all our supplements.
Every bottle of 30 pills has a 100
percent money back guarantee for 90
days.
You don't even have to fucking bring the
product back.
You don't have to return it.
Just say it sucks.
We're not sending the selling you stuff.
That sucks.
Everything we're selling you is
something that is been Peruvian to work
that we find effective and that we think
is something that we would want to buy.
So that's the whole concept behind it.
It's definitely not to rip anybody off
A.
I've said that too many times.
It sounds almost insincere,
but it's true.
Shit bitches.
All right,
go fuck yourselves and cue the music.
Use the code name.
Rogan.
Save 10 percent at [inaudible] dot com.
O n n I t hollow
Joe Rogan Experience
Joe Rogan podcast by night.
Right before podcasts.
Edwards.
I popped out for those bad pitches.
Shit.
Ian To getting healthy my phone during
the podcast too.
Do you know how to,
you know Joe over here?
Ian Edwards.
Man,
I've known you for probably as long as
any comedian that I,
that
I'm friends with.
Oh Shit.
I've known you for a long time man.
We met at Boston.
Comedy was at Boston comedy in the
village and the village man.
Where's third?
Was that like 1990 or some shit?
What was that?
It was,
it was in the nineties.
It's fun talking about,
uh,
you know,
reminiscing about the early days of
comedy.
It's one of the only times that you
don't feel like you're talking about the
glory days.
So like,
you know,
we hear dude talking about like college
football,
career,
a lot of times like a ride already will
you shut up about your fucking football
career.
But I love hearing stories like about
the early days,
like from everybody.
I love hearing them from Chris Rock.
I love hearing them from Jerry Seinfeld.
I love hearing them from Rodney.
I just love those stories
man.
I love him too man.
Like,
like one thing I used to do as a comic
was hanging out with older comics.
Go to diners at night.
I have to show up and just to listen to
them.
Yeah.
And you go eat and Carnegie data,
they'll tell you who used to eat there
and just just all the stories man.
Big like comedy story person.
Yeah.
When you get to go on the road,
like one of the coolest things when you
first start out as you get to go on the
road with a real veteran,
someone who's got some good stories,
you can tell you some crazy shit about,
uh,
other dudes that did this and that dad.
And he showed up.
It was on heroin.
And the owner told him to put your pants
on and pushed them on the stage and he
fucking killed somewhere.
It's like classic rock and roll stories.
But for comedy.
Yeah.
Well
yeah.
You and you and I kind of lived those.
That Boston Comedy Club was a fun spot.
Is that still this?
Nah,
it's a,
it's like an upscale kind of bar right
now.
But it used to be like an addict,
like a snow large,
like a large,
like they kind of had a fireplace on
stage.
It was a place.
It was a weird little spot because a
weird little spot,
but it was perfect.
You had it only seated like what?
Like 80 people or something.
How many people could get in there?
Maybe 100,
maybe 100 years.
Stuff to share that place to get 100
people in there.
But man,
we had so much fun at that place is fun.
We just used to hang man.
And uh,
we saw some great short.
We saw like we saw shit we took for
granted,
you know,
is a,
you should see Jim Breuer,
Tony Woods,
Chappelle,
read Johnny the Round Guy,
like just a bunch of killers and killers
to kill us telling people don't know
about Tony Woods.
Tony Woods is funny as fuck.
He was always really strong.
I know he's one of those dudes like I've
talked about before.
Reggie Mcfadden's,
another one.
I don't understand how reggie mcfadden
isn't like Kevin Hart,
right?
Yeah.
Reggie.
It's kind of crazy.
Yeah,
but I've seen crazy people make it
before so it's still a valid question.
Right.
Crazy Safari.
Ms Dot Manche or something.
When I saw reggie mcfadden in 19,
like run time.
I met you in 1990.
He worked at.
He did a spot at a place in new Rochelle
called the champagne comedy club.
I couldn't work there because I was
dirty.
Dude did not allow any dirty comedy.
Nothing that you had to give you a
speech before you worked there.
He would say no motherfuckers who was
real serious,
like he put his finger up and he goes,
you don't say the bitch had a big ass.
You say the woman had a while back.
I'm not joking.
He had,
he had rules.
I mean it was the champagne comedy club
and he was trying to make it very
upscale,
you know,
and some of my friend John,
uh,
open for Reggie and he had a respectable
set,
you know,
but Reggie without a swear with real was
no bad language too strong.
I mean he destroyed.
I was watching him.
I was like,
I'm watching the next Eddie Murphy.
I'm like,
this guy is going to be gigantic.
You can't stop this.
I'm like,
this is the kind of talent you can't
stop.
Right.
And he was the one that,
that what if,
for whatever reason,
when you say the word regiment fat and
there's a few comedy fans who know who
he is or he's not.
He's not like Kevin Hart is or like,
you know,
and no disrespect to Kevin Hart who I
think it's hilarious.
I'm not,
I'm using this as an example because
he's really good.
Just trying to show people how funny.
Reggie.
Fucking amazing.
He would erase your performance.
Who would destroy?
Who was the guy that went on?
I don't know.
I just remember.
Yeah,
he was so,
like his whole animated on stage.
Perfectly animated.
Yeah.
There's one joke.
I keep telling people.
I was in Amsterdam doing a short reggie
and uh,
he went on,
he did this joke about,
you know,
when he was little,
he had a cousin who was retarded.
Right.
And then one day he was in the basement
playing with his cousins.
They,
you know,
they came over and then the cousins
playing with him and a cousin like
unstretched and I'm glad they're gone.
Shit.
And it's Reggie is looking at it.
What the hell?
You're not retarded.
Nah Man,
I just do that because it's just easier.
People take care of you.
They feed you.
You don't have to go to school or shit.
They're coming backwards.
I see you later.
He goes back into being retired.
Reggie's new shit.
He used to have a bit that would just
below the room apart and a bit was about
his experience at a club trying to pick
up a girl,
but she had this really unattractive
friend who is very persistent and he had
to,
had to be wherever her friend was.
He couldn't get the two of them away.
It's a fucking the one at the end.
I don't want to give up the bed in case
he's still doing it because it was just.
It was so fucking.
There was a bit where the ugly girl
parts in.
Do you remember when the other girl
would smash through the.
You can just be crying.
He'd be crying,
laughing because he was so animated and
the way they played the girl was like so
like floppy and fucked up.
It's just you couldn't.
You would just cry and laugh and he was
so confident too.
Yeah.
He had an ego like this.
How funny.
Reggie is like,
I guess.
I guess it's A.
I don't lie on funny,
like when Reggie first started,
he was so cocky.
I could not like Reggie,
but I could not deny that he was funny.
He thought he was talking.
Really?
Yeah.
I'd never had that experience with him.
Now he's just like,
maybe it was just,
maybe it was even part of my insecurity,
but he,
he was like,
me and reggie are good friends now,
like later on,
but I think it's a testament to how
funny you are when I don't like you and
you're like,
this dude is funny and I would never
walk out the room when I'm seeing
performance.
I just watched that shit.
Not Laugh.
Yeah,
you're rolling ben over at a dude you
don't like.
You know what I'm saying?
That's a funny motherfucker right there.
Yeah,
no shit.
That's hilarious.
No,
I never.
I never had any issues with them.
It was always nothing but friendly to
me.
That's why I was shocked that he said he
had an ego because I thought he was a
head like a real.
It's like in my mind that perception was
like,
this guy's just got the full package.
He's kind of all together.
That's why like when you tell people
about them and they don't know who he
is,
like how did that happen?
They don't understand that
it is,
uh,
it was kinda crazy.
Like how does that happen?
Because when we were all coming up in
that time,
you know,
in New York,
he was one of the big guys just like
brewer,
just like all the other guys towel,
who everybody knows now,
but you say Reggie Mcfadden and they
don't know who he is.
I would have never guessed that would
have happened based on how you and I saw
him then
like you could,
this is a funny game man.
You could never tell you something.
People just can't keep it together to
the,
the same thing that makes you funny also
makes you feel a little bit fucking
crazy,
you know?
And for some people they just did.
Life just goes off the tracks and into
the woods and there's no one there to
manage it and bring it back on and go a
little Duh,
Duh Duh Duh.
You're going to be okay.
All right,
listen,
you got to stop smoking that shit or you
got to stop doing this so you gotta stop
doing that and no more gambling and
let's.
We're going to get you to a yoga class
when we get you into tries more
gambling.
Grieving.
Yeah,
let's just keep calm me down a little
bit,
but for some folks,
you know,
they don't have a person like that in
their life that looks out for them and
then they just go 100 percent cat
Williams on you and you know,
you don't know what the fuck is,
you know what's happening.
They're like,
well,
how do you get a talented guy and allow
them to go off the rails like that?
You know,
he needs someone in there to settle
down.
Man.
Jesus,
we're going to be fine here.
Last time I saw Reggie last few times,
I so reggie,
you probably know this,
but he was trying to get people to
invest in a gold mine in Costa Rica.
Swear to God.
Really?
Yeah.
I think it's gold.
Gold or copper mine in Costa Rica.
And then it's funny,
like we're in a profession where we're
all taking a chance were in
entertainment lotto,
right?
But to us hearing that,
it makes him sound crazy.
Yeah.
You know what I'm saying?
Just saying that makes him sound crazy.
But we're in a crazy business period
where we're all taking a chance like we
are
sort of.
But I think at a certain point in time,
don't you feel like you've developed an
audience.
The people know that if all you have to
do is keep being funny and keep writing
jokes and you're not going anywhere.
People
don't like in La,
like even the brand new comics,
like they're in such a rush and then if
somebody gets one little thing,
if it bothers him so much mentally,
like people can't handle not being
famous right now.
Like my shit is taken like the slow
cooking burn.
Right?
But I'm just like a relaxed Jamaican
dude.
This is normal pace for me.
Well,
but you know,
famous.
No fame,
you're still a top notch.
Stand up comic and you could work
anywhere you want.
You know what I'm saying?
I mean,
even if you are still very known in the
standup world and so you could always
work.
What I'm saying is once you become like,
you,
you reach a certain level of proficiency
isn't just about maintaining and about
writing.
You mean you're already,
you're already in a good groove.
You can already make money doing it,
you know,
so the,
the real chances are gone.
So then the chances has to be just
coming up with new material.
But I think people would just want,
I think,
I think Reggie did have an ego.
He wanted superstar.
He should have had it and he shouldn't
have had.
I don't know how he didn't have it.
And it's,
I think people,
some people can't handle not having it.
Oh yeah.
Look,
I've been around people who act like I
stole something from them because I've
know because I've been successful,
which is ridiculous.
They'll say we're shitty,
like,
must be nice.
The fact that the white sand.
And so do you know,
that's not sincere.
That's like a weird passive aggressive,
Douchey way saying it,
you know,
but
which is fucked up because you turn
obtained like uh,
a lot of success and you're still
working hard.
Like what?
In like some building in woodland hills,
like banging out a podcast,
you know what I mean?
You don't have to do this shit.
Yeah,
you do.
Yeah.
You got to keep doing this shit.
You have to know since of the program,
but you're saying you're saying you do.
You do.
Are you saying you do?
Is Good,
like a good testament for you?
You know what I'm saying?
Like there's other people like fuck that
shit.
Famous ain't doing nothing.
Is there,
you know,
like some people that ain't gonna work
as hard as you are.
My point is your work.
Yeah.
It's not that hard and it's not really
work.
See that's the whole beauty of it.
Like it's a pleasure to come here and
sit down and have a conversation with a
funny person,
you know,
or an interesting person or scientist or
whoever the fuck it is.
It's fun.
So it's not work.
It just so happens that it's pays money,
it's just figuring out a way to do
something you actually like doing and
then it just pays money.
So then he'd be like an idiot not to do
it.
Like why wouldn't you do it?
It's fun.
Some people are too lazy to figure out
what they like.
Yeah.
But you know what the difference between
doing this and not doing this,
it's just I'm doing something else for
three hours and this is a fun thing to
do for three hours.
So it's like,
I hardly ever think of it as work.
Well that's a good thing.
Yeah.
That's,
that's,
that's why you got to keep it going.
You can't,
you got to keep it going.
So the,
you always have like a comfort zone,
you know what I mean?
Like if you just completely lay back,
then people forget you.
It's like
you're doing a lot of shit.
You got to Jujitsu,
you got the,
you know the fights,
you got the stuff.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You don't combined them.
No shows.
I'll do like a show the night before the
UFC,
like that's a lot like you,
you keep it moving,
but it doesn't feel like nothing to you.
But if,
if you're on the outside looking in,
if you're working a lot,
but if you're listening,
you hustling.
Yeah.
But if you were doing what I was doing,
it's none of it's work like that at all.
Like if I had to do something that I
don't enjoy doing and that was traveling
as much as I do,
I really would not be happy.
But it's like everywhere I'm going like,
Hey,
I'm going to go do some comedy.
Like Hey,
I'm gonna.
Go see the fights,
you know?
And it's like,
to me everything's fun.
Hey,
am I going to do a podcast with Dan
Edwards?
It's fun.
It's all good stuff.
So there's nothing immediately.
Even though you've got to discipline
yourself a little bit,
force yourself to do stuff that's fun
and which sounds ridiculous,
but you did.
You got to just force yourself to make
sure that you do it on a regular,
regular basis.
But other than that it's easy.
You know,
it's just a matter of finding something
that you do,
that you enjoy doing and then just do
that shit.
I just know that there's a lot of people
listening.
All they do is listening,
listen,
and watch and they're not getting to do
as much as they could be doing.
Well.
You saying like some people that like
tune into too much shit and don't
produce enough shit.
So what you mean?
Yeah.
Like there's this,
there's a lot of people in this world
that don't like the way you put it.
You know,
the way you said you're doing something,
it's work,
but you disqualified as work.
You qualified as something you like
doing.
It just happens to be work and then
everybody else,
like they might just qualify it.
As I said,
a lot of work.
Well,
some people do.
It's perspective.
Your perspective allows you to do as
much as you do and other people's
perspective doesn't allow them to do as
much as they could do.
That's a very good point because some
people,
even with things they used to love
doing,
they don't love doing it anymore and
becomes a chore.
Right,
exactly.
This could never be a chore for me.
You and the UFC could never be a chore
for me.
It'll never be a chore.
It's,
it's not.
It's not even possible.
Like I met you.
You,
you know,
you,
you're a fucking master.
Yeah.
That was in the nineties,
you know,
I think I was a taekwondo master black
belt.
It was a black belt and talk with them
when I was a little kid.
Doesn't really count though for real
until you're 16 so you can actually
knock a grown man out.
So there is legit when your six year old
black belt,
that's just not real.
They have those.
They have six year old black belt,
a six year old black male to fucking
kill.
I'll take on for you at the same time.
I mean they would try hard,
I'm sure.
Maybe like a 13 year old and those
Jujitsu,
it could get you a 13 year old jujitsu
prodigy.
They wouldn't do that 13 year old.
Fuck that.
It's too old.
Yeah.
You can get you in his legs.
That triangle the fuck out of you and
put you to sleep under 10.
Yeah.
I'm down to old
testosterone is balls of drugs on
interested on this one.
All the 13 year old Jujitsu people out
there to know that you're too old for me
prior to get it out there.
I'll fight any of you.
Hold on.
Let's see.
Your boss.
Let me see what you got.
Okay.
Your balls are too big.
Get outta here.
Your balls have dropped.
Yeah.
Even that might be to the young kids.
Like what would that one,
seven year old kid that was like all
buff.
You know,
they worked out every day.
Remember there's videos of him and it
like,
it looks like a creek.
Yeah.
That kid of the family was giving him
steroids.
Yeah.
No,
fuck.
That's fucked up.
Now.
That kid I'd be scared of.
Yeah.
Well he's still a little.
They get cheerios and throw it on the
gram.
Like here's cheerios.
Get away from you.
It's probably never been kicked in the
Dick before.
You would have no idea how to react.
You don't develop the right kind of
composure when you're six to take a full
shot to the Dick.
I start kicking him in the Dick.
He doesn't have strong gonna run,
crying and screaming and he's not going
to think of doing it first.
You just go right for his little Dick.
This little six year old Dick with a
boot.
Your defense would be saying that Santa
Claus isn't real and stuff like get away
from me isn't real.
Where you could talk about kicking a six
year old in the artificial sixth year.
It was a real six year old like saying
you should actually go out there and
kick back in the day.
This is a complete.
I mean that kid this day.
It's probably like 20,
you know,
that was a long ass time ago that he was
like a child.
It's probably list.
Sorry Buddy.
We don't really mean.
You should've got kicks on the deck.
This is all hypothetical comedy.
You say they get it,
but under the Patriot Act I think we
have to disclose that we have to tell
people.
But um,
yeah,
but even back then,
you know,
like doing comedy never felt like,
like real work.
I mean it was like,
it was the real work was the fact that
you didn't know if you were going to
make it and you're scared,
you know,
like we'd be terrified.
And when I first started out all I
wanted to do our member very clear,
like what,
what,
how awesome it would be to pay your
bills,
doing comedy.
So I saw all these guys that were like
the main headliners and Boston and all I
could think of was like man to one day
be able to pay my bills,
doing comedy.
I never thought that I would get to the
point where people would actually come
out to see me.
I thought I could just like headline at
a club and that would be who would be
there that weekend because the way it
worked in Boston,
it was like you looked at the local
lineups,
like Kevin Knox would be there one
weekend and then Robbie printz would be
there the next week.
The guys,
it was all the same dudes that worked in
our circuit and we sort of went in all
these different Boston comics.
Really good,
very good,
very good comics and so like you.
What you hope for is to get into that
line up with your hope for it to be one
of those guys where you're making a
living,
you know,
just telling jokes.
Because I would look at those guys like
would be like,
this guy doesn't have a job at all.
All he does is tell jokes while there's
that kid,
Jesus Christ.
That's so sick.
They were given that kid steroids.
Man.
That's so funny.
How old is he there?
Seven.
What?
Oh,
that's so crazy.
That's so sad too,
because that his whole system,
it just gets fucking red line at an
early age like that.
Pumping all that shit into his body
because it's really hard for top,
top.
Yeah.
It's really hard for a kid to get that
kind of muscle development at seven.
I mean,
you can't mean it is possible.
You could be some freak.
Now,
if you looked at this with like blurry
eyes,
he would swear his.
It's hanging out.
I know I didn't want to say anything
because his thumbs in the perfect spot.
I'm going to send a lot of pedophiles to
decide they're going to go wacky.
This is like free free pedophilia.
Like you can get away with it.
You can pretend and just get away with
it.
Look at that TV over there too.
Muscle bounds,
year old TV over there.
It looks like he's holding a flashlight.
It does.
If you're a little further away,
if you just squinted,
if you're looking at it on your phone,
you would swear that if you don't have
20 slash 20,
that's a car.
Don't do it.
Beaver cleaver.
Yeah,
he's a,
he looks very like thick faced like
instrumental
boy.
But that poor kid,
whatever the fuck they did to him.
But um,
you know,
when we were,
when we were doing comedy back then,
uh,
you know,
in Boston it was like,
I still wasn't really like a
professional.
I've only been doing it a couple of
years.
I wasn't,
I could fall apart at any moment.
You know,
and I still didn't think that I would
ever like continued to be able to pay my
bills,
doing comedy.
Like I was still like,
did you make any money up there?
I made a little.
When I first started going to New York
was when I got a manager and that was
the first manager I ever got.
And uh,
when I got that,
the best thing about it is that he
started getting the books in like these
little clubs,
you know,
I mean even our couldn't headline.
I could middle and spots and I can make
a living,
but I knew that I,
I,
you know,
I had to like progress past that and
figuring out a way to actually have
enough money.
So for sure I knew how to pay my bills
because he was still like,
touch and go all the time.
Who was your manager back then?
Same Guy.
Same guys today sitting.
I said,
yeah,
he picked me up when I was an open
miker.
Who is that?
Jeff Salzman.
Oh,
Yeah,
he's the shit.
He's a great guy.
He's like an old school manager,
you know,
he's like one of those guys who was
people care talent.
It's kind of a little piece of paper in
his pocket.
He writes his notes,
he's just fucking,
he's an awesome human to just a really,
really great guy.
He doesn't like me talking about him.
So I stopped talking about them now,
but he's been my manager since I was
like 22 or some shit when I met you at
the Boston.
Like I think like we're in different
mental comedy phases.
Like I was trying to.
I had some material that got me into the
Boston and I was trying to get off that
material and just come up with new shit.
Right.
And then.
So then there was moments when I just
struggled for a while just trying to
figure shit out.
And at the same time I was repeating a
lot of mistakes and I wasn't a writing
as much as I should.
Well,
you writing a lot back then
it tried to try to,
you know,
I tried to constantly,
I feel real bad if I don't constantly
come up with new material.
So I went through a phase,
the beginning where I was
writing a lot,
but I didn't know how to write very
good.
So most of it was shit like man,
when I would like when I was living in
new Rochelle.
So when I was in New York I wrote,
I wrote three pages of it.
That might be one line that should be
considered a second time.
I'll go back and look,
I've keeps,
I've kept some of my notebooks.
I go back and look at my writing,
but it was a box.
This is horseshit.
It's just utter complete horseshit,
you know,
I just,
it was just hard to write,
you know,
I had to develop a point of view.
You have to become a,
an actualized human being.
You can't just,
you can't just write with no life
experience.
And that's essentially what I was doing.
I didn't know anything.
I didn't belong.
I shouldn't have been the one talking.
I really didn't deserve it.
I didn't have enough to say.
I didn't think about what I was going to
say.
I didn't,
you know,
I was just trying to stumble through it.
Like most 20 years,
like I felt that a lot of times it's
like,
what the fuck am I saying?
Oh,
you're just trying to be.
He's trying to be funny.
So you were watching people and you're
getting ideas of funny.
Yeah.
And,
and you're,
you're trying to build something.
You don't even know what you're
building.
You don't know what.
You should have a perspective and kind
of right from there like you,
you have no idea.
Shit is just happening and you and
somehow you figure it out later on.
But in the beginning they,
maybe only a few people know exactly
what they're supposed to do.
Yeah.
It seems so easy when you watch it.
When you watch a guy like say if you're
seeing a guy on stage,
like a good example,
like a Jerry Seinfeld type character,
he seems like he's just talking.
He's just talking.
They just,
he knows how to pause at the right time
and in the timing and pause the way it
cracks the material inside your echoes
off the inside of your brain.
But it looks easy and if you've ever
made your friends laugh,
like I was trying to explain this,
this young kid the other day,
this kid came up to me and he said,
hey man,
I just started doing comedy and he lives
up in Santa Barbara and it's like we've
got a little amateur scene up here.
Not much,
but you know,
I'm practicing there and then I'm gonna
eventually come down to La and do some
real open mics and this and that.
And he's at that spot where you start
out and you're like,
man,
I don't,
can I fucking do this?
And I go,
why'd you want to do it?
He goes,
because I make my friends laugh all the
time because I could.
I could kill like a bunch of people at a
party.
I'll say some funny shit,
man.
Especially if I'm a little drunk.
I go,
well,
let me tell you something.
If you can do that,
if you do that in a party,
you can do that on stage.
You just have to figure out how to do
it.
But it ain't gonna be easy.
It's going to be confusing because it
seems like it should be easy,
but the ability to relay a thought to a
bunch of strangers and have them accept
that thought and it's most efficient
form and have it hit notes that they
didn't see coming.
That's hard to do,
man.
It is hard to do and it's like
indifferent.
I don't know about you,
but in different stages of my comedy
career,
I.
They were things I was trying to figure
out.
So what you mentioned about talking to
that kid like one time it was like,
all right,
no,
I guess I'm kind of funny but I'm not as
funny as I am in conversations with
people.
So how do I transfer offstage,
meet on stage and then so then I have to
think about like I took awhile to
examine that for like maybe a year or
so.
It's like I need to be me offstage.
I need to bring that dude onstage
because the onstage dude,
it's kind of different than the offstage
dude and I just want to be one person I
don't want to be too.
So then it was just like so many like
things you've got to go through to build
yourself into who you gonna end up being
enslaved and then there's perspective
and then there's jokes was my writing
style and that changes from time to time
and it's sometimes you have a set that's
really good,
but then as you get tired of it and then
you gotta come up with some stuff that
you're not tired of new stuff.
It's just like it's an ongoing thing.
Yeah.
And the knowing when to put new stuff
out there too.
So it's the beginning of standup comedy,
like developing it.
I guess it'd probably be just like
developing a band,
you know,
the band doesn't know what the fuck it's
still in the beginning either and then
you get together,
you fucking bang on some jobs.
Somebody comes up with some chords,
you figure out how to write some words
down and who knows what it becomes.
A lot of times bands changed too.
But yeah,
the time we were,
we were in very similar positions that,
that,
you know,
like what the fuck am I doing time?
It's funny.
Like,
Oh,
you know,
is that,
you want to make people laugh and that's
all you got.
It's like,
it's like somebody saying,
here's the topic,
write a movie.
The topic is,
uh,
going to the store now,
right?
A 120 page script about going into the
store and it's like,
that's it.
That's all you're going to give me a
comic days.
Like I know I want to make people that I
could go there.
There's a stage getting that figured out
as fast as you can.
Every anybody has.
Everybody has their own path and your
way of doing it just because like,
like I can't,
I would not do comedy.
Stephen writes way.
That's his way.
He came up with it.
Obviously.
It was awesome.
Obviously it was brilliant.
Obviously it was amazing,
but that's how,
that's,
that's his thing.
And he found that thing.
So that's proof positive that there's no
real prescription for this.
There's no,
there's no real guidebook.
You got to see.
Everybody's got their own funny.
Mitch Hedberg is funny.
It's different than Cat Williams.
Funny.
Everybody's got their own with those two
guys are similar.
Mitch Hedberg the same purpose,
not well,
maybe similar in their choices.
Yeah.
Crazy,
crazy making choices,
but it's in that beginning,
if you don't know if you're making the
right decision or the wrong decision,
you're going down past and trying to
figure out what's the right one and you
know,
I went for A.
I went for a period of time.
I was trying to dress up nice.
Larry Snow wearing was my manager.
Talked me into it man.
I wore like a nice button up dress
shirt,
club support that.
That was a cool period and I thought I
was.
I know you mean you're thinking of when
my album came out.
Yeah.
That was just an idea I did only for the
album.
It was the,
the idea was that I figured out a way to
get through life without wearing a tie
and when I was a,
when I was working as a limo driver back
in Boston,
one of the things I thought I would like
to get through life where I never have
to wear a fucking tie.
Like that was like a thing.
Like when people say,
what do you want to do?
I want to get through life without ever
wearing a fucking tie.
And when I finally got something that
was on like a copy of something,
like a CD,
that was my first thing that ever
released at all.
So it was like putting that on like,
let me wear a fucking times suit jacket
just for goof.
So it was a mess.
It was a good mix for me.
That was just.
I thought it was cool.
That'd be cool if you did that all the
time.
Well I don't.
I'm not,
I don't really like ties,
man.
I think that especially with my history
in Jujitsu,
I don't want to wear something around my
neck.
You could choke and I'm not into that.
Do you remember what?
Too many dudes that could put me to
sleep,
but they grabbed my tie.
That's funny.
I hate suits because the only time you
wear them is that a,
a funeral?
So I wanted to do it.
Nothing.
No funeral attire ever.
So I just hate to hate it.
Suit.
So that's why.
That's one of the reasons why comedy
fits perfect and you'll always run into
like a manager or somebody that has a
room that wants you to dress up and you
just feel like a rash breaking out just
at the thought of having to put some
formal shit.
Hell No.
I dressed real nice at the end of the
world party though.
Yeah,
you did?
Yeah.
That show A.
I wore a suit.
I wear like a tailor made suit and pants
and a nice shirt.
I didn't wear a tie though,
but I thought it looked very like so you
weren't chalkable sophisticated.
Actually.
Just got off work and if you have any
collar on me call on.
Anybody that can.
Like for Ronda Rousey chick gets a hold
of your collar first.
Social,
she'll throw you in your fucking head.
Chicken from the movie?
No,
she's the chick that's a UFC champion.
Oh,
okay.
She was in strikeforce women's champion
and now they give her the UFC belt and
she's.
She's headlining a big paper yet.
We're going to try to get her in here
before then,
but I bet she's busy as fuck now in
training and she says a lot of books in
a month.
She says bug stuff.
Yeah.
Like she's like,
Shit,
you know,
whack.
She talks a lot,
but she's awesome.
She's a fun check.
She's very cool.
She's hot as fuck and she can kick your
ass like.
It's very like.
She's like legit man.
Like she'll tap a man.
No doubt type of man.
She gets your arm.
She'll break your fucking arm,
son.
She was.
She break it on the second level of
women that could break my arm.
She will no doubt about it.
She has tapped six women in a row,
six first round armbars these.
They can't fuck with it.
Her arm bar.
It's just so nasty.
She flips you around until she gets it.
She's done it a million times.
Her arm bars,
so god damned good.
I seen an interview,
but I've never seen a fight.
She's fought six times with the same
exact move.
Nobody's ever done that in the history
of MMA.
It's really fucking crazy.
When you stop.
Think about it,
there's not one person who became a
champion and all of their fights leading
up to the championship.
We're one in the exact same message.
You only see that in the ww.
Oh,
he's going for some dudes that have won
a lot,
but like even more than she has.
Like this is a guy named Paul Sas and
he's got a really good guard.
This kid is nasty off his back and he
taps people by triangle all the time.
So I think he has something like nine
taps by triangle,
which is like unheard of.
Unheard of,
but he also won by.
He'll hook.
He's,
you know,
he's lost a fight or two since he got
tapped.
Recently.
Someone took us.
I think Matt Wyman tapped him.
So it's like he's had some bad results
with her.
It's just every single result was she
wins by Armbar her whole career.
That's craziness.
That's pretty unusual for a chick was
hot as fuck.
Oh good.
Good Dude.
Come on,
sign.
That's got to be nervous.
Unnerving.
A hot chick throws up flying triangle on
your ass because you're so close to
heaven and yet you're going to black out
any second.
Now she's choking her legs.
Okay.
That's horrifying from man,
but that's the move.
Like she puts a leg on bar,
but it's a triangle triangle.
The triangle has an well.
What it is is it has an arm stuck in,
in the legs are wrapped around your head
and shoulders.
Questioning,
chokes you.
Has anybody tried to start eating her
pussy when they're in that move?
You
could,
but you don't have much time and you
would have to.
You'd have to.
You train your tongue.
I'm here.
Okay.
Let's.
Let's just go through the motion.
I think you might be able to eat my
pussy for a little bit,
but you got to get it
to work.
You're going to have to get through that
span.
Index and granny panties.
She's got underneath there.
For you to be really effective.
If you're going to have to somehow know
the rip her panties open
during the fight.
Suppose you practice that in training.
I don't think.
I think you're going to sleep.
I think she's going to be insulted that
you think you'd get out of combat,
but just eating her pussy like a woman
that you know,
a woman when she can tap you and
dominate you like that,
she's not going to respect you and allow
you to breed with her.
So just the fact that you got into that
position and it's her mercy that you.
She lets you eat her pussy and then she
kills you with her legs.
Is that what's going to happen there?
At least you get more pleasure.
I don't know if you do some lose,
lose anything.
Anyway.
If you were in that position when the
lights go out
crying,
it's like the ultimate perv begging me
alive.
I feel.
Can you imagine her kaggle exercises?
Price.
Snap your chicken head right off.
Yeah.
Don't let anybody tell you that.
Trying to get you in a tongue bar.
All vaginas are created equally because
of vagina that's built in a woman who's
built like a woman who has like a good
musculature is healthy.
Everything will be tight in there.
There's muscle ass,
muscle,
leg,
muscle.
It's a tighter vagina.
It's a better fit.
She could pretty much give you a hand
job with her vagina.
Yeah,
I'm sure.
Like a world class athlete.
Right,
and let's just say any random world
class athlete.
I wouldn't want to disrespect Rhonda by
speaking of her vagina graphic manner,
how we're buddies.
Name girl.
You see a girl who's like a serious
crossfit athlete.
Fucking that girl would probably be like
having sex with a fist.
You know,
like a girl is like really muscular.
It's probably better.
It makes sense.
It's a reward.
The University of rewarding you for
meeting with someone who's not a lazy
bitch.
I'm into.
I'm into that.
That's what I'm talking about and
thinking about that shit with a porn
star because they use it so much with
it.
Build up that muscle and they lose their
tolerance skits.
All sloppy.
No,
I don't know.
I mean porn star.
The reality of a porn star is they
probably don't have any more sex than
the average person because the average
person,
if you're in your twenties and you have
your,
you have a boyfriend.
If you guys are monogamous,
that dude's gonna.
Try to fuck you at least five times a
week and if he doesn't fuck you five
times a week.
So when you do,
especially if you're really stupid,
you're saying I don't want to do it.
You don't want to do it.
You're 20.
Everybody wants it's 21 to fuck every
day.
You know that's normal.
So like every,
any normal girl who's like in her
twenties is probably getting fucked
constantly.
If she has a boyfriend.
Right?
So what,
how much is a porn star?
Have sex,
they have sex,
like you know,
maybe they have sex with a few more
people,
but in a lot of ways being a porn star,
but other than the fact that people
watch and masturbate and then it becomes
a public thing,
then it becomes a weird thing where the
way you interface with people is a lot
of times sexual.
But if you think about the way porn
stars have relationships,
it's really more like what that dude who
wrote a sex at dawn,
Dr Christopher Ryan was talking about
when he was talking about the communal
societies where they had multiple sexual
partners.
Because if these people are all just
having like what you said,
there's like five guys or something like
that.
Yeah.
So they all just,
they have,
they all just trade off.
So really that's not that much different
than a lot of like regular girls.
Even if you're with a different dude
every night.
It's like some girl's boyfriend every
night.
Yeah.
Some girls are with their boyfriend
every night and you know,
and some girls who are playing the
field,
they've got a couple different guys that
are competing for their attention,
which means they're getting drilled by
like two or three different guys who are
also nonmonogamous.
So maybe they're having sex with other
people as well.
So like it's not that scary having sex
with a porn star that way at all in that
way.
And that way it's not that much
different than a regular person.
Like if you could just have you count
the partners.
Yeah,
the number might be different,
but if you count the amount of times you
having sex
and that probably is the same.
The number might not even be different
over time because what if the girl only
has sex when she's at work and you know
she can't have a relationship because
dudes can't deal with it or whatever the
fuck it is.
So she's only having sex at work so
she's only fucking the same three or
four guys for a whole year more.
Whereas another 20 year old girl who
likes to party and she does coke,
she might fight.
Fuck
some guys a month in one night at Vegas,
things can get crazy.
People do crazy shit.
So it's like,
it's funny that porn is such a gigantic
business,
but that it's still this weird thing,
this weird fucking.
Everybody wants to have sex,
but if you're having sex and people can
watch everybody's,
what the fuck or more than like apple
won't put it in Itunes,
but yeah,
you go to any hotel chain and you can
rent fucking any porn movie you went.
I watched the other day I was at the war
or some chain hotel and I've got like
double anal video.
Why did you,
why did you buy it on the TV?
Why don't you hit the girl I was with
was in it and we wanted to.
Jesus Christ as some vanity.
You just broke the Internet.
You are a mess.
She watched a girl get fucked by other
guys.
Yeah.
On.
It's weird to watch her,
you know,
I would imagine there'll be while on
molly.
Oh my God.
Well,
hey,
different strokes through.
Do you need say the data from different
strokes time.
That sucks,
Mr.
Yeah,
Mr Trump,
and by the way,
creepy moment of history,
uh,
the first episode of different strokes
were Mr Trotman is like,
hey,
come on,
get down to your,
your,
your tidy whities and let us all go into
the bath tub together.
You remember that scene?
Oh
sure.
No,
I blocked that one out.
Like a bad molestation.
I don't even want to watch it about
that.
There's no need for that.
You know about this Aaron Swartz Guy,
this,
uh,
the coder,
the committed suicide and all the
trumped up charges that they had on them
to have this kind of cocreated rss feed.
Yeah,
he did.
He couldn't cocreated the RSS feed.
I think when he was,
um,
fuck,
I think he was like 15 or something
crazy,
like he doesn't even exist.
You Guy,
just the guy just started dating some
football players committed suicide.
Do you understand that?
The recommended suicide,
they didn't really commit suicide on
Saturday.
Right?
It'd be a little more respectful son.
He was only 26 years old and they,
the reason why he was incredibly
clinically depressed,
whatever he might have problems on his
own,
but on top of whatever problems he might
have had,
the government was trying to go after
him,
the crazy fucking case and he was up for
a potential thing where he was going to
be in jail for 50 years.
50.
What is the charge?
Is it not?
Not Anything to do with RSS Feeds?
Obviously.
I do not know the exact charges.
I don't know,
uh,
what,
what they were trying to nail him with,
but
whatever it was,
it was,
it was.
The way it was being done was really
crazy.
Like this guy was,
he was like a big innovator in,
in the,
in the field of coding and the creation
of the rss feed is really important for
things like this.
Podcasts,
like without his contribution,
who knows what would've happened if me
and apparently by all accounts was a
very nice person.
Was He paid?
I don't know.
I don't know how much money.
I didn't know what his situation was,
but it doesn't matter when the
government's going after you like that.
Like it's either way you're fucked.
No.
You know what I like about court cases,
how like a prosecutor will tell a
jewelry who you are as a defendant,
like this person.
We're going to tell you how we're going
to tell you what they did and how they
and why they thought of it and why they
did it.
Like you'd never met me.
Like,
how the fuck do you know?
It's like you made this story up and
you're going to try to prove it,
but you know,
you don't fucking know me.
Yeah.
It's,
uh,
it's very weird when someone decides
that they're going to take you in front
of a group of people that are going to
define you,
write a bunch of strangers who have to
like judge you carefully and really the
people that judge you,
the people that actually know you and
would know what kind of person you are
and what you did right,
and what you're capable of.
When you see jury,
people like God,
you've got to rely on their opinions and
you got to rely on whether or not some
dude who's really crafty with the words
can be reality.
Yeah.
It's like,
it's like a lot of people crafting with
words,
man,
tastes change shit around and that's
your ass.
I feel bad for Lindsay Lohan having to
deal with that like every day.
I mean that's pretty much what she does
every single day now.
All the court cases and shit.
I did it for like seven months and it
was like one of the worst times in my
life having to deal with just fucking
going to court.
Having lawyers.
Didn't you wash it or what was it?
Eh,
there was some shit,
but if your um,
yeah,
if you're stuck like that man,
you're,
you're in like a,
a legal turmoil.
That shit will take years off your life.
It's a lot of stress,
man.
This,
uh,
this guy,
he was part of the RSS Development
working group,
coauthored rss one point zero.
I mean,
just that alone,
man,
they should be kissing this guy's ass.
He shouldn't be rich.
Whereas bill burr that night though,
they got no,
he didn't.
He was arrested by federal authorities
in connection with systematic
downloading of academic journal
articles.
So it's crazy.
It's so,
it's academic journal articles.
I believe those are free.
Yeah.
So he was arrested for providing people
with the ability to download something
that's already free.
Oh my God.
It doesn't seem like it makes sense,
but he opposed their practice of
compensating publishers rather than
authors out of the fees that it charges
to for access to articles.
So he contended that the j Isto our
fees,
limited access to academic work produced
at American colleges and universities.
Wow,
that's really interesting.
So he pretty much was paying like the,
the use or the subscriptions to certain
articles that maybe the school was
trying to sell for a higher price maybe.
And it's hard to tell.
It seems like,
um,
yeah,
it's the bullets.
Apparently he gave them access to this
digital library j store,
what we're talking about.
That's what the thing was that,
uh,
was accusing him.
It's short for the journal Storage and
it's a digital library founded in 1995
originally containing a digitized back
issues of academic journals and now also
includes books and primary sources and
current issues of journals.
Provides full text searches for more
than a thousand journals,
blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Okay.
Check this out.
It a program providing limited no cost
access to old articles for individual
scholars and researchers who registered.
So you just have to register so that it
sounds like some trumped up bullshit
that they were going to put this kid in
jail for 50 years for that.
I mean that sounds really fucking crazy.
It sounds like you could have got out of
it.
I don't know.
Maybe not.
You know,
and just that kind of fucking pressure
breathing down your back when you think
that the government is after and they're
gonna come after you and they gonna lock
you up for some technology related shit
because technology related shit gets
really wacky because the idea is like if
you create rss feeds,
rss feeds have been shown to be used in
committing what they believe is a
technological crime.
Then all of a sudden you know,
like when somebody else does is you'll
blame almost like a rico.
Yeah.
What do you need to go swabbing?
Since he was one of my first.
He was one of my first.
I'm a celebrity sightings women.
Yeah.
That's when I first moved here in
[inaudible] 94.
I was on Hollywood boulevard right in
front of Man's Chinese theater and Rico
Suave and his,
his buddy and two ladies were walking
across the street and Rico had the
Bandana on and everything and I was
like,
God damn,
that is Rico Suave or you might
yourself.
I was by myself.
I was like in his Bandana.
I wasn't a Volkswagon Corrado.
Look at Rico Suave to make an inner
monologue that's like,
this is going to be okay living here.
No,
no,
but uh,
but my,
uh,
my,
if I did have an inner monologue of bill
as,
wow,
that's fucking Rico Suave
I would say.
And then I would think
a famous person because he's probably
one of the first actual famous people I
ever saw.
I really didn't want to think it.
He was
huge back then.
If I think about it.
I mean I guess I knew,
um,
Mario Joiner because I had already done
mtv.
I met Mario joinder was more famous
probably at that time.
Didn't even Rico Suave men.
Remember Memorial Joyner was a hosted
the MTV half hour comedy hour.
He was fucking huge man.
He was a failure.
I think I want,
I want to say it was funny as shit still
is.
Funniest.
Funniest Shit.
Yeah.
Well he's another one of those guys,
like how come they're not gigantic?
Explain that.
Explain all the dudes that you know that
are kind of mediocre.
There's a lot of people know.
And then I kind of know what the fuck
it's like music does that.
Like,
like when I look at like musicians,
like there's a music she's done more
than isn't named Chubby checker.
The guy that took the twists.
Yeah,
but why do we know him?
And not people that had albums were for
work.
Cause that shit caught on fire in the
1953 people were dumb as fuck
and there was so many remakes of that
shit.
Even the fat boys remade that shit in
the eighties
so it's would never die.
And this guy is famous for one,
he made a song but it's a song about a
dance work.
And back then man,
any opportunity to be joyful and be like
thank God the opportunity to be joyful.
People just got back from World War Two.
Okay.
World War had just ended.
We dropped bombs on them.
We were in a cold war with Russia.
Everybody thought that nuclear bombs
going to drop our heads for 30 fucking
years.
Between 1950 and 1980.
Everybody thought we were going to war
with Cuba,
but literally through that whole time.
So you know,
any toys,
he likes to let this guy just dance me
out of my worry because my dad went over
and now he has no legs and I don't want
that to happen to me.
That's going on now.
Yeah,
it absolutely don't.
Any type of instruction,
dance songs,
they still work.
The only difference between then and now
is then everybody thought they were
gonna get drafted.
It was a different feeling.
So come on,
let's twist this.
Any opportunity to fucking 50.
SPLUNK's sucked up fat dick.
They look so dumb.
They're cars are stupid.
They couldn't slow down for shit.
You know,
nobody had seat belts.
Get out of here with that seatbelt.
You just traveling around that metal
cage rattling around inside with your
baby in your lap.
It was things were death traps and
that's how everybody got around those
big fucking old bel airs and Shit.
Chested drawers on wheels.
I always described those little cars
like rhinos on rollers and ozone
smashing into each other like sounds
uncoordinated shit.
Although a little more.
It's less,
more ridiculous than yours.
Yours is actually a better description
because it is like that.
Those,
those fucking things are pieces of shit.
Those old cars feel all bouncy
and the fucking steering is vague as
fuck.
To steering is vague.
You're pissing off everybody that hangs
out at Bob's big boys in Burbank
cars.
Man.
I had a lot of old cars.
I know the difference between those.
The old steering in those cars.
It was ridiculous.
There was.
It was so dangerous.
The braking on those old cars,
the balance,
they weren't balanced at all.
They just made them the shape they
wanted to make them.
Women didn't need yoga back then.
They get yoga.
I'm just the car.
Yeah.
Those things were away.
Easy to crash with the cars we have
today.
That Burbank night,
the Friday night.
That's crazy.
They had a Batman one where it was just
every single Batman car ever made people
do those every Friday mean Batman car.
Oh yeah.
I think there are kits.
I think you could lower it by an old
cadillac and have it converted.
Know what's funny about the Burbank on
Fridays.
It's like the black version of that was
crenshaw on Sundays.
Oh really?
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
He's back there.
But they shut down the crenshaw one for
titus.
Wasn't there people got shot.
Joe Friends.
When you're showing off your car only
milkshakes and delicious food happening
at the Burbank ones.
All white people.
Oops.
The uh,
the Bob's big boy one is a,
that's what?
Burbank.
Burbank near all of Burbank in Alameda.
And uh,
something like,
that's the one where it actually has the
big,
big boy.
Big Box where I go every night.
So every Sunday they get together and
just look at cars every Friday.
Yeah.
That night at like 8:00
PM or something like early,
like some people have really nothing to
do and there's a lot of older guys and
this is the highlight of their week.
So they'll be out there in a day and it
just goes to like nighttime.
Huh.
And I recommend if you go there to
actually get the steak and eggs there
because they have a higher quality
version of stake there.
So it's good stuff.
It's good.
I haven't eaten at Bob's big boy in a
long fucking for 24 hours,
man.
Boy,
they got Internet there.
That's where you go after.
You know,
I'm usually waiting with a girl so I
don't really see a way of life.
The last thing wants to see is that girl
fucking watched the girl,
the girl.
Fuck.
Why are you eating state quarter
dudes in their cars.
It's a funny thing when the pussy just
stops,
there's no more pushing your life and
you just polished the share that car,
the car all the time.
Just,
you know those older dudes with like
vintage cars that they clean with a
toothbrush.
Okay,
I see what's going on here.
Can I see what's going on here?
They take care of the other special
cloth in their pocket that they hope to
get that special cloth out the micro
cloth and wipe it there.
Do you fuck with cars?
Is it anything that you,
uh,
you fixate on cars?
Do you like cars?
Nah.
No it wouldn't.
I fixate on.
Is this just jokes really?
And maybe trouble with girls.
Trouble with girls.
He mean relationships.
I think that's what you're saying.
Yeah.
I just,
I just like any,
any.
I think most disputes I have with a
woman end up on stage,
like,
like most of my friends,
like why are you even dealing with these
pictures?
I said,
because it's material,
it's constructive,
you know?
Yeah.
A lot of comics take that approach.
That's what I did.
That's why I'm going to avn tomorrow.
Good luck fucker.
Yeah,
a lot.
A lot of comlex take that approach.
I used to think that he couldn't be
enlightened in not claiming
enlightenment by any stretch of the
imagination.
I'm certainly not enlightened,
but I used to think that you couldn't
even seek it and be a funny comedian.
I thought,
you know,
lightened meant seek peace because to be
a comic,
to me that was like the,
the idea was always that if you're going
to be at my favorite kind of comics,
there was no peace.
My favorite kind of complex where
Kennison and hex and prior and you know,
and the guys from Boston,
you know,
the,
uh,
the guys that people don't know about,
like Steve Sweeney and Don Gavin.
And so there,
there,
there was a salt comedy and that was
coming out.
You're beating you over the head with
it.
There was no sot nom up in this bitch is
crazy comedy.
So I always thought that like to do that
kind of comedy.
Like you really can't be like trying to
like get your shit together.
You have to have some cash in your life.
You have nothing to talk.
Well I think the good thing about life,
it'll always bring your chaos no matter
how peaceful you are.
And then being a human,
you still going to do human shit though,
you know better.
So you know that that's always a but.
But I understand always wanted to keep
your comedy edge and you probably walked
away from like peace like earlier on
just because you thought you wanted to
keep it comedy edge but now a little bit
grown and you're like fuck it,
I can be funny and be peaceful
a little bit.
But it was also like with me,
it was like a sort of a,
a natural process of doing everything
stupid that you can do to realize,
okay,
well I won't be doing that.
And there's another one.
Well,
all right,
I won't do that one again.
And then by the time you get to be like,
you know,
37 years old or some shit,
you go,
okay,
I think I've accumulated a pretty good
database of what's gotten me in trouble
and when it's not gotten me in trouble
and I need to figure out how to navigate
towards the right hand side of this
equation because this is,
I'm not,
I'm fucking up my own life by doing
this.
And this night I'm enjoying it.
I'm like,
what do I enjoy?
And I had to kind of break it down,
you know,
I enjoy,
different activities and enjoy doing
standup.
And I enjoy hanging out with my comedian
friends.
What I tell him,
enjoy his girls were telling me that it
shouldn't hang out with comedians all
the time because they just reinforce
your opinions and you think that you
know that you're not fucked up,
but you are fucked up and you're just
hanging around with these comedians and
they're fucked up too.
So you're like,
oh,
I'm okay because fucking Ari Shaffir
thinks it's okay.
It's funny because I say something funny
and fucking Joey Diaz Lab said that's
not okay.
They never even got a chance to say that
I didn't allow them.
Girl tries to talk shit about my
comedian friends shoot talking about
crazy,
but you know,
in my younger days I just won't tolerate
it.
But then by the time I hit like around
30,
I was like,
all right,
first of all,
I got to it instituted no headshots,
policy and no hair,
no head shots or chicken with no head,
no headshots,
none.
None.
None of that nonsense.
Trying to act.
We try to do,
try to say,
fuck Outta here.
Get outta here with half of the chicks
in La.
Yeah.
And you know what?
And it's a rude thing to say,
especially because I've had headshots,
you know,
it's ridiculous.
It's,
I can understand you being upset with
me.
Like I'm not saying I'm perfect,
but I'm saying as far as like the people
that I get along with and I can't get
along with other performers.
It's a Yin Yang sort of a thing.
And it's.
It is,
it's not a jealousy thing.
It's not a selfish thing.
Like I don't like to talk about like
when me and my wife talk,
we never talk about like my comedy,
like never.
I'll tell her like,
ah,
it's fucking show was great.
It was a lot of fun.
I'll tell her that,
but I don't ever like,
Whoa,
I don't need to go over the process with
you.
I don't need to go.
What,
what do you think?
This is funny.
We don't have,
I don't have any of those conversations.
None of them.
And there's a lot of shit that I would
say I'm sure that she wouldn't find
funny or that she would think it's
fucked up.
But.
But I know it's funny to me and the type
of people that I like to hang out with,
you know,
it's funny,
if it makes me laugh when you're dating
someone that tries to kill him,
that undermine that.
Yeah.
You know,
and that's why I'm single like cars.
You find that happen.
What is it all just a woman saying if
you say something that you would
normally say to a point and they say,
that's not funny.
First of all,
I don't have to be funny every minute.
Right?
And if I'm not funny,
I don't need you to tell me that I hang
out with people like,
yeah,
so what are you doing?
Like.
And by the way,
sometimes you miss,
sometimes you miss and that's the,
that's the game.
But nobody's out there keeping score.
And then in like pounded in you that you
had an unfunny moment with them,
especially after you just made them
laugh.
Like what's,
what is your problem?
Exactly.
How much lack of understanding do you
know about the human condition?
Well,
you never said something that you
thought was funny and it wasn't.
That's like part of life.
And then some of them girls cheat when
it comes to funny,
like they'll say something and they'll
laugh and I said I had just clowns.
You pitch,
you can't determine that.
It's funny because you said I have to be
laughing too.
That is funny.
Or I or when they try to give you a bit
like that's funny you should say that on
stage sometime.
Ever had that.
My mom does that.
But do you know sometimes a woman will
say something
and sometimes I'll be like mad that they
said something funny to help me.
Oh really?
That's funny.
Like she gives you some pointers and
they work shit.
That is fucking funny you like because
you just want to take it from you where
you want to take it from.
Sometimes.
Yeah,
that's true.
But you can get some good pointers even
from idiots.
You can get some good pointers from
people that you don't even respect.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
that's true.
I've had that happen.
I've had someone given me some good
advice once.
I didn't want to hear it at all.
This guy was an idiot now.
Like did.
He gave me good advice,
he gave it to me into a tape recorder.
He was hanging out with another comedian
friend of mine and I had a tape recorder
and I put a tape recorder down and I was
recording my set and this dude picked up
a tape recorder and was given me notes
on the tape recorder.
You feel like you're taking,
talking too much about sex.
You're repeating yourself,
you're,
you're the.
And he said that like on,
on the recording.
I wish I saved it because she was like,
no,
no.
This is a long,
long,
long time ago.
This was probably like 1991 or something
like that.
It was GRANDPA's on Staten Island and
the dude was talking into my recorder
and I'm like,
you know,
look man,
don't.
I don't want your fucking opinion.
Okay.
You don't need detail.
I didn't ask you.
I don't need to talk to them.
This is for me.
This recording is for me so I can go
over my shit and decide what I think
about it.
So violation.
Yeah.
Not that I hear your voice saying what I
would.
Maybe it wasn't a good set.
I didn't have a good set because I think
I'm fucked up the order of material or
something.
There was some sort of error there,
but he was right.
Like what he sat on the recording was
right.
Like he said,
like you're talking too much about this
and you know,
you repeating yourself.
He's right because I fucked up one of my
bits or something.
Whatever I did,
I knew that this asshole and that's like
the worst.
He gave me.
Good advice though.
I mean it was,
it was really good advice from a
douchebag that shouldn't have been given
advice.
You can accept that shit from people.
But I've been in relationships with
people that like all they do,
like if you dated someone who's trying
to be an act or something like that at
all they do is talk about acting.
All they do is talk about that and
about.
And they'll like,
they'll like fake talk to you.
Like it's almost like they're talking to
you and this is one of the weirdest
things that an actor will do.
They're talking to you and they're
pretending like they be talking to
someone in an interview,
so they're talking to you,
but they're talking crazy bullshit like
talking to me and like,
um,
what'd you think of the movie?
I thought her performance was stunning.
It's like there.
I thought she was amazing and I thought
it was really powerful the way it was
presented.
I felt like it was like,
what the fuck are you saying?
Who are you talking to you?
I would,
I could tell that this was like some
weird speech because there's like a,
there's a mantra that gets chanted
whenever anything
is successful in Hollywood and the
people that want to be successful as
well.
They'll go along with the.
Yes,
good.
This is good.
Like whoever's good is it Daniel Day
Lewis,
Daniel Day,
Lewis and Lewis,
and then everybody will chant that
mantra and it gets to a point where you
see people repeating these mantras,
patterns and conversations,
right?
Like it was an amazing film.
The powerful portrayal just shone light
on that time period in a way that's in
escapable.
Like the,
there's the,
there's shit in the way they're talking.
We're like,
I know what you're doing.
You're not really talking,
you're,
you're just using talking points that
all these other actors in your acting
class or saying they're all talking
crazy talk.
Right.
It's funny like Hollywood is the only
place where everybody.
Maybe it happens other places,
but like everybody like kind of has,
its not,
you know,
how style set trends,
but there's,
there's personality trends.
Like there was a time and I think people
still didn't like don't say that.
That's negative.
Like how the fuck is that negative?
Like you'll say something and just
because.
Because it's real because it's real,
it's negative,
it's real,
and a lot of times it's negative to not
say it.
And that's what I'm saying.
That's why I always tell people,
well I'm so negative,
I'm positive that shit.
It's negative to not point out negative
things because you're not contributing
to fixing any problem that might exist.
That could be correctable if someone
would address what the fuck is going on,
you know,
but yeah,
that don't be negative shit.
That was a big one for me.
That was a big one for a while.
He used to bug me and a is always
something or or just to the illegal use
of the word like me and Patricia talks
like I was like,
hey,
you can't say haters.
Like if you disagree with somebody or
you're a hater,
what happened to when you could just
disagree,
right?
Like,
and not be a heater like so I have to
have your opinion on this.
I'm a hater.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Well,
and there's also.
Here's the thing.
This is a way to express opinions in a
respectful way and some people don't do
that.
Some people,
if they disagree with you,
they do it in like they try to discount
your point and like an insulting way and
haven't been to.
I think we all have been,
but that's one of the hardest things
about accepting contrary ideas is a lot
of times is the way they're presented.
If someone has a different point of view
than you,
especially if it's like a kid,
here's a hot button topic,
global warming,
you sit down with the wrong motherfucker
and talk about global warming and they
will insult you.
They will find a way to to figure out
like,
what side are you on?
You,
you know,
if you're,
if you're a Republican,
most likely you're siding with big
business and you say,
well,
you know what?
The trends have shown that global
warming is a natural cycle is repeated
by the guy and they just repeat those
talking points.
Or if you're someone who's a Democrat,
it's very likely you will get emotional
and you say,
you think it's okay to fuck up this
earth and fuck it up.
For my children.
I think you know,
and there's,
there's that point of view like the
people that are extreme ecologist,
we need to all go vegan.
We need to all grow our own vegetables.
I don't know who's right,
right.
No,
I'm not.
I'm not neither one of those fucking
people.
But people fall into categories for real
easy and sometimes it's hard to find
like a real person and the real opinion
and a real point of view in the hot
button topics.
Like whenever you got you talking about
rape or you're talking about,
uh,
you know,
the environment,
violence,
gun control,
you're talking about gun control.
You just get to.
I was just thinking about the gun
control thing.
Alright.
So let me,
let me ask what you're thinking about
this.
So yesterday I tweeted that a stoney
hook is the NRI and an Nras 9:11,
right?
Because there's like conspiracy
theorists,
right?
They're saying that it was staged,
I've seen that.
So video.
Fuck is that all about.
I'm like,
is that someone please someone debunk
that.
It's got to be a debunked sandy hook
thing.
Somebody sent me the video,
I was looking at that shit.
And then they were,
they were pointing out how the media
story changed as the story of Stony
Brook became,
you know.
But to me it's like one of the things in
the video was they said there were two
shooters and they chased the guy through
the woods and then.
But to me it's like,
well,
the guy who's making a video,
like when a story first breaks,
there's gonna be differences in the
story until they figure out what really,
really happened.
Yes.
You know what I'm saying?
So that I only watched like half and I
got to finish watching the rest of it.
But so far it's like,
yeah,
they was inconsistency in the beginning,
but that's because it's the beginning.
Like later on.
And then they had the father,
the father of emily who did his speech
and it was a great speech about his
daughter.
And uh,
he went up
and they were making it seem like he was
faking it.
Like he was faking the speech.
Listen man,
you got into,
you imagine how bad it would make that
guy feel if his daughter was murdered by
a cycle.
And then people accused him of lying,
right?
And then based on what?
Based on you looking at him,
talking where he smiled a little bit
before he talked.
People deal with grief very differently.
Some people bawl their eyes out,
some people joke around about it,
and then just get it home and sit in the
fucking dark and,
and cry by themselves.
I mean,
who,
who the fuck knows how you would react
if your baby got shot down like that?
That'd be so fucked up.
And for all these so called experts to
be so insensitive when you're dealing
with something so horrific.
You know?
So the crazy thing is it's more fucked
up.
Like the video is more fucked up than
the shooting.
Like you think the shooter was crazy for
you to make this video.
That's fucking.
He's got.
This is my opinion that you got.
If you're going to say something like
that,
you got to be really fucking chore.
If you're saying that someone's faking
and their daughter wasn't really killed
and they're just an actor,
man,
you better fucking go and do the work.
You better had photos of this guy.
Where you see him in the production of
hamlet and you know,
this is real fucking name and this is
where he lives.
You can't just speculate and say it
doesn't look like he's sad.
Right?
That's crazy.
Or what about that guy that found all
those kids at the end of his driveway
and then just like took him inside and
hung out with them and he's getting
harassed and his story's changing too.
Well,
he,
he said,
uh,
I didn't hear that.
It's the only thing that bothers me
about his story.
So they say this guy is a hero because
he came outside,
there was six kids on his lawn and he
took them in his house and gave them
toys and kept them safe.
But when he found than they will with a
bus driver who took them away from the
scene.
So why isn't the bus driver hero?
But then you know,
he's crying about the kids and cool,
okay,
this,
that's just a moot point.
So then now the conspiracy theories or
hitting him and saying,
well,
his story changed at first it wasn't a
bus driver or something like that.
You can't rely on people when people say
the story changes and plus you didn't.
It doesn't change.
It just.
It's just you don't know what's going
on.
Right.
How many times have you told a bad
store?
You remember you have ever said
something and someone will say,
no,
no.
We were in Phoenix.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
That happens all the time.
They get you in court.
That's why prosecutors like he changed
his story soon because first of all,
you asked.
I didn't even know what the fuck you was
asking me.
It's like
testimony is notoriously unreliable.
Notoriously it doesn't.
The people see the shit that didn't
really happen.
Sometimes they freak out,
they hear things,
they repeat the things they heard.
Those things become.
Gossip becomes.
It Becomes Gospel,
you know?
No,
no,
no.
There are three shooters,
three shooters in the building.
What the fuck?
No.
You know,
how do you know?
How do they got the one guy?
You see the one guy go in and start
shooting people?
Did you watch the whole thing?
If you didn't,
then you don't know that there's only
one guy when you the police and you get
there,
the only thing you know is every shoot
is in the building.
And the people that met the shit of
dead.
Yeah.
And the people had escaped.
They were trying to run for their lives.
So you try like,
how do you.
You don't know what the fuck is going
on,
what the fuck is going?
You don't know what the fuck is going on
either.
You don't know who's doing it.
Right.
And I and I know that I'm unreliable
like this.
Things that I thought I remembered the
way they went and later on realize that
they didn't.
And I have to come to terms with that.
Like Damn my memory is not as great as I
thought it was.
What's really scary that people think
that the government would be so corrupt
that they'd be willing to either murder
kids or there's no real murders,
I think.
And they think that they could pull this
off.
Like I've heard those two conspiracies
that someone is hired and this is all to
take our guns away.
Right.
And then the idea is that in,
in doing this,
what they're going to do is they're
going to get people so freaked out that
they're gonna be able to disarm them and
then the tyrannical governments going to
take over.
Right.
It's really weird.
Were these kids in a petri dish?
They started at seven years ago.
You know what I mean?
Like
something terrence parents went on
television and talked about their
children's not like,
you know what I mean?
Like actual human beings.
It's,
you cannot have.
And this doesn't even exist in
Connecticut.
She just put it in my head.
The whole thing's a big CIA plot.
I've been on the show homeland.
I finished the second,
second season.
God Damn,
that's a good show.
I've heard people say,
oh,
it's called and moves with one small
words.
So good fucking show that Claire Danes
asked her hits off.
Did you ever watch a Joe Schmo show back
in the day?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That was the show where they,
um,
they had uh,
uh,
one guy who thought he was on a reality
show and everybody else was actors or
they're doing another one right now,
favorite show ever.
And then I met was at bear Chrysler,
his house when we killed that pig and
ate it and stuff.
And I met the executive producer that
Schubert killed a pig at his house as
well.
No,
they just cooked it and skinned it
alive.
I was like,
wow,
that's gangster.
But I met the producer guy of the show
and I was like,
so happy.
That's one of the few shows that I just
loved the idea,
loved.
Remember when,
I don't know if you remember Brian from
one of the first episode,
he used to hang out at the comedy store
all the time and he was at main
character,
the first series,
Natasha Leggiero is second thing,
but I was sick yesterday,
so I went home and watched the marathon
of the first four episodes of the new
one and do it.
It's so fucking hilarious,
man.
You have to check it out.
The one main guy does that podcast with
Kevin Smith,
a Hollywood Babylon.
I can't remember his name,
but he's like the main guy.
Check this.
Check this part out.
This trailer here.
It's funny.
It's honestly,
I think chase thing.
Remember Lorenzo Limos today.
We're going to use all of this to our
advantage to see him.
Chase actually has a dark side
guy right there.
He's the only one that thinks this.
A reality shows real.
Everyone else has paid actors,
so the whole reality show is that
there's only one guy that thinks he's
actually in the reality show.
Nice.
I kind of want to be the guy on the
reality show whose name you might not
learn until episode seven,
who's kind of the opposite of Lorenzo
Lamas and just kind of flies under the
radar.
Ralph Garman in this as well.
The guy from a red state,
he was in red state.
He's in Hollywood Babylon.
I her to talk to you about maybe helping
me today.
Damn.
Lorenzo alumnus.
Let himself go little.
You got a little sloppy on that girl.
I played depths.
There's an access that actually has to
play deaf and she keeps on fucking up
because like,
like champagne bottle will snap off and
she'll react,
but you shouldn't have to work their way
out of that.
Damn.
Lorenzo got all sloppy.
You don't have to be sunning
or swimming.
Lorenzo and acts like he owns a company
that sells these things called a
European bio or something.
Look at this guy,
this gay black dude,
and he kind hit.
Is it a really gay black dude?
As a actor?
I don't think he might be really good.
So he's an actor.
He's an actor that's gay and gay in real
life.
I think they're all.
They're all walking around for the folks
listening on itunes like,
what the fuck are they saying?
It's a bunch of dudes were in speedos
walking around.
That's the whole joke is that they're
wearing speedos and you think this is
awesome.
No know what they're doing is because
one of the character Lorenzo,
he has a speedo company.
Right?
And know I heard all that and what
they're trying to do is they're trying
to make the real guy put a speedo on
speed.
That's what the whole show is.
It's like fucking with this guy.
The whole show is.
I just don't think this is very
interesting.
It's a bunch of idiots in speedos.
I know what you're saying,
but it's a good show.
You got to check it out.
I'm just saying TV shows,
working for them or something.
But go to the olive garden.
[inaudible].
They have this new two for 25 now.
But no,
I'm just saying I watched like the first
four episodes of this and it's really
fucking good.
If you're looking for a new TC
prank shows.
Do you like watching people lie?
I mean I liked punk.
You know what I used to like Jamie
Kennedy experience.
Jamie Kennedy experiment was the
experiment,
right?
Yeah.
That was a.
That was a good fucking show.
That guy did some crazy shit man.
When he had those guys sign up for a
boy's gun.
Nuts.
You know,
there was the boy version of girls gone
wild boys got nuts and they're like,
you're going to be on police.
Got nuts.
And they like talked him into doing gay
shit.
Like they told them,
you know,
we wouldn't even have to do some gay
shit and you know,
these guys are on camera and like all
right,
like they think it's real.
They were agreeing to do some gay shit
for money and so that is like on camera
for ever.
You can always tap into people wanting
to be famous who doesn't do that
anymore.
But it does stand up.
But I don't hear anybody talking about a
standup.
The way I heard people talking about
that show,
that show was a crook.
He was really good at that man.
I mean I think I just moved to la or
something.
I don't know,
but I'm just amazed that he stopped
doing it.
That was a good fighter.
She's heck maybe annoyed me because he
didn't have hecklers.
It's like if you're going to make a
heckler movie and talk about heckling,
at least have real heckler footage.
Well,
he had a little bit of it,
but it has a lot of critics.
It was more critics and hecklers,
you know,
like fake.
It was filmed is what I heard it was.
Hmm.
I Dunno.
I mean I think he got actual people that
gave him bad reviews,
but there's nothing wrong with someone
giving you a bad review.
I mean everybody's got different tastes
and his standup's not the strongest in
the world.
So it's like,
what are you trying to say?
You know,
the.
Is it,
is it a review thing or is it a heckle
thing?
Because the problem with heckling is
you're interrupting a performance and
you're being rude and you think that
you're bad ass and you know,
you think you're funnier than the show
and so you,
that's us.
You're,
you're fucking up the whole agreement
that an audience has with a performer.
You know when you're sitting in the
audience and you're watching a bad
comedian,
you can yell at him
and fucking and kill if you want it to,
but you would never do that because it's
an agreement when you're in the
audience,
you'd behave as an audience member
would.
When you're on stage,
you do your fucking act and if you
hackle your account,
it's really that simple.
That's the.
That's the whole formula.
The only time it's not bad,
it's when someone's doing it.
Good naturedly they got a couple of
drinks and I'm gonna yell something out
and it might be funny.
There's nothing wrong with that.
It's when someone is like intentionally
fucking with you or insulting you and
trying to throw you off of the
performance,
trying to stop you or demanding
attention,
unwanted attention for themselves.
You ever had that accident?
I guess you have like the accidentally
good heckler where they're not heckling
you per say they are,
but they're while you're setting up your
joke,
they always seen,
oh yeah,
yeah.
And it throws off your timing.
It's like,
how the fuck did you learn how to do
that?
Shit?
You ever see comics that you thought
were really funny back in the day and
then you see them today and they're
like,
still like relying on like old stupid
tricks and you see their jokes coming a
mile away and you get really
disappointed.
Yeah.
I'm watched some dudes on TV the other
day and uh,
I was just sitting there watching this
guy set and I was like,
and then you're going to say that and he
said that.
And then,
um,
I mean it wasn't even like,
like lobs.
I mean he's just rolling balls on the
ground.
He wasn't even trying to get them over
the plate.
I was like,
some people like they get to a certain
point in time where they just fuck.
It looks like they stopped trying.
I guess
that's my,
that's like I used to watch boxing a lot
and then you can realize when there's a
shock boxer had one fight too many.
And I remember a guy named,
his name was Gerard Washington.
Now the first time I seen him perform he
killed and then everybody went up to him
afterwards.
I mean,
he ripped the place apart and we'd been
doing it like two or three years and
say,
how many times you've done it?
He said,
it's the second time.
It was like,
Whoa,
shit,
this motherfucker in any,
any,
any.
He started doing shows around town and
Harlem is head.
He's just ripping.
Then he quit,
became an ems worker and shit and then
got married and then came back and he
threw the show in Queens.
He had a room in Queens.
I used to go to the room and then I used
to rip the room and then he used to go
up and he used to do bad and he was
doing the same material from before and
there was something missing.
You don't know what it is,
but in all my life,
my fear is to not make that thing that
was missing from him.
Be Missing from me.
You know what I'm saying?
Make sure you don't catch it.
Catch.
Catch like it's tough,
man.
Whoa.
Almost every great comedian except
prior.
Prior was the only one who kept,
in my opinion,
getting better and the strongest
material is the.
The later material,
even like it's like some live in the
sunset strip,
some of the strongest shit ever,
but you know,
and then you'd go back to his early
stuff.
It was still all like really strong,
but like Kennison man Kennison
had one good cd while or it wasn't even
a CD because I don't think warner
brothers wanted to release it on cd
because it was so offensive to gay
people,
but it was louder than hell.
Kennison had one hbo special that was
not quite as good as louder than hell
but pretty close.
And then from there it was a slide from
the HBO special.
It was like he had,
he had a Rodney dangerfield sat and he
had an hour to hour still fucking bad
ass.
To this day I still watch that and laugh
your ass off,
but it's still not quite as good as
louder than hell.
The cassette,
the cassette was just on fire.
It was just him,
you know,
doing performances at different clubs
all over the country.
And it was all spliced together.
It was ending.
He was just the best shit.
But then if you listen to like the stuff
from like to not even a year later,
two years later,
the next whatever the next cd was,
it's like a copycat of his old act.
It's like somebody,
yeah,
somebody pretending to be him and his
him like a dumb guy.
Like a dumb guys got the reins now and
then he's going to make stuff that's
like barely amusing
he's got.
And it's just like,
man,
if you,
if you looked at that like as a store,
like the structure of that,
it's like,
so lacking in a joke structure.
Yeah.
You can go back to like his,
like,
um,
the Ethiopia bit,
which is a,
that's the one that's on louder than
hell.
I don't think it's on the um,
I don't know if it's on his hbo special,
but that Ethiopia bit is fucked up
where he's already at a point.
Yeah,
he had a great point.
It's like he goes,
you know,
we just drove here with your friend to
us.
It wouldn't be if you see that,
don't want to know.
It's going to be 100 years now.
Fuck.
We got deserts in America too,
we just don't,
and he was just destroying and he made,
he had a the
point and it was like he thought it out
and it was fucked up that he was saying
it,
but it was still funny.
And then he went from that to just like,
I guess too much coke and too much
parties.
He got really fat.
He looked like,
like rotund onstage,
you know,
he became like a caricature and then he
just was never the same guy again.
He was like,
he got by the same way and old rock band
gets by.
But he did it over just a few years.
Like if,
if his health was okay,
like we,
we could have seen the better years of
Kennison after he became famous.
I mean if he could keep it up,
but his type of party in like that
cocaine and whiskey partying,
it became about the party.
I remember seeing that Jay Jimmy's
comedy alley in Queens and Queens,
like two years after,
like the funny Shit,
you know?
Oh,
when it was going away and doing smaller
venues again,
like I saw him twice,
three times,
some three times live and he got worse
every time a song,
whereas everything it got got Saturn,
Saturn,
the opening acts get shittier
and Shittier.
It was bad.
Like the one of the last times I saw
him,
it was just not a good shot.
You wanted to laugh,
but there was no opportunities.
Just it just wasn't good.
And then his last thing that he did,
I think it was like a CD.
It's a lot of things not that bad,
but if you compare it to like louder
than hell.
Yes.
The funny thing,
you can compare it,
that's the only problem you can't get
louder than hell was fucking
outstanding.
I think he was the best comic ever for a
year.
That's what I think for one year,
but overall I would say prior,
prior just overall he changed the whole
style of comedy that people did.
Opened him up,
opened himself up in a vulnerable way on
stage and nobody had ever come close to
before.
You know,
the way he would approached comedy,
I think changed comedy.
Kennison changed a little bit.
No,
he certainly influenced a lot of people,
me included,
but prior just in my opinion,
he was like the number one
guy ever.
I called him a dirty cosby because
remember we used to imitate Cosby,
cosby,
tell people spoke to them,
and then it's like if you listened to
bill cosby to like,
I think himself,
Bill cosby himself,
like they update.
Those are the first two guys I
reenlisted and then this is blasphemers.
Prior used to talk about Red Fox and how
it influenced them and I listened to
read processes like,
Eh,
I just,
you know,
this is blasphemy,
but I didn't say it.
Well,
try going back and watching or listening
to lenny.
Bruce,
you won't last.
You won't laugh at all.
I believe you.
I don't even have to go back.
I believe it's the people
and I'm a huge Lenny Bruce family and
you go with my house.
I have an old concert posters framed on
my wall from when he was at the fillmore
in San Francisco.
I got it.
I recognize that without him,
I mean he's,
in my opinion,
he's the godfather of monitor standup
comedy.
He's the first seed,
the real spark,
and then from him,
you know,
there's other guys in that era like the
more sols and a lot of those other guys
that just pointed out shit and saw
things in a very intelligent way,
but then prior comes from that seed and
prior takes it to the next day.
The differences prior.
Still funny.
You go back and watch Richard Pryor lot
not live on the sunset strip.
That's a great one too,
but though even the one before that,
I forget what it's called.
The specialty did before that.
That's fucking fantastic.
It's great comedy.
I mean it's great observational comedy
when he's doing the thing about the
Italians they were digging to get.
It's funny,
man.
It's still,
it's still really good to this day.
Whereas like the Lenny Bruce stuff and
in Red Fox to a certain extent,
but Red Fox,
I think,
you know,
I think it's just a different era when
he was just saying dirty things like
nobody had ever heard anybody do that
before.
It was like God damn,
you know,
and also I think being there,
it's different,
different than then that word spreads
and you're listening to those people
like God is going to be like,
there's one thing,
pride didn't want to have a specialist.
That was amazing to me.
Like he was killing,
he was up here just killing and then
somebody said,
do mud bone,
and they begged him to do mud bone.
But then I've never seen somebody like
take it down.
It's like you're in a dance club and
you're playing all this hard music and
then we're going to play a slow takes
place,
gets quiet.
And it's like everybody's splits still.
Everybody's paying as much attention as
when he was.
He wasn't afraid to take it down and
like that's ballsy.
And they bring them back up.
Just a master.
Yeah.
I mean he.
And by the way,
there was nobody like that before him.
He was the first guy that was really
doing it like that.
He was the first guy that it was really
just genuinely balls out funny all the
time and had like these really
heartwarming points,
you know,
when he came back from Africa and he had
those stories about meeting Africans and
that he was gonna stop saying the word
nigger because of going to Africa.
Like you heard that you're like,
wow,
what comic has ever made you feel like
that?
It was funny,
like I heard that when he said that,
and I said,
man,
I'm sorry.
That's a great point,
Richard.
You basically my comedy guy saying it's
just too potent a word and only allowed
to toss it around.
Can't stop it.
Stopped is what you started.
Well,
it's amazing that it's become a
and empowerment word.
It's like the word has gone from a word
that's a slur to still being a slur,
but more often and empowerment and
unlike a film familiarity word that
black people are allowed to use amongst
themselves and when you actually do try
to,
like a white person does try to use it.
It's like almost legalized violence like
there will almost legally allowed to
kick your ass.
So it's become a crazy thing.
It's not like it's never said what you
say,
it'll make people devastated.
No black people say it all the time
amongst themselves.
A very interesting sort of a dynamic.
But the daringness of it and the,
the,
the chance of saying it makes white
people I know say it like hey,
like I was hanging out in this coffee
shop who's eaten and one of the young
comics,
he was like,
he started doing this,
this verse from this.
Right.
But he knows the word Niggas ain't
right.
Right,
right,
right.
And then he says it and it's like,
but I'm not going to react to that
because you know why?
Because I'm over the word nigger.
This is nothing.
But there's a difference between that
and him calling somebody.
Yeah.
But,
but there is a way they know they can't
call,
you know,
they know I'm there.
You can't call somebody there.
So it's just saying it to get a rush
themselves because now they're getting
away with it
to get away with it.
Yeah.
And so I noticed that white guys do that
to try to get away with it in front of a
blackboard.
It's no fun if you say it in front of
white people.
Right?
It's like,
if you can say it,
like somebody will repeat one of my
jokes back to me.
Oh,
the n word.
And it's like,
it's like there's nothing you can do
because it's your job.
You did say it.
What did you think about the controversy
with this?
Uh,
the,
uh,
the Django movie,
Django unchained,
I think it was a,
uh,
no controversy,
controversy.
Like I'm wondering if spike Lee is
really just trying to help at the boy.
He's boys with terantin on the low and
this,
this is his way to help him sell movies.
I don't think so.
I think he's a professional troll at
this point.
I mean he supposed sued spike TV and one
a shitload of money.
I mean,
there's a lot of spike Jones,
there's a lot of spike Lee and none of
them says,
yeah,
there's,
there's a lot of other spikes besides
spike Lee.
I mean,
I would think it's got to be hundreds of
them.
Right?
How many different spikes are there in
that famous football guys named spiker?
Does that dog from the fucking comic
memory?
Let me go and spike,
but we go into bike chat APP.
Big Bull dog and the dog.
The dog's spike suit.
Spike Lee?
Yeah.
How fuck he should sue them.
I love fucking.
You say that you got out or rap on the
name spike
now.
That to me is like,
like the Django Shit with Spike Lee.
That's him hating.
That's to me,
that's like,
you should have made this movie.
You didn't.
And this white guy made it.
Yeah.
He uh,
he fell apart artistically awhile ago.
Something happened in that guy.
He doesn't do the same shit that he used
to do.
If you go back to like do the right
thing,
like his movies had this crackle to
them.
Mo Betta Blues.
You know
what happened at her?
Oh my,
this,
this pen clicking the grades over there
because it's hilarious.
I think spitely this is,
this is spike Lee's emo.
Make one really great movie and then
make one really bad movie to the point
like,
is this the same person?
Then he'll make another really good
movie and then they'll make another like
you can name like,
like,
like what was it?
She's got a,
there's a movie where she's got a habit
and she's got a habit.
Then he made some movie where
you got to give it up to that movie
because that movie made girls empowered
to go get some deck.
Like it was okay to go get some Dick.
Like,
you know,
like he made a whole movie about a girl
has got to get some tech and every,
all the other girls like,
wow,
I don't have to feel bad about having to
get some tech because this is like the
lead of the movie.
Getting some data in that way.
I think he hooked a lot of dudes up and
he probably got a lot of guys laid for
that.
Yeah.
Spike got two movies,
made,
two movies that's in my top 10 movies of
all time is Malcolm x and do the right
thing.
And then he's got movies that are in my
own words,
all time.
Worst movies.
Like what?
Uh,
forgot the name of his fucking movie
man.
Something like girls six or girl
something.
And you don't know what the fuck is
going on.
Did you ever see the 25th hour?
Yeah,
the dude's pretty decent.
Okay.
It's pretty decent.
But it's hard to believe that again,
that that's the same dude.
That's the best to do the right thing
guy.
Yeah.
I don't mind guys a switch up like an
ugly girl.
Six.
You can't tell actually.
You can't tell.
Like if you put a bunch of movie posters
up on the wall,
he said which one did angalee direct?
You're like,
they're all different types of movies.
There's hulk,
there's a,
you know,
the,
the brokeback mountain.
And then there's the one that he just
did and like,
they're all different styles.
So I don't mind that.
Is that like he made a movie about
black,
like a black,
like the black soldiers in world war
two.
I think spike Lee,
this shit was horrendous.
I wanted to support the shit.
And I did.
I went to the movie theater,
but I was like,
really?
It wasn't that bad.
It may tell you something.
It was,
it was,
it was bad.
Bad Dialogue is works.
Yeah.
Have like flying the planes and the
shooting at the train from the plains.
Well that was red tails.
Red Tails wasn't that great.
But he didn't make red tails.
That was George Lucas.
Okay.
So his was,
I forgot the name of this shit,
but it's,
it's forgettable.
And I went to the moon with it now,
so I was like,
what the fuck are you doing then?
And it's the same guy that made inside
man an inside man.
It's pretty good movie.
Yeah.
It was pretty good movie.
That was good movie.
But it's like,
yeah,
that was actually one of his better
ones,
but yeah,
this guy,
he's a bad motherfucker.
Yeah.
Life of Pi.
Which you didn't like the story.
I thought the store was ridiculous,
but it was so visually stunning and
impressive that it mostly kept me
occupied.
Especially when you consider the fact
that wasn't even a real tiger like that.
Fuck.
It's like they're so close now,
man.
They're so close to looking like real
animals.
If you go back just five or six years,
they couldn't do that.
They like,
we always talk about that movie.
I am legend.
There's a scene where the lion takes out
the deer and Manhattan Line looks fake.
It looks so fake,
but this tiger looks way real.
And it was in some things.
Yeah,
the whole movie and you know,
the uh,
the visual aspect of the scenery and the
shots that he had.
I mean it was just a brilliantly film
moved to the point where a stupid plot
like didn't stop me from enjoying the
movie because it was so good because I,
it's really when I go to a movie for the
visuals.
Yeah.
And that's exactly what I went for.
I wasn't really counting on the story
either.
Yeah.
I went for the visuals.
It was stunning,
you know,
it was like brokeback mountain had a lot
of visuals too,
and the guy spits in his hand and fix it
on that dude up.
Now Watch this cock right in one stroke
type of visual.
That was a visual like and he knew what
he was doing when he showed the guide.
You showed the guy spitting on his hand
and stuffing in that guy's ass for you.
Just look the idea,
the idea that you get so horny that
you'd be willing to let a dude fuck you
because you're out on the,
on a,
you know,
a cow train for a couple of weeks.
That's a little silly.
Okay,
so leap.
There's a gay dude there and there's a
dude who's Goldbelt fucking got talked
into letting the gay dude fuck them.
That's what happened.
Now,
did she ever hear that video or audio of
Obama has a book called hope and he did
it,
the audio book of it and they ruined and
they.
Somebody took all the cuss words and put
it like edited together and like a quick
little audio clip.
It's so trippy to lists he has cuss
words.
Oh yeah.
And his new book.
Yeah.
Check this out.
This new book,
hope is.
When did this come out?
I don't know.
And this customer.
Yeah,
exactly.
There the white folks and then they're
ignorant.
Motherfuckers like you now you know that
guy in shit.
Sorry,
motherfucker got nothing on me,
right?
Nothing.
What am I bitch Nigga.
By your own damn price.
You said it's way too complicated for me
man.
That's Morgan Friedman.
Lockhart crush a lot of white people's
confidence in him.
That's uh,
that's interesting.
That's interesting that he would do a
book while he's president where he
swears on it and then do the audio
version of it when he smokes weed and
plays basketball.
His first book had crosswords,
right?
Was that his first book had cost?
I don't know if it's from his book.
Hope so.
I'm not sure when that came out,
but the version of the hulk was pretty
fucking good,
man.
That guy,
he did a good job that Eric Bana sucks
the fat one solar in that movie.
That was a movie I went to see when I
was high and I was acting.
This is terrible acting because acting
was bad.
Phoning it in when you're high,
that's when you can really tell.
And by the way that Eric Bana Guy's a
bad motherfucker.
Who's great in that movie chopper.
You ever see that movie chopper?
Nah,
but I seen him at other shit where he
was good,
but in the hall I'm like,
Son,
get out of here.
You are not acting like you're about to
fucking green dots.
It's fake.
It's stupid.
But the new dude who's the new dude that
played the hulk and the x man.
Fuck you mean adventure the avengers.
What's that?
Mark ruffled.
That guy's the best.
He's the best banner they've ever had.
Whether it's David or bruce,
whichever one you want to call.
His name was bruce in the comic book,
but David on television because they
thought Bruce was too gay.
Oh,
for real?
Yeah.
They changed it for the TV show.
The Hawk was different than the comic
book.
Everybody was like,
why isn't he bruce banner now?
He's David Banner.
Different guy.
He's a guy that the guys unassuming and
that's part of my gruffalo.
You really believe that he could be a
scientist to.
Whereas Eric bounty like,
listen,
bitch,
stop it.
Stop it.
You are not a fucking nuclear
scientists.
I just saw you in a.
What was the name of that movie with
Brad Pitt and I believe you.
You're a scientist.
The fuck out of here.
What?
What's his face was pretty decent in it.
What's the little dude's name that was
in American history x.
The other guy that played the whole
call?
Norton.
Yeah,
at Norton.
He's a great actor,
but even in him he just wasn't as good
as that guy that ruffle a guy.
You really believe it when he was about
to into the hulk
is a clear separation.
Yeah.
But he's got a certain kind of crazy to
him.
Yeah.
And it has a certain amount of like,
you know,
like I don't know what it is,
where you,
you accept a guy in a part of what it is
when you don't,
when you're not willing to go with it.
Some people have this overwhelming type
of performance ability that just makes
you,
like,
you just get sucked into it and you
enjoy it.
And there's other people that sort of
Nicholas cage it where you're like,
all right,
just saying the dialogue and moving,
you know,
not that Nicholas Cage is capable of
great performances,
but there's been a few nicholas cage
movies where you're like,
this fucking ghost rider.
This dude does not believe he's the
ghost rider.
All right.
This is just for taxes.
Yeah.
You,
you owe some money that government.
I totally understand.
And I'm not shitting on you man.
I'm just saying.
But there's something dudes that just,
they just lock into a role and you know,
like fuck God.
Damn it was that one dude.
He was in do the right thing.
He looks like a Spanish dude.
Tell him I said John called Esposito.
Yes,
yes,
yes.
Oh,
funny.
Always liked him.
Yeah.
And he ended up,
you know,
you're sitting here man.
That guy can act as fucking ass off that
I can act it
fucking ass off.
Wasn't he in Mo?
Better Blues too?
Wasn't he like part of the band?
They didn't get along so well.
I think he was in school days.
I think it was in a bunch of spike Lee
joints,
but he's one of those dudes that like
when when you see him in a role,
like he can lock onto that fucking
thing,
he can lock on to you believe you
believe he really is pussy whipped to
really believe it.
You know,
some guys can do that.
Denzel Washington obviously can do that.
He can do that in any role and whatever
it is you,
you buy him.
But some dudes you just like,
this motherfucker's playing a vampire or
this motherfucker's plan.
It's fucked up because sometimes it's so
disappointing because you've seen them
in one movie.
Yeah.
Great.
And then this one is like,
man,
I could do that shit.
Yeah,
that's sad.
When you see like Deniro late the later
movies,
like the recent movies and we've seen
any of the recent movies.
Uh,
I try not to just fucking phoning it in.
It's Robert in the Arrow and he's
fucking phone and then you're like,
wow,
this is the man from fucking raging
bull.
If you go back to raging bull and see
what a bad mother fucker,
Robert Deniro was,
you think about like Cape Fear,
how bad ass he was.
It is like enough done.
I'm done.
Give me the check.
Done.
Very.
They say about Al Pachino.
He just yells.
Yeah,
he's like a bad actor.
Yeah.
He's not the same anymore.
I mean,
you go back to like dog day,
afternoon,
man.
Shit.
Yeah.
He had already lost it by the time he
started.
Who?
While in a woman.
That was a great movie.
Jesus Christ.
It's okay.
Like they just gave that to him.
Yeah.
Go back to dog day afternoon and you see
him and his fucking boyfriend who are
robbing a bank to pay for sex change
operation.
I mean,
that is a fucking mean and he's so good
in that movie.
He's so good.
He's so good in so many movies,
man.
It's scarface.
Are you fucking kidding me?
The guy that was in scarface.
I mean,
think about how good he was in that
fucking movie and to go from that to
what you're seeing now.
Come on.
It's like it's a shame.
It's almost always just talk about
comedy and just saw that guy on TV.
Tell them this is rolling the balls.
See how you were talking about shot
fighters.
Fighters.
Sad,
sad,
sad.
Especially when you see Mick Jagger
still slinging Dick like 76 back.
He's out there fucking strutton and
sweating and shit.
That guy with his heart will explode
onstage one day.
Be Perfect.
Perfect way to go out as the best way to
go out.
He's he's performing like I've seen some
of his videos of jagger performing.
He looks like.
I mean if you're not looking at the
lines on his face,
if you look at the way he moves around,
it looks like a guy that's 30,
40 years younger than him.
He's right there.
I mean because he knows he's 70 mixed
emotions.
That mixed emotion song.
I saw a video of him singing it and
dancing it and he's fucking dance
around.
He's doing all that crazy shit that he
used to do as he moves.
Good for like an old dude because I
think Mick Jagger's got to be fucking 65
years old or something.
Now he's up there,
man.
How old is he?
Brian?
You Know Mick Jagger?
If you get.
Let's get.
We'll google it.
Bullets.
Gas.
I say 65 years old.
What he say?
Seventy two 72 77.
Seven 77 77 $77 too high.
Yeah,
that's right.
I'm doing 72 72.
Oh Wow.
I say 65,
right?
That's what I signed.
What do we got here?
What are we going?
Come on mic.
Oh Mick,
how old are you?
Might 69.
God Damn Son.
Jesus fucking Christ.
He's almost 70 years old.
So I think you're the closest now
because he's at work and you went over
it.
What did you get to 72.
Oh,
72.
My father died when he was 69.
Oh my God.
And Mick Jagger is impregnating on stage
and he's still like Finn and fairly
healthy.
God Damn it.
Sixty nine years old.
That makes me feel good because that new
song that they have,
I was kind of joking around about like
they never come out with new material,
new songs.
Pretty fucking good.
Oh that's good.
That's not bad.
Just turn into Jerry Seinfeld right
there.
Why would you say that to do with Brian
would ever disagree with me like that.
That's one of the beautiful things about
being a comic.
Like when you start out like I got to
see Seinfeld on a weekend at governance
and I got to see like on the weekends,
like I would go my home club.
We'll let you go and see.
The headline is,
who's the most impressive guy that you
saw in your open mic days?
Did you like when you're open,
like days,
do you ever paid to see some money and
get rocked a?
We,
they will let us come see,
see them all.
So seinfeld.
I didn't believe in Seinfeld until I saw
him that weekend.
He didn't believe in them.
No,
I didn't because you saw like the
evening at the Improv sets and then he,
I saw him coming rock for an hour and
then I was like,
the five minutes I'm doing that I
killed,
Hae,
just killed harder for an hour.
And like my five minutes ain't shit.
Five minutes wasn't as good as his intro
was when he said Hi.
And then he just rocked for an hour like
that.
And I was like,
yeah,
it's inspiring to want to throw your
shit out,
but you want to tell you shit out every
time you see somebody.
Good.
Yeah.
But you really should throw that shit
out,
you know,
really,
like you're not a bad thing.
Yeah,
you're,
what you're doing is you're sort of
getting a picture,
a greater picture of like where you
stand in the world of comedy really
beginning.
You fucking suck.
You think you're good because you got an
ego,
but you put me fucking suck.
So you need to see a guy like I saw
Richard,
Jenny man and I,
uh,
I paid the Sim because I wasn't in catch
a rising star.
Catch a rising star,
the guy who ran it was a dick.
Oh,
you're such an asshole.
And he wouldn't let me work there.
So I paid you.
Paid the same like night to my open mic
time to see a jenny during the week,
night,
fucking destroyed man.
He killed and he killed so effortlessly
and he did like an hour and a half on
stage and he just kept going and kept
going and kept calling and finally looks
over his watching her show was supposed
to be over about an hour ago.
So,
uh,
I guess I should enzyme,
but uh,
I got nothing better to do it,
so fuck it.
So he just keeps going.
It didn't like another 15 minutes and he
had more material that he did.
Um,
east side comedy club.
Remember that place?
They said that he was there for two
nights,
two shows a night and he did a different
hour every show and crushed and crushed.
And by the way,
it was constantly writing.
You get off the stage,
fucking write down on a Napkin back of
this hotel.
I mean,
it was constantly coming up with new
material.
That dude was a man.
He's one of my favorite comics ever.
People don't realize how good he was.
I saw that guy at the comedy works in
Montreal and um,
that,
you know,
you ever do that place?
Yeah.
The room upstairs,
Jemma was place.
Oh,
that place is magic.
It's like another one,
like the Boston comedy club seats 100
people at the most.
I'm going to be there in March.
I'm doing the club in March with fear.
Oh,
you are?
Yeah.
Because last time I did it,
I did it a few months ago.
I did a big theater in Montreal.
I'm like,
I don't wanna like go to a theater and
then go to another theater like four
months later.
That seems rude.
Asking people to come see you again
later.
I do.
So I am working on some new shit anyway.
So I liked,
I liked doing like little clubs you want
to go?
Yeah.
Well I'll bring it up to a um,
the other one in Vancouver,
Vancouver's going to be crazy.
We're working on that.
But uh,
what was my point once they saw Jenny at
the car,
I saw him up there in the,
uh,
the comedy works and it was during the
festival and a bunch of us went upstairs
just to see his set because we wanted
to,
like we heard Jenny was going on at
10:00
and went up there to CSI and he fucking
destroyed with he talk about anything he
was talking about buying a car.
He's talking about going to a car dealer
and you know,
the guy offered him a bunch of shit that
he didn't ask for,
you know,
like,
but I didn't want that and that's why I
didn't like we'd come up with a bunch of
funny shit that he would say to the guy
and this and that.
And Are you the guy that does.
And we were dying,
dying.
And I remember thinking I had never
heard any of these bits before.
He's fucking killing.
And He,
in my opinion,
didn't get the respect that he deserved.
He wanted to be like a movement stopping
that bugged them,
fucked them like crazy because being on
the road apparently he would get like
real snotty with people on the road,
like you would work in clubs.
And I think with a lot of guys,
it's a prestige thing.
They don't feel respected if they have
to do the road.
Like he said something once I remember
this goes up.
I knew how much,
uh,
I was going to do the road.
I wouldn't be living in La.
I moved to La because I thought I was
going to do TV.
Like you were saying that it was like,
do you know that you're Richard?
Jenny,
do you understand that most comics,
like they'll step back and go,
like,
there's a master that's master guy just
walked in.
The guy that's about to go on stage,
watch what he does because that is a
master at crafting and delivering comedy
material.
He was over being Richard Jeni.
He's,
yeah.
He's like looking at Seinfeld and all
his peers and their success and it's
like,
it's tough to look and see how it's
problem.
You really are.
That's it will eat away at you because
like you said,
like a different hour every night at the
east side comedy club and he did a lot
of specials.
Yeah.
And it just didn't get to where he felt
he could have.
Yeah,
I guess so man.
I don't know.
I think that his,
in his mind,
if you want to do in movies,
have,
you weren't doing a big hit series.
You were a failure,
you know,
for,
for whatever reason.
That's how he looked at it.
And when he was 49 it was when he
committed suicide.
I guess he just got to that point where
it was like,
you know,
he just couldn't imagine it getting any
better.
He's not going to become a movie star at
50 and just couldn't fucking take it
anymore.
But as a comic man mean he was a fuck is
wrong.
It's just one of the best I've ever
seen.
Who's a great comment.
The good thing is I met him before he
died.
He,
he was coming to the laugh factory and
he is friends with Jamie said,
I got to say hi like a few times.
No long conversations really,
but I didn't tell him how.
I ain't going to have to tell them how
funny the fuck he was.
It was a very,
very funny comic man.
He,
uh,
I ran into him a couple of weeks before
he died.
We were on a plane together going to
Austin,
just just randomly.
He was sitting in front of me and I was
like,
hey man,
what's going on?
What are you doing?
I'm going to do a private gig.
I'm going to do cap city.
He was doing a corporate gig or
something like that.
You've seen.
Does it seem exuberant?
But it seemed like normal.
Richard.
Jenny.
He was always friendly to me.
I had heard weird things about
them,
but to me he was always friendly.
But he did five comedy specials.
Tan from.
Yeah,
from 92 to 2005.
He did five of them.
He did to showtime specials.
Crazy from the heat and boy from New
York City.
The boy from New York City,
it was probably the best one.
That was the first one.
That was the first one that came out.
He came out guns blazing in 1990.
That was a.
That was a fucking killer special.
I remember.
I can always tell by friends who aren't
Comedians,
how they react and my friend guy who
used to own executive billiards in white
plains,
New York,
he's just fucking fabulous guy.
His name is guy as a reading,
but he was a piano player so he changed
his name.
That Guy Hamilton,
because people get nervous with that
Kenny shit or if they don't want to hire
a guy as a to come over your house.
They up because he was like,
he had like nice watches.
He always had like a nice ring and nice
clothes on.
I might trust.
Okay.
And everything's Nice.
So he comes into the pool hall.
He goes,
I saw this fucking guy.
Richard Jenny's,
he's the funniest guy on earth.
He must be the funniest guy on earth.
And I was like,
he's probably one of them,
man.
He's right up there.
And he was just about this boy from New
York City special.
That was like,
yeah,
like 1990,
1991.
And then he did three hbo specials on
top of that.
He did a platypus man in [inaudible] 92.
So he did two comedy specials in 92.
That's how gangster.
Is that the same year?
Yes,
he did two.
He did.
Platypus.
Man.
And he did crazy from the heat,
both of them in [inaudible] 92.
Then he did a good Catholic boy in
[inaudible] 97 and a big steaming pile
of me in 2005,
which is still good.
It was still even that.
But he went on.
That was a long stretch.
He went eight years without a,
without doing a special
thinking about try to copy those and
check them out again.
I just remember like the bit when he's
talking about a football referee,
like during the call and then it was,
you know,
player offside,
blah blah blah blah.
Then he started getting personal and
then last week,
I can't remember who said it,
but he ended up like laying on the
stage,
like having a casual conversation with
them at a stadium full of people.
And this is the balls at him to just lay
on stage and take that joke as far as
ticket.
That shit was like he would,
he would take shit like really far.
That was one of the things I learned
from him.
That's one of the things I learned from
him.
Yeah.
I learned that from him because he
would,
he would go like my jokes at the time
were like,
really?
You like rudimentary.
They were like,
look,
a little clunky wheels that I'd made out
of like,
you know,
out of a piece of wood.
They were one very sophisticated and
that I would watch him and I would watch
how he would take a subject and explore
every possible angle.
And when he did that,
it made it so much funnier.
Right.
And then I realized like,
Oh,
I'm not doing that.
Like I'm not exploring things far
enough.
And now to this day when I watch a on
stage
and he keeps going with a bit,
I enjoy it more.
Like when you were doing a bit the other
day that I was dying laughing on man.
The difference between how many white
bankers rob people and how many black
dudes with hoodies and the black dude
with hoodies,
Robert things because he's got to pay
the white bag or like damn,
I got to play these bags and you take
it,
you know,
you take it really far,
you keep going and going and going and
going with it and as it goes on and on
and on it becomes funnier.
And as a,
as a comic,
like I know that already,
you know,
like sort of as a way of operating,
but to see it,
I like to see it
sometimes we forget what we know.
Yeah.
And then like,
like somebody told me that about me and
I was like,
Oh shit,
I do do that because sometimes you
forget what,
what makes you operate.
Like I remember being a comic,
like an early comic and then pipe man,
I need more topics so I can have more
jokes and then it hit me later on.
I don't need more topics.
I just need to explore the topics that I
have more.
Yeah.
It's not about how many topics I have,
it's how many like how much I can milk
something.
Yeah.
And it,
it becomes better,
it comes better and then,
you know,
once you have the crowd rolling out a
joke and you keep hitting them,
you don't have to set anything up.
Everything is a joke.
It's like it's almost like a boxing
match.
Your work in the volume work in the body
and they're bending over and now I can
hit them in the head.
You can knock them out
and then sometimes you milk it too much
and you've got to back off that shit.
Like sometimes you're like,
alright,
gotta change.
You learn.
You know,
sometimes somebody has the whisper
something into a tape recorder.
Fuck.
But sometimes you,
uh,
you know,
that's the only way to come up with new
angles to explore.
Like that's one of the cool things about
doing a small club is that you can fuck
around Brown and a small club way better
than you can in a giant theater when
you're in a giant theater.
Like for the most part you kind of doing
a show like I'll fuck around a little
bit,
but for the most part you're doing a
show you give,
you give the people what they paid for.
Yeah.
But I still let leave room to fuck
around.
Right.
You have to.
And when I did my,
uh,
the end of the world show at the wiltern
and down was like a big show for me
because it was like,
it was a honey honey the band,
which I think are great.
The,
they're good friends,
they'd be on the podcast many times.
They did like 20 minutes and then Joey
Diaz does like close to a half an hour I
guess.
And then Stan hope does close to an
hour.
He did 15 minutes,
so the whole show's like an hour and you
know,
30,
40 minutes long before I even get up on
stage.
Yeah.
But they were so good that right away,
like the crowd was so good that right
away I was fucking around and I came up
with a whole new bit,
like onstage in the moment,
just riffed a whole new bit.
And then I remember like I got to get
home and listen to that one because
there was a lot like that was a lot of
shit.
I just thought of,
you know,
because when you're doing a bit and it's
killing sometimes you'll just think on
the spot.
Oh yeah.
And then you could,
why wouldn't you just do that?
Yeah.
And then just go with it.
But sometimes it doesn't work.
Sometimes you,
like,
you come up with a new thing for a bit.
You've been doing for a minute.
You know what took me so long to think
of this shit.
Like,
alright,
how stupid am I?
I didn't see that in front of my
friends.
And then the worst is when you record a
bit and then after it's done on a CD or
a special,
you have a new tagline for it,
you know,
it's too late.
That's Hedberg actually did a joke on
two separate cds and he goes,
yeah,
this joke is on my first album,
but I added something to tell you like
what party added.
I'm paraphrasing,
I don't remember how you signed up,
but he's one of my favorites ever to
listen to like in the car cause and
squeaky clean.
Hedberg squeaky clean.
You could play it in front of your
mother.
Like he might say what the fuck man.
He might say that every now and again,
like very rarely,
but like the content of his material was
just observational humor that was just
ridiculous.
You know,
he would make you stoned.
You would feel stone.
Listen to Mitch Hedberg,
you know,
jazz comedy and Shit.
Yeah.
Somebody asked me if I wanted a frozen
banana.
I said no,
but I want a regular banana later.
So yeah.
Yes.
So stupid.
If you saw that written down on paper,
it's like,
that seems like,
like a line that would be in a
children's book,
you know,
it sounds Dr.
Seuss's,
but coming out of him it was hilarious.
He just,
he was just such a fun guy to listen to
this and then that's a perfect example
of like comedy,
like being like something dudes have a
style and it don't make any sense that
you couldn't do it and I couldn't do it
that way,
but for him,
Bam.
That's it.
Shit.
He knows he knocks out of the park with
that style.
It's weird.
That's comedy is the only art form I
think where you really making your own
instrument,
you know,
you're like,
you're like everybody who plays the
guitar,
you're playing a guitar.
I guess if you're singing,
you make your own different kinds of
noises with your mouth.
But the styles of comedy very so fucking
wildly like when you're trying to piece
it together.
So much uncertainty in the beginning.
So it makes me mad when people aren't
trying to make their own instruments and
you're listening to me like what?
You're wasting this opportunity.
Yeah.
Well there's a lot of uh,
imitation in the beginning and then you
really,
I found myself imitating Richard Jenny
once I was on stage.
It was probably like a year in two,
maybe two.
I was still living in Boston and I was
like doing a bit and I was doing a bit
the way I thought,
like Richard Tray would do a bit like,
as I was saying it,
I was realizing I was like,
oh,
it's so gross.
Like I knew I was influenced by him
because I was like,
I would see him and I go,
man.
I was like figuring out how to be funny
like that.
But to actually like here you imitate
them coming out of your mouth.
Some people get like super sensitive
about that shit.
I was talking to somebody last night and
uh,
I think like there's one female con is
this female comics.
She sounds like Sarah Silverman and I
think Sarah Silverman stitches.
She was like,
man,
I don't see with ms dot always kinda
cold with me.
And in my mind I'm like best because you
sound like Sarah Silverman.
This is a chick that sounds exactly like
a felicia Michael's.
I mean I don't know who she is,
but he wasn't Felicia Michael's.
And I was like,
wow,
that's not felicia Michael's.
That's crazy.
Like the sound of the voice,
the delivery,
the pacing.
It was like she was a big Felicia.
Michael's checked or Swagger Jack.
Jack the Art Kalitta and shit.
Does Kelly,
Jeff,
they say he took a joe style.
Oh yeah.
Really?
Yeah.
Did he piss on girls too?
Nah,
he added that.
That was.
Well,
you know,
he added his own thing.
So twists,
take,
take all the game.
Yeah.
They are Kelly videos of him pissing on
that girl or like how did that guy get
off?
And it didn't.
It didn't even put a scratch in his
career.
He came back stronger than ever.
Black people lie to me.
I'll tell you,
that was going on.
First of all,
you know,
the funny thing is I went to a viewing
party where a friend called a bunch of
black friends over and we watched the
video with his wife and we had food and
we watched the,
the,
the art.
Kelly secretary.
Kelly sex tape.
What kind of funny it was just,
it was just,
you know,
they're all comic mind.
So it was fun,
but then everybody that I met that was
black,
they was like,
we done with him with done with him in a
fucking,
you can't build,
you can't do that.
Then.
Then the album after that,
the chocolate factory,
because number one,
it doesn't even with no radio play.
And I'm like,
I thought y'all said we was done with
him.
I was,
I was with y'all.
Nah,
we ain't done.
What is it about him that he's got such
teflon skin when it comes to
controversy,
that shit is unexplainable to me,
but I'm not mad at it.
He seems so confident.
No matter what happens.
He seems like,
like no problems but just going to get
through this.
He's got a me.
I didn't get on that girl.
I was like,
what?
Like that real talk song.
I know you've seen that song when you
watch that Bill Thompson.
Yeah.
When he,
when he's in the nice talking to the
beginning,
you know,
got,
got was stoic.
He's about to jump off.
You're like,
this is not a smart guy,
but this guy has figured out a way to
carve a career through the some of the
craziest
controversy ever,
but as that humbled him.
No Bitch,
I wish you would burn my mother fucking
clothes.
I mean,
Shit.
He says we'll talk.
I mean,
he's not backing off of this at all.
Like I like,
I just don't have an issue with Lindsay
Lohan.
Right?
Like all this shit,
all the shit that she gets into.
Then I realized,
listen,
if I was her and I could get away with
all that shit,
why would I stop?
I think it's for her though.
I mean there's new outlet.
Like people are saying online that she's
like a high price hooker now and that's
what they're saying on websites.
Like this guy paid her like $100,000
to spend the night with him and I know
celebrity girls that do that though.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You know,
they tell you.
No.
I know.
I got a friend who works for a really
rich dude and if he wants to fuck a
celebrity,
it's almost like a.
You know how Jenny was doing that
corporate show?
It's just like that.
We'll fly you into the island.
How many celebrities do this?
Quite a few.
I think really more than you think,
man.
I really like,
like what level?
Celebrity.
They do a Steven Seagal movie and you
know,
it doesn't look to be in the sequel from
there,
up from there,
up here,
from there up.
So how does it work?
Like the guy like watches TV,
like calling us bitch.
Yeah.
Basically.
And how much does he offered them a
figure.
But you sorta.
You're sorta bar at movie.
I did not see the boy.
Boy,
they didn't see Bruno.
Bruno.
What's the dictator?
A dictator.
Dictatorship.
Like who do you have?
Megan?
Megan Fox,
Megan Fox.
And he pays her and she leaves and he
takes a photo with her,
puts on the wall in the camera,
pulls out and it's all celebrity
pitches.
So it's like he's done this with every
stolid.
There's some shit that happens up there.
How does a fucking agent even call you
with that?
Say if you are Megan Fox and let's just
go with Megan Fox because she was an
example using that movie.
If that's real,
how does that even get to you?
How does that get to your desk?
How does that offer you know how it
might get to you from another famous
celebrity chick who already did it?
Who already did it?
So listen girl,
I think she's.
Because what I did this weekend,
transformer two's didn't pay that much
money,
but look at your car,
which you should see my house.
Fuck this dude for 50 minutes.
How did you get $50?
Million.
50 million to a trillionaire.
Ain't nothing that didn't make sense.
A couple of weeks.
He paid a couple of weeks.
Our to Megan Fox in the ass especially
goes asked her mouth.
I'm not going to just clean her out and
just put her mouth is cleaner out.
I mean look 50 million to to assault
number ny.
I.
That ain't shit.
It's
nothing.
I bet it really.
I mean,
it's probably doesn't spend it that
often,
but you remember when that thing broke
where there was a girl,
I think she was a penthouse pet or
something along those lines.
She was writing a story about her time
with the sultan of Brunei.
She was ratting out all the other girls
and there was all these different girls
were like.
Some of them were models,
some of them were porn stars and he
would just decide I want that one,
that one,
and he liked the agency would bring them
all the girls to him and he would pay
them extravagant amounts of money,
like hundreds of thousands of dollars.
He'd give them jewelry like really like
insane amounts of money in in jewelry,
like hundreds of thousands of dollars in
gold and diamonds and shit like that and
he just would keep a giant private Harem
and you keep them there for a few months
or six months,
whatever the fuck it is and these girls
would go back to la and just live like
ball players.
Now all of a sudden that this chick has
400 grand in the bank or something crazy
like that and so they had to like lie
about what they were doing.
Oh,
we were modeling in Bahrain.
Meanwhile they just couldn't fucking
trains right on them by the salt and all
his boys.
The sultan parties and shit like that.
Yeah.
They say he has a.
He has like a whole disco in his house,
like a giant lavishly appointed club and
he hires all these girls.
Happens all the time.
I hear it all the time from the girls.
So I got offered again to do it.
I'm not doing that shit.
How much is you offer them A.
I don't know.
I didn't really get into the same guy.
Or is it different guys?
I think it's different guys,
but there's like all these different
deals were like,
I hear all the time.
People are like,
I can't get offered,
but I'm not done do that.
The guys are not a bad guy.
You know?
He seems like a nice guy and you
wouldn't mind fucking them for
$50,000,000.
It's not gonna.
You're not gonna beat me,
I don't think it's 50 million I think
made a $10,000
range,
but can you imagine seeing like the
black book of like somebody like the
president of paramount or whatever and
like seeing like what the celebrities
are for sure.
That,
that are also like would like Taylor
swift one,
but she has conditions.
She's allowed to write a song about it
later.
Like Taylor Swift,
she will write a song about your.
Especially if she doesn't.
If she breaks up with you,
she'll still wrote a song about the
Salton Song.
We know what she did.
You think you're the king.
You might be the king of a small desert
country with a lot of natural resources,
but you don't have apathy back and
forth.
Hey,
ruined my whole country.
Taylor swift song.
She's got those little cute pouty lips.
You just want to turn his song pop.
I'm wonder what is the highest level of
celebrity that's been paid to fuck?
Like a prince.
Like one of those Saudi Arabian dudes
were just stupid cat.
Like the CALC.
I think it goes all the way up to the
top.
I think really,
I think,
I think we're given like female top
celebrities.
Too much credit.
Really?
Yes.
Wow.
Strong words from Ian Edwards would have
to agree with that 100 percent really?
Because you know,
it's like women,
like an adventure man.
They'll do that shit.
Why Venture?
They do it for money.
Actresses important stories are very
similar.
Are they really getting paid to do
whatever the fuck,
you know,
like it's money.
It's like,
what?
I'll get that for that to do this.
Okay.
One time.
The Sultan of Brunei,
his girls.
There's A.
Yeah,
there's a whole fucking.
There's a bunch of different stories
about it.
The swinging salt.
Who's telling the truth?
Let's say there's a question.
Is it the girls?
You can't trust those girls either
because if the girls want to fuck a guy
from money,
she'll probably make lies up about it.
But if a chicken describe inside the
castle or wherever that in there
was like.
Yeah.
I don't know man.
I don't know the guy,
the guy obviously without a doubt.
Obviously his paid some chicks for
pussy.
Okay.
He's got something like a trillion
dollars.
So when you're just a regular looking
dude and you got a trillion dollars and
you're like,
how much you're gonna have to pair,
and then you just decide,
like put together your own disco in your
house.
Fucking why not,
man?
Yeah.
What's the problem?
He,
uh,
apparently he owns the Beverly Hills
Hotel and it has home in Las Vegas.
He claimed exemption from us to
jurisdiction as a foreign head of state.
So they were trying to bring him.
They're suing him.
Who's sewing them?
Some woman,
some woman who,
uh,
he,
was uh,
trying to fuck.
This is a story her,
her name is.
She's a former Miss USA.
Her name is,
uh,
let's just say her name is Shannon.
We don't have to say her full name.
You can google it if you want.
We want defame her publicly.
Let's call her country.
And it got hired and she says she
innocently accepted a $3,000
a day assignment in Brunei for personal
appearances and promotional work in the
company of six other American women.
She alleges she was made to dance
nightly from 10 till 3:00
AM,
groped and called a whore.
She was barred from leaving the country.
She alleges when she refused to
prostitute herself,
she was not raped,
nor apparently did she have sex with
anyone.
Instead,
this devout Christian girl from Malibu
is suing for mental anguish,
nightmares,
difficulty sleeping,
and other trauma.
Although she never claimed to have met
the salt in or his brother.
Wow.
She never even met the salt and she
didn't even get that far.
You gotta go through all those other
boys.
You got to be proven that you're down.
You DTF.
She was allegedly forced onto to be a
private dancer in his palace grounds and
did not like it.
One bit.
Her lawsuit is laden with phrases such
as white slavery and Human Chattel.
Chattel means.
Yeah.
What is c h a t t e l l or c h a
t t e l.
What does that mean?
This is from 1997 by the way.
This is before the Internet.
So I guess,
um,
she put,
uh,
a lawsuit out,
but he's a,
he's exempt.
He doesn't have to,
uh,
he doesn't have to appear and deal with
all the bullshit.
It sounds to me like she thought that
she was going to be smarter than that
and she wasn't gonna have to fuck them.
It was probably pretty obvious.
You getting paid 3000 bucks a night.
It's either that or she's insulted.
She didn't get to fuck the prince.
Prince.
Yeah.
To deal with these underlings.
I didn't even meet them.
That's probably exactly what it is.
She probably thought she would play him.
You know,
there's a lot of chicks that have a
ridiculous amount of confidence.
Like,
I'm going to be the one.
I need to see the salt and have you to
see the Salton.
I'm not getting $3,000
a night to dance for you.
I am not like these regular checks.
I'm better.
Yeah.
I need to meet the salted.
I wonder how many he has in his Harem.
Why Brian Stop you stopped with that
number seven.
Fucking try to insert that everywhere.
You think that's cute.
How many things he has.
I mean if you were going to rock it like
that,
would you go with 20?
I was being honest.
No,
I'd probably.
It's probably something small and not
too crazy,
but not too little.
Not too little for 14 is good.
14.
Do you think there's too many?
You would like seven.
If you had,
let's say,
Brian,
if you had a billion dollars
I would have around seven,
but all different.
Like I one black,
one Asian,
one purple,
whatever.
But here's the thing.
You've got to think about.
Seven is good for you,
but anybody that has anything that they
like,
they want to show it off.
So you're going to have the boys over
and you're gonna throw some parties
apparently at any given time.
He had more than 40 girls.
Forty Hugh hefner.
Usually.
How many did he rocked for a while?
Just kind of married the son before love
before that he had like,
he had like how many girlfriends he at
one time he had like seven girlfriends
or something like that.
I Dunno,
I don't.
Uh,
I think that was the story,
but I think a lot of them was acting,
you know,
it was like he was like putting on this
act.
I always thought the,
that's why I made that whole bit about
him.
I always thought that I was kind of
gross.
It was like,
it was like this,
like look at me,
I've got my smoking jacket on.
It was like so contrived,
all of it and the girls would all tell
stories about how the fuck other guys
and try to sneak out and that they are,
a lot of them had boyfriends and shit
and,
or one of them is to come to the comedy
store and she would just tell horrible
things about what it was like.
He had to watch gay porn and it's like
Weird Shay had to watch gay porn.
He would watch it.
Like he would watch gay porn.
He had a,
he had a lot of gay experiences.
Book talks all about it.
Yeah.
Some girl wrote a tell all book about
how he looks watching gay porn things in
his ass and shit.
Yeah.
Apparently at one point in time he had
like a lot of those dudes in the
sixties,
they,
they tried fucking dudes for a little
while.
They were like,
try gay.
Just fucking dudes.
That happened.
A lot of guys gave that a shot.
It was like sort of like this,
this idea of rebelling completely
from the roles,
the gender roles that were established
by our parents who obviously were wrong
about everything else.
Was it the rat pack that started it?
Are seen as more like dudes who took
acid?
See,
I think we were on acid.
You wouldn't want to do it,
but like if you're hanging out with
Sammy and all the guys and getting drunk
and you know,
playing around with sticks.
Visual Sammy,
show us that black truck.
That's why you're here.
Show us that black cock and dense you
son of a bitch.
Let me suck it out.
Suck it off.
Well that's good.
Crazy.
No,
like,
you know,
like David Bowie was it make Jagger's
wife or David Bowie's wife.
One of them claimed that they had caught
David Bowie and Mick Jagger in bed
together getting their frequency,
everything so totally.
I think a lot of dudes back then did
that.
They all look at an interview of either
of them,
like on Saturday night live when they
just are guests.
They always have that vibe like,
hey,
had the gun.
I tell him what to do with that.
Don't have that bug.
You just made that up.
They don't list.
You're so ridiculous.
That version of homosexuality was so
fucking stereotypes.
They don't happen to American list real
quick and then I'll.
Which guy?
David Bowie or Mick Jagger.
What are you gonna look them up.
Well,
you can show them.
Don't want to do it because they don't
get banned off of you two.
Don't get banned off of Youtube.
We're uploading some stuff off on the
youtube and if we do anything that has
like a video that you know,
it's a clip from a movie or some shit,
they'll get mad at us.
It was certainly,
definitely.
I was going to play the Mick Jagger
Saturday night live skit where it's
just,
if anybody knows,
um,
I think there's a way where you can pay
a certain amount of money every month
and use music like as bumpers and stuff
like that and use it and the,
the artists get paid.
I need to know what the best quality or
the best services for that.
If such a thing exists where the artists
actually get compensated,
it must exist.
I think it would be nice if we could
find something like that where we could
know that when,
you know,
if we pay a certain amount of month,
we could play songs every now and
probably limited to like,
oh,
you can only play warner brothers songs,
you know,
it will be.
Then it'd be just like,
what the fuck?
Well we'll be in less.
We've paid for more than one service,
which I'm willing to do.
I'll pay you.
I'll pay for every service there is.
We could play everybody's shit.
I mean if it's only a few hundred
dollars a month or whatever it is a
month,
I don't know.
Would like like,
why am I looking at a man's butt wiggle
back and forth?
Is that supposedly the reason why that's
entertaining with women is because it's
sexual.
Okay.
When you see a woman shaking her ass
back and forth,
you look at that and you go,
fuck that.
When you see a man's,
but in the band sticking his butt
outlet,
that is equally sexual and sexual in a
submissive homo sexual way,
Jesus,
her beds,
this type of behavior,
and you wonder why there's a meteor
shower scheduled for tonight.
That's gay as fuck,
man.
That might be the gaze video on the
Internet.
Yeah,
that's pretty up there.
It just implies a lot of gay sex.
Do you guys think Paul Mccartney ever
had sex with Michael Jackson?
I don't think it's.
You know,
I heard the most compelling and haunting
idea about Michael Jackson was that he
was castrated.
I think I heard that before.
That's a fucked up thing because the
idea is,
and this is some crazy horse shit.
Okay.
I don't even want to entertain this
other than the fact that there's things
called [inaudible] and pull this up
because,
um,
you want to hear some of this.
The castrati is a specific type of
performer that is castrated,
[inaudible] to achieve a certain pitch
because it's a man,
a male pitch mixed with the way a woman
Castrati like castrate,
not cal cal zone.
Yeah.
Castrati.
These were famous.
See that thing.
That is the thing that guys holding up
that they're making fun of Justin Bieber
there saying he's a Castrati,
but in effect it's a very similar type
of sound that Justin Bieber makes
because Justin bieber's sound is made
because he doesn't have any.
Just astro and was young.
This guy has a clipper that he's holding
up and that is the actual tool that they
used to use to cut your fucking balls
off to make you sing different and you
would develop like this real kind of
like halfway feminine way of looking.
And they were Unix essentially,
but they did it on purpose to make them
sound a certain way when they sang.
And it's really fucking hard to believe
that that's real,
but it is.
And if you,
if you google it,
I'm like,
sounds of a Castrati,
you can hear them singing and it's so.
It's a weird fucking.
It's a weird sound that they do,
man.
The thing,
Michael Jackson,
they one thing with him,
like when he was up for that trial and
the cops arrested him,
like when the plane landed and you
complain about how they handled him,
search dominated,
touched his penis.
But um,
if his balls was admitted,
having a penis back there,
if they were extracted,
castrating doesn't mean they cut your
dick off the ball.
They cut your balls off and they don't
even have to cut your balls off.
They can just snip them and pulled a
little fucking little sperm makers out
of there.
And then the testosterone
production essentially done.
Look at my face as you're seeing this
Chili.
But it's an unbelievable thing in the
whole entire world.
Look at,
this is fucking crazy.
They used to do this to babies.
They used to do this to kids before
puberty so that they can achieve that
sort of sound.
Yeah,
it's really.
The baby can sing.
Well,
they teach them how to sing.
Gee.
Yeah.
Seventy percent.
And this is during the Baroque period.
Seventy percent of all opera singers see
where Castrati 70 percent of them were
young boys that they took and cut their
fucking balls off to.
This is between 1,617
50.
Luciano,
Australia,
they,
they comprise 70 percent of all operatic
singers and that nuts.
That's bananas.
That is,
that is fucking terrifying,
man.
Check this out.
Look how Larry says we accepted this
back in the eighties because everyone
loved Michael Jackson so much,
but it was like,
look at this muscular guy and then we
are supposed to believe that Michael
Jackson is having an arm wrestling
competition in this guy and wins.
Oh yeah.
That doesn't make any sense.
There's got magic.
Yeah.
He's supposed to be magic.
What the fuck?
That's just stop and think about that
man.
Seventy percent of all their fucking
opera singers were castrated.
What a weird time in history.
That must've been around for centuries,
the 16 hundreds,
1600 to 1750.
It's called the Baroque period that mean
that is so fucking hard to wrap your
head around man,
and apparently it was devastating for
their,
their emotions like they were crazy.
They fought,
they suffered.
The effects of development or
developmental hypogonadism develop
developmental hypogonadism including
infant tile,
penis and the underdeveloped prostate.
They also had more developed
subcutaneous fat and the normal male fat
deposits local last on the hips,
buttocks and breasts areas,
fatty deposits on the eyelids and skin
that sometimes appeared wrinkled or
swollen because they had no testosterone
ever.
The arms,
the legs of many Castrati were unusually
long as compared to their torso.
The long bones never stopped growing,
which made them look distorted.
Wow,
that's nuts,
man.
Lot of personality disorders.
It's creative.
You got to pull some of the sound up.
They'll pull some quotes
of what?
Oh,
you mean people trust strati singer.
Even if the operation like,
no,
I don't.
I mean,
that sounds like he was too skinny to be
a cast.
A cast rate,
a person.
It sounds like if they contain that much
fat,
they hold that much fat.
It wouldn't be real unless he had the
money to get perfect tits and shit like
that.
I don't think that's it.
I think,
uh,
the ideas that he,
he,
even when you take someone's balls,
that's it.
There's no more balls.
Go.
Go to Castrati singing on a,
on youtube.
Another thing about Michael Jackson,
like the people that I know that norm
said he had a deep voice.
What?
Never heard that what?
Like yeah man,
get the fuck out of my house.
Was his,
that was his,
like public voice like that.
But it made me like,
Yo,
what's up man?
How you doing real?
I swear to God.
I met several people.
Told me that shit.
Imagine Michael Jackson was yelling at
you.
Get Out of my house.
You're like,
what?
Did you find it?
This is not real.
Brian.
Stop.
That's a movie.
You got to get a real castrati.
Go to,
uh,
Alessandra Maurecio dot the last cross
Toronto.
He was,
that's actually a biography.
That's a film about a real life
customer.
Oh.
So it's like a biopic.
Yeah.
Well I was just.
I just wanted to get the original sound.
There's a dude from 18,
58.
He was one of the last one.
He's got a beautiful face.
I don't think he's Kinda fat faced.
Were pitching for the pushing.
This is a.
This is that movie again.
This is not real.
This is actually just the audio or the
audio supposedly.
Only have the audio.
Okay.
Let's hear this shit.
16,
14.
How do they have recordings from 16,
They made records back then.
No,
it was a famous castrati throughout
history.
That's what this is.
This is a real castrati voice over
images of famous Castrati is because
they didn't have records back then,
man.
When was the first record?
I think as the 20th century.
When was the first record made?
Siri.
Nineteen.
Oh,
three.
Hmm.
No,
I'm Thomas Edison recorded his voice on
a piece of tin foil and 18 slash 77.
Wow.
In 18,
89,
Edison and Columbia began to sell signal
cylinders in 18,
92 berlinger berliner began to sell
disks.
So it looks like the 18 hundreds.
So play it,
play that shit and this,
listen to this.
This is a guy with no balls and then in
2000,
10 hours listening to Taylor swift,
but that's a girl.
Girls do shit for girls,
man.
Imagine being a girl living in this
crazy world
kind of give them,
given their bullshit.
It's a strange sound.
You know what?
Where's that guy?
That's a drawing.
That's how stupid they are.
They didn't have
cameras.
These dumb asses.
The pictures of these people.
You don't know what the fuck that first.
That was.
That was what you did back then.
He had someone draw you like,
yes.
That is what it looked like.
They barely had mirrors these dummies.
Chop and balls off.
I think they knew what the fuck was up.
Joe Pesci,
Giovanni,
Giovanni Ngud only he'd have an old d.
Oh,
guide down guadalupe and Fed Nando's.
10 Duci.
What a shock that the Catholics are the
ones that are kind of kids calls off.
It's very fucking psychos.
Other faces look like they just smelled
a fart.
Those are grandmother Peci d,
no bowls.
But listen to my voice.
Domenico Bodine.
Seventeen 81 to question mark,
maybe still alive,
not zero
Zuni.
The Zuni Luigi much use.
It's an amazing thing that this famous
Castrati.
What can you imagine giving your son to
someone to hack his balls off so he
could sing in a weird way.
People were so poor back then.
It was like this.
The only way out God like opera was like
white people's basketball like that.
But you have a chance to be a
construction from Nike camp.
You know the customer already put spot
was a Nike camp is so fucking funny.
Dude.
White People's basketball from the 16
hundreds.
Singing is the way I like the way out
has changed so many times with different
races,
like whatever it was the viable way.
Like you just have a kid,
you can't take care of them.
You're like,
here Andrew,
my son and hopefully you can sing and
fight and shit and it's like put them in
this farm of like kids raising them and
somebody is feeding them in.
This hopefully will be the one that
turns out to be one of these.
Gets a painting.
It's just Michael Jackson's.
Remember when he stopped playing Mrs
Pepsi Commercial,
but remember when the commercials were
even amazing,
like you'd like the Pepsi Cola.
He had his brothers along with him too.
He brought the Jackson five.
They were like,
yeah,
we're still in this together,
but after a while it's not really.
Oh my gosh.
I wonder if this is going to.
Yeah,
he's the one that's the fresh prince of
Broadway.
Wow.
Look at this.
Can you ever break dance?
Like singing?
You're the Pepsi generation and he's
singing it as Billie Jean.
It's so gross.
It's so gross that Pepsi gave her enough
money to do this kid's wearing
sweatpants.
You can address up a little,
but it's the same.
I'm guaranteed we're going to get
flagged for this because it's the same
song.
The same fucking beat.
It's the same song.
So much doubt it,
man.
I bet.
We're looking at waving.
Goodbye and weird when you go back and
see that shit,
isn't it?
Yeah.
I looked back at how they were
addressing,
especially since like I think it was
right before this or after this.
They burned him,
you know,
they burned my wiring is the commercial.
That's right.
They did fucked up.
Hey Man,
they killed Michael for that because
right after that happened,
that's when all the pills happened and
all the shit where he's,
you know,
depression.
And yeah,
it was because of that commercial and
him getting in so much pain and being
prescribed painkillers is what
supposedly brought down this whole
entire Michael Jackson from like getting
into drugs and all this shit.
And they still use the footage and the
Pepsi commercial.
I listened.
I believe
I've told you stories of several people
that I know that God on pain pills from
her back's.
I know a pool player who did it,
but he had a hurt back.
It's dude was like super squeaky
healthy,
didn't smoke cigarettes,
didn't drink.
He got all these fucking pain pills.
He hurt his back and they got him hooked
and he was done.
He became a fucking straight degenerate
loser.
People tell stories about him falling
asleep in his mashed potatoes.
Just literally falling asleep face
forward and mashed potatoes.
And uh,
I have someone close to my family that
have that regular guy,
regular job,
hurt his back on the job,
got on pain pills,
dawn just fucked his two chapters in his
life because pre pain pills and then
there's post pain pills and post pain
pills.
He's a fucking loser.
Pre pain pills.
He's taking care of his family.
He's a good guy.
He's working hard.
He's funny.
He likes to ride motorbikes on the
weekends.
It seems like a normal dude post pain
pills.
Fucking loser.
And it's clear as day.
Afraid of that shift should be.
Should be fucking terabytes of footage
of him catching on fire.
Oh Wow.
Oh my hair's on fire now.
Oh my God.
He's not touching it.
Doesn't know.
Oh my God.
They may notice before he noticed that
dude,
his hair was on fire for a few seconds
and now there's just stomping his head
on the concrete.
Third,
second and third degree burns on his
face and scalp.
Third degrees.
No joke.
Oh my gosh.
Look at.
This is dawn Harris,
scorched George Jefferson and shit.
So he had to wear a wig after that.
I heard too,
so that's when he started wearing a wig
because like,
you know,
we had a fucking big patch of his head
was like fucked up raw.
No hair like scar tissue.
Like when you got like scar tissue,
10 minutes.
We're done.
You got scar tissue on top of your head
like that.
That's got to suck.
Pampering pain.
It's
painful.
Fucking scar to burn scars all for
Pepsi.
What's your.
What's your worst down the ways you
don't want to do this and I want to
live.
Okay,
let's think of that.
What's the way I want to live?
I want to live the way I'm living right
now.
Ian Edwards on a Goddamn podcast and
telling people that needed to follow you
on twitter.
Need to fall.
Ian Edwards,
comedian.
What the fuck is the difference between
a comedian in a comic?
I've been a comic or a stand up comedian
or something along those lines.
For how many fucking years?
Twenty years plus.
I don't know what the differences
everybody's comic is or this unit is
with that.
I don't listen to that.
Like my.
The only reason why I'm at Enh what's
comic is shorter.
It fits on twitter.
Yeah,
it's better.
Yeah.
Like,
like if I try to put comedian a comedian
as a fit.
Too many,
too many words,
hard to retweet you and let us hear it
when it was the zero ne and Edwards
apparently.
Yeah,
there's a bunch of,
a bunch of,
a bunch of shit.
Even make it easier.
Just like silly in psyllium.
He's not silly.
That's you Betcha.
Thanks for the bad advice.
But we should tell everybody that he has
a show with Brian.
They do a show together so he doesn't
show and just rebroadcast it.
He actually does it with Zara.
It's compromise rosters
session,
so preposterous sessions and that's
available on itunes.
You fucks.
So go,
go get yourself something and follow him
on twitter.
Ian Edwards comic fall.
Brian on twitter.
That's red B,
a n on twitter,
right?
It's just red band,
Yeah.
And uh,
you can follow me on twitter too,
bitch.
Go ahead and go buy my comedy special.
It's five bucks.
My best shit ever.
Saw Joe Rogan.net.
It's drm free.
You get like a few choices that how you
want to download or stream it and
whatever.
It's for real.
My best shit ever.
But I already got a new our son,
some plotting my next move.
I'm thinking,
uh,
April again,
I might record my next one because I,
I,
um,
I like to scare the shit out of myself.
Were you going to do it?
I don't know.
Texas.
Um,
I'm.
Well I wanted to do the last one in
Vancouver,
so maybe I could do this one in
Vancouver.
The only problem was it was like
problematic with taxes and paying people
and Shit.
No,
no,
no.
You gotTa,
you gotta pay taxes and stuff.
It's kind of funky.
So I might not be able to do it in
Vancouver,
but if I don't do it in Vancouver,
Texas is a good one.
Texas is always good.
You know,
good energy in Texas.
Austin,
man,
that show in Austin.
Come on.
That's one of the greatest shows we've
ever done.
Ms Dot Texas Tech.
Yeah.
I gotta I gotta release that.
Especially now that,
uh,
Alex Jones is becoming famous,
that backstage footage of me backstage
hanging out with Alex Jones right until
the point that I get on stage because
it's pretty funny stuff.
So we'll put that on youtube.
We got a new youtube channel.
It's a powerful Jr.
He at youtube,
youtube.com/go
fuck your mother.
I don't know wHat it is.
Silly,
but we,
uh,
we started releasing all these podcasts,
on a,
on Youtube as well.
Um,
so that's it.
you freaks.
thank you to onnit.com.
Go to o n n I t use a code name.
Rogan save 10 percent off.
That's,
I said that earlier.
You know these things.
Okay.
but I must contractually repeat some of
them.
Go pick up blade swinger blades,
winger.
That's another cowboy fuck.
Other
bionic punks,
blade slinger from kerosene games.
It's only two 99.
and uh,
and they help support the podcast and
also hover h o v e r.
And if you go to,
what was the,
was the,
the harvard.com
forward slash joe rogan or some shit.
I don't know.
What is it?
Do you know god dammit,
because I got to find out what we end.
Oh,
well I think it is.
I think it's a joke.
Hold on.
Uh,
and if you're in la,
wicked stupid.
See joey diaz and duncan trussell and me
and a couple other people at the er on
the improv on melrose at 24th,
24th.
I will be out of town and I'll be,
I'll be in chicago,
but uh,
that'll be an awesome show.
Hover.com.
Forward slash rogan is what it is.
Go there.
Get 10 percent off your domain name and
that's it.
I guess.
Anything else?
Go to [inaudible] dot tv.
Buy herself a kitty cat shirt and if you
want to buy my psychedelic monkey shit,
it's all@higher-primate.com.
All right.
we will see you guys next week with
powerful new guests and a lot of really
stimulating discussion.
So until then,
have yourself a super sweet weekend.
And uh,
that's it.
New aids monday for me,
you know.
Stop it.
Yeah.
brian,
we'll have plenty of stories.
Make sure you tune in next week.
We might do one with just me and brian,
so you could tell me what the fuck went
wrong.
Went wrong powerfully in edwards.
Thanks for coming by,
man.
My pleasure.
Good time as always.
And if you catch ian on the road.
Oh wish.
What's your website?
a comedian.com.
You're confused.
You're confusing.
People.
See if fuckers.