Five,
four,
three,
two,
ladies and gentlemen,
live and available right now.
Everlast,
Whitey Ford.
How's a pain you?
Yes sir.
How are you sir?
How are you doing,
man?
Good.
Seeing you again in a minute.
You're going to vegas this weekend for
the fights?
Yeah,
man.
We got a little party the night before.
We were doing a little show at the
Brooklyn bowl with my buddy evidence.
And you don't know where I put the
headphones.
I feel like I'm alone here with the
headphones on.
There we go.
Here we go.
Now we're on the same team.
Now we're locked in.
Um,
does this out?
This is out,
right?
Yeah,
it came out about three weeks ago,
something like that.
Maybe a month.
Beautiful.
I've been in Europe for the whole month
is touring.
So this is like everything everlast
presents Whitey Ford's house of pain.
Yeah.
It's,
it's,
it's everything in the toolbox I brought
to this record.
So that's Kinda where the title came
from.
Just,
you know,
it's been eight years since my last real
studio album,
so I figured,
hey,
maybe this could be the last one.
I hope not,
but just like,
you know,
I mean like,
that my story,
it's like,
you know,
with the family,
I dedicate a lot more of my time to the
family.
Then I used,
yeah,
I'm just because of some of the,
you know,
um,
extra issues we deal with which
everything is wonderful and great.
Now,
you know,
and dude,
I'm 30 pounds lighter than the last time
I was here to do that.
Honestly,
it started here because I,
I put,
I purposely came here that day.
It was the first time,
if you remember,
it was awhile ago and you've done a
thousand podcasts since that day.
But,
uh,
it was the first time I had come out and
they started talking about anything
like,
you know,
that was going on in my life in a public
way.
And uh,
you know,
I got a lot off my chest that day and I
also plan that day to,
to put myself in a position to hold
myself accountable by this,
by stating I don't feel good about the
way I look right now.
And I reached out for like,
theoretically for help,
you know,
and I got an incredible response from
the podcast audience and my own fans and
I mean I got offered from everybody
everywhere how to do this,
that and the other.
Um,
didn't really need that because within
my own circle some people stepped up and
I also did it to hold myself accountable
to put it in the universe.
Like I've thrown it out there,
I put it up there on the wall and snip
and stamped it and said,
here's what I want out of life right
now.
And you know,
there's nobody stopping me but me and at
sometimes some of the things I used to,
I used to get on and see you talking
about I'm not letting this inner bitch
kicked my ass today.
And I just started taking things like
that to heart,
you know.
And again,
after she changed.
What'd you do different?
We started talking about it last time in
therapy.
You know what I mean?
It's helped a lot for me because of
this,
you know,
the,
the added pressures are family faces
with my oldest daughter having cystic
fibrosis,
you know,
it just for a long time it was just
learning how to live life with it,
you know,
and that got heavy.
There was some real dark,
you know,
heavy moments,
scary moments for her in the hospital,
you know,
so we,
I mean as a human,
you know,
you have this baby and you're just
trying to figure out how to not screw it
up with a normal health situation,
you know,
this is this added thing.
So it took a long time for me to come to
terms.
At first I got really angry.
I got into some real,
you know,
Lieutenant Dan more with God kind of
stuff,
you know,
at the top of the sail boat flipped,
as I was there all the way.
And it got to a point where I almost,
I was at,
I almost got locked up for trying to
fight a cop that was,
you know,
trying to just talk to me about
something,
you know,
I just lost my job.
I had no,
I had so much anger over so much that I
wasn't dealing with.
And then I found a guy that really got
me therapists and,
and it,
it began the,
the,
the ball rolling of understanding how
to,
how to cope with a lot of that stuff.
Wow.
So,
um,
as far as like,
first of all,
you look really good.
Think your face looks great,
your skin looks good.
I'm taking a lot better care of myself.
It looks like it.
Thank you.
Are you,
what are you doing different as far as
like how you eat or I'm just eating
cleaner,
you know,
just trying not to,
uh,
to be more aware of what's in the food
and listen to the meat and stuff.
You know,
I'm still part of the whole commercial
meat system though.
I long to to,
to get it to a situation where I'm
hunting and doing things like that.
It's just,
we had talked about that for 100 to try
hunting pigs at a to hone,
right.
I asked you what would be the best
starting point and you were like,
you know,
they got bore up there.
Well to hone and I know some guys and I
actually contacted them and I just,
again,
this is so busy.
It's not just this,
it's the added stress of like,
you know,
I have a wife that when I go on the
road,
she's the sole handler of these
problems,
you know what I mean?
And so that these things pile on you
guilt and stress and all this,
you know.
And um,
so yeah,
it's just between that and when I'm home
I just invest myself.
I want to be home,
I want to do as much as I can to lift
that weight.
So like I get caught by the things,
all the things I want to do,
I can't do all the time,
you know what I mean?
But it started again.
Now I'm taking care of myself like I'm
actually about to start Jujitsu again,
you know,
which.
Yeah,
because I forever,
I was so goddamn fat in the middle of
hip escapes.
We're like,
you know,
I was hurting my back or my neck every
other time I tried to do,
I just quit because it was getting,
you know,
I mean,
I wasn't,
we were advanced.
I was probably pretty close to getting a
blue belt,
you know,
that was about a year in,
on like four lessons a week with just
the private.
I was with mark,
as Vanessa said,
Beverly Hills Jujitsu for a while.
So now I'm just looking to see what I
want to do.
You know,
I've talked to Eddie a few times.
I'm talking to a few other guys.
Cron has taught you doing any exercise
at all besides that?
Cardio.
Not much weights or anything like that.
Just,
you know,
keep it moving.
I two hour,
two hours on stage tonight.
It's good to do something first.
Uh,
I feel like a,
I always tell people like Jujitsu,
so grueling that I,
I think,
uh,
why?
I mean,
you could just jump in and you will get
in shape through Jujitsu,
but a good thing to do is find a place
that teaches you kettlebells and take
some Kettlebell and just just get your
body strong enough that it can remember.
One of the things marcus used to do
brought marcus,
used to run me around the gym for 30
minutes before we could even start a
lesson.
Like I literally had to Puke for the
first like month.
Yeah.
That's that old school way.
A lot of it would take so long that he
would be like,
all right,
you're past the puking thing you ran
into.
But it was like at first I would like
literally be run till I was puking.
Then the crazy part of ours is 15
minutes after you felt great when you
were doing the last thing,
so it was it all work.
Yeah.
Those.
The old school guys,
that's how they used to do at these two.
I'm like all the old school Carlson
gracie classes,
you'd have a grueling physical workout,
first hip escaped pushups,
sit ups,
bodyweight squats,
all this different stuff.
There's a good thought process behind
that,
not just that it gets you in shape,
but also that you learn how to do
Jujitsu when you're tired so that you
learn how to just use technique and not
use like you're almost have no choice
but to relax.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
There's a people that disagree with that
though.
They think you should learn technique
when you're fresh in it,
like sits and better,
but it's just two different schools of
thought.
I don't think either one is right.
It's definitely good to understand what
it's like to be tired and how to,
how to train and how to,
how to push yourself when your tire
shore.
Yeah.
I'm excited.
I'm really looking forward to it.
Like I just started talking about like
about two weeks ago.
Really getting back to,
well that's a lot of weight to lose,
man.
That's a big accomplishment.
I got 15 to go to really to hit my goal.
Yeah.
Will it be 2:25
to 25?
So you good?
Wait.
Yeah.
I'm taking vitamins or supplements or
anything along those lines.
Like a daily.
Um,
but I,
you know,
I have restrictions because I take blood
thinners and stuff because of titanium,
heart valve I have so like I have to
have a vitamin that's devoid of a
vitamin K because that's what makes your
blood clot.
So I like a lot of things,
like a lot of the juicing things and
like things like that when you want to
go on a juice cleanse,
I can't do it because it's like a lot of
it's Kale based and like Kale is heavy
green with it's high in vitamin K,
it'll totally screw up my blood
chemistry with,
you know,
because I'm going the other direction
with blood thinners.
Jesus Christ,
I have to otherwise like a clock could
hit,
like stick to that titanium valve,
break off and wind up in my brain,
you know what I mean?
And then Tom stroked out and that's the
last thing we need.
Fuck yeah.
I remember when you put the microphone
up to your heart and you can hear that.
Yeah.
I would say I'm so,
so like when I'm in here I've keep
feeling like you can hear it anyway.
It's like all through this.
I hear it.
Twentieth white noise to me.
If I want to hear it,
I can hear.
I can take my pulse like this just by
telling you.
Wow.
Very.
You can feel it.
I can hear it in my own skull.
Like I could hear it in my bones that it
can hear it.
It's in me.
How long is that?
Good for?
Forever.
As long as I take care of him.
I mean it's been 20 years.
Literally in,
in 2018 it happened 90 or [inaudible]
98.
And um,
I just get,
you know,
as long as I keep the thinning,
the blood thinners going and you know,
I get checked in,
you know,
two times,
three times a year,
you know,
and then the blood thinners it because
if you got a clot it would somehow or
another get stuck in that valley or,
or you know,
it.
It's a titanium valves to the clock
could actually form on it that the metal
like it could book.
If it's the bloods to sticky into it has
too much claude.
He could stick to the bow,
then break off and then wind up in your
brain,
you know.
So to avoid blood clots in general.
Yes.
What's the difference between that and
the regular regular valve?
What would happen to the regular?
The other choice would have been a pig
valve and those are good for about 15
years.
Like they used to open you up again?
Yeah,
yeah.
I would have had to have it.
I'd probably be do.
Yeah,
probably right now to like,
I'd be like,
go here.
I don't know.
Yeah,
they do that for older people is what
they do.
Could like,
you know,
when you get into your sixties they,
really explore that because they don't
think you're going to be around $50.
Right.
They just say here just for now.
Yeah.
So,
um,
it's called a St Jude's.
St Jude's artificial valve.
Powerful medical technology.
Any brothels got a titanium disk in his
back now?
Yeah.
He just had a surgery this,
right?
Yeah.
His back moves around.
Great.
It like he was fully compressed.
Whether it was like nothing left.
It was basically bone on bone.
He was in pain all the time and they
just opened them up and put a fake valve
in there.
Crazy fake disc rather in there,
but it's articulating so like moves
around like a regular desk.
His,
it doesn't.
It's not like he's fused.
Even if you're seeing people that are
off.
Yeah,
they get the few.
I have a friend who got that down.
Yeah,
they're super stiff.
Like wherever it is is basically locked
down.
There's no movement to it anymore,
but Eddie's is,
is actually moves like a real desk for
shoot.
That's going to be coming down the
pipeline is going to be crazy,
man.
Yeah.
I mean I know people with fake
everything.
I know people with fake hips and knees
and what's fake?
Heart valves.
Yeah.
It's amazing.
I mean at a certain point in time
they're just going to replace your whole
body and take your brain out and put it
into your skin to be able to download
your consciousness.
That's what ellen was saying,
had gotten mad trouble.
He didn't really.
They made it.
Made some noise,
man.
But here's the deal,
Dude,
when you got $25,
billion dollars,
all trouble is bullshit.
Truth.
It's like,
good luck with your trouble.
Trouble.
He's out there with a fucking flame
thrower shooting rocket ships into the
atmosphere.
That flame throwers crazy too.
Does whatever he wants,
man.
He's basically like a little kid who.
And you actually buy that.
Is that like not anymore hail.
There's one right there.
Oh yeah.
He sold them all out like in like two
days or something.
I don't doubt it.
I would've had him in hip.
What are you going to do with it though?
Just fun.
It's just you have a flame thrower,
but it's literally called not a flame
thrower.
Yeah,
it's amazing.
Yeah.
It's basically what you saw in the movie
aliens movie.
The second angle when they're shooting
the flames at the aliens.
That's what that thing is.
Yeah.
I seen him on something just the other
day almost.
Was it here where it looked like you
were going set the building on fire?
Yeah.
That was in here.
That was all my instagram.
Yeah,
he's a mad man.
The world needs more of those,
more people like him,
not more flame throwers.
Know plenty of philanthropists.
So,
uh,
you looking forward to the fights this
weekend?
I'm,
I'm super jacked for it man.
Oh dear.
We got this little show before.
Is anybody coming out to jump around?
Um,
I don't know.
They have to.
They,
you know,
I'm waiting for Connor.
Did you know how does he not know that
song?
Well,
he comes out to Sinead O'connor,
right?
That he does like usually like that into
like the notorious song,
like the,
you know,
the.
Yeah.
I don't know,
but no Pto Rias.
Right.
Or who was coming out to jump around?
Marcus Davis did.
He did.
I know,
uh,
Coviello that,
that the female fighter.
Uh,
she coveo thank you.
Yeah,
I know she comes out to jump around.
I met her at a fight.
She was super cool.
She was super troopers will get called
quite a few people have come out to it
and I think Machida came out to at once.
He's over in belt right now.
I'm not,
I'm not always sure they have a choice
sometimes.
I just think Dana says you're coming out
the job.
Well,
he definitely takes away bad choices.
That might be what might be the sub when
there's a really shitty here.
Throw that in.
But then Darren till came out to sweet
caroline.
He came out to uh,
who is that Neil?
Diamond diamond.
Yeah.
And he had the whole crowd singing along
like,
this is crazy.
Crazy.
Was it,
was that in Boston or in that area of
the country?
No,
it was,
uh,
where was that fight?
Chicago.
Makes Sense.
Neil diamond wasn't in Chicago.
It could,
it could know Dallas was Dallas.
That's should've came up.
Yeah,
it was weird.
It was weird.
Yeah.
It's just like,
you know,
that's a big deal.
Like walkout songs are a big deal.
You can't have a wag.
Sets the tone.
The thing for me is when I hear one of
my songs,
I'm just,
I'm just always like,
oh,
please.
When you saw him becomes a curse.
It's like,
Oh man,
come on.
Jon.
Anik does stats on fist bumps,
like how many times people fist bump
bruce buffer whether or not they win or
lose.
You know,
like,
and Diego Sanchez broke the curse and
his last fight he fist bumped bruce any,
any one?
So the fist bump was a cursed.
We're trying to figure it out cause he,
he was like,
I think it's like 50 slash 50 right now,
like whether or not people when they
fist bump priest buffer when they went
and there was a bad streak for awhile,
like three or four people in a row last
that we're fist bumping,
you know,
bruce gives you the intro,
uh,
you know,
and when he gives you the Dji go a
nightmare,
she's a little fist bump and if you fist
bump them back,
you know,
if you,
if you do engage in that,
like Anik was trying to figure out like
Anik is kind of a degenerate gambler in
the most positive way.
I mean he's not losing his family or his
life,
but he fucking loves gambling.
And so he's always giving you stats on
this and that is something to put a on
things he actually bets on.
But he's always thinking that way.
Would you bet on it?
Yeah.
I wonder if you could bet on how many
people who fist bump bruce buffer,
you could find somebody to take the bet.
The thought process would be you're not
totally in the zone if you've got the
time to fist bump bruce buffer.
I'm not sure if it buy it though,
because it's also your moment when
you're saying your name and.
Yeah.
I don't know.
It's a tricky,
tricky.
Well,
it sounds like it's about even just one
of them things.
Someone should do stats on it because
Jon Anik is only done like a,
you know,
just off the top of his head in his
basement right now.
Starting.
Starting to watch the fight for sure.
Write it down.
Okay.
Let's take the notes.
Well,
you can basically bet on anything these
days.
Right?
In Vegas you can pretty much find a lot
of things.
I think you could bet on you that you
can.
I don't even bet,
but I liked the fact that you can bet on
everything.
Why Not Anders coin flips.
Also,
I liked that it's freedom.
I don't like this idea that people are
telling you what you can and can't do
with your money.
Like you can't gamble your money.
Well,
you have to go to a spot in the desert.
Like why says who says,
oh,
like why can't you gamble right here?
Why can't someplace,
you know,
why can't you have a casino on every
corner?
Who Cares?
Like,
well,
people are going to lose our paycheck on
wolves are family and one was really,
really well.
They really is that what's going to do
it?
So at the casino maybe be for a while,
but then people will be like,
you know,
we shouldn't go there as much as like
the infant tyler [inaudible] of people,
you know,
keep them,
protect them from themselves.
You don't protect them from liquor
stores are fast cars,
you know,
those things were everywhere.
Everywhere.
Good point,
right?
Yeah.
I'm with you man.
I could never live in Vegas.
Oh,
I could live in Vegas.
You know,
if it was between Beirut and Vegas,
Vegas,
do it.
I'll figure it out.
But you know,
it just,
it seems to me like this.
Just the whole thing is it's built.
I mean there's shows and it's wonderful
and as neon there's great restaurants
and all that stuff,
but it's also built on you losing money.
Yeah.
The whole thing is built on you losing.
When's the real population of Vegas?
Like a half a million people like that
of people that aren't there visiting
gambling and for the fuckery.
Let's take a guess.
I'm guessing like half a million people.
Yeah,
I bet you're about right.
Six,
600,
30,000.
I'm pretty far off.
Pretty close.
That's a good guest.
How would that have been?
Close enough to win the price is right.
Yeah,
so if you've got a real small town there
that's acting like a city too.
It's kind of weird.
Well,
like what is the population at any given
time with all the hotels filled?
This weekend's a big week,
at least dolt more than that probably,
but I'm saying at least even like an off
season,
off day.
You're probably at least double that,
but a lot of the folks that work in
Vegas,
they live in like Henderson or something
like that where you can go and a nice
neighborhood.
Kids can ride bikes in the street.
It's like normal for there to uh,
uh,
summerland too.
That's really nice over there.
Yeah.
There's a few of those spots that are
like,
no,
actually like staying over there at that
red rock.
That's not the don't like the Strip
fuckery,
man.
That's why I like,
you know,
just seemed like a quiet.
If I want the fuck where y'all take a
cab over 40 minutes away.
She says there's one and a half 90
people there at any given time.
Probably more like that.
Yeah.
So for the fights,
what about a big fight weekend I typed
in for hotels.
How many people were in that hotel
rooms?
Yes.
There's a 148,000
rooms.
Whoa.
Do they might be 148,000
Irish people there this weekend.
Just screaming if you,
you're.
If you're there this weekend,
just pay attention because it's going to
be bananas.
The last time for the mayweather fight,
there was a video that someone posted of
Mandalay Bay and Mandalay Bay was not
anymore.
The fight was taking place and the irs
had this one hallway completely filled
and they were all singing.
They were singing dot avenue in New
York.
They don't give a fuck.
Yeah,
England.
So little islands all got on a plane to
fucking crazy and there's a lot of us
here too,
you know,
and I say us,
I got a little in me one quarter.
There's so many more Irish or Irish part
Irish people in America.
There's more than.
There are Irish people in Ireland.
They did a lot of fucking.
They came over here and did a lot of fun
and they fought and they weren't
discriminated about color or creed
anymore.
Jamie's got a notorious tee shirt on
with the Irish flag savage.
Is that available at Young Jamie Dot
Com?
There's a link there if you need it.
Oh my goodness.
Powerful commerce.
I would have tried this whiskey
honestly,
that he's got.
I've got.
I got it.
Yeah.
You're a whiskey expert,
right?
I wanna I wanna lay hands on it and see
what's a good whiskey.
I was,
I actually was going to bring you a
bottle of this and I will next time,
but I didn't because of Celebrex for
sober October,
maybe falling apart.
I'm going to tell you right now,
gentlemen,
Burke crushers going on a cruise and
ours should fear and Tom both gave me
the green light to drink because uh,
this fitness challenges falling apart.
Meanwhile,
Bert is strongly in last place.
Yeah.
All that.
Talk about the Mickey Mantle Gene.
He's not even close.
But what's fascinating is red shift.
Fear is very close to me.
He's only,
he posted today before my workout.
That's sneaky bitch that he was ahead of
me,
but that's how close he is.
He's so close that before his workout,
he was like 100 points ahead of me
before my workout rather after his.
Now he's like 400 points behind me,
but that's a,
that's close.
Four hundred points is one workout.
If you're an asshole and you want to get
on a fucking treadmill for two hours,
you can bang out 400 points.
I banged out 500 today.
Five.
Oh,
seven at the end of the workout
therapies to.
It's not a beast,
man.
It's boring.
Registered watching.
I was watching a gladiator.
There's little red spikes in my workout
where I hit 93.
That's when the fights were happening.
I got amped up to a podcast while you
were on a elliptical commanded that
month.
It would suck.
Redbreast is my favorite new whiskey.
Redbreast.
Who makes that?
It's red breast is the second Irish
whiskey and get to come and bring you
about another 20 year old.
It's.
It's gorgeous.
Twenty years old.
It's beautiful.
What was that shit that we drank with
Stan?
Hope that was really good.
Was it Stan?
Hope?
No.
Stand up.
Stand home.
Brought it and doesn't some band make it
at the Florida Georgia line or some
shit.
Did they make it?
Is that there's no like a pop band and
they make a good whiskey like a country
band?
I think country pop,
whatever.
Old Camp.
Listen man.
If you call yourself country,
but you get them fake rips and Eugene's,
you can go suck a bag of depth.
That ain't country.
Not saying that they have that.
I don't even know,
but you know what I'm saying?
Like those fake grips in the genes might
have a couple of little groups in my
teens do.
I checked those fake grips drive me Damn
Banana Bananas.
Like what are we were pretending that we
work hard.
What are we pretending that we.
We've had these jeans for a long time
and they're special to us.
Or did we just buy them off the shelf at
macy's?
Pre ripped like assholes.
Like where the fuck did that take place?
Like if our grandparents who made it
through the depression could come over
here and see us buying rip jeans would
they would realize like,
what is wrong with this nerfed up soften
down fucking shitty country.
We live in America.
It's too easy,
too easy to get by wolves in the
streets.
Young Eric.
We can't be running around with fucking
fake rips in jeans.
You know on Brendan Schaub.
One of my best friends does that.
Oh,
who's this?
That's them with the five.
Nailed it.
I didn't even mean to nail it.
I didn't even mean that.
I just took a wild guess.
I don't know a goddamn thing about these
fellows.
Go to that other one.
Go to that last picture.
We put the glasses on and look at.
Look at those genes.
Make that bigger.
Well,
he looks like he got a shark.
I got some paint.
Oh,
you do have some gray.
Got Some fucked up shit on your jeans.
I'm gonna.
Keep it real though.
I'm not gonna.
Let you go in on them and not come claim
my jeans here.
Listen,
I should shut the fuck up.
I'm basically wearing yoga pants.
I got these barbell jeans on.
These aren't even jeans.
These are Goddamn Yoga pants.
Jeans,
or made a weird like this thing.
I mean,
well these don't.
These aren't even Jesus.
Actually Denim.
These are like they.
They might as well be spandex.
I might as well be wearing yoga pants
most,
most pants or that now.
Even the ones that look like jeans and a
lot of them are that they feel better.
Technology,
it's called advancement in human
civilization.
Yeah.
You want to drive a car with leaf
springs like an asshole or do you want
some new magnetic Cadillac escalades
Vung like to cruise through your pants
or you want to be sweaty?
All the breeze from fake holes.
I'll take the sweat like a man.
I want to rock my because I got skinny
enough to where these motherfuckers.
Okay.
I respect that.
Wifey.
Your fastest links.
These motherfuckers.
Well that's two.
Two pluses.
Just don't wear cowboy boots.
Oh,
we jay.
We rocking the sneakers for life to my
friend Cam Haynes.
He wears cowboy boots and I just shut my
mouth.
Look down those big old woodland hills.
I think Andrew Sandino's bit never seen
Andrew Sandino's,
but he's got a bit about dudes who wear
cowboy boots.
Holy Shit.
Is it funny?
Oh my God.
I'll look it up on the to it.
I don't even know if he might not even
put it on a special yet,
but he's a whole bit about dudes dressed
up like with cowboy hats on and cowboy
boots.
Fucking hilarious.
Anyway,
but I digress.
What's this a cow skull with the third
eye.
What's that?
Just a sweatshirt or liked.
Okay.
I like it too.
It's one of those brand called
adaptations interested.
It has a fake colon.
The elbow.
Oh Jesus.
Sorry Dude.
This full disclosure.
I'm not going.
I'm not going to tell the truth.
Why is that happening with the holes?
How did that happen?
What happened to us?
Sorry Dude,
I'm disappointing you so much.
The reality is,
and this is what's fucked up,
why does it look better?
Because it Kinda does kind of looks
better if you wearing a shirt and it's
got like even if it's a new shirt,
it's got like those little holes around
the collar,
a little tiny holes,
like a little bit.
A little bit of rip here.
A little tiny rip their why's it look
better.
I don't know.
Maybe it's because it's not.
Maybe there's some psychological way of
ripping things that some people are more
talented at it,
that they just know where to make cool.
They make it look like if you had like a
pair of Levi's that were the.
He was getting thin,
we would advance that shit.
You know,
there was something cool.
Yeah.
You would like if it was like we didn't
do it on like rip them up like they do
nowadays,
but like let's say you had a pair of
jeans long enough,
they know the knees would get thin and
they ripped a little.
You just kind of run with it.
Maybe stress him out a little bit more
like that.
Oh well presenting the $1,625
designer tee shirt complete with tears
and holes.
Okay.
We can all agree if you buy that you're
a fucking asshole.
If you spent a thousand dollars on a tee
shirt,
you're kind of.
The only good thing about that is I
think that's the lady's tee shirt and
I'm holding bumped them and all she has
to do is bend over tire shoes and it
might not be a nip slip.
It might be a nip poke through.
Right?
Like look where those holes are.
Quite possibly those ties are jutting
out.
Right?
Look at that.
You know how that works too.
She might not even be wearing that
shirt.
That might not even be a person.
That might be a mannequin.
Yeah.
They do things and they just put
different shirts on.
Shit would photoshop and shit that.
It's crazy.
But that's a stupid shirt.
That's a shirt.
Like this one.
There's a t shirt that has a button down
shirts sewn to the front of it.
What's dude?
It was like on the blogs a couple of
weeks ago.
You know what I'm talking about.
So he's in the sneaker blogs using some
of that shit.
It leaks through and shit.
So I'm like be using like these greg's
designer crazy.
I have a couple pairs but I don't really
wear them that much.
I'm more of a Jordan guy.
You have a thought about lighting them
on fire sometimes.
Like when I was,
you know,
the dudes kind of batshit crazy.
I actually say that on his album.
Patching crazier than Yay.
And Sarah Pailin.
Oh look at this.
Yeah,
that's a real thing.
Oh Lord.
That's a real thing.
So one side has a tee shirt and then the
other thing is sewn to the front.
But it like,
it doesn't even,
it looks like it's hanging there.
It is just hanging there,
but it doesn't even look like you're
wearing it.
It looks like it's running your shirt.
Oh,
what,
what?
Hold on.
Go back to that price.
$200.
$1,300
was saying that is worse than the
teacher.
You know,
buy one right now.
Oh my God.
$1,300.
Wow.
For that.
Do you see Kanye jumped on a table at a
university,
was talking about leaving Elon musk
alone.
Who's lost his mind?
Man?
What's going on?
I don't know man.
You know,
there's a lot of people that speculate
and that's all I would say.
This is from me.
Ever since that man's mother died,
he's been on a downward spiral,
like losing his shit.
Well,
you know,
I think he's suffering from some
serious,
like no bullshit.
He did get into a serious car accident,
broke his jaw,
was seriously injured a few years
before.
That is not a joke.
No.
Like brain trauma.
And listen,
I'm not a doctor or anything even
remotely related to one,
but I've been around.
A lot of people have been hitting the
head a lot.
That shit's real like that.
That will change your brain chemistry.
It's a 100 percent legit like getting
hit in the head is no Bueno and car
accidents will fuck people up forever.
Some people,
some people are okay.
They get they recover.
Boy,
there's a lot of people that come back
for some significant head trauma and
just they're scrambled man and he might
be one of those and it also might be
what I talked about in my last special
triggered,
but you lived with crazy bitches long
enough to get something happens.
You were talking about the soul stealing
suck you buy might be true.
It was an amazing routine.
I got it while I was trying to figure
out a way that I get away with making
fun of Bruce Jenner without being called
transphobic,
circuitous route.
It was brilliant.
Go along route.
First Time I saw it.
Yeah.
I had to drag Kanye in that to you,
dude.
Every mail that's gone into that circle,
into it.
Lost all it's spooky.
Borrowed them was like a world champion.
Yes.
Ballplayer dude.
And he's got cracked out drag Bush.
What happened to him?
Reggie Bush got wise and detailed.
He's got my old car.
He.
Reggie Bush has my 1970 Barracuda.
Is that right?
Yeah.
I sold it to this other dude and this
other dude sold it to Reggie and he
drives around that car.
It's a dope car.
And he was a dope car.
Yeah.
So he's got some taste.
You have any weird things are going on
over there,
man.
He smashed and bolted.
That's how you do it.
And he's.
He smashed before the fake ass came into
the picture too.
That's another phenomenon.
I don't even understand diaper,
but it is like I'd like a nice round,
but yeah.
Here's my car.
It was Reggie Bush driving.
It was not.
My Card Says No.
Oh,
look at that Reggie.
Glorious Bastard.
You had her first.
Yeah.
I'm not a really good car.
Good car.
Look at records.
Had to get rid of it.
Oh yeah,
that's the Ray j song.
Right in your window.
You go full circle.
You wouldn't want to take second place
to Reggie Bush to.
That guy is built like a brick shit
house,
you know,
he was smashing that.
Right?
Whatever he damaged.
He did that.
He probably was like a car accident.
Maybe all that fake ass shit came after
him.
You get hit by that dude I read.
She used to wake up before him and get
hot towels ready and put his toothpaste
on his toothbrush.
Smart.
Yeah.
Him like a king probably just smashed
it.
She's pot all day.
Just delirious.
Just from all the orgasms.
Just walking around,
bumping into walls and shit is a picture
of him and her by the pool and you'd
look at him and you love that guy.
Must be just smashing that.
He's a super athlete.
I mean that guy is built like a fucking
superhero.
All of them.
That's all they really date.
Yeah,
right.
For the most part.
Yeah.
Except Kanye.
She just settled down behind a
basketball player to player.
Do the dude who was on the show all the
time.
That guy was on the show all the time.
Crazy living.
I can't even see living your life like
out there and fucking public.
Just every fucking biddy or business.
Oh,
that would be a nightmare to me.
Well,
it's also not interesting but yet edited
so well that you just go slack,
jaw and you just watch.
It's just they switched from one scene
to another quick enough so that you keep
watching it and when it's over,
nothing happened.
Nothing.
And you're like,
what the fuck did I do with my hour?
You gave it to them and they advertised
like 18 and products that they got paid
for it and they made a fucking ass load
of money.
When you find out how much that family
has made,
you just go,
wait,
what?
What,
It's.
It's amazing.
Yeah.
Can't Karen.
Hey Ken.
You should make fun.
Make Fun.
All days.
That's our God given,
right?
Yes.
When you get that much money,
if I get that much money,
I can't even get mad.
No matter how much fun you can make it
with me,
no matter what I do,
I could be a saint.
You still could make fun of me because I
got that much money.
Nobody.
That's just the way it goes and you are.
I mean,
you want to talk about someone out
there.
Those fucking people are out there.
They got everything out there,
you know,
they're living like performance art.
They like living in a giant glass house
on a pedestal in the middle of a city
were almost.
That's where all that comes from though.
It was like,
you know,
the fake ass isn't all that you gotta
keep the spectacle alive almost.
You know what I mean?
If it's not a spectacle,
it's not interesting.
I have to keep changing things.
If it's not an absolute spectacle to the
vision,
your,
your brain will catch onto the my
favorite word fuckery.
I love that word too.
It's my favorite word.
It's a great word.
It's a good.
It really is like a great.
First of all,
it's a word that you can get away with
no matter what.
It's not a word that you know eventually
you won't be able to use anymore.
No,
fuckery is just going to be around
forever and it's just,
it is perfect for like nonsense.
Yeah.
I've been my English friends for years.
We're saying fuckery on that.
That's the thing.
That's the only reason they catch none
over here.
Really.
The last 10 years I'm talking about
since the eighties I been hearing
fuckery trying to figure out when I
started using it,
I started using in regards to martial
arts,
like fake martial arts.
I use it in all kinds of stuff.
You can use it lightheartedly.
You could use it seriously.
It was viewed everything.
It's as versatile as just plain old
fuck.
Yeah.
Steve Maxwell.
That's where I got it from.
Then I started using with Steve Maxwell.
He was describing some fake martial arts
talking about cause you know Steve's a
black belt in Jujitsu and he's like,
yeah,
that's a lot of fuckery.
And I was like,
Ooh,
that's a great word.
That's a word I'm going to keep using.
I just looked it up to see if there's a
good definition and it says it's also a
definition for another word for a
brothel.
A fucker.
Fuck.
Holy Shit Dude.
You're just like open my brain in a new
way.
Cloris.
That's like,
Duh.
Of course they've called it.
Are you going to the fuckery?
A brewery fuckery.
Oh,
that's too.
That's never.
That never would have dawned on me.
How vulgar,
slang,
uncountable sexual intercourse.
What?
Wow.
That which is fucked up,
that which is fucked up,
fucked up his definition.
It is a fuckery.
That is hilarious of fuckery.
Well,
I had only used it in its verb form.
It's actually a noun is a fuckery.
Fuckery.
A place place.
We get your.
That's brand new.
Literally brand new translation in
French,
I guess is what it says.
Oh,
French.
And they figured out shit.
Have you ever been to Paris?
I love Paris.
It's one of my favorite place underneath
it as all the skeletons.
No,
I have not been to the catacombs.
The Friends of mine have gone though.
Yeah.
I want to go man.
I want to go and see that you can get
tours and all kinds of shit.
Like what happened was that the people
that died and the plagues that with it
is.
I think so.
And they just buried them,
you know,
the um,
the church put them all in the
catacombs.
Do you know at one time Paris had a wolf
problem and people getting killed by
wolves in recent history?
$1,400.
Look at that.
Wow.
Look at those pictures.
All those skulls.
Yeah.
There's a crazy story by habits will
place that whenever I see pictures of.
This is the reminder.
There's a place in,
I want to say what countries?
Prague,
the Czech Republic.
I think it's called Aura.
K U t n a h o r a.
it's like a church that's like thousands
of peoples skeletons.
Grays.
Yeah.
There it is.
That's it.
That place is bananas,
man.
Did you go to that too?
Oh No,
I've been there.
I haven't been to the catacombs saying
whenever I see pictures of the
catacombs,
but this place it's like an entire
church decorated and then they have like
little dens of like places like
thousands and thousands.
It was like vertebrae the spine.
Oh No.
There's another one where it's like,
Whoa,
crazy that is beneath the aura and it's,
you know,
you can just go there and I think you
pay like a couple of whatever.
Euros and you can walk in there and I
got tons of flakes in there.
It's weird when you go to those places
and you realize these places with that.
Like I was in Italy and uh,
there was a church that I went to and
there was this glass floor.
The church was over a thousand years old
and is a glass floor that you walk on
below.
The glass floor is the old church that
the thousand year old church was built
on and they have no idea how old old
churches.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
Which church was it?
It's in Ravello.
It's at the top of like there's a bunch
of cute little shops and little uh,
hotels and shit out.
So I make sure I check it out.
Small Church that the church that you
could visit is more than a thousand
years old.
I put a picture on my instagram of this
crazy picture of what they thought a
whale looked like.
It was a story of a guy who was the dude
who got eaten by the way on the Bible,
Jonah,
and the whale.
And it's like in a mosaic on the wall,
but it's like what they thought a whale
was.
It's like,
you know,
before they had photos that some dude
would like draw you a picture of some
shit he saw like this is what I will.
It looks like my friend.
And then,
you know,
some other dude who never saw.
Well we'd make a mosaic of this shit and
put it on the wall.
It's just so weird.
And we went to the place that got fucked
up by the volcano to um,
palm palm pay.
Yeah.
That's fascinating.
Too.
Crazy.
Just instantly.
Twenty feet of ash just covered in Ash.
Just can't even imagine.
Yeah.
One minute.
Nothing.
And next one.
A little earthquake.
And why you're there.
You can see the volcano.
It's right there.
So active.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I mean I don't think it's had a real
issue in a long time.
See if you find that instagram picture
of Jonah and the whale.
That's scary shit from July volcanoes in
Hawaii.
Everything going on there.
Yeah.
That's Nutty,
man.
Just scary getting the.
I read a story of like,
somebody didn't touch the lava,
they just got within like a couple
inches of it and like burnt themselves,
like melted their skin,
like off.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Not even getting,
like actually hit by it.
You get hit by it.
Your Shit's desolving.
Oh,
you can cook on it.
Just slap a stake on that bench.
It would dissolve,
wouldn't,
it wouldn't.
It's not the best conductor of heat.
You know,
you just slap a stake on that.
Sear it,
flip.
It may take one second.
There was a uh,
some crazy chef did this where they took
molten iron and they poured it down this
chute.
And as I was going down the chute,
they slapped stakes on.
It was like they were cooking on this
hot molten iron.
That's crazy.
People get bored.
Wonder if it tasted any protests.
Like Shit.
Probably ruin a good steaks,
like multiple fucking whatever.
But yeah,
like molten dirt.
Did you see the video of the lava
consuming that Mustang?
Did you walk Haasz dissolved if you got
payments and you just fucking damn,
man,
this car is killing me.
These payments at killing me just parked
that bitch.
Why would that lava is coming in Hawaii
watching get melted.
Set up a camera better.
Imagine there's a lot of mustangs over
there either.
I probably is a lot of American cars
over there.
They,
they,
they buy a lot of toyotas because they
don't break.
They're small.
Yeah.
Well it's also like you don't do,
you know,
everything has to get flown over there.
So you don't want anything to break
superexpensive yeah.
Everything.
Food is more expensive there than like
the only other place that it was
comparable to me was Perth really?
Well because everybody.
So it's like everything is same day.
It's the furthest like city,
like isolated by itself in Australia and
I think maybe in the world away from any
other major city.
That makes sense.
Right?
Because Australia is as big as the
United States and it's really the only
major city on the west coast that you
guys.
How big is Perth?
It's like,
I don't know how many people,
but it's like a city and know.
Do you perform there a lot?
I'm not allowed to spend.
Probably almost 10 years since I've been
in Australia.
I love Australia,
but I do not love that fucking flight,
baby.
Tough.
That's a rough life.
Takes a minute.
They'll get over that shit.
Yeah.
You,
you land and you're like,
where am I for a couple of days.
There it is.
That's what the fuck is that man.
It's like a fish with a lion head.
Like,
look,
that's what they thought Jonah and the
whale looked like.
That's hilarious.
Thousand years ago.
Strange,
right?
Like dude was trying to make a run for
it and then look at emily was like,
I'm going to get the fuck away from this
dude.
Kind of looks like me.
That's a little disturbing.
Like I'm gonna get Outta here.
Bald headed dude with a beard.
Trying to get away from this lion fish
with wings thing.
That's.
But that's what they thought.
A whale was.
Craziness.
How?
Just imagine what it was like living a
thousand years ago when there was no
pictures.
That's the glass floor.
Yeah,
that's my feet right there.
So you're in this church,
the church.
A thousand years old.
And that goes back to that last one,
Jeremy,
that one that's,
that's the glass floor.
And then you look down and they have
this entirely different church
underneath it that's way older.
They don't know how old it is.
Been there forever.
It could be several thousand years old.
The church is gorgeous though.
There's a lot of those churches.
And have you been to the Vatican?
Right?
Yeah,
that's the mind fuck of all mine phones.
It's crazy.
Like St Peter's Basilica when you're
walking around that place and you just
like,
what?
How,
how did people do this?
It's retarded,
man.
It's unbelievable.
Vatican's no power saws.
Nothing.
No,
no fucking cranes.
Everything was like ladders and shit.
The paintings and art.
Just stunning,
stunning.
Billions of dollars with the art and the
whole area.
The whole Vatican is essentially its own
country.
Yeah.
So they can keep those kid fuckers over
there and they never have to export
them.
You know?
That's.
Yeah.
That's the darkest.
No,
nobody can man dig.
They'll try.
People get mad and look,
I get it.
I was a Catholic for a little bit.
That's a dark,
dark institution.
There is no denying it.
I mean they just,
they just busted another group of
priests in,
in Pennsylvania,
molested more than a thousand kids.
Moving them around,
charging them organized religion in
general is the biggest mind controlled.
It's over existed,
you know,
trying to control popular populations
and what's the best way and make you
believe a certain thing.
You know what I mean?
But there's,
there's better ones.
There's some that you go,
oh,
for sure.
For sure.
What are the baptists have done?
What have they done?
It's so terrible.
Oh,
it,
no baptist scandals like that large
scale scandals.
Even the Mormons,
like they've had a few like dudes who
want a more than one bride that got
greedy and more than a few.
There's a whole part of their thing that
that's how they still live,
but there's some sex sec,
sec tease that a branched off and got
real,
real freaky on the scale that the
Catholic Church has done things.
It's unprecedented.
Unprecedented.
Completely.
Yeah.
Because they,
they actively shield these people from
prosecution and they kept it all.
I mean,
are people actually getting like,
like I've heard some things like they're
going after like cardinals and shit,
like the criminals.
That is the step down.
Yeah.
That last pope had to step down because
they wanted to prosecute him for crimes
against humanity because he was one of
the dudes who orchestrated a lot of
that.
Exactly.
The Guy Right before then he moved a guy
who went on to molest 100 deaf children.
Yeah.
I remember reading stuff about that.
It's dark,
it's dark,
and it's one of those things where
people,
you know,
it's been a part of their family.
It's been a part of their families
family.
It's been a part of their history.
They go to church,
they pay their respects.
Everything's okay.
They don't want to hear it.
People don't want to hear it,
but it's over.
The old evidence is just so
overwhelming.
There's so much,
so much shit that's attached to the
point I.
I didn't know.
I just think again,
people like you're saying you get.
I was raised Catholic.
I just.
By the time I was like,
I did this thing called confirmation,
which is sort of like this,
a similar thing to what this,
the time that you're becoming a man,
you're making good choices as an adult
because it wasn't just men,
but um,
by the time I did that and realized
like,
okay,
this is,
there's not a lot or you know,
there's low too much magic going on for
me.
You know what I mean?
Like going on with this.
Like I like just factual,
knowledgeable things,
you know,
like if these people really existed,
and were they really like,
I'm not buying into the fact that
anybody on this earth didn't take a
shit.
Like I took a shit.
You know what I mean?
We all take the same shifts.
It'd be nice if someone came up with a
good religion,
a real solid locked down one.
I mean there's,
there is one.
We,
we'd all just would have to agree on it.
How about just the golden rule that you
don't mean that could basically be a
religion and it's of the Church of
universal law,
you know,
do unto others as you would have them do
unto you and you could hold corporations
to that.
You could be like,
all right,
we stuck what's,
what's more powerful than 10 million
people on a facebook page that are
watching these corporations and the
minute they say,
hey,
you're not giving back to the community,
are taken care of the people that are
taking care of you,
that's easily.
But it takes work.
It's a good point.
It's easily done.
If everybody in the world just really
treated the next person like they wanted
to be treated themselves,
there you go.
And did it as a law.
Right?
And then we,
we,
we held people accountable to that.
Yeah.
You are not responding to the universal
law,
universal golden golden rule.
You know,
it sounds super simple,
but I mean to get a lot of work,
but it's the principle is simple,
right?
And all the other stuff,
like all other forms of commerce and
everything else would still fall under
that.
Just like you could do whatever you want
as long as you're treating people
kindly.
Exactly.
Like ideally commerce and capitalism,
all that stuff should be real simple.
Like you have a great cd,
you want to sell it,
you want 20 bucks for it.
Somebody gives you 20 bucks,
they're happy,
you're happy.
That should be commerce,
right?
Yeah.
It should be.
You sell something,
people buy it,
everybody's good,
but then you get a little greedy,
you know,
if we can figure out a way to corner
this market and keep other people from
selling this or selling that or we've
got to stop people from growing this
because if they grow this and sell that,
you're not doing what's best for doing
what you would want them to do for to
you.
Exactly.
So you're breaking the law violation.
The golden rule.
If,
if that's what I've thought about it
obviously before,
like,
hey man,
what would be like,
yeah,
that'd be a really cool thing to do.
You know?
That would be the way you know somebody
with enough charisma,
you know,
could pull it off,
get people to get behind it.
That's really all it would say because
people getting behind it.
Yeah,
but the problem is there's so many
people that just.
We're seeing this with politics,
right?
Like I'm,
I'm fascinated by these cabinet
hearings,
like a watch little clips of it before I
just have to tune out and talk fuckery.
Talk about fuckery.
I mean,
I don't know what that do did or what he
didn't do,
but I think what's happening is more
than that,
what's happening is first of all he's
involved with a.
He was a big part of the Patriot Act.
He was,
you know,
he's involved in some,
some issues that a lot of people are
very concerned with in terms of like how
his position,
his stance on privacy and on rights and.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
There's more to it than just did you
fuck with someone in high school?
Did you sexually assault someone?
Did you do that when you're 18 digit,
do you remember?
Like there's more to it than that.
There's just like they don't want that
guy in there and then you're seeing all
the people that want to pretend that
he's the best guy ever.
And all the people.
It's crazy.
It's fascinating.
It's really fascinating.
It's fascinating to watch because it's
essentially like a less like the
Clarence Thomas hearings from.
Was it like the 19 eighties?
I believe Clarence Thomas.
I feel like that was late eighties.
Early nineties.
Yeah,
somewhere around there.
Clarence Thomas.
That was with Anita Hill where he had
sexually harassed or they were working
together and she came whatever,
coke or something.
Do you know that he's now the longest
running a member of the Supreme Court.
He's.
He's now been in the supreme court
longer,
I think.
Read that check.
Make sure that's true.
Isn't Bruce Katie?
Ken's Bader Ginsburg.
Has she been there longest serving 26
years as of October fourth mob?
Yeah.
Crazy.
So it didn't work.
Needed hell's out there then with the
memory of pubic hairs on Coke and a
movie now and Hbo Movie Not Too Long
Ago.
Oh yeah.
Did you watch it?
I saw it.
It was,
it was.
Was it okay.
It was a pretty good movie.
It was just,
you know,
we lived through it.
So it's like,
it's like whenever I see movies about
like the Oj trial or something,
I'm like,
no,
I saw that.
We saw it live for like 700 days.
I'm always fascinated by those movies
because of creative license.
Like if you do a movie on Richard Nixon,
right?
What do you sure he said that?
Or even crazier.
You do a movie on Lincoln Bitch.
You don't know what the fuck.
He said you can't be like Sibley unless
he wrote it down.
You're having him say a bunch of Shit
Day to day talking to his wife and kids.
You don't know what the fuck he says.
He just making this up.
This is weird that we're allowed to do
that.
You're allowed to just put some words in
George Washington's mouth like
you don't know what the fuck George
Washington said.
You know,
have you seen this movie coming out
there?
Christian Bale is Dick Cheney and dude,
it looks amazing.
Steve Carell's,
Donald Rumsfeld,
Christian Bale is a fucking bad
motherfucker.
His acting as Dick Cheney is off the
charts.
I mean he does the voice.
He got fat for it.
Everything.
That's him.
Whoa,
dude.
Here's the video of.
First of all,
him and I'm Sam Rockwell is George Bush.
He's amazing to Sam.
Rockwell is one of the most
underappreciated vice price.
It's amazing,
dude.
Sam Rockwell nails it as joy here played
the trailer where they pull us.
It's too new yet.
Oh son of a bitch.
You turn it up.
A large company.
If you folks who are listening to this
on youtube,
we can't play this for you,
but I mean that's weird.
They wouldn't want you to like play
their trailer.
They want everybody to go to their
trailer.
True.
Oh yeah.
It's strange.
I should make that.
Yeah,
you're right.
It's just so good.
He just does an amazing job of the
voice,
the mannerisms and so to Sam Rockwell.
Well,
they're both incredible actors.
Samara,
mercy.
Sam Rockwell in that movie,
Moon the Moon or moon moon.
I'm not sure.
It's a movie where he is the only person
in the movie.
The entire movies.
I don't want to spoiler alert it,
but it has to do with cloning and it's
him on the moon like him,
him or him in space.
It's fucking amazing.
It's an amazing.
I love
Chuck Barris.
Yes.
That was an amazing movie,
man.
He's a beast.
This guy is a
fucking incredible actor and he just
doesn't get enough credit.
I met.
He's,
I think he might be married to her now,
but he was,
or maybe they're still dating,
but he was dating Leslie Bibb when,
uh,
I did a movie with her and I got a
chance to meet him and I was a little
bit starstruck.
I'm a big giant fan of that guy,
but he's one of those guys I feel like I
want to say like,
dude,
you're fucking amazing.
Like,
I don't know if anybody's telling you
because you're fucking amazing because
it's like,
you know,
you hear about the great actors.
You hear Daniel Day Lewis,
you hear Gary old men,
you know,
you hear Christian Bale,
you hear the,
the great actors,
Faye Dunaway,
sigourney weaver.
You don't hear about Sam Rockwell.
Why Not Jamie?
Why not?
God Damn it.
Maybe you will.
After this movie,
maybe he looks like he's never been
nominated for anything.
Probably was probably was from moon,
was nominated a few things.
That one that just came out last year.
The three billboards.
Oh yeah,
that's what I was thinking.
I just remember hearing about him.
He was getting,
you know,
he's just one of them dudes too.
Like when you're that good of an actor,
you blend into these movies.
So good.
It's,
it's not,
it's not Sam Rockwell.
You know what I mean?
Like that's almost a compliment to the
dude.
Now should he be more of the leading guy
and doing those big rolls.
Yeah,
I agree.
It's an amazing actor.
But he's gotten,
he's done some really big things,
man.
It's just,
he's one of them dudes.
It just blends too.
Good.
You know who's another one like that?
Vigo Mortenson.
Yes.
Everything is in you just lose it.
And he's in it like he's that guy.
Yeah.
Uh,
the,
the one where he was the far eastern
promises.
Yeah.
Was the Russian mob movie in here?
Yes.
And then what?
The Year of violence that he did.
That was a good one too.
It was a good one.
The road freaked me out.
I turned it off when you're teaching his
son how to shoot himself in the mouth.
I was like,
done.
We're good.
I need to watch this.
Watch the flintstones.
Fucking crazy.
So what I heard.
Yeah,
I've heard the books too.
Crazy dark man.
Like that's one of the things like a
sake said,
taste.
That stays with you a little too long.
I want it to go away.
There's a few of those movies that are
just so depressing.
When you leave,
you're like,
what did I do?
Like I don't want to be depressed.
I know that it was good.
I know you nailed it.
I know you.
You dragged my mom once on tour.
I fucking.
It was like back when you got when
everyone.
When the tower records and those things
were still around like on Tuesdays the
movies and the records would all come
out.
So we on tour we would stop and buy a
bunch of shit for the bus by records and
I bought a bunch of movies and I threw
on Magnolia had just come out.
I watched that and I was like,
oh wow.
That was fucking fucked up and then
without looking I just grabbed the next
movie and put it in and it was titus
andronicus and I don't know if you're
aware of like hip to this,
like one of the darkest fucking
Shakespeare fucking place ever about
this dummy goes.
If you ain't seen it when you got
the wherewithal to sit through some real
fucking darkness.
Anthony Hopkins is fucking insane.
In this movie is Titus Andronicus.
It's fucking dark.
So I watched these two movies back to
back and for two weeks joe,
I can't shake the like just seeing like,
oh my God,
there's no happy endings anywhere.
The world's.
From then on,
I'll only watch comedies and fucking
like pixar movies and old warner brother
art students out there on the road.
Man.
Damn.
Why people are hanging in front of them.
I do.
You want to know?
You're never going to watch this.
Right?
He's about to cut them up and make
dinner out of them and serve them and to
their families.
Like it's dark.
It's really dark.
It's one of the darker.
It is the darkest Shakespeare like thing
I've ever read or seen.
Okay.
That's enough.
And that was right after Magnolia.
I A double whammy.
Fresh dude.
Oh,
it was horrible.
I remember that movie.
Twenty one grams.
Yeah.
That movie's swore me off.
A depressing movies.
After that movie was over,
I left the theater.
I'm like,
why did I do that to myself?
I was in such a good mood.
Who wants to.
Who wants to leave a place with that
feeling?
Don't,
doesn't,
doesn't life give you that enough?
I was all happy.
I was all happy,
feeling good.
Uh,
walked into that movie and I left going,
what in the actual fuck,
what am I doing here?
As Dj Kelly would say,
played yourself and other people said it
beforehand,
but he's like known for it.
It's funny how that happens,
right?
I do just says something just right.
And then everybody just connects it to
him.
He had a string of them.
He had a bunch of his little in meeting.
Uh,
you know,
he's got the new deal alerts.
These agencies is a bastion of these
little sayings that people catch onto
it.
He's got a lot of good things going for
him.
He's unthreatening looking because he's
kind of a big Chubby guy.
People like him because of that,
you know,
there's a lot of good things going.
Obviously Energy,
energy likes shiny flashy shit.
People like.
Yeah.
And he couldn't afford it.
It's nice.
Hashtag ball and kind of do it.
Yeah,
I guess so.
Yeah.
Part of that lifestyle,
that's a crazy lifestyle.
Kanye is a part of that lifestyle too.
Right?
But in a weird way,
he's a weird part of that lifestyle.
It's never been a jewel.
That jewelry you seen anything new?
Not really big.
I mean like,
but he's big on design and Ferrari's and
Lamborghini's and beautiful houses and
showing that.
Aware of like winning a note.
Yeah.
Design.
No,
I know just from what I know of him that
he longs to be Ralph Lauren.
That's really his,
you know,
probably like you said,
who is your biggest influence or who
would you want to be?
Ralph Lauren.
Yeah.
That's kind of hilarious.
But he just loves design,
right.
Loves clothes,
I guess.
Yeah.
I mean why not somebodies gotta?
I mean,
he knows all that stuff he was doing was
looking like homeless people's clothing
into.
It's like daryl leaked,
right of fucking suitland or did you see
that one video picture that Jamie showed
me?
He was walking around with slides.
Easy slides on,
but there were like four sizes too
small.
I didn't make any sense.
It's like heels hanging off the back of
him.
Like the way he designed them.
Exactly.
That's like he's probably trying to push
a new thing here.
Tiny yeezy slides too small for your
feet to small yeezy slides.
There you go.
Yeah.
That's the new look.
Like if you're crazy,
you might think it's crazy to me because
there's an era of his career that I look
at it and I'm like,
well man,
there's a lot of genius shit.
He was doing musically a lot of records
he was doing and then I don't know what
it is,
but to me,
to me now,
and I don't say this in a judgmental
way,
but he's a professional troll now.
Just like that's the most successful
people in the.
In the entertainment business.
Now,
if you're not an amazing actor or a
super amazing,
you know,
whatever is like just keeping people
trolling everybody.
He literally dropped a song like at some
point,
like eight months ago where that was
like poop scoop,
scoop it,
Ipu de Boop,
boop,
boop.
You know that sort.
And that was the song.
It lasted that long.
Jamie came and played for me or you told
me the lyrics.
I can't shut the fuck up.
No,
but it's like,
it's again,
it's the spectacle.
Jamie,
you stopped putting this evil in my
head.
It's the spectacle.
Like,
I mean I made this album here.
That's music.
You know what I mean?
This is music.
A lot of people don't give a fuck
anymore.
Well,
you're not that guy.
You've never been a,
I need publicity guy.
Well here's what it is and here's what
that is.
It's like people like to fucking
speculate about what I do or my career.
You know what I mean?
I've written a few songs in this life
that I could go somewhere and sit down
and just sit on a fucking stump and eat
food for the rest of my life.
I never worry,
you know what I mean?
I could feed my family and all that off
of a few songs.
I make music because I love making
music,
you know?
And of course you want people to listen.
You want to fucking the more people you
know,
you want people you want fame or all
that.
But I don't,
I'm not,
I'm not.
Again,
one of the first things is the first
time I ever came on your podcast was
like,
I like going to Ralph's and sitting at
the olive bar and fucking getting my
olives while my songs playing on the
radio and the guys standing right next
to me.
I had no fucking idea.
I don't mind that at all.
That doesn't bother me.
I love you're not a need attention kind
of a guy and some people are and that's
sort of part of their business.
Like this whole Kanye Donald trump
thing.
I just,
I wonder if that's trolling,
but I also wonder if what we were
talking about earlier about car
accidents and brain damage.
I wonder if that's a little bit of
everything,
but also the reason I,
I,
I say it's trolling is because there's
likes and stuff.
When you get to car Dash Ian,
Kanye West levels of,
and I'm sure you know this just you have
for fucking million instagram followers.
I didn't start
instagram until you told me to.
I know that,
but what I'm saying is like,
you could monetize that shit really
easily.
Those 4 million people.
You're not that.
You're not selling that shit out.
These people,
they are definitely monetizing that shit
fucking.
When Kim Kardashian gets on there,
she doesn't give you a commercial,
but she'll tell you,
I'm just using this new cream on my
shit.
You know what I mean?
Here it,
somebody paid her 100 fucking 50 grand
for that post.
You know?
It's like,
that's,
that's so the more eyes,
the better.
That's really what they're monetizing as
I can.
If I had 10 million people on my
instagram,
I could sell fucking posts.
The real problem with that is people
don't believe them,
you know,
like you,
but their eyes are still.
If I say I like something,
it's because I like it.
Like if,
if,
and this is people but cues me and have
an ads,
I've never had a single ad.
I'm my instagram.
If I tell people about a product and
people like,
what are you?
Do you getting paid for this?
Like,
nope.
Nope,
I just like it.
Yeah.
Sharon,
something I thought you might think is
cool done in a few times,
but I usually say,
hey,
I'm not getting fucking paid.
I'm just telling you.
Yeah,
I do now because it is not.
I like this.
You know what I mean?
Plus I ain't got enough instagram
followers to get Jamie.
Jamie was saying you need $70,000.
That's the number.
First of all,
I don't.
I don't know.
I know you don't give a fuck,
but if you did,
if you were a chick with a fake,
but you might be able to get a little.
I might have 4 million followers of.
Yeah,
you might write,
you might have 20.
Look at this.
Kim Kardashian has got $118 million
followers.
Just wow.
Good googly Mowgli.
Okay.
And let's say,
what did they say?
If you're,
if you're actually good at social media,
maybe 10 percent of your audience
engages you.
So that's still 10 million people that
will engage with her.
A lot of fun.
I believe I threw that number out there.
Just cut it sounds about right.
Yeah.
A lot of God damn people.
Woo.
Yeah.
It's a weird business.
Matt's famous now,
like when we were young,
famous was,
you know,
if you're on tv or the radio or you
know,
movies,
if you did something in life,
I wrote a book,
wrote a play or a movie,
you know what I mean?
You invented the plane and that's what
got you famous.
Now you just got to keep eyes on you
doing fucked up shit.
I was thinking about that today while I
was watching gladiator because uh,
what I was watching that movie,
I was thinking the,
in the Roman times there was no
accountability like for emperors,
you could do all kinds of fucked up shit
and no one could do anything about it.
These are the killed you eventually or
you got away with it for a long period
of time.
But today,
you know,
like there's so much,
there's so much accountability.
People find out what awful things you've
done.
They find out you've stolen money or had
people killed or do you know,
took over this or dominated that.
Like this to be a like to be a dictator.
Look at Kim Jong Aoun like someone,
some along those lines today.
You have to keep those people locked up.
Like,
and he's barely keeping that together.
They barely have an amaze me how they
can like,
you know,
like there's not a whole scene there of
people with the Internet like sneaking
it in and you know what they did?
They,
everybody,
rats and everybody else there.
They have like a whole system of ratting
on people.
They have a culture of rats and they
believe their leaders of God or
something of that nature.
They just don't want to die,
man.
They're scared and they're hungry and
they don't have any power.
They don't have any energy because
they're eating just rice and fucking
starving to death.
Even imagined when they catch those
dudes that sneak across the border,
you know,
that make a run for it.
When they get them and bring them to
hospitals and patch them up and shit,
they find all these crazy parasites in
them.
Massive mountain nutrition and these are
soldiers like North Korean soldiers.
They're just all fucked up and this.
But that's a window into time.
Like if you went back into the Roman
days,
this,
that's how everybody was rocking it.
They were all dominating their people
and use an iron fist and keep.
Keep these generals well fed and keep
the army well fed and use it to dominate
the civilians.
And uhm,
I mean,
I know gladiators,
just a movie and just fake and fun,
but still,
you gotta wonder like that.
How close was that to life back then?
And how bad did it smell?
Bad?
I mean like tubes have on hbo called
Rome,
like where they had and they had this
one scene,
I remember it like were they were all in
like a public toilet,
a shittery,
sugary,
and they had it.
I'm like,
what at the time was,
I guess the toilet paper,
which was like calf skin rags or
something.
And they book and like white rats and
they walk out and throw it in a pile.
It's like,
how could that have smelled,
if that's accurate,
if that's accurate.
You know what I mean?
Well,
that lives,
there it is Roman public toilets.
And they would go into like a tube and
that tube would go right down the
street.
Yeah.
I imagine how the whole city smelled
like shit.
Well that was one of the reasons why all
these people got sick.
Like when a disease would spread through
the city.
I mean there was no sanitation.
It was terrible.
But I mean,
how did,
they didn't even have like flushable
things,
right?
Nothing flushed out.
They had developed aqua ducks so they
just had a system of flowing water.
But it wasn't pressurized or anything,
so I just have to pick it up was one of
the things that was cool about Pompei
was they had a sauna.
They had figured out how to boil water
and then they had the water would go
through the floor and the walls they had
like,
like double spaced walls.
So they had one outside wall and the
inside wall and the heat would go
through and they would go through a
sentence.
So you could go into the sauna and you
just like a regular sauna here and be
hot as fuck in there.
Yeah,
they were just pump a sauna.
That's it.
Like they figured out how to make things
pretty cool for what they had,
but fuck live and back there.
But meanwhile tell me people aren't
going to think like that a thousand
years from now about us.
Those dummies shitting into a ceramic
bowl and then hitting the water to flush
it away.
Idiots.
I can't imagine what it's going to be
like.
Did we installed these toilets here?
That shoot hot water up your.
But you know those up or just cleaning
it to a right in the hole.
It shoots right in that hole.
You got to be careful.
Feels like you have to take a shit
because he gets up in there and you're
like,
oh I have to shit again.
But no,
it's just the water's literally getting
through the door,
but it cleans your butthole so nice.
And after you have one of those,
you're like,
why would I ever use a regular toilet?
First Time I was like in the nineties.
In Japan.
Japan.
Yeah,
that's why I experienced it to me.
For me it was just a few years ago,
but Jamie says he holds his shit.
Is that correct?
Preferred versus the home toilet that
like why would,
why should it home if you'd like it make
sense to ship you.
Like I can keep this one in at bay for
me honestly.
Honestly.
I mean like in Europe a bad day is a
normal thing in our hotel room.
It's not here as much as not as good
though.
I have a bad day in my house and never
used it.
Once it's a magazine rack.
I throw magazines there.
Wash your hands.
It's just weird.
It's weird.
It's,
this doesn't work as good as it's.
And I think it's more for women.
Like,
no,
it's a cooter cleanser.
But um,
here's,
here's something funny.
He's like,
I just did this tour of Europe and we
started noticing like,
and I'm not going to name countries by,
you know,
because I have fans and all them.
I don't want him to get upset,
but we noticed there's a different of
some countries you can,
you get washcloths in your bathroom in
some countries you don't [inaudible] and
me and my band,
you know,
came to the conclusion that from now on,
whenever we come to these countries
where you don't get the wash cloths and
your hotel room,
we're not going to shake hands with
people that didn't,
didn't even wash closet in the bathroom.
I don't get it.
Yeah.
What do you wash your hands with bro?
You could wash your hands like this.
What are you washing your arse with,
man?
Shoving your hand crack up.
They're doing.
What are you doing?
I don't mind if you wash your face with
your hands are your hands,
but I'm not going to.
If I can't find a washcloth in the
summer they have garden hoses attached
to the toilet.
They don't fuck around with all that hot
spicy food.
They know it's going to come out messy.
So they give you a goddamn garden hose
to clean your asshole.
Was this Thailand in Thailand?
Everywhere.
Even the airport.
What's the toilet?
The airport right next to the shit box
was this goddamned garden hose.
I mean like when you would wash the car
with like the pistol grip one.
Yeah,
let's just get that fucker back there
and there it is right there.
Garden hose,
bom.
Bom Gun.
They call them gun.
Wow.
Was in Thailand.
Keep yourself clean with a squirt of
water yet a squirt that.
That shit.
That shit could move a boat across a
dock.
Yeah.
Wow.
The direction our conversation's taken
today to test the water pressure before
you use it.
The British called the toilet hose,
that bum gun for a good reason.
The nozzle,
the end of the hose is shaped a bit
loaded gun with a trigger.
The press to release the water.
Yeah.
Wow.
They don't fuck around and tie and been
in Thailand.
Obviously.
It's beautiful there.
People are so nice.
It's one of the friendliest places I've
ever been in my life.
Like universally friendly and everybody
looks at you and they all do this.
They make their hands like a lotus
flower.
That's what they do.
They don't shake hands a lot.
They just touched their hands together
and give you like a little bow there.
Is there.
Is there a wash cloth?
They just tie their hands are tired from
holding onto that hose.
Squeeze,
squeezing that bump gun something.
But uh,
the food there is fucking amazing.
If you like Thai food man,
you learn like from like the way they
cook it in the motherland,
you know,
with all those fresh ingredients.
Thai food.
I love Thai food.
Spicy Guide.
You like spicy?
Oh,
sands.
Being in Thailand,
this spot.
I was in a place in Melbourne,
Australia.
We talked about earlier the hottest Thai
food I ever had in my life.
Like so hot.
You're sweating and you can't stop
eating it because the minute you stop
eating it,
you're going to catch fire.
Have you ever been to exotic tie over on
Ventura and Woodland Hills?
I feel like I have a super legit time.
Bunch of Thai people run it.
Super Nice people.
Food is jamming and there's a spot right
here.
Close.
Not far from the general area.
Uh,
jasmine tie.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
There's a bunch of good Thai restaurants
in La.
Even been to a.
what's that place on sunset that's open
real late.
Oh,
right there.
Next toy toy toy.
Toy ties grant to men.
That's a,
that's a great late night spot.
Like legit Thai food.
You get a 2:00
in the morning,
you know,
after a set of the commerce store
teaser.
Amazing.
That shit's terrible for your diabetic
though.
There's like 180 grams of sugar,
but it's so delicious.
So delicious.
But honestly,
you know,
that's like I used to drink so much coke
and then that's,
that's another one we talked about.
Weight.
That's the first thing I got rid of,
man was drinking Coca Cola.
The weight falls off about 20 pounds of
the 35.
Now it just falls off.
You realize like,
what was I doing was I doing to myself
and just a little bit of cardio and I
was like every other day I was like,
whoa.
I just lost like,
like I said,
$35 because I dropped five pounds out on
the road that I didn't even realize it.
Not even worth trying.
Wow.
Just continuing just consulting that.
And I think that food in Europe is a lot
cleaner just in general.
Yup.
Well they don't have a lot of.
Our,
first of all,
their wheat is like what you would call
heirloom wheat.
They don't have a lot of the complex
gluten's in our wheat that make it a
little bit more difficult to process.
Um,
this is all real thing.
Like people think there's some sort of a
like that people are exaggerating the
effects of gluten and gluten
intolerance.
The issue is that at one point in time
bread was different.
It was just,
it was different,
but it was a lower yield,
so say like if you had an acre and you
were planting wheat on it,
you would get way less wheat out of that
Acre than you would with the newer wheat
and the newer weed is just more complex
gluten's in it and you get a higher
yield.
And so that's what they're looking for
and,
but when you eat it,
it's just harder to digest.
And it's just.
When I was in Italy,
man,
everybody skinny.
Okay.
They're all eating bread,
they're all eating pasta,
they're all eating pizza.
They're all skinny at the most.
These dudes who don't work out at the
most get like a little paunch the most,
uh,
drinking wine every night.
They got a little paunch.
They also walk a lot more than us.
They also ride bikes a lot more than us.
Like they'll,
all those things,
but a lot of time in Holland this last
trip and I couldn't find a fat person to
just biking everywhere,
biking everywhere.
And they're eating cheese and bread all
day.
Yeah.
So like literally every meal she's in
bread with your meal,
but they must be pissed that weed's
legal everywhere else because people
used to go to Holland,
specifically
the friends that own shops over there
and they're like,
yeah,
there's,
there's a lot of fuck.
What's going on right now is there's,
um,
if I understood what he was telling me,
right?
Um,
Canada is investing shit.
Tons of money with the government over
there to like corporate,
like start growing corporate we'd like,
and they're going to phase out to the
locals and take it over.
Like they're going to phase out the
coffee shop because there's weed isn't
legal in Holland.
It's decriminalized.
If you own a weed shop,
you can only have let's say 500 grams of
time in the shop legally.
Alright.
If you have a good shop,
you're moving that,
you know,
in an afternoon.
So,
and getting,
bringing weed to your shop is illegal.
Like it's like it's a smuggling
operation needs to be in there.
And once it's in there it's okay.
Once it's in there,
you could sell it.
But getting it to your spot is,
it's fucking illegal to,
to move that much weed.
It's fucked up.
Like these guys I've know a couple of
guys I want a cup of coffee shops and
they're just like,
it's fuckery man.
You know,
it's like a constant.
It's like half a criminal operation.
They're running and it used to be the,
you get mushrooms,
you used to be able to get mushrooms,
you'd be able to get like a bunch of
shit and now you can't.
Not like hard,
like narcotics,
like coke or anything like that.
But anything natural like mushrooms,
you could get acid.
When I was first in there,
I don't know if that was legal because I
was really young.
I just.
Well Holland,
just a wild ass place.
I mean that is the spot where like some
of the best kickboxing ever came from.
It's weird.
One little spot in Europe and they
created Ramon Dekkers,
Rob Cayman,
Ernesto hoost.
Like some of the greatest kickboxers of
all time.
Everywhere.
Everywhere you go see them with like a
gym.
It's amazing.
Yeah,
I mean it's just amazing that this one
place became a hotbed for a source of
their prize kickbox footballer.
Kickboxing are probably the top two
things.
I mean they literally have created some
of the all time greatest kickboxers and
it's not a big country.
It's really,
um,
and some of the greatest kickboxing
coaches as well,
but some,
it's amazing,
really unusual,
really unusual that,
that happened there.
And it's hard to describe why like no
one really to be an interesting
documentary.
So figure out the roots of that.
Somebody went to Thailand,
you know,
somebody brought it back from Thailand
and.
Yup.
Just switched it up and put their own
little spin on it.
Yeah.
And a few guys went over to Thailand
fuck some ties up to because what they
had done is they incorporated a lot of
western boxing,
like Ramon dekkers in particular was one
of the greats.
And uh,
what he did was he was a small guy,
like the same size as the ties,
which was unusual because a lot of the
people from Amsterdam or big people,
it's one of those places where I think
the average height for a person who was
like six feet tall.
Yeah.
So it's an unusually tall place as shit
going on.
Some fucking Viking DNA.
I was watching that show for awhile.
Vikings.
I got deep into that show,
that show it was pretty dark.
But Mrs Reagan got tired of seeing
people get sorted up slashed to pieces.
She got bored with it.
It's pretty dark.
People would just get fucked up with
arrows cut open and it's the whole show.
They're always going to war.
But they did their viking.
Yeah.
And they took a lot of mushrooms to
pillage,
I believe is viking a way of life.
If you could go back in one time to
like,
if you had like a time machine,
go back and watch one time in history,
what do you think you would go to see
him go to see?
Like how people lived well at being very
smell sensitive.
It wouldn't be that far back.
I'd probably want to go.
I know that's not true.
I probably like,
you know,
King Arthur era.
Yeah.
Like that kind of thing.
I was heavy dungeons and dragons.
Maybe go,
go,
go see if there's anything to add of
that dragon shit.
You know,
the goal,
the grail,
you know what I mean?
Any of that drag shit.
I wonder what that was all based on.
Like why there's so many dragons in folk
lore,
in Chinese folklore and European
folklore.
There's so many unrelated dragons.
Well,
I mean,
you know,
there's people that have been,
I've watched a lot of ancient aliens so
that they'll always have an explanation.
My man with the hair,
Joe,
sucralose.
Georges is a podcast a long time ago.
I love that guy,
dude.
He's my favorite dude on that show,
man.
He's a good dude.
I don't necessarily agree with
everything.
They say no to everything,
but that's.
There's a,
there's merit to some of it,
man.
There was a show you watch with your
boys at like 1:00
in the morning and you get baked and
everybody laughed.
You ever watched the vice virgin where
like action Bronson guys are getting a
complete fucking nonsense,
but if you're high,
it's fucking fun to watch.
He came on the podcast.
I never seen a dude smoked more weed in
my life.
He smoked by himself at least six blunts
during the podcast.
While it's so hard,
man,
I don't think that we'd really fucks
with them anymore.
Man.
I can think it takes that much weed.
He just kept going and I got paranoid
just watching them.
I'm like,
oh man.
I smoked a little bit with them,
but I mean I got to keep the ship on the
water.
Exactly.
You got to let me keep my hands on the
wheel,
sir.
Like he just kept going with that.
We took a photo of the astro after it
was over.
Was preposterous.
Was like,
look at that.
That's one show that he's a crazy guy,
man.
Fun Dude though.
He's a good guy.
I love that.
Fuck.
That's delicious.
Show.
No,
that's a great show,
you know,
without alchemist is a good friend of
mine.
I've known him since he was young,
so they're good buddies.
I've met him.
I hung out with a few times.
It's really fun guy,
man.
It's a unique idea for a show because,
you know,
Action Bronson used to be a chef.
Yeah.
So seeing him like interact with food
and she has like,
he's.
He really knows about food and really
understands food.
Yeah,
I think he should have a cooking show he
actually know can whip up some fucking
mean food.
Yeah,
right.
Like we like now that Bourdain's gone,
like we'd need more of those kind of
shows that explore food and bordain show
changed the way I feel about food.
I used to think of food is just
something that tastes really good.
I didn't think of it as an art form and
then I watched his show and the reverend
he had for chefs and for the creation of
food and made me realize like,
oh,
this is an art form that I was ignorant
of.
I didn't think of it the right way on
all levels.
Not just like the high chef level,
he brings it to the home front where
it's like even as local,
let's eat,
Cook and some sandwiches.
Making sandwiches.
No,
you're right man.
Like street food level.
He loves Tony.
Loved Street Tacos and Shit.
He would go everywhere and by street
food.
Me Honestly,
when you're cooking,
you feel like that though.
[inaudible].
You just now I see you cooking all the
time.
Whenever you're posting.
This should never invite me over to
somebody else.
I was going to set it up here.
I was going to set a thing up here,
but they never figured out how to get
ventilation.
Here we have a grill back there that's
never been used.
It's just sitting back there looking at
me.
He's taken a stake to be nice and pink
in the middle and gorgeous.
He's drinking wine.
I wonder why.
See?
This is how.
How stony his show is like they let him
wear a shirt that you can't wear,
so they had a blur out his shirt thing.
Oh,
okay man.
You can't wear that shirt.
All.
Yo,
I got it all.
This is.
This is what I'm wearing.
So do what you gotta do.
Exactly.
So they got to follow him around.
That blur thing drives me nuts.
Like what is it,
what could it possibly be that.
So,
but it's,
there's,
there's times when I see cyclists back.
Alright,
back when he had that loser video,
the first thing that comes up when the
video is him in a mask that's blurred.
Right.
And I,
and I was like,
what the fuck?
Why would,
why would you wear it was purposely done
like I think sometimes maybe it's like,
yeah,
it's like,
what the fuck?
What is that?
As his back being a Weirdo.
You're but what is it makes you go,
like,
what the fuck is it?
He's a fascinating guy to,
you know,
he's a devout scientologist.
Yeah.
Which is his dad did,
is uh,
is an amazing string arranger,
an orchestrator.
And he,
he,
he did a couple of my albums where I'm
going.
I had string arrangements and stuff.
Really?
Yeah.
I mean he's a legit musician.
Like a really interesting back is his,
is his next level.
You don't hear about him that often.
Again,
another thing,
I think it's the same kind of thing,
dude.
It doesn't.
He's not playing the game.
I mean,
you know,
he makes music.
He's just an artist.
When it's time to make music.
It's music.
Yeah.
There's still.
I mean,
in other words,
it's for me,
I'm sorry,
but it's not,
it's,
it's like,
okay,
this is a product,
this record.
Right.
But it's not a product.
To me,
it's like I did eight years of my life,
you know what I mean?
I didn't make it because I was concerned
about keeping my otherwise that's why
the guy,
because they got to put a record out
every year.
Those are the guys.
I'm like,
Whoa,
how do you fucking.
That's all us,
you know,
that takes a lot to put a fucking room,
especially if it's going to be good.
So anybody that can put out a record
every year,
that's good.
That's next level.
Yeah.
Well Louis Ck was doing that for awhile
at standup.
Yeah.
That is hard to do.
George Carlin did it every year.
George Carlin did a standup special
every year and to us to to all stand up
comics.
Will we all get together and talk about
that?
Everybody kind of agrees.
It's almost impossible.
He did it,
but very few people could do it and not
to criticize Carlin because Carlin and
did it and pulled it off,
but most of us feel like that's not
enough time.
Like you need more time to let it cook.
Need more time to add twists to never
had a record come out.
Like I think the shortest period would
be two years,
two and a half years and that's you
probably just constantly going at it.
Anytime I wasn't touring or something
and we locked in a room somewhere and
trying to make music.
Now when you record,
when you will like say if you're going
to lay down an album,
do you have everything completely mapped
out before you go into the studio or do
you fuck around with it while you're in
there?
Will the process for this album in
particular,
which was wild because again,
when layla was born and the disease we,
we,
we found out she was diagnosed with
cystic fibrosis.
I actually was planning to not tour any
of that anymore,
but I was going to write songs.
I was gonna go to.
I went to Nashville,
started hanging out with a few
songwriters out there and wrote some
stuff.
One of the songs,
it ain't easy,
which I played years ago on your podcast
is on this album.
Um,
uh,
so I wrote some songs with people but
it,
the intention was they were going to be
for other people.
So I recorded them in a very kind of
plain Jane Way.
Not My spin on what they would have been
an after a few years.
I just never really pursued.
It's too much of a sales pitch I had,
would have had you have to go out and
like be that smooth or selling your
songs and it just never appealed to me.
And so after a few years I,
I'm just,
I did an acoustic record and then I
started touring that for awhile,
just old songs,
but I recorded them acoustically.
And um,
then,
uh,
after that was done and I realized,
all right,
you know,
I need to keep working,
what am I gonna do?
I went back and revisited some of these
songs,
but I realized after we record them,
that's why I didn't see that they were
my songs because I recorded the demo way
that I thought other people would want
to use them.
So I went and rerecorded about,
I dunno,
five or six of the songs that were
already here.
And then my buddy evidence from dilated
peoples,
um,
got involved with me and we recorded a
few of these rap tracks and it started
kind of coming together and it kind of
started coming together in a similar way
that the original Whitey Ford sings the
blues record it.
That's why I kind of also named it what
it is.
Um,
there was a lot of similarities and I
feel like I just pulled everything from
every,
every part of the tool box that I've
learned from since I started,
you know,
what it was the ice tea years or the
house of pain years or the Whitey Ford
years.
I just drew on it all and trying to see
what you,
like I said it was the eight years of
life.
It's not like a literal representation
of what's happened to me,
but it's an emotional journey of like
all the kinds of feelings and shit that
I like a lot of struggles and a lot of
it's,
it's my best record,
you know,
but eight years right here.
So I've never been in no rush.
That's a big statement,
but it's your best record.
It's my best record ever.
Um,
I'm confident in it.
It's,
is it available everywhere?
Like the shit out of it.
I own my masters.
I mean,
how does that work?
Do you get more extreme?
Well,
if you own your masters,
you get paid outright.
Like you know,
you're the label on my own label.
So the people that complain about not
getting paid by streaming or people that
are signed to record deals that are
getting a small piece of what the
masters getting a.
do you own the master,
you know,
so streaming is viable for someone who
owns the map.
I mean it's viable period.
I mean,
kids know what I mean.
That's the way it is.
It's just the,
it's the future.
I mean now.
But the people who say it doesn't pay
their in shitty deals,
you know what I mean?
Because it,
it pays.
No,
I would like it to pay a little better.
But you know,
he pays.
He pays.
All right.
Who Was it?
I think if you take a million streams it
equals out to around $8,000.
That sounds like it just in general,
like that's the payment from,
for what that is to have to a label,
like it would be around a million
streams.
This is about the equivalent of about
eight grand.
And uh,
that doesn't sound like a lot,
but a million streams is like,
you know,
a thousand guys that or people fans of
yours that stream you're shit,
whatever thousand times,
100 times,
you know,
it's not,
it goes quicker.
And I think drake like streamed a
billion streams as first week.
Right.
Know that's a nice chunk of change,
man.
David crosby was tweeting about how bad
streaming deals are,
but that is because he has a bad deal as
he doesn't know what his master.
Yeah.
If,
if he's recording a deal for another
record,
for the record company,
you know what I mean?
And he's all his older songs.
Oh,
that's.
Yeah.
Then he's probably got shit deals on.
I mean some of my older stuff,
I don't get paid on what I feel like I
should,
but it's like the stuff since I've owned
my masters,
which is the last 15 years of my life,
you know what I mean?
It's fascinating for me on the outside
looking at what happens with labels and
how they do things.
It's,
it's just,
it's amazing.
They're sort of survival instincts.
How they figured out how to labels or
signing casters now because of streaming
streaming.
You should be getting checks from this
Joe.
I don't,
I don't allow them to stream me.
But honestly you could come in door a
spotify.
I say nope.
Well you'd probably have to be exclusive
to one of them is the deal to um,
well either way what they are is just,
it's not just streaming digital.
Your Youtube views are streaming.
That's streaming doesn't have to be with
a streaming service.
Right?
I mean,
but you,
you should have a digital company that
is representing you,
that's collecting all that.
If you don't know,
I just make sure.
Yeah.
But that's like streaming.
It's,
you know what the youtube thing,
the most fascinating thing about it is
it's only youtube.
That's the crazy thing.
We think about how big the Internet is
and there's really only one thing like
youtube,
it's a,
it was a good moment.
They came and the branding and
everything they did.
I saw like,
I don't know if it was a documentary
because it wasn't full length,
but it might've been just like a little
like feature,
like within a news kind of segment thing
about how the,
you know,
the original videos that were huge on,
on youtube or like a kid biting another
kid.
And like the original first for the
longest time,
the most played video on youtube was the
charlie biting the kid or something,
you know,
that's where it all came from.
Like it almost came from America's home
video,
like funniest home video kind of thing.
Youtube kind of filled in that void for
a long time.
They were memes before there were memes.
They were just viral videos,
you know,
um,
that's so long ago.
That's crazy.
It's like a decade ago and that,
well,
I mean the necessity of having to change
the music business is what changed
youtube,
you know,
because they caught on like ritv knows
and play videos anymore and nobody's
buying records.
So we got to.
So you know,
the whole,
the whole thing for the longest was like
when the bottom had really fallen out
for a while of making any money off of
actual records was like,
well you can pull my record and you can
download my record,
but you can't download the tee shirt
that.
So it became sell the lifestyle.
So the music became background music to
everything else.
It was part of the lifestyle and the
cars and this and all I wanted you to do
is really go by this limited edition tee
shirt that I'm sending you right now.
You know what I mean?
That's what that's the game changed into
and it's still that.
You know what I mean?
That's why the fuck are you in the troll
ism and all that because people want
eyes on them.
So the next thing they have the
opportunity to sell,
they can sell.
Yeah.
That's what's interesting to me about
labels is now labels get a piece of
everything.
They do these three 60 deals.
Don't say Chris,
that was unheard of.
You didn't get that many tee shirts or
you get piece of it.
They get pieces of live money because
every,
you know,
it's like how cool it used to be like I
had to pay you.
I used to be like,
alright,
a record label would give me half a
million dollars.
All right.
And I'd go and make a record with that.
I'd have,
I could spend whatever I want and making
a record and whatever the rest of money
leftover was mine.
That 500 grand was mine.
I spend it all making the record or I
could spend 50 grand making a record and
pocket the rest.
That was up to me.
Um,
and then after that,
my job,
your job as a label is to sell that
record.
My job was to hit the road and go tour
and I go to her for a few years and at
first I'm not even making money touring
and you're giving me money to go out
there and tour.
It's called tour support.
That used to be.
And that actually gets added onto your
bill.
You didn't get paid?
No.
You would get like money for tour.
But like it wouldn't cover like a bus
and abandon all this.
So that the label would supplement that
with what they called tour support,
which would also become part of the
debt.
You owe the label,
but as you built your live audience,
your guarantees would go up sooner or
later you can stop taking that money and
then your record sales would pay that
off hopefully if you were doing well
enough and now you've got your own
stream of revenue with live t shirts,
all this other outside shit that yours.
That's the way it was when I came up.
Now it's like that's not a deal.
They want it how they sneak that in
because when napster and shit drop the
bottom out of the record business,
nobody was paying for records.
Labels weren't going to give you a half
a million dollars just for your record
because nobody was buying records.
They want to sell your tee shirts to.
Isn't that amazing?
Note they figured out how to stay alive
like that just because they always knew
that people are going to be needy.
It always it.
It all boils down to this too,
and I host somebody one day like really
investigates this and make some sort of
documentary about it is like they had so
many opportunities to be ahead of the
movie industry,
didn't take the same hit.
They took hits and they deal dealt with
piracy,
but they,
the music industry had a moment,
if you remember,
there was like some kids that got in
trouble for downloading ridiculous
amounts of music and their parents were
being held responsible and the music
industry backed off of it because the
news wasn't good.
The movie industry never backed off of
that kind of shit.
They've told you,
we're going to fucking sue your life
off.
People did get sued for your music,
but the music industry backed off
though.
They didn't put the pedal down and keep
the foot on the neck like,
you're going to steal this.
This costs.
You got to remember back then,
if I were to got a half a million
dollars,
I probably would have spent up to to
have that on a record,
$200,000
just on them making studio time.
Whoever's got to be involved,
engineers,
producers,
200 grand off top,
just minimum we would have spent on a
record and then it gets.
You go out and people steal it.
Right.
You know what I mean?
It's the same,
you know we're going with do you ever
download shit for free?
My thing we not.
At first my thing became later like,
okay,
this is what,
this is the wave,
whatever.
But if I adapt my.
My philosophy was if I downloaded your
shit and light,
I liked it.
I would go.
I'd go buy it.
Like I,
if I,
if I downloaded it and it was trashed
and vague,
I looked at it as like a taste test.
That's okay.
Maybe if more people adapted that things
would have.
But again,
the record industry had plenty of
opportunities to jump ahead of it.
And B,
they didn't.
There was technology out there already
that people were dealing with bringing
it so that I'm telling him and this wave
is coming.
So when the recommendation was making so
much money at that time,
if you look at the amount of money they
were making off of the boy bands and the
Brittany Spears is enough that it was
retarded how much money was in the
record business and they let it all go
down the drain because they thought they
had all the answers and they thought it
had no money.
What could they have done to stop?
I'd have to go back.
I have some books on it.
Like there was taking out a lot street
people.
There were people ready there to help
set up things like master and how to
monetize it and control it.
Like there was ways to deal with it.
There were ways to be part of it instead
of like wait till it was too late.
Will think about the movie industry too
though,
is that people want to go to the movies.
Like the experience is not as good.
Apple Music saves the music industry.
Like apple.
If first items,
why didn't the recognition like there
were people telling them,
this is coming and I didn't mean to
interrupt you,
but I don't think they could have made
the itunes first,
not called Itunes,
but like the industry itself should
digitize and been ready,
right?
Would have been that simple.
Come up with their own version of itunes
and they could have invested a lot more
money to music industry is booming,
but artists are losing big because most
artists are signed to record deals with
just 12 percent of revenue.
Twelve percent whoa.
Forty $3,000,000,000
a year was its most profitable year
since 2006 listeners to spending more
money than ever,
largely on streaming and live music with
consumer spending tow totaling more than
$20,000,000,000
last year.
Wow.
Yet artists aren't feeling the increase
of the 20 billion music industry
entities such as record labels took home
10 billion musicians taking home just
five point 1 billion with the majority
of the revenue coming from touring and
concert sales.
It's amazing.
That's amazing that it's like a
parasitic industry.
It's like you.
They don't.
People don't necessarily need them the
way they used to.
No,
not they'd like they use to.
I was going to just play devil's
advocate and say,
well,
it used to be that I'm the guy to put up
all the.
If I'm the label,
Oh,
I'm putting up millions of dollars in
advanced gambling it on you right now.
When you.
When you want to take away my lion,
share it.
No,
fuck you.
Now it's totally different.
Now you can do this on your own.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
You could start an instagram started
youtube.
Start this and you can make beats on
your laptop or like,
right.
Isn't that the guy who does everything?
Everything he's done is his own shit
online.
Sure,
sure,
sure.
Yeah.
You don't believe it.
What do you mean?
Oh,
Jamie's got a conspiracy theory
conspiracy,
but he's got more support than he would
say.
Now he does.
Sure.
Yeah.
Now it does.
Maybe,
but I mean basically has become huge all
on his own.
Right.
And you meet me,
you look,
it's like so many viral music hits,
you know,
they get,
they get big online just because kids
share it and they like it.
Then then it becomes gigantic.
Like with the music industry that the
industry,
the,
the labels have nothing to do with that,
right?
No.
There's labels that are doing their
thing out there that they actually know
what they're doing in marketing wise and
all that.
There's still a lot of kids that are
being made famous by label.
So there's some benefit.
I mean there's a lot of these,
a lot of the reasons that some of these
artists are only seeing five point one
minutes because they're signed to record
deals.
You know,
Jay z ain't only seeing five,
five percent of what he's due because
he,
you know,
he's been in the game long enough,
and they started out with their own
label.
They started to beverly beginning
Rockafella records was independent.
So that's the kind of,
you know,
those guys are never gonna lose as long
as you know,
they can still make music that people
buy.
Yeah.
They figure out a way to rope you in
early to work,
like even if your record is successful,
the second record,
it's not like you're going to be able to
be independent on the second record.
They'll you,
they own you for several down the line.
Right?
Usually,
I mean it used to be.
I think the standard was like eight,
eight that.
But that's it.
That's,
it's,
it's misleading because it depends on
where you're from too.
There's also like,
you know,
if your first record was very successful
and you have a lawyer that has anywhere
with all your renegotiating before you
do second record,
you know what I mean?
These are things you learn,
but like if you're struggling that at
eight record thing too.
Also if you study the record business,
it goes back to like when actually
artists used to be built that like over
it.
Nobody expected the first album to do
anything.
Like when you signed bands like in the
sixties,
the bike,
you know,
they had a plan like my album three and
four,
here's where we'll be used to build
artists.
They used to be a and are they actually
used to nurture and fucking take care of
a band for a long time and watch them
grow?
What I mean,
that's the way it used to be until like,
you know,
whatever it was.
I maybe the eighties had changed.
I had a record deal for my comedy album
in 1999.
I had a record deal with warner
brothers.
It was like a real record deal,
like a met with them.
They,
they promoted it the whole deal.
I was like,
I went through the whole record industry
business and there was always a comedian
or two on labels,
so they don't have that anymore because
comedy albums,
the do it yourself.
Well,
it's not just that you definitely can do
it yourself,
but comedy albums just aren't that
popular anymore for some strange reason.
Well,
because it's,
it's,
it's a peer support.
Also the art form you want to watch it
exam was about to say it's so.
It's so visual that now
comedy albums were big when everybody
didn't have a TV screen or everything is
like you could listen and imagine what
we.
What he was doing or saying and
translate super well,
like Mitch Hedberg translates amazing to
cd to,
to,
to just audio only because his,
he basically just stands there and tells
great jokes.
Like he doesn't have like,
there's,
it's fun to watch them,
more fun to watch him,
but once you know what he looks like and
how he does it,
it's kind of cool to listen to it on the
albums.
I was just talking about Steven right
the other day to Steven Wright was a
genius.
He was amazing.
Yeah.
But that,
that style is hard to do.
See what,
what Mitch Hedberg basically did was do
that Steven Wright style,
but like a more stony drug style but,
but the drugs allowed him to come up
with way more of those things.
Hedberg he just go on for days.
He had so much fucking material man.
That guy wrote constantly.
He was always writing until the end.
In the end,
you know,
the drugs got to them.
Obviously they killed him.
But um,
he was uh,
his,
that's a,
that's a non sequitur style.
That's the hardest style of comedy.
You say one thing and then you say
something totally unrelated to the next
joke and the next joke.
Totally unrelated.
No sequencing or no man and you know,
it's all segues.
I'm sorry,
that wasn't a secret.
Yeah,
that's an outlet.
Sequency too.
It's like they don't.
They don't fit in together in any way,
way,
shape or form.
They're just total non sequitur.
It's just.
Here's a funny thing.
I thought of his,
another funny thing I thought of,
you know,
but his style is so unique.
Just the way he delivered things was so
unique.
He was funny just talking about nothing
like talking about anything.
One of my favorite jokes at his.
He goes,
he goes,
somebody asked me if I want a frozen
banana.
I said,
no,
but I want a regular banana later.
So yes,
just silly joke,
but it's such a great job.
Oh Man.
All Day.
He's got like one of the best.
He's his albums with some of the best
donor material of all time.
Maybe the best made me go listen to
some.
Oh,
he was an incredible man,
so I'm familiar.
I just haven't listened to him or heard
any of them throwing them on every now
and again when I'm on my way to the
airport,
I you still listened to on serious all
the time,
the comedy channel than the dirtier,
darker one and he'd pop on there every
once in a while.
Yeah,
yeah.
That.
Yeah.
I haven't had Sirius in forever.
Do you still?
It's used to listen to that now because
I just,
yeah,
I don't really honestly,
my favorite thing in the car is silence
really by myself.
Like I,
I get a lot of thinking done driving
like it's or like if I'm ever really
like stumped while I'm working on a
song,
like because I don't write things down
or anything.
Like just I'll get in the car and drive
and then somehow it'll work itself out.
I can really just relax behind the
wheel.
Yeah,
I know what you mean.
Unless I'm in the middle of like fucked
up,
be like at night I can get in the car,
I could drive on an open road and it'll
just.
It really relaxes me.
I have a car that it take to the comedy
store all the time and it's a 1993.
Porsche doesn't have any radio,
no radio.
It's manual transmission,
no power steering,
no air conditioning.
It's just,
it's just an old car and everything,
like when,
when you drive it,
you feel every bump into you shifted.
But because of all that I have to think
and it makes it fires my brain up
because I'm doing all these different
things,
hitting a clutch,
shifting the gears,
you know,
managing this heavy steering wheel and
all that jazz.
And when I get to the store,
my brain is like charged up because of
it.
It's like I've been doing a bunch of
things.
It's exercise and your brain.
I'm not in the back seat,
sleeping,
you know,
waiting to get to the show.
And then I leave myself up.
I love to drive.
Do you still get that crazy audi?
No,
not right now.
I have a judge just bought a truck
actually.
And I got a um,
a cls 63 s yeah.
It's nice that I just couldn't bring the
kids in the Audi,
but I'm actually,
I miss it so much.
I'm actually about to get another one so
they have a new one and I know.
What do you think of a car?
I was like,
alright,
I gotta hit the road for about three
months.
I'll be back with that car.
It's an amazing car.
Yeah,
it's a good time if you're into cars.
They got a lot of crazy ass fucking
automobiles now.
Jack,
when I did have the rn man I would just
like.
And then I lived much further south.
Actually lived off the 15,
like below the 91 and I would,
when I would shoot to sometimes it's not
the biggest for fights.
I would just show up in the Ra like on a
Thursday night,
like 11:00
I'll be there,
but to get there like three hours,
like Jesus.
I mean I was already on the 15.
I wasn't coming from deep la still
Jesus,
but I do.
I do like a fucking book the whole way
fast.
That's a four wheel drive car to that
tech cars glued to the ground.
It's like on fucking rails,
man.
It's one of my favorite cars I've ever
driven.
Yeah.
It's in the style,
like it's still relevant,
like they've kept that style basically
with just a little few facelifts and
improvements for a few years.
Essentially like a mini Lamborghini.
Right.
It's the same engine.
Yeah.
That's the Guy Yardo at the same engine
as the guy who was a vet.
I mean it's more than enough power.
The crazy thing about today's cars are
so they have so much power.
It's just ridiculous.
Like every year it's like a new faster
zero to 60 time.
New Records on the nurburgring.
It's like,
what are you doing?
Like what are you taking this?
Like what are you going to drive this
thing that fast,
you know,
just going to be teleporting the new
corvette,
Zr one has 700 and something fucking
horsepower.
How does the,
how does even stay on it?
Barely does that.
One of the drivers from GM,
one of like the head execs from gm took
it on a race track like when they were
first releasing it and crashed like
immediately spun out and slammed into
the fucking wall.
You got to know what the fuck you're
doing.
If you're you're throttling.
I mean you have to be able to navigate
that throttle with 700 horsepower
because no matter what those wheels are
spinning,
I'm going to how much especially rear
wheel drive them and how much traction
control do you have ever seen that
video?
See?
Find the fucking hilarious.
It's a good video to watch to let you
know like this is a crazy vehicle that
you people are selling.
You're,
you're letting people get a car that is
so much faster than anything that was on
the road five years ago.
I mean,
it's a fucking insane mobilian this
speed limiting changed.
That car comes in handy.
Germany.
Yeah.
GM exec crashes.
New Corvette Z R one.
I mean he got.
This was before it was even released.
This dude showed everyone I got an extra
one you sent me.
That was funny.
I was talking about this guy,
but I liked a picture of his so long ago
and like,
here it is.
Look at this guy.
Play that again.
This play it from the beginning.
This knucklehead started to click.
I'll see if there's more angles on.
No,
no,
no.
Look at this right away.
This,
this guy.
Hey,
I know how to drive.
I'm a fucking executive.
Wow.
Yeah.
He's driving like an asshole.
He doesn't know how to drive.
Sorry sir.
Put the foot down and he doesn't know
what the fuck he's doing.
Dumb ass.
Look that.
That's a car that you have to know how
to navigate once the side one the asset
kicks out to.
He was just stomping it.
Sure he got uh,
he felt like a nice amount of shit at
the next board meeting.
We should look at that fucking car
though.
Good Lord.
What a beast of.
What are they retailing for?
Oh,
it's more than a hundred.
I think it's like 150,
160,000
probably fully loaded,
but is a monster.
It looks like what they've done to the
body stuff.
See,
but you know where your Ra has a huge
advantage.
You're,
you're already as a four wheel drive car
and 755 horsepower.
Good Lord.
Good Lord saying Lord.
But the problem is it's hard to keep all
that power down on the,
on the ground with a rear wheel drive
car.
You're just going to get a lot of
sliding and if you know how to drive you
like that.
People who know how to drive,
they want to kick the ass end outside
ways.
But like if you drive a like say a
Nissan gtrs perfect example,
one of the best things about that car as
a regular person can drive it pretty
fast because there's a lot of
electronics and what they would call
nanny controls and sort of keep
everything in order.
So that car has been around for a long
time.
They really haven't changed a whole lot
about the way it looks.
They've,
but they've made these incremental
improvements and performance and to this
day that is one of the cars you could
drive.
That car is a mother fucker.
I rented one of those in Austin last
year.
Holy Shit.
Was it fun to crazy to like does it
defies logic?
It defies physics.
That's the NYSSMA one.
You don't want that one unless you want
to take it to a track because that
shit's harshest.
Fuck.
You just want the regular one.
The regular one is beastie enough?
They're amazing cars though.
All the pop up windows trying to get you
to buy it,
buy it,
buy it.
But really if I was going to get a brand
new Japanese car,
the real car to get now is the new NSX.
The new NSX.
Tj dillashaw has one.
He brought it in here and I was checking
it down outside.
Fuck man.
It's got electric engines on top of the
regular engines.
It's a,
it's an amazing car.
Just fucking amazing.
And it's gorgeous.
Oh the accurate.
Okay.
And they have a 2019 one's coming out
then as even more improvements,
but it's hard for them to sell these
cars because like look at how good that
looks.
Good.
That looks.
God,
they still kinda partial to the Audi.
Audi is a beast.
I love it.
Look,
it's just it's apples or oranges.
Just what you're into.
Tj has got that color to that blue bolt.
Pull up 2018 Audi R,
eight.
Nineteen.
Oh,
look at that.
Gorgeous.
Come on son.
You got to get silver too because it
looks like a fucking spaceship.
That's a monster car.
Look how beautiful that is.
That's one of the best looking cars I've
ever seen.
A book.
Eighty two,
something like that.
Monster.
Monster vehicle.
Just ridiculous looking car.
Yeah,
and easy to drive to.
It's one of those cars.
Is this just a.
it's glued to the ground.
Four wheel drive,
electric power steer or electric engines
controlling the wheels.
Crazy brake system's amazing.
Fuck God dammit.
Look at that fucking thing.
Correct.
One hundred and 59.
Cheese Mo's.
That's a lot of Cheddar.
Chow.
Chow,
but it doesn't have the sound that your
car had.
See the thing about the Audi is they
have that big ass fucking v eight or the
[inaudible] depending on which one.
Again,
that'd be.
That's,
that's a different thing,
man.
It's a different thing.
What does that beast.
Oh,
what the fuck?
Two thousand 19.
Our eight Lms,
oh,
that's the race car.
That's a monster as gorgeous.
Pull up.
Two Thousand Nineteen Audi r eight.
People get mad.
We talked too much about cars but
couldn't even afford to lose cars pro
while you're talking about these cars
say cause it's fun.
That's.
That must be the camouflage one actually
hurts or I saw on twitter someone posted
a picture.
They saw one like this.
Driving with like the squared paint job.
I've seen that.
Yeah.
They,
they drive them all over cities and
everything like that to testament.
Yeah.
They do that for quite a long.
I've been around a few of those cars.
You ever see the one that they still do
what?
With regular cars?
I remember when the.
Remember the PT Cruiser?
Yes.
When that was first by long before it
came out,
like about a year before it came out.
They would like see this ugly fucking
thing driving around with these
magnetic,
like covers all over it.
So you couldn't see the car,
but you could totally tell what the
shape was.
Right.
It was fucking hilarious.
Nobody gives a shit about that car
anyway.
What they're going to steal your design?
No one's stealing the car.
And I drove one.
Once I had,
I rented one because it looked kind of
cool.
I said,
I'll take one of those.
That's kind of cool looking all my God,
what a death trap I was driving.
I was like,
this thing has zero control,
like you can't corner in it.
The break suck.
Just looked like an old surfer car.
Way Worse.
I've rented a Hummer h three once.
I wouldn't,
never even.
Oh good Lord.
And I took it on a dirt road.
I was in,
uh,
in Colorado.
We drove up this hill,
that Dura,
like every time I was going around a
corner,
it was kicking out sideways and then
things like zero traction was a terrible
car prowler.
Oh,
never.
Interesting.
Cyber chip foose design.
That same guy who built my barracuda or
designed by Barracuda,
not built it.
Yeah.
No,
thanks.
Yeah.
Disgusting.
That was like the hot wheel you hated.
Right?
You're like,
get this one out of here,
man.
The hot wheel.
You put a firecracker and yeah,
give me that old corvette.
Fuck this little thing.
Yeah,
they tried those.
They tried those for awhile.
Know it's an interesting time for cars.
Doe down.
They mean and people are starting to go
towards electric cars.
Have you driven a tesla yet?
No.
That's a goddamn space machine.
Those things are rocket ships are so
fast.
They don't even make any sense.
They don't make any sense.
There's zero to 60 in two seconds.
That's crazy.
There are so fat.
There's.
There's no,
there's no gears.
Right?
Because there's no trends.
The transmission is not the same because
there's no,
it's not a combustion engine has to feed
in the transmission,
the clutch and all that stuff.
Kind of like when you just let roadster
press forward on the remote control
cars.
Right,
exactly.
Just to make sense.
Yeah.
Just electric car.
That goes one point nine second son zero
to 60.
What?
In the actual fuck and it can go 620
miles before you have to charge it.
That's crazy.
That's going to be a monster.
Yeah,
and long.
You got to wait to get one.
Hey,
maybe you got a word in which your
buddy.
Yeah,
I was not ready yet.
It's 2020.
They're going to start selling them.
I don't even think they've.
They've not even in production.
Meanwhile he's shot.
Went off into space.
Look how pretty it is though.
God,
when I think comes out.
That's a gorgeous car.
That's a CGI though,
right?
No,
no,
because remember they had one.
They shot into space.
Look at that.
Look how fast that fucking thing goes.
One point nine seconds.
Two hundred 50 plus miles per hour.
I mean,
what the fuck?
That's going to be one of the most
amazing cars ever.
Once it actually comes out.
That's kind of cool.
Save up your Cheddar.
200 gs.
Two 50.
Fully loaded.
Whoa.
It's just a quarter brick doc.
I said founders series reservation.
What does that mean?
Cool.
Awesome.
Yeah.
That guy was a weird guy to talk to
because I couldn't get over all the
stuff he does like how do you do all
these different things?
How do you make these and then you make
roof panels and then you like drilling
tunnels and then you shoot and rockets
into space.
Space X.
Yeah,
he's doing everything he alien said he
was.
Maybe we should listen,
said he was an alien.
He might be.
Might be a higher thinking life.
Well,
he might as well be right if he was an
alien and he looked exactly like that.
I'll be honest,
when he grabbed the joint in the way he
kind of looked at it,
I was kinda like,
it seemed kind of like a guy who was
kind of like,
we're not familiar with this practice,
but.
Or maybe he's so smart that he thought
it would be funny if you print attended.
He didn't know what a joint was.
Could be.
I don't think he didn't know what it
was.
I'm just saying as he was about to
partake,
he kind of had this real inquisitive
lake.
Yeah.
But there was a part.
It was a blunt and he almost seemed like
he didn't know what a blunt was.
Like you've never been a believer that I
can believe that the glass tip could
have thrown them off because that's a
little unique.
If you're not.
If you're not familiar.
Not Everybody is hip to weed culture,
man,
as we think.
You know what I mean?
Right.
But when he said that Tesla is going
private funding secure at 4:20,
which is $20,000,000
for that joke,
that joke cost them $20,000,000
to sec got mad at him.
They find him.
It was also your stock price is a little
bit.
Well that was one of the things in your
shareholders into a panic.
Jamie was concerned that they were going
to contact us and see if we arranged
that pot smoking part.
Like if that was something that had been
arranged in advance because it crashed
the stock stories.
That was.
I was like Joe Rogan making noise out
here.
Jesus.
We didn't do that.
Did.
We definitely didn't.
Yeah.
That was organic folks.
It was amazing.
Strange.
That's what this podcast is for.
Yeah.
For strange shit.
Strange moments that you can't get on
NBC.
Well you can't even get it on Netflix.
You know what I mean?
A liquid norm.
Macdonald's show on Netflix like he's a.
he's got that thing that he's doing with
Netflix is probably the most
unrestricted of all networks of all
things you trying to do.
And in terms of comedy,
there's nothing ever been like it's the
greatest thing.
Netflix for sure is the greatest thing
that's ever happened to up comedy ever.
I can see that.
Never been accompanied special.
You want to give you no feedback.
They don't.
They don't give you.
They don't fuck with you at all.
They don't.
They don't censor you.
They don't tell you what to do.
They don't me.
They have.
Some people have said some things that
they wanted to edit out.
What's a number has to be like way,
way across the line for the Joe Rogan
numbers are they?
That's when they come to you and they
said,
here's your special.
We're going to do this.
But they know what they are doing.
They don't.
They know who you are,
what you do.
They know their sign on what you are
doing,
your special with you because they know
how many eyes you're going to bring to
the channel.
Yeah.
They know what they're doing,
but it's still just having this ability
to have something streaming.
I was like,
there's never been like if you,
if you,
if you are a person who said,
oh,
I want to do a show on this network,
forget about Netflix.
Like if you just decided,
that's almost like,
I don't want people to watch this.
I want people to watch it one time.
We want it to be on 10 PM,
Saturday,
October 17th and that's it.
Like,
cool out.
Fuck wants that.
Nobody wants to.
You want someone to be at the airport
with their phone and be and I want to go
to Chris rock special.
Let me check it out right now.
Bam.
Amazing.
And then you're sitting there on your
own just watching it.
The only.
There is no live TV and all that's gone
the wayside.
It's useless.
It's,
I see commercials now I start laughing
like,
ha ha,
you fucking dinosaurs.
Which your bullshit ass commercials and
I just finished ozark.
Did you finish it the second season?
Don't say anything.
I'm still starting the second season.
I'm on second episode.
It's so good on the episode where they
just the the,
where the hand guy blew the hand
earlier.
Don't you should spoiler alert that sir.
What?
Nobody knows why when or don't people
out there?
I'm just saying Netflix is killing it.
Stranger things.
You ever watch that show?
No,
I'm playing for the next season.
Goddamn Netflix.
Here's what Netflix is for.
Like for me and my wife.
That's like one of our things.
We find a show.
Yeah.
So spend some time together.
It's too.
Yeah.
She found like,
you know what I mean?
Stranger things I think I found.
But yeah,
we,
that's,
that's our thing.
Like,
well like Ozark has been kind of tough
for us because we watched the first
episode of season two and then I went on
tour for a month so we just watched the
second one and I got to leave now.
So it's like.
And we can't,
we don't have time to binge the whole
thing.
So is there any other good ones that I
need to know about?
People occasionally tweet me once and I
forget.
There's a weird German one called I
think dark.
I mean it's,
it's,
it's subtitled,
this stuff,
but it's crazy black mirror.
Of course you.
Yeah,
black men watched the show though shit.
But that is a weird one.
That's one of those ones that I watch.
Look,
I'm stone.
I come home from the comedy store and
I'm smoking a little weed and I'll watch
that and I'm like,
why am I watching someone that you were
about the one,
the star trekking one and that's what
made me go look at it.
And I was like,
let me go look at it again because I
think I watched it in the beginning.
I think I tried early on and it was the
one where the politician had the fuck
fuck the DA.
Yeah.
So,
and that kind of just seems like all
right,
sorry,
whatever.
This weird shit.
And I probably just wasn't as good.
I don't want to.
But then when you told me about that,
when I went back,
started there and that was the last
season and I worked my way back and
actually got to that one again and
rewatched it and I was like,
oh these are all pretty crazy.
Did you see heavy metal?
You see that one?
That's the one with the drones.
The drones coming after people.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Well,
Well that's too close to home.
I binge watched black mirror.
Pretty tough over just two or three day
period.
And like for like a couple of weeks I
was convinced I'm living in a simulation
like after watching,
especially the dating ones where they
just keep me.
Just blew my mind a little bit.
That was another thing that Ilan must
freaked me out about.
He was saying it's quite possible that
we are living in a simulation.
Oh Dude,
I,
I'm always playing with that idea.
Like is it like you posted something the
other day that was like someone.
Oh,
what was the trump thing with?
Was that a real t shirt by the way?
It's a,
well,
it's a real teacher that you can buy,
but it's not from Donald trump store.
It's a company that sell them.
It's like trump store.shop.
Uh,
yeah.
So we're living in a movie.
I was like,
yeah,
the sick.
That's fake news.
It's not fake news.
It's a real short.
I know it's not his,
but eat the fact that that's a shirt.
It says,
I like beer and it has a guy who's run
did trying to put this guy in the
supreme court.
It's fucking hilarious.
The whole world is hilarious.
Hilarious.
All fucked up.
Yeah,
but this is one of the cool things about
black mirror is like black mirror
showing you like where some things could
go in a total dystopian way.
Like where do you see crocodile that
episode?
Crocodile is the one way you can.
We.
You can record memories and they did all
of them.
I just don't know the title.
Remember this lady.
Remember this lady with the car
accident,
the beginning and insurance company.
Remember this,
remember this.
This was the darkest of the dark ones.
That one was so fucked up.
That one wrecked me.
Oh,
that was the one where the people could
a rewind each of those memories in
playback.
Yeah.
Which is all that is coming.
Oh,
that's easily call.
This shit is coming.
Then there's the one where it was.
It wasn't super dark,
but it was where the chick was trying to
up her status in the world.
Yes.
Stars up the Star Trek.
One's my favorite.
I think that one was fucking amazing.
Is it going?
It was amazing and it's just in that is
this sort of weird blend of current
reality.
One a possibility of where it was the
chicken session and like she doesn't
know where she is,
who she is,
whatever.
And everybody's recording the murderer.
That was a crazy one too,
man.
It's fucking amazing show.
Yeah.
I only do it if you hadn't mentioned the
Star Trek
when I probably never would have
revisited that.
So good.
There's so many good shows.
Now.
What else is good?
What else I need to know about anything
you've seen it.
It's not a show.
It's a,
I think a documentary ish.
It's like Kinda like half documentary.
And then they did some like
recreation's.
Um,
it's called wormwood now.
It's all about the,
uh,
the uh,
the acid CIA,
mk ultra program and shot a Netflix.
It's on Netflix.
Yes.
Wormwood.
Oh,
you got to check it.
It's still.
You don't want my favorite one.
They did.
Do you know what operation midnight
climax as it sounds.
They ran a brothel and they gave.
They gave John's.
The guys would come to the fuckery and
they would,
uh,
they would give them acid to run tests
on.
They loved,
give people acid back in the fifties.
They didn't know what it's called.
Wormwood.
Yeah.
It's really good.
Man.
Has like a really good actor,
like doing the,
playing the main role.
Like when they do the recreation's,
you'll recognize him.
I forget his name,
but he's been in that time.
He was in that movie.
The other marines were with a guild hall
where they were in Iraq.
He was as part of our head,
no jar jar.
Head partner in jarhead.
He was that guy.
He's in a lot of stuff.
I can't remember his name.
He's a really good actor though.
This is just almost too much good shit
to watch today.
Oh yeah.
Another one I watched because he was
the,
the documentary a wild.
Uh Oh wow.
Wow.
Wild country.
And then it all started coming back.
Like I remember that news when we were
like,
when I was young,
this game for that at all,
it started being like,
oh man,
I kind of remember this.
You don't really know what.
I just watched three identical
strangers.
Oh Dude.
About the triplets to.
Oh Dude,
I can't even,
I'm not going to spoiler it,
go watch that.
Some netflix thing to it.
It's,
it's a big site.
Got It on.
I rented it on Itunes for like five
bucks.
Three identical strangers.
It might not be on Netflix.
No,
no,
no.
But it's basically some triplets that
were separated at birth.
And,
and um,
did I say birth?
Birth at birth and uh,
the store that.
I mean,
and that's,
that's the first 20 minutes is amazing.
After that it gets crazy.
Like,
and dark.
Really?
Yeah.
Okay.
Let's come back onto.
Oh yeah,
making a murderer.
Is that so,
is that Netflix three identical
strangers?
It didn't say.
It says a documentary.
I don't know if it could be.
Well,
wild wild country is just God damn
amazing.
It was a cnn film so it could be on
Netflix too,
but right now it's on itunes and you
have to run it.
So I don't think I found it on Netflix.
You know,
what's weird about wild wild country and
it's weird about all these crazy sex
cult.
It's like part of it.
You Go,
yeah.
Like they got,
they got something going on.
That's right.
Like the figuring out something like
they're a little bit.
I couldn't figure out about that was
where was the flash point where this guy
became this guy.
Like what was the thing he did make
everybody believe because that was never
made clear to me.
I never understood like,
okay,
I can understand people getting this
excited about it,
but what was the thing that he did or
said or that.
And I never understood that
part of.
I've been reading this book and it's
actually pretty interesting.
I actually have it right here,
the art of living and dying.
And uh,
he,
he wrote this book about one.
Yeah,
he wrote this book after he became Osho
or maybe they published it after he
became Osha,
but it's a very good book.
It's,
it's weird.
He's like,
he had some very good.
I know what I think I left it at home.
Oh No,
here it is.
He had some very good ideas,
like it's like he's like
philosophically,
he's a fascinating guy.
Um,
or it was a fascinating guy and there's
real good evidence that his followers
fucking poisoned him.
Like there's a lot of people,
I shouldn't say this real good evidence.
There's a lot of people that filed the
case very closely that believe that
people close to him may have poisoned
him and taking his,
taking his money.
So the whole thing,
the,
you know,
I mean the whole thing was just a
massive mind.
Fuck.
Those houses are still there in that
place like that,
that ranch that those guys set up,
they're either all would've mentioned
down the,
they show to the end of the documentary
and you're like,
whoa.
And there's an interesting.
Now the dude,
I don't know if you've ever heard of
him,
a guy named Dr.
Malakai York.
No.
Who's that guy?
This.
He started in New York doing this like
sort of Islamic sec thing.
He did and then he brought it into like
aliens and and ancient Hebrew stuff.
He liked it,
brought all this stuff together,
all these philosophies.
And he made this Utopian society and
like Georgia.
Oh,
but like the dude was like doing mad
criminal shit and they got it.
I don't know if there's any movie about
this,
but I'm going to smile,
but this dude was like,
oh,
maybe,
look,
I look at Smiley.
He is,
it's an incredibly crazy story.
Damn.
They put them away for 135 years.
Yeah,
he was doing some stuff like sex cult
stuff was going on with stuff in it and
you know,
always becomes that,
wow,
cool there because I've never seen
definitive.
I've read this and that.
So it's like there's motherfuckers to
say it was like,
you know,
you set up and all this shit and that he
had such a perfect society going that
nobody wanted,
that they would succeed,
you know,
that,
like,
I mean,
I'm pretty sure it's been proven that
the dude was doing some pretty criminal
shit.
Here's two things that seem to happen
whenever anybody runs any kind of crazy
called or any sort of like a weird
community outside the norm.
It always becomes sex.
It always becomes like the dudes as a
man.
I think that's what got him in trouble.
I'm and I'm,
I feel like I remember there being some
sexual.
Yeah.
They're having sex with children.
Oh yes.
That's what they got.
If
they wanted to bust him on something.
I mean,
if they're really wanting to bring them
down,
that's what they would accuse him up.
I mean,
you can't truly,
once someone accuses you have sex with
children.
Even if you're not guilty,
it's on you forever.
But the thing is like these no one has
ever pulled off like a Utopian
alternative society.
Never.
It's crazy.
It's really interesting because at the
entire history of the United States,
no one's been able to do it like they
try it,
they'll try it for a little bit and then
it falls apart every single one of them.
That's amazing.
It's amazing that no one,
whether it's Waco,
no one like this.
I look at it like the line from the
Matrix.
It's like our first version of the
matrix kept failing because it was all
too good and too nice.
We had to fuck it up a little for
everybody will accept it.
It's just to me it's,
it's quite fascinating that you know,
we stick to a standard way of living,
which is,
you know,
our modern industrial western
civilization and that is it in any
deviation of that is scrutinized to the
point where it's dismantled and the
government steps in.
They always have guns too.
There was a guns and gun.
Wait too many guns because they're,
they want to protect their way of life
and then someone's banging people's
wives and taken all the money.
Fascinating.
It's weird that no one has figured it
out.
Not One group has just got it nailed it
once.
Probably part of the thing that power
corrupts.
You can't have one person that's like
the Almighty.
No.
It all over over thing because he's
going to take advantage and then
somebody smart within click is going to
say,
hey,
this is not right and it's going to fall
apart and it always is one person or
there's going to be a person underneath
that wants that position and it's going
to do something to get it.
But it's always like one charismatic
person that seems to lead these things.
Like whether it's Jonestown or whether
it's Waco,
Charles Manson.
Yup,
Yup.
Yeah.
It's always one.
One Dude's like,
this society is fucked up,
man.
You can take that and apply it to
Hitler.
Yup,
sure.
Me.
Yeah.
One guy gets to everybody's attention
and next thing you know.
Yeah,
it is weird,
isn't it?
Like this desire to have like our big,
uh,
big daddy who got all the answers,
who's better than us because we're all
so confused.
It would be very comforting if someone
came along who really understood at all,
I've got the solution.
They have a big ass giant,
crazy white beard like Osho did,
and then they bowed you,
their answers,
blame the people you wanted to blame and
make you.
You know what I mean?
That's another good technique is to make
sure you know,
what does everybody want to be.
Okay.
That's what we're going to blame it on.
We'll focus our hate capitalism.
That was,
you know,
a lot of these things don't work out
because they have to be based on what we
talked about earlier.
Yep.
Doing unto others as you want them to
try to fully living that lifestyle.
Yep.
All alright.
When it doesn't happen like that,
it's cats get the power they getting
charged.
They want to keep that power.
They want to stay in charge
and they're not going to treat other
people that way.
They want it.
They're gonna.
Start intimidating people because that's
the way you keep people in line.
Always.
People want to be subjugated,
man.
Like you saying.
They want it.
They want.
They didn't want somebody to babysit and
know,
oh,
I can just sit over here and just be
dumb.
Okay,
cool.
And if no one was in charge,
someone would come along that would want
to be in charge of.
Someone would say,
you know what?
The problem with this organization is
there's no leadership.
We need a strong leader.
We need someone who respects the values
and principles this society was founded
on,
but someone who also understands how to
be a leader and then people go,
yes,
yes.
That makes so much sense.
Yes.
Guide us.
They just want to.
It's,
it's,
it's the same thing.
It's the,
it's what goes on in instagram.
Everybody wants to believe everybody's
got their.
That that guy's got his shit together.
That guy's got his shit together,
man.
Fuck.
I want to be like that.
Not knowing that like behind the scenes
he's falling apart.
It's falling the fuck apart,
man.
I know.
They're just trying to make it look like
they got there.
She had a friend recently.
No names or anything but like a friend
in a couple you would never ever in your
life think debut.
The,
I mean,
I was like,
man,
I just want to have a relationship like
yours,
you know what I mean?
And no foster mess anything.
One day I just turned around and they
have their instagram names are different
and all of a sudden I call him
whatsoever.
He's like,
oh yeah,
we just.
It didn't work.
We couldn't fake it and man was.
I don't know if that was,
if it's that serious,
but something it was just like just
shows you none of that shit is real
because we don't put.
We don't put our shit moments up for
everybody to see.
Yeah.
Elon Musk talked about that to the
people that you see on instagram that
you think are on social media that you
think are the happiest are probably the
biggest smiles are fucking struggling
the most for sure.
Yeah.
Well they're trying to project that.
They're always trying to project you the
best version of what their life is.
The best response all over my instagram
when I post about my family or even our
struggles like this,
this rough right now,
but you share it.
You say,
Huh,
but we're going to get through it.
We're going to be one of the things that
people like about you.
You know that you're real.
You're not.
I mean,
even though you're a famous guy who's
been a successful musician for a long
time,
so I used to be fast,
but you are,
you're,
you,
you're a normal dude.
You know,
I'd take that as the highest compliment.
You should.
It is the highest contact of that.
Seriously.
I gotta wrap this podcast up because I
have to ship my brain before we do.
Unfortunately tomorrow night,
the Brooklyn Bowl,
Friday,
August fifth at the Brooklyn Bowl,
UFC ultimate pre party.
He wouldn't leave his hosting.
Oh,
beautiful.
Oh yeah.
A cycle realm and my man evidence if you
want to get a discount.
UFC unfiltered is the code.
Put it in there.
Come see us tomorrow night is going to
be the ball and get it.
Ladies and gentlemen,
everlast,
Whitey Ford.
House of Payne.
Available now everywhere.
Thank you my brother.
Thanks for having me.