Hello freaks.
That's right.
We're back.
Just when you thought you had had enough
of us,
you will listen to this one as well.
Some of you out there will say,
this is the last one.
Other ones.
This will be the first one for you.
One day you'll get sick of me.
It happens.
Everybody gets sick of everything folks,
you know,
eat meatloaf every day fucking tastes
like shit,
but if you were lost in the woods and
you hadn't seen meatloaf for months and
you're living off frogs,
fucking pond water,
meatloaf would be awesome.
This episode is brought.
That's not a good way to start a
podcast.
This episode is brought to you by
stamps.com
stamps.
Dot Com is an awesome service that
allows you to bypass the post office
with stamps.
Dot Com is is a.
it's a service that allows you to print
and by us postage printed on your home
computer and right there from your desk
and then put it on packages and send
them out.
You don't have to go to the post office.
You just hand them to the postman and
say,
here you go dude.
And that's it.
You're done.
Go to stamps.com.
Click on the old school,
the microphone in the upper right hand
corner,
entering the code wordj r e and get our
$110 bonus offer,
which includes what are you looking for?
Abi.
That room there you go.
Get in there.
Um,
includes a free digital scale and up to
$55 of free postage stamps.
Dot Com.
Allows you to bypass the lines,
get away from all the nonsense.
And whenever postage rates change,
they change automatically@stamps.com.
It's a,
it'll be a beautiful service to save
time and money.
I'm leasing a postage meters.
Expensive multi year commitments and
hidden fees.
You don't have to do all that shit.
Just go to stamps.com.
It's a very sweet way to save time.
Very convenient way.
We use stamps.com.
Brian uses it for desk squad dot TV.
Our Friends Thompson and Pristina
present ski.
They use it for your mom's house,
for their podcast and they send stuff
out.
Stamps Dot com is an absolutely
wonderful service.
Go to stamps.com.
Before you do anything else,
click on the microphone at the top of
the homepage and type in j r,
e that stamps.com,
j Dot r dot e dot and get yourself a
$110 special bonus offer.
We're also brought to you by legalzoom
and legal zoom.
Much like stamps.com
allows you to do a lot of shit from
home.
That's what today's all about folks.
It's about saving time,
being convenient,
optimizing your,
your,
your minutes here on this earth and with
legal zoom allows you to do is do a lot
of shit from home naked that you would
have to do at a lawyers office.
You'd have to make an appointment,
go in there with clothes on.
You couldn't be drunk,
but you can be drunk and naked and still
do legal shit.
Like incorporate form an llc for just
99.
You can do a lot of things with legal
zoom that you would ordinarily have to
make appointments for and spent a ton of
money.
It's a very easy and convenient service
and if I correctly,
I believe you used it to incorporate on
it.com
is that labs llc was formed originally
by legalzoom.com.
If you're thinking about starting a
business,
you can do that from legal zoom.
You can also protect your family with a
last will for just 69 bucks or get a
living trust power of attorney and more
legal zoom gets the job right?
Nine out of 10 customers would recommend
the service to their friends and family
and we all know that at least one out of
10 people is a fucking whiny bitch,
so that's basically.
It's awesome.
Nine out of 10 says it's awesome.
Nothing.
If Jesus came back today,
his youtube comments would be atrocious.
Okay?
No one rides for free in this world.
This world is overrun by cons were like
rats on a boat.
Okay?
You get personalized,
affordable service that you can trust
and that's why they earned an a plus
from the better business bureau.
I'll say that again.
Legalzoom.com
earned an a plus.
That's right.
That one out of 10.
You fuckhead you're wrong.
You're wrong.
No,
you're wrong.
They can help you with trademarks,
copyrights,
patents,
all that good shit.
In the past 12 years,
over 2 million Americans have used legal
zoom and they've saved a ton of money.
Legalzoom is not a law firm,
but they can connect you with the third
party attorney and provide you with self
help services.
The third party attorney thing is very
important because if you're one of those
people that you're in the middle of this
and you're like,
oh,
I'm panicking.
This is not where going to go to jail.
You don't have to worry.
Legal Zoom will connect you with someone
that lets you know that everything's
gonna.
Be Okay.
Use the code word Rogan,
and you can get a special discount.
For listeners of this podcast,
enter Rogan in the referral box at
checkout for more savings.
That's legal zoom.com.
Go there and get your freak on and you
can do it naked.
There you go.
We're also brought to you by [inaudible]
dot com.
Hey,
what a coincidence.
Today we happen to have Aubrey,
the CEO of [inaudible] dot com with us,
so he could tell us lots of groovy shit
about on it.
I'm on on it right now.
I'm wearing a tee shirt and I'm hopped
up on Alpha brain,
some fucking Alpha brain dreams.
Last night,
son,
go good googly moonlight.
I took Alpha brain with dinner and uh,
I went to bed about four hours later and
had paula deen wrestling dreams.
I was wrestling Paula Paula Dean on a
psychedelic rainbow is the most bizarre
shit there was skateboards involved and
it was the drippings at.
Even if you're going to get an animation
of that now,
the birth of that into the ether,
one can only hope if I'm even if Alpha
brain didn't,
it didn't enhance your cognitive
function,
which it does,
and now it's been clinically proven to
do so.
It's worth taking just for the fucking
dreams,
man.
I believe it's Coleen is a Columbian.
Coleen helps regulate the rem state in
your sleep.
And Rem state is the dream state.
So the more acetylcholine you have,
generally the longer and deeper your rem
states going to be.
So the crazier dreams can get,
so whether or not even want to take
Alpha brain,
double up on that Acetylcholine and go
for a wild ride and it's a safe ride
folks.
Okay.
You're not going to die.
You might think you're going to die,
but I'm pretty sure you can die in your
dreams.
Has that ever been proven can die in
your dreams?
Right?
You just wake up.
That works.
I don't know if that's a fact.
Yeah.
No.
Yeah,
because you could lie about it.
I thought in my dream people will be
like,
well the fucking.
But if.
Well usually the adrenaline of the pre
death moment usually wakes you up.
Okay.
Yeah.
Like,
yeah.
Yeah.
The other thing I've found with Alpha
brain that's really interesting is that
lucid dreams are much more.
They're much more durable.
Like I've always found that whatever.
I've never taken any lucid dream,
uh,
courses.
I've never read any books and lucid
dreams.
Apparently there's a lot of strategies
that you can use and one of them have
done that I saw in one of those silly
movies,
like the secret one of those movies.
What was the rabbit hole or whatever,
what the bleep do we know?
I think it was where a guy was saying,
go to every door that you walk through
and before you walked through a knock on
the wall and say,
am I dreaming?
And do it as a habit so that every time
you go through a door you go,
am I dreaming?
One time I did it my dream and it was
like,
whoosh.
Oh fuck.
Um,
and so,
uh,
I really did wake up in the middle of a
dream and it was,
but it was very,
very durable.
It was really interesting.
Yeah.
You can stay in it and play with it and
see what,
see where you can take it.
Yeah.
That's not normal.
Usually I go,
oh my God,
I'm dreaming and I wake up and then it's
gone parties over instantly.
Like I've had a few where I was flying
for like 15 seconds or something like
that.
But the Alpha brain dream.
How long does it take for you to turn to
lucid dream into sex?
Because all,
instantly,
instantly I find someone and just start
a rape fast.
You know,
in the dreams they all want to fuck,
which has reared in your mind.
It's my dreams.
Very exciting since
I've been here last.
We were finally able to publish some of
the,
uh,
the first of a series of clinical tests
and the first one on Alpha brain.
So tell,
tell some people about that because it's
pretty exciting.
Yeah.
We did a pilot study just to kind of
prove the concept with the Boston Center
for memory and a double blind placebo
controlled study.
People took to Alpha brain pills,
which was kind of hard to figure out
because we did a survey and a lot of
people take three,
but the majority is still take to some
people or some people take one.
A few savages take for you in J.
Hawk take for fees.
Averages take four.
So we went with two and um,
you know,
and did a study testing a bunch of
cognitive markers and even with a small
sample size we had 17 people total go
through.
We're able to achieve statistical
significance in a couple of key tests,
stroop inhibition,
test,
executive cognitive functioning,
some verbal memory tests.
So some really good indications that the
Alpha brain is having the desired effect
that you know all the people who take it
and you know,
everybody who likes it as has been
talking about now we have some science
to back it up.
So we're currently in a followup study
with about 80 patients that's halfway
through right now.
It's kind of a rolling enrollment and so
hopefully we'll get some of that data at
least to us by the summer.
And then you look at the publication and
presentation scheduled,
but they're stoked.
I actually found out after the results
came out that they didn't expect it to
work.
Not The people who are doing it.
They're like,
Whoa,
shit.
It's really worked well for folks who
don't know before we did any studies on
on it.
There have been studies done on the
individual individual ingredients of
Alpha brain and that's something like
people go,
there's no forgiveness is snake oil.
It's not at all.
Snake oil did the.
The concept behind Alpha brain was just
that they would work synergistically,
which has proven to be correct,
but the ingredients,
the individual ingredients,
there is science behind it.
There's research and references.
All of it's available at [inaudible] dot
com,
so go there if you're interested,
what on it is.
Even if you go there,
you're like,
what the fuck are these guys doing?
They're preparing for war were a human
optimization website and what that means
is we're trying to sell you things that
can enhance your cognitive function,
enhance your mood,
enhance your physical fitness,
enhance your body's ability to do work,
enhance the way your body functions,
and there's a lot of stuff out there
that does that,
whether it's new mood,
which is a five htp and l tryptophan
supplement that actually can enhance
your brain's ability to produce
serotonin.
It's pretty spectacular stuff.
It really does make your mood better or
whether it's strength and conditioning
equipment like the Zombie bells and
kettlebells are a primal bells,
which are kettlebells that we had
designed by Steven Steuben Junior.
That's how I say his name.
You got it.
Steven Shubin Junior.
That's fucking awesome.
Artists has made us these incredible
kettle bells that are also works of art.
I know people that have these that don't
even work out.
They just have them because they're
fucking cool.
It's just a cool thing to have laying
around your house,
especially the gorilla.
He's my all time favorite.
I just love working out with that
gorilla man.
It makes me feel like,
like I'm doing something special.
I just set the top secret monster bell
series.
I know that that's coming out in 2014 by
lots of bells.
I've seen some of that.
Go to [inaudible] Dot Com,
o n n I t,
if you use the Codeword Rogan,
you will save 10 percent off any end.
All supplements.
All right,
ladies and gents.
Robert Greene is here and we're going to
get busy.
We're going to talk about some shit.
We're gonna.
Enhance your life.
We're going to get you fired up and
you're gonna.
Fucking get shit done.
Cue The music.
Jamie,
the Joe Rogan experience.
Try My podcast by all day.
First of all,
Robert Greene.
Thank you very much for doing the
podcast.
I really appreciate it.
Pleasure to meet you.
Pleasure to have you in here.
Um,
I've heard many,
many,
many fantastic things about you,
but this guy over here raves,
rants and raves and I know you were
recently on the warrior poet project
podcast,
which is his podcast and he couldn't say
enough good things.
So,
uh,
had to have you in here,
man.
Had to have to learn some stuff.
Have to figure out what you've
accumulated for all your years of
research and writing books and your
books all seemed to be about getting
your shit together.
About producing results.
Yeah.
Starting with the 48 laws of power,
I basically decided to enter the self
help genre with a lot of trepidation
because I think it's full of a lot of
bullshit.
Wait a minute,
hold on.
What are you saying?
I'm saying that it's filled with a lot
of tree stuff that's gonna make you feel
good about yourself.
That's going to boost your ego a bit,
but doesn't get anything.
There's nothing real behind it that
there's,
there's some things about life that are
harsh.
There are people out there that are
dirty and mean that you need to know
about.
There's all sorts of things that aren't
being discussed in these books.
And I know for instance,
when I started out,
like in Hollywood,
I used to work in Hollywood,
um,
I was really shocked by all of the kind
of power maneuvers and the kind of
passive aggressive games that were going
on.
What did you do in Hollywood?
I wasn't horribly successful.
I was a writer.
I was assistant to a producer,
assistant to a director or a researcher,
a story developer.
I basically did everything.
So you were where you were connected to
the machine,
you were in there?
Very much so you got to see the gear
span.
Very much so.
And nobody writes about what really goes
on in the world.
I got so sick of it.
I see,
you know,
all sorts of weird games being played.
The one director,
this one producer who wanted to direct
his first film and basically it would
look bad if he was the director of
something that he had sort of put
together,
just wouldn't look good politically.
So what he did is he hired somebody he
knew would do a terrible job,
a director,
first time director,
he knew the guy would fail and then he
could go in and rescue him and become
the director on the project.
But in the meantime,
totally destroying this other person's
reputation on and on.
I could list 100 other sorts of games
like that.
That's quite clever.
Move all sorts of things right out of
the art of war.
That's basically,
that's just what I can jump in here and
give a bit of my story.
I found that book,
Robert Greene's 48 laws of power before
I had met you and I was in kind of a
dark time in my own work climate and I
started reading it and I started
realizing all of the things that were
happening.
Like,
Oh shit,
that's what's going on.
That's why this bad shit is happening.
That's why I'm being thwarted in this,
in this goal that I have.
You know,
because you go in with these good
natured intentions thinking,
I'm just going to do my best.
I'm gonna wear my heart on my sleeve.
And it's all gonna work out bullshit,
it doesn't work out,
it's all his.
But you can kind of get lucky and get in
touch with the right people to be,
yeah,
or be in the right in the right
situation.
But a lot of times if you're in a kind
of politically charged situation or a
situation with a lot of ego,
uh,
his book was like this,
this wake up call of just sheer,
unabated truth about what the fuck is
going on.
It's not so that I could do it myself,
but at least so I could see myself and
see it and identify it.
So the,
this,
this move that this producer did in
order to.
And that surprise you at all when you
were,
you like,
oh,
you must have
fucker completely.
Because he never told me.
Obviously it wasn't going to confide
that this was going on.
I,
it's my interpretation later on.
So you're sure that that's what
happened?
Or completely,
100 percent.
And I've seen him do other things.
So I saw,
what's his name?
What's that?
I can't date you,
shouldn't he?
He's,
he's no longer among us.
So I don't want to fuck around and he
wasn't,
it wasn't a totally awful person,
you know,
he had a good side to him that is ripe
with that stuff though.
What really annoyed the hell out of me
about the Hollywood businesses that
people would pretend to be so liberal
and wonderful and good.
I love your project.
You're wonderful,
you're great.
But at the same time they were so
fucking power hungry.
Yeah.
Then nobody really talks about the power
hungry side and about what people are
really up.
I worked with a guy on my very first
sitcoms.
The first time I ever did any acting at
all.
I was like 20 something,
25 I guess,
or 26 and I was on the show on Fox
called hardball and there was a guy that
was on the show that would insult people
right before it was their time to
perform.
Like you would say something about what
are you fucking gaining Wayne here?
Like something,
what's going on with the gut?
And the guy would be like,
what?
And then you'd see the guy perform with
this.
Like he would fuck with you.
It's pretty good.
I've seen it.
It was really interesting to watch.
It was bizarre,
but it wasn't pretty good.
It was really shitty of them,
you know,
you did it to me once and I went,
what,
what the fuck did you say?
And then I cornered him and I said,
dude,
I go,
don't insult me.
because you're an ugly fuck,
you understand who you are.
I go,
we could just start talking about what's
wrong with you?
Fuck this in.
The guy would go,
come on,
we got to film the scene.
I go,
no,
this guy's a dick.
I just kinda likes to talk shit to be.
But right before they.
And everybody was like,
what is he doing?
He's calling out the thing that,
you know,
this guy's doing like,
you're not supposed to do that.
But he would be like really subtle about
it.
You know?
He'd be like,
who picked out that shirt?
Like weird shit to girls to man.
It wasn't just a guys,
but this was his thing.
He would be like really catty and he was
always reading like entertainment
weekly.
He was always reading,
I would call the devil's rag,
like the Hollywood reporter,
all that Shitty,
but read those things and you'll see the
little fucking power wheels spinning in
his devious mind.
Luckily he's dropped off the face of the
planet fortunately.
So you could read some of Robert Green's
books,
like strategies of war maybe and
probably find some tactic in there that
this guy was applying in order to weaken
his,
his people that gain power probably.
Right?
I mean,
does anything come to mind Robert?
Oh,
several come to mind.
Mostly passive aggression
creatively though that stuff is very
ineffective because I firmly,
absolutely,
wholeheartedly believe that if you put
your effort into diminishing others
creatively,
it diminishes your own creative ability.
I really do believe that.
I also believed that performance wise,
if you try to diminish someone's
performance,
like as an actor,
this is one of the reasons why this guy
sucked.
He was so transparent,
like he's such a shitty person.
You know the guy that he did it with,
a guy called fat to wanting to kill him.
I had to talk the guy out a calender
like you want this big fucking guy,
like you know,
it shouldn't call them fat.
Even if he is fat,
like he was doing it to fuck with the
guy right before it's seen because he
wanted to shine.
He wanted to.
He wanted to be the guy in the scene
that was really on top of the ball.
Yeah,
so the key thing is to know these
strategies so you can do with what he
puts in there.
It's called the reversal,
you know,
like how to be aware of it and then
reverse it.
Well,
the main thing is to never get emotional
in these situations.
If you're in control of yourself and you
can do like Joe did,
you can sort of see the game behind the
game.
Then you're in the position to do
something that strategic like he did to
to play the same game back at.
It's mostly like a warrior.
I call it kind of a warrior pose where
if you're calm and centered and you're
aware and in the moment of what the
other person is doing,
then you've got strategic options to
play the game back.
But if you get emotional,
you get angry,
you get intimidated,
then forget about it.
So yeah,
I would probably today respond very
differently,
but when I was in my early twenties,
it was scorched earth.
Every time I was,
I was going to def con nine.
Every time I'm like,
let's see who can hold their breath the
longest.
I'll drag him in a pool.
That was always my strategy just because
I was always nice to people,
but as soon as people weren't nice to
me,
I just said that's a good way to be very
bad way of handling it.
Um,
but that,
that thing that people do seems to be
not just calculated,
but it seems to be something that's been
going on since the beginning of time.
As soon as people invented language and
they invented the ability to deceive,
you're touching upon the subject of my
next book.
That's why I'm smiling.
What is that?
It's tentatively called the laws of
human nature and essentially I'm saying
that somewhere around 10,000
years ago,
maybe 6,000
are nature was set because we've started
living in groups that were larger than
10,
23,
the size of a tribe,
and once you put 100 people together,
all sorts of political game start
happening and things like envy and
passive aggression and basic
irrational responses.
They already occurred in the time of the
Bible and so there are these laws of
human nature that are so deeply
ingrained in the third grade,
just like a chimpanzee will react a
certain way under certain circumstances,
and I'm going to show you what these
were.
These laws come from why people are
envious.
Wife,
people are insecure.
Why?
Somebody who has a certain exterior of
face that they present to the world
wide,
it's generally hiding the opposite on
and on and on,
so you have.
You can understand where people's
behavior comes from and not be surprised
by it anymore.
So
what you present is steps to recognize
cons.
Yeah,
but you know what?
There's a little bit of cut and everyone
and all of us,
including myself and you guys.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And those who deny it and I hopefully
you're not.
One of them deny our are actually are
actually crypto club.
I was so excited.
That's a greatest word.
That's a great band name by the way.
You can use a crypto conscious.
Yeah.
If I was going to start a band,
it might be the crypto can just end up
getting arrested just so they'd have to
talk about it on CNN.
Like they did pussy riot,
but it was my favorite thing.
Favorite thing about pussy riot was
great.
Them talking about it.
I can name see riot.
The members of pussy riot.
I was like,
stop.
This can't be real.
This is a beautiful time.
Beautiful time in history.
Those girls are fucking bad ass man.
Not just bad ass for their.
Their ability to come up with an awesome
name,
but they get arrested.
They spent fucking how many months in
Siberia they get out and start
protesting at the Olympics.
Horse whipped.
Those chicks are fucking gangster.
They're so gangster.
I love pussy riot.
I'm a huge fan of their music sucks and
I don't even know if it does.
It probably does live performance on
Jerry Pussy riot make it happen.
So the crypto con,
so that's just my next book.
Yeah,
everyone.
Does everyone have content in them
because they're reacting to other cons
or do you think that everyone has like a
selfish aspect to them that's
undeniable?
I mean,
what?
What is it about people that you think
everyone has a little bit of continuity?
Is it reactionary or is it.
Is it actionary set?
Both.
It's both.
I suppose there might've been one
saintly figure in our history who
doesn't have any of this,
maybe a Jesus or something,
but pretty much the.
The underlying philosophy of all my
books,
particularly the 48 laws of power is it
human beings have a primal need for
power and we've.
We've used that word power in the wrong
way.
When we think of power,
we think of white men up in the White
House controlling the world.
I try and bring power down to an
everyday level and say the feeling that
you have no control over your life,
over your destiny,
over the people around you,
your children,
your wife is the most miserable feeling
that any human can have,
that you have no power over them,
no ability to them and so stunned in the
age of one,
two years old,
we have had this feeling of insecurity,
of weakness and we want to have control
and power over the people around us,
the events that go on in life,
and that is the source for a lot of our
manipulative behavior.
Some people are overtly manipulative and
very dangerous that way,
but all of us,
all of us engage at some point or
another in something that teeters on
manipulation and my books are about.
Let's just be honest about who we are.
Instead of trying to imagine that we
were somehow descended from angels
instead of primates.
No,
we're descended from chimpanzees.
If you studied chimpanzees that are
pretty machiavellian creatures,
that's where we come from.
Let's be honest about the human being.
Instead of trying to pretend that we're
all born like Gandhi,
well the the chimpanzee has one thing
that we don't and that's language or we
have one thing that they don't rather,
which is language and language is where
things get weird because you get
deception.
Yes,
and you also get strategy.
You were chimps,
have some strategy,
like you ever seen the videos where they
chased monkeys,
where they,
they corner him on the sides and then
other chimps rush them towards them and
they climb up and they eat them.
It's pretty radical stuff and until the
19 nineties,
people didn't even know that champs
eight monkeys,
you know,
they thought these beautiful berry
eating friends and they eat bananas.
Like curious George.
No,
not really.
They fucking rip monkeys apart.
Needham alive and engaged in warfare.
Yes they do.
They engage in warfare against other
chimps.
They get engaged in it in a very
strategic sense.
They have lines where they're not
allowed to cross and when they do cross,
they they,
they take action.
This is actually an interesting topic
because if you read Chris Ryan,
he's had proposes a theory that this
behavior that they've observed,
the chimp warring was created by the
artificial production of this food box
in the,
in the chimps habitat.
When they were observing them,
they would have food around that.
They were giving the chimps.
Right,
so this is this.
This is pretty well done.
They didn't see any of that prior to the
food box.
Oh No,
no,
no.
I don't know who Chris Ryan is,
but I,
I think that's very wrong.
Well,
Jane Goodall observed this,
but to keep the chimps around,
she had a box of food.
So this is a fact.
Right?
And after that it created this zero sum
game where the chimps were competing for
a limited resource of food,
which actually goes to the argument that
when you create a civilization and it's
not just tribal and it becomes a zero
sum game,
that's when the war and the strategy
gets to a peak because you're creating a
zero sum game.
There's a limited amount of resource,
a limited amount of crop,
or in the case of the chimpanzees a
limited amount of food that was coming
out of this box,
so only a certain number of the chimps
would get the food.
So kind of interesting.
I just thought I'd bring that up and
when Dr Ryan's on here,
you can certainly bring that up next
week.
He'll be on the 11th.
What was your issue with what he said?
Well,
it's always a zero sum game.
Why isn't it a zero sum game and it's
always limited foods,
but there's always.
There's more resource you can go to.
You're not competing for one very
specific section.
You can go to more acres,
more hectares of land and find the grubs
or the fruits or whatever of that,
of that area rather than competing over.
I don't want to argue with somebody that
had on red,
so maybe he has a very valid point.
I haven't read it so it's not fair for
me to.
But it does.
It doesn't affect your.
It doesn't affect your theory that once
you're in civilization,
these games begin and the tighter the
resources in that civilization I bigger
cities and the more closely people
working together,
the more fever pitch these games.
Well,
I don't want to,
I don't want to get on a tangent here,
but there's a writer,
a scientist named Eo Wilson.
I'm a biologist and he's pretty much
demonstrated that are our earliest human
ancestors going back to
Australopithecines.
Um,
we're engaging in forms of warfare.
Sure.
So he wants to sort of debunk the notion
of the happy,
peaceful savage that that goes back to
Jacques Rousseau,
etc.
That we do have very violent roots.
And so maybe chimpanzees,
iT becomes a zero sum if there's
overpopulation and they're fighting over
smaller territories,
which we humans we're doing as we became
more populous.
So he was trying to debunk the notion
that it's only at the advent of
agriculture where we started living in
settlements and became civilized at
warfare began.
And he shows very clearly that the
beginnings of warfare go back hundreds
of thousands of years.
Well,
it seems unavoidable.
It seems like all animals who compete
for breeding rights,
who compete for food,
they,
they engage in some form of combat.
Deers regularly kill each other,
you know,
that happens with elk.
It happens with stables,
stables,
with those crazy big horns that they
have.
They fucking,
they spear each other and they kill each
other.
Um,
I had louis throw on the podcast
yesterday and uh,
he,
one of his documentaries,
he had this african hunting camp where
they sort of,
these canned hunts where they have these
high fence operations and they breed all
these animals and they have these
samples in their fucking murdering each
other.
They knew eAch other and gouge each
other when,
when the females are invalid,
are staples that they're like,
it's one of those crazy fucking deer
things.
You pull up a picture of a sable jamie.
It's a one of those african dear,
like creatures with big crazy horns.
They have these fucking murder weapons
or if they have built in their face,
you know,
that's really what they have.
Um,
but the point being is that yeah,
there they are.
Those guys murder each other.
It looks like an oryx similar.
Yeah,
there's a.
There's a lot of those different types
of antlered horned animals that they
clash heads.
I mean that's what they do.
They go to war with each other.
It's.
It seems to be a part.
I mean it's also part of genetic
selection.
It seems be unavoidable and I've always
felt that when we look at the timeframe
between now and 6,000,
10,000
years,
whatever it was,
when we started having these
civilizations,
these were wearing a very small window
between then and now in such radical
change has taken place between them and
now then and now,
but yet genetically not much.
A few variations,
variations have been observed between us
and people that live thousands of years
ago,
but god not that much when it comes to
need,
when it comes to sexual desire,
when it comes to greed,
when it comes to automotive,
motivating factors,
it all of the reward systems that are in
place and the other thing being that we
don't have release anymore.
The physical release that a human being
is essentially hard wired.
Every chimp there swinging from branches
and they're.
They're working out all day,
I mean they're,
they're constantly getting this release
of energy
and they're also getting a release of
some of their aggressive energy as well,
which we don't seem to have.
Have a lot of
exactly what I'm talking about.
I think people are essentially leaky
batteries of aggressive energy mean when
someone's in their car and they start
fucking freaking out because you got in
front of them and fucking honking their
horns.
That's a leaky battery of aggressive
manner.
The other day this mild mannered woman
in her forties or fifties cut me off and
she just turned around and get.
I'd never seen a woman show that kind of
absolute chimp like aggressive bearing
where teeth at me in a car.
It was shocking.
I haven't been to the post office
stamps.com.
Yeah,
it's a.
It's a weird thing and it's also.
There's the cars,
a very unique environment in that
because of the fact that you don't,
even though you see people,
you don't feel them.
You know,
you're not in front of them.
Like I'm looking at you right now,
and if I said something that hurt your
feelings,
it would bother me,
but if I didn't know you when you're in
a car,
I'm like,
fuck you dude.
Fuck you.
You know people do that all the time.
I've seen people cut in front of each
other and raced down the street in front
of each other and just madness that you
wouldn't see in a line you wouldn't see.
If you're waiting in line to go to a
movie.
It's very rare,
but you see it there because this,
all the social cues are missing.
All the human interaction that is
missing.
It's like there's this wall and this
filter up.
Same thing on the internet.
Yes,
more so on the internet because you
don't even see the person and they're
hiding behind.
You know,
dick fuck.
Sixty nine is their name and whatever it
is,
they're not real,
and so they can reach out to Robert
Greene and go,
you're fucking bugs.
Or for faggots posts,
youtube comments,
and go fucking crazy on your block.
Like people,
like a friend of mine writes a blog and
someone was like,
why don't you have comments on your
blogs?
Like,
well,
what do you read comments?
Do you read comments on blogs?
Why would you want anybody to write
where you're writing?
You know,
if you had a painting,
would you allow people to,
you know,
paint underneath your painting what they
think about your painting.
You'd be a lot of dick's pointing to
your painting,
piles of shit with flies.
That's what they would draw in.
Not not all people,
but enough people to where it's a
problem because they haven't earned the
ability to communicate with you like
that you,
you choose who you communicate with in
real life for the most part,
especially who you surround yourself
with on a regular basis,
but online,
you choose nothing online.
It's the beautiful thing about being
online is that everyone gets to say
something and it's the horrible thing
about being online is that everyone gets
to say something and do so anonymously.
Yep.
Which is another part of what's weird
about our progression from this ancient
society where we hunted and gathered to
eventually agriculture and then
civilization in quotes to where we find
ourselves today.
So your books essentially,
and this new book especially is sort of
recognizing these traits so that you can
move away from them.
Well,
you're talking about my new book that
hasn't been written yet.
The point of the book is that this is
human nature and it's an animal nature,
and to be truly human,
we have to overcome these traits in us
to be truly rational,
reasonable.
I'm empathetic,
abbott creatures.
We have to overcome these various
aspects of our own nature which are
embedded in each one of us biologically,
genetically,
such as our propensity to feel envy.
The propensity that envy is basically at
its root.
The fact that we humans are constantly
comparing ourselves to other people.
Look at your own life on a day to day
basis and be honest with yourself and
try and calculate how many times during
a day you're actually comparing yourself
to another person.
He's got more money.
She's prettier,
he's got a better job.
You're doing that's so completely human
for various reasons,
which I'll explain in the book to reach
a higher nature,
which is the goal of my book.
You have to be aware that that's
happening and you and you have to find a
way to disengage yourself from that need
to constantly compare yourself to others
to find your own value,
your own self worth from within on.
These are all kinds of cliches,
but I'm going to show you in a very real
fashion how you can overcome them once
you're aware that they're inside of you.
Yeah,
but the book is not written yet.
It's a beautiful point though.
That's the beautiful point of being
aware of them instead of denying them
instead of getting all fufu chimes and
indian chance.
Thank you.
being aware of them.
Yes.
So when you started reading all of the
self help books and started recognizing
that there was all this horse shit going
on,
what was your immediate reaction to try
to write something that you thought was
more realistic and beneficial or did
you.
How did you.
How did you deal with it?
Well,
there's a lot of anger.
I have,
you know,
I have less now.
I'm older,
but I had a lot of anger back then
because it really pissed me off that no
one was talking about it.
people were pretending that this was the
world we lived in.
There'd be books in the business section
about management,
how to manage people,
which is a very primal,
a topic of discussion.
You have a group of people and you're a
leader.
How do you manage all of theSe insecure
egos who are thinking of themselves,
and these books were essentially
dishonest.
They weren't confronting the fact that
when you put 10 people together,
those people generally have their own
agendas.
they're thinking first and primarily of
themselves and their future and their
careers and what they can get for
themselves,
and if you start from a basic false
premise,
you're not gonna get anywhere.
So I was dealing with.
I wanted to cut my soar through all of
this thick bullshit and say this is what
really happens in business,
in the music industry,
in hollywood,
among lawyers in politics,
and if some of it was a little brutal,
maybe I gave myself a little bit of
literary licensed to exaggerate ever so
slightly,
but for instance,
I have a chapter in there about how to
create a cult.
Um,
and it's obviously ironic.
I'm not telling you you need to go out
there and create a cult.
What I'm saying is we humans are very
gullible and we're very easy to mislead
and we're very easy.
We want to believe in something.
We want to believe in a cause.
This is,
these are the strategies that people
have used in history to create a cult
like following.
and I'm going to sort of reveal that to
you.
Um,
these are things that just aren't in
self help books at least in 1998 when
the book came out.
So when [inaudible] writing about
creating a cult.
Yeah,
what do you,
what are your strategies?
How do you go about doing that?
Well,
you're trying to wrap yourself up in
this sort of mystical vale.
The chapter originally already fucked
that part up.
You probably haven't because you have a
cult following and therefore you like
different though from what then called
cult like is different than cult because
I'm not,
there's no organization whatsoever.
Not trying to get anything out of
anybody.
Trying to tell them what to do.
Oh,
there's,
it's different.
I'm not trying to benefit from it.
What you'd want to have as many
followers as possible,
as many people shouldn't have as many as
possible.
Quality over quantity is very important
business.
And I'm sure you're right though.
I keep hearing you say content,
colton,
that we're done with con,
you know,
once you,
uh,
what was your term again?
Crypto.
Crypto con?
Yeah.
You fucking knocked it out of the park.
Uh,
basically if,
if somebody is using numbers,
now I know I have the 48 laws of power
so I couldn't be guilty of it.
Thirty years.
Three strategies.
Law probably
starting to create a cult because that
goes back hundreds and thousands of
years.
Not that I'm not hundreds,
thousands,
but hundreds and thousands take you.
Yes,
uh,
giving us sort of mystical edge to what
you're doing.
You're trying to make people think that
you're creating a religion without a
religion.
Um,
and they're,
you know,
I,
I show you the steps that people go
through five steps in order and you can
pretty much,
if you see those steps happening,
you know,
that this person is creating a cult like
following and one of the steps towards
near the end is creating an us versus
them dynamic.
It's us 1000 followers against the whole
world that doesn't believe in our theory
of how the know of how aliens landed on
the planet and started the human race.
So whenever there's,
they're creating this false dichotomy of
us versus the nonbelievers and you know,
that you're on your way to a coat.
That the.
Yeah,
that cult of thinking is very common,
isn't it?
Yes.
The us versus them is really a,
that's the big one that is the big.
And that goes back,
I'm going to say in my new book,
which hasn't been written yet,
um,
that,
that goes back to our hunter gatherer
ancestors where we're separating
ourselves very violently from us,
from them.
That tribe over there,
they're evil.
They don't believe in the same gods that
we believe in.
They don't practice the same rituals.
We have to go kill them.
It's a very primal human thing.
Yeah.
That seems people have this really seems
inescapable.
Need to be a part of a group.
Yes.
Whether it's a group of mac users or you
know,
whether it's a whatever the fuck it is.
So I like fords.
I like chevy.
You know,
if people get,
they get really crazy about that and
it's a very weird aspect of human
nature.
People want you to be on the same cell
phone provider as them.
Like what are you doing with t mobile
man?
Come on over to the t and t.
Well the,
the,
the companies have used some of those
strategies.
They've created this us versus them
mentality to help make people feel like
that,
you know,
all of these advertising practices that
you see,
you know,
generally you can find a lot of their
roots and you know,
some of these larger scale strategies
like look at this map versus this map
creating this antagonism that actually
probably helps both sides and it's,
they're all just shaking hands like that
plane ride where the republicans and
democrats were playing yahtzee with each
other and having a big laugh.
I remember the think different Ads.
Do you remember the things she ants for
apple where they use all these dead
people.
It was like,
does that guy,
even though he's in an ad dead,
this is weird,
you know,
think different with the apple logo and
that everybody wanted to think
different.
Effective,
very effective,
but almost,
you know,
kind of deceptively so in some weird
sort of a way.
You know,
you will.
You're just fucking computer man.
Yeah.
Which you have is a computer.
It's not thinking for you.
It doesn't.
You could write the most racist,
horrible shit on a mac and it doesn't
stop you.
You can totally plot your agenda against
whatever and they fill in the blank,
anti homosexual,
anti woman,
anti,
whatever.
You could just write the worst shit ever
on a mac.
It doesn't discriminate.
It doesn't have any effect on how you
think.
Like it's,
it's such a dumb ad.
You think different.
Think different.
How was sitting in front of this thing
going?
I'm not thinking any different.
I think it's also grammatically
incorrect.
It is differently.
Think you're right.
Yeah.
It's fucking dead wrong,
but yet effective.
Yeah.
I guess it's that the need to be a part
of a group is a,
it's one of the things that people
definitely play against
that was completely social animals.
Um,
and uh,
that's the source.
If you think about the human being,
go back a million years ago where we
were incredibly the one of the weakest
animals on the planet.
um,
you know,
we were just barely learning how to
stand up on our two legs.
We were slow,
couldn't run very fast,
didn't have teeth to kill another animal
with no poison,
no clause.
We were the maybe one of the weakest
animals on,
in,
you know,
in the,
in,
in africa,
and yet look at us now.
It was from our,
so becoming the preeminent social
animal.
We learn how to work in groups to hunt
in groups to cooperate out of that came
language eventually so you can't divorce
are extreme social nature from who we
are.
And because of that,
we have a tremendous propensity to
conform to,
to want to think like other people.
I don't know if you're familiar with the
milgram experiments about authority and
obedience.
It Was in the sixties.
A yale professor had people come in for
an experiment where they were made to
give electric shocks to other people.
If they didn't answer a question
correctly,
they weren't really giving a shock.
It was all a plant that he was trying to
see how they would respond to authority.
And the most mild manner housewife would
be given those shocks to people when
they gave the wrong answer.
And he was showing how inbred rna,
how we are all wired to obey authority.
Um,
so these are things embedded deeply in
us as a social animal for the good,
for,
for a good thing or our ability to
cooperate,
but also it's a very dark and negative
side,
which is our ability to engage in group
think and are mindless obedience.
40.
Is that where that's coming from?
When someone with a mild mannered
housewives are hitting that button and
shocking people,
is that worth coming from or is it they
finally have some power over something
because I feel like there's a lot of
people out there that feel incredibly
power,
less and frustrated and they feel like
they have this backlog,
they have a leaky battery for that.
Like they want to have some fucking
power over people.
and when you finally do,
like,
what was the stanford prison experiment
was the same?
Was it the same thing?
There were two professors who were
friends and they kind of,
oh,
bullshit heads pointing out how to make
people evil.
The stanford prison experiment,
I mean they caught them off after they
cut the experiments short because people
were being so evil.
they had fake prison guards and
prisoners.
Um,
I,
I personally experienced that on a
personal level when I was a security
guard.
I worked as a security guard at great
woods,
which is a concert center for the
performing arts in Massachusetts to
nashville,
man manfield,
I think,
man,
mass,
wherever the fuck it is man field,
I think it is,
it's a,
this outdoor venue and there was a lot
of crazy shit going on.
They had all these nutty concerts there
and all these fights would break out and
it became us versus them,
us as a security guard versus them.
And I saw some really mild mannered
people do some mean shit to the people
that were,
uh,
were guests.
They're very interesting.
You know,
I saw a guy that would never hurt
anybody,
punch somebody in the stomach because
the guy,
I forget what the guy did,
but I remember watching him hit this guy
going,
wow,
this is crazy.
Yeah.
And it was because of that,
it was because he was wearing a security
jacket.
He was security.
The guy was a drunk asshole.
And but where he would normally,
if you ran into this guy in the street
would never hit him,
but because he was in this position of
power in quotes,
you know,
he,
he hit this guy.
I mean,
I don't know if the guy pushed someone
or something,
but it would,
it was avoidable.
He didn't have to hit them.
Yeah.
And I remember that mentality being very
clear,
the us versus them mentality.
So the key to avoiding these dark
characteristics is you have to be
honest,
number one,
which I think he's very good at doing,
but then also understand and identify
him,
not be able to look and say,
this is why this is happening.
We have this us versus them dynamic.
It's creating this,
this thing.
And unless you can identify it and
become aware of it,
it's pretty much powerless to break it.
So the knowledge that these books give
give you,
at least in my opinion of,
of one of the reasons I loved him so
much,
they give you the power back by saying
you're not just a leaf at the mercy of
the wind,
of these forces of human nature.
And the forces of other people wielding
these power games and the forces of
seduction by these people who are
desperately trying to date and how
they've got you all wound up inside.
You're no longer powerless because you
can see,
aha,
this is what's happening.
And you can take some of that back and
then chart your course with your own
intent,
with your own morality.
How you want to Do it.
Yeah,
that's,
that's fair.
Thank you.
That was very well put.
But I have a book.
I should have you just do all the
answer.
All the questions plugs busy.
I did a book with fifty cent a rapper
called the 50th law.
And basically what I did in that book
was I wanted to figure out what made 50
so interesting,
so powerful.
And after hanging out with them I
decided that the guy was fearless.
He had a just incredible fearless
quality and philosophy of life.
So the book that we wrote together was
sort of a meditation on fearlessness and
the and the whole point of the book was
being fearless isn't a question of just
going out there and saying,
fuck you.
I don't care what anybody does,
I'm going to push you around and I'm not
afraid.
That's about fearlessness
is first coming to terms with the fact
that you are afraid,
you are afraid of death,
you are afraid of other people getting
one up on you.
You are afraid of being alone.
You are afraid of people thinking that
you're different.
Okay?
Look at it in yourself.
Be aware that that's existing,
that it's.
It's happening in your body before it
even hits your mind.
Now that you're aware of it,
now you can start conquering your fears.
So I say we say it in that book,
for instance,
napoleon bonaparte or general patent,
two men who were incredibly brave who
would be on the front line of battle,
take bullets flying past them.
These were men who were very afraId in
the beginning when they first went into
battle and we're quite ashamed of the
fear that they saw in themselves and
they became aware of it and then slowly
they overcame it by exposing themselves
to the very thing that they were afraid
of.
So that's sort of the paradigm you're
talking about.
Becoming aware of the process of these,
these sorts of qualities we don't want
in ourselves.
Seeing how they operate inside of you.
Instead of saying,
oh,
it's always the other person.
It's not me.
I'm not afraid.
I don't have these problems.
No,
you do have them.
Let's,
let's confront it and let's show you how
you can rationally and in a intellectual
and mindful way.
Overcome.
Overcome them.
Yeah,
because it truly is no managing of
anything that you're denying.
If you're denying that it exists,
you cannot manage.
That was well.
Put two guys are much more eloquent than
I am.
We take a lot of mushrooms.
Robert grant helps us confront these
interference.
Ever.
Taken mushrooms.
Robert?
Yes.
Deep breath.
Of course he has,
but I took a lot of pot.
That was my drug of choice.
That injustice.
Good?
Yeah.
Go.
Just talk about a way to show you the
fears that you didn't realize you have
and help you confront them.
You know these things.
They're really a great mirror to reflect
upon yourself.
Hallucinogenics.
I mean,
I think that's one of the great values
that it brings is,
you know,
you don't know exactly what our deepest
fear is until you do iowasca and then
it's like,
oh yeah,
that's it.
The thing that you've been showing me
for the last three hours,
I guess I'm most afraid of that.
Well,
the thing with pod is you never knew
what was going to happen.
You never knew whaT one trip was never
the same as another.
So you always had like,
trepidation,
like,
whoa,
this could be really ugly.
I don't know what's going to happen.
And you had to deal with it.
How did you do it?
Do it in traditional native american
setting?
Uh,
no,
I was in berkeley college.
Uh,
we would take the buttons and you take
off all the little white,
stringy poisonous bits and then you cut
it up and you either put it in a shake
or a peanut butter sandwich and then you
go find a nice safe place.
Traditional peanut butter sandwich.
Exactly.
I mean,
they would eat,
they would eat it.
They taste horrible.
It's just,
it's not the taste is that consistency
and unless you're a native american,
it's hard to stomach it,
you're just going to vomit it straight
up and you don't want to vomit it
because then you're not going to get the
trip.
So you got to trick your body into like
digesting it and so you have to put it
in a smoothie.
If you brominated it doesn't work.
No,
you're vomiting out immediately.
All of the stuff you just didn't pay
attention because it works well if you
vomit based on the taste,
it hasn't had time to assault it later
in the trip based on it trying to clear
your body.
that's a different.
It's already assimilated.
So,
um,
anyway,
so do you feel like those pod
experiences help form your view of
things?
Very much so.
And you know,
it just made you kind of put,
connects you to reality where there's
things where you're just in a fog all
the time because we're so conditioned to
think in certain ways and to have
something that draws you out of the same
rut of thinking and confront you with
really the real world.
This amazing world.
It's aroUnd you,
uh,
has had a huge influence on my writing
and I know this next book hasn't been
written,
but I have another book after that that
has not even begun to be even thought of
as written.
And that's going to bring together all
of my experiences on that level of book,
on what I call the sublime,
which I've written about in the 50th
law.
And we'll write a whole book about at
one point.
so the 50th law is the one that you
wrote with fifty cent?
Yes sir.
Now what was the motivation behind that?
Well,
basically my early books,
meaning the 48 laws,
seduction and war to some extent were
very popular among hip hop artists.
Yeah.
Basically because you know,
the music industry,
I described you hollywood.
Well,
hollywood is kind of like kindergarten
compared to the music business that they
are.
The real sharks are in the music
business.
They are pretty nasty,
pretty machiavellian.
Um,
and people like 50 jay z and their
managers in the late nineties,
early two thousands were coming to grasp
with the fact that they,
they wanted to control their own work to
have some power and some money and
become entrepreneurs and,
and dealing with these sharks in the
music business was something that
nothing,
not even any kind of street life
prepared them for 50 would tell me.
He hustled on the streets dealing crack,
saw people being knives and killed and
dealt with a lot of danger and nothing
prepared him for the sharkey horrific
games that he saw in the music industry
with columbia and interscope,
etc.
So they were reading my book to help
them deal with this.
They did.
These are not people who went to harvard
business school,
they didn't have a book out there to
help them understand how manipulative
these people could be.
And so they gravitated the 48 laws of
power.
Fifty was one of them and he contacted
me at some point I think,
oh,
five or six wanting to meet me because
he liked the book a lot and then we met
and we had a really interesting synergy.
Obviously we're not,
we don't come from similar backgrounds.
We don't look alike.
They don't see that on the street.
I'm from history,
but I'm not the street or you're born in
the field.
Everybody's born from the street.
Uh,
I'm uh,
you know,
I come from a middle class jew,
jewish background,
so I'm not quite the same as,
you know,
south side queens.
But uh,
but we had a really nice energy
together.
Like we think alike.
Like I told you about,
that hollywood director,
most people in hollywood were getting so
angry with him and so angry about the
games that they never took a step back
to figure out,
oh,
this is the strategy that this guy
applied and 50 was the same way.
He said,
I took a step back and said,
this is what the guide in her scope is
really doing.
So we thought alike and we thought let's
bring two minds together that think
alike,
but from totally different backgrounds
and see what happens.
Fascinating.
The,
um,
the music business for folks who don't
know,
it's been a,
it's really a fascinating operation and
it's kinda been gutted because of the
mp3 influx and napster was the first
blow.
And then from there it's like,
really now it's kind of interesting
because the performers actually make
their money from performing more than
anything else.
It's very difficult to make the millions
and millions of dollars that the rolling
stones and what have you.
All those bands in the past made from
selling records.
he,
there's not really that,
that doesn't exist anymore in the same
way.
But courtney love wrote a piece about.
I'm sure she probably didn't really
write it.
Probably they said it was ghost written.
I agree.
It's pretty fucking smart.
And I've smart woman.
Yeah.
Okay.
I believe you,
but I don't know,
maybe not anyway,
whether she.
Let's say she wrote it.
Okay.
It's,
it's insane.
If you've ever read it,
that piece that she wrote on the music
business and how it really works and how
they extract everything from your
profits,
everything,
promotion,
expenses,
all these different things.
By the time the artist gets paid for the
records,
they have all this weird way of doing
math where it shows like no money,
no money has been made and they use that
for not just the music business but
hollywood trudeau.
I have a friend who produced a
television show and it's a very
successful television show and it's not
just,
can you stop doing that start crunching
thing,
sorry.
It's really distracting.
The television shows not just successful
nationwide.
It's syndicated across the world and the
company that made this show,
the production company is claiming that
it doesn't turn a profit.
I mean,
I'm not talking about one country,
it's in 16 different countries and
there's like several versions of it with
different hosts all throughout the world
and they're trying to tell him that it's
not always suing them and there's like
this crazy fucking lost.
Lawsuits are just course for business.
It doesn't even scare.
It doesn't even make people bad an eye
in those industries,
but it's pretty sad.
It's weird,
like how has it not making a profit?
Did you get paid?
like where's there's got to be a fucking
profit here because there's all this
money,
like a movie that can make $100,000,000
can be said to have turned no profit.
Yeah.
Wow.
That's bizarre.
Where's that money going to?
But this fuckery,
this,
these shenanigans are sort of a lot of
the stuff that you're talking about in
48 laws.
Yep.
Yeah.
Courtney love was a big reader of the 48
laws of power.
She used it in one of her lawsuits
against the music industry.
She held up a copy of the book and said,
this is what you guys are using against
us.
You bad motherfucker according lab.
Did you ever see that documentary that
claims that she killed kurt cobain or
had kurt cobain killed?
No.
One of Them was fucking bizarre
documentaries ever.
Like someone fucking set out to prove
that courtney love was responsible for
kurt cobain's death.
Oh,
all right.
Are you sure you're not sure?
Yeah.
That's a pretty fucking crazy statement.
You know?
How can you just.
You can just do that and you can just
say that.
Yeah.
Nobody tried her for that.
Like can you sue someone who says that
you're responsible for the suicide of
your fucking husband.
Awful off track.
Obviously back to the book.
So this,
this business,
this music business is just an example
really of what happens when power
structures are created.
When people who were in these power
structures understand the game and then
take these people that are just coming
into it fresh and especially artistic
types.
People who are creative,
people who are artistic types,
oftentimes not very good with money,
not not sound financial thinkers,
and just the opposite of these business
sharks that are involved in interscope
or whatever the whatever the label is,
katie themselves to the mastery of their
craft and this whole other craft.
This business sharkey genus is this
other whole skillset that it's
challenging to be able to master both.
You know,
so getting the cliff notes is awfully
helpful to be able to sort that out
because that is to be as where they are
at that point and obviously he'll go
into his book mastery,
but that is a relentless pursuit of
excellence in a well defined niche that
doesn't allow for a lot of time to
explore these other things unless you
know you're forming some bridge.
If you were going to recommend your
books to someone,
what,
what order would you recommend them in?
Well,
it depends on what business you're in
and what point you are in life.
Okay.
How about you?
How about me?
I'm a comedian.
Yeah.
Which I do
you,
you who are already so successful.
Well probably mastery in some ways
because maybe it'll take you to the next
level,
but I don't know if you're dealing with
a
lot of political stuff.
If you are,
then you're going to want 48 laws or
maybe the strategies of war.
Uh,
it depends on who you are,
what your weaknesses are,
what your strengths are,
where you are in life.
If you're 22 years old and you're just
graduating college and you're about to
enter the real world,
um,
I'd say mastery for reasons that maybe
will.
Hopefully we'll get into a.
But if you're a 25 and you're now
working at goldman sachs,
god bless you.
If you are ever saved you,
I think you're gonna probably want the
48 laws of power because man,
that's a power hungry,
nasty,
manipulative,
machiavellian environment.
If you're in the music industry as well,
if you're a person leaves a fairy
afraid,
you've got all sorts of great creative
ideas,
but you're never going to the next step
and starting that great movie or project
you have,
maybe the 50th law would be good for you
so you can get over some of those fears
that are holding you back.
If you're some guy who just can't find
a,
you know,
ken is really bad with women.
Art of seduction,
obviously it would probably be just so
it depends a little bit on who you are.
Now you wrote the artists deduction to
help people get laid.
Is that the idea of.
No,
I didn't know.
I know it sound great.
I know I probably have 8 million people
buying the book tomorrow and now I'm
only going to get like 15,
but the truth of the matter is artists
deduction is about how to seduce people,
how to get them to like you or love you.
It's all about creating a spell,
so if you want to just get laid,
you know,
maybe neil strauss or the pickup
artists,
that's probably more your speed.
It's got all sorts of gimmicks about how
to sell a woman's something in a bar and
melt her resistance and etc.
I'm more about the longterm,
how you can take that woman or it can be
a woman seducing a man obviously and get
and play a mind game on her.
So in the course of three months,
she doesn't want to just sleep with you.
She wants to give you everything she
has.
She creating stalkers a could be and I
have and I'm afraid I'm ashamed of it,
but more likely I don't believe you at
all.
When you say I'm ashamed of it,
you're fucking proud of that shit.
I said,
oh,
I don't like stalkers because really the
book is about casting a spell.
Okay.
You know,
let's say,
let's say this is the goal of seduction.
When that woman leaves you after the
whatever night you had together,
the date or whatever,
or just an encounter,
she's going home and thinking about you.
Okay,
now you're starting to seducer you.
It's a mind game.
It's a mental thing.
We humans are sex drive and our mental
process are really interconnected and
I'm kidding you to play on that and you
play on psychology and melting other
people's resistance is getting them to
lower their guard because everybody's
very got their guard up constantly.
Particularly in this modern world.
Nobody is opening up to you or nobody
wants to show vulnerability.
It's just you're just dealing with a
million porcupines out there showing you
how to get those resistance levels down
and give room to finagle your way into
their head.
And the converse
of course too,
you know,
which is a lot of people are getting
these things played upon them
constantly.
And again,
it goes back to the same thing.
If you're not aware of the tactics that
somebody is using,
you know you're defenseless against
them,
you're just completely vulnerable and
you'll get sucked into this lure of this
spell that they're creating by this push
pull tactic that they're using and
whatever strategy that they're using and
you'll just be helpless to it.
And you see guys fall for these all the
time.
You know,
it's something that bums me in you out
personally a lot.
When we see friends and people we love
caught in this spell that someone's
woven where they can't let go despite so
many other things going bad in their
life.
They're just trapped in it and reading
something like the artist's deduction
says,
oh,
she's using law number seven as her
primary means and 13 and 17 and now I
see you now.
I got you a bitch.
You know,
like you can switch it back and say,
okay,
now what do I want?
Do I want to keep you around?
Do I want to or do I want to just
release myself,
you know,
remove these hooks,
these invisible hooks that you've
created,
and just be free to chart my own course.
Well,
thank you all for you.
I find that a lot of people enjoy the
struggle of relationship struggle
because it distracts them from their own
life,
just distracts rama,
distract them from their shortcomings
and achieving their goals.
They put up obstacles almost on purpose.
They create these inner personal
relationships that are going to ensure
conflict so they don't have to deal with
success,
so they don't have to deal with a fee.
They have like a built in excuse for
failure.
Yeah.
That's very common.
Yep.
Freud called that air full angst.
I'm basically.
That means fear of success,
which is something I talk a lot about in
my book.
That's real,
right?
It sounds like it sounds ridiculous.
It sounds like an oxymoron,
but it's real.
Yep.
That's a main main.
One of the main points in mastery about
mastery is basically a book that's
trying to get away from all of the
political stuff I've described in my
previous books,
and here I'm going to show you how we
humans can attain excellence in this
world,
how we can be really,
really the best at what we do because I
think that's the highest form of power
we humans can reach when we're so good
at what we do,
then all the political games in the
world can't topple us from where we are.
Um,
and what holds a lot of people back is
that they're really self sabotaging,
their finding all kinds of excuses why
they can't go through this process.
They believe in the myth that people are
born talented,
are geniuses,
are simply born that way or that they
didn't get to go to the right school
where their parents were mean to them or
yada yada yada.
Or my girlfriend is that,
you know,
whatever.
As you said,
they get involved in drama games that.
So fill up their mind that can't think
of anything else.
So I'm going to make you
as this book as well aware of what's
holding you back and these fears that
you're using to sabotage yourself.
That is one of the most frustrating
things to me when I'm talking to someone
and they have these built in excuses for
why they can't do what they want to do.
Give me some of these excuses that you
hear.
Well,
I have a friend who wanted to be a
comedian.
He wound up not being a comedian.
He doesn't have children,
he doesn't have a wife,
doesn't have a mortgage,
so he's not.
It's not like he has this job that he
has these responsibilities to feed his
family.
So he stuck in his job,
but he was like,
well,
you know what man,
I.
I've missed the boat with comedy.
If I had started in the nineties,
everything would've been great.
I go,
what are you talking about?
Is people that start right now?
There's,
there's open mics right now.
Good.
The tuesday night to the laugh factory
is a fucking line around the block.
They get there at 9:00
AM and they wait in line.
You should do that too.
If you want to do comedy.
A mannequin,
do that.
I'm 30 years old.
Do you think the orion gives a shit and
how old you are?
Man,
the line has no idea about your age.
The line is there.
The microphone is on for an 80 year old
man.
If an 80 year old man talks in that
microphone,
it makes noise just like a baby.
If a baby cries into that microphone,
it also makes noise like,
what are you talking about?
And they're like,
he and I got into this crazy debate
about.
He's like,
look man,
it's easy for you to say you're already
successful.
I'm like,
look dude,
it's not easy for me to say.
It's hard for me to hear because you're
fucking yourself.
You're you want to be a comedian and if
you think you're funny,
and by the way,
you don't even really have to be funny.
You just have to have the ability to
figure out how to become funny and that
self analysis,
objectivity and work,
that's what it is,
but you are already creating this
insurmountable barrier.
You didn't start in the nineties,
like,
what are you fucking talking about it
in the book mastery,
I interviewed nine modern masters to
sort of embed them in months.
All the ancient masters that I talk
about and one of the nine modern masters
I interviewed as a woman named temple.
Granted,
I don't know if you've heard of her.
No,
to emigrate and it's like a very famous
animal behavior scientist.
um,
and she was born with autism and at the
age of two was basically going to be put
in a mental institution for the rest of
her life because she was a severe
autistic.
She couldn't learn language.
He was just the kind of kid you see.
It was just banging their head against
the wall.
She was severely autistic.
And through a process I describe in the
book with her mother's help and the
speech therapist,
she slowly got to the age of four to be
able to start speaking and going to
schools.
And I show the process that eventually
led her to become a great scientist.
Now,
if somebody's born with severe autism,
at the age of two is going to be
institutionalized for their whole life,
can become a master,
then there's no fucking excuse for some
30 year old who has nothing,
no barriers like that at all to ever get
to that point.
It's really the reason I put it in
there.
If any.
If somebody like that can overcome their
limitations and there's no more excuses.
Okay,
well there is one excuse.
He's a weak bitch.
Well,
that's the excuse and my eyes don't be
weak,
bitch.
It's so simple.
Break it down to that.
Yeah.
My other advice that I always give out
is be the person that you pretend to be
when you're trying to get laid.
If you can Just do that and just be that
guy,
what would that guy be?
That guy and let it become you.
That was something I never covered in
the artist seduction.
Damn.
Be the person.
Be the hero of your own movIe.
that's the other thing I say to people
when people were there,
feel like their life.
Pretend you're a fucking loser in A
movie.
You woke up today the same scenarios.
You always see guy wakes up,
makes a fucking blender full of pizza or
whatever they do,
you know,
get their life together and smoke a
cigarette and realize that you're a
failure.
You're,
you're the bills are piling up.
The phone's ringing off the hook from
bill collectors.
What would the hero in the movie do
right now?
Do that shit and it works.
It works at some people,
other people that find excuses to not do
it.
I got that
vice from a,
from a family friend one time and I was.
I was terrible at dating until I was
about 22 or so,
21.
I was awful.
I was way too nice.
It was so doting and it wasn't even the
real me.
I was just being playing this overnights
person and people hated it.
It was the most repulsive being nice,
the most repulsive thing I could have
done.
And so he told me,
he's like,
just analyze your actions and what
you're saying.
And ask what would Bruce Willis too
at that time?
At the time it was,
that's who is like the big action hero
or whatever.
My advice That helped changed the game
for me.
Stay nice,
but be willing to walk away as soon as
you expose that someone else is not nice
back,
be nice always,
but then as soon as someone's not nice
backside.
All right,
good luck.
Take it easy.
Not need them at all.
If you don't need them to know.
The problem with nice people is they're
needy motherfuckers.
It's not just nice.
The reason why they're being nice is
they need you to like them.
You can be really nice and not need
people to like you and if they don't
like you or they didn't want to be
around you,
you're fine with it.
Then they freak out.
They don't know how to handle that.
Like shit,
I missed a nice guy.
He was nice.
It slipped through my fingers.
Personal sovereignty.
It's one of the most important things to
have in this life.
The ability to be yourself,
to be by yourself and why would other
people like you if you don't even like
yourself.
You got to do things in life that you
would admire.
You got to be the kind of person that
you would like and if you're not,
why would you expect anyone to like you?
I have this argument with guys all the
time where the talk about women and you
know,
the fucking girls want money.
They want this,
they want that.
You know,
women always like,
you know,
I just,
I'm not so good with women's.
I always say this,
would you fuck you?
Fuck you.
How dare you,
you know,
it's not just physical,
it's mental.
It's the way you behave.
Or are you a kind of person?
Are you fun to be around?
There are people that are just genuinely
great to be around.
You know,
they don't have to be good looking,
you know,
they don't have to be,
they don't have to be
well read,
they just have a quality.
They have quality.
And do you not have that quality and if
you don't have that quality,
can you,
can you acquire it?
Well,
what I try to do in our seduction is a.
I'm saying people who read a book and
try to seduce,
so usually the worst seducers or who've
taken some advice because they're not in
the moment.
Um,
and there seemed like they're kind of
being cold and calculating and the trick
to seduction is to appear or to be as
natural as possible and to at least
appear natural.
Um,
so everybody has a different style.
Some people are funny and great to be
around,
but maybe you're just not born that way.
Maybe you're just not widi.
Uh,
maybe you,
but you have other strengths.
You have other qualities,
something naturally seductive about you.
Um,
that could be you're very social and you
know,
you can think about what the other
person wants.
It could be.
I have one of the types in the,
in the book.
Maybe you do have coquettish qualities.
What does that mean?
You can blow hot and cold
coquettish ooh,
new word.
Cocaine,
cocaine,
reddish.
Never,
never heard anybody say that.
Tree.
French coquette.
Isn't that amazing?
You could live 46 years on this world.
I've taught you several words.
You have.
Thank you so much.
Crypto.
Contemplate a favorite word.
Everything you're free to use it,
use it,
announced in the world that kind of what
you're saying,
it kind of reminds me of what you talk
about it,
but go ahead.
Sorry.
No,
go ahead.
You can finish what it reminds me a
little bit of what you're talking about.
In mastery of going with your natural
inclination,
that is going to be the best thing.
Like going with that vocation.
Whatever makes you that unique
individual,
it's almost the same and seduction as it
is in mastery,
pursuing that channel,
that venue of what is going to bring you
out,
your highest qualities is going to lead
to the greatest success.
No matter what it is.
SedUction or mastery.
Yeah,
I've tried.
I make
the point in mastery that you have.
You're born with a key to success.
Every single human being is born that
way.
I'm not tried.
This isn't some new age bullshit that
I'm trying to pedal here.
What that key is,
the fact that you're,
you,
you're,
there's something unique about you.
Uh,
your,
your dna is unique.
Your brain is wired in a unique way.
They've done these really interesting
studies on newborns and infants one
month to six months and they've been
able to show that an extremely early
age,
infants are already distinguishing
between things that they like and don't
like.
I'm very particular levels like foods
and colors and sounds,
so when you were really,
really young,
you had what are recalls,
and I call them the book,
primal inclinations.
These,
there were things you were attracted to
that are very,
very unique and distinctive about you.
IT could be sports,
it could be competing and winning.
It could be working with people and
social situations.
It could be music.
Whatever it is,
if you're able to stay true to that or
rediscover it when you're older and
mine,
what's unique about you and your tastes
and your way of thinking and your whole
spirit,
you are going to fucking succeed in this
life.
You're going to create a business.
You're going to create a book.
Some have a podcast that reflects your
weirdness,
your uniqueness and people will come to
you because it's true.
It's authentic and it is nothing else
out there like it.
How do you do that?
How do you stay true to that?
How do you fIgure out what your life's
task is,
as I call it?
How do you keep connected to those
primal inclination set what that's what
the book mastery is about,
but you first have to be at least aware
of what the root of your possible
success in life is,
and I try to make the point that if you
aren't pursuing something that's
personally and emotionally connected to
you,
you're never going to actually succeed
in life.
If you go into law and you are meant to
be a writer,
you might be able to bullshit your way
for 10 years or so and be a pretty good
lawyer,
but eventually because it's not
something you were meant to do,
you're going to disconnect.
You're not going to be into it.
You're going to emotionally disengage.
You're going to start drinking.
Your hair's gonna fall out.
You're gonna.
Start seeing hookers
getting on drugs.
Wait a minute.
You were good.
Up until that point.
I lost ya.
Well,
because you're not
pursuing what you were meant to pursue
and your life's going to fall apart.
You're not
have a good time with hookers and drugs.
Well,
you can.
I see.
That was.
You're right.
I probably lost you there.
People are probably going.
That's what I really want to mastery is
you become a lawyer when you're really
supposed to be a writer.
Then you get hookers and drugs and
hookers and drugs are fun.
No,
no,
no.
I'm just playing.
I,
I fully see what you're doing.
And I do think that that is a very
important point that people do sabotage
when they're unhappy.
And I find a lot of people that tend to
work jobs,
they find very unrewarding to be
exceptionally materialistic because
they're trying to reward themselves with
these material items in these material
items.
Become goals for plowing through another
daY doing this shitty job.
So
it's a real dead end.
That's like one of the worst traps that
people fall into.
Now.
I have nothing against money.
I like making money.
Um,
but the goal of your life when you're in
your twenties,
for instAnce,
should be learning as much as possible.
Developing skills in differenT areas and
not worrying about how much money you're
making,
giving yourself the freedom to make
mistakes,
to explore,
to have some adventures,
to try things out that don't quite work
for you.
And then when you reach your thirties,
you've got all these skills and
experiences and you're going to make
that money eventually.
But the path to mastery,
you look at somebody like steve jobs,
you can hate them or you can like him.
You can think he's great or not,
but he ended up being one of the
wealthiest men that ever existed in on
our planet.
Um,
he never thought about money.
He never cared about it.
He lived in a,
in a house that was hardly decorated.
He just,
you know,
it was just,
was never on his hierarchy of values to
quote maslow there.
So if you're,
if you're obsessed with money,
you're actually going to find all sorts
of problems in life.
you're going to become hooked to that
paycheck.
Let's say you're 32 years old and
suddenly you're downsized or you're
fired from your job and you've been
addicted to that $80,000.
100,000
dollars a years that you've been
getting,
now you don't have the mental freedom to
take a job for half that price where you
can now maybe start learning some skills
and moving on and really finding your
way because you're addicted to all that
luxury to the things,
into the ego that you have connected to
that paycheck.
So money is one of the worst chaps and
the reason people get into that trap
generally is because of their parents.
Their parents tell them,
johnny,
susan,
I have whatever your name is.
You've got to make a living.
You gotta,
you gotta,
go get a job.
That's luca.
If you've got to become a doctor or a
lawyer,
you know,
you got to go to yale and get this
degree and go into the business school,
et cetera,
and then you're not listening to
yourself.
You're lIstening to other people in
their and their values.
So you call that a counterforce in the
book.
It's things that work against you and to
pushing work against you from finding
what you call your vocation,
which is like what is going to make you
the most happy and doing and being and
when you're in your vocation versus just
doing a work.
When you're in your vocation,
your passionate about it,
you love what you're doing and so you're
going to naturally be more inclined to
be great at it because you're going to
put way more energy,
way more passionate into it.
I mean,
think about the people who have achieved
greatness and in any different field.
All the people we know,
you know,
even the bowhunter,
he loves it.
He loves whaT he's doing.
He's found success in doing it,
but yeah,
he found his vocation and he's just
stuck with it and so he's become a
master,
but if he was trying to do some legal
job or some accounting job,
he would suck.
Suck
at it.
Probably actually has a day job which he
fucking hates.
And when he describes it,
he talks about dying there.
Feels like he's dying every day when
he's at work.
Yeah.
But yeah,
you're absolutely right.
Um,
is,
is there a benefit in experiencing that
resistance early in life so that you
stay,
you steal your resolve against it?
Which resistance?
The resistance to do what you actually
want to do.
I mean,
I feel like a big part of my motivation
in life and the,
the strength of my resistance to getting
other people happy or to doing what
other people wanted me to do was that I
was pressured in a way that I didn't
towards the direction that I didn't want
to go.
And It was all the course.
Yeah.
I mean,
one of the things that I would hear all
the time when I was starting out and
stand up is my mom telling me that I
wasn't funny.
My mom was like,
why are you doing this?
You're not funny.
Like this is not a smart.
And I would bite down on my mouthpiece
and fucking plow forward because of
that,
because I didn't want.
I didn't want to hear that.
I didn't want to hear,
finish your college degree,
get a,
get a normal job.
Stop being a dreamer.
I didn't want to hear that because I had
heard it and it strengthened my resolve.
Yeah,
very much so.
It's definitely a theme in the book.
I mean,
if your path is too easy,
if you just fall out of the womb and
suddenly you'll note this is what you
were meant to do and that 18 year doing
it,
you're going to have other problems down
the road.
It's good to have resistance.
It's good to have people's fucking with
you and saying you're not good at this,
et cetera.
Um,
I know,
for instance,
in my path to writing the 48 laws of
power,
I kind of knew I wanted to be a writer,
but I went into forms of writing that
didn't suit me.
I started off in journalism,
did that for several years and really
kind of hated it.
And at one point an editor,
um,
had lunch with me and he pointedly said,
robert,
you never going to be a good writer.
You just don't have the chemIstry for
it.
You're just all over the place.
You're not disciplined.
maybe go to law school or something.
And that got me out of journalism
because I've made me realize I really
hate the assholes who worked there,
who was just got to stick up their butt
and can't think about what real writing
might be like.
Got out of that and wandered around
europe and tried writing novels and all
sorts of things that didn't work either
that I tried hollywood and I tried
television.
That through that process I discovered
what I loved.
When it came to the chance to do a book,
I suddenly the heavens blew open for me.
Yeah,
a book I can have total control over it.
There are no assholes telling me coming
in like in hollywood and changIng
everything that I write.
There's no writing for an article for
one week that disappears.
I've a book,
but it was only through this process of
finding what I hated.
So when people come and tell me I don't
know what my vocation is,
I don't know what it is I should be
doing.
I often say,
well,
what is it that you hate?
what are those things in life that you
don't like?
what are those jobs that you've had that
suck the life out of you?
They're going to.
They're sort of indications of maybe
something that you should like.
You don't like working for large groups
of people.
You should be an entrepreneur.
You should be working for yourself.
You're.
You're shaking your head.
You look very skeptical.
No,
no,
not at all.
I'm agreeing with you wholeheartedly.
The total opposite.
Okay,
so I'm like,
no,
please on.
No,
no.
I'm just.
Yeah,
so I love it.
You got to have the resistance
and the worst thing that happens are
people who get successful at 25 and then
think that they've got the golden touch
and they don't realize that they don't
have the golden touch that,
that they were.
They were kind of lucky and then they
keep thinking that they have to repeat
the same thing that they did.
Let's say they became a comic at the age
of 25,
became hugely successful,
but they didn't have the resistance that
you had.
Now they start not listening to their
audience or to other people or to their
who says they're not really
that funny and they just think
everything.
They do,
everything they should.
It's just wonderful.
By the way,
that's very common.
Very common.
That's a huge issue with comics.
Yeah.
A huge issue with comics.
As they become successful,
then they start to suck.
It's a real issue with some of the
greats.
I won't name names,
but what happened to woody allen?
I mean he's an older guy,
but you know,
I disagree with you there because his
movies,
his,
his movies are fucking brilliant,
man.
Blue jasmine was great.
It was a great movie.
Midnight in paris was fucking fantastic.
It was a really good movie.
I think he's just a crazy pervert and
then that's the problem.
I think what we don't like to admit it,
but what fuels woody allen is he likes
getting his dick sucked,
you know,
and he likes.
He's a freak.
You go back and you ever seen woody
allen's young standup when he was
hilarious.
He was really good.
I thought he was much funnier back then
than he is now.
He certainly is,
but he also wasn't exposed like you is
now.
He isn't hated and vilified like he is
I mean,
he became a pariah.
I mean he became like a real freak.
Yeah.
We were talking before the podcast,
I was saying that the sound of clicking,
I was putting something on twitter and I
was like,
I'm going to miss that.
If they ever get rid of that,
like the sound of clicking.
It's like so a real rewarding to me or
something like that.
Woody allen does all of his typing all
of scripts on an old typewriter and the
way he edits,
he takes pieces of paper and if he
changes a scene,
he'll print it on a piece of paper and
then cut it and then staple it to the
other thing or tape it to the other
thing.
Like he's like so old school in his
approach,
he uses the same typewriter that he's
always used for everything.
Yeah.
Well it's probably because he's fucking
terrified to go on the internet if he
googles woody allen is a.
I mean,
you know,
whoever you are,
jesus is a first word,
is going to be con.
You know,
if jesus ever gets online and googles
his name,
but for woody allen,
I mean the fucking hate and the vitriol
that that guy must experience on a daily
basis.
Just looking people in the eyes at a
restaurant must be like really pretty
fucking intense.
Yeah.
I think that phenomenon that you're
talking about with comics,
it applies to pretty much everything.
Athletes,
entrepreneurs,
because if you use this resistance of
your struggling trying to get to the
top,
people telling you you're not going to
make.
You'll never be a champion.
You'll never start on the basketball
team.
You'll never do this,
and then once you get there and once you
achieve that,
that kind of opposing force that allows
you to bring out the best can can kind
of go away.
It's why it's hard for teams to repeat
championships and things like that.
It's,
it's an interesting phenomenon.
It's almost like you need this kind of
heat and resistance to create the
greatest out of yourself and when that
goes,
you have to look elsewhere and find it
and other things.
Yeah.
You can't make steel without fire.
That's right.
I have a story in the book of freddie
roach.
He was one of the modern masters that I
love.
Freddy freddy's amazing guy and the
story of freddy's really kind of a
a model for mastery in a way and
basically I'll summarize it quickly.
He,
his father was a fighter and he got all
his boys into boxing and the age of
four.
They were already in a ring boxing away
at the age of four and so matt,
age onward.
Freddy was boxing and an amateur level
and at one point in high school,
just like your mom,
his mom said to him,
freddy,
you're not really very good at boxing.
why are you doing this?
Your brother is so much better than you.
And I got him really pissed.
So he went back into the gym and he
started training twice as hard and he
suddenly got better than his brother and
not only he started getting really good,
got on the olympic team,
became a professional,
I think it's around age of 18 or so,
and he had a boxing career as a
professional for about eight years and
he was good,
but he wasn't great.
He was kind of slow and he started
taking a lot of punches and it had an
effect on him.
And finally at the age of 26 people were
saying,
freddy,
you better retire.
Something really bad's going to happen.
And so he retired at the age of 26 and
if you think about it,
for 22 years,
boxing was his whole life.
That's all he ever did.
And now it's finished.
It's over.
His career is over and it's just,
he's ready to go on a downward spiral to
suicide or something bad.
And he gets a job in vegas as a
telemarketer because he'd been living in
vegas and fighting and he's drinking
heavily and in the day in the daytime
because his jobs at night.
And then he goes,
does it tell me it's,
he's on a fast track to suicide and one
day he decides to go back to the gym
where he used to train under his old
trainer eddie fudge.
And he's just watching the fighters.
They're like,
he used to be trained and he decides,
hey,
I'm going to maybe help this one guy
out.
He's not getting any attention right
now.
And in that moment he just,
he sort of realizes,
wow,
I like teaching.
Like maybe this is what I was meant to
be.
and he starts coming back every single
day.
He's not getting paid.
The trainer isn't hiring him.
He comes on his own and he starts
helping out the fighters and he slowly
realizes that training is the ultimate
job for him.
He loves competition.
he loves winning,
but he doesn't have to take a punch as
the trainer.
He can in the training area with his
large myths,
but no punches to the head.
He can strategize,
he can win,
he can compete,
you can do all the mind games that he
loves and he can give these years of
experience.
The reason why I consider this a model
is it took him a path where he sort of
looked like he was going downhill where
there was nothing left for him to do and
suddenly just a chance encounter,
made him realize what is real task in
life was and all that experience that he
had now could be applied to becoming the
greatest trainer,
a boxing trainer of our era,
and also a mixed martial arts trainer.
Um,
and so people always say,
well,
you know,
I,
I can't make it.
I don't know what my path is.
I,
I don't,
I can't figure it out.
I'm too old,
etc.
It's not a question of what age you are.
This,
you can always take the experiences and
mistakes that you've had in life.
And if you still got some guts and
you're not a whiner,
you can find a way to apply those
skills.
In a new way that's going to be
something that more engaged as you
personally and emotionally because in
fact,
he really wasn't meant to be a boxer.
His father had pushed him into it.
What he was meant to be was a teacher
because he's fucking brilliant at it,
so that's sort of like the model of the
path that god has for you.
It's not all rosy.
It's not all instantly finding the
perfect job.
It requires some pain,
some defeat,
some loss,
some really tough moments,
and then it's going to click together.
As long as you don't give up
here,
and it is important to to experience the
loss.
It's exploring.
It's very important to feel the lows.
If you don't feel the lows you want
appreciate the highs.
People in this day and age,
they want instant coffee.
You know they.
They want instant gratification.
They want everything to come to them
with very little work.
They want to win the lottery.
Winning the lottery.
It's probably the worst fucking thing
that could ever happen to you as a human
being.
I think bAck,
I played the lottery wants.
I want a free ticket.
I played it again.
I lost.
I'm done.
That was it.
I never played the lottery again in the
same way,
but what if I fucking one man,
what if I want 100 million dollars when
I was 21?
I would be the biggest fucking loser of
all time.
Now I probably would.
I would.
The money would be gone.
I'd be suicidal because I blew through
$100,000,000.
But it's what happens.
There's a reason why so many lottery
winners burned through that money and
it's because you don't know what it is.
You didn't earn it.
It's not yours.
It's crazy.
What you've done is you've found a
weakness in the system.
You've exploited it because the system
is designed to steal money from people
and get those dummies to spend all this
money on a fucking lottery ticket.
It's legalized gambling and the state
profits from it.
Not just once but twice because they
don't just take the money.
Your tax dollars.
Okay?
The money that you received after you
spent all your money on taxes and all
that,
just what you've got left over.
Then you buy a lottery ticket.
Well guess what?
All that money goes into a pool.
The government takes a piece of it
always,
and then when you get paid,
they take half of that.
They fuck you every way coming and
going,
and you get all that money and you still
blow it.
You still blow it.
You can't keep it with almost no one
does.
You can have a million other fucking
parasites trying to steal it from you
and because they know you don't deserve
it,
it's a.
It's a mad,
mad pursuit.
The way you appreciate money,
whether it's a dollar or a million
dollars is when you earn it,
you work hard,
you experienced the loss,
you go through the trials,
tribulations,
and then you get it.
when I look back at my path,
I'll just say real quick,
when I looked back at my path,
you know I've got out of school and I
didn't know what the hell I was.
Gonna do and already felt terrible.
I had some idea that I was already gonna
be in my vocation doing something great.
By the time I finished college.
Well,
that didn't happen,
you know,
I was successful in a variety of
different things.
I kept trying but not really nothing
that I could really hang my hat on.
So I was really anxious and antsy and I
kept trying things.
I started a marketing company.
I sold fake vaginas.
I worked for a pharmaceutical company,
plus fleshlight,
the largest fake vagina company.
This is a tangent we don't need to go to
for what?
For stick your penis in them,
you know,
and I was working with oil and gas
companies,
but every single thing it was like the
universe came and just bashed me on the
head.
Something didn't work out,
you know,
I'd even get options in this company
that was going to strike,
you know,
they were fracking some gas or something
like that.
I didn't really understand it at that
point,
but if that would have been successful
and worked,
I would've made a huge amount of money
and that would have deterred me from
this path I am now.
Which now I truly feel I'm in my
vocation.
But if I look back,
all of these things that I was fighting
for for success,
if they would have come and they would
have come lucratively,
they might have deterred me from what my
real vocation is.
So all of these things,
all these bashes on the head,
like the universe takinG a fucking
hammer and saying,
wack not going to work has kind of led
me in this weird path to actually doing
something that I truly now feel is my
vocation.
But those things are blessings.
Those failures.
I think eventually you would have found
your way because it's just who you are.
Maybe.
So like maybe
it's easy for say when to say when
someone's successful.
I know that's like the secret.
My issue with the secret is they only
talk to the ones who worked.
Like I was hanging out at the comedy
store once and my friend kelly,
kirsten,
very funny,
standup comic had a friend that came
with her to the comedy show.
She seemed like a very nice person.
And she was talking about the secret and
this is the first time I met her and she
was going on about,
you know,
I'm going to have this and I'm going to
have that and because I discovered the
secret and you know that movie where it
tells you to manifest your own destiny
with your imagination and you can make
things happen.
She had decided that because she had
this belief in this system,
this,
this secret thing,
that she was going to somehow or another
be super successful and find the man of
her dreams and be rich beyond our
wildest imagination.
Then I ran into her many years later.
She came to another comedy show that I
had a at the ucb and I remember she was
very nice.
So I was talking to her.
I was like,
hey,
how you doing?
I hadn't.
I talked to her once and then I talked
to her twice.
Those are the only two times I ever had
an interaction with this woman.
She seemed very nice,
but I'm talking to her and she's like,
I don't know why it's not working like
my relationships with terrible.
I can't cut myself off of these bad
relationships.
My father is always wants money from me
and he's always broke and he drinks and
it's like she had.
She was like,
I thought that I was going to be able to
create my own life and it's just not
working.
And the secret,
when you watch those fucking shows,
it's only the people that succeeded
there.
Like I drew a picture of the house that
I wanted in 10 years later,
I'm living in that house.
I set a goal.
My goal was $10,000,000.
I have $10,000,000.
The secret is real.
Well,
there's a person out there that drew a
picture of a fucking castle on the moon
and they're still in pasadena.
They're like,
where's my fucking castle on the moon?
He ain't getting there,
bitch.
Okay.
It's not that simple.
And when you,
you're,
you're dealing with a very biased
profile.
You're only talking to the people that
are successful.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean,
one of the things in the laws of human
nature coming up is this idea that if
there's something that's easy,
uh,
that someone's trying to pedal,
it's a deception.
It's a con game.
We want to believe we humans wanting to
believe in something quick and easy and
simple.
And if we believe in something that
means it can't really be real.
If we believe that because of that,
um,
in other words,
we want to believe that we can,
that god will grace us with,
you know,
if we do perform certain rituals or that
we can make a lot of money by just
following the secret.
The truth of the matter is that to get
really successful,
to make money that lasts,
it takes hours.
It takes 10,000
hours,
it takes 20,000
hours.
It takes a lot of work,
tedious work,
drudgery,
boredom,
moments of challenge,
two feet.
That's the reality.
So anybody that's trying to tell you
that,
that is not the case,
that there are shortcuts.
They're con artists,
okay?
That's just pure and simple there,
connors.
And one thing I'm trying to tell show
in,
in mastery is that we humans are geared
towards pleasure.
We don't want to do things that are
naturally painful.
We are immediately attracted to things
that offer us some kind of pleasure or
reward.
And the problem is too many things
nowadays offer pleasures that are
immediate,
instant rewards,
um,
you know,
a movie or a video game or something
like that,
or a drug where without much effort,
we get a feeling of relaxation,
pleasure.
and what I'm trying to show in mastery
is that there's a different kind of
pleasure that you want to train your
body towards,
aiming at.
And that's a pleasure that comes from
conquering yourself,
from learning something deeply as you're
taking up a or you've been doing archery
for some time.
It's probably not too satisfying the
first few days that you were doing at
our first few weeks.
It was a challenge.
There wasn't much creativity involved,
et cetera.
But if you keep doing this for five
years,
10 years,
suddenly it's reach a level pleasure
that no video game could ever,
ever begin to supply you.
And I want to reorient your whole value
system towards this other kind of
pleasure that comes from conquering your
yourself,
getting discipline,
getting skilled at something,
becoming really good at it and feeling
incredible sense of fulfillment as
opposed to all those immediate rushes
that our culture tries to pedal.
That's such a huge point for
satisfaction in life.
I feel most relaxed after I've worked
out really hard and not just physically
because I've blown off all this steam,
but because I did it,
you know,
I'm,
I'm a big fan of being uncomfortable and
I tell that to people and I go,
what are you talking about?
Like,
look,
nobody likes sleeping in more than me.
I mean,
maybe you do,
but I doubt it.
I love it.
I love sleeping in,
but I don't do it.
Okay.
I get up,
I get up and a half to get up unless I
can,
you know,
did all my shit.
But my point is in when I have something
that I have to do when I do it,
if I don't want to do it,
it feels even better once I've done it.
And that's,
that's the fan,
that's the fan of being uncomfortable,
that I liked that feeling.
I liked that feeling because that
feeling of shaped me.
It's rewarded me.
It's one of the reasons why pursue so
many things that I've never done before.
Why I got into archery.
Why,
why I'm enjoying it.
I'm enjoying it because I fucking suck
at it.
You know,
I like sucking at something.
Yeah.
Because you suck at it.
And now I don't suck out as much as I
did three weeks,
three months ago.
Whatever the hell it is.
When I first bought a bow,
I'm better at it now for sure.
I put pictures online of my,
my fucking my patterns that I can hit
my,
um,
the uh,
you know,
arrows in the bull's eyes and shit
because I want to reinforce that in my
head to keep doing that.
And also there's a discipline involved
in something that's very difficult to do
that requires all of your concentration.
That clears the mind.
And I think that that's.
You can get that in gardening.
You know,
you can get them running up hills,
whatever it is.
When you're running up hills,
you're not thinking about too much other
shit when you're absolutely exhausted
and your heart's pounding your chest and
you know you've got 300 yards to go and
you don't think you can make it.
There's,
there's a.
there's a beauty in that.
Yeah.
You're talking a lot about zen
philosophy almost too,
as well as using some modality of
movement,
which is often it is or anything to find
a,
a sort of presence of mind,
you know,
returning to that state of openness of
consciousness and archery is one of
those main channels and in the art of
archery,
great book,
I've read that and you know,
you,
you work for these moments,
they call it satori where it's these
moments where you have this really
mindless shot that you take in archery
and everything is just completely in the
moment.
And I think the masters have found a way
to duplicate that more.
You know,
more often more.
They have a almost a formula that can
allow them to get
these moments where they're really in
the zone as you would call it,
or flow the flow.
Yeah,
getting these flow states,
which is really,
you know,
hearkening back to that old zen
philosophy of being of no mind and that
is the the experience that best
describes martial arts at its best as
well.
When you're fighting,
when you're competing,
especially if there's anything on your
mind,
anything else besides the task at hand,
besides dealing with the other skilled
person,
you're going to be diminished.
You will be diminished.
Your skills will be diminished.
Your mind will be diminished.
It's one of the reasons why so many
people talk trash.
They talk trash to fill your mind up
with other tasks.
They fill your mind up with insecurity
and doubt or anger,
which is just as bad.
Fill your mind up with all those
emotions.
You might be able to win with anger if
you're fighting a less than skilled
opponent,
but if you fight a real master and you
have anger,
you're going to make mistakes.
You're going to open yourself up,
you're going to fight with that anger,
and in fighting with that anger,
you're gonna.
Expose yourself.
You're not gonna fight with perfect
strategy,
unless you're Mike Tyson versus michael
spinks were is fuck.
No maTter what he does to tyson could
come into that fight on cocaine,
angry,
didn't matter.
He's going to kill you because he's just
so much better and less that,
but when you have to mike tyson's,
you know what you get,
you get Mike Tyson versus evander
holyfield.
You get a guy who was fighting with
purity and a guy who's going to beat
your fucking ass.
You're not going to take him out of
there with one big rush in the first
round and you know you're going to wind
up getting knocked the fuck out,
and that's what happened to holy wood to
tyson.
When he fought holyfield,
he fought a real master.
He fought a master when he wasn't a
master anymore.
Yeah.
This.
I didn't include them in the mastery of
an inclusive in my next book,
but I was reading phil jackson's most
recent book and he said,
master himself,
and he discovered then dealing with all
these incredible egos on the team as he
did with the polls and later with the
lakers that if he tried to get them all
wired up before a game and emotional,
which is what a lot of coaches would do,
gala,
we're going to rip the guts out of them.
Let's go kill the lake or whatever,
that they would play much worse.
So his job was to imbibe in them
incredible peacefulness and calm this so
they would meditate before a game which
no other coach ever did before.
And he wanted them completely to be
mindful in the game so that they could
focus on the task and not use all that
anger to push them.
And some players could use the anger a
little bit,
but most people like dennis rodman.
He would make them do all sorts of
terrible mistakes and look at the
results.
you know,
there's no coach who's had more
championships or more success than
someone like phil jackson,
but the thing that I tried show in
mastery,
because I have a story of a great zen
master,
a man named hakuin,
uh,
because I myself practice zen meditation
had been for many years.
This man,
if this was in sEventeenth century,
18th century,
Japan,
he was reacting against all the zen
practices that were going on in Japan
that we're trying to promise you
enlightenment through something very
simple.
All you had to do was sit in what's
called zaza and seated meditation and
enlightenment would come to you.
And he said,
this is such bullshit.
I hate this.
This isn't the way to mass,
to enlightenment.
They've gotten away from the true
essence of zen.
You have to have pain.
You have to go through 10,
20,
30 years of tortured doubt,
misery.
The zen master hitting you over the head
with that stupid stick.
Every time he saw that you weren't
concentrating and then you would be
enlightened.
And so I'm trying to show you,
even if it's enlightenment,
which seems like the most material thing
you could think of requires the same
process of going through a practice of
having pain,
of having resistance,
of having a teacher tell you that you're
fucked up,
you're wrong,
hitting you on the head,
on and on.
It's a life.
Is that okay?
Greatest teacher of all life will hit
you on the head.
It's sure if you don't have any teacher
with an actual stick,
you better believe that you know life
itself will handle that.
No,
I mean the.
What I try and say is I'm grounding you
in what the human brain was evolved for
because our brains aren't,
weren't wired for ipods and iphones and
twitter.
They were wired over hundreds of
thousands of years of hunting,
of dealing with extremely radical,
dangerous situations in which it the one
moment,
if we're not careful,
the leopard will come and eat.
Us and early humans were being eaTen
quite often by large cats.
I'm very dangerous environment in which
your awareness,
your focus,
your ability to understand your
environment as if it were on your
fingertips,
to know every square foot of that very
dangerous african savanna that you're
on.
That's what the brain was wired for.
Focus,
seeing something deeply,
understanding your environment,
not being distracted here and there and
looking over there.
That's not how the brain was evolved,
so all of these disciplines,
from boxing to zen enlightenment,
to archery,
to music,
to whatever,
they're all connected with the same
brain process that we all have to go
through in order to reach this point
where we've mastered our environment.
Whatever that might be.
your work in meditation,
what,
what type of may saId zen meditation.
What type of zen meditation do you
practice?
Well,
I've done mostly renza was called
rinzai.
There's soto and rinzai.
I used to go to a place where I was
trained and now I do it on my own.
What's the difference between the two
schools of thought?
One of them is more of a passive process
where you're just sitting there trying
to completely empty your mind and that's
sort of the easier,
slightly easier path and the concept is
if you're able to reach a state where
you're not thinking at all and you've
your mind,
enlightenment will come to you.
The other school is more active.
You can't just,
not just so passive.
You just can't empty your mind.
You have to do something else.
And that something else is.
I'm simplifying it my junior,
but that's something else is,
is more discipline and going through
learning these various coeds,
uh,
for instance,
the most famous koan is these are
usually a series of questions they'll
sound of one hand clapping,
but the one that I've used for years is.
The question is,
does the dog have buddha nature?
And the answer from the zen master is
move,
meaning no,
but it means more than no.
It means like nothing just nothingness.
And it's the most powerful zen koan ever
written.
If you ever try and think about it
deeply,
you will reach enlightenment.
The different school of thought is you
meditate on that koann almost like a
mantra and try and figure it out until
it opens up a gate in your head.
Um,
that's a simplified version of the two
different types.
So the idea being that this preposterous
question becomes sort of a pattern that
your thoughts go into and you become
empty because there's,
this pattern becomes you.
You say it over and over and over and
over again.
You recite it.
You think about it over and over again
until you reach a state of mind,
until you become so absurd that the
words fall off of you.
Zen is trying to teach you something
that's wordless.
We're so trapped in language and words
and thinking that that's,
it separates us from our natural state
of know of original mind,
of the nonthinking mind.
I know that sounds strange idea,
but um,
so through words,
you're going to realize the absurdity of
words that they're not.
They're disconnecting you from reality.
And so at that point you realize that
move means everything.
There's absolutely nothing real in this
universe that can be encompassed by a
word.
My talking about it here is absolutely
completely counterproductive and and
ridiculous because people are going to
think,
oh,
I'll just repeat the word move over and
over again.
No,
it takes months of,
of thinking very deeply about this is
trying to cut you off from that chatter
in your head from,
from thinking constantly,
linguistically about.
It's a total physical form of
enlightenment,
zen.
It's,
it's most physical form of enlightenment
you could reach.
I keep getting reminded of that bill
bradley story that you told,
you know,
and kind of repeating the same thing
bill bradley was,
he was a terrible basketball player to
start big,
gangly,
slow,
not,
not terrible,
but it wasn't good,
but he had the most relentless pursuit
of improvement of anybody that I've ever
read.
You can probably pick up the story,
but he,
you know,
dress,
dribbling the
ball constantly.
Eight hours,
nine hours a day,
you know,
again,
over and over and over again.
And that kind of repetition,
you know,
it's,
it's all part of this same pattern of
doing the same thing over and over
again.
well,
I'm glad you bring up music is a great
story.
It's kind of another like freddie roach
type thing.
You take the skis,
he's a white guy who happens to be tall,
but he loves basketball.
He's like nine years old,
and I know this myself because I love
basketball when I was a kid,
just the sound of the ball swishing
through the net.
He just loved that,
that side of the sound of that,
the feel of it.
So we had this sort of visceral love of
the game,
but he stunk at it.
He was tall,
awkward,
slow.
There's no way he'd become good at it.
so he decided he was gonna train himself
from a very early age and I call it,
um,
you know,
they have a concept in called deliberate
practice where you learned to practice
what you're not good at because we
often,
if we're taking up archery or
basketball,
we find something that we're good at and
we tend to just repeat that.
And tHen our practice becomes very one
sided,
deliberate practices to practice on what
you're not good at.
I call it resistance practice,
actually practicing it.
What is painful in enjoying the pain?
And that's bill bradley.
He put these special glasses on his head
that prevented him from looking down so
he could.
He would dribble on a court for 10 hours
or 10 hours,
three or four hours,
and he couldn't look down at his feet
which trained him to dribble.
That's the worst thing.
You can have fear always looking down.
You're not able to see where what's
going on on the court.
So he did.
He did that.
He went on a cruise with his parents
across to england and he didn't.
He wanted to build a practice there.
He brought his basketball and below
deck.
There were these incredibly long alleys
that would go from one end of the shift
to the other that were very narrow.
He would put on a special glasses and he
would dribble back and forth in this
narrow area so that he could dribble
with absolute complete control.
He devised all of these other exercises
where he could train himself to see
almost behind himself or at least way
over to the side on and on and on until
he became so good that by the time he
got into college at princeton and then
later he played for the New York knicks
in the seventies with all the great
champIonship teams.
People would look at bill and they go,
my god,
this guy is.
He's a born.
He was born with a basketball in his
hand.
He's naturally gifted.
He is so graceful.
He has eyes in the back of his head.
He could make a pass to walt frazier
without even looking.
They didn't realize that he had gone
through the most insanely rigorous,
painful,
deliberate form of practice ever
invented by a single human athlete.
I'm at a very early age,
um,
and it made,
it,
made the game fun for him.
It was sure it was a lot of pain,
but by the time got good and he was in
high school.
All the girls were admiring him.
You know,
he got invited to go to princeton.
I mean,
it paid off.
And he got a huge level of pleasure and
the game became incredibly fun,
but it was all based on these insane
moments and periods of of pain that he
put himself through.
That's a beautiful story.
I love that story.
That's amazing.
That's such a huge lesson for young
people coming up to learn and here to
instill that into your mind and to use
that as a template.
Yeah.
Particularly nowadays when you're just
so inundated with immediate pleasures
and so many young people are
disconnected from what I call,
you know,
the,
the pattern that our brains were built
for.
If you're going against that pattern and
trying to get things quickly or
immediately,
you're just going to fail.
You're just going to be a loser in life.
there's no you can't.
You in your short life,
can't suddenly move against 2 million,
3 million years of evolution.
I'm sorry.
It's just can't be done.
That's a beautiful statement,
man.
That's so that what you said is so
important and that story,
that bill bradley story is such a
powerful story because anyone can do
that with whatever you're trying to do.
Exactly.
I mean,
he just happened to be born tall,
so if you hadn't ended up being six foot
six or seven and he wouldn't know,
but that's all.
What about muggsy bogues,
he was a great bass player.
There's plenty of examples of people who
exactly.
They physically weren't built for.
I mean,
Mike Tyson was one of the smallest
heavyweight champions of that modern
era.
You know,
he was five foot 10.
He,
you know,
he weighed 215 pounds in his prime look,
go back to primo carnera who was a
heavyweight champion and the fucking
twenties or thirties or whatever the
hell it was.
He was like 300 pounds,
you know,
I mean,
mike tyson's,
in my opinion,
the greatest heavyweight of all time,
and it wasn't that big.
It wasn't a big guy,
you know,
and the,
the cool part is that ultimately,
you know,
we've talked about it before.
Any master that you meet,
they're generally a real true pleasure
to be around.
You know,
if they've worked through all of these
country egoistic attitudes that they may
carry along.
And it's through this,
almost overcoming this physical
resistance in the very heart of the
mastery that they're doing.
It doesn't matter,
ping pong,
bowhunting,
comedy,
whatever,
basketball,
whatever it is,
you reach a certain place by pushing
through that pain and going through
those hours and doing those things that
almost tempers your spirit as the,
as the main thing that's happening.
And it just,
the skill kind of comes along with it
sometimes been focused on the sometimes
not though unfortunately sometimes
focusing on that skill becomes to the
detriment of all other aspects of your
life.
And there are people that achieved
mastery in very specific things that are
fucking total shitheads ty cobb.
Great example.
It was famous shithead.
You know what I mean?
There's a lot of people,
Mike Tyson in his prime,
you know,
went to jail for rape.
There was a lot of.
I mean,
I don't think he did it.
He says he didn't do it and he's really
honest pretty much everything else in
his life.
But the point being,
you know,
he was a wild,
crazy fuck.
And that was one of the reasons why he
was being successful.
There are very many examples of people
who become so selective in what they're
trying to do and so obsessed and focused
to the detriment of personal
relationships to the detriment of their
own personality.
I mean,
steve jobs would definitely fall under
that.
I agree.
It doesn't have to be that way though.
it doesn't have to be that way.
Then I always say I'm even with ty cobb
or steve jobs,
they were probably miserable to be
around,
but he had a pretty hugely satisfying
life.
Maybe.
I don't know man.
I don't know that guy now.
I don't know.
I think it kinda goes to your.
Use the bathroom real quick,
please tell you.
Hey goes to kind of one of your final
points which is on that path to mastery.
The final level is building bridges back
to nature,
back to different and making other
connections.
You know.
So if you stay too focused in that one
thing,
he never looked to build a bridge to
anything else you can probably result in
some of these issues.
Yeah,
I mean,
for those who don't know the book,
essentially I've laid out kind of five
or six steps towards this ultimate form
of mastery.
It's like a path and it involves first
discovering who you are,
what you were meant to do,
then going through what I call the
apprenticeship in which you develop all
of the proper skills later in life.
You have like a real firm basis for
becoming creative.
And part of that apprenticeship involves
working with mentors and masters and it
also involves learning how to work with
other people and deal with their
weirdness and their political games and
then showing you then how you reached
the creative level and then the mastery
level.
And it's a loose path.
It's not like a straight line,
uh,
but I'm sort of showing you the various
steps that get you there.
And as he poinTs out,
um,
particularly nowadays,
uh,
it involves the kind of a
well-roundedness.
You're not just some asperger's guy in
silicon valley who's great at a
logarithms and creating the ultimate,
you know,
facebook or whatever.
you also have to have social skills.
And I have a whole chapter in mastery of
social intelligence.
You have to learn how to deal with
people.
You have to be socially fluid,
you have to know how to be empathetic,
how to understand what other people's
feelings are,
how to handle the assholes that will
inevitably cross your path.
So sort of the people that that joe's
talking about who are a little bit one
sided,
they've kind of bypassed some of these
other things that I'm talking about
because I'm trying to get you to that
well rounded form of mastery,
which is true mastery mastery over your
whole life,
not just a specific task.
very much so.
Do you.
You were talking a lot about meditation.
Did you ever spend anytime in an
isolation tank?
I have.
Do you do iT on regular basis?
When I was living in New York years ago
as a journalist,
they asked me to write an article about
isolation takes.
This was when they were just starting
out early eighties.
They were around before that.
They were,
but they became a recreational thing in
the early eighties.
The yeah,
they were around as a cia experiment and
the people know john lilly,
the guy john lilly,
but,
but for the general public,
it really became like a fad in the early
eighties.
Uh,
so I,
I was asked to cover and I got kinda
hooked and I did it for awhile.
I haven't done it since then,
but I was quite.
It's a great experience.
I think that was because of the movie
altered states.
When did that movie come out?
Because that was how I found out about
this.
I think you're right.
81.
No.
Nineteen 80,
80 altered states.
Exactly.
Yeah.
It's,
isn't it funny how a movie can just
start a trend like that?
Um,
I found out about altered states when I
was in high school.
I watched the movie in high school or
right after it came out.
I actually saw in junior high because
there's 80.
I wasn't in high school yet,
but uh,
I got into isolation tanks when I first
came to California because they had them
here and I never knew that there was a
place where you could get into one and
through talking about it on the podcast,
the,
the entire industry has got this massive
bump now and there's isolation tank
centers opening up all over the world
that credit me talking about it on the
podcast and youtube videos that I talk
about it.
I have one of my banks meant,
oh man.
I think it's.
How often do you do it?
All the time.
I think I was in yesterday.
I think it's the most important tool.
Actually,
yesterday,
not online day before yesterday.
I didn't go yesterday.
I think it's the most important tool
that I've ever discovered.
How often should it?
I at least an hour.
I think an hour is the right amount of
time.
Is there somebody that wakes you up and
gets you out?
No.
I have a timer.
I set a timer if I have to,
but sometimes I go in there if I don't
have
sense of time.
You have no idea,
but an hour is
kind of.
Yeah,
maybe.
I don't know.
My brain seems to know when to hours is
two hours seems pretty standard for me.
Like if I,
if I don't have any time constraints,
two hours seems to be what I really,
depending on whether or not I'm sober or
not when I go into it,
never drunk.
But marijuana is usually the,
uh,
intoxicant of choice,
especially edible marijuana,
which provides a much more
hallucinogenic effect.
Yeah.
I think it enhances the experience of
the psychedelic state inside the tank.
You don't freak out or.
I like figuring out,
freaking out,
freaking out.
It's important.
I'm a big fan of freaking out because
then much like,
you know,
the stress of exercise or discipline
through the experience of complete
freaking out you.
There's lessons to be learned.
Confront your demons and stuff.
Yeah.
The psychedelic state that you can
achieve inside an isolation tank.
I'm edible.
Marijuana is pretty,
pretty
fucking intense.
Wow.
But it's just the data environment for
meditation.
I mean,
there's no better environment ever
created for meditation.
In fact,
it's the only environment like it on
earth.
You're a successful man.
How come you don't have one of those?
I don't have a basement,
but the basement.
well,
I don't know.
my girlfriend would want
edit our hub shit.
Get a new one.
New girlfriend.
Moving on.
She tried to keep you from having an
isolation tank.
What's she trying to do to keep you from
enlightenment?
Yeah.
All right.
I'll try that.
Honor the artist talking about your own
laws.
You're violating them right now by
saying that.
Did your girlfriend tell you what kind
of car you can drive to?
No.
Oh,
but sometimes you got give in to the
other person.
You know relationships a little bit
about that.
Compromise.
Not if it's about an isolation tank.
No,
you're right.
You're right.
and no fucking reason.
I'm sorry.
I'm beating you over the head with your
own work.
That's all right.
Everybody does that.
But zen meditation is sort of like the
the isolation because the point of it
is,
is to cut off all stimuli and you're
not.
You don't have to rely on this
environment that you're putting yourself
into.
So your eyes are open when you're
meditating,
but you're not looking at anything and
you're not getting in any stimuli at
all,
so you're not hearing anything.
I mean there can be sounds outside,
but you're not paying attention to them
and you enter the state that's similar
to what the isolation take is.
I can enter a state like the isolation
tank without the isolation tank because
I cut off all stimuli and I enter my own
mental space and incredible things can
happen.
So you just,
nor the stimuli until the point where
it's not reaching the mind,
is that the idea behind it
training it's years of meditation where
you're not good at it and still to this
day,
thoughts invade your head,
which probably don't so much.
Well they do when you're In an isolation
tank of course to do.
Um,
but if you go,
uh,
it's called samadhi and somadi is a
state where your samadhi tanks.
No.
Yeah,
that's the name of the company,
right?
That's right.
I remember tanks.
I remember that.
Well,
somebody is a kind of mindless state or
that's not exactly the word,
but you're,
you're,
there's no thinking going on and it's
just incredibly euphoric.
You could reach that through medItation,
but it maybe after 20 minutes or 25
minutes you get to that state,
but you're cutting off all stimuli
and the reasons they founded yoga was to
make it so that there was less stimuli
coming from your seated ass,
you know,
and the law,
the way that your legs were folded when
you're meditating because all of that
noise that an isolation tank filters
out.
And I love,
I love the tank.
It's most effective for me.
but you know,
they would do yoga so that they could
sit in that pose and have less of that
stimuli yelling for longer so they could
reach those in which they
could find that wow.
So personally find that yoga releases
some form psychedelic chemicals in the
mind that it's,
its own practice and gotten high,
like legitimately high from yoga to the
point where uh,
not I don't want to say intoxicated
like,
um,
like diminished in some way or affected
like I can't form sentences or anything
like that,
but like I feel like a chemical effect
or a biological effect,
some sort of a real tangible effect from
yoga definitely.
Which I have always wondered.
I mean,
my thought process was why would these
people do all this for so long?
Like what,
why would they have this practice for
thousands of years unless there was
something to it and there's something to
it.
I do a lot of swimming and I find
swimming the x absolute ultimate form of
exercise because there's nothing,
there's no stimuli.
I mean You're not sitting there thinking
about the water anymore and your brain
just zones out and after you do long
distance swimming,
you can reach very interesting alpha
states.
Yeah,
I agree.
I find it incredibly,
I'm not just beautiful in that sense
where you achieve states,
but it's really taxing.
it's really hard to swim like most
people think of swimming is like
recreational activity,
like I do a lot of swimming with my kids
and we play around,
but when I do laps like fuck.
It's fucking hard.
Yeah,
swimming is hard to do,
man.
You look at it dude,
like Michael Phelps.
That's a bad man.
That guy has achieved this incredible
ability to move through the water.
Like a fucking fish.
That's not an easy.
That is a real legit difficult
accomplishment.
Yep.
I like the pain,
the mental pain involved in swimming
because I like to swim long distances
where you're like,
I just can't do this anymore.
It's so boring and it's so painful and
I'm just going to drown.
I kept.
I'm taking whatever,
and then you just push past that and you
swim two miles and you get out.
Man.
What a great feeling.
Do laps in the pool over and over and
over again.
You're not one of those crazy fox.
It gets in the ocean.
Are you?
I would love to,
but I live close to the ocean and it's
cold and polluted.
If I lived in Hawaii,
I'd be swimming in the ocean and then
they get radioactive shit come from
Japan.
Says if I lived in the yucatan,
I'd.
Ah,
there you go.
That's it.
That's the spot.
Long ocean swims moved to the uk.
That is a beautiful patch of water
though,
by the way,
to loom you ever been into loom?
No,
I've been to teach an eatsa chinita.
Yeah,
it's amazing.
Yeah.
Incredible.
Yeah,
that's freaky spot.
You know,
being around those ancient ruins is one
of the most bizarre moments I think I've
ever had.
Just walking around knowing that people
were playing football with human heads
where I was standing scant 1500 plus
years ago or whatever it was.
Um,
so this,
uh,
these,
these altered states that,
uh,
you achieve with zen meditation,
do you,
do you find them to be psychedelic?
Do you find like that you can
hallucinate,
do you?
Well,
they,
you're not supposed to.
That's not the goal.
They have this word called,
which means a demon.
And what it means is after a certain
point in,
in meditation,
demons start appearing in your brain
where you've cut out all sensory stimuli
and suddenly images start coming up that
are just weird and random and somewhat
frightening.
Uh,
and I,
that happens to me all the time,
like a almost or like in a dream state,
you know,
how in dreams their thoughts and images
that it seems so random and sometimes
scary by how random they are.
You're consciously getting that in your
head as you're entering deeper and
deeper into this state,
but you're trying to push past that.
You're trying to push to the state where
there's nothing coming in at all and you
kind of transcend the,
this sort of thinking state that you're
constantly in.
Can't really put it in words.
I don't even want to try and put it in
words.
So the goal isn't really to have these
vivid hallucinations,
but they happen and they're very
interesting.
That's fascinating though,
that it's thought to be demons.
Yeah.
And in the traditional zen form,
they,
that's what they call them.
Um,
and uh,
I know that,
um,
they have in japanese iconography these
very frightening looking demon like
figures and then they do actually have a
concept of hell,
uh,
in,
in japanese culture that came into zen
buddhism and I know hakuin talks about
these very vivid images of demons that
he had when he was a child that he was
so afraid of them that he decided he had
to get into buddhism and zen to overcome
them.
So I don't know exactly.
I'm not going to be hallucinating these
japanese demons that were probably very
much in their minds and in their
culture.
Uh,
but if,
you know,
it's interesting.
This is a total,
I don't know how far we're getting away
from things here,
but there's no getting away.
Okay.
This is concept in ancient times.
So there's a great book called the
bicameral mind.
I don't know if you're familiar with it.
I never read it though.
The ideal is in this book is that for
ancient people,
consciousness was almost like a voice in
their head and it flipped them out and
they couldn't understand it and they
were constantly like on drugs.
Hearing their own thoughts and that's
why they had to project it onto gods and
demons and other things that are out
there in the world,
but literally hearing their own thoughts
was almost like a continual trip for
them.
It's hard for us to imagine because
we're so used to the chatter in our
minds,
but originally,
according to this man,
this was how they experienced
consciousness with this in the early
days of language.
Is this a
fairly recent?
Is that was the idea
behind it is 6,000,
7,000,
10,000
bc.
It's a,
I can't remember the writer's name.
Julian something or his last name is
julian.
Great book.
Um,
but if you read books like about
buddhism,
which I do for racially,
uh,
the history of it,
early people in meditation,
early adherence to buddhism,
we're constantly talking about that
chatter in their mind as if it were
hell.
It was like hearing this noise of
thoughts was just awful.
It was claustrophobic and frightening
and they had to get into meditation and
buddhism just to calm the mind down and
not hear that voice in their heads.
Now,
this is a totally alien notion to us
because we're so used to it and it's
almost not a good thing that we're so
used to it.
Um,
but I think that that's sort of the idea
of the demons constantly hearing this
voice,
these things in your head that aren't,
you're not willing them,
you know,
like you're not willing these thoughts
that are constantly coming up into your
mind.
Where are they coming from?
There's a great zen cohen called,
who is the master?
Where are your thoughts coming from?
Who is the master calling up these
thoughts in your head,
particularly in your dreams or
particularly when you're not,
when you're maybe tired and suddenly
this image comes up,
you're not calling it up.
Well,
where is it coming from?
That's where I think this idea of demons
is,
is connected.
This reminds me a lot of going through a
psychedelic experience like iowasca in,
in that path,
you reach this very visual point in the
experience,
which is generally,
it can either be incredibly beautiful or
it can be incredibly hellish.
Like would make well incredibly hellish.
For example,
I'm,
I have different spiders going inside of
me and laying eggs and exploding and
bugs are coming out of me.
There's eels coming inside,
eating through my intestines and eating
all my organs coming out.
I'm sliding naked through a va,
down a vine of thorns.
It's ripping up my flesh.
These are all images that happened in
moscow trip or incredibly beautiful,
the most beautiful colors you've ever
seen.
The most beautiful lights,
images,
things and you know,
I get a lot of people asking me about
these trips and for them that is,
you know,
who haven't done it very much.
They focus very much on those visions,
but those visions are almost like the
fireworks and the chatter to what's
going to come after and what comes after
is this kind of oneness with your
thoughts and your,
your highest consciousness in your
highest being that has passed all that
and maybe that brings up resistances.
Things you can overcome.
Maybe it helps you with some thoughts,
but the real value of it in Iowa,
oscar dmt or any kind of psychedelic is
that period after were these demons,
are these visions.
And everything goes away and to me
that's the real end goal.
That's the real gem.
Well that's really similar to the zen
meditation because you're going through.
So I meditate for 35,
40 minutes,
the first 25,
I'm having those demons.
I'm hearing my thoughts.
I'm trying to get over.
And then I finally reached that state
only lasts for 15 minutes.
That's the best state.
It also sent a similar process.
That's it.
Yeah.
So it's not so much about the visions,
it's about what happens after the
vision.
So it seems to me very much like what
you're saying.
Yeah,
the that state after very difficult yoga
sessions,
it doesn't last very long,
but there's a period of intense
relaxation and enlightenment that you
achieve where you kind of have a better
perspective of things,
but it only comes through this very
difficult work of the hour and a half of
yoga that you have to do to get to that
spot.
And if you have acid anywhere along the
way,
you don't reach that spot.
I don't reach that spot every time.
You know,
I reached it a lot,
but I don't reach it every time.
It's very tricky,
isn't it?
Yeah.
You'd ever know and they're like,
I don't know if it's the same with
archery or the things that you do like
that,
but when you start the meditation you
bring a mood and it's never the same
sunday for no reason.
I just falls into place and some days
you don't know why this anxiety is not
on your inside.
You never could figure out what you
bring to it.
It's interesting.
It really is.
What do you have a very rigid schedule
when it comes to your meditation and
your discipline?
Like how do you structure your days?
You're obviously self employed,
you know you're a writer.
So do you.
Do you have a structure?
Like I must write for this amount of
time.
I must meditate.
Like how do you,
how do you do it?
No,
I every morning I wake up and I meditate
for 35 minutes and nothing will stop me.
I'm sick.
Or even if I'm traveling or whatever,
every day.
Do you sit in a particular way?
I have the proper pillows and I have a
little place and I have a little clock
that goes off with bells and I sit in
the lotus position until my legs are
like screaming
really,
that you can pull your legs up.
Yeah.
It's hard to do,
huh?
Yeah.
I've been doing it for many,
many years,
but then I recently broke my foot and I
couldn't do it for about three months,
so now I'm fine and I can do it.
So I'm back to having some pain again.
Uh,
but the pain is good as we all know.
Um,
and then I,
uh,
then I,
I'm not usually writing because my books
require so much research.
Uh,
so right now I'm in a research period
where I'm reading for racial sleep books
about human nature,
psychology,
etc.
And then in Nevada year I'm going to
start writing and then I go onto a kind
of a different routine where I'm a,
I'm a little more crazed and hard to be
around.
That's fascinating.
So you researched for a full year before
then,
right?
Yeah.
You discipline the research aspect of
it.
Oh man,
I'm so disciplined.
It's probably bordering on ocd.
I read,
you know,
three,
400 books and I read them,
I don't them.
And then I go back and I do these note
cards and it's the note cards that's
excruciating.
That's like the bill bradley part.
I put every book onto maybe 10,
20,
30 cards depending on how good a book it
is.
And at the end I'll have two,
3000 cards and I can written handwritten
and I can take these cards and move them
around and in the book is created out of
the cards.
So the cards are the beneficial aspects
of whatever book you're reading or what
strikes you or.
But I'm able to break a book down that
can be chaotic.
So for instance,
for this new book,
uh,
I have it a love a niche,
a lot.
I've never loved them since I was a kid.
Uber manch the uber manch.
This is a book about the uber match.
My next book,
and there's a book that I've read for
him,
uh,
early book called human all too human.
That's just the most amazing book,
but it's chaotic.
It's all over the place.
He's got all these aphorisms and these
thoughts and it's just like entering a
rat's maze.
I with my cards can organize all of his
ideas and all of his thoughts and bring
some order and show you the amazing
pearls of wisdom this guy has gleaned
out of his mad syphilitic brain.
The syphilis.
Oh yeah.
He,
yeah.
He went mad at the age of like 44 and
the best spent his last eight years and
basically too much pussy,
huh?
no crazy.
Well,
he probably not enough pussy really?
So you got syphilis.
Pussy.
He got.
He probably went to a prostitute when he
was in the prussian war and then got
syphilis and then he.
He didn't get laid enough.
I was certainly probably his problem.
That was why he was obsessed with uber.
Manch a syphilis.
That's probably why he got.
It's probably not the not getting laid.
What'd they do?
Back in those days when you had
syphilis,
there was no cure,
right?
You an apple or something like that.
That was before penicillin,
right?
Yeah.
Nothing much to do.
I think some,
some people were smart enough to start
trying silver.
I think silver had some use in some of
these things,
but it's not verY effective.
Not like,
not like an antibiotic.
Yeah.
It's fascinating because I was trying to
explain to my kids the plague because
we're reading a book and my five year
old and my three year old,
we're sitting in bed reading before
bedtime.
And the story involved the plague a
plague upon you was one of the lines and
uh,
you know,
they were like,
what's a plug?
That's shit.
Before doctors,
when they didn't really have doctors,
when all doctors could do is like cutoff
broken limbs.
They,
uh,
they had diseases that would kill giant
chunks of people.
My kids are like,
what the fuck?
I'm like,
yeah,
not that long ago by the way.
They wrote about it.
So they had language and we were,
were,
were talking about earlier about the
evolution of civilization and the amount
of time,
the very brief window between us and
when we were animals in relationship to
the length of time that things have been
alive on earth.
It's smaLl.
We're going through the most crazy and
chaotic time pretty much ever.
When the wheel,
you know,
descrIption that mckenna used to use
about the exponential growth of
technology was about sending a ball
around the top of a funnel and then it
takes a long time to get around the top,
but that we're somewhere towards the
bottom of the funnel now where that
fucking thing is going around the tunnel
going around the funnel so quickly.
it's just,
it's hard for us to really wrap our
heads around.
But when we talk to children about it,
when I talk to children about it really
sends it home.
When I tried to describe to my kids what
would a fucking plague is,
as you know,
and just.
I just remind,
reminded myself of when you read actual
accounts of the true pirates like
blackbeard and things like that.
One of the things that they would barter
with for the most,
like when they were making deals with,
you know,
the british ships or different thIngs
and striking deals was venereal disease
medicine.
Like syphilis medicine.
Like it'd be like we'll give you all the
gold,
but you have to bring over a chest of,
of a medicine to cure that.
Venereal disease,
I think that was a probably a much
bigger problem in ancient history than
not.
We're not completely ancient,
but in past civilization than we give it
credit people first venereal disease.
I don't know.
I have no idea how fucking dirty trick,
you know.
I mean think about how few diseases kill
you that you catch it just walking
around like the flu,
but you know,
I think it might be nature's way to keep
the population down a little bit.
Most likely,
right?
Yeah.
I mean it seems like what's going on,
there's always a battle,
right?
Just like we were talking about the
battle between discipline and success,
the battle between being uncomfortable
and doing things that are hard to do and
the reaping,
the rewards of that seems to be a battle
nature of trying to fucking kill us so
we get stronger.
You know?
I mean,
we don't like to think that,
but it's been directly proven that many
plagues and many diseases have certain
traits have risen through those,
through those diseases which have made
the human race actually stronger.
Although they say our cro,
magnon ancestors,
for Instance,
lived longer than we do.
Really?
Yeah.
I've never heard that.
Wow.
That's amazing.
And they've died at like 12.
Um,
I mean,
I know in the bible,
but who believes the bible?
Oh,
600 years ago,
like moses died at the age of 193.
That's a little shaky.
I know.
It is.
They didn't know what a year was back
then.
Now they're making shit up now.
The calendar suck written on a rock that
you can't really.
Yeah.
That's a lot of shit in the bible.
It's fucking tough to swallow.
Yeah.
Um,
so where did you read the cro?
Magnon lived longer than us.
Uh,
well,
for one thIng that's for certain,
they were bigger than we were real.
Uh,
they had a,
they were taller.
That's a known fact.
Agriculture.
Uh,
we did not have certain diseases that we
have now talked to the paleo people and
they can fill you with,
with all that stuff.
Uh,
but before we started having grains and
all that bad stuff,
people were perhaps living longer.
They were certainly bigger.
magnum was five foot seven,
five foot nine.
Oh you're,
you're,
you're showing me wrong.
But they were taller than the people
that came after them.
Oh,
okay.
Well,
there are.
That's the average,
but large males stood as tall six foot
five.
Not really taller than us.
Okay.
But taller then the people living than
the humans of those after
in ancient Greece or whatever.
Nothing like the internet to be able to
show that
wrong.
You know,
10 years ago there was no way you
would've been able to prove me wrong.
We've had many examples of people
stating,
I know you're not doing it,
but there's been a lot of people that
have bullshitted us.
Yeah.
Unfortunately,
and I've spread information,
so now I have to be diligent about that.
What does that wikipedia.
This is wikipedia,
but it has references.
If you'd like me to find the scientific
references there in there as well.
Don't get crazy.
I think that.
I think the path back between what we're
talking about is that life itself needs
resistance.
Just as masters need resistance,
you know?
I mean there is no,
there is no life that's worth living.
IF everything is like that Alan Watts
video,
if we could make everything absolutely
perfect and nothing is a surprise and
there's no resistance out there,
it doesn't become what it is.
It's not as rich anymore.
It's not filled with the magic that life
can be.
I mean,
resistance is an intrinsic part of that.
And the fact that nature is constantly
looking to,
you know,
pick us off is part of that resistance
and the fact that all of these forces
are aligned against someone who's trying
to become a master.
The pain sacriFice,
whatever people are saying,
all of that,
that is required for a master to be
created,
you know,
that's,
it's all part of the same thing.
you know,
it's this kind of dualism of force and
opposition.
The average liFe expectancy of cro
magnon was 35 years.
Alright.
So I met,
I meant the high.
Sorry,
did most of them.
I've got something.
I've got something that's maybe on
chromat.
I better shut up.
40th five would be exceptionally old for
cro,
magnon math.
So if I was crow bag now,
might be the fucking old wise man in the
village she gets compared to the people
who got into agricultural settlements
after cro magnon they didn't live to be
35 years old.
That age is also factoring or infant
mortality for things like that.
Things don't happen.
Disease mortality,
you know,
it doesn't mean that the,
a healthy crow bangin wouldn't live
longer.
That's the,
that's the big things.
Factoring infant mortality.
That's a big one,
right?
Yeah.
Mother's dying in childbirth.
Shit that doesn't happen anymore.
You know,
that raises or as much.
Yeah.
Um,
but when I came back to what you were
saying in the preface to mastery,
I try and say the times that we live in,
first of all,
I,
I make the point that we need masters in
the world now.
This is a time where we have incredible
opportunitY largely through the internet
where access to information,
the ability to learn things,
to develop skills,
to have an isolation tank,
to learn archery,
to do all of these things.
The world is opened up and the ability
to develop skills and master something
and create something is just completely
unprecedented at the same time.
The distractions and the resistance that
we have to go through is equally
unprecedented with the internet,
with iphones,
with all the other things that are
making it so much harder for us to
focus,
and I want you to think of all of these
things as the kind of the water that you
have to swim against and if you're able
to swim against all of these
distractions that the world throws at
you,
you're going to become a real kick ass
master in whatever it is because you've
overcome something that 90 percent of
the people in this world just submerges
them under because they're too weak.
But there's also the clIche and it's
very important to point out that there
is no end result.
That it's a journey and this journey
does not mean becoming a master.
There's not.
There's no end point.
You continue to get better at everything
you do or you start to suck and that
that's what happens.
You will get better if you do not
continue to get better.
You are getting worse.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it's true.
And uh,
you know,
you take someone like einstein,
one of the greatest masters,
he discovers the second theory of
relativity at the age of 26 and nothing
after that,
he tried to do his unified theory.
You know,
why?
Why posey again?
All that scientist was too much.
oh,
you mean he had too much?
So I was a famous pussy out.
A lot of people don't know that.
It's true.
It is true.
Yeah.
Einstein loved it.
He was smart.
So it was fine.
When you know,
two guys with the most brilliant minds
of the 20th century,
love pussy,
don't want to go to baptist.
A big old smile on einstein's face,
wacky fucking image going on him and
loved him.
He was like,
yeah,
why wouldn't you?
I mean,
you talk about all the favorable traits
for evolutionary success talking about
one of the most brilliant men
scientifically ever.
Yeah.
I would think that a lot of women will
want that seed inside of them.
You know,
look at it.
He's like,
see this,
look at that lady's fuck gene simmons.
Look at that as the tongue of a fucking
super genius with his own hair.
He was,
excuse me.
He was a very unique individual in that
that uniqueness.
I'm sure there was some motivation
behind that,
not just the scientific motivation,
but the actual natural motivation to be
exceptional for breeding purposes that
you know,
women would find him exceptional.
Yeah,
absolutely.
but you're right,
it is a process so that you never can
sort of rest on your laurels and say,
oh,
so the way I do it,
I'm not saying that I'm a master,
so don't misinterpret me,
but the way I do it for myself is every
book that I write,
I'm back at square one.
I,
I'm nobody.
I have no history of no fault readers.
I'm not successful.
I have to make it's death ground.
I have to make my next book work or I'm.
I'm a total loser.
So
that's exactly the same process involved
in standup comedy,
standup comedy.
You put out a new special and then once
you have that new special,
you throw all that material out and you
start from scratch and you write all new
material and if you do it that way,
and that's the only real way to do it in
this day and age,
because too many people have the
internet.
Too many people.
I mean everyone has the internet.
Obviously too many people have access to
your previous work,
I should say,
and in comedy you constantly need new
material unlike in music.
So rough.
It's not.
It's great.
It's rough,
but it's great.
The roughness is the great part of it.
yeah,
but that,
that whole process of mastery,
you know,
you say you're not a master.
I think you are,
but I think there is none.
This is what I think you are a master,
but there's no ultimate mastery.
A master is someone who is very good at
the process,
but there's no end.
Yeah.
The end doesn't exist.
There's no.
There's no where it becomes easy.
There's no golden age of retirement.
That's a bunch of horse shit that they
fucking sell you to keep you in your
job.
There's no golden age.
You're fucking dying,
man.
You're going to get old and you're going
to reach that point where you know you
can't really work anymore so you don't
have to work anymore,
and then you've got to watch your money.
You know this,
this selling point of one day and you'll
retire and everything will be groovy the
fuck it will.
It's not going to be groovy.
There's that whole half waiting for
something to drop on you.
Even the religious belief that you go
through this life and just do your work
and then you get to heaven.
Yay.
You know,
or you go through.
If it's not religious,
this capitalist belief you,
you work in this job and it's gonna
suck,
but then you get to retire.
No bullshit.
You got to enjoy that every minute along
that path that you're going on or choose
a different path.
Fuck the money.
Fuck everything else.
Do what you love to do the whole time
and you'll smile at the end when your,
when your time is up.
Yeah,
and if you do use the wrong motivations,
you will not get the results you desire.
You know,
I know a guy who has been trying to get
famous forever and he's trying to do it
in all the wrong ways,
you know,
it's trying to become famous instead of
focusing on whatever art form you choose
to make you famous just wants fame and
it just escapes them like sand through
your fingers.
You just can't hold onto it.
You just can't,
can't get a quantifiable amount in your
hands and the motivation is incorrect.
It's like the motivation was just on his
art.
I think probably he would be far more
successful,
but instead the motivation is based on
the green demon of looking at all these
other people becoming successful and not
being able to find out why he can't
achieve it himself.
I mean it.
Attention is never the goal in.
In mastery,
it is actually a negative.
Yes,
but learning,
learning is what gets you high.
LeArning is what you love.
If you love the attention more than the
learning,
then you're fucked.
You're never gonna make it.
Yeah,
and that need,
that need
for acceptance and it's like,
it's the very opposite of what you
should be striving for.
Yeah.
You know,
and we were talking about people that
become really successful and then lose
their way and how you can learn so much
from that.
And in comedy.
My um,
my guide for that was always sam
kennison because I think that sam
kennison was the greatest comedian of
all time from 1986 to 1987.
I mean,
I'm not kidding.
I think maybe before that,
you know,
I found out about 86.
I mean probably it was the greatest and
85 and maybe even in a four,
but that's it from then on it's dog shit
if you try to listen to sam kinison from
89 or 88,
it's terrible comedy.
I went to see him alive.
He was awful.
I saw him live several times because it
was such a huge fan of his work and 86,
but the dropoff was.
So there's guys who have good cd's and
you know,
they'll have hills and valleys.
I myself,
I have stuff that I really love and then
stuff I was like,
well that wasn't my best one,
but then more motivation to do better
than the next one.
There's just sometimes creative glitches
or what have you.
A part of the process,
but with kennison there's this fucking
monster peak and then this crazy drop
off of coke and hookers.
A coke,
a lot booze,
a lot.
You know,
we had mark marin on the podcast who was
palling around with kennison in the hay
day at the comedy store when mark was a
young kid and he told some amazing
stories about this,
the amount of substances.
Mark hung out with kennison and he had
to escape.
He left la and he hit it So hard that he
was hearing voices in his head for like
almost a year.
Like literally he was psychotic and I
met mark soon after that I met mark in
boston like after he had been hanging
out with kennis and after kennison was,
you know,
riding the wave and you know,
he,
I met mark I think in [inaudible].
80 eight was when I started and I met
him soon after that,
so he had already gone through all this
and he was a young guy working at the
comedy store and he got to see this,
the overwhelming amount of substances
that kinison was consuming and massive
and it just destroyed him.
He never recovered from this cocaine,
alcohol.
I mean that.
It wasn't writing either.
His brother,
his brother wrote about it.
There's a book called mY brother sam was
a great book about kennison written by
his brother,
who was,
I think also his manager at the time who
wrote about how there was a.
He wrote about the tangible,
tangible dropoff in his writing.
It didn't write new materIal anymore and
was sort of like,
just partying.
Yeah,
I mean there's,
I talk in
the book about this myth that drugs will
just instantly make you more creative.
In fact,
it's often the opposite.
um,
and I have example of coltrane who was
probably maybe one of the greatest jazz
artist who ever lived and he got hooked
on heroin for awhile.
When people have this myth that that's
what made coltrane so great was the
drugs and the heroin and the coke and in
fact he,
he said it was the worst.
He did his worst work in that period and
he got off of it like in 58 and never
touched the drugs or drinking after that
and did is better.
Workout is much better.
Work to create something requires so
much discipline and so much mindfulness
and focus that you just can't do it if
you're constantly drugged out.
Yeah.
Especially those to those very
depressive ones and very like.
Coke and heroin are probably two of the
worst,
but there seems to be a connection
between heroin and deep soulful music.
Like maybe it helps them for a small
time,
reach a state,
but then ultimately the abuse of it
destroys your body so much that you
can't keep it up.
Yeah.
You mean like a velvet underground or
something like that?
yeah,
like there's something will hendricks
and well people will argue dangerous
wasn't really into heroin,
but if you look at that photo behind me
of his mugshot,
that is from the fucking toronto police
department when he was arrested for
heroin,
so it was a little problem with that
little heroin in his system.
I don't know what drugs.
I mean,
I know he was also involved in acid and
You know,
morrison was into heroin.
There was a lot of alcohol involveD with
a lot of those guys as well.
But the ability to escape your
inhibitions was they were chasing the
dragon in a sense.
Yeah,
but look how long it lasts.
Twenty seven.
They're all died at 27.
Janice joplin,
hendrix,
morrison.
It seems to be the most dangerous
path to embark upon iF you're looking to
gain something.
I think one of the things I got from one
of your books was the story about
theater or dusty was that in was that in
48 laws of power where it gets in the 33
strikes for add in the 40 lows.
Well,
basically after he would be successful
with a book,
you would find that he was unable to
really write and he didn't have that
creative fire anymore to create another
great work so he would take all of his
life savings and go to the casino and
just gamble it away in the night so that
he was desperate and hungry again.
He waS penniless,
penniless,
and at that point he had to write
something great to get himself out.
You know,
so these,
these people use these different
strategies and he did that over and over
again.
That takes guts.
You got to be a fucking crazy person.
That death ground,
putting yourself on death ground.
It comes from sun tzu says a general
with deliberately put his army on death
ground,
meaning he would deliberately put their
back against an ocean or a mountain and
they either had to defeat the enemy
that's confronting them or they would
die because they had no escape route,
no safety net,
no escape
route safety nets or something that I've
argued against ever since I was a child,
which was another thing that my parents
instilled in me that I had to have a
safety net.
And I've always told everybody who would
listen,
don't ever have a fucking safety net
because if you have a net you will fall.
You might not make it without the net,
but you will not make it within that.
So there's that.
There's that.
Uh,
I had an interesting experience with
mastery,
uh,
were in writing the book where I've
written four of the six chapters,
but I was getting really late in
delivering the final result.
And the publisher basically said,
you have like 11 weeks to finish the
book,
or we're canceling the project or,
or postponing it.
And they were,
the,
the two chapters left were the longest,
the hardest,
the most abstract and the most
important.
And it was like,
there's no way I'm exhausted,
I just can't do it.
But I had no choice because if they
cancel or postpone it,
all of my hard work would be thrown out
the window.
So that was death ground.
And finally,
after three days of torturing myself and
whining and bitching at myself,
I decided,
all right,
I'm going to do it.
I'm just going to try.
Let's just do what I can.
And it was the most incredible writing
experience I've ever had in my life.
I was,
I had to work harder than I've ever had
to work.
I got on this high where thoughts were
just coming to me and my dreams and my,
you know,
I'm having sex every.
It's just the most amazing.
And they worked.
And I was sitting there writing about
creativity and intuition while they,
while this was happening to me.
And it just demonstrated to me that the
limits that I thought I had are just
sort of self imposed.
And if I stop complaining and stop
saying that I had these limits,
I could explore beyond them and explore
what I was capable of that I never
thought I was capable of.
Prior to that.
You know,
hunter thompson wrote hell's angels.
You finished the last x amount of
chapters in like two days on cocaine?
Yeah.
Like you just got cooked up and fucking,
he like,
he had a deadline and maybe I should
have tried that.
Have you ever seen.
I could have written it in two days.
Me being maybe need adderall.
Have you ever seen,
um,
the uh,
the hunter s thompson documentary.
Fear.
not fear and loathing.
Fucking was it called what?
Yeah,
gonzo years ago.
Like what is it?
The life and times of a hunter?
S thompson is of the name of it.
I got it saved on itunes.
I should just pull it up on itunes.
The documentary just from a couple of
years ago.
Have you seen that a couple years ago?
No,
I have.
It is a fairly recent documentary,
but god damn,
it's good.
God damn.
It's good thing it's gone though the
life and work of hunter s thompson.
Is that it?
Yeah.
I watched it in a hotel in seattle and
fucking spent it.
That's it.
I'm liking the woRk of dr.
Hunter s thompson.
I'm so good.
It's so good.
A seven point eight kit.
That fucking blast me off there.
It's not a 10 that just shows you.
There's constant matter what you do in
this life.
That's that documentary,
that Goddamn
10 and incredibly inspirational and I
watched it in seattle at a hotel room
and just on a whim,
just larry will watch this.
I was alone.
I was doing some work and you know,
I,
I fucking wrote all night because of
that documentary.
Got on the keyboard and just smashed
keys all night.
Oh nice.
It's those things that,
you know,
you catch these bursts of inspiration
and thompson who's a personal hero of
mine,
used to call them fuel,
you know,
and he said that he personally believed
that with the right song you could drive
further in your car and your car would
figure out a way if the right song was
playing to go to go miles past the and
theoretically obviously not even
theoretically he was a,
it was just a metaphor.
Metaphor.
Metaphor,
right.
Thank you.
Metaphorically he was,
you know,
just great at figuring out how to put
these abstract ideas into a tangible
form that you mind accepted and never
met a deadline.
And his whOle thing was like putting
things off until the last minute.
And then this fury of fucking teeth
gnashing,
slamming against the keys and this
fucking.
But it's almost like he forced himself
into this,
this back against the wall.
What would you call it?
The death ground.
He forced himself into a death ground.
Well,
in order to complete.
I wish I'd done that.
I would've included it among you.
Do so.
You know,
I've know you've talking about comedy,
you like following someone like joey
diaz who is hilarious,
right?
Because you've talked about how that
makes,
you know,
that would make some people a little bit
scared and a little bit nervous,
but you like it because it's going to
bring out your best following somebody.
That's that great.
You know what I mean?
Haven't you kind of mentioned isn't
there something there in that same
philosophy?
Maybe,
but my philosophy in that is that I
think that not foe,
not working with funny really,
really funny people is a twofold
problem.
One,
it's famine thinking like they think
that there's,
there's a lot of really selfish
comedians out there and one of the
things that they like to do is they like
to stack the deck so they'll bring this
guys had a national touring headliners.
They bring the worst fucking comedians
you've ever seen in your life to open
for them because these guys go up there
and eat dick for half an hour and then
you go on stage.
The crowd has been tortured,
waiting for actual entertainment and
you're the hero.
You're the conquering hero.
So nobody out shines you this,
but it is incredibly common and I think
it's gross.
I think a disrespect to the audience,
first of all,
I think it disrespects the fact that
these people have paid money to see you.
They deserve entertainment,
not just from you but from other people
as well.
And you shouldn't be scared of other
people being funny.
It doesn't take away from you being
funny.
The only way it would take away is if
the person on before you is stealing
your material or what it's called,
stepping on your material.
Like say if you know you had a very
particular subject that you were famous
for.
Like jim gaffigan likes.
Talk about hot pockets.
He does this whole hot pocket bits.
Really hilarious.
If you went on before I even started
talking about hot pockets,
you would kind of step on his bit.
You know you would and people will do
that.
The same shit heads like that actor that
I told you that we'd like to go up to my
friend and say it was fat right before
he would go and read his lines.
That's that same sort of thinking,
that same sort of famine thinking you
like another person.
Success should be inspirational to you.
It shouldn't be detrimental to you.
And so I.
Um,
and then the other thing is I'm a fan of
comedy.
I want to laugh.
So I bring joey diaz who I personally
think is the funniest guy who's ever
lived.
I bring him to open for me because I
want to be.
I want to be in a hilarious state before
I go onstage.
I want to be laughing.
I'm not worried about not being funny
because if I've done my job,
I've done the work,
it's going to be good.
Like don't worry,
you can't worry about that.
That worrying is the enemy of comedy
here.
Yeah.
It's just,
it's pathetic.
I bring murderers with main man
everywhere I go,
duncan,
ari,
jo.
I just bring the biggest killers that I
could find.
I take headliners at me.
I've taken greg fitzsimmons on the road
with me.
I mean,
I like doing shows with guys who were
fucking awesome.
I think it's reaLly important.
It's,
but it's not because I want to die
something because we want to put my back
up against the wall.
I want the audience to get their money's
worth and I want to be around my friends
and I also want to support my friends.
Part of the reason to bring in joey and
ari and duncan on the road with me all
these years is it's selfish because I
want to have a good time and I want to
be with them and I want to enjoy myself.
So there's that.
But also I want people to know how good
these guys are and a lot of these guys
are good in a really fucked up way.
That's not it.
It's not really palatable for comedy
central.
It's really hard for them to get on hbo.
You know,
for a guy like joey diaz,
the only way for that guy to get famous
as the internet.
That's what made him famous and my help,
you know,
helping get him out there in front of
thousands of people that would never
have had an opportunity to see him and
telling people as I introduced him
basin.
Gentlemen,
please welcome the funniest motherfucker
that ever stepped foot on earth,
joey diaz and I would bring on stage
like that all the time.
I tell everybody is funnier than me.
He's the funniest guy ever.
Doesn't mean I'm not funny.
You know,
it's just,
it's not bad for things to be great
other than you.
It's good.
There's this.
You should be inspired.
The greatest people want those people
who are great alongside them to push us.
Although bird and magic were nemeses,
you know,
you talked to him now how thankful they
were that they had each other on
opposing teams.
Oh,
for sure.
Which are all of these.
All of these people you know,
you need greatness around you.
You need them.
You need going to get to have yang.
You need which one's good,
which one's negative,
and which ones pumping.
This once again is passive.
Gang is active,
man.
You need that yang to have.
Again.
You need both.
Yeah,
it makes yang.
The university has,
you know,
the tide comes in and goes out.
Bill o'reilly,
you know,
it's,
there's something.
don't talk to me about bill o'reilly is
not the greatest fucking.
Okay.
Carrie,
you can't.
You can't explain it yet.
She can't you fuck.
It's called gravity.
They figured out a long time ago.
Shit you've ever seen.
That thing that he did where he's
talking about god talking about the tie
goes in.
The tide goes out.
You can't explain it like,
you know I'm going with god.
It was the so disingenuous from a
harvard graduate.
He said,
yeah,
to
fucking have.
I have my own bill riley's story.
Please tell it to me.
Well,
48 laws of power just come out in
[inaudible] 98 and bill o'reilly decides
to have me on the if o'reilly factor,
which was big then,
but not as big as it became later on.
And so I'm like,
this is like one of my first shows I've
ever been on you.
No,
no,
no.
Nothing like this ever happened to me
before.
And basically you go to a studio in los
angeles where he's in New York and
you're in this room and there's nothing
around you,
and they put an earphone in your head
and you're staring at a camera.
You don't see anything.
You just hear bill o'reilly's stupid
fucking voice in your ear asking you
questions.
It's like you're on drugs and it's so
disconcerting.
It's like the guy who's trying to put
you off your game before and you're
already put off your game the moment you
start.
Anyway,
he interviews me and I prepared like
shit for this interview because I knew
the questions coming.
It was all about monica lewinsky and
clinton and the scandal and the 48 laws
and I nailed it.
And he said,
oh,
that was a great interview,
robert.
I'm going to have you on again.
Okay,
wow.
And so I'm feeling pretty good about
myself.
So four weeks later I trudged back to
that office and I sit in that same chair
with the little earphone in my head and
he proceeds to just rip me to shreds
about what a.
Well,
essentially he hated the 48 laws of
power,
he liked the writing or whatever,
but he was just using his game.
He was completely,
he was just using it as a way to attack
clinton,
which I wasn't wanting to do that.
So anyway,
sorry.
He was just like totally messing with me
and I was so expecting the opposite that
I was like woo.
And then he goes,
uh,
and then he says,
well,
what about this law about use selective
honesty?
And I said,
weLl,
it's something that politicians and
business people use all the time.
Like lyndon johnson for instance.
And then I was about to explain how
lyndon johnson,
he cuts me off.
Yes,
yes.
The same man who said 58,000
men of our young men to death in
Vietnam,
let's break for a commercial.
And that was the end of the interview.
So he like made me look like a.
I was supporting lyndon johnson,
massacring 58,000
americans in Vietnam.
He manipulated me and humiliated me and
like,
and um,
the whole thing was he hates the 48 laws
of power because it's all about
manipulation and ugliness and he's the
most fucking manipulative interview you
could ever imagine.
Look how he manipulated me,
be completely set me up by making me
think this was going to be like a
softball interview where we were just,
you know,
well,
he's a hater.
He just hated that someone else wrote
something brilliant.
That's all it is.
That guys a fucking hater.
He's,
he's the ultimate hater.
And it was a,
it was a special type of looking glass
that allowed people to see bill o'reilly
for the fucking monster that he was.
Yeah.
And I find it just the book incredibly
ridiculous that that guy got to
interview a obama,
you know,
not that I think obama's particularly
unique and special human being
relatively to what his position is and
what could have been done by a guy like
that in that position.
But I think that,
you know,
having an obama being interviewed by
this fucking buffoon,
I think obama has the most thankless job
probably in the history of the world and
maybe the most impossible job.
I don't think he's done the best that he
could with it,
but I don't think anybody can.
I think you're set up.
That's what I've come to.
The more I think about being a president
and more think about dealing with the
house and dealing with congress and the
senate and all the fucking laws and just
just look at what's happened to his
hair.
The gray.
Yeah.
Well that happens all the and gray.
But like in this course,
it's like a year.
It just suddenly turned gray.
I don't think we can even imagine the
kind of pressure that you'd have to be
to be the leader or the supposedly
commander in chief of the greatest
superpower of the world has ever known,
which wants to consume the earth.
You know,
this crazy super power that literally
thrives on consuming the earth.
I think we can gain so much from
listening to eisenhower speech about the
military industrial complex when he was
leaving office,
that intense speech warning the people
about the military industrial complex
and the dangers of it and the influence
of it.
I don't think we could even imagine what
that is actually like when you're in
office.
I mean,
I'd like to think that obama,
one day we'll write a book explaining
everything and we'll be like,
oh,
I get it because I don't get it.
I don't get how he could have made the
decisions that he's made based on what
he said before he got into office,
unless he's totally full of shit,
which I'd like to think that he's not
that set him getting interviewed by a
fucking buffoon like bill riley.
It's just like it's watching that and
just that he's one of the most popular
people,
but it's so silly.
It's so silly that he's one of the most
popular people on television.
It's so fucking silly.
It's just,
it's just you'll get no argument from
me.
Well,
it's,
it's unnecessary and I think I
personally believe that that style of
television is like fucking silent films
where you debate a very important issue
on a split screen for six minutes and
you know,
people yell over yell,
yeah,
well bill,
that's not the case.
And rambam fracking doesn't produce any
negative results.
We'll be right back.
No,
we won't be right back.
This is not the way to talk.
This is not the way to address complex
issues.
It's just not the way to have
interesting discussions.
Did you ever see John Stewart on the
firing line years ago?
We almost five minutes.
Yeah.
I was supposeD to pimp something that I
forgot to.
What he supposed to been,
um,
some special offers for getting the book
mastery.
Yeah,
that's right.
Didn't somebody emailing that or
something like that?
Is it too late to do now?
No,
not at all.
Now we've probably lost everybody by
now.
Everybody's still here.
If people still about still in,
you'd be amazed.
These people sticking into the end,
most of the people listening to this or
commuting or they're on the treadmill or
on a plane or something like that,
but a huge majority of them are,
are hanging out to the very end.
You'd be completely and it's like
archived.
And they listen.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
For this will reach fucking probably
close to them,
but we have all sorts of offers for the
book and for special bonus things that I
used to give away when the book first
came out and you need to go to power
seduction and wore the and is spelled
out power reduction in war.com/joe.
Yes,
I got it right here.
Um,
I'll put this up on twitter right now.
A copy link address and what is the
special offer that people get?
Um,
there's some things that are not
included in the actual book itself.
So the full intervieWs that I had with
some of the contemporary masters like
freddie roach,
uh,
some material that never got included in
the book for reasons that don't have
anything to do with the quality of it.
um,
and then this kind of essay that I wrote
about the writing of the book itself and
things that I explained today about my
deadline and how would you explain it?
a tweet to give it to people.
Like,
I'm writing a tweet right now.
How would you explain it?
Explain what,
explain what this offer is.
What is like free.
You're getting free bonus material
that's not in the book itself.
Okay.
He really gives insight into some of
robert's process because I've looked at
some of these,
gives insight into his process,
how he did this plus bonus content and
stories that almost didn't make the cut.
Kind of like the director's cut.
Thank you.
It just got out to one point,
two,
8 million people.
For those of you thinking about more
than five,
for those of you thinking about reading
mastery,
I've read it and it's been an invaluable
tool along with the rest of your books.
I'm really,
you know,
you allow people to get the best out of
themselves and that's something that I'm
incredibly passionate about and I think
these are incredible tools to have and
you decide what to do with these tools.
You're a unique individual,
but there's no doubt that knowledge is
power in itself and you can use that.
Power for however,
however means you want to do it.
It's up to you,
but the books have knowledge and when
you consume those books,
that knowledge will translate into your
own personal power cliches.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Robert Green,
you're a bad motherfucker.
Aubrey.
Marcus,
you're a bad motherfucker and enjoyable
podcast.
I really appreciate having you on.
It's been a real treat to pick your
mind.
Thank you very much.
Great time.
Thanks to our sponsors.
Thanks to stamps.com.
Go to stamps.com.
Click on the microphone,
the top of the page
and enter j r e for your special $110
bonus offer which includes a free
digital scale and up to $55 in free
postage and thanks also to legal zoom.
Go to legal zoom.com
and use the code word rogan in the
referral box at checkout for more
savings.
Thanks also to [inaudible] dot com.
Go to o,
n n I t use the code word rogan and save
10 percent off any and all supplements
tomorrow.
Greg proops will be on one of the finest
comedians and the land in any land and
the host of the smartest man in the
world podcast.
Just a real treat to having him on
anytime he's on.
He's a fucking awesome dude and he's god
damn smart and hilarious and we'll be
back tomorrow with big kisses from luck.
Thank you.
Great.