Boom, and we're live. Hello Charles or
chuck? Which one? So Chuck is my, uh,
Internet named Charles is like my real
person name. Oh, you're one of those,
do you got a dual personality thing?
Goal at?
Somebody took some at some dude in like
Michigan took at Charles C. Johnson,
so I was like, all right
chuck. It is then. Does anybody
actually call you chuck?
Yeah. Um, like my grandma and
like a few people from Boston,
but not that many folks. Chuck, what,
what part of Boston you from? Um, from a,
so it was [inaudible] seven hills
stopped like on the red line. I'm like,
did that be like the Dorchester
south line? So I'm from there.
Then we moved to Milton when I uh,
went to, went to school and uh,
Dorchester's a rough neighborhood.
It was more rough back in the day.
Now it's become kind of a
Vietnamese kind of, you know,
there are lots of games that have moved
in. It's kind of moved a little upscale.
Interesting. The gays are very
good at making things upscale.
It's a gentrification.
You're allowed to say the gay still,
but you can't say the blacks if you
noticed that. Yeah, I have noticed that.
My rule is that if it's one syllable,
if it's like fewer syllables,
you should be allowed to say it though.
You know like,
but like you know like African American,
it's really like a long word.
Like blacks. It's just simple. It's like
quick, you can tweet it faster, right?
Caucasians too much. It
should be white. The whites.
Now you could say the whites because a
there, you know the preferred, what is it?
Oh, how would you say the
privileged class, and you're
allowed to say the whites,
but if you say the blacks, it
sounds like derogatory. It is.
It depends on the tone too. Like I
think juice is one of those words too.
Or if you say the wrong
tone, that's true. Bad. Yeah.
If you say the Jews have one more Nobel
prizes than any other people that,
and then you're all right. You
know European Jews, which is true.
They have one more Nobel
prizes for science and I
think than any other racial or
gender or religion.
It's not really a race though.
Did you choose your very confusing,
was it,
cause it's you would call it a
race but it's not necessarily,
it's based on a religion, you
know, you like guys, you know,
so it's like kind of its own thing and
then you just look at like how wealthy
they are and how successful they
are and it's kind of interesting.
It's a grind to get into.
Like if you want to become a Jew,
my uncle Salvador Digerlando became a Jew,
married a Jewish woman and I had
to go through the whole grind.
But that mother fucker had a work
like you got to learn a bunch of Shit,
you've got to go to Hebrew school.
It's, it's not easy. It's pretty legit.
Like so legit. It's not like, you know,
I became a Catholic and it
was kind of kind of easy.
You got to show up for a
few things, you know? Yeah.
Like you could be a born
again Christian tomorrow.
You could walk into any church and say,
I want to be a Christian.
Like come on in son.
The Lord touched you or you just have to
say what is in the Shahada for Muslims,
right?
Like is that what you have to do?
You just have to say that and you're good.
Like that's all it is.
That's all it is. Not the Jews. You
got to jump through hoops. Gotta work.
They gotta they gotta look
at you side betting. You,
I don't know about this motherfucker.
When did they start using the term you
this for blacks because that's a great
question.
That is a,
they never say youths stealing and
rioting when they're dealing with white
people.
They will say white teenagers
causing violence. You know what?
They don't say youths.
Will you remember like two years ago
there was like this Huntington beach,
you know,
riot or like stealing bicycles and stuff.
I was there like with my wife and I,
we were just like chilling on the beach.
You know, like we start seeing like
all these cops show up and we're like,
what the hell's going on?
Like is it martial law? Like
what's happening? You know,
cause you know, like in
the movies, you know,
like some stuff starts to happen and
then like all the cops show up and it's
like by essence since like we were
just kind of confused or whatever.
And the whole like riot took a place in
like an hour and people like turned over
a few Porta potties.
And so everyone's been like tweeting out
pictures of that as like white people
riot too. And I'm like, no, no. Like
this is not, this is not comparable.
Like I was there for that and I
didn't even know what was going on.
Well the only way you could compare it
as are there pockets of white people that
experienced such absolute poverty,
like pockets of black people.
And until you have that,
it's really difficult to,
to make that sort of a comparison.
Like there's no giant ghettos of white
people the way there are giant ghettos.
But I, I don't know what that
would even look like. I, you know,
I'm sure like the depression, like back
in the old days, yeah. Trailer Park,
Irish and Italians back in the day.
But yeah,
back in the early 19 hundreds so I'm
sure there were places like that.
We also used to be a bike,
a much more violent,
like white people used to be
much more violent. I think too,
like if you just think about like the
index of like bar room fights and all that
stuff.
It's all been like plummeting.
And I don't know if that's because we're
becoming pussies are like what that's
about.
But like if you just think about it
like when was the last time you heard of
like a legit bar fight?
Recently like Canada,
they still fucking throw down in Canada.
Yeah,
they're Canadians kind of
like a different thing.
There are different kinds of white people.
They're more polite too, which is odd,
but they will fuck you up in a
bar like Jacqueline Hyde, the,
the booze flows, it comes
out well, it's also,
they have a long tradition
of hockey fights.
So they have like this sport that you
could use as like an analogy to society
and in that sport occasionally shit goes
wrong and they just start duking it out.
But you know, like I was talking
together mechanics and they like,
they like don't have black people there.
It's like the strangest thing.
What do you mean in Canada? Yeah,
but not, I mean they have them,
but they're like not on our,
it's like scale.
Like they don't have like urban ghettos
like we, that is true. Yeah. And you know,
like, um, there is sort of no
Baltimore equivalent in Canada. Well,
they didn't have the level of slavery.
I'm sure there was some slavery in Canada,
but the level of slavery in comparison
to the United States, I mean, we,
we will conveniently, people always
want to go, oh, that was so long ago.
Not really. No, no. I mean,
150 years, right. Shit. I mean,
Ben Affleck's ancestors on slaves.
Right.
Isn't it funny that he was trying
to cover that up? How would that,
I want to know what that
conversation was like. Like a skip,
skip gates like comes in and he's like,
Yo, there's something you should know.
Like, I want to know what
that was like. Right. How
would you break that to somebody?
Um, I guess you would call them.
Well,
I don't understand why anybody would
want to cover up the fact that someone in
their life, I guess because
he's benefited from that. Well,
he's called for reparations in the past.
He has. Yeah. Yeah. That's interesting.
So I wish, I wonder if he's like,
should I pay up now? Like how does that,
how does that work? That ain't going
to fucking fix shit. It's like,
reparations is like giving people the
lottery money, like lottery winners.
They all go broke.
You could just give people reparation
money that's not going to make them feel
better. The only way reparations
are really going to work.
Because if you look at,
if you look at it, okay, say you got 18,
65 was women's slavery was abolished,
right? Yeah. In this
country. Yeah. Look at, um,
the areas where people had slaves.
Look at the ghettos.
Look at these entire,
almost entirely black communities
that are ridiculously impoverished.
And then look at this cycle and say,
all right,
there's gotta be a way this can be fixed.
This has gotta be a way,
this can be mitigated.
There's gotta be a way you can,
I mean a lot of people say that
that sounds like socialism.
That's all well and good,
but until someone steps
in and does something with
these incredibly impoverished
areas,
you're going to have this repeating cycle
over and over again of people who were
born in poverty and crime ridden streets
that have children that were born in
poverty and crime in the streets.
And occasionally an athlete breaks
through and occasionally a comedian breaks
through or a rapper or musician or
someone escapes this, this cycle.
But most people do not.
And that is a symptomatic problem
with these areas. I mean it is,
you have a,
a symptom that needs to be addressed.
You have a shoes issue
that needs to be addressed.
And that's if you wanted to say that
there should be reparations for slavery,
that should be the reparations,
not like individuals getting a
check that's not going to fix shit.
You've got to go in and figuring
out how to make these areas safer,
how to make communities safer,
how to make like community centers and
then give people counseling and, and,
and better education.
You think that would actually work?
Like so like there's this thing called
Dick to Shaker heights effect, right?
Where they found that like even like
wealthy black suburbs like, you know,
like in Shaker Heights, Ohio, like
still don't really do all that well.
Like the Asian kids still do
better, you know, academically,
you know like, I dunno,
I mean I used to be like one of these
guys that thinks that like we could just
like solve the problems of the ghetto
and like move everyone out and everything
would work out. But I think
there's something to be
said that some people like,
like living there,
you know,
like there's kind of like an undercurrent
of our society that they like digs the
poverty stuff that like
digs the gangster style.
I think a lot of the people that
do it's because it's familiar,
it's how they grew up.
I mean,
I think if you took that same child
from birth and you know trans,
I mean if you,
if you could obviously couldn't do it,
but if you could live two
completely separate lives,
if you could have two of the exact same
people and one of them is born to a
really happy,
uh,
educated black couple and they live in
a nice suburb of Atlanta where they'd go
to great schools and the other
one is in Baltimore and you,
you get to see the same child develop
with different stimuli in different
environment. And one of them was
like, fuck, I liked the ghetto.
And the other one is like, man, I'm glad
I don't live in Baltimore. I mean you, you
say like,
so I was talking to my cousin and my
cousin likes an employer in Baltimore.
Like I know a number of people,
like in Baltimore,
number of black people and there's so many
people who are just sick of this shit,
like so many black, they're like, we
never hear from like from them. Like,
we never hear like, oh
fuck, like riots, you know,
like you imagined like were just
like chilling here and there,
like a riot breaks out.
I mean, that's like,
that's like a legit thing that you have
to worry about when you live in some of
these community.
It is. Yeah, it is. It absolutely is.
But again, I don't think it's the,
it's a fucked up thing to say,
but I don't think it's the fault
of the people that lived there.
I think the people that live there,
if you look at those kids that rob,
that rt reporter, do you see that
today? Yeah. Yeah. That was wild. Wild.
That was like,
that was like something out of like
a movie that was like the purge.
You know what I loved about it?
They got saved by the cops.
The Archie reporter got saved by the cops.
The cops came in and tackled the guy
that stole the purse. Like there you go.
You need cops.
Okay.
So for all these fucking crazy ultra
progressive fuck the police people,
it's not fuck the police.
It's, um, managing, doing the
fucking job of the police.
It's an impossible job.
It's what it is. No, I
saw it. So I mean, I was the guy who sued
to get Michael Brown's juvenile records.
Like we sued unsuccessful,
I think we wake went all the way
to the Supreme Court in Missouri.
Like I like fought this one really hard
because like people should know like
what these communities are actually like,
like Canfield apartments where they
were brown was from was like a fucked up
hell hole.
And like the more we're just,
we gotta be honest about these places
and like we need people to actually see
them. So whenever we get these
riots it's like on the one hand,
like it's sad and like,
you know,
I'm obviously worried about
my family that's there.
But like on the other hand it's like,
it's such a great illustration of like
reality, you know, like of like, you know,
forget all of your progressive
social justice nonsense.
And like in the final analysis
when the shit goes down,
you either want to have a gun,
you want to know a Korean who's
got a gun like here in La, right?
Or you want to like,
you know, take care of,
take care of business and people
don't, people don't get that. They,
this whole like fuck the police mentality
is really causing some serious stuff
to go wrong in our society right now
because people are starting to have this
like mindset that like cops are evil,
that they're predatory,
that they're dangerous.
And it's obvious like why the Obama
administration is pushing it because they
get these consent decrees in where they
can basically rewrite the policing rules
and essentially take over
the policing departments.
So it's obvious like it's a power grab
for like the control of these cities. Um,
and that's why like,
I think we should be very,
very cautious about how far we
push it. Because I mean, yeah,
there are some messed up cops and I think,
but you know,
you have to walk a day
in these people's shoes.
Like I did a ride along with the LAPD,
which I highly recommend and there's some
stuff that they have to deal with just
like on a routine that's pretty wild.
Like even here in La, you know? Oh,
they certainly do it.
I think the issue is not
that cops bad and that,
uh, you know, we need to clean
up the police department.
The issue is we need to figure out a
way to make society safer for everybody
involved, including the people that
are stuck in those places, like,
like Brown's apartment complex and the
neighborhood that he lived in. When,
you know, growing up in that
neighborhood, man, you're gonna be fucked.
You're fucked.
You're growing up around thugs.
Every one of your friends
are all criminals. Every,
it's just the people imitate their
atmosphere. We always have. But you know,
like if you take brown as an example,
right?
We did a bunch of research
on him and he hadn't,
so he went to the second most violent
public school and like all of Missouri and
he actually chose to stay there.
Like he could've moved out with,
I think he was a giant dude though.
Yeah.
So that's what I'm saying
though is that like, you know,
to some people like living in these
environments can actually be kind of
rewarding if you're a big dude and
you don't have a lot of skills,
you can be big Mike and be
an enforcer, you know? Right.
But if big Mike was living in,
you know,
San Francisco and a
really nice neighborhood,
progressive parents went to good schools
from the time he was a baby who did be
a different human being, I hope. Thank
you. Yeah, I think you're right. But like,
even if you look at like,
I mean if you just look at the
numbers for black on white crime,
violence and all that stuff, it's like,
it's pretty, it's pretty shocking.
Even among relatively like affluent areas,
you know, it's, I mean, uh, you know,
there's been a lot of
discussion, like, is this innate?
Is this like just something
we have to deal with?
Like there's this whole debate
about the m a Oh, a gene,
which is like this gene that black
America black Africans have like much,
it's like a proclivity to violence
that they have and may owe a gene. Um,
I, you know, I recommend people
Google it and do their own research.
It's like a big debate
about whether or not,
but basically like what it is is it's,
you know, if we, if you think about like,
you know,
kind of white European,
Asian ancestors as we kind
of moved out of Africa,
like aggression and violence was kind
of less necessary cause we were like
farmers and stuff. Right.
Is that really true though?
I mean you look at all the
violence and murder and death,
it's been done by the military and you
think about how many people involved in
the military are white and how many
people making the decisions are white.
I mean ultimately that's white people
causing violence. True. But like, I mean,
I totally agree with you,
right?
Like the industrialized kind of like
Nazi effication or like of like the
industrial size, like military industrial
complex is like a serious threat,
no doubt about it. But if you
like there's a book by this guy,
Steven pinker [inaudible] hit a about
violence and he's basically like, look,
if you just look throughout human history
of violence is actually going down
because like back in the day,
we'd be like in tribal societies and we
would go and beat the shit out of this
drive and take their stuff.
And you know,
most of the violence was like we'd
spring up on people and then just butcher
them and, you know, steal their
women or whatever. And that,
that was like the way that was like
the way politics was hilarious.
That was like a big thing. They would
go and steal women. Where are the women?
Yeah, I'm gonna come
steal them. It's Kinda,
it's Kinda weird like to think about
like that rape culture versus like this,
this fake rape culture that they're trying
to promote. Yeah. Well, I think that, uh,
if you looked at these people, I mean
if you're saying that, um, as a whole,
that white folks are generally slowly
becoming less and less violent,
whereas there is a certain percentage
of whatever it is of black people that
contain this gene.
Look at what black people have to
deal with as opposed to white people.
Like what we were talking about with
Canada, Canada has no, no black ghetto,
if you're growing up in a ghetto is,
I mean,
you're fucked from birth.
I mean, you really are.
There's really not much as far
as options to get out. Sure.
And the constant inundation of negative
influences is his innocent blood out.
I mean, we always talk
about people like, you know,
getting out of the ghetto and
thriving, right? Like we always like,
that's always like the thing you hear,
like when you hear about it like
successful black Americans, right?
It's like the one tuna that gets
through the net. You're right. Whole,
we never hear about people being like,
you know,
I started a great small
business in the ghetto,
in the ghetto is my corner of the ghetto
is now got Starbucks on every corner.
You know,
that was one of the saddest things about
Ferguson was they were robbing black
owned businesses. Yeah. Smashing down
the windows, burning them down. I mean,
this was like people were freaking
out. They were like, God damn it.
I'm a part of his fucking community.
I didn't shoot that kid.
I didn't do anything wrong.
You're using this as an opportunity
to better yourself using this as an
opportunity to steal and just take things
and claim that it's because there's
one guy got shot and you look at
like, um, like my in laws family,
they're a Asian immigrants.
You know,
my wife's an immigrant from you and you
look at like the kind of neighborhoods
they move into to kind of like,
you know,
run the corner store or run like
the quickie mart or whatever. Um,
terribly racist set up.
But nonetheless,
it's like there's some
truth in the stereotype.
And then you look at like
welcome to America. We, you
know, the Democratic Party,
we love immigrants.
And yet if you build your little
corner of the American dream,
we're not going to protect
you when the riots start.
And you look at a lot of these businesses
that were like burned out in Ferguson
and they were like,
you know,
a nice guy from India coming to this
country putting away some money for his
family and yet like his property was
destroyed and there's a whole bunch of
right wing,
you know,
people on go fund me trying to raise money
to basically make these people whole.
Um, it's kind of like, it's
kind of wild. But I think,
I think the technology plus the,
the,
the history of violence plus like the
ghetto politics and the urban policy,
I think all of that's like combining
right now to create this like massive
craziness. I mean, everyone's
got iPhones, everyone's like,
it's like flash mobs meets
Ma, you know, the real mob.
Everyone does have this unique ability
to organize riots or protests or meet at
this place and meet at that place.
And I have friends that were involved
in the black lives matter thing and they
would organize these things and
most of the things I disagreed with,
like especially the blocking the
highway shit, I was like, it's wild,
guys are causing death.
You're going to cause death.
You're going to cause someone's loved
ones to die because they can't get to the
hospital. That's a fucking fact. Yeah, no,
it actually happened I think in a
few occasions. Yeah. Yeah. I mean,
and then you're doing it to just
because lives matter. Okay. Look,
this is the transportation system.
It's where we get medicine through.
It's where we get people to the hospital.
It's the way we get important things
happen on these roads and you're being
insanely irresponsible. If you want
to, you want to block something,
find out where they make the laws and
don't let anybody leave block that you
know and you want to get
arrested somewhere and you
want to make a big stink,
go to the fucking Capitol building block,
that fucking thing. Storming the lawn,
you know?
But you can't block the God damn
highway because that's just too random.
I mean you, you, you're from
the Boston area too. Yeah.
So you remember when there
was the Boston thing,
like it was like a black lives matter
protest in Boston and they like shut down
the freeway and like the guy who was like
running that was like this hedge fund,
you know, he's like the son of
some wealthy family and it's like,
it's always like these
super like, you know, uh,
kind of liberal white people who
are like trying to like, you know,
strike back at the system and you look
at all those people who are like you.
I mean it sounds like kind of,
kind of, kind of silly to say this,
but like if you're delayed from
work for like 30 minutes or an hour,
like that has like a serious impact on
your whole day. It has an impact on your,
your job. I mean, let's say you're trying
to huff it to get to work, but hey man,
protests are not supposed
to be convenient man. Yeah.
But it's like such a Dick thing to do.
Well, it's, it's, it's shortsighted.
I think the idea that these hedge fund
guys realized they were born into this
privileged life and they want to somehow
know to give back or make an impact.
I love that. I think that's great. I
just don't think that's the way to do it.
And I think they get organized
like fuck the system.
Fuck Yay everybody was to put a
backpack on and run through the street.
That is not how you change things.
It's just not,
it's certainly how you make a little
bit of a stink, you know, hey,
can you make a ripple?
You get some cameras on you.
And I would hope that some of this stuff
will stop some cops from shooting kids
when they don't have to.
I mean I think there are times where a
police officer is saving someone else's
life or trying to protect their own
life and they have to use violent force.
That's a fact.
Yeah.
But there was a lot of times where cops
shoot people with it shouldn't fucking
shoot people and you know it.
And I knew of it.
We've all seen the videos and
there's no denying it. And I think,
but they're humans, you know, like what
would you do in that situation? I mean,
I always made a point is like you,
you got to look at the whole thing
like what we're talking about with the
ghettos and white people
and, and violence. You've got
to look at the whole thing.
And the whole thing is w determinism,
there's a bunch of different variables
that are taking place that are causing
certain Accenture. And if
you just say, you know,
we gotta block the highway
to make black lives matter.
What about a black guy that dies because
it's fucking wife wants to get him to
the hospital because he hasn't got damn
heart attack. What about that black life?
You don't give a fuck. But you know,
a lot of it though is just like,
it's like vanity, you know what I mean?
It's like posturing. It's like, um,
it's like advertising your virtuousness
by how much you hate this, right?
Once you hate that. And what's kind
of weird to me is that like there,
we've created a culture right now where
the people who can basically like be
professional fuck
the system people, you know, and it's
like, it's wild that these people exist.
Like in our society like that that
basically they wake up every day and they
have enough money, they have enough like
donations, whatever to basically just,
you know, fuck the system
professionally. And it's like,
to a certain extent the system probably
has accounted for these people. You know,
like to a certain extent they buy them
off by giving them like, you know,
working on Wall Street or the giving
them, you know, prestigious internships.
But like to a certain extent these
people end up becoming tools of the very
thing that they're trying to eat.
Well like think about it.
Like what are they actually like?
They're not really accomplishing anything.
So like the social justice warrior
types there are basically reflecting the
establishment view of the colleges.
Right. And what are these colleges?
They're basically like giant money pits
with have large endowments who then
invest in, you know, all kinds of
things. Like, and I mean in, you know,
uh, if you look at like
all the investments they're
doing, like fossil fuels,
you're looking at all the investments
they do. And like, I mean,
the colleges are so much a
part of the system, right?
And what they're doing is the social
justice warriors are taking their crazy
nonsense that they're learning in schools
and they're trying to imply it to like
the rest of society.
But if we did stuff like if right
away what we did was we said, look,
any of these in college endowments,
they have to pay out like 5% of their,
of their tuition.
Like we do with foundations immediately
colleges free for a lot of people,
people aren't making massive student debt,
but instead the colleges like fight
their fight for their privilege. So like,
I think what,
what I'm,
what I'm trying to say is that basically
like the bees people are basically the
shock troops for the elite without even
knowing that they're shocked groups for
the elite.
Right?
Like if you think about like if we talk
to like the rape culture stuff, right?
It's like a perfect example of this.
People are trying to advance a narrative
about women and about society and it's
a power grab.
I mean it's really as simple as that.
Like they're trying to end due process
rights for young men on campus.
They're trying to basically
give a, uh, you know,
if you don't create a know a title
nine compliant college, you know,
what we're gonna do is we're going to,
we're going to stick our trial lawyers
on you and sue you. What does title nine?
So basically what the feminists say,
all right,
this is how they get in to
like the whole college racket.
We can probably talk
about that if you want.
But basically what they do is they say,
all right,
you're not creating a college campus
environment because you allow too many
rapes on campus.
You're not creating college environment
that's conducive to men and women.
So like what you're doing
is essentially your,
because you have all these rapists running
around what they're, what, you know,
it's harder for girls
to get good education.
So you have to create
these like special courts.
And if you don't create
them to our liking,
we're going to sue you and you have a lot
of money because if you have, you know,
these endowments we just talked about
and so it's basically like trial lawyers
combining with SJWs to basically to
w being social. Social's for us this.
Yeah.
I mean it's funny how like all this stuff
has been reduced to like three or four
characters. You know, it's like
all like, yeah, it's the, yeah,
it's the Twitter thing
that's like infecting your
brain, right? Also military,
military
IED is, they love doing
that stuff. You know,
he talked to guys that had been in
the military, they love using those.
Not An acronym. Right? An acronym is
like NASA, right? If you say NASA,
like I don't know if it's an acronym,
the abbreviation, whatever it is,
whichever else I should know what
that is. Um, but it's okay, so,
so what you're saying
is that these people,
it almost becomes like
a Gig. Yeah. They like,
they like never leave.
They never mentally live.
They never mentally leave college.
Well that's a real problem with academics
in general because a lot of people who
are academics, they went to college,
they went to graduate school,
they got their doctorate, they
got their phd, whatever they got,
and then they started teaching and
they never entered the real world.
And they live in this world
of extreme liberal values,
extreme liberal biases. And who pays for
that? Like the tuition of the kids, right?
Yeah. And then the endowments that
he's like massively rich schools,
which are all invested in like horribly
anti social justice warrior causes.
But what is it that about colleges?
This is where it gets fascinating with me.
What is it about colleges that
almost invariably lean left?
Like there's questions you call. I
mean it wasn't always this way, right?
I mean if you look back historically,
like in the 20s and stuff,
they were kind of right wing places,
Kinda hate left and right. I really do.
I kind of hate saying it.
I really mad at myself that I just said
it because I am just as right as I am.
I mean, I am pro gay
rights, pro gay marriage,
Pro Chan's transgender rights,
transgender marriage,
pro abortion. I'm pro
choice. I'm pro, I'm,
I'm so left in so many ways.
Um, I'm against the drug war.
I'm against privatized prisons.
I'm against,
I'm pro legalization of drugs,
um, against police violence. Sure.
But I'm also in the NRA, you know,
also, I think the military is important.
I think if you go to parts of the world
and see how fucked up it is and you
don't think you need to have a military,
well,
you're being a child because we
don't live in utopia yet. We're not,
we're not in a, in a time in the
world where it's safe. We're not,
we haven't reached some
age of enlightenment.
We're on some strange gradual progression
pace to one day be free of all the ape
violence that lives in our genetics,
but in tool. I hope you're right.
I don't know.
I don't see it happening anytime soon.
I mean if you look at what's
happening in Baltimore, it seems like,
it seems like a lot of the times are
kind of primal instincts and our kind of
violent stuff.
It seems like it's lurking just beneath
that thin veneer of civilization.
That's Baltimore.
And here's the other problem.
We're talking about a country of 350
million people yet here we are in woodland
hills. Go outside. What are you going
to see your birds Chirp? Beautiful.
It's sunny out. People are
Nice. Go to Starbucks down
the street. They'll say, hi,
can I help me? Everybody's
friendly. You know,
this isn't barbarian culture or
maybe talk to you about ages,
race matters or something.
Larry is when they tried to do that,
is that the quickest accompany
has ever abandoned an idea start.
Let's explain it to people, but a lot
of people again who have lives unlike
us, they might've missed this
particular thought. It was, I thought,
I thought it was the onion and then I
looked into like the corporate leadership
of it and they're like all white dudes.
They're like all white dudes and
white chicks. Hey, I got an idea.
This is the way that we
can make things different.
Let's encourage our Brrristas
to talk about race. Hey,
you want to a cop? And she knew, um,
how do you feel about black be the bell?
I wonder what that I would say
I wanted to go in. So like what my buddy
and I went into the Compton, uh, you know,
Starbucks like right when they were doing
this and I was wearing like a suit and
like a, you know, expensive tie,
like all that stuff would come in there
and like we're the only white dudes in
there. Like where are the, you
know, where the dot and the domino,
you know what I mean?
And we're like walking up and I was so,
cause they had the race matters
things out and I was like reading it,
I was like leaning
like behind me,
it's like a nation of Islam,
like you know, coffee meetup.
Because apparently they have those
like, yeah, seriously, I'm not,
I'm not making this up. Bean pies off. And
there's like a picture of me like yeah,
I put it up on my Twitter of me
like reading the, the, you know,
race matters thing while they're, you
know, behind me, you know, discussing all,
that's Hillary you have done on Twitter.
I have on Twitter. Yeah, find out,
find that Twitter and let's put it, I'll
retweet it. That's fucking hilarious.
But so explain the campaign because a lot
of people would have no idea what's it.
Basically there's this
idea that Starbucks had,
which was that like the
future of the country,
their views that like we're going
to be a much more racial society,
which is probably true. Like you
know, diversity and all that.
People moving in immigration so forth.
And so their view is that like we need
to get ahead of it and we need to talk
about race because like
that's like a big issue.
And their attitude was like if we get
people together talking about stuff,
stuffing coffee shops, it
will be like, you know,
it's like the old salon stuff
like the 1850s or something.
People are going to be debating issues
and politics and all this and it just
totally backfired because
people were not having it.
They were just making fun of it.
They were making fun of the
guy who was the head of it.
Unbelievably stupid and poorly planned
out to the idea that you're just going to
put that on w one thing.
Writing it on cups or something like that.
We're going to write,
yeah,
they're going to read it on
cups that are going to basically
Hashtag race together. Is this the
guy? This is a guy, I swear to God.
I thought this was an onion
because you know their stuff.
I mean it's so preposterous.
Race together. What the
fuck does that even mean?
That's a terrible Hashtag [inaudible] it
sounds like something for the marathon
race together.
You know like if maybe if you were running
a marathon and everybody donated and
the charities went towards
the human race. It's like if you,
if you read it, the non, the non PC,
it's a race to get her
was a friend of mine was
clearly he was like, is this,
is this a subtle rape culture thing?
Oh No.
What a backfire. Well that's why they
capitalize the t and they are sir. No,
but you can't, you can't not
see it. Once you see that,
oh you can't see a picture of the
chick. So true. That's so funny.
She's got her hands up like dope rape
me. I have fins. I don't
even have hands. Oh fuck.
That's hilarious.
But Starbucks I think stopped being
cool when they changed the check.
Like remember where like way back in the
day she had like you could like see her
boobs and every time it's right.
Those cowards and they changed it.
So she's like Nazism androgynous.
What's wrong with boobs railing?
Come on, relax. Everybody
relaxed. It's kind of nuts.
Did the race together.
That'll be ditching race to get her,
we should just say it
was just called that.
So this race to get her idea was they
would put a Hashtag on the cup and what
would spark up a conversation
that would lead the fucking line.
The lines are long enough for Starbucks.
Those slow poke ass motherfuckers need
to drink their own coffee cause they're
always real slow.
Well imagine if you are like and metric
if you're like actually a Barista, right?
So you're like there,
you're probably a Barista.
Like nobody likes sets out in like, yeah,
I'm going to be a Starbucks Barista.
Like this is not like something you set
out like wanting to do with your life.
I mean I'm sure it's a perfectly good job,
but like nobodies,
nobody dreams about this when they're a
little kid and so you're working there,
you know, you're having to deal with
all these like, you know, bitchy,
caffeinated people. Right? And
like you're supposed to just like,
Yo take some time out to go and
discuss race with some custom,
something like stranger.
I mean it's Kinda like,
it's kind of like a very
anti employee mindset, right?
Like, and their timing them,
they time them on their drink orders.
So it's like kind of a really,
they really like how cells
they said like Tippett. Um, no.
What they'll do is they'll time people
on like how long did it take you to do
this coffee? Like when they're doing
the training, the training stuff,
and they want you to basically,
you know, do it faster.
But apparently your experiences
that hasn't sort of worked
out well did not that
bad. I'm fucking around joking around, but
you know, I have been to Starbucks with,
they're slow as shit and you're like,
there's no double Cappuccino and that
guy's diet. Kick it up a little sign.
I got to get out of it.
Wish you could.
I wish you could pay to get faster
in line like you can at Tsa.
You know, like I know that's like a
terribly privileged thing to say anything.
But sometimes you're like,
Yo,
trying to get to work or
whatever or trying to get to
somewhere and you're like,
fuck it. I need to like, I need my
coffee and I just get outta here.
You know what I mean? And there should
be some way you can be like, nope.
Like I know what you're,
I don't know what you have to pay a year
to get like the expedited service or
something. But yeah, I don't know either.
I've gotten that accident only before,
but I never,
I never,
I always say I'm going to sign up
for it but I never signed up for it.
Are He tried to sign up for it
and they denied him. Really? Yeah.
He's an asshole to TSA so
he's an asshole to him.
He got screened once. This guy, he farted
in front of this guy and go, go ahead.
You got to smell my fart now he's
like farted really loud cause his,
his idea is that this is
not protecting anybody.
This is a absolutely a violation of our
rights and if you don't yeah and protest
it, it'll escalate. My Buddy Neil who's a,
he's a Tsh and he couldn't get a
job anywhere else and he hates it.
Like it's like the most solace job ever.
And he was saying like,
God bless you to people like right before
they're getting on their flights and
the TSA people are like, no, you can't
say that anymore. To people and he's like,
well,
you made me swear an oath to like,
you know, under God to like,
you know, like why can't I just,
he's not even like a Super Christian
Guy. He's just like, yeah, God bless you.
Like have a nice day.
It's kind of his way of doing it,
just to try and meet and just
trying to be nice and they're like
the nation of Islam. People in the back,
it's funny. Or The Nation of Islam,
they're back.
The like the dude behind the chick is
there and then there's some other folks in
front of me too. That's
so funny. Yeah, so my,
and it was all black people working behind
the counter and everything. Yeah. Yeah.
Did you ask anybody? Did you interview
anybody? How they feel about it was like,
well, what's going on with this?
And they're like, we don't know.
Like they just put these things here.
They're just trying to get paid. Why?
Why the fuck did they have to
deal with this stupid shit?
Could you imagine if like you,
you're supposed to be some social
justice engineer while administering
cappuccinos? This is, it's so goofy.
It's such a weird thing to ask
your employees to do. Bull idea.
Like nobody's doing this at home depot.
You know what I mean?
Like what kind of education in the
subtle nuances of race relations are you
giving these people before you have them
communicate publicly on behalf of your
company?
Waddling while an employee like I couldn't
think of a more poorly thought out
idea executed by a giant corporation.
Totally agree with you.
And then you the fact that it was
like designed to all by white people.
Like it's like the weirdest part.
Zach. I have a black girlfriend,
the older dude that was
in the race to get her,
I know it's a good question.
He might have a hot black girlfriend
and she's trying to like the bill Maher
thing where he thinks he
can like criticize black
people cause he's dated them
kind of thing. Is that what he does?
Yeah, that's what he does. Yeah.
It feels like he can criticize
and he said this, he said like,
I've had black hair on my pillow.
I like, it's, Oh God. He's like,
you said stuff like that. Oh
that's so gross. It's creepy.
That black hair on my pillow.
Oh you girls.
It's such a weird thing to do.
It's fucking statement.
I've had black hair on my pillow.
I think he set it on something
like marriage counseling thing too.
You know how they have like guest judges
or whatever. I remember watching that.
I was like,
well yeah that is crazy.
I just think that if you just, if you're
capable of saying something like that,
I think he's probably just
trying to be like, you know,
cause he's a joke writer
and he's a like a one word,
one line impact sort of a guy.
That's a kind of thing.
I've had black hair on my pillow and
you could say things like that's like
something that you can see on his show.
Like that would be a line
to like it's concise.
It's quick and has a period at the end
of it and it boom and as an impact. Sure,
sure. Yeah. I mean something you could
see on his show but it didn't quite work.
You can't fault them too much for it
because of the way he communicates for a
living. But as a person, like if you
were hanging out with them. Yeah.
In fairness, like I got some shit
on Twitter cause like, uh, so I,
I kept getting all the stuff like your
anti-immigrant and your other stuff
because I was like tweeting
out stuff like, hey,
we should be kind of careful about this
amnesty stuff. And uh, I was like, yeah,
I hate immigrants so much.
I'm married
one. And then all of these people
were like, all these people are like,
you're using your Asian wife, you
know, to like protect you or whatever.
And then I just Hashtag [inaudible]
at my Asian wife and I was like,
my Asian white. Yeah. Like I
was just like making fun of it.
And then people thought I like the social
justice warriors thought I was serious.
So like all of like the Asian social
justice warriors started being like,
you know, my wife is like a cultural,
like appropriation, you know,
whatever nonsense they were spewing.
I remember just sitting,
sitting back like yeah, that's why as
my wife and I were like having like,
I think we were having like omelets
or something in the morning like just
sitting on, you know like
in, when you, you know,
when you wake up on a Sunday and you're
still in your pajamas or whatever,
it's like holy shit honey.
I think I accidentally started a movement.
That is a very funny line though. What
he said, I hate immigrants so much.
I'm married one. That's very
funny. I mean it's kind of true.
The amnesty thing would be the people
that have been in this country for a
certain amount of time be allowed
to be United States citizens.
I mean here's basically the Gig,
right?
So like people like my wife came to this
country from Indonesia and can't really
swim from there. It's kind of a long
way. And like they waited in line,
they like followed all the
rules and all this stuff.
And then we've got all these people who
come into this country illegally from
like Mexico south of the border.
Cause just cause it's easier to get here
and there are a lot of folks who want
to make them citizens. The Democrats
want to do it because they get, you know,
lots of voters, the Republicans want
to do it because they get cheap labor,
you know,
and basically drive down wages are,
some Republicans want to do it
and I'm just like, you know,
it's probably not a good idea to like,
you know,
give away citizenship like this because
we have a lot of people who desperately
want to get in here and it's kind of like,
it's kind of racist in a way.
It's kind of like pro Mexican in a way.
If you think about it,
just like logically because yeah,
that people from Africa, from Europe,
whatever who wanted a much
harder time and it's just like,
it's a much kind of unfair
process. You know? I have a very,
I wouldn't say unrealistic or Utopian
view of this whole thing. I feel like for,
first of all, I'm not a big fan of
nationalism. I'm not a big fan of borders,
but I'm also not a big fan of fucking it
up where people have figured out how to
get it right and not necessarily
the United States has got it right.
But I think the real solution is not
to like make it easier for people to
immigrant.
The real solution is to make it
easier for Mexicans to live in Mexico.
Oh totally agree. Like Mexico. So like
it goes amazing. Go there on vacation.
It's fucking beautiful.
Like it should be like,
but there are all these anti
white people laws there.
They're all these antique gringo laws.
Like you can't own beach front property.
If you're a white guy there you can't,
you can't,
you have to or have some
crazy beach front. Probably
has some like Alibaba Dude,
you know who like,
no seriously though like you know they
have like some Mexican guy who is like
the front man for him that runs his thing.
But like there are all these antique
gringo rules down there and it's kind of
like my attitude is like everything we
allow Mexicans to do in the states we
should be allowed to do in their country.
Right.
I should be able to get a driver's
license in Mexico. You know,
you should be able to do all this stuff.
And why not?
Like I think the real tragedy about the
Mexico, first of all, like the drug war,
like a policy.
We've got to get rid of it cause it's
like clearly fucking up Mexico. Um,
but we got to just like make Mexico like
a good place to live because maybe that
way they won't all move here. You know,
like if you, if you live down there like,
and you're like in cartel land and you
go to the u s and you get paid like 15,
you know, 15 times more money than
you would otherwise. I mean, why?
The real question I have is like,
given how shitty things are in Mexico,
why are so many of them still there? You
know, like you have like a great country.
Well, there's a fucking wall,
first of all. Well sort of,
but like people are breaking in
all the time, but it's not easy,
especially if you have a
baby with, sure, sure. Yeah.
I have a friend who came over here
illegally and she came over here with her
baby man.
She had a fucking two year old baby
and she made it to the United States.
How'd she do it? They got an a
van or some crazy shit, you know?
I mean it was all decades ago, but
it's, yeah. Yeah, like back in the day,
I think it was a lot easier and
it's also terrifying shit, man.
If you really stop and think about the
idea of going in a van illegally across
the border that's got a fence and you
have a baby with you and you're just
hoping for a better life.
But you know, I've been, so,
my uncle lives in Guatemala of all places,
believe it or not.
Like I live in Guatemala, but yeah, as
he just banging young Guatemalan chicks,
I don't really know. We don't talk
about tall man. That would want to know.
I know he likes to drink down there
cause that's what I'm talking about.
Go down there with a fucking fat bottle
of Tequila and ask him some questions.
I mean you can get beer, they're like
16 cents. Like, I mean it's just,
it's out of control. Um, but
I've been to the Guatemala,
Mexico border and it's like, you know,
there's like machine gun turrets and like,
so like,
you know,
they're always criticizing our border
buildup and yet if you go to their border
with their southern neighbor because
they don't want the Guatemalans breaking
into their country. That's
hilarious. So it's like, you know,
they're all criticizing the u s for being
racist and everything and yet there,
you know, well that's one of the
things about if you talk to Latinos,
like tail always joke around about the,
the racism inside Latino culture.
White dudes like don't have any
idea about this. Mexican's are,
have always had a problem with Puerto
Ricans and it's the way that's been
established as in boxing
and the boxing world.
The Mexicans voice had Puerto Ricans
are lazy and like this Mexican fighters
versus Puerto Rican fighters
had been a longterm rivalry.
And then there's the Cubans and the Cubans
have a problem with the Puerto Ricans
and then there's the Guatemalans Hondurans
who get no respect and it goes like
lower and lower. The further south you
go, the more they fuck with him. No,
totally right. I mean, and you look at
like here with the Salvadorans and the uh,
the Salvadorian gangs versus the Mexican
ones. And it's like, you know, to, uh,
to the social justice warriors are
all Hispanic or Latino, Latino.
But then you actually like,
these are like legit countries that
have like legit histories and you know,
the real problem and things,
even the term social justice
warrior is that they're aggressive.
Like the, the thing about social justice,
so it's like, what do you, what do you,
what do you really want? What you
want? Peace it. Guess where it,
guess what the worst way to get pieces
being an asshole. Oh, totally. Being
an asshole will almost
kind of antisocial and yes,
there's a sentence in a lot
of ways cause they're like,
like they're about doxing people and
aggressively pursuing actions against them
and trying to get people fired because
they don't share their ideology.
The weirdest road testing. Totally
agree. Like the weirdest thing to me.
And I think like people have
started to becoming more like,
I've certainly become more aggressive
just dealing with their shit,
you know what I mean? Like
less aggressive. Believe it
or not about them. Like I,
I don't,
I don't want to fight with that kind of
shit at all because I think it's because
it creates a dust cloud of confusion
because it's counterproductive.
Totally counterproductive. And I share
their beliefs on a lot of things.
I just don't, I don't share their
methodology. I don't share the,
the aggressive tactics and I just think
that what they're doing is like insanely
short sided. They think that
their Malcolm x or something,
they think that they're like trying to
fight the system by screaming, yelling,
fuck capitalism.
And it's kind of like the people
who are born like after the 60s,
like they were born after
the party and I'm like,
and then you could tell they're
kind of pissed about it. My friend,
my friend Andy Sarabian and I were
talking about this and uh, uh,
we were talking a lot about like
how basically they target you.
Like all right so there are two gay guys
who like had Ted Cruz over just like
chat with him, right? Cause he's like
running for president, you know, whatever.
And these guys were targeted by all of
these like gay social justice warrior
types being like,
just for talk,
just for talking to him
like you're mainstreaming,
his auntie gave you and like how are we
supposed to persuade people of our views
if we can't even like talk to them,
you know what I mean?
Like how is that supposed to work?
I'm on a bunch of block lists.
I'm on block lists,
social justice and what I've done,
but they're all going to
figure out what I did.
They're all watching your stuff though.
This is the weirdest
thing like they block you.
And then they all like freak out if
you say something like incendiary,
but it's like Cindy Arie stuff primarily
supportive of almost all the things
that they're supportive of,
which I think is funny,
but I'm mock male feminists the same way.
A mock like males,
like social justice warriors because
I didn't know what your doing. Okay.
Like if it's a play for pussy.
Exactly.
It's a power grab for Social
Brownie points. That's what it is.
That's primary.
I went to this one guy's Twitter page
and it sets the quote was something like
aggressively feminists or
fiercely feminist to like,
God damn it son, you need to lift weights.
You need to fucking eat some meat.
You need to do some squats. You need
to be, you need to go run a marathon.
You need to do something difficult.
It's depressing how Beta,
so many of them are going to man up
and you don't, you don't, by the way,
you don't have to be Alpha
and you want to be Beta.
There's nothing wrong with that
or that's trends that are Beta.
Brian Redman is pretty God Damn Beta. You
know, he's one of my best friends. Sure.
I have a lot of friends that are like
feminine or were like less aggressive.
There's nothing. We'll just go do shit,
just go do shit with that. What I'm,
what I'm saying is like this attitude and
this aggression that they have towards
things masculine,
they're sexist. Well like for me that
the line was crossed, like all right,
so I knew the rolling stone thing was
a hoax. Like I was like the first part.
Explain to people who might not be
aware of what this was one of the first
people that did this.
I was calling bullshit.
Like it's one of the reasons
why I wanted you on the show.
And then one of the things that I did
was I called up some people at the
fraternity and just seemed like an
obvious thing to do and I was like, yeah,
it was there. A party. All right,
so there's a story that runs in Rolling
Stone magazine and what happens is that
it's basically this,
this story,
it's written by this woman Sabrina Reuben
Eardley and the story is about a gang
rape. Like a brutal gang rape that occurs
at, um, at Uva, university of Virginia.
And basically the story has an anecdote
in there about this girl Jackie,
who is like apparently raped by like if
he was either like five guys or seven
guys.
And this anecdote was like such a big
deal among like the rape activist types
that it was actually used by this chick,
Emily Renda who's he?
UVA former UVA student.
And it was like used before it was
testified before Congress. So it was like,
you know, under oath, like brought into
the congressional record and I was just,
you know, the, the,
the gang rape was so ridiculous to me
because it was apparently like over hours
and I was like, what college dude
has like the stamina to go for hours.
So that was like the first,
no,
I mean like legit that like that
was like the first tip off to me.
And then the other thing too
was it was like so graphics,
so violent and it was like apparently
at a party. So I was like, all right,
there's a lot of stuff here that you
can just kind of like tease apart.
And then what happened was I
figured out the girl's name,
like I went through and researched like,
you know, talk to some people at Uva. Um,
got like a list of all the kind of campus
feminist and kind of just caught cross
referenced it. It's been a long
time kind of finding it. And anyway,
it's a founder name, you know, his name's
Jackie Coakley. Um, and I was like,
I published the name of her and I knew
that all these people would freak out on
Twitter about it and like freak out in
the media but something like 150 to 200
newspapers so that I outdid a rape victim.
And like my own mother called me up,
like complaining about it. And
I was like, mom, like, trust me,
like this is not what it appears
to be. Um, and the, by the way,
this newspapers still haven't like done
retractions or anything and these are
like us news and world report.
I mean all these things, they,
and they all got me thrown off Twitter
for like outing this rape victim and she
wasn't a rectum, you know, it
was like the weirdest like posts.
You didn't totally know though.
No,
I did because I called up
enough people and I knew enough,
like enough of the details that the
whole story was like just falling apart.
Like there was no party that
night. There was, I mean,
she had a history of making
up other stuff in the past.
Like I talked to somebody,
she's like, you know,
who was like kind of close with her.
I looked into like the three people who
are quoted in the article who are kind
of like anonymously quoted.
And then I started looking into more
and more on Sabrina Reuben Eardley
discovering that she'd gotten in trouble
for like faking stuff in the past.
And I was like, all right,
this is not, this is not legit.
Like this is fake when I'm kind of
stuff that she faked a, she, I mean,
I put up some videos on my side. It
got news. Um, but basically she, uh,
her very first story she ever did
for rolling stone was w was a,
an interview of some, a
profile of a country singer
where she got a lot of facts,
just basically wrong.
And then she started fabricating and
she's actually talked about it on video
about how she's gotten these things
wrong. And so she, like, she's wow.
She fabricated and shit and she still
got published and rolling stone her after
this was been correct. And this
was what, when she was a college.
And so her entire career basically
starts is winning the college journalism
award from rolling stone a while she was,
you know, at u Penn working with, um,
with a glass, you know, Stephen Glass,
the guy who was famous fabricator, uh,
the new republic. And she
basically, her college, her career,
her entire life is as at rolling stone.
And she was talking about things like
how she likes to shop around for victims.
I mean, these are like verbatim quotes,
how she has a good bs detector. I mean,
go and watch the videos. You mean not put
them all online on Youtube and they're,
they're kind of wild.
It's such a fucking explosive subject.
It's so dangerous because real
gang rapes, real rapes, excuse me,
are horrific. They're terrifying.
It's disgusting. I totally agree.
Humanization that can be
eradicated from societal fact.
Many of the women who helped me on this
stuff like are victims of sexual assault
because they're so disgusted
with this bullshit. I mean,
imagine like actually being a rape victim,
right?
And then like having to deal with all
these bullshit posers pretending to be
rape victims and imagine
how infuriating that is.
Theory and just hearing about
this [inaudible] rolling
stone failed every single
checkpoint of journalism.
They did no background
check on this whatsoever.
They did no vetting of the source.
They did.
And what happened was I
did violates journalists.
You see the movie almost famous and how
they had like the famous rolling stone
fact checkers. I kept wondering like,
when are they going to show up? You know,
like, when are they gonna like, right. Um,
but it makes you wonder about
like the whole publication,
other shit. Like, I mean,
I know Michael Hastings was a
great reporter and everything,
but people call bullshit
on some of his stuff too.
And obviously we can't check
now because he's dead. Right.
But like you makes you wonder about all
the other reports that they do there
because if they're, if they're so
falling down on this one story, um,
and apparently like, you
know, she's gotten other stuff
wrong and other, you know,
other stories as well,
not just the one I mentioned,
but like I wonder what their
standards are so lax for her,
what the standards are like for
the other writers too. Well,
it's always a problem when,
because of a salacious story,
because of anything that's big and
juicy, you can become a star. Yeah.
Glenn Greenwald is a star and he's
a star for a legit reason. I mean,
what he did was a legit story. Totally
agree. Totally agree. He's a star now.
And so there's a lot of people that may
be less scrupulous that are looking at
that and they're saying,
if I can get some of that juice and if I
can find a juicy story that I can cling
to, I can also become a star.
You know, what's weird to me?
So like I like taboos like for me,
like the whole point of being
a journalism or you know,
being in journalism is to be basically
tell stories that no one else will tell.
Cause first of all it gives
you a monopoly, right?
If no one's talking about topic
than you like own that topic. Right?
And then second of all, like there are a
lot of taboos and our society like race,
rape, uh, you know, military,
industrial complex, you know, drugs.
I mean you could basically,
you know,
figuring them a genetic differences
in intelligence. I mean,
that's a big one that we're not
supposed to talk about. Um, and for me,
like what's weird about this is that
journalism increasingly as used to like
justify the state justify
power, justify, like, you know,
basically to push agendas
that then become law.
And for me that's like kind of like not
the point. Like the point is to give the,
you know,
give the finger to the man.
The point is to basically be like
against the system. So like, you know,
I'm identified as being on the right
and I have some right wing views,
I have some left wing views, but no one
seems to like asking me about those. Um,
but yeah, I'll do the story's going
after like corrupt Republicans.
Like I did a story,
you know,
voter fraud within a Republican primary
and Mississippi there was like ugly.
But the thing is is that people want,
what they want is they want you to
reflect their tribal views and their
political views and they
don't really want the truth.
So like they will fucking hate you even,
especially when you're right.
So like for years I was talking
about this guy, Menendez,
US senator who's going down
for corruption for years,
I was talking about him and I had all
the other journalists make fun of me.
Like you're just a blogger.
You don't know what you're talking about.
Even though like I won awards at these
guys competed for back in the day,
I just didn't want to be in corporate
journalism and even more cause I thought
it was too restrictive and
these guys are assholes.
Like you have so much of
the culture right now.
They just go after anyone that's new and
different and it's creating a narrower
and narrower and narrower space for
people to let their freak flag fly.
And I think this is really,
really dangerous for our society.
And we used to be a society that was like,
Yo, this guy, you know, he's, you know,
he's a crazy black supremacists, but
you know, he makes really good bagels.
And I kind of like go and
hanging out with them, you know,
like we used to be a society that was
okay with a little freakiness among people
and now it's like you all
have to think a certain way.
You have to behave in a certain way.
And it's like, what could be like,
what could be more like anti liberal?
Like what could be more
like wrong than that.
That's a very good way of putting
it. Yeah. I think that that,
that tribalism things a real issue. You
know, that you're with us or against us.
How about I'm just a fucking person.
I don't want to join your team.
I don't want to be on anybody's team.
How about can we just be
on team human race? Yeah.
Can't we all have our own
unique viewpoints because
we have a unique lives. We,
we, we grew up in different environments.
We have different points of view,
different genetics,
different life experiences.
The thing that makes me the most excited
is when I meet somebody who like thinks
something totally outlandish that I don't
know. And then I started reading it.
I'm like, Holy Shit, this
guy's right. Like that's cool.
Like it's exciting to change your mind.
Like when you don't know something.
It's exciting.
And I always look for the people who are
like courageous enough to be like the
Galileo is of our day. Like,
no, you're wrong about this.
And who are like, you know,
sticking it out.
I think people have a real issue with
admitting that they don't know something
and a real issue admitting
that they were incorrect.
And their assumptions and some
people don't ever totally right.
They don't ever admit it. They don't
ever say, I think I fucked up there.
They don't,
they don't do that.
They just because feel like somehow
or another that makes them less,
they make like someone's
like, ah, you were raw.
I think it actually a backtrack
what your Dick Tuck over there?
Chuck get tucked on that subject.
No,
and I've seen this like when
I say stuff on Twitter like,
oh I guess I was wrong on that.
Like I guess I was mistaken or whatever.
I think it gives you credibility but
all these people are like freak out and
like you were wrong about this. Like
fuck you. Like did it. It was like, dude,
like you're on Twitter right now.
Like you know at your mom's house.
Like you know you're a Twitter right now.
Like at work when you show you're
working and you're like bitching at me.
It's like, what do you, what have you done
today? Like what are, what's the word?
Ultimately though that that's a good thing
that this Twitter thing, I, I've, I'm a,
I might be like too optimistic,
but I've been accused of that.
But I think that this,
the ability to complain about everything,
the ability to interact with people
instantaneously is ultimately a good thing
because, awesome. Totally agree.
Anybody that's darling like you or
not you, but like anybody today,
like some kid today can
just fucking fire up a blog,
some 17 year old girl and just say,
I am going to be a fucking journalism
journalists major and I'm going to be,
I'm going to be a journalist,
I'm going to be,
I'm going to make my own website that's
dedicated to news that people don't want
to talk about and I'm gonna try to uncover
things and you could do that. Yeah,
it's fucking awesome. It's like the
coolest thing ever. And I mean like,
like I was at the Wall Street Journal
editorial page I like was in the News Corp
You Fox News,
evil empire thing.
I worked for all these different
publications because my face got it.
She was like, I knew shit. Like I
started on my career and I was like,
nobody knows anything about journalism
and the right for as many publications I
can,
I'm going to go out there and just like
how all sorts of crazy wild experiences.
And then it became clear to me that like,
Holy Shit,
like I could run my own website,
I could hire people,
I could like pay people for information.
I could basically like do what I want to
do and I could have more impact than if
I did like the corporate,
the corporate route where I basically
have to pay your dues and get coffee and
you know, basically be like a
cog in the machine. And yeah,
this is like revolutionary the fact
that like when 140 characters, you know,
you can basically, I mean
I posted documents that
showed that people are lying,
you know, in real time while they're
talking on Fox News, I posted stuff like,
I exposed this chick Elizabeth though
baggy who was like the face of going to
war in Syria. She like wrote a Wall Street
Journal op Ed Column, uh, saying that,
you know, there are all these moderates
there, we should arm them in Syria.
I proved that she was being paid by the
Syrian rebels and she faked her phd and
like became like a whole scandal.
It led to all this stuff and I did
that like with Twitter and like fucking
around on the Internet and like that
is so cool and so revolutionary.
The scary thing to me though,
right,
it's like the combination of like
using Twitter and using like the mob,
the flash mob stuff like in Baltimore.
That to me is like,
the real question is like,
is the crowd like, you know,
as the crowd going to do good things
like are we gonna use crowds to like,
you know,
solve major social problems?
Are we going to use them like for as
terrorist operations that basically spill
out into the real world. And I think it's
probably both. There's definitely both.
But I think that
ultimately information and
the access to information is what kind
of sets everything free because you, you,
you get a, an accurate, clear
understanding of what's going on.
There's going to be some
deception is going to be some,
some confusion initially,
but I think we're, we're in
this trend as a, as a society,
as a race,
the human race,
we're in this trend of
expressing ourselves in a much
easier way and a much more
instantaneous way than anybody's ever
had the ability to do ever by far.
It's one thing we can pretty much say
for a fact as long as we've known about
people and the things that
people have written down,
no one's been able to communicate
the weather able to today.
And if you look at the slow progression
of culture from the dark ages to today,
well what is accentuated that progression?
What has it been about?
It's been about information. It's been
about education and ambition, freeing,
freeing information,
expressing yourself and,
and people debating these ideas of
expression with now with facts also,
like someone could say, you know, you can
say something on a podcast, someone say,
well,
you know what actually that's not true.
Here's a link and you go to that
link and they go, Whoa, oh shit,
I didn't know that that's happened
on this podcast a hundred times.
No Dude, I love that. Like to me,
like to me the most exciting thing is
when I got a reader who comes forward and
like has information that nobody else
has had, right? Who's like a stockbroker.
Like I have a lot of like stay at home
moms who work with me on stuff because
like, you know, their kids are
sleeping and they're like fuck it.
Like let's Kezar evolution on Twitter.
You know, like that is so exciting to me.
And like when I learned stuff that like
totally up ends how I thought about x or
y, it's like, it's cool. You know, like
the way, the way I thought about this,
there's this essay like I
highly recommend called a,
what you can't say it's by this Guy
Paul Graham. And he talks about like,
you know how like if we think about like
fashion, right? Fashion comes in and out,
we have moral fashions to,
right?
And what he says is like anytime something
says somebody says that's racist,
that sex is something ist,
right? Capitalist, whatever.
They're just reflecting the
taboo of their time, you know,
that's McCarthy or whatever. And he's
like, the most powerful argument against,
you know, against something is
that it's false. It's bullshit.
And if you can figure out,
like you can basically check yourself,
like I believe x about something,
you can check yourself and you'd be like,
is this true or not?
And if it's not true,
then like you gotta have
some soul searching.
You got to be honest enough to be
like, Hey, I might be wrong about this.
Or maybe there's just
not enough information.
Maybe I'm just going to have to like,
you know, keep studying on this.
You know what I mean?
And I think a lot of people just want to,
they want to join their gang on Twitter
or in like real, the real world,
like in Baltimore and they
want to go in like, you know,
basically be led by somebody. And to me
that's like such an elite liberal thing.
It's such a dangerous thing,
but I think it's ultimately such a human
thing that it's kind of scary, you know?
It's kind of probably why it takes off.
Well, it's, it's also exciting. Yeah.
I mean if you want to go to Ferguson,
and that's one of the things that
I thought was hilarious was, uh,
this black eye on Twitter
row that the thing that scares me more
than the cops in Ferguson is all these
white dudes that don't live here,
that come down here, that are yelling,
fuck the police and that,
that are trying to get like,
you know what we're talking
about social and Brownie points.
It's to a rock concert that was,
that there's a certain sense of like
how fun it is to be a part of something
crazy. Yeah. Right. Like, but
we've all met those dudes to those,
those dudes that try so hard and you
know that there's some insincerity that's
attached to and they know that if they
go there and they put that backpack on,
they put their fucking sock
beanie on and they, you know,
yell out all the right things and get
the right fucking youtube videos up.
It'll make it look like they're socially
progressive and they're a part of the
solution. No true. But you know, we had
that sort of on our side, like we've been,
yeah know, probably been to
sporting events or fights
or whatever where you like,
you feel yourself like kind
of overcome by, you know,
like how violent it is or how exciting it
is or whatever. And like you, you know,
it's part of the human nature to
like want to belong to something.
And I don't blame them for that. I just
think they're like stupid. You know,
like it's just,
it needs to be called out on it.
And that's what's going
on with this is this,
this age of communication that we're
in right now. It's there. You can,
you can expose.
The hypocrisy is you can expose anybody.
Anytime you run into
someone that's never wrong.
When you were running into a liar,
it was like people wrong.
If they make mistakes,
they're incorrect and their assumptions.
It's just a part of being a person.
To me that's like the most fun though.
It's like when you're,
when you're like,
when you think something so profound
like to me like to be a writer,
to be a journalist, it's like, it's like
an adventure. It's like a quest, you know?
Like I, you know, I don't mean
to be like too nerdy on this,
but like you go on this adventure where
you like arrive at something approaching
truth and you arrive at like not knowing
shit that you didn't know before and
some of that stuff can
like toppled governments.
It can cause elections to change.
I mean it can,
like you can be pretty revolutionary.
Now,
let me bring you back to this UVA thing.
Sure.
So you were the first guy calling bullshit
on this or one of the first people.
I'm sure there's probably, there's
probably like two others. Yeah.
And then all of a sudden, you
know, you get kicked off Twitter,
people are super angry at you. Your
own mother is saying, what do you do?
An outing rape victims.
And did you question your conviction?
Did you question whether or not you were
correct about it? See, the thing is,
is that like I know enough about how the
media works that I know that like they
need villains, right? Like
all of the media, basically
their heroes and villains,
just like total morality play, even
though my boys are the ultimate villain.
So like Frat boys,
the military,
I mean depending on what kind
of story you're writing in,
the military is either to Hillary hero
or the villain, right? Depending, right.
So I think human nature is
like far more complicated.
I think we're both like hero and villain.
Like this is part of like what makes us,
this is what makes us cool.
Like as a species, you
know? Um, so like I knew,
I knew that the whole thing was bullshit.
I offered like 300 bucks to somebody else
because I wanted to go and hire other
researchers.
And I look for people who like flout
taboos like to me that one of the things
that makes me interested in people
is like when they're like, hey,
everyone believes this.
I believe this and I'm right and
they're so confident of it. So anyways,
so I knew that this was all bullshit
and I knew it was bullshit because of
summary reporting.
I'd done some other research I'd done,
it took me a while to like find the name.
It took me a while to find out more stuff,
but I just started poking around more.
And the thing is like, if you've
seen enough of these fake rape pokes,
his are enough of these fake like, you
know, race hate crimes or whatever,
you develop this like weird,
I don't know how to describe it.
It's like I used to play
chess all the time. Um,
and you see in chess
you see all these games,
enough times that you're
not even thinking,
you're just moving the pieces because
you've seen this orientation before.
It's like the same thing
with these fake crimes.
So like I had enough information,
I had enough stuff to go on and I
have my intuition was like, you know,
my spidey sense was going crazy and it
became clear to me that like they need a
villain in this story.
So they're going to look for me.
But what it's going to do is it's going
to amplify the reach of my website,
you know,
gotten news and it's going to make it
so that they're gonna make me the story,
right? They have to. It's
just the way the media works.
And so I realized it's like a great
promotion tool. Like if you have no you,
thanks. And then what I'll also do
is it will also bring people to me.
So like there's a case right now,
this kid Tyler coast in Arizona who's
like wrongly accused of rape and it's like
a whole scandal and
it's going to break up.
It's going to blow up like
probably over the summer.
And what's going to happen is all of these
weird people are going to come out of
the woodwork and they're going to
start helping me on other projects.
And that's exactly what happened.
Um,
now how do you know that this
kid is not guilty of rape?
Because they're all these text messages
and messages showing that the girls can
aspire to set them up and it's like,
it's like pretty sick stuff.
What was the one recently where a girl
sent a guy a message asking him to fuck
her in the ass? Oh yeah. This is the,
the mattress girl in, uh, Columbia.
What a great kid. She is. She,
she sent text messages as guys
saved asking Facebook messages.
So the, I guess he can't
fake them, but you could,
someone else could have said them.
Someone else could have gotten our coop
on our computer and typed them. Right. No.
But I mean like there were so many of
these messages like in the deposition or
the filing that they, that they did
to sue Columbia, um, that it's like,
it's kind of like outrageous, you know,
like some of the stuff that was described,
like the sex acts, like stuff
that goes, it's pretty like nasty,
just disturb stuff. Like I'm not like
judging people's sex lives or whatever,
but like,
it's kind of not the kind of thing that
you would expect from somebody who was
like, Yo raped, you know, that wants
to go and fuck her rapist years later.
The problem with the word
rape. Okay. Um, rape itself.
The idea,
when you say the word rape,
we think of it as holding someone down
or forcing someone to have sex with.
Sure. We think of it as a violent act,
but there's a lot of progressives,
I don't want to call them progressive,
but let's just call them social justice
warriors that are making these really
ridiculous connections between
other acts and calling them rape.
One of them is having sex while drunk
where two people consenting people who are
both the same fucking age have
sex while they're drinking.
And the man is a rapist in California.
Occidental University.
I'll have that is Russell on the podcast.
I love that guys. It's fucking awesome.
Love that guy too.
And you know,
he was a part of this whole thing
while it was going down and he's like,
this is insane. Well that ruined the kid's
life. Ruined the kids' academic career.
Kid gets kicked out of school, girls
still in school and they just had sex.
That's it. There's no, I
wasn't, I was at college,
I was at Claremont Mckenna out here in
eastern La County and I wrote something
on my website and the school brought
me up before it has a sexual harasser,
even though I didn't even
name my ex girlfriend by name.
I just said my ex girlfriend's a
liar, like on my website, on my blog.
And they brought me up before the sexual
harassment code at Claremont Mckenna.
Was it sexual harassment if you
accuse a person of being aligned,
didn't even use her name. No. And so what
they did is, so what I did was I just,
I just said,
you know,
I wrote like my cheating lying
ex-girlfriend is reliable source as she a
girlfriend, which is to say not very.
And then they brought me up, you know,
it was brought in actual harasses.
Yeah.
And so what they did was they wanted
to basically investigate my sex life.
And so what I did was I had,
I had every guy she cheated on me with
and I had them go and testify on my
behalf. So like, wow. It
worked out. And you know,
like my girlfriend at the time who's
now my wife was like, this is crazy.
Like this is stuff that's bananas though.
Like this is happening all the time.
Like my case is like, by no means. I
mean, I wrote about it on my website.
Everything. It's by no means unique.
Like I can't even tell you how many,
since I did the Jackie Coakley Uva thing,
I've gotten like hundreds and hundreds
of emails from people all around the
country that have similar, that
have similar like crazy. I could,
I could basically dedicate,
I actually bought fake rape registry.com
because I figure like they might come
in handy later on,
but the problem is this is a sexist
thing that the men are always the
perpetrators.
The men are always guilty.
The men are always the ones that need to
be removed, locked up there, the rapists.
And when you start saying that,
there was another one in New Jersey,
they're trying to pass a law saying
that if a man and a woman have sex,
and it turns out that the man deceived
the woman having sex with, they call it.
I mean they're, they're trying to make
that rape when they dating, isn't it?
It's like, well, how about
men raped themselves then?
Because we've lied to ourselves.
Men will lie to themselves about wanting
to be monogamous with a girl just so
they can get, get her in bed.
We lie to ourselves about, yeah,
I'm going to settle down with her. And
then if you decide, you know what man,
fuck this, she's too, too much work,
and then you were a rapist. He lied.
He knew he didn't want to be monogamous.
What about like fat chicks that look
for guys who are drunk and passed out?
Are they rapists? Right? Like, I mean,
what is that? They certainly are,
I mean there's a lot of like you could,
you could start playing this game.
Like in California right now we have
affirmative consent. Like that's the law,
right? So my wife's means yes, if
my wife and I get drunk, right.
And then go in like, you
know, like a bottle of wine
or whatever. And I don't get,
I've technically raped my wife.
Like that's how like wild
the wildest society you guys,
even if you have sex with her and she's
willing, she's not able to consent.
But you know, the whole thing, the Michael
Shermer case, do you know that whole, Oh,
a case,
he was accused of rape because of him.
And a girl had had sex
when they were drunk and,
and she did the language that she used.
He got me drunk to a po point where I
couldn't consent. And then, you know,
there was a guy wrote a blog about it,
this asshole of social justice warrior
guy that's as a professor and they,
you know,
the guys name got pushed out as a rapist.
I mean there were essentially saying
consenting adults having sex is rape
because both of them had been drinking,
but the man was the rapist because men
are evil because it's sexism, it's pure.
It's totally,
well that's why they're saying that guy
who's suing in the mattress girl case,
uh, Paul like nuns, Burger, whatever.
And by the way, this guy's like,
he's like a social justice warrior
himself. Like his mother's like, yes,
I'm leading feminists and he's the one
who needs to know he's the one being
accused of rape.
And so he's like,
you read the messages and he's like the
most like passive aggressive. I mean,
he's like the liberal, you know, I don't
pass in that passive aggressive. And so,
you know, he's like, oh, I'm so sorry
that I don't like you kind of seven.
She's trying to torture
him using the system.
And so what he did was he said Columbia
and it was like, look, you know, uh, uh,
title nine,
you know,
you can't discriminate against men and
you're creating an unsafe environment for
me here. You're saying you're
allowing my rapist. Yeah.
This woman accuses me of being a rapist
to wander around defaming me even though
you found me guilty and
your bullshit kangaroo,
I mean found me not guilty and
your bullshit kangaroo court.
So they found him not guilty of rape,
like under their administrative policies,
which by the way, those things are like,
they almost always convict you, right.
So he's found not guilty and he
sues them and I hope you win.
It's like he's going after Ballinger,
the guy who's the president there,
he's going after the, um,
and this chick, you know,
she was running around with her mattress
saying that her rapist was on campus
and he's dangerous to her back. Right.
She was at carrying out and stuff.
Yeah. She was trying to like,
is there like a performance art
piece to what a crazy bitch.
I really do think.
I really do think that by the way,
like I think like legitimately,
I think like Roosh and some of those
like men's rights people are like,
I'm not a men's rights guy. Like I, you
know, I'm a people's rights guy, you know?
Um,
but like I think they're right.
Like if you don't go to the police and
you go to like college administrator
shoes,
that chicks accused of rape by mattress
girl suing Columbia University reveals
her damning tax and that's
her. Yeah, that's wild. Wow.
We're in this like weird states.
Kind of cute though.
Like go back to that picture again.
Just kind of, she's wearing sexy shorts.
She should want her legs. She's got heels
on or those heels. It's hard to tell.
I think they're like clogs or something,
but she's got all leg, you know,
if a guy was walking around like
that with those cutoff shorts,
he'd be like that. Gosh,
look at her. She's,
her jeans are cut so low that are pockets
are hanging out underneath the gene,
which is always adorable.
And she, yeah, she's hot.
It's kind of off. It's kind of awkward. I
hope we didn't. We didn't mentally. Right.
Those aren't, those aren't heels
at all. They're like Birkenstocks,
which is even more appropriate. It's kind
of weird though. Like, can you imagine,
can you imagine being like a student
and being like accused of this though?
Like it's pretty wild. Like
it's pretty scary stuff. Well,
it's terrifying that we live in
a terrifying age and look, kids,
when they go away to college,
they get drunk and they fuck and they
make mistakes and they have sex with
people like don't have sex with,
that's like the point.
But here's the number one thing that's
fucked up about this idea of people
drinking alcohol, having sex and
have that being raped or people, uh,
being deceptive and calling that rape.
You're just talking about sex.
You're talking about consensual sex and
you filtered consensual sex into your
these parameters and now you're calling
it rape and it's people fuck up.
People lie.
People do.
And that's how you find out who to hang
out with and who did not hang out with.
But the worst case scenario that's
happening to these people because they had
sex with someone that they regret. That's
part of being a person. You find me,
someone who has never had sex with
someone they regret and I'll find you a
person has never taken a
fucking chance. Yeah. I mean we,
we have ex girlfriends and ex
wives for a reason. You know,
people out there in the world,
right?
Like this is like part of life
boyfriends or boyfriends or X.
Whatever's people fuck up man. You make
dumb decisions and you're like, oh my bad.
Have you ever talked to
a girl ever that said,
every guy that I used to date was amazing.
They're the best person ever.
I'm so happy I fucked them.
To know that I've ever blown was
the best dude of all time. No,
that's not nearly every conversation
with a friend who just broke up with his
girlfriend is bad and that bitch is
crazy. Right? I mean, how about this?
Every girl that ever broke
up with me was right.
She was right at the tone because I'm
a different person than it was 20 years
old or 18 years old or 30 years
old. You fucking grow, you evolve.
Totally adapt, change. So
this idea that that's rape,
that's if someone's
deceptive or if someone,
the one that drives me the most bananas
is the two people drunk together,
two consenting adults.
And then there was a whole feminist
blog that I wrote about that,
that if two people are having
sex while they're drinking,
even if a man is drunk
and the woman's sober,
the woman raped the man,
which is just adorable.
It's adorable. It's
adorable. First of all,
it's not possible because there's not a
fucking guy on earth that's going to say
that if a woman had sex with him
because he was drunk, that he got raped.
It's like all those, uh, high
school kids, the other where they,
where the kid is like 16,
17 and he's like screwing the 24
year old teacher or something like,
is that really re like, I mean, I
know we're supposed to say it is,
but like is it really as a joke that,
did he get his dick get hard? Yeah,
he's all right. Emotionally. Yeah, he got
raped. But guess what? He'll get over it.
Who Do? Zach Galifianakis has a great
joke about that, about a young man
who died because he had sex with his
teacher and his friends high fived him to
death.
I remember there was a case
recently of that guy who, uh,
he got in to teachers or whatever
and they found him bragging about it.
That's how they like caught the two
teachers cause he was just bragging.
It'd be Kinda hard not to like imagine
your 17 year old self and you got two
teachers at a party. Like it would
be hard not to brag about that.
Me a 15 year old kid who got blown by
his teacher who was good at keeping a
fucking secret.
You're dealing with crazy people.
You're dealing with a woman who is so
crazy. She's blowing high school kids.
She's having sex parties and drinking
with high school kids and having sex with
him. And by the way, the ones that get
caught, how many of them don't get caught?
Oh total.
And how many hundred of them are out
there running around below in high school?
Kids right now.
And how many people are really smart
and just shut the fuck up about it when
they're young. How many of the boys?
Yeah, I mean the boys. We had this case,
so I went to this prep school and
Master's, Milton Academy, you know,
probably probably remember from
your last mass. Yeah. Milton mass.
So scholarship winner there.
And we had this like crazy case where
we had this chick who like willingly 15
years old,
gave head to this guy who we on his
18th birthday and five other guys.
I think it's like four other guys.
And the school just expelled all of them
because of the Romeo and Juliet laws,
like if you're 15 or under 16,
it's like rape automatically.
And so they just expelled
all five of these guys. I'm
like, no trial, no anything.
Just expelled them. Uh, was it, that was
an issue when I was in high school, man,
I was,
when I was 18 years old,
when I turned 18 my girlfriend at the
time was 17 and her mother was worried
that like what we were doing was illegal
and she brought it up to me that my mom
thinks that you could go
to jail for having sex men.
I'm like, Whoa, Whoa, whoa.
Like we've been having sex for like
seven months or something like that.
Like almost a year. It was okay then. And
it's not okay today because I turned 18,
like I was nervous. I
was like, I had, yeah,
I remember who I had a conversation
with, maybe my parents, but it was like,
can I go to jail? Like,
cause it's really kidding.
Isn't that like an inherently terrifying
thought? You know what I mean? Like,
so like they're all right, we
know this like genetically, right?
Like something like one in 10
people are genetic Kuk holds, right?
Meaning like your dad is not
who your mom says it is. Right.
Because like it's not a cold.
I thought a cuckold is like you want
to watch dudes banging your wife.
I don't know what that,
I don't think that's kind of a cuckold
is somebody who doesn't want that to
happen. Who was a dude who has
this wife go shagging on other men.
That's a different situation. Maybe.
Maybe like, I don't know. I mean,
but I know the cuckold that I'm talking
about might be another second definition
that you're talking about. I
don't think I've ever, by the way,
I only I've ever said that word. I've
only like a Shakespearian thing. Yeah.
I've only read cock hold. I don't think
I've ever said it until this podcast.
Yeah. But uh, and so anyway, so
don't even, so like one in 10 people,
their moms or their dads or not hit her
mom says it is. Right. Because humans,
we know that like women
prefer the Alpha male sperm.
But Beta male to raise the kids because
the Alpha male will run away, right?
So a lot of women we've seen,
like in fake rape cases,
they'll go and they'll have an affair
and they'll say, oh, that guy raped me.
Right? And we've seen this happen time
and time again and that kind of stuff.
Like people lie about stuff.
The thing that the people just me off the
most about the feminists are like the,
the social justice warriors is to
say what woman would lie about rape.
Like as if it's like some unnatural thing.
Like people will lie about all kinds
of shit all the time for no apparent
reasons. I can't say things like
that. What woman to a crazy person.
But one would lie about bigfoot.
What one would,
would lie about Ufo is what woman would
lie about anything. Sometimes the crazy,
but sometimes it's an a tactical
advantage, right? Like there was a case,
we did it, uh, University of
Hawaii, there was this chick,
mckenna facto is her name and she liked,
there are two guys,
like one who lived in one room, one
who lived in the other, you know,
like dorm situation and she liked
the, you know, the hot, you know,
football player guy. Um, and
he didn't like her anymore.
He was like banging on some other chick,
right. And the guy next door was like, uh,
you know,
she fucked him to get him jealous and
then said that this guy next door,
like the nerdy guy next door raped
her and he was found innocent.
He was like clear,
but he was like expelled from
school at the University of Hawaii.
He had to like spend all this money
to defend himself and he was found not
guilty. You like, you know, one in
everything. But imagine like how,
I mean that that's like a perfectly
human thing. Like who, who, I mean,
who hasn't seen situations where somebody
will sleep with somebody else to get
them jealous, right? Like this
is like how humans behave. Like,
this is what people love to do,
things to get reactions pro or con.
Totally pro or con.
They love to do wonderful things like
bring you flowers to get a reaction or
they look to accuse you of things you
didn't actually do in order to get a
negative reaction or fuck your friends.
I mean, how many girls have done that?
Fuck her boyfriend's
friends when they break up.
And that's how super common thing.
I've had fucking girlfriends of x book,
you know guys who are still good friends,
like girlfriends when they break up,
come after me and I'm like, get the
fuck out of here. And I immediately,
we'll call them and tell them, dude,
your, your ex girlfriend tries to fuck.
She's trying to fuck all your friends.
Like I had a situation where
I had a friend who like,
I dated the girl beforehand
and I was like, Oh, you know,
my friend is actually better for you
than I am. You know what I mean? Like,
so I was just like, all right, these
people should date. And it was,
that was a very healthy of you. I think
people, I think that happens a lot more.
Like sometimes you're, you realize
like this is not right for me. Right.
It certainly should. I mean it'd be cool
if that's how it worked if, but you know,
the only way that does work is if the
person is mentally healthy and not lonely.
True.
You know,
the problem is people get lonely and
they get sad and they get super depressed
at that person doesn't want
to be with them anymore.
And that sometimes that sense of loss and
it's ingrained in our DNA because it's
how people stay together,
which is how people procreate,
which is how the human race expands.
Because if it didn't,
if you didn't have that sense of loss
when someone no longer wants to be with
you anymore, then you would have no
incentive to improve your personality.
He'd have no incentive
to get your shit together. No incentive
to be a good mate, no incentive,
just like hold the reason why people
have that feeling when someone wants to
leave.
That feeling of rejection is terrible
because you're your body and your DNA is
telling you, hey fuck face, you got to
learn how to be a more attractive person.
You have to learn how to be more accepted.
You have to learn how to figure out
a way to be more valuable to mates.
And that is one of the problems
with social justice warriors,
that same instinct to be more valuable
and better is what's leading these people
to loudly proclaim that
they're fiercely feminist.
They'll the go after men exclusively
not be objective about the situation,
not saying hey,
you may be these two people got drunk and
maybe this girl had sex with a guy and
kind of regrets it,
but and then in the guy didn't regret
it and now lets just accuse this guy of
rape because that's what they're doing
and stepping forward and proclaiming that
this guy's a rapist and
writing blog entries about it.
All your doing is trying to set yourself
aside as being the moral high. Yeah,
but you know there's a
biological reason for this.
So like there's this great
documentary series from Norway.
I know it's like kind of random,
but there's this document it's called
like Javier Nasca translates to brainwash.
It's all free online. I highly recommend
it. And you spell it like H, j.
E r n, a, Google brainwashed Norwegian
region documentary you'll find. Okay.
Um, and what he does is he interviews
all these people, like horseplay,
scientists and specialists. I'm like all
these taboo subjects. It's really like,
it's kind of up your alley. I mean,
I think you'd, you'd dig it. Um,
but basically there's a section where
he talks about how men and women behave
after they have casual sex. Both
groups will party to want it, right?
Because of how we're wired genetically.
But women tend to regret it far more
often than men to the social consequences
for women. Not just, not just
like the sociological pressures,
but I'm talking about like biological
things. Because women, when you,
when you have sex with them, they,
you know, they, they get oxytocin,
they get all the kinds of like basically
chemicals in their brains that make
them attach to you. I
Dunno, maybe, I dunno.
Maybe. I Dunno. But, um,
yeah, this, this show,
I highly recommend it and washed it
just like 10 parts in the paradox. Yeah,
it's pretty good.
So anyways,
what's interesting about it is this whole
like kind of like brainwashed kind of
this, this kind of like brainwashed
culture. There's like a biological reason.
And if you're a woman and you have
sex with a guy and you regret it,
and then the campus
feminists come in there,
the social justice warriors come in there
and say you'll regret is actually rape.
It's a very like,
biological thing that produces this.
And then on the other side of it too,
you've got this other biological problem,
which is that in all animal
species, right? Like rape, I mean,
animals don't rape each other.
I mean, I mean, they do like,
that's basically like the whole
point of the animal kingdom, right?
So like you've got cases where males
among primates will go and they'll just,
they'll rape some desirable female
because they're like the lonely animal and
the tribe. You know what I'm saying? So
it's like, it's like, um, in our society,
if we
had some loser dude as a last ditch
mating strategy, they'd go and rape.
And I think that's like,
that explains an awful lot of like the
actual violent predatory rape that we see
now, that kind of acquaintance rape,
you know, I'm writing this down.
Gender equality. Parents love
it. They're all 10 of the parts.
I think they're like 30
minutes a piece or something.
They're in somewhat in English,
somewhat in Norwegian.
He interviews all these people. Um,
but the other subtitles is pretty good.
The idea that someone could go to jail
for something like this or get their
life's ruined for something like
this, it's just so creepy to me. It's,
it's so creepy that sexual attraction
and then regret it could lead to someone
being accused of a crime,
especially a heinous crime like rape,
especially in how much money you have
to spend. Less so like Alan Dershowitz.
So I actually worked for,
back in the day was accused of
rape by this like crazy chick.
We're Virginia Roberts and he's been found
like totally innocent and everything,
but he's a lawyer, you know, like one
of the best lawyers in the country.
He spent all of this like attention
and money basically defending himself.
And that's like a terrible situation
because even though he's found innocent,
even when people are found innocent,
people still kind of wonder, right?
Cause you can never know
what happens with two people.
You can never kind of get that back.
You know what I'm saying?
Like that's what makes it so hellish.
But once you're accused of
something is as disgusting as rape.
I mean it's very difficult
to shake that moniker.
I gotta tell you there's a case right
now I'm in la that's kind of like getting
some attention. I wrote about it a lot,
but there's this actress, Pauley Perrette,
you know like the NCI s chick,
I don't know if you've seen that show,
but basically a NCI as she's
like accusing her husband.
It's like this long drawn out custody
or long drawn out like divorce thing.
And she's been using the state and her
restraining orders to go and hire people
to follow her husband around and basically
show up so that he gets thrown in
jail. Um, yeah, it's
like this whole thing.
If you Google Coyote Shivers when Kelly
paret she, hold on, let me explain.
Let me clarify this. So they had a
divorce, so like it was like 10 years ago.
He married this like hotter check,
I think she's like a Brazilian Brazilian
journalist or something and he's like
moved on with his life. He's this, um, you
know, musician type, he lives here in La.
And what happened was she created
this whole elaborate story,
like as a tactical maneuver
in the divorce, right?
That he like beat her and like created
this whole like, elaborate thing.
She hired this Pi who's like famous for
basically lying and getting, you know,
the evidence to help his clients. Right.
Nothing wrong with that, you know,
in a legal sense, but in a moral
sense, it's kind of messed up.
And his name's coyote shivers.
I've interviewed him a bunch of,
posted some stuff and he had nine one
one calls that basically proved his
innocence. And yet what she did was she
hired all these people to go and say,
uh,
to follow him around.
And whenever he goes anywhere she'll
then show up cause they'll to,
and then he'll be within,
you know,
within the vicinity or whatever
and he'll then have, you know,
face a chance of violating
the restraining order.
So she got a bullshit restraining order.
She hired people to basically track
this guy around in La and she's a star.
Like she's on the top show on television.
I've
written about this. It got news. Other
people have written about this too,
but it's like one of the
greatest like loss, you know, uh,
a restraining order abuses against a guy
out there and this guy is facing like
30. Yeah, I think he's facing like a,
I think he'd say you seem like a year in
prison are a year in jail for violating
a restraining order. That was like
bullshit Lee obtained and you know,
you could interview this guy.
Like I vetted him,
I've had all these people look into him.
Like everything he said
to me has checked out. Um,
how do you know her interviewed
her? So, so I've got,
so I've got a lot of the documents that
confirm what he's saying and no one's
really dug into it.
So what she's done is she's used the
threat assessment office of the LAPD,
which is like basically a bunch of star
fuckers. Like they love celebrities.
And so they tried to make it like this
guy who's also kind of like a minor
celebrity,
they tried to use him and say like he's
a stalker or whatever to advance their
power and interest when it's really
just a dispute that they had.
And they got into an
argument like is couples do,
he divorced her and he
then married somebody else.
She was all like upset about this and she,
she hired people to basically torment
this guy. Um, and it's like no,
that he wasn't a dick,
that he wasn't a beating or whatever.
There was no record of that.
There's no record of anything.
There was no record as far as her going
to the hospital or no record of like
abuse, no record of like, you
know, of him hurting her in court.
Actually they suggested that
he sat on her, you know,
but that the other than the court,
then the lawyer kind of retracted that.
I mean basically there's no evidence,
physical evidence whatsoever
that he was like beating her.
I have with that is there's a lot of
women that don't want to admit that there
man beats them.
They should freak out about it or there's
a mutually abusive relationship and
the man takes it too far and they don't,
don't ever go to the hospital about it.
I don't think
that's the case here. I mean, you would
have to drill down on the particular,
cause I've written about this a
bunch already. It's been 20 months,
but you have to communicate with her. I
have, I've reached out to her. I've got,
I mean all of the documentation that's
in the case supports this guy's side of
it. And she has said
things that contradict the
documentation that's out there.
Like,
uh,
she said that she feared for her life
and she called the nine one one nine one
one call and I posted the audio of that
and it showed like she wasn't, you know,
freaking out or anything.
She was very calm.
She was like trying to
get her husband right.
I mean there's a lot of physical
evidence in the case. You should,
I mean you could, you should. I mean
not to tell you what to do your podcast,
but he's somebody you should have on,
cause he's kind of,
he's kind of an interesting
guy. He's been, you know,
he was like a total liberal kind of
guy and he's been like dealing with the
trauma of this. Um, and there's,
I mean if you go to God news,
I've kind of written it out
and kind of more detail,
but there's a lot of
evidence to kind of point me.
I tend to be very suspicious of men who
are like accused accused of beating in
general because like, yeah, like a calm,
cause it's common like people do it,
you know, like a friend of mine, actually,
I'm not a friend of mine, but you know,
like a Twitter friend of mine,
uh,
Todd king cannon who was a famous kind
of Republican guy is wailing on his wife
for a long time and you know, was
apparently arrested for it. So like I, I,
I don't discount that, that,
that happens, but the, the,
the evidence that's gone on here,
the number of, you know, um,
different civil rights groups have got
involved in a number of researchers got
involved.
There are a lot of people who are like,
this guy could go to jail for a
year on trumped up charges. Um,
and it's kind of wild, but, but again,
you know, you never really know,
like this gets to what we
were saying earlier, right.
You never really know what
goes on with two people.
Right. Right. When he'd go to the
girl with the mattress on her back,
it's obvious that it does happen.
Sure.
Obviously there's some people
that are fucking crazy.
There's also some people that
want to do that Glen close thing.
I'm not going to be ignored. I will
not be ignored. Like you, they don't,
someone doesn't want you to just
move on with your life. You know,
some men and women women after
they just go crazy. Yeah.
There's certain people that,
that feeling that they get,
that we discussed before
when someone rejects you,
that horrible feeling of
loss and it's like God,
which is nature trying to get you to
do some deep fucking soul searching and
figure out how to be a better mate
drug thing too, right? When
you're getting, when you're
fucking on the regular,
you know, you get certain brain
chemicals released, you know,
you feel good about
yourself, right? Like I mean,
that's what the whole like
when you first fall in love,
you're getting all that Aussie Towson
into your brain, which is like a narcotic.
Like it's uh, you know, it's an actual
like, and then when you stop getting that,
you go through withdrawals.
Right? And that's what you,
that's why you feel like physically
like your body hurts, right?
Like that's what that is and you've
got to go and build yourself up to be a
better mate.
But a lot of people unfortunately don't.
And then then the sad thing is then they
start using the legal system or their
power or their money or whatever
to then fuck with the other person.
Yeah, it's dark, it's dark.
What people are capable of doing and
deception and the fact that they can plot
and conspire to have someone locked up
for something just to sort of have an
impact on their life.
And I don't think it's like uh,
I don't think it's always an everywhere,
a malicious thing. Cause I think
sometimes you go, you just go crazy.
Like I mean we've all had bad breakups
where we are like we don't recognize
ourselves. Like the actions that
we're doing like don't seem rational.
Well also there's some people that have
some sort of crazy aspects of their
personality.
They are attractive because they're wild
and impulsive and you hold off it when
you first start dating him.
You know,
like if you're dating a girl and she pulls
her pants down in the parking lot and
he's, come on, let's do it. And
you're like, wow, this is crazy.
People are going to see us.
I don't care. Fuck me, whoa.
That's a crazy bitch is going to walk
around campus with a mattress on her back.
You know, like that kind of, and you don't
really think about it, you know. Yeah,
you're exactly right.
Like sometimes the things that draw you
to them or the things that ultimately
repel you from them. Right? Like
you know, my friend Tony's Arrow,
he says that that's psychotic and erotic
or basically the same thing expressing
themselves and just
different ways that like the,
the girls who are the most erotic and
crazy in bed or on their fucking bananas.
Like he only dates crazy
girls cause they're fun. Yeah.
I mean I got to tell you,
like said,
I'm coming up with my two year
anniversary of being married.
I got to tell you like the faster I got
rid of the crazy in my life to happier I
was for sure. Well, especially when you
recognize the consequences of that crazy.
No
financially like debilitating.
When you're,
when you're dating crazy
people, they can't, it can be,
it certainly can just drive you.
It can be pretty bad.
Why don't you just gotta be
aware of the consequences,
not just jump to the deep end of the pool.
You gotta share.
Just tread slowly like dancing on
dynamite though. Like it really is.
And a lot of guys think like,
no, no, no, I can control this
shit. And like, no, no, no,
no, no. Like there's a legal
system that's got to get you.
Certainly if someone's
inclined to sue and my God,
I mean anybody that finds
out about mattress girl and,
and then still decides to date or after
that. But what a glutton for punishment.
You must be. I would, I would
be fascinated to interview
that guy. Like I wouldn't,
wouldn't, wouldn't you be
like, what would you, I mean,
what was going to be cooking at Uva girl,
let's go back to the rolling stone
sharing this because we'd never really
completely completed it. I'm
completely completed this. Um,
you were the guy who were one of the
people that called bullshit on this. Yeah.
And when it all fell apart,
which took a long time. Yeah.
It was a delayed reaction. Well,
like three or four months, but yeah,
it took a long time. Yeah. I mean there's,
this whole thing was a huge
story and you know, uh, yes,
all women and all that shit went down
there that, that bothered me a lot too.
That was,
yes.
All women than me about that that guy
killed more men than he did women.
And everybody was like, yes. All
women. Like what does it need?
You're dealing with a psycho,
whatever happened to just like plain
crazy like people are that are just nuts.
Like it's not even a political thing
like whatever happened to just like this
guy is nuts. Yeah. But this,
the whole focus became,
instead of his mental health issues,
does the guy in Santa Barbara,
the for the focus became that this whole
thing was about men's rights activists
and pickup artists who have fucked
with this guy's head and gotten him to
objectify women and that women have to
deal with this guy kind of person on a
regular basis.
It's just a nonsense.
Completely ignoring the fact that this
guy murdered four men and two women and
he stabbed more people than he use guns
to people who were trying to ban guns
doing that. But the whole thing
was just so completely fucked up.
Like how can you,
and I saw that there's so many
social justice where he couldn't,
one guy that I respect wrote this article,
this Hashtag yes. All women article.
I'm like,
Jesus fucking Christ dude.
You're dealing with a person with obvious
mental illness problems and the fact
that you're writing. Yes. All women when
he murdered men as well. It's just crazy.
It's sexist.
It's fucking sexist is,
and it's sad too because like there's
so many people out there who had lake
legit and mental health issues that
like we shouldn't be putting them into a
like, uh, into like a political
or social or religious lens.
Exactly what you just be like, we should
just get these people help. Right.
And we should try and identify them, not
give them guns. Right? Like I think we,
you know,
those of us who are pro guns,
we should recognize that like there's
the people who shouldn't have guns. Um,
not that we should be overly restrictive
about gun Ross because I think a lot of
people in Maryland right now kind of
wish they could have concealed carry,
you know, um, yeah, in
Baltimore or whatnot. But we
should be like, we should stop
trying to politicize everything
and try to like help people.
And the thing is when you start like
framing these things as political
discussions rather than like, hey, like
this guy's crazy, like we should help him
and it's a power grab for
Social Brownie points.
Is this God that I know that I respect,
that wrote this article.
He's a fucking Dork. He's a
Dork. And I've seen, you know,
I mean I say that with all love,
but he's just as super nerdy guy who's
very weak and this is signaling thing.
Hollowness, peacock feathers. Yes.
It's all, I mean this is where monkeys,
right? Like we're, we're like, you know,
we are primates or whatever
we want to say, put, you know,
the Pc version of it all monkeys signal
like all of them socially, they, you know,
that's what the gorilla does this for.
Like this is what,
this is what this is and what
they're doing is they're using the,
the taboos of the society to show to
women that they're virtuous and that
therefore they're deserving of
female attention. And you know,
they don't know that they're doing that.
I'm sure they see like a political lens
to it, but that's what they were doing.
Absolutely. I mean, this is
also, by the way, while heinous,
horrific acts are going on all throughout
the world that these people are
conveniently ignoring. Like she's not,
they're not focusing on the Congo.
Then I focusing on, there's like a real
rape culture, a real rape called total.
I focusing on Afghanistan.
They're not writing articles and some
of the most heinous activities of the
human race.
They're writing articles about this
one thing that's in the news and then
they're using it to focus on one
very specific aspect of that thing.
Not to mental illness as
the gender aspects of it.
Easy man. Like I mean I watched all
these videos, I read every article,
Sabrina Reuben early wrote like I watch
all the videos that I could find of her.
I like, yeah, like it was hard to do
this shit. Like, you know what I mean?
And it's easy just to be like,
yes, I'll live in a, you know,
140 and it's hard to go to like see the
rape rooms in like you know it and you
shitty countries. Right. It's
hard to get access to it.
And then the people who do get access
to it, it doesn't trend on Twitter.
Nobody really sees it,
you know,
which is the sad side of
like our media landscape.
What is the consequences for the woman
who was a false rape accuser? Well,
there's no victim cause
there's no real guy.
She pointed to write the
[inaudible] fraternity
was vandalized. I think something like
$100,000 worth of damage was done.
Like people saw that as an excuse. This
is the thing that scares me, right?
This is like, I don't like the Hitler
reductive added Hitlarian thing, but like,
you know, like the Kristallnacht thing
when people were like targeting Jews,
right?
Like there's a certain aspect of this
where like it becomes okay to hate certain
people and to be kind of, because it's
okay to hate them. It's okay to harm them.
And we are seeing this with like,
you know,
attacks on the police in Baltimore right
now we're seeing this with a tax on
fraternities. I mean if you, the social
justice warriors are honest about this.
They say like, we want to destroy
fraternities in this country.
It's like bastions of male power, right?
Like that's what they're trying to do.
That's why you saw it.
You remember that? Uh,
like a video a while back at
Oklahoma where the, you know,
the Frat boys were saying some racist
shit. Like, which was like, you know,
we've all been in environments
where people said Shit that like
probably shouldn't be broadcast to the
entire world. Right? Like, we've all been,
we've all been like, I'm
not saying, well, you know,
the Donald Sterling thing isn't,
he is a good example of this,
like a private conversation.
I mean,
if you can't have a private
conversation with your mistress,
who can you have a private conversation
with the Donald Sterling thing?
She's as Christ.
I mean,
I had a bit about it in my act
because it was so ridiculous.
He's asking her to not take pictures
of the black guys in the same sentence.
He said, I don't care if you fuck
them. The joke I had, my act was,
could you imagine if it was
the opposite way? If he said,
I don't mind if you take
pictures of the black guys,
but I don't want you to fuck on. People
would be like, that's pretty reasonable.
You know?
I think it's kind of how another,
it's racist because it wasn't
one or taking pictures with them.
Like the whole thing is nuts.
The whole thing was nuts.
They took that guy's fucking team away.
I think he did it deliberately.
I have this whole theory
about how it's like,
how was like an elaborate
play to like sell the team.
I mean he increased the rent. Oh, if
you look at like when he bought it,
he's not that bright. If you've ever
heard of the talk, he's a fucking billion.
He's a financial genius but not socially.
I'm sure. I'm sure there Kate. I mean he,
I think he got back with the chick too.
I could be wrong on that,
but I think he got back with
her. He should. You know why?
Cause she's getting sued
by his fucking wife.
She's losing everything that
she's going to be broke as a joke.
His wife is going after money
that she donated to charity.
Like when she bought things with a
credit card and they can give away $5 for
breast cancer. She wants that money
to, she's divorces ugly. Well,
the wife has just going after this cunt.
I mean like this chick,
like the wife is going after her
because she can and because she can,
she can break her. She can show her. Yeah,
you might be able to fuck my husband
because you're young and pretty,
but guess what I can do.
I had lawyer million dollars and I'm
going to sue you into the ground and if I
lose I'm going to sue you for something
else and I'm going to keep going until
you got no fucking money. It's kind of
wild, isn't it? It's crazy to me. This is,
this is our legal system right now,
but I mean in some ways the legal
system is super important to have.
It's important. If somebody victimizes
you, you have a, you have recourse.
Sure could. You could get that
money but you can get it back.
But those shitting get victimized.
She,
she had a husband that was fucking the
hot young girl and buying or condos and
Byner Mercedes or whatever the fuck
he bought or of Jaguars or Bentleys or
whatever the fuck it was.
But it's,
it's the whole thing is kind of hilarious
when it's all played out in front of
you. Yeah. You would think
it would be like, yeah,
you would think it was like a Tom Wolfe
novel or like you would think it's like
some kind of fun play or something.
But I mean like with the Jackie Coakley
situation at the University of Virginia,
right.
I thought it was kind of racist that we
all like know Twana brollies name but
not Jackie Coakley.
Like people didn't want to name her.
Well Tawana Brawley though
came out publicly. Sure. But
this is a big difference.
And then she did too. Like she
participated in, in a story. Right?
Like a lot of the Times that,
you know,
if it was so important to
keep on a bit reluctant,
I mean she wasn't cold so we're
told now. Right. But like,
I mean I'm sure there's some
power that comes with being I,
it was brought up before
Congress,
like they tried to pass like laws based
upon this grow based upon Emily Renda
who was her friend who apparently has
this whole other problem with her own rape
story where she was allegedly raped but
they're like conflicting accounts on
that. But like the thing that
bothers me about this is not,
is not the girls cause I do,
I think there something like
mentally ill with Jackie,
like Jackie's clearly bipolar.
Like a lot of the people I've talked
to who know her says she's just not,
well the thing that bothers me is
there's this desire by a lot of like
journalists now to go and shop as,
as Sabrina Reuben early put it to shop
around looking for victims. Right.
Rather than to like tell the
complexity of like, you know,
an actual fight that goes,
I mean what they do is they reduce people
to like characters in there like agit
prop play,
right.
Rather than like get into
like the motivations and the
psychology and they don't
really, like, they don't really
need to do the actual work.
They basically use the gang rapes or
the [inaudible] sensationalist things to
basically push people
emotionally manipulate them to,
to like advance an interest or an agenda.
And what's happening right now on
college campuses is there eliminating due
process rights for men? And like, I was
a nerd in college, like I'm a nerd now,
right? Like nobody was asking
me to join a fraternity.
Like I live with football players and I
like, you know, I saw the progression,
you know, the, the procession of hot
women that came in and tried to fuck them.
Right. Um, like I, you
know, I saw this, but the,
and I'm not like trying to like defend
some of the boarish behavior that like
football players and Frat guys have.
Like,
we all know there's some stuff that goes
on there that's probably like probably
not the coolest stuff in the
world, right? Absolutely.
But we also know that some women are
attracted to Borsch men of course,
because those are, that's what I,
yeah, it was just good old war.
And those are the men that defend them.
And those are the,
the violence aggressive manner,
attractive to their jeans.
You can't have a society,
you can't, on the one hand,
have a society that tries to turn us all
into basically feminized men and then
hope that things will work out.
You need burly,
disturbed men to go and
break stuff. You know, like,
this is what you need in this society.
And if you're just constantly putting
upon them and constantly, it's not gonna,
it's not gonna work out. Well, this
movie does not, does not go well.
Yeah. Uh, this Uva thing,
so Rollingstone publishes this store and
with very little vetting of the facts
and just violate it all the
laws of journalism, which is,
it was so disturbing because rolling
stone is this iconic magazine that in my
mind is ultimately connected with hunter
s Thompson and Matt tie eat totally
pisses me.
They pissed me off when they put the cover
of the fucking terrorist on the cover.
Yeah.
Like my sister,
my sister was there 20 minutes beforehand
and when he did that I was like,
fuck them,
I'm done with this
place. Well they didn't
just put him on the cover.
If they put him on the cover handcuffed
being, you know, covered in blood.
Like they found him under that boat.
Tarp. Yeah. That would be one thing.
They put a glamour shot of him. Yeah.
He's a cute kid, you know, and yeah.
And then you had all these fellows.
This is what we're getting at. Yeah. I
was like women boarish men.
Right.
So like they were going all these
chicks like the free, you know,
Free Dzhokhar Siren. I have brigade on
Twitter who are like, oh, he's so hot.
Like there are all these people have all
these chicks like high school checks on
Twitter who are like, oh, he's so hot.
He's so dreamy. He's all this. Oh yeah.
It was like diff of stuff like, uh, uh,
I mean it just goes to show
you that women have, you know,
some women have no taste and
just fucking around, you know,
so I don't know that some of
them were fucking around though.
Like there was some stuff that was
done. Yeah. Like this is what happens.
He's an attractive kind of guy.
Um, but that, that pissed me off.
And then then with the
rolling stone stuff,
what I discovered about a
lot of journalism out there
that you see all the time
is that it goes through
very little fact checking.
And the Sabrina Reuben Eardley is like
a prime example of this. But we've got,
there are many examples of this.
You could,
you can shoot down a lot of articles
these days. Yeah. Well you certainly,
I can shoot down that one.
You know,
that that article is a rough one and
that that article being in rolling stone
was so disappointing to a
lot of people that it was,
a lot of people canceled the
Rolling Stones Subscriptions,
I'm sure because of it. I mean it's,
it's one of those things where you,
you're always going to have to wonder
about any scathing report that they
published in that magazine
now. But you know, there's no story,
there's no story without Jackie Coakley
talking to Sabrina Reuben Eardley so why
does she go and talk to her?
Because Emily Renda,
who's like trying to push this
campus rape agenda story, you know,
this kind of rape culture
fantasy. She was, she was,
she was shopping around for victims and
there's no story without Jackie Coakley
and note, and she lied. I
mean, she lied repeatedly.
She realized about the guy even existing,
she hadn't talked to the photo of the
guy that she had seen in all these years.
Like there's just, I mean,
you have to vet your sources,
you have to vet people that you talk to.
And none of that was done because the
story was too good. It was too sexy. Well,
it's one of those things,
this story where you,
you can't,
you can't question a woman who says
that she was involved in a rape.
Because if you do, you
become a rape apologist. You
become a part of the problem,
you become,
there's all,
I mean you could talk to a bunch of
different negative monikers to it and uh,
that sort of,
that hands off non objective
approach to one very specific thing.
If you talk about a man who
has been beaten up, you know,
and a man who is a violence has
been perpetrated on you, you,
you can ask all sorts of questions.
But if it's a woman and it's sexual,
why do you think, I mean, so
I've been thinking about this,
I've been having this debate
with a friend of mine, right,
about the Rape Shield law, right? Cause
you know, like in a lot of newspapers,
a lot of newspapers do
this. Like, you know,
by design they say like they don't
mention the name of the woman, right?
Whenever there's a rape allegation, they
say, you know, this woman was raped,
she's turning 19 whatever.
They never tell you like her name.
And I always feel really uncomfortable
with this because it provides a great
shield to do damage to
somebody. Right? Like if you,
if you don't identify the name
of a victim supposed victim,
it's an alleged victim. We haven't had a
trial yet. We haven't had conviction yet.
We haven't had anything.
Right.
And when people we know are doing power
place to kind of like screw people over,
I mean I posted an article of 13 women
who lied about rape, um, or you know,
on my Twitter page and like I think the
rape shield idea existed like in a time
before kind of the sexual revolution.
So it made a lot of sense then like
when a woman's virtuousness or you know,
not having sex was prized,
but like we're in 2015 like most people
are having sex before marriage, right?
Like a lot of people,
you know what I mean?
Like it seems kind of weird that we still
have this thing where we keep the name
of the victim.
It's an alleged victim,
but they always pretend like it's a
real victim and we don't know that yet.
Like there hasn't been.
And it seems like if we named,
if we named the women,
you know, like, hey,
so and so's accusing such
and such of this crime. Um,
and we just named them like we do for
attempted murder like we do for all kinds
of cases. Um, I think we would get
fewer of these fake rape incidents.
But on the,
do you also think though that we would
get few real rape accusations of actual
rape because women don't
want to be shamed. There's
some woman that's a shame of,
of,
of coming out publicly
about an actual real rape.
It actually prevents them from going
after a real rapist. That's a fact.
So we're told, yeah, I mean
that's not, so we're told there's,
I mean this is let people
that have actually been
raped where it's totally fun,
they've been raped,
have said that they were reluctant
shock about it because of the shame that
comes on them.
The shit that gets put on them because
of the situation where a woman who gets
raped,
it's very different than a woman getting
beat up or a man getting geed up or any
other situation when a person gets raped.
It's a shameful,
horrible feeling that this
person has to deal with publicly.
They have to be publicly humiliated by
the fact that this guy sexually use them,
held them down. It's not just
about a woman was assaulted
if a woman's assaulted.
That's one thing. And it is,
it does have to do with our,
our unusual connection with sexuality.
We have this,
this thing about sexuality.
There's this sort of demonization and this
right. Women either had are whores or
uh, you know, or uh, or nuns, right?
Or Saints, you know, like that.
There's kind of like this, uh,
kind of like in the post sexual revolution
era where like not sure if w if women
should be virtuous,
if they should be the same as men,
we're not really sure what
to, what to make. I mean,
I've thought about this though.
Like I would never shame a woman.
Like if somebody came to me and they were
like, you know, I was raped, or like,
you know, my sister or friend or
whatever, I wouldn't be like, you know,
shaming them.
I don't know that like,
I don't know that the shame thing
really is as true as it once was.
Maybe it's still there and
maybe you're right about that,
but like you wouldn't shame a curl,
right?
Like who came to you and said that
she was raped. You pick, oh my God.
Like I'm sorry, like, you know,
anything. I can do a slot. Of course not.
But what kind of man would do
that? I mean, not to say that,
not to say that that wouldn't happen.
Well, this isn't a lot of shitheads out
there though. Whenever you go public,
you expose yourself to
all people and out of all people,
there's going to be a certain percentage
of them that I love to use this term.
The 1% you know,
the 1% everyone always wants to use the
1% in terms of like the judges and the
bankers, but the 1% of people
are just fucking cunts.
And 1% of men,
1% of women,
this is 1% one out of a hundred
magnified on Twitter, aren't they?
They're magnified when you get a
public exposure to millions. Well,
if you're dealing with 300 million people,
the United States population,
whenever the fuck it is,
you're dealing with 3
million cuts and if there's,
and if there's one in a million, there's
still 300 cons. Yeah, that's a lot.
That's a lot. I mean one in a million
is a ridiculously optimistic outlook.
Of course it's way more than that.
It's probably one in a hundred if you
get to be together with a hundred people,
especially when you add anonymity at the
anonymity that the Internet provides or
you don't have the social consequences
of being questioned for your behavior,
your tweets,
or it's like being,
it's like being on the freeway
and being a shitty driver. Right?
Cause nobody can identify. It's the same
kind of thing. There's a lot of that,
but at least they can see you and look
in your eyes and see your car, right.
Your plate down and gives us some jumbled
the series of numbers and letters.
It's your Twitter account, you're
an asshole on it, you know,
and you can do it anonymously
and you can get away with it.
So if you find out that someone has been
accused of something or some woman is a
crime, like rape has been perpetrated
against her, what's the stop?
Some anonymous fuckhead from just
harassing them and going after them.
And a lot of people have like
made of, you know, they've made a,
a strong habit of doing that to
people. Yeah. Well let's take,
let's take it a good example.
Like,
so I was reading John
Krakauer's book and Missoula,
which is like about this campus
rape phenomenon and in Montana,
University of Montana,
this is a phenomenon.
He says there's a phenomenon going on,
but he's at the University of Montana.
He lives in Montana. So I seen him,
he was just interviewing people,
but they're there like five or
six anecdotes of like rapes.
And one of the cases is this guy who was
a football player who in 2012 was found
not guilty of rape. It was like brought
before the courts and everything he was,
he was exonerated and Krakauer wants
has got to be expelled even though the
court system found him innocent
and he's created this like um,
anonymous identity for this chick, her
name, he calls her Washburn, like her,
I forget her first name in the book,
but like there's this case, you know,
University of Montana where the guys
found innocent and even after he's found
innocent, he's still being tortured
with being called a rapist.
He's still being tortured with
calling, you know, being called.
And I think I got to say like
damaging accusations of rape.
Rape is like a serious, terrible crime.
It's like as, as Dershowitz has put it,
it's the most falsely reported crime,
but it's also the most under reported
crime that we sort of have in our society.
Blot. On the other hand, like it should
be a big deal to accuse somebody publicly.
You should, I mean, under
the sixth amendment of the
United States constitution,
you have a right to
confront your accusers.
How can you confront them if the trials
occurring the media without your ability
to even respond to the non, you
know, anonymous allegations.
So it's kind of like,
it's like a trade off thing and it's
really difficult to make the balance.
Anyone who says definitively like I
have the answer for you on this stuff,
she totally full of shit because
it's really hard to know what to do.
You know like should we not write about
the University of Montana case where
this guy was found not guilty because
he's now been found not guilty even though
he may have raped her.
Right. We don't know.
Just because the court
system decides something.
We know there are many cases
where courts get things wrong.
Somebody on Twitter pointed
out something really good,
but I need to adjust the white people
that rioted in the hockey riots have a
Vancouver.
I was actually there for that.
I was there right before that went down.
I left just before the riots. It was,
well I didn't see the riots, but I
had been in the town. I was like,
there's so nice up here.
How the fuck are they riding?
So somebody had a good point.
White people do. Right.
But it's all over sporting events
and it's over relatively quickly.
We're not only that, the people
that riot, we're so fucking stupid.
They were doing it while everyone was
taking pictures and posting it on social
media and a giant chunk
of them went to jail,
like a giant chunk of
them got arrested for it.
Take for you to actually write
it. I've always, I've always,
I asked my wife this the other day,
I was like, well what do you like,
why would we riot honey? You know, like,
I can't imagine a scenario in
which I'm like burning things down,
destroying people's property.
Well, you're not poor, true,
poor and desperate and you don't,
there are lots of poor people. Those,
a downside future like,
right. No, definitely.
But I think that's a big
part of it. I mean the, the,
the writing and the hockey riots,
those are fucking retards.
I think it's a young man thing
too though. For sure. Yeah.
It was all a whole lot of young
women out there rioting a video, uh,
which is making the rounds, um, called
good morning, good morning, Baltimore.
You know, like that old, we did
a video where we took all of the,
the shots of the rioters and put it
to like this music and it's like,
it's really like, it's fucking, it's
perverse, but it kind of funny. Um,
but I think, I dunno man,
like there's something,
I think there's something tribal about
us as people that like, you know, I've,
I've had,
I've had this experience at tri at like
sporting events or like at political
events where you feel
something like overcome you.
And I'm like pretty rational,
you know, nerdy guy, you know, high
Iq and the bell curve kind of thing.
But like there's something if, if I'm
drawn to it and we're all drawn to it,
like then the people who are really like
dumb and poor and don't have a lot of
options and yet they all have smartphones.
Like it gets really scary.
I can certainly, damage can be done. Well,
there's without a doubt there's a certain
aspect of human beings that allows us
to go with the flow of big movements when
there's big things that are happening,
there's horrific things that happened
in large groups and mass groups.
It just wouldn't happen when there's one
person is a weird thing and I think the
sporting events like thing of
the white people that riot.
I think that that is like what I'm
talking about like part of this tribe and
you're just like boils over cause when
you have a whole lot of like you know
shit heads together like we
were talking about earlier,
like 1% of them are going
to be assholes or whatever
and I'm sure it starts really slowly
like one guy break something and then
everyone else starts breaking shit.
Right.
Well think that's also speaks
to what we're talking about,
the incredible difficulty of escaping
from a ghetto because we imitate our
atmospheres and we
maintain our atmosphere.
Atmosphere is boiling over into mad
violence and rioting and looting.
There's a lot of people that just succumb
to that influence and just give in and
be overcome. I don't think we're nearly
as autonomous as we like to think we are.
I think we are a giant super organism
and we have our own individual identities
inside the super organism.
Wilson says that he says we're like
ants like as a species. Um, you know,
the great biologist,
evolutionary biologist, he says
that we're basically a soup.
Well, it's not just us, it's
pretty much every organism.
How do you think those birds fly together
in these giant flocks and go left and
right and move around like,
like, like they're like,
they're all being controlled.
How does it happen with fish?
How does it go with all sorts of animals
that exist in pastoring? Totally. Yeah.
We, we have, you know, we, we,
we have groups and these groups act
as a unit and when the group riots,
I think people become incredibly
compelled to become a part of that.
And it takes amazing
resolve and intelligence if
you're a trapped in that to
avoid the influence of that.
Sure. But like, so like take the case,
like there was a famous sociological
experiment where we took,
we gave blacks in the ghetto.
We gave them like section eight vouchers
to like get the hell out of the ghetto.
Right.
And we started,
it was like an Atlantic article on
this like maybe four or five years ago.
But what happened was was that we gave
all these section eight vouchers to get
out of the ghetto.
Right. And what happened?
Like people got out of the ghetto and
then they started committing crimes like
in their new area. So like
we gave everyone, you know,
like whatever the rental equivalent is
and then you can move into like a nicer
area and they brought the crime with them.
So that just goes to show like how much
it's like a part of you once you grow up
in it or how much it's a part
of your brain. You know, like,
so this book I'm reading right now,
this is like the best book I've read
in like 10 years. It's called sapiens.
And it's about basically
what makes humans like,
what made us different from all the other,
you know,
homos or I guess animal almost.
You know,
I'm a erectus homo
neanderthal or whatever.
And what he says is there's this thing
that we have as humans where we take on
fictions,
like we believe certain isms and that
becomes like most primate species.
It's like, you know, a few people are
in your tribe and are in your group.
You know, like humans. I
think it's like 150 maximum.
That's like the Max size of
uh, of, uh, of a tribe. Um,
but what happens is that we all start
to like believe certain narratives about
the world in our brains.
We're getting kind of like brainwashed
or whatever and then we start to act on
our commitment to that fiction that
we've created. And it's kind of wild.
Like when you think about it, like
there's so many fictions in your society,
so many things you unconsciously
believe so many ism, you know his isms.
But also like things like joint stock
companies or like legal documents.
I mean all of law,
if you think of it as just a fiction,
we all agree on it's
the same kind of thing.
And his book is really kind of like
challenged a lot of my thinking on this
because like, you know, if you're in the,
if you're creating this mindset that
like people are so put upon, so put upon,
so put upon, they'll start to act
like they're so put upon, right?
Cause it's like there they get infected,
their brains get infected and it
becomes really hard to persuade people
particularly it's like
it's pretty self serving.
If you just say like you're in the
ghetto and you're fucked because like,
you know, there are many examples of
people like surviving out of the ghetto,
people moving out of the ghetto.
There are many like human beings are
much more malleable I think then of like,
you know,
escaping from terrible circumstances and
yet what we do as a society as we say,
like, no, you're fucked. Like you're done.
You know, you're never going to end it.
Like we should be like thinking about
waste so we can orient the society.
So they're more options. But like it's
really hard. People are more malleable.
But I disagree that people are more
malleable when it comes to the ability to
escape the ghetto. I think there's
everything is stacked against you.
If you're in that environment financially
it's tacked against you as far as the
behavior that you're imitating,
your atmosphere around all those,
the fear affects too,
like your fear of friends and stuff.
It's not like you live in Irvine and you
know your family's of moderate income
and you figure out a way to make it so
it's nothing that's really weird to me.
Like I did a lot of reporting on the
Ferguson stuff and the thing that was
really weird to me are like where'd
these affluent black kids who are like
coming in like slumming in the
ghettos of Ferguson? And like,
I'd never seen anything like this.
I mean,
so like there were a number of like black
radical activist types of can Chicago
and the suburbs there who basically like,
you know,
black guys who his parents are like
doctors, lawyers, whatever. You know,
like people who like, you
know, not, I mean you know,
not obviously not every black person
is kind of like living in the ghetto.
I mean there are lots of dumb, we
live, you know, whatever. Right.
So what was interesting about this is
there all these cases of like to be like
authentically black.
These kids who were like,
you know when to fancy schools
went to good schools or whatever,
they felt they had to go and participate
in like you know the anti-cop protests
or the,
you know what I mean?
Like but isn't that also possibly because
they recognize that they were lucky
and they want to help maybe yeah,
you could be right.
Like I hadn't thought of it that way.
I think you may be right but
I I maybe on the other hand,
I mean yeah you probably are right
about that to a certain extent.
I'm sure there's a motivation of that
but I also think it's kind of weird too
that your parents give you
all these options, right?
To escape the ghetto and you returned to
the ghetto as like a, you know, to like,
cause trouble, like in their
mind they're not causing trouble.
They're there in their mind they're
trying to enact some sort of change. True.
True. To a certain extent. Yeah. What's
going on Aaron? Greer? Baltimore.
Not Mom beats the mom who rescued.
Uh,
she saw her son on the TV and went after
him. She beating the shit out of them.
I liked, I liked that. I
mean, I think it's good.
I think if people took more
responsibility for their own,
for their family members,
you know, like if you saw,
if you saw like your friend on TV, right?
And you'd be like, dude, like don't write.
I don't like the beading thing though.
I'm not cool on.
That's probably the only way to get this.
He's got a mask on.
Oh yeah. I mean, I don't agree
with the beating either, but fuck,
the whole thing is Iraq.
What do you think's going to
happen in Baltimore? Yeah.
Well ultimately,
I mean I'm sure they have the national
guard's down there now and there was
probably going to Bli on,
so we'll escalate and then like
Ferguson will eventually calmed down.
But do you know what really pisses
me off though and this whole thing,
there are all these people who are like
trying to spin it politically. How so?
Like all of these people were like,
it's true.
Like there hasn't been a Republican
mayor of Baltimore since like the 60s or
whatever, but they're like, liberals
did this, liberalism did this.
Like there are lots of places that are
run by liberals that are like perfectly
fine places to live and go to boulder,
Colorado. Yeah. It's all liberals.
Nobody gives a shit. Everybody's
nicest shit. Or West west side La,
Seattle or Boston, you know,
like Asheville, North Carolina,
liberal places that are great. Yeah. Yeah.
It's not a liberal or Republican thing.
It's a poor people thing. It's a lack
of hope thing. It's a crime thing.
It's a poor people too.
To him of the environment thing.
We have a whole lot of poor
s Asian people like you know,
in the San Gabriel valley,
we have a whole lot of poor ass Mexicans.
We have a poor la boats all sized right
to the heart of what happened in the
first place. It's so fucking
police brutality is. Sure.
I mean we don't know what
the fuck happened. We don't
have a video in this one,
but we do have a video of that guy
running from the cop and getting shot from
behind. Sure. You know we have that one
from South Carolina. Yeah, Walter Scott,
we case. Yeah. You know we
have a series of of that.
We have the 12 year old kid that had the
fucking toy gun where the cops pulled
the car over and just shot him. Sure. We
have a lot to put yourself in that case.
Right. And that example of the Tamir Rice
situation, right. Kid with a fake gun,
fake gun. So that area is like
known for having people with,
with those types of guns,
robbing people. Right.
It's known as like a
really shitty part of town.
You're getting reports of somebody who's
like running around in a park with a
gun,
right?
The kamikaze known for
being an overbearing over
violent cop who was released
from another police force and they
didn't want to have to retrain him.
So desired and another cop, bad
cop, no doubt about it. But,
but in any population of anything,
you're going to get shitty teachers,
good teachers, bad cops,
good cops. You know,
the system that you build should be
built towards like trying to assess the
worst case scenarios. Right? And like
in some of these cases, like, you know,
Darren Wilson is a good example by the
way. People should go see that Ferguson,
the play, like it's getting all
this attention. The Guy, yeah,
there's this Guy Phil Mcaleer, he's like
a friend of mine, he's an Irish guy,
he's a journalist and he
did verbatim theater of, um,
of the Ferguson stuff where they just
read the grand jury transcript and it's
caused like all this controversy
and craziness. It's here in la.
And it's like totally not even political.
They're just like reading this.
But it's political because they're
reading the script, you know what I mean?
It's like one of those kinds of
situations and it's really fascinating.
Like I'd read the grand jury
transcripts and everything,
but to see like actual actors and human
beings like talk about the, you know,
what actually happened,
like,
and then obviously the actors are
making choices and whatnot, like stress,
certain words cause we
just have a transcript.
But it was like pretty
riveting stuff of crazy.
But like if you look at like
the Darren Wilson thing,
it's like a perfect example of this.
Like we don't really know what happened.
Like what, we definitely know that that
kid punched him. The kid's dead. Yeah.
The kid punched him and the kid was shot
at close range while I was trying to
get the guy's gun. Yeah, we know.
We know the autopsy all that's true.
But like we don't know what was said.
We don't know what they had for breakfast
that well. You know what I mean?
Like we don't know. No. And
the thing is like we as humans,
like Ben Gazi is another example.
This,
like all these events happen and people
just go on like project their views,
their experiences, their life,
their whatever unto them.
And did they come kind of like roar shock
techs are like inkblots and we should
be really like hesitant.
Like it's true that co that blacks
are disproportionately killed by cops.
It's also true that blacks
disproportionately commit
a lot of crime, right?
Like if you, if you look at
like the Asian stats, right?
If you compare the Asian to the
black stats in terms of crime,
it's like night and day, right? Right.
But you're also dealing with people
that again grew up and are a sub.
There are product of these environments
and disproportionately black,
disproportionately black in,
in these crime ridden,
horrific environment.
I mean like if you have all these housing
projects and the hell hole of like not
having fathers around, I'm
with you on all of this, right?
But I think we need to be like,
I think these,
these communities are so intractable
and the solutions that we've offered for
many, many years of like
they're not solving the problem.
And I don't know that we can ever really
solve them. And that's kind of like,
to me, that's the most terrifying thing
about this is that it's just a permanent
feature of modern life.
Don't think there's enough effort
put to try to solve the problem.
And I think the,
the clear root of that problem is,
I described it yesterday in terms
of if we are a super organism,
we look at it and look at our,
our,
our country as a microcosm
of the world super organism.
What's the issue with this organism?
Will,
the issue is the organism has some
six spots. It's not dealing with,
the way I described it yesterday is if
you have a staph infection and you're
angry at the staph infection for
not healing, sure. Right? I mean,
it's like a fucking
stupid staph infection.
Why don't you pull yourself
up by your bootstraps? I like,
but if you look at like say
like a staph infection, right?
Like if you're a super organism or
whatever, we're all gonna die, right?
Like at some point like
we're going to get, you know,
we're going to get inoperable
brain cancer, whatever,
something's going to happen to us.
Like that's part of life.
Like I think we undersell how much of
life is just playing shitty and like we're
always like,
as like Americans,
like we're always trying to like
solve these problems. Right? But like,
like sometimes things are just not
solvable, right? Like sometimes,
so this is certainly solvable. This
is, you're more optimistic than I am.
We're optimistic.
But you're talking about like we've,
you have a broken arm but he then
we'll fuck it. I'm going to die anyway.
Why go to the Donald? But I mean that's
essentially what you're saying. No, no,
not exactly though. I'm
saying like there's certain
things, let's take a cancer,
right? Inoperable cancer. Right.
And we're a staff weren't, you know,
there are citizen and nonporous but there
are certain ghettos aren't inoperable.
I mean how would you, how
would, how would we solve that?
We would go home my money and go,
fuck, it should make an effort.
How about some effort?
There's almost being done.
If you look at like Dorchester
while I used to live, right. Um,
and how shitty and rundown it was.
You know,
they're putting in all these new schools,
they're putting in school choice things.
It's charter school is all that. I'm all,
some people get upset at
that. I'm all right. Yeah.
And then they get pissed off because
they're real estate prices go up. Right.
So it's like, and then, yeah,
poor people have always gotten
fucked throughout human history.
Like it's just a shitty part of existence.
You know, like, and I don't know,
so many of the solutions we offered,
we built housing projects to help
people with affordable housing. Right.
Then they became like dens of crime,
you know, like affordable housing.
It just makes it cheaper for people
to live in a fucked up place.
It doesn't change the fucked up place.
You have to figure out a way somehow or
another, and I'm not a social engineer,
but I think there has to be some sort
of a way to look at these communities.
And there's six spots.
These are,
these are areas where there's a
disease and that disease is crime.
And poverty and you have to figure
out a way to make it better.
And one of the ways to make it better,
as you got to shine a light on it,
you've got to pay attention to it and
you got to put a lot of money into it.
You gotta,
you gotta put a lot of money into it
in terms of trying to build up that
community,
trying to help those people.
But if you look at like the La public
schools or you look at some of the public
school systems up there, we pour shitloads
of money into them. Yeah. Awful there.
We get nothing for the money. See,
to me, what's scary about this,
like I talked to my family in Baltimore,
like if,
you know what's scary to me about this
is that like what happens is that they
get political leadership and it's
not a Democrat Republican thing.
People are trying to put it in that Lens.
It's they get political leadership.
I mean the mayor before this last one,
like when to jail was indicted for
corruption. They get these really corrupt,
thuggish bad people. And I'm not saying
that thuggish cause they're black,
you know I'm saying they're thugs
because they're thugs, right? They,
they prey on their own people and they
pray in their own communities and it's
really like sick. And I don't know how
you solve that. If we're going to have,
like, if we're going to have a society
where people can vote and elect people,
like, I mean, so much of the
political system is bullshit.
Even in like the wealthier
parts of the country, right?
We still have to deal with assholes who
like pretend to represent us who are
whatever party. And yet like these people
have no choice. They're often like,
you know, the people who
get elected or like corrupt,
they're bad people and yet
like they're supposed to,
I mean you can't get a good system out
of a corrupt yeah. Group of people.
You're just not going to happen. Right. I
see what you're saying. And I think the,
uh, you're ultimately correct and I think
that, I mean, what do you do? Do you do,
do you send in like the National Guard?
I'm like martial law.
No cause it's a millet. There's gotta
be some way to enhance the communities.
There's gotta be some way to enhance
the education is going to be some,
there's gotta be some way. I'm not
the guy you, no, no, no, no. My time,
and I think this is something that
needs to be looked at objectively over
longterm. It's, it's gotta
be a project where you,
he's somehow or another half to revitalize
and reenergize these areas and then
deal with the fact that the momentum of
the past is so goddamn strong in these
places and they've been fucked for
decade after decade after decade,
generation after
generation, after generation of people
born to this thing with very little
recourse. I think Obama's right. I mean,
I don't agree with Obama
and all that stuff,
but I think Obama's right
when he says that, you know,
he quotes Faulkner saying that the
past isn't pass. It's not, you know,
at the past is not finished. It's not
even past. Yeah, you're right. Like,
I mean there is something to be said
for this being a legacy of slavery.
It's a legacy of like failed
urban policies of the 60s.
It's a legacy of like,
we're always like kind
of dependent on history.
Like history is still very much alive.
And some of these places, you know,
well it's so recent as we're
talking about slavery being 1865,
that's just not that long ago and
50 years. It's nothing. It's a blip.
Um,
the University of Virginia Case,
is there any repercussion against
the girl who filed the fee? She's,
she kind of dropped out of school.
I think she works at last I checked,
she works at a hair salon and it's
just sad. The whole thing is sad.
Like it's a lot of people think
I take like joy and having,
I take joy and like exposing the truth
always. But I don't take joy in like,
you know, these people whose property was
destroyed. This girl's life is ruined.
I mean, to a certain extent,
there's, that's like the
social costs. Like I had to,
I had a responsibility to like make it
public who this person was. Um, I think,
but um,
it's sad.
Like the whole situation is kind of sad
and I know there's some people right now
who want to do like a more comprehensive
report and I'm probably going to help
with that going into more stuff on
Sabrina Reuben Eardley but they're,
I mean their fraternities,
their football teams,
there's all this stuff that's under attack
all throughout the country right now
by the social justice warriors. And um,
it, it's going to be quite frightening.
I think it's going to be, I think it's
going to intensify before it gets, and it,
what we have right now
is we have a war and I,
and I hate the word war because like,
and I hate even the warriors
thing of the social justice thing.
I prefer like social justice activists
because they're active there.
It's not a war. Like we're not shooting
each other like thank God. Right.
But I think there really is
like a political electronic
civil war going on right
now between people who have narrative
based views of the universe and people who
are fact based and and and their big,
excuse me,
they're basically at loggerheads and
I don't know how long this can endure.
You know like you talked
about like slavery and the
civil war. Like Lincoln said,
a house divided against
itself can't stand,
I don't know how we have journalists
on the one hand who present facts and
figures and trying to like understand
the world and then others who try and
basically preach and sell like
crazy narrative the world.
I don't know how this coexists,
wow.
I think it coexists in that they're there.
This conflict and the debate and the
discussion people like you or people,
like many of the people that are
listening to this now or watching this or
people that are discussing this right
now on Twitter and arguing pro and con
[inaudible], these subjects get vetted
out. They get discussed, they get debated,
they get bound, you know,
bounced back and forth.
And some people will change their minds.
And some people were will be reinforced
by this conversation and some people be
angered
by this conversation. Some people
will anger that I have you on. Yeah.
And I saw that it's kind of, what do you
think is up with that? The, the rape, um,
the outing people.
I think people need to saying their names.
I think that's a big,
that's part of it.
But I think I also think I've
said some stuff, you know,
I've said sums up where I've changed my
mind on it and I'm also said stuff on
Twitter. So I see Twitter as a
way of sparking conversations.
Like a lot of the stuff that I put on
Twitter I don't necessarily always agree
with and I'm not trying to be a
troll like necessarily, right.
I'm trying to like force conversations
that I want to have that no one else has
having,
well you was the one you have like name
the names of celebrities that are a
support the Baltimore
riots. Yeah. Yeah. No.
What I want to do with that is I want
people to understand like, you know,
there are people out there
who there should be a
consequence for like supporting
it. Well, I'm not saying anybody
support any fucking riot.
There are people out
there like Sally Code.
I mean there are people out there who
are saying them Saturday cone, I'm sure.
I think she's on a MSNBC or she's on CNN
or something. She says riots or, yeah.
Oh yeah. There are people who
are saying that the riots,
the response to the riots are a
political thing. It's an uprising.
It's an insurrection.
Same people who defended the Ferguson
stuff is a uprising against the police.
Against the system. Right. Don't
you think though, in some ways the,
the what the benefit of it is, is that
we're all forced to discuss this now.
We're all forced to look at the Sherry
of Baltimore, this horrible area.
And my friend John Rollo lives in
Baltimore and he said, fucking,
he says there's parts of Baltimore
that are just God damn crazy.
And we're seeing it right now.
I mean a lot of people were exposed to
it from the wire and they weren't aware
of the problem of the wires I tweeted
the other day is that there are far too
many white people on it. I mean that's
what, that's what this is showing to us.
I mean, yeah there's, there's some truth
to that. But you know, and like if you're,
my cousin likes to say if your,
if your show,
if your city is known for the wire
and homicide and all this other stuff,
it's probably not good. Well
it's definitely a fucked
up part of the country.
It's, and there's many areas that
are like it. Detroit is pretty,
God damn fucked up.
Tons of Philly Chicago out there.
There's some places that could blow
and there's some places now because of
youtube and all of these videos that
everyone has a rather a phones that can
take videos,
you can expose all sorts of shit
that shouldn't be happening.
But police brutality and then there's
a reaction to it. Do you know, like,
so I've been thinking about this, I
totally agree with you, but nature,
the nature of like everyone has
these, right, and how awesome that is,
how powerful it is.
Andrew Breitbart,
others have talked about how awesome this
technology is. But to a certain extent,
when I turn on the camera, right, you're
turning on the camera on me. You know,
we've got this audio equipment
people change, right? So
like to a certain extent,
when I'm,
when you're running around filming stuff,
some people are performing for
the camera, no doubt. Right?
That's escalates because of that.
And I don't know what you do
about that cause you can't,
you can't on the one hand sensor
it because if you censor it,
like that's evil and wicked.
Like we're against that.
We have a first amendment for a reason
we want to show. But on the other hand,
like, you know, it's like the, the, what
is it that, um, uh, Paredo a factor.
There's an effect where basically you
watching something causes people to change
their behavior.
If you watch your employees
are gonna change their behavior, well,
it just is. I don't think there's,
I mean it just is, it is a fact. No
solving it. Yeah. It doesn't seem,
it seems to be a new reality.
Just like how do you get away from the
fact that everyone has a cell phone, you,
you don't,
unless an asteroid hits and we have a
massive cataclysmic disaster that shuts
down the power grid and there's no more,
no more monitoring or whatever,
unless that had walking dead style because
there's not really much you're going
to be able to do this, this,
this is our new reality.
Just like the people that live before
cars could never have imagined being able
to drive across the country in four days,
just like the people existed before.
Planes can never imagine
it doing it in six hours.
You're just not going to change that
unless you change the entire civilization.
This is going to have to happen for
that. Something new. Yeah, totally agree.
So I don't think we should necessarily
concentrate on that as much as we should
concentrate on what are the lessons that
we can learn from all this and what I
think ultimately we have to concentrate
on these areas, whether they're Ferguson,
which is a very high crime area,
has been for a long time,
or whether it's Baltimore,
there's, there's areas of
the country that need help.
And the people that grow up in their
grow up in these horrible crime ridden
environment that really don't have
any other recourse. They don't,
or a lot of recourse I should say. Yeah.
I don't know what to do about it. I mean,
like one of the things that,
one of the things that I kind of
feel bad about this, you know,
like everyone's going after this,
you know,
this woman Stephanie Rawlings
Blake for saying, you know,
we need a space to destroy. I went after,
I know a lot of people are going after,
um, you need a space to
destroy. Did you see this?
So she did a video where
she said, um, I actually,
the video that we did have
a good morning Baltimore,
where with the riots we started with this
opening thing where she said, you know,
we need a safe space
for people to destroy,
for writers to destroy and people are
going after. She said she misspoke.
I don't know.
I'd give her the benefit of the doubt
cause she's been kind of like reluctant
and bringing in the police
to basically solve the riots.
But basically I feel really bad for her
because like this is a really tough job
to be mayor. Like, you know, like
I get to be a journalist, you know,
we get to basically just like bloviate
and bullshit about this, right?
Like we're not the ones like in these
cities like making these decisions.
Like I always try and put myself
in the position of people,
you know what I'm saying?
Like I was trying to put
myself in their chair and like,
it's a shitty situation and I don't see
any situation short of like bringing the
military, which I, you know, I'm not a
big fan of military industrial complex,
but like that's what
they're going to have to do.
They said did the same thing with the La
riots here, right? Like, um, you know,
the Koreans were defending themselves
and their rear property. Um,
and they can't really do that in Maryland
because they don't have concealed
carry and they have a lot of guns,
gun restrictions and people who
are in the kind of white areas,
they are kind of liberals then
wouldn't have guns anyways. Um,
but what I find really interesting about
this and like is that how quick people
are to judge our elected leaders
and we should judge them. But like,
it's a hard life.
Like it's a shitty situation that these
people are in and I guarantee you like
Stephanie Rawlings Blake,
you know, the mayor there,
she never thought she'd
have to deal with this
shit. You know, like it's
tough thing. It's a tough gig.
While we try to make sure that we're
protected from the cars and other things
that were going on.
We also gave those who wished.
What does that the space to destroy?
Yeah.
There's this face right there,
Huh?
Wow.
The mayor is not saying that she asks
people to give space to people who sought
to create violence and he suggestion
otherwise we are misinterpretation of her
statement or statements sucks,
which is not a good statement.
What she's saying within the statement
and it ended the video itself like be
people should watch it.
People should make up their own.
I think what happens a lot of these
situations is that the police,
the the activist, there's like a view
among the sort of like, you know,
municipality run system. There's a
view that like, hey, we can't bring,
I can't bring the cops in cars.
If we bring the Compson,
it'll just inflame people because like,
you know,
it's the same thing with the video camera.
If you could put a cop and a ghetto
environment, people hate the cops.
Like they're going to react, right? Like,
and so their view is like we shouldn't
bring the police but then you don't bring
in the police and then the riots get
even more out of hand and it's like,
it's like you can't win situation.
I'm of the opinion that
when we look at these I,
these isolated instances, any of them
we, we look at it and we say, okay,
wow this is horrible.
The world is fucked.
But I think that what's going on with
all of these incidences is we're reacting
to problems that we have in our society.
We have, we're reacting to these,
these areas that need attention and
these explosive events that cause whether
it's riots or protests or marches or
all of these things are ultimately good
because I think they cause people to focus
on these areas that are convenient to
ignore.
I told him, I mean I agree with you
that he does spotlight this stuff.
I had just not, I hope
you're right. Like, I mean,
like if I go pray that you're correct,
that we can solve a lot of this stuff,
but like we've been dealing, like not
every society gets a do over, right?
Like some societies are humble are
fucked from the beginning. Yeah. Right.
That it's just a question of it playing
out, right? Like, you know, you could,
we're also the first society that's had
this kind of access to information ever.
The history that we're, I mean if you're,
if you're, there are two ways to bet,
right? There's the pessimistic kind
of like, Shit's going to go down,
all that kind of thing. Which
like, temperamentally, I'm
probably more that way. Um,
but you could be right. I'm not, I'm not,
I don't dispute you like there's
shit that we'd like, I mean,
the fact that I have this effect that
I have a career because of this exists,
right?
And the fact that I'm able to disrupt bad
stuff on the Internet and cause things
to change, it's all awesome.
All good. Like I'm all for
it. But I think there's a,
the same technology that allows us to
spotlight government abuses can often, uh,
you know, in the wrong hands can be
used to basically promote and do riots.
I mean like,
well,
there's not going to be immune.
It's not ultimately the solution.
But I think that if you look
at the course of human history,
there's no denying that this is
the safest time to live ever. Yeah,
it's awesome.
And it's also very difficult to deny
that the United States is one of the most
innovative governments,
the most innovative countries ever.
It's only been around a couple of hundred
years and look at all the crazy shit
that's happened here. I mean, this is
the, this is awesome. This is so cool.
The forefront of the world when it
comes to culture. I mean, I feel like I,
I feel like every day with all the
new technology, everything, I mean,
I grew up with the Internet. Like
I remember waking up one day, fuck,
there was Wikipedia like you,
you know, like I remember like,
I remember my first Google search.
Like I grew up like
basically with the Internet.
My point was that I'm with
you all to more itself.
It's fucked as it is as fuck
does. It's been, you know,
it's just these people
that grew up generation,
generation after generation
live and in poverty.
It's only been around a
couple of hundred years total.
This is a new situation,
but a completely new country.
Ultimately when you look at the,
the, the history of the world. Yeah.
And you look at like
shit like crack babies,
which we thought was
going to be huge problem,
turns out to not have been
a bigger problem. Right?
Like there's a lot of stuff,
there's a lot of room for optimism and
even things like social justice warriors
are people that are going after college
campus scenarios where they believe that
there's men that are committing
rape ultimately what they're doing,
even if I disagree with their methodology
or disagree with their ideology that
they're pushing forth in
favor of objective truth.
Ultimately it's to try to stop crime,
stop people from being victimized. It's a
trend. That's a good trend. Yeah, totally.
I mean, even if it's done in
the wrong way, I mean, look,
but the road to hell is paved with
good intentions. Right. By you,
you son of a bitch. I'm not honestly, it's
true. It is true. Nobody says like, Yo,
I'm the villain. Right. Like nobody
ever says there are a few guys,
but they're pro wrestlers. Yeah,
yeah. And, but they didn't.
And they do it as a branding thing.
Yeah. Listen, I gotta get out of here,
but I really, I really enjoyed this
conversation and I appreciate it.
And for all the people
that judged you coming in,
I hope they gave you a shot and
let you take the first song.
I'm happy to come back anytime. Let's
do it again. Do it again. Definitely.
Thank you.
And you can get ahold of him and send all
your mean shit or nice things to chuck
c Johnson,
uh,
on Twitter and got news.com
is your website and a,
I think you're very thoughtful
person and thank you for having me.
I appreciate it. It's nice to meet you
in real life. Nice to meet you too.
Thank you. All right. You fuck.
See you soon. Bye. Bye. Big Kiss.
Okay.
Yeah.