B,
two,
one.
Hello,
Steven.
Hello Joe.
Welcome.
Thank you.
Thanks for coming,
man.
I really appreciate it.
Thanks for having me.
I've enjoyed a bunch of your shit
online,
man.
You've got some really fucking cool
articles and some great ideas.
And uh,
we were talking about,
um,
the other day,
a friend of mine,
we're talking about creativity and the
source of creativity and how to
cultivate creativity and I stumbled
across something that you had on your
website about creativity,
about different methods or different
ways to try to inspire your creativity
or shock your system into creativity.
I'm always really impressed with people
who take things that I've always like,
man,
I wonder why or when my ideas come from.
And then I go,
oh,
check out this guy.
He actually kind of broke this shit down
and tried to figure out what was the
source of.
A lot of these ideas is aware where
these,
these groovy moments of spontaneous,
you know,
just just like a blossoming of ideas
where they come from.
My mechanistic,
I like to know how the shit works.
Yeah,
I've seen that by talking to you just in
the past 10 minutes.
You've got like order,
so it's a show,
but thank you.
But you have like,
you know,
like when I was talking about you want
cream in your coffee,
like no drink should have one thing,
scotch neat.
You know,
coffee,
black,
you've got,
you've got order or opinions.
Yes.
But in your mind there it's very rigid,
right?
I mean it there liberating structures to
me.
I do everything like that.
I do six things in my life I've ever.
If it doesn't fall into those
categories,
I don't do it.
You know,
I mostly just at discovered years ago
that the only stuff I've failed at was
the stuff when I was too over extended
and I was quitting,
I would give up half way,
but if I could stick to it always led to
success.
So I was like,
okay,
let's pare it down to essential.
Well,
and whenever life gets crazy for me,
my first instinct is go small,
get small.
One of the hardest things I think about
being married and running an animal
sanctuary,
my wife is.
There's so many dependents on me now.
When stuff gets difficult,
I can no longer get small.
You can't minimalize and get down to a
duffle bag.
I have a friend of mine,
Steve Maxwell,
he literally lives out of a,
like a dry sack,
you know,
one of those dry socks that you could
just throw in the river and that's like,
here's a Duffel bag.
That's his whole thing.
He Lives Hotel to hotel travels all over
the world,
teaching people a strength and
conditioning routines and wellness and
health.
That's all he does.
He just,
he has nothing.
He has no items.
He has a like a ipad and he's got a
watch.
When I was writing my first book,
it was right out of college before I
went to Grad school.
Uh,
I lived in a place called anti matters,
one of the largest performance and video
gallery video galleries in the world.
It was in San Francisco and huge space.
20 people living there.
But I lived above the tool room on a,
a plank of wood,
the size of a Volkswagen microbus you
like,
crawled over my bed to get to my desk
and my clothes were on one side and
there were books on the other that was
it.
And it was small and tiny and you know,
crazy.
But it was a great,
you know,
I got to spend a couple of years there
and it where I started writing my first
novel and it was just wonderful owning
nothing and being that free.
That seems like one of those things
where it sounds like a really good idea
if you don't have to do it forever.
Like if someone said,
uh,
this is how I'm going to live for
awhile,
you be like,
Ooh,
cool.
But if you said this is how I'm going to
live for the rest of my life,
and be like,
oh,
that poor,
fuck weird.
Right?
Yeah.
It's always a good thing to do.
When I was 18,
19,
20,
whatever it was,
now you know,
I,
you know,
come back and see my crib,
honey.
It's,
yeah,
that wouldn't work.
But like this idea that you have of like
coffee black,
but do you,
do you vacillate at all?
Do you vary?
I do.
Every now and again I'm down.
I got to go from starbucks or something.
No,
I actually would like,
I have an urge to punch people and they
ordered that crap.
Really?
Why?
I just cause it's Yummy.
Delicious.
I believe you do believe you.
I do know I'll be an asshole.
I get that.
But no,
it just like I walk in,
I'm like he takes them 17 minutes to
order their coffee and 20 minutes to,
you know,
make their coffee and I'm sitting there
and I just want like a small cup of
coffee,
black place.
But let's be honest,
if you're ordering coffee from
starbucks,
you have shitty tasting coffee anyway.
Their coffee tastes terrible.
True.
That if you're going to,
you're going to get burnt coffee for the
most part.
The thing about starbucks is it's
convenient and consistent,
but it's not good.
Right?
What are you measuring against?
Are you measuring,
install their other copy?
Are you talking about what was there
before starbucks?
We,
yeah.
Well,
well you can get diner coffee,
which is even worse.
Right.
One thing that starbucks does have is
that weird machine.
What the fuck is that called?
Is a compressed clover clover?
Yeah.
It's like a.
it's ridiculously expensive machine.
I think it might cost 50 or $60,000.
It might be even more than that.
And starbucks bought up the patent for
them and the guys who invented it,
some series geniuses,
dis.
They were coffee dorks and they said,
okay,
let us find out what is the exact
correct temperature for each individual
being program a bruce cycle where you
brew it for the exact correct time for
each individual being.
Obviously it's subjective,
but they got it down to a science,
so inside starbucks is almost the anti
starbucks,
so you have your regular starbucks drip,
which is almost always burnt to a crisp
and tastes bitter and then they have
this machine.
It'll come on a second.
This machine that clover and it's a
digitally programmed a poor.
That stuff in there,
you could only get it at starbucks.
Now the water comes out.
It's heated to the exact correct
temperature.
They stir it with a whisk and then it
works on a vacuum and as it goes down
and presses this thing it the grinds
come up to the top and you have like
this hockey puck of grinds,
so like it'll brew it for the exact,
you know,
one minute,
15 seconds that this program,
Ethiopian coffee should be brewed for.
Or if you have some sort of Colombian or
some,
you know,
whatever the coffee is,
does,
does it know like you're throwing in.
Yes.
You program it like you,
you know,
you whatever coffee it is,
whatever type of coffee.
It has a different individual settings
for that type of coffee.
So then it brews it and then when the
six seconds is up,
see it lifts up like this and that's the
grinds it or the grounds rather.
And then the coffee comes out and it is
really good and the coffee comes out the
perfect coffee cup size and then the top
thing when it comes up,
it's like this.
A hockey puck have used up coffee
grounds.
Do we know why it's called the clover?
That's a weird name for a coffee
machine.
It is weird,
I don't know,
maybe someone just really likes clovers
and they invented it,
but then you use a little squeegee,
clean that sucker off and that's a wrap
and you know,
soon there'll be homeless guys cleaning
off the coffee for you.
Do you think.
So it's a new market for the squeegee
men.
Oh,
squeegee thing.
Yeah.
Nobody knows about that.
La doesn't have the squeegee people.
Too many guns to anything.
I think after the dire wolf wolf
incident,
when the first freeway killer,
I think people got dire wolf.
That's what they called them.
There was a grateful dead song called
dire wolf,
but it was one of the early freeway
shooters.
Oh,
out here.
Out here.
And I think that sort of like in la,
like we don't want anybody coming.
There are cars because was there one
freeway shooter?
Was there more than one or more than
one?
A friend of mine,
uh,
um,
it did a little story about him as a pro
skier and he got,
he was driving through the Sierra Nevada
mountains is 20 years ago,
25 years ago.
And somebody,
some snipers perched up on a bridge and
put a bullet into his heart.
Craziest part is he pulled off the
highway,
found a fire station and like walked in
and like collapsed on a table and had
been shot in the heart.
Just dropped.
Holy Shit.
Did they catch the guy?
I don't think they ever caught him.
What a crazy impulse
to just decide you're going to make your
life more exciting in this moment by
taking another person's life.
Very,
very strange,
strange thing.
Thing that happens every now and again.
I mean that's a reoccurring phenomenon.
It's super,
super rare,
which is why the people with guns get so
frustrated when someone does something
like that because they say,
well,
the access to guns is not what causes
this.
Someone has to be sick in the head in
order to do this in the first place and
you have millions and millions and
millions of legal gun owners who
wouldn't even consider doing something
like this,
but every now and then someone gets on
top of a rock and puts those cross hairs
on a person just for whatever fucking
reason.
Some strange chemical imbalance,
some strange combination of a fucked up
childhood and very depressing life and
neurochemistries all out of whack.
You gotta.
I mean I don't.
It's five percent or 10 percent of the
number.
I can't remember which one it is,
but it's psychotic.
Just,
you know,
just happens.
So if you've got that portion of the
population that you know
is crazy and doesn't feel empathy,
makes you wonder if we should have guns
or not.
Well it definitely does,
but then it makes you wonder,
well,
they're not going to follow the rules.
Maybe we should have guns just for them
fuckers.
Fair point.
You never know.
There's like many things in life to
really is no ultimate answer.
Have so many variables going on there.
That is true.
That's why black coffee's not always the
way to go.
Sometimes throw a little cream in that
thing,
man.
Just mix it up a little Stevia.
No,
it's got.
I get it.
A little like Ave,
you know,
jack and coke occasionally.
You know,
I understand just every now and okay.
Then we'll go out later.
We'll have pina coladas.
That'd be fine.
There'll be blended,
there'll be frothy.
You'll have an umbrella to become mine.
Umbrellas.
Dude,
I'm,
I'm comfortable with my own masculinity.
I will.
I will drink a cosmopolitan boat.
Drinks.
Who drinks here?
There's something about those that are
very unmanly.
You're not supposed to be enjoying the
actual taste of a sugary sweet things if
you're a manly.
No,
absolutely not.
Especially not if they have alcohol.
You don't kick ass and drink strawberry
Daiquiris.
It's a contradiction in term.
It seems like you could do it if you
were like the rock though.
Yeah,
I mean,
who's going to have Mike Tyson once
daughter Strawberry Daiquiri on backing
him up.
Yeah.
If like you get to a certain level of
manliness,
you could just take it completely the
other way.
Absolutely.
Wearing clogs.
You just go off,
wear a kilt.
Nobody gives a fuck.
So,
um,
this,
this article that he wrote about
creativity,
do you remember which one was called?
Which one of you're looking at him?
I do not know the.
You had a bunch of different things
listed as a various things that people,
you know,
do northern.
It was long haul creativity and that was
it,
so I was looking at kind of a strange
topic because it turns out very few
people have looked at it and I wasn't.
So there's a lot of work that's been
done.
We can talk about it.
I'm on,
how do I be more creative in the moment?
Right now I'm working on this project,
whatever it is,
but I started getting curious about,
well,
what does it take to be super creative
over the course of a career over 10
years,
20 years,
30 years,
40 years.
And I started to realize that there's a
lot of kind of points in the life of a
creative that nobody talks about.
Places we get creative ended up getting
derailed roadblocks.
I wanted to start taking a look at that.
It may be my next book,
not sure,
but something I've been poking at.
Do you?
Uh,
do you follow Stephen King it all the
writer?
Yeah.
Every now and then.
And I like his book on writing a book
and reading.
Yeah,
that's a really interesting one because
he kind of,
you know,
a lot of those people that are super
successful and very,
I mean he's probably one of the most
prolific writers ever.
They have this sort of like just show up
mentality like that.
You people have all these ideas of what
needs to be in place in order for them
to be creative.
And Stephen King in a lot of ways is
saying just fucking do it.
Just sit down every day and do it and
this is what you do.
You are a writer and this is what you do
and you sit down,
you don't make excuses.
And he went over all the different
authors that had 19 kids and you know,
put out 50 books and it's just got to do
it.
And we have,
have you read the war of Art Steve
Pressfield's book,
which is amazing in that regard too
because he kind of breaks down.
It's a very small book.
It's an easy read for anybody who's
interested in it,
but he breaks down all the different
variables that come into play where you
give yourself out and excuses.
And he calls it resistance and beating
that resistance and forcing yourself to
show up.
And then the rewards come for me,
it's wake up at 3:34
AM and I like to be.
I like to be writing before my brain is
even awake.
I want to be writing within four minutes
of getting out of bed because I don't
want,
you know,
when you sleep,
your brainwaves dropped down kind of to
the Alpha Theta,
borderline alphas,
creative state.
And if you wake all the way up,
your brain waves are going to jump all
the way back up to Beta.
So I don't want that to happen.
I want to keep my brainwaves in that
kind of create a face.
So I don't.
I never check email first,
never do any of that stuff.
I want to immediately get out of bed,
get to my office,
have the coffee brewing,
and then be writing instantly.
That is a very.
That's a very interesting choice.
I like it.
It's very smart.
Trust.
But God damn dude,
3:30
AM.
I don't think it's every,
every writer,
every writer.
I don't want to say ever writer.
Most of the writers I know tend to find
time to write when nobody else is awake.
Either they do it late night or I just
happen to do it early because I.
it's an old habit.
When I was living in San Francisco and
coming up and I was starting as a
journalist,
I was writing my books also Edward who
is young and hungry.
I had editors in New York would start
to,
you know,
they were in their twenties to and they
were,
you know,
they'd get in,
they'd start calling me at 8:30
in the morning their time,
which in California was 5:30
in the morning.
The minute an editor called me and said,
hey,
I need you to do this.
I was young.
I was hungry.
I was poor.
I one of the work with the answer was
yes,
I'm going.
So I wanted to be able to write my books
before that,
so I just started getting up earlier and
earlier.
That's a.
it's probably the best way to do it
because I do the opposite.
I do it when my kids are asleep,
my wife's asleep when everybody's
asleep,
that's when I hit the bong and then go
crazy,
but oftentimes I'll be five,
six hours in and then it'll be 5:00
in the morning and then I stopped and
then I'm freaked out and I just lay in
bed with my eyes open,
going over all the different things that
I just wrote.
Well,
that's the.
That's the other reason if I'm,
you know it.
The good news is my.
Most of my writing has probably done at
least by noon,
right.
I'll right from four to 8:00
AM.
Then I get some exercise,
I'll come back,
I'll do another session,
I'll get some more exercise,
but at the end of the day I can shut it
down because I feel like,
okay,
I thought everything through.
I've done everything I possibly can so I
can actually like get some sleep and
started again.
I've heard a lot of people say that like
they'll take a break and then they'll go
for like a long hike,
like,
or they'll do some,
some something that's only mildly
exerting.
So there's again,
back to creativity,
so you know,
I do some work on flow states being in
the zone.
Optimals definitely want to talk to you
about that.
And one of the things we know is there's
something called exercise induced
transient hypofrontality.
Ooh,
I like the fancy term transient
hypofrontality.
So when we're in flow,
one of the things that causes it is,
and this is why your sense of self sort
of disappears in flow and why time
passes strangely,
is your prefrontal Cortex,
the part of your brain that right back
here that governs most of your higher
cognitive functions,
executive functions,
sense of morality since,
uh,
will complex planning,
long term decision making,
blah,
blah.
Turns off,
inflow shuts down.
That portion of the brain shuts down.
Transient meaning temporary hypo.
Hypo is the opposite of hyper.
H.
Ypo means to slow down,
to shut down in front prefrontal Cortex,
a transient hypofrontality when you
exercise,
right?
You've low grade physical exercise,
you're walking,
going for a hike,
25 minutes.
And you know this feeling,
you're brain gets quiet,
right?
Everything starts to sit down.
That's exercise induced transient
hypofrontality.
So you can sort of walk yourself into a
low grade flow state.
So it's really,
it's a great reset if you've been doing
something creative and you didn't get
into flow and it was frustrating.
This is a way to sort of reset your
brain and start over and if you did get
into flow and as a really vibrant
writing session,
here's another way to chill it out and
start over.
Now this area of the brain that quiets
down because you're.
You're no longer second guessing
yourself.
You no longer thinking about the,
you know,
whether this is the right thing to do or
that,
that does that have to,
does that have,
do you have to be doing something that
you've done many,
many times?
We've carved these sorts of paths of
recognition,
like say like if you were a guy who is
really into running and you run all the
time and like this is like once you
start running is your body's like,
hey,
we run and this is what we did.
We already know how to do this.
And so then you can get into that sort
of strange flow state.
Is that what it is?
So there's a couple of different answers
to that and probably the truthful answer
is we're not 100 percent certain,
but here's what we know.
Usually flow is what happens when you've
let.
You've automatized a whole bunch of
skills,
right?
And they come together for the first
time.
Automatize means you've just passed them
to your conscious mind,
your subconscious,
so you now know how to do them,
right?
You no longer learning the skills.
Usually what happens with flow is when
you take like three or four of those
automized skills and bring them together
for the first time and everything sort
of levels up.
So that's typically how it happens.
But you see things with like action
sports,
right?
People go snowboarding for the first
time and you know the first couple of
hours where they don't know what they're
doing.
It's awful.
They're falling all over the place,
but by the end of the day,
because snowboarding's a fairly easy
sport to get down,
like the first time you can actually
start gliding down the mountain.
By the end of the day,
you'll see people get into flow that you
know and they'll have these really deep,
powerful flow states.
One of the reasons is because risk is a
flow trigger risk spikes dumpmen in the
brain which drives focus,
which helps kick you into flow.
One of the things that'll get you there.
And so that shows up with the
snowboarding with the action sports.
So I think there are certain things that
you can get into flow along the way
earlier on,
but as general rule,
it's skills that you've already
automatized and you're really,
really good at.
Yeah,
that's why I was asking because,
um,
I've achieved those states,
with uh,
like playing pool.
It's called being in stroke or being a
dead stroke.
And when you get,
when you play pool,
especially if you play for hours and
hours at a time,
you get to this place and sometimes it
doesn't last.
Sometimes it only lasts for a few games
at a time.
But you get to this place where you can
put that ball exactly where you wanted
to go.
And you know exactly where the ball's
going to reflect off that ball and
bounce to the next rail and being in a
perfect position on the next ball and
you get into this flow,
this dead stroke stage,
and when you're there,
you're almost like a partition or almost
like rather a passenger.
You're almost sitting back and watching
this play out.
And the key to maintaining that state is
to never recognize the state.
Never acknowledged the state,
never go,
Holy Shit,
I'm in dead punch right now.
Because if you do that,
then you'll start thinking and then
you'll start.
You'll bring your prefrontal cortex back
online and it'll kick you out of that
state.
Exactly.
So let me ask you a question.
You were talking earlier and you're
talking about fighting and how
everything fits together in that moment.
Did you find more flow as a fighter,
as a comic?
Will the explain to people?
What we were talking about,
we're talking about is that I'm
preparing for an martial.
Arts in general can be very psychedelic
because there's such an intense
introspective aspect to training where
you have to examine your skills so
closely and you have to be so acutely
aware of your strengths and weaknesses
and you cannot have any delusion about
it because once the moment funnels down,
all this pressure builds to this one
event where you have to actually
compete.
That event is if you do not have all
your ducks in a row,
if you have not examined all aspects and
prepared for all aspects of this
competition,
like 100 percent honest,
you're gonna fuck up and you're going to
be scared and you're going to be nervous
and you're going to be nervous anyway,
but you're going to really be nervous if
you haven't done your work.
So it'd be you.
There's a selflessness that gets sort of
exposed when you're doing that.
Not Selflessness rather,
but the,
you step outside of yourself to examine
yourself almost as if you're looking at
yourself as a mathematical program
rather than as a person.
Um,
and then when you're,
when you're fighting and all and it's,
if it's going well,
which is,
you know,
not always happening,
but if it is going well,
sometimes things happen.
Like sometimes you'll hit people and you
had no idea how you did it,
like you,
like you're so it's so programmed in you
that you have to figure out how to quiet
everything down and just react.
But that only happens through intense
training for so long that you have these
pathways carved.
Like you'll see it in a fight with floyd
mayweather is a great example.
Someone will throw a punch at him and
you will literally see his eyes open as
the glove comes to his face.
He moves just out of the way and it
counters any counter so quickly.
There's no way he could have thought of.
He's not even thinking.
It's just he's his patterns recognize,
oh,
there's this and then that comes after
this and there's not even a thought
process behind it.
He just does.
He just flows with it.
It's when you can be,
when you have actual space to be
creative inside that are right,
when it's not,
when you're just not reacting in a fight
and whatever.
When you actually,
you know when,
when the flow is peaking,
you really can make any decision you
want to and it doesn't actually feel
like you're.
You're making this decision,
feels like you're,
you're watching somebody else make that
decision.
You're a passenger.
And the way I described finding,
I say fighting is extreme problem
solving with dire physical consequences.
That's what it is.
That's,
I mean,
that's why I like action sports as well.
It's the same thing.
Yeah.
When you see someone doing like 15 flips
with a bmx bike,
Ooh,
if you don't land on your tires,
you got a real problem there,
Fella.
Yeah.
There's something superintendent to it
now in fighting add on that.
It's not just the air and the ground,
but another person who's just like you
just as trained as you and is trying to
do to you what you're trying to do to
them.
So you're solving this puzzle that's
alive,
human being with all these preprogrammed
variables that they have.
So your question was like,
where do you experience the flow state
more fighting or comedy?
I think probably comedy.
It's easier because there's not as many
consequences and you also,
you develop a routine or like you'll um,
the way I do it and a lot of guys do it
the same way.
You put together a special and then you
film it and then you abandoned it and
then you start from scratch.
So that I just did one and it just aired
October 21st.
So now I'm in this like new material
acquisition mode which takes,
uh,
takes a while.
So there's very little flow going on
while I'm on stage.
It's a lot of its calculation and
thinking and remembering all the new
stuff.
But then after a few months of that,
then you get to this point where,
Oh,
I know that bit and then there's this
bit and this.
And then you get into this comfortable
zone and then it starts to flow again.
And then you just got to figure out,
okay,
this is what we got,
like an hour and 20 minutes of this
here,
let this simmer this down to 60 bad ass
minutes and wrap it up.
And then I start all over again.
It's usually like a two year,
two year presses.
Yeah,
two year cycle.
Do you know when you're developing a
good bit?
Sometimes.
Sometimes you think it's good and it
sucks.
Sometimes you think it sucks and it
turns out to be your best one.
You know?
And sometimes you're onstage and then in
the moment a new idea pops in your head
that makes it way better than it was
before.
And it's one of the only art forms I
think we have to do it in front of a
crowd to develop it.
He like,
you could write the dopest song ever by
herself.
You know,
there's a lot of people that have wrote
some written,
some amazing songs and there was no one
in the room and they wrote it and they
programmed the music and
then go,
hey,
check this out.
There's a song I wrote and you're like,
Holy Shit,
this is incredible.
They didn't need anybody for that.
They came up with it in,
in like in their own personal head and
sat down with comedy.
You kind kinda have to have an audience.
You have the idea,
you write things out,
but it doesn't really come fully
together,
doesn't.
It?
Doesn't cure unless the audience is
there,
if that makes sense.
That totally makes sense.
Different kinds of jokes for different
audiences as well.
I'm sure.
Sort of.
Yeah,
but you can't see those people change.
You can't worry about them.
You know,
you're,
you're got to do things that you think
are funny because the problem with
comedy also is that there's only one
genre,
but there's not,
there's many,
many genres of comedy.
Like,
you know,
comedy is comedy,
but who the fuck goes to see live music,
you know,
and you go to see live music.
It's Johnny Cash fall by the Wu Tang
clan.
That doesn't make any sense.
You know,
you would go see rap,
you'd go to see country,
you go see rock.
You would likely go to see the kind of
music that you're really into,
whereas comedies,
just one universal generic term for a
bunch of
go see Steven,
right.
Followed by Dave Chappelle or radically
I would.
Yeah,
sure.
Yeah.
But some people like only squeaky clean,
like Brian Regan type comedy and if they
went to see doug,
Stan hope they would leave and disgust,
you know?
Yeah.
That makes sense.
It's interesting.
Yeah.
Well it's weird because there is,
I mean there's a bunch of different ways
to do it,
but it only has one name,
you know,
where it's like,
he said,
well,
and what kind of music do you do?
Just,
you know,
so we need new names.
I mean,
it's no problem.
No,
no,
it's fine.
You're the one who started it,
man,
tried to back you up.
Just thinking about it too much.
Overthinking,
overthinking a I think is a,
that's.
You've talked about that many times with
flow state,
that the second guessing and that part
of your mind,
that doubts is really the enemy of that
state.
It's twofold.
One,
you're activating your prefrontal
Cortex,
right?
The party of brand that's doing that
overthinking and whenever you get
stressed,
obviously the brand starts releasing
cortisol.
Norepinephrine,
your stress hormones,
right?
There's so flow exists.
One flow exists,
they call it the flow channel,
and the idea basically is that one of
the easiest ways to trigger flow is to
is what's called the challenge skills
balance,
so flow shows up best when the challenge
of the task at hand slightly exceeds
your skillset,
so you want to stretch but not snap and
there's nothing fancy or flow follows
focus,
so everything that triggers flow is a
way of driving intention.
The present moment.
So if I was to what this emotionally I
would say flow exists sort of not on but
near the midpoint between boredom.
Hey,
there's not enough stimulation here.
I'm not paying any attention and
anxiety.
Whoa,
way too much stimulation.
I'm overburdened that anxiety,
norepinephrine and cortisol.
You get up in your head,
you're producing norepinephrine and
cortisol.
You're knocking yourself
out of that sweet spot and why does
norepinephrine knock you out of it?
Isn't that like a like one of those feel
good hormones?
It.
It can be as well.
It can be a feel good.
It's essentially right.
It's the internal indogenous version of
speed with the external substances.
Same chemical.
Basically a little bit.
Wakes you up,
drives focus too much.
You're jittery and freaking out.
Okay.
That makes sense.
And there's got to be a spectrum as well
to the toes date,
right?
So a bunch of different ones.
But a check sent me jaime high chicks at
me.
Hi.
Who's sort of the godfather of flow
psychology was that he says his name.
Mihai chick sent me.
Hi.
That's his whole name.
That's how you.
That?
Yeah,
he's Hungarian.
That's high.
Chicks set me.
Hi Me hot chicks sent me high and by the
way,
funny story about how I.
So I was on NPR after my second book,
which was the first time I wrote about
him and I slaughtered his name.
I mean just slaughtered,
destroyed it.
And the phone rings.
It was live.
I think it was in Cleveland.
I think that's where I was.
And the color comes,
gets on like how can we help you?
What can you do?
Tell them moron sitting next to you.
It's me.
Hi.
Chick sent me hi.
Chick sent me high and he did like four
times.
We're out.
I was like,
okay,
I've been schooled.
I got it.
I was kind of a moron.
Oh boy.
You really?
Or that guy just looking to get some
fucking Brownie points because he knew
the name.
Okay,
so that too.
Yeah,
I think that guy's an asshole.
Don't moron.
Moron.
Because you don't know the craziest
fucking name than anybody's ever put on
a kid.
It's true.
That isn't a poor kid in school.
Me,
hi.
Chuck sent me hide.
The whole class was like,
what?
Where did we,
how did we even get to him?
A flow state spectrum spectrum.
So a check sent me high up in the
seventies,
sixties,
seventies and eighties.
Discovered a bunch of things about flow.
That kind of fundamental.
First thing he discovered is that
there's.
He came up with 10 characteristics that
define the state.
I think he actually sort of mashed up
three triggers with seven
characteristics,
but these are things like uninterrupted
concentration,
your sense of self vanishing time
passing strangely.
Uh,
and the reason,
by the way this happens,
why does self vanished?
But as time pass,
so strangely,
inflow self and time are both
calculations performed in the prefrontal
cortex.
So for example,
time is calculated all over the
prefrontal cortex.
This is David Eagleman is work from
Stanford,
used to be at Baylor,
and when parts of the brain start to
wink out,
when part of the prefrontal cortex start
to shut down,
as you move into flow,
your brain can no longer perform the
calculation so you can no longer
separate past from present future and
you're plunged into a deep now are
internal present.
So that's some of where that comes from
is the deactivation of the prefrontal
cortex.
But anyways,
he figured out there were these seven
characteristics of flow and there's
micro flow states when a couple of them
show up.
So like you're at work and you're
talking to,
you
know,
you bump into a colleague in the hallway
and you fall into a conversation,
gets sucks.
You in an hour goes by and you don't
notice.
That's microflow macro flow.
When all the conditions show up at once.
For the first 70 years we were looking
at the experience people thought we were
looking at a full blown mystical
experience.
They didn't know what it was because
everything can happen.
You can have out of body experiences,
you can have really strange,
you know,
phenomena as a consciousness show up.
So macro,
micro flow to macro flow and it's a
spectrum experience.
It's one of those words are one of those
terms rather flow
state where there's a lot of woo
attached to that sort of state.
Like a lot of people almost want to call
bullshit automatically.
Like,
Oh,
you're in a flow state.
They stayed there.
Well,
there's reasons for that.
And then,
so the flow genome project,
which is my organization,
our whole goal when I started with my
partner,
Jamie wheal,
was to grab flow back from the new age
and put it on a hard science footing and
sort of what happened.
There were a number of things that
happened,
but,
uh,
who do I kill?
Which is actually a woman's name,
another person with a crazy name.
H U,
D A,
I think it's a k I l she was the world's
leading endorphin expert.
She's with the University of Michigan
and she was president,
the American Society for neuroscience
and back in,
I want to say 99 or 2000.
Gina Kolata was a science writer for the
New York Times,
asked,
uh,
who do I kill about endorphins,
which everybody had thought were one of
the reasons,
one of the things that causes flow and
they were having a really hard time
measuring endorphins in the brain.
So there's that kill said,
told the New York Times,
this is a total fantasy of the pop
culture.
It's bullshit doesn't exist.
She was totally wrong,
but it wasn't until 2007,
2008 that are technology got good enough
to actually visualize the endorphins in
the brain.
But at that moment,
flow research in America kept going in
Europe and other places in America
basically it went to a dead stop.
Nobody else was gonna fund it and I
think the new age came in and went,
oh,
flow.
It's such a great term working.
And that's what happened.
So a lot of,
a lot of what I tried to do at the flow
genome project and what we've tried to
do is just put it back on a hard science
footing because there's 150 years of
science behind flow flow science dates
back almost to the 18 seventies to
almost the beginning of cognitive
neuroscience and cognitive psychology.
The research goes all the way back.
William James was looking at this stuff
at Harvard and the turn of the century.
There's a 100 years of research.
I mean ultimate human performance,
optimal performance.
Of course we want to study it.
No,
it's funny because skeptical people will
rally against it in a weird way.
Like I had a conversation with Sam
Harris about it.
We were saying that when you look at it
statistically,
when people are in the zone,
they are not more accurate in basketball
than they are outside of it.
That it's an anomaly and then it's a.
it's an illusion.
It's an illusion of the state of mind
where you're achieving this.
And I was like,
I don't know what you're talking about,
man.
I just don't know how.
First of all,
how often that's been measured where you
can say this because he was really
adamant about it.
It sounds like a super hyper skeptic.
Sam's talking specifically about streak
shooting,
right?
That's what they're looking at.
Yes.
And which is a funny and he's right.
His,
his dad is absolutely correct.
Let me give you,
just give you a counterpoint from my own
life.
So I have a book,
my third book called a small furry
prayer,
uh,
which is about the relationship between
humans and animals and sort of on the
work that I do with dogs and my wife
does with dogs.
And I wrote the first half of them.
It's been a 300 page book.
I wrote the first half of the fourth.
The whole thing turned it in and my
agent called me up and she said,
or my editor called me up and she said,
look,
the first hundred and 10 pages are
pretty good.
You got to Redo it.
But like everything from that point on
sucks,
I need you to rewrite it.
And she was totally right.
So I sat down to rewrite it and I sort
of polished the first hundred and 10
pages and couldn't,
got stuck,
couldn't write,
couldn't write months,
go by closing,
and my deadline,
I go downhill,
mountain biking the very first time in
my life and it just kicks me into this
down if you know how to ride a bike,
you can get downhill,
might have found biking pretty quickly.
Um,
and it just kicked me into an amazingly
deep flow state.
I went home and I started writing and I
didn't stop for about two weeks
straight.
I went to sleep and things like that,
but it was a nonstop flow state.
Finished the book,
wrote 160 pages in like two weeks,
which is incredible and bizarre.
And talk about feeling like a passenger
earlier.
I have no idea who wrote the second half
of that book.
No idea,
just flowed out of me,
pardon the Pun.
But when I turned it in,
my editor came back to me and they had
the first hundred and 10 pages.
The part I had written outside of flow,
there were still lots of errors and can
change this and fix this and this from
page one,
10 to the end of the book,
not one change.
She was happy with everything I'd
written.
Book was a bestseller,
is nominated for a Pulitzer prize.
So obviously I did something right along
the way.
Second half happened totally in flow,
you know,
that's the counter to Samsung argument.
What was the subject of this like?
Well that's interesting,
but what was the subject to the,
uh,
of the second half of the whole book is
about the relationship between humans
and animals and about animal welfare and
running a dog sanctuary and in where
empathy and altruism comes from and what
it has to do with evolution.
Things along those lines.
Uh,
the second half had a lot to do with
sort of a little bit to do with animals
and spirituality and why we have this.
What is that,
you know,
non we.
What do we mean by like the spiritual
relationship to nature.
If you strip out the woo what's
underneath that now?
When you were on the bike,
do you remember the thought?
Do you remember what it was?
What the catalyst was?
The catalyst was Bob Dylan's going to
occupy local this song and it wasn't
even his.
It was a,
I don't remember the movie that where
they did all the Bob Dylan songs over
again a couple years ago and was so
somebody's version of that and something
about the first couple lines to that
song.
It got the tone right.
It was like the.
There was something really kind of
bittersweet and raw in that song that I
needed in my book and that's what it
was.
Somehow I came home with the salt,
with that lyric in my head and I just
started writing and that's what it was.
Why?
By the way,
that's probably the.
You happen to pick the one thing where I
could have given you the cause.
Any other book.
I'm probably going to whiff on that
question,
but that's the one I remember.
Is there
weird how certain songs will trigger
like some sort of inspirational
creativity inside of you?
And I've always wondered what that is.
I,
I learned this from Hunter Thompson and
I've done it many times myself where
I'll take a song and I'll put it on
replay replay and the same song.
Like I flew from the south.
I'm from San Francisco to New York once
and the entire flight actually la,
La and New York.
The entire flight I listened to Ozzy
Osborne,
crazy train the entire flight while I
was writing.
Just I just kept playing it over and
over and over again and do it with a
fixed playlist.
I usually pick about seven to 10 songs
and for her book and I usually.
It's usually two different playlists for
the first half of the book will be one
playlist and then they'll start to fail
and I can sort of feel like the Jews to
go on and I'll have to find a whole
bunch to the woo woo magic.
Yeah.
There's something
about songs to where sometimes I'm
listening to music when I'm writing and
I'm like,
I'm listening to this music too much.
I can't pay attention to what I'm doing
and I've got to shut it off.
And then I can get,
uh,
get into a state sometimes where I'm not
even hearing the words,
like the music is almost just like,
like a,
like a fuel or something or like a,
a,
like some sort of a motivating factor
that's not really totally taking in.
Like I'm aware of it,
but I'm not addressing it.
I'm not really focusing on the lyrics.
I'm just sorta like riding the head dod
and the beat is kind of driving me in
some sort of a weird way.
Also find my latest book stealing fire.
The one that's out in February,
most of the writing that I had a
partner.
So he did something,
something.
But most of that book was written to
Amanda Palmer's cover of Nick Cave's the
ship song over and over and over again.
I know.
I don't know who Amanda Palmer is.
I don't know who nick cave is either.
My,
a bad person.
I was at work.
I don't think you're a bad person.
Who is Amanda Palmer?
Uh,
no.
She uh,
married to Neil Gaiman,
the writer.
I know that guy is seen him on twitter.
Amanda's on twitter too.
She's just a singer,
songwriter,
psychoactive substances or anything that
people do that could enhance creativity.
Is there like a proven thing that Keith
or enhanced flow state or enhanced
creativity?
So there's a couple different ways to
answer this question.
Um,
for sure.
So neurobiologically we know for
example,
so let's.
First of all,
creative is a really fricking fuzzy
words,
so let's,
let's put some meat around it for
starters.
There are lots of different styles of
creativity,
types of creativity,
et Cetera,
but usually not 100 percent,
but usually what you're talking about is
the brain taking in more or different
information per second.
And then finding connections between
this new incoming information and older
ideas.
Right?
So you've got information acquisition on
the front end and you've got pattern
recognition which is closely related
ideas,
finding connections with lateral
thinking,
which is far flung ideas.
And then on the back end,
usually you have to.
Creativity involves making it public,
right?
You gotta have some courage and some
bravery on the back and we got to take
it out into the world.
So to me,
when we talk about creativity,
that's the process.
So if you want to tell you about
amplifying creativity,
will you have a bunch of different
places you can intercept in the chain?
Right?
So when we have norepinephrine and
dopamine in our system,
so it internally,
we get nor up effort and dopamine,
they're focusing chemicals.
Dope means shows up whenever we link
patterns together also.
So you've done a crossword puzzle,
you don't get an answer to that little
rush of pleasure,
that's dopamine,
I'm more norepinephrine and dopamine.
Not only do you take in more information
per second when they're in your system,
you also,
they also amplify pattern recognition.
They lower signal to noise ratios is
what they do.
So we notice more patterns and mine
which is the psychoactive inside of
marijuana,
amplifies lateral thinking,
long distance connections,
right?
And then there's a bunch of different
chemicals that will show up and help you
take risks.
All these chemicals can produce,
can be produced internally or dodge if
you want.
Like I always say,
I'm not,
you know,
only you,
I guess there are more states you can
now do this in.
But a really cheap flow hack is an won't
work over time,
but if you go for a 20 minute,
25 minute run,
low grade Ron,
you're inducing exercise induced
transient hypofrontality,
we talked about that,
followed by a cup of coffee,
followed by a joint and you're going to
essentially mimic the majority of the
neurochemistry that shows up in a flow
state.
So it's an artificial flow state.
So you can,
you can do it that way.
You can do it with a,
you know,
go for a run and you know,
do it that way.
I can do the same thing if you go for
I'll do something and I do this,
my dogs,
the dog sanctuary,
I want to put them in flow because all
these same neurochemicals boost your
immune system and reset your nervous
system a little bit.
So we work with very,
very sick animals and so flow is really
beneficial.
That really extend pet lifespan.
We've discovered we do this thing where
we'll hike for like half an hour or so
again to get to the point where low
grade exercise induced just handwritten
hypofrontality and then we will sprint
up a cliff or up a hill,
something like a five to seven minutes
sprint just long enough to get the
endorphins going.
Right?
So you get that pain relief.
You sort of know you've gotten there
when you get in the pain relief,
so the cycle gets you sort of end to the
low grade flow state and then you're
going to add endorphins in by pushing
yourself physically for like five to
seven minutes and then I turn around
from the top of the cliff and I run back
down the cliff face,
which is a big risk and gets a bunch of
dopamine into your system.
And usually by the time I hit the bottom
of that cliff,
I'm in a flow state.
So like if I'm trying to solve a puzzle,
a writing puzzle and I can't solve it,
I will get.
I call it a flow hike.
I won't go out and do this exact format.
And usually by the time mom hiking home
with the dogs,
the answers are starting to come.
Hello.
Now we.
I think we'd be remiss if we didn't go
back to what Sam was talking about where
he was talking about his streak shooting
and comparing streaks to shooting just
flow state,
which I think is kind of very different,
right?
Because street shooting has some pretty
definitive results.
If you,
if it's very repeatable or you're,
you're doing the same thing over and
over again.
He's shooting a ball into a net and it's
not an easy thing to do.
And statistically when someone's in a
flow state,
they're not more successful or
they think is a flow state or in the
zone.
That's the thing that I was going to
point out and I like,
you know,
I've seen that same data and I have a
hard time believing it.
Like it doesn't actually make a whole
lot of sense to me.
It's not anomalous finding.
It's interesting for that reason.
We know people go on streaks,
right?
I just want what I like when I talk
about flow.
Right.
Everybody's got what I mean we can.
It's defined as an optimal state of
consciousness where we feel our best and
perform our best.
There's more words we can layer under
it,
but what I'm talking about specifically
is specific changes in brain function.
You're getting prefrontal cortex is
turning down.
You're getting five or six
neurochemicals that tend to show up in
your brainwaves,
dropped down to the Alpha Theta
borderline.
So when somebody tells me they're in the
zone,
we don't have a biophysical based flow
detector yet.
There's we're working on one.
Adam Gozali at CCSF is working alone,
but it doesn't exist yet.
So right now if I want to know if you're
in flow,
I have to give you a subjective
questionnaire is extremely well
validated.
We've got like 50 years of research
around it works,
but it's still.
There's no way to like look at that and
say okay,
this person is in deep flow or not,
so we don't have that way to do it yet.
So I don't don't quite know how we do
this research yet,
but it's something that's interesting.
So
do they know what a flow state is?
You're saying that they don't have the
exact ability to test it,
but would it,
what would they use with the use f MRI
or some sort of a new technology?
People have done it 100 different ways
and this is stuff I talk about in,
in rise of superman primarily,
but um,
so there's Eg work,
right where they're looking at brain
waves that sort of goes back to the,
to the sixties.
Um,
and it was at that point they just
thought it was alpha waves.
So when you're quick primer on
brainwaves,
normal waking consciousness,
where are we right now?
Beta?
It's a fast moving wave.
It just means that we're talking,
we're thinking we're engaged.
Alpha,
which is right below that is daydreaming
mode.
It's where you sort of flitting from
thought to thought without much internal
resistance.
Theta is below that data.
We only tend to drop into in rem sleep
or say hypnagogic state or which is when
you're falling asleep,
right?
That weird state where you're falling
asleep and you think,
oh,
that looks like a gray elephant.
And then turns into a grey sweater and
then it turns into a great camry pub a
lot that's happening.
Goget state,
that's data as a general rule.
Um,
so flow takes place.
They used to think it was just alpha.
Now they think it's the borderline
between Alpha Theta.
But we've gotten very,
very precise with Eg.
Eg was one of these things we thought we
could sort of measure it for a long
time.
But in the past 10 years it's gotten
very,
very robust.
We have a pretty good look at,
you know,
what people's brands are doing in flow.
They've also used FMRI.
The best work.
The cool work is Charles Limb,
he's at Johns Hopkins and uh,
he's got all kinds of talks.
You can find them online.
Um,
executive a Ted talk about this work.
He did something really cool he took,
he started with jazz musicians and he
built a keyboard with no metal in it so
they can put it inside the f Mri.
And then he visualized the difference
between the brain of a professional jazz
musician playing a standard,
playing the same notes over and over
versus improvising in a flow state.
So we got to start to see what the
differences are.
This work has sort of been extended a
little bit by a guy named Judd brewer at
Yale.
He's also worked on this.
Um,
he's looked at flow and meditation.
He's found some slightly different
things than Charles limb,
but.
So it's a combination,
but we'll keep really,
really need to know.
It's the neurochemistry that I think is
going to unlock this puzzle.
And a lot of that stuff takes place deep
in the brain.
It's really our imaging technology isn't
quite there yet.
It's starting to get there and probably
will be there him,
you know,
three to four years because this stuff
is advancing so quickly.
But we haven't put the whole puzzle
together.
So for example,
I can tell you these five or six
neurochemicals show up in flow states.
Can I tell you the order that they show
up?
Can I tell it?
Do we know if the order that you drop
into flow versus how I drop in?
Are they the same?
Are they the different.
We have no idea.
That's so fascinating.
It's almost like we're looking at
something that's taking place behind a
wall and we know what's going on over
there,
but we just don't know exactly what it
is.
I think that's one of the things I've
often,
I've discovered about science and I
just,
you know,
I sort of learned this the hard way
coming up as a science writer is I'm
always stunned by how much we don't
know,
like really basic basics.
A lot of really basic,
simple questions.
Nobody's even thought to ask them yet
and it's really,
it's really astounding to me how,
you know,
how little we know,
how much more we need to know,
but,
but really with stuff that,
you know,
people speak very,
very learned Lee and authoritatively
about,
and you start poking and you're like,
look,
we don't even know the very basics here.
What are you talking about?
Yeah.
Like what is consciousness?
We know if you're conscious one,
right?
I mean that isn't that the big one.
What separates people from almost
anything else is that they're aware of
what's going on and they can communicate
it and they're here.
They're conscious,
they're.
They're not just conscious,
but they're somehow or another.
I'm imparting my consciousness in your
head and you're imparting yours into
mine and I'm bouncing your thoughts
around and try.
Okay.
I see where he's coming from.
I see where he's kind of like,
what,
where?
Where's
that coming from?
You talking about theory of mind,
which is interesting because they're
starting to believe that a lot of a lot
of mammals,
health also have theory of mind is not
just humans,
right?
The dividing line between like what is
distinctly human at this point is really
thin.
We've only found a couple of things
right now.
Robert Sapolsky at Stanford talks about
this a lot.
He's great.
He thinks the only two things that
separate humans that lower species can't
do what is distinctly human is our
ability to delay gratification super
longterm.
Like we have religion,
right?
You we're willing to delay gratification
until after I'm dead,
right?
This life socks and then you're going to
go to heaven.
So we're willing to do that.
And we also have,
uh,
the ability to synthesize opposing
ideas,
right?
They can galleon dialectic.
I can take this thing over here on this
side,
this thing over here on this and put it
together and synthesize new ideas,
which most animals don't seem to be able
to do.
But everything else,
we pretty much found.
Well,
isn't language one of the big ones
because with the law,
I mean I think most animals are,
even if they're aware and their
consciousness and even if they have some
sort of a crude form of communication,
what they really lack is the ability to
understand how the other person thinks
like you're talking to me and this is
the first time we've met and we're
talking and I'm,
I'm getting inside your head even from
the whole coffee should be black,
you know,
and you have your methodology for the
rest of my life.
I'm drinking black coffee.
I'm fine.
Alright,
what?
I mean,
but it's like I'm,
I'm,
I'm seeing how you think and what I do.
What I try to do,
at least is when I'm talking to someone,
I try to sort of empty my head out and
let them,
let them get in my head.
Like I would try to think like you're
thinking.
Um,
and when I think I've always said that
that's what's happening in an audience
when someone's on stage and they're
killing when a comedian is on stage.
Like if someone,
if uh,
if I'm watching someone I think is
really funny,
like bill burr or something like that,
I give my brain to him.
I get like,
like go ahead and take me on a ride.
And so when,
when he's on stage and he's killing,
I'm sort of like letting him think for
me and I'm not questioning or taking
things down other paths or allowing
myself to also think about my bills or I
got to get gas before I go home.
I'm just thinking what he's providing
me,
you know,
there's this and that ability is
uniquely human.
The ability to try to understand how
another person is communicating and
thinking.
And then I started taking it into
variables.
Okay.
Like W,
especially now that I'm a father over
the last,
this last quarter of my life,
I've really concentrated on the concept
of everybody used to be a baby.
Like when I was young and single.
That was everyone was static.
That old lady's always been an old lady.
That'll do.
That's always been an old dude.
Now once I had a kid,
once,
you know from,
from then on when I'm raising my
children,
people now are babies that grew up.
Everyone's a baby that became an adult.
I see some crazy old man with a big
fucking WC fields knows and he's
drinking and like,
oh,
that guy was a baby at one point in time
and I've forced myself to go down that
sort of a path.
So I think that the ability to,
to,
to think how other people think and to
sort of commiserate with each other in a
very broad and expansive way.
I think that's a very uniquely human.
I'm not sure.
I think we need to under.
I mean the more we figure out about like
whale language,
Dolphin language,
right?
There's really,
Jamie,
if you look,
you might be able to dig it up.
There's a,
there's a guy I want to say is that
northern Arizona University who worked
on prairie dog language.
Have you heard about this?
This is crazy research,
so one of the reasons we've never been
able to study animal communication,
and I could screw this up,
but we'll try it is we couldn't talk
back,
right?
We couldn't talk to them.
So what he did is he recorded a ton of
prairie dog communication and then
started sort of decoding what little
things mean and but used a computer to
play it back to them.
So what he discovered is prairie dogs,
which you don't think of as particularly
intelligent.
When they'd started decoding their
language,
they started to realize that prairie
dogs routinely say things like,
Hey,
be careful of that right path over there
because there's a fat guy in a purple
sweater coming this way.
That detailed like in the beginning of
the.
Yeah,
they used to think animals only sort of
communicated in like nouns and verbs.
Present tense nouns and verbs,
right?
Snake,
the,
you know,
there are some certain calls that are
monkeys,
monkeys right now,
the three calls now they're starting to
realize they've got adjectives,
they've got tenses.
They can think in the for a while they
thought animals lived in a perpetual
pleasant,
present,
right?
Like the argument was all animals are
always in flow bright,
which is the effort focused.
Everything in the now it turns out
that's not the case at all.
They have passed,
they have futures.
We asked this question a lot running an
animal sanctuary because if we,
if we're caring for a dog,
it's not just older special needs,
it's compromise shelter.
It was on death row is probably if it's
ended up with us because we work with
the worst of the worst of the worst.
It's been very,
very badly abused,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
And the question my wife and I always
used to talk about was do they know?
Do they like,
do they feel grateful to us?
Do they,
can they remember their past enough to
know that you know,
the president is different and we were,
we were.
What was different?
Like those kinds of questions and after,
you know,
10,
12 years of doing this work,
hard core,
I think they really know and I think,
you know,
they live in a,
in a timescale that's a lot broader than
we've given them credit for now.
This work that's been done on prairie
dogs is.
It had been done on any other animals.
He knew language,
discover,
prairie doggies.
It's a radio lab episode.
Nice.
Powerful radiolab from 2011.
Radial abs.
Fucking awesome.
By the way,
if you haven't listened to that podcast
as folks,
that's one of my all time favorites.
I've learned so much from that show,
but that's incredible.
They can tell you the color of the
clothes.
They have a noise for the color.
Fuck nate.
Right.
It's incredible.
And it changes the way you think about
animals.
Oh yeah,
for sure.
You know?
Well the dolphin one is really weird.
Dolphins.
I've found out recently that the babies
come up with their own names.
They come up with names for each other,
like the mother will say something to
them and then the baby will say
something that.
And then the mother will repeat that and
the baby will choose that as a name
Dolphin's name themselves.
Yeah.
They named themselves baby's name
themselves.
Could you imagine if we like human
babies named themselves again?
Yeah.
Well I mean,
dolphins all sound like babies,
you know?
I mean,
they don't really have.
It's sort of like eating,
right?
Yeah.
Well,
Dolphin cognitive chairman sounds.
Yeah.
I mean,
you know what I mean?
There's such.
That's one of the weirdest things about
people's that distinctly different
sounds that we have geographically.
You know,
Middle Eastern has a German,
has a lot of the guttural sort of.
And then you know,
South America is that flow sort of,
you know,
the beautiful Latin sounds to a lot of
their,
the way they speak.
Yeah.
You don't really see too much of that
with dolphins,
but you do see some of it.
You definitely see some dialects and
some,
some variables.
That's always the most fascinating thing
to me is that we really don't know what
the fuck.
They're soft.
They're saying adult.
Yeah.
And we've been studying it forever and
there's a lot of.
I mean,
you've got it.
There's a lot of human arrogance,
right in the way.
There's a lot of us being full of
ourselves and what I mean,
you know,
we,
we want to believe in it.
You know,
they put it in the Bible where the
master of Earth Week and you know we,
and that's a hell of a lot easier to be
if other species aren't conscious and
aren't communicating and aren't feeling
well.
What's interesting to me is that they've
determined now at least the people that
are studying a great,
great apes that chimps have moved into
stone age.
They believe that chimps are now at the
beginning stages of the stone age and if
chimps continue to evolve the way they
have and the way supposedly we have in a
million years from now,
chimps might have fucking houses and
tools and cars and they might be some
totally new,
completely different thing.
There's some kind of Charlton Heston
joke here just waiting to happen for
sure.
Can't get to,
but I mean it makes sense.
If we did at one point in time,
if we.
Obviously we weren't,
unless you believe in creationism,
we weren't born as human beings,
we weren't invented and there wasn't an
anatomy in eve.
There was some sort of hominid that
eventually got smarter and through
natural selection and through the
genetic mutations,
diet choice,
all the different variables that they
think contributed to the human being
becoming a human being,
but it wasn't always that.
So if a chimp,
like right now,
if we can,
like,
we observed the meeting tools of,
I'm sure you've seen the famous photo of
the rang Tang that's holding onto the
branch spear fishing.
Yes.
Fucking a man.
That one's a mindblower you like,
he's got a tool.
So here's the interesting question,
of course,
because we're probably,
I mean,
we've already accelerated evolution
among humans.
We probably can accelerate it among
other species if we want to.
Oh yeah,
that's interesting.
Well,
don't you think it's happening amongst
humans right now at a spectacular rate
to.
Oh yeah.
I mean that's all,
you know,
technical physio evolution is a Robert
Fogle's term from timbers.
No,
physio evolution.
He came out of the University of Chicago
still.
He's an economist.
Um,
and tech,
the physio evolution is his term for the
fact that we've massively sped up
evolution.
Um,
and it,
you know,
it's interesting because if you look at
his work,
it's again,
nothing fancy.
It was sanitation systems and a cleaner
water and slightly better food and
slightly better,
but you know,
suddenly our lifespan has doubled.
Now when he's talking about techno
physio,
he's only talking about using technology
in terms of like the health benefits of
it medicine or is he talking about are
interfacing with technology.
But our interface and we see that to me
is one of the most bizarre ones.
Talked about this yesterday,
but I was watching another teen movie
the other night,
which is just,
it was,
I was writing and sometimes our right to
keep the TV on just for a goof.
And it was so unbelievably bad and weird
as I'm moving from 2001 and it was like
a time capsule and I'm watching this
thing and I'm like culturally we are so
far removed that you could not make this
movie today if you made another teen
movie.
It's failed with racism and sexism and
people get a guy punches a woman in the
face and it's like a punchline.
I mean there's a lot of crazy fucked up
shit in this movie and obviously it's a
comedy and it's parody,
so I'm supposed to be taken literally,
but you can't even do comedies like that
anymore.
Like you watched that movie and you go,
wow,
this is a sign of a time before people
could communicate instantaneously
online.
What would happen if you released
blazing saddles today?
Holy Shit.
It's.
So let me ask you a question since you
brought it up.
It's totally off topic,
but why doesn't comedy age?
Well,
it's a very good question.
You know my,
I think if you want to look at like the
all time,
most important comedians,
I feel like I've always felt like number
one is lenny bruce because lenny bruce
was getting arrested back when you can't
arrest me.
I didn't.
Haven't said Cock sucker.
Yeah,
exactly.
He had cultural.
I mean we had cultural blinders on and
we had these notions of things you could
and could not say,
and he shattered those.
And one of the ways he did his but going
to jail,
but what he was doing was he was
interfacing with a society and a culture
that was infantile.
We were childish back then and we are no
longer like that.
So the things that he was saying that
were naughty and funny are so
commonplace.
There's,
there's nothing funny about it.
He did have some lines though that still
to this day hold up.
Like one of them was about gay people.
He was like,
let me get this straight.
See if you're gaining.
It's illegal.
So they do is if you have sex with a
man,
they put you in jail where men want to
have sex with you.
I mean this guy fucking nailed that in
like 1960.
It's like,
what in the fuck are you doing?
I mean people have inadvertently stolen
that bit.
Like reinvented it themselves.
I got a friend,
it was a really funny comic who did that
bit.
And I go,
hey man,
you need to know Lenny Lenny Bruce did
that night,
Mr.
Sixty two.
And he's like,
no fucking way.
I'm like,
yeah.
He's like,
I thought it was too obvious.
It's too obvious.
That's pretty funny,
but he,
some of the stuff,
I mean,
you know Robin Williams,
a lot of it's not funny,
but what he can do with his face,
Jim Carrey,
Sam,
like some of the physical stuff seem to
hold up because it's still amazing.
You're like,
how the fuck did you do that?
But you know,
interestingly Steve Martin's still holds
up.
Like if you listen to like let's get
small leg,
it's still holds.
It's so silly and a lot of his stuff was
very physical too.
We do the balloon animals on his head
and shit like that when things.
A lot of Richard Pryor hangs in there.
A lot of Richard Pryor still holds up
some of the standup seems to last a hell
of a lot better than the funny movies.
Like go back and try to watch some of
the.
My wife had a very strange childhood so
I didn't see everything I saw coming up,
so I showed her everything,
including all the like Bill Murray
Movies,
stripes and all that stuff from back
when stripes now is a really sad movie
about war.
Right.
I mean at the time I remember like
falling off my chair and being under the
seat.
Couldn't even breathe.
I was laughing so hard and now I watch
with my wife and she's looking at me.
She's like,
you sure man,
this is supposed to be funny.
I'm like,
no,
this is.
It's coming.
And it never comes.
Yeah,
I mean I think that movies are in a lot
of ways like a slide,
like a slide for a microscope.
Well,
we can look at a culture,
you know,
from a time period like,
oh,
this is 2001 another teen movie.
Let's look at this under the microscope.
And you can check out aspects of the
culture.
I mean,
watch,
try to watch a father knows best.
It becomes a comedy,
like it's sort of kind of a comedy when
it came out and then it becomes lame and
now at the comedy again because really,
because now you watch it and you go,
what in the fuck are they talking about?
It's,
it's almost like some sort of a weird
sketchy on some television show.
Similarly it's to,
it's a different thing.
So my wife was,
my wife's a writer also and uh,
she was working on a project that didn't
end up going when everybody was a TV
series based around the women in the
Manson family.
So I ended up reading everything I could
possibly,
you know,
to help her out,
learn about the mansons.
And the most interesting thing is how
they talk to each other about emotions,
right?
Like whatever else you want to say about
the map Manson at that point they
thought they were doing the deepest shit
out there in terms of before things
got crazy right when it,
when it was just like a psychological
calls before it got totally nuts.
But you listen to how they.
They talk about psychedelic things,
our emotions,
and it's you.
She had one of the problems.
You ran into it.
She was like,
I don't know what to do here because I
can't use their dialogue.
They sound like absolute morons all the
time.
There's nothing like his pages of look
into my.
I know you look into my.
I know you look into my eyes and be
like,
holy crap.
This really like,
it's that dumb.
Yeah.
I'm always interested in and I've looked
at it and I can't.
I can't really,
but I'm interested in how the language
has changed.
I always thought that,
you know,
in the sixties we had no language for a
lot of,
a lot of these ideas by the seventies
with the me generation,
we started to put a little more language
around psychological states and what
that it was by the eighties,
it got a little farmer and around the
nineties is when it cut a normalized and
suddenly like guys could talk about
having emotions for the first time.
People don't talk about this back in the
eighties,
but like the most rebellious thing a guy
could do in the early eighties was have
feelings which nobody.
Now you'd be like,
what really are you kidding?
But that's,
you know,
I thought that was really interesting
and you can see it in the language and
how we talk about things like emotions
and psychological problems evolve.
Yeah.
He didn't cry in the sixties right after
day.
No,
not definitely.
Not In the fifties.
Definitely not in the fifties.
There was the strong silent.
I mean,
you know,
obviously it's a stereotype so it's not
real,
but it was the strong silent type.
We know that's what people wanted.
They wanted that
John Wayne guy or counselor.
Yeah.
That's interesting.
I,
you know,
I mean maybe that's just a sign of the
times because the world was hard and
you're coming off of the depression and
from the depression,
you grow up and you're living in the 19
fifties now.
Does those are the adults that grew up
during that time,
you know,
you're in your late thirties or early
forties and your,
you know,
you're dealing with the ramifications of
all the shit that you had to go through
and what society was going through when
you were a kid and it was hard,
hard times.
W no room for pussies.
You asked my grandmother what life was
like in Russia before she died.
She only had it.
She would never tell us which had one
answer,
which was we ate potatoes.
Whoa.
What was,
what was Russia like?
Grandma,
we ate potatoes.
So it was Russia.
Difficult.
We ate potatoes.
Yeah.
My Grandmother,
when she died,
had money stashed all around the house.
She'd take money and put it in coffee
cans and Tuck it under a floorboard or
stick it behind book somewhere like they
had.
She had stashed things everywhere.
She was always worried that it was going
to fall apart again because she had
grown as a depression baby.
She had grown up in the heat of it and
it was just people not knowing if there
was going to be any food.
And wondering,
you know,
if they were ever going to get a job,
if they're ever going to get out of this
whole,
yeah,
we're soft as fuck right now.
So we concern ourselves with the 78
different gender pronouns that they've
decided exist and all the other
different.
Is that a real number?
We make a.
no,
it's real now.
It's apparently it's deep into the
seventies.
And you're supposed to recognize them.
Yeah.
No,
not kidding.
I'm Jordan Peterson coming on in a
couple of weeks and talk about this.
He's a professor at the University of
Toronto and I'm in Toronto.
Canada has different laws and they don't
really.
They have censorship,
they have legitimate censorship and they
have a human rights council and the
human rights council can determine
whether or not you are insensitive to
someone else's belief systems.
And if you are,
you can be charged so you can.
You can go to jail,
you can be brought in front of a court.
You could be fined if you don't use the
correct gender pronouns that they have
decided.
I mean right now it's just theoretical.
It hasn't been,
you know.
No one's at straight out of orwell.
Well,
it's also in New York City.
I don't know if you know this,
but New York City now has new laws were
31 different gender pronouns are
recognized and if you are either an
employer or if you are a landlord and
you choose to miss gender someone and
not use the appropriate gender pronoun
that they prefer,
you can be fined $250,000.
That has not happened yet,
but that is a real law that has been
passed to try to stop transgender
discrimination.
But how would you know in advance which
you have to ask?
What pronouns do you prefer?
I see,
so everybody gets to be special without
doing anything special.
Why?
Because it's easy to get food and
there's nothing.
Nothing does nothing dangerous on the
horizon.
So we look for problems and these are
one of the problems that people look for
and what's really fascinating is that
it's not really.
It's not transgender people that really
want this.
It's Weirdos because transgender people
want to be either.
If it's a man,
they want to be a woman and they'd
prefer to be,
for the most part,
prefer to be called a she or her and use
the female gender pronouns.
And for females to male,
it's the opposite.
It's these people that want to be a z or
a here or a bunch of different fucking
weird ones that they've invented.
They're just,
they're playing a game.
They're like,
they're,
they're in Narnia.
I mean,
they're,
they're playing dress up.
I mean,
it's just weird,
bizarre thing.
I've,
I'm now I'm making up names for what I
am.
I'm a Fox.
Can you know what I mean?
Uh,
you know,
I've,
you look a little like a fuck.
Thank you.
Just thinking that when I came in,
I mean this is exactly the same kind of
thinking that's behind it.
It's like this is not an
antidiscrimination problem.
It's a,
it's a self indulgence problem more than
anything.
And,
and you know,
what passes for creative self
expression,
like gut and do something in the world
and go do something.
Yeah.
What do you do when they have time to be
coming up with 78 different gender
pronouns?
Fuck doing right.
Let's examine what's going on here.
Tinder updates including 37 new gender
identity options,
37 new ones,
new ones,
37 new ones.
We're going to look back at this time
and we're going to fucking laugh the way
we don't laugh at old comedies were
going to laugh at the actual historical
documents that show how fucking
ridiculous people in 2016,
where we're going to look at people 50
years from now,
we're gonna.
Look back and go,
what in the fuck were they doing before
the asteroid hit?
Right?
They were going crazy that it's almost
like Rome before the fall,
right?
We're all just going crazy and just
completely obsessed with nonsense,
but I think that that also speaks to the
desire or the the requirement that human
beings have for a certain amount of
engagement in their environment and a
certain amount of drama and conflict.
I think we're wired for it.
I think we're wired for a certain amount
of conflict and resolution and problem
solving and I think that's one of the
reasons why people really like doing
things that are difficult.
I've been writing about this lately
because I've become obsessed with yoga
over the last couple of years and I suck
at it.
I'm not very good at it,
but as I do it and continue to do it and
get better at it,
I feel like it's making everything else
in my life better.
I don't think there's any way that girl.
There's an athlete without yoga.
It doesn't.
It doesn't work.
You just break too many things.
I think you're totally right and I think
it has a negative connotation because
people think of it as like being soccer
moms and it's fucking hard.
Oh yeah.
The first time.
So I put about 65 hairline fractures and
my legs.
I shattered my legs and I'm 65 hairline
all in one.
Okay.
Longer story.
When I was a 16,
skied off a cliff in Switzerland,
split my.
Didn't see it,
the nose there and split my Patellas so
my knees never folded right.
So when I started,
but when you say split my Patella,
I mean I cracked my kneecaps and back
then they couldn't do anything for it.
They couldn't.
So they just let it heal and my legs
didn't fold quite right.
So the angle was off.
So I,
you know,
when I came up I started out as a
journalist.
One of the action and adventure sports
were starting out.
It was the early nineties and you could
ski and ride or surfing right,
or rock climbing or there was work and I
couldn't do any of those things very,
very well.
But I lied to my editors because I
wanted the work and I was really
fascinated with.
So I spent about five or six years
chasing athletes around mountains and I
broke a lot of bones along the way.
What happened was every time I impacted
right ever.
So if skiing bumps dropped off a little
something,
I would put microfracture in my legs a
little one.
And then as of your nice structures,
they weren't told it wasn't folding.
Right?
So the shock absorbers was working,
working.
And so,
you know,
one day they all turned into bigger
fractures and I sort of collapsed and
you know,
I remember when I was at the Cleveland
Clinic and the doc walked out holding up
my extra and he was like,
the cube.
He's like,
how do you even walk in here,
man?
And I was like,
what are you talking about?
He's like,
yeah man,
you're days of skiing or running.
He's like,
that's over.
And I was like,
fuck,
if it's over,
you're out of your mind.
It was like 20 or something like that.
No.
And I,
for whatever,
I don't even remember what tricked me
into it.
I started doing the yoga and the reason
I,
I mean I like,
I went,
I was like,
maybe I needed more flexibility.
Maybe that was the key.
Um,
but I remember the first time I went
into the yoga class and you know,
you sort of like,
you look to your right and there's a 75
year old woman who's doing stuff that
like I can't even begin to do.
And I like,
it hurt so much.
I've got tears rolling down my feet to
try to like get in that position and I
was like,
fuck that.
There's no way I'm going to be
fascinated by that and I just stuck with
it because I know I'm competitive and I
was like,
she can do it.
I can do it.
Yeah.
This is one old woman.
I hate calling her old woman.
She's a nice lady.
I don't want to use any pejorative,
but she's a probably deep into her
sixties I would imagine she's there
every time I'm there.
I don't know how often she goes,
but she's there almost every time I'm
there.
That lady busts her ass every class and
she walks out of there smiling and happy
and I'm like,
how many people that are in her age
group have that kind of energy and that
kind of vitality to get through a 90
minute hot yoga class.
It'd be smiling and chipper when it's
all over.
It's awesome.
It's.
But my point was that the.
I really think that doing difficult
things.
Oh yeah.
Totally.
Very important.
Will you also,
you know,
we were talking about earlier like flow
shows up when our skills are stretched
to the Max and we know,
and this is go back to chicks at me.
Hi.
Um,
but there's massive data on this at this
point.
The people who are happiest,
the people who have score off the charts
for overall life satisfaction and
wellbeing or the people with the most
flow in their lives.
So people the most flown their lives are
people who are constantly challenging
themselves,
are constantly pushing all the time.
That totally makes sense to me.
I'm,
I'm absolutely at my most happy when I'm
involved in difficult activities.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
And in you know,
and also like shitty results sometimes
too.
We don't feel good and then you just
rebuild and figure out what went wrong
and then bounce back from those shitty
results and then achieve something that
you had achieved before.
And then you get this giant boost of
happiness and satisfaction.
And it's also,
I feel energized and engaged as long as
I'm doing difficult things all the time.
Whether it's archery or martial arts or
yoga or something difficult things for
whatever reason when I'm doing them,
my brain is in a good state.
You know,
it's one of the reasons why I've been so
fascinated with your work and these,
these concepts of flow is because I feel
like there's a whole bunch of different
variables that or different states that
you achieve in the mind.
Like there's a,
there's a momentum state that I feel
like I get when I'm doing all the stuff
I'm supposed to do when I'm writing a
lot.
I'm exercising a lot and I'm eating
healthy a lot.
I have this momentum state and that
momentum state is a different state than
the flow state.
It's like this,
um,
it,
it success or it propagates the concept
of a continuing to improve [inaudible] I
know what you're talking about.
And it's,
I tend to notice,
let's call it the momentum stage.
When I'm getting into flow fairly
frequently,
that tends to show up at other times.
And I,
you know,
I,
I always,
I always think like when that feeling is
really present,
that's when you make big bets.
That's when you really go because you've
got,
you know,
wind in your sails driving you.
If I'm not feeling that,
I mean I will always be willing to take
a big risk and challenge myself and
whatever,
but I'm much more comfortable doing it
when I'm feeling that momentum because
then I,
you know,
I know I've at least I got a shot at it
for sure.
One hundred percent.
And that exists with a.
it's a big one with martial artists.
It's a big one with fighters.
You see that with fighters when they
have a bad result,
they have this rebuilding period.
We're oftentimes they are on shaky legs
and then sometimes they never come back
from it.
You know,
sometimes one bad result for a fighter
in their careers essentially over there
ghost of themselves.
But up until that moment,
there's fighters have these dates that
they achieve.
A perfect example is Anderson Silva,
when he was in his prime,
Anderson Silva was widely recognized,
is if not number one,
certainly in the top two or three best
fighters of all time and UFC considers
them the best of all time,
but he had achieved this state of mind
and of performance when he was at the
end of his reign is the middleweight
champion when he was almost in the
matrix,
I mean he would fight guys and stand
right in front of them.
They would throw punches and he would
just slide out of the way effortlessly
and then knocked him out and drop them.
There's this famous fight that he had
with forrest griffin for the,
um,
well it was one of his first fights at
light heavyweight when he was the
middleweight champion.
So he's fighting 20 pounds above his
weight class against,
uh,
a really like,
watch this,
look at this.
This is a look at this.
Watch how he's standing right in front
of them.
And it just moves out of the way.
Every time for us tries to punch him.
He's not there.
And then watch this being.
It just cracks him.
I mean it's,
it's,
it's watching it live.
I was like,
this guy is a fucking wizard.
I mean,
it's really strange.
I mean he was standing in front of them
like,
like he saw everything coming in slow
motion and forrest is a world class
fighter.
He,
I mean there's a bunch of videos of
Anderson like that being in the matrix.
He stood with his back.
He fought this guy,
Stephan Bonner stood with his back
against the cages,
stood there,
dropped his hands and invited the guy to
just throw punches and kicks Adam.
And then when the guy tried to attack
you just slip right out of the way and
then he went right back to the spot and
he goes,
come on,
let's do it again.
And the guy who was,
he was like,
what in the fuck is happening to me
here?
Because he was being humiliated is
embarrassing as hell.
Fifteen seconds later he smashes him
with Anita stomach and knocks him
unconscious.
And I mean it was just,
he,
he had achieved this weird state because
of the momentum of his success,
his confidence.
And you also had this weird aura about
him when he was at the top where
everyone was terrified of him because he
could do things like that and you had a
feeling that maybe he's going to put his
back up against the cage with you and
humiliate you.
So you were almost training in vain,
like training,
thinking that like one day I'm going to
get in there with this guy and I'm going
to get fucked up.
Like everybody else.
Be like,
well,
I'll tell my friend.
Yeah,
well he was like water for a long time.
But the thing that got him,
well father time got him for sure.
But he had.
He got knocked out by this Guy Chris
Weidman.
He got knocked out doing that.
He got knocked out like joking around
and putting his hands down and Weidman
just judged where he was going to be and
faked him out and caught him with a big
punch.
Knocked unconscious.
And he's never been the same again now.
That's interesting.
Yeah,
just all stopped right there.
I did not.
I have noticed,
and I think it's one of the more
interesting things about kind of
breaking bones as an athlete is it
doesn't matter consciously how brave I
want to be.
Like a couple years ago I did this and I
basically nearly severed my hand from
my.
What's going on in there?
I was at 25 foot cliff that I swear I
ordered a 35 foot cliff at.
I under jumped it and I basically went
wrist.
I flipped upside down,
rates went down,
um,
but for a year and a half after it,
whenever I was above exposed rock.
So which happens as a skier,
a downhill mountain bike or all the top,
you're always,
I would have an immediate fight or
flight response.
It would freeze and just start shaking
and I couldn't.
There was nothing.
I mean that I just had to kind of expose
myself to it over and it took about a
year to like calm down.
I've discovered that after a big
accident,
like a broken bone,
torn rotator cuffs,
something like that.
It's going to take me six to eight
months at to just like get my
unconscious back and ready to kind of
take risks again.
It doesn't matter.
You know,
I could be healed from the injury.
I could be in better shape than I was
before the injury,
whatever.
It's gonna take like six or eight months
from my subconscious to like get all
that fear out and actually reset towards
normal.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
And when fighters lose,
there's a,
there's a physical aspect of it to the
injury.
Like if they get knocked out,
especially they're worried about taking
a punch and sometimes that takes a long
time before they can feel confident
enough to take a blow again.
But there's also this,
uh,
there's an illusion of invulnerability
that they achieve when they're at the
very best.
And that illusion is shattered when they
realized like,
Oh,
well now I'm the nail.
I used to be the hammer,
but today I'm the nail.
How,
how do you deal with being the nail?
And that's,
I think probably one of the biggest
psychological barriers that a fighter
can overcome.
Their own mortality
was your answer to that problem in what?
Which one?
How do you come back from becoming an
ale
ends on the person?
Depends on where you are in your career.
For some fighters they have to recognize
that because of the amount of damage
that they've taken,
I'm like,
you have what?
The way I always like to describe it is
like you have a ticket and there's a
certain amount of holes you can punch on
that ticket and when you punch too many
holes on that ticket,
you don't get those back.
That's it.
It's over and you have to really be
aware of that because if you start
getting delusional or new started having
this ridiculous idea that you're
different than everybody else had been
there before you and even though you've
been getting knocked out regularly and
training because your Chin's gone that
somehow now they're going to be able to
put it together.
When the fight comes,
you can only take so many shots.
You know,
you can only take so much trauma
particularly in the brain,
but I'm sure in the body as well.
I mean,
I don't know how much work has been done
studying body trauma,
but I can only imagine the amount of
scar tissue that you build up.
I getting kicked in the liver,
you know,
camp after camp,
fight after fight.
I mean it cannot be good for your
kidneys.
Get abused,
your,
your internal organs get smashed by
kicks and punches on a regular basis.
Your body only has so much resilience,
so if someone is there because someone's
in a bad state because they're 22 years
old and they fought someone that got
knocked out,
I would say they just need to take some
time off rest of the brain because
that's very important.
It's one thing that a lot of fighters
fuck up on as they try to get right back
in there and you're vulnerable.
You're much more vulnerable than you
were before when you were.
You've been knocked out.
Have you been knocked completely
unconscious and flatlined.
It is way easier for you to be knocked
out again.
Well,
that's.
that's all the Tbi stuff,
right?
Like that's why there's concussion
protocols.
Yeah.
You've got gotta wait super vulnerable
right afterwards.
I remember like it was a car accident,
concussion,
but I remember going rock climbing and
it was two,
three weeks after and I was,
you know,
500 feet up on the wall as vertigo or
something.
All kinds of craziness.
Like legos started sweating.
Thing started like it was,
my brain just was like,
Jesus Christ handle this at all.
It was fine.
There was lots of ropes and protection
and my friend just got me off the wall.
It wasn't,
it wasn't a big deal,
but I remember at the time and I was
like,
you know,
I'm looking for a hole that was looking
for a cold and a crack or something like
that were like three cracks.
And I was like,
wait a minute.
There were not three cracks here a
second ago.
What the hell just happened?
Have brain trauma is no joke.
So I think for fighters there would be
the physical aspect of it and the mental
aspect of it,
both of them are very difficult to
overcome.
I think if you're younger,
the physical aspect is easier to resolve
and you just need time.
And uh,
the psychological aspect,
you know what I mean?
Some people get over it better than
others.
Some people have a more honest
assessment of themselves as a human and
as a,
as a competitor,
and they,
they understand that this is just a
really difficult thing they're doing and
sometimes it's going to work out and
sometimes it's not.
And other people to just think I am the
baddest motherfucker that's ever lived.
And then boom,
something happens.
They're like,
oh my God,
I'm just,
I'm normal.
And that's really hard for them.
It's a mindset thing,
right?
The difference between a fixed and a
growth mindset.
Yeah,
it is.
And it's also,
it's a,
it's a difference between someone who's
been lucky and understands that they've
been lucky and someone who's been lucky
and it feels like they've been blessed
by the gods.
And then all of a sudden the gods have
rescinded their program and they say,
look,
they're fickle that way.
You're just normal.
You're mortal.
It's,
there's so many variables.
And it's like how it happened to you.
Was it a lucky shot that you got hit
with?
Was it a prolonged beating?
Which is oftentimes the worst when a guy
really gets beat up,
it's really hard for them to come back
because what you see inside the octagon
with when a person gets beaten up is
just the beginning of it.
What really happens after that is
ringing in the ears for weeks with
Vertigo.
Fucking horrible bruises all over your
face and your body and aching and in
terrible pain for a long time.
When you see a guy get the fuck beat out
of him.
That's just the beginning of his
struggle.
You know what?
What you see,
especially a really bad knockout.
You our entire.
It's entirely possible you're seeing
someone will never be the same again.
That's heavy.
Yeah,
change.
It changes the way you watch fighting.
Well,
my good friend Dr.
Mark Gordon is a specialist in traumatic
brain injuries.
I know mark.
Yeah.
Palladium.
Yes.
He's helped me when I had lyme disease.
Oh,
did he really did that?
That guy's awesome.
I love him.
But he's worked with so many football
players and soldiers and now he's
working.
He's done some work with fighters too,
but you know,
he's adamant about it.
He's like,
once you start ringing that bell,
you know,
you,
you gotta do everything you can to heal
that thing up and you cannot just jump
right back into it.
So when you see these football players
that are getting fucking cracked and
then two periods later they're jumping
back in,
you know,
that's crazy.
You're doing a crazy thing.
You got flat lined and then you're
jumping back in the game three quarters
later or two quarters later.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
and it's common.
It's common wealth.
I mean,
you know,
try to tell anybody anything when you're
22,
23,
24,
you know,
at that age,
especially at.
But if you're a professional athlete and
you've trained yourself to be fiercely
competitive in that ferocious and
everything else,
it's hard to dial that back was just
such a scary thing though because
compromising the ability to think
correctly to me is one of the scariest
things that could happen to you.
That was,
I had lyme disease and one of the,
and I spent three years in bed,
but the worst part about lyme disease,
I was really sick.
Jesus Christ.
That's where the research came from.
Yeah.
I pulled myself out of it through
surfing and these crazy altered states
that was happening while I was surfing.
And my first question was,
what the fuck is gold?
Right.
Surfing is not.
I've known carol for chronic autoimmune
conditions.
And why was it having,
having these crazy altered state of
consciousness experiences while surfing?
That's where it started for me.
Um,
but with lyme,
I mean,
you'd go crazy.
You become extremely paranoid.
The most common misdiagnosis for lyme is
paranoid schizophrenia.
So you become extremely paranoid.
I was hallucinating short term memory
gone,
longterm memory gone.
Been dyslexic.
I couldn't write.
I couldn't even read because I would get
to the end of a sentence.
I couldn't remember the beginning of the
sentence that I read,
but it's like watching yourself go mad.
I don't know of any.
I don't have been through a lot of
physical pain.
I've been through a lot of different
illnesses.
Whatever.
Nothing is worse than watching yourself
go crazy.
Wow.
Terrifying.
That.
My good friend,
Tommy,
his girlfriend just this past weekend
was telling me about she had lyme and
she was misdiagnosed.
She had to go to more than a,
I think she said more than a dozen
different doctors before somebody
finally listened to her.
If you find,
if my second book west of Jesus,
which is the book I write about this,
this is very early,
it's the first couple of pages.
I have a list of all the diseases that I
was told I had before they actually
discovered was lime and it's,
you know,
it's half a page of diseases.
It's just,
I'm so confused by that because lyme is
common.
So first of all I was,
I had it,
uh,
I got it on the east coast,
but I was here.
I was living in California.
I was living in La at the time were they
hadn't really.
Now they've seen it,
but at that time nobody had really seen
it and they didn't believe it was a west
coast disease and it,
you know,
it's still this point that diagnostics
are not fantastic for lyme.
But what I was saying,
my friend Katie,
my friend,
Tommy's girlfriend,
Katie,
she lives in New Jersey or Connecticut
rather,
where it's really common.
I mean,
line Connecticut is where it came from,
so they live in a place where it's
really common and the doctor's like,
nap time.
She was like a thing.
It might be lime,
not lying.
You're going crazy.
I went in,
I don't know if I can talk about this.
I can't talk about this a little bit,
but.
So we'll keep names out of it.
So the first time I walked into see my
doctor,
um,
I've been sick for awhile and I just
moved to La so it didn't have or a
regular practitioner.
I finally got one and I've been sick for
a while,
so a lot of my friends had been trying
to figure out what the hell was going on
me.
And one of my editors said,
Hey,
I've been doing research.
I think I think we have and go ask your
doctor.
And I remember walking into the doctor's
first time I'd seen him and I was like,
hey man,
I,
you know,
Blah Blah Blah.
This was going on.
Uh,
I think I have lyme.
And he's like,
no,
you don't have lyme,
you have aids.
Which by the way,
like,
you know,
I was like,
are you sure because decided you were
gay,
know I looked at him,
I was like,
are you sure?
Because my mother was one of the very
first AIDS activists in Ohio.
So like I've been having protected sex
my whole life,
or baby have true that heterosexual,
no intervenous drug use at that time and
you know,
just any dudes,
nothing,
nothing at that point.
And you know,
I'm willing to learn if you'll send me
someplace special.
But uh,
so this guy decided,
this guy just looks at me and the work.
You're gay?
No,
I thought I was like,
I was like,
buddy,
I'm not like I haven't add homosexual
sex.
I've never used Ivy.
That was what happened.
And the worst thing is like I go home to
your girlfriend who you're living with.
And she's like,
how was the doctor honey?
MMM.
Yeah.
Did he test you before he tested?
He tested.
That's just,
that won the lawsuit.
Oh,
I know.
By the time it was all said and I'm holy
Shit,
you have to assume,
wow.
It got really obnoxious,
I mean they wouldn't test me for
anything and it dragged on and on and on
that because they're worried that if
they do test you for something and they
confirmed that they were incorrect and
it sets them up for malpractice so
they're trying to drag it out and it was
an Hmo.
Thanks.
So insurance has changed,
but back in this was early $2,000
a year.
Ninety nine,
98.
I paid my premium was hmo coverage was
like,
let's say at the time it was like a
couple of hundred bucks a month of that
200 bucks a month,
$7 went to the doctor for testing the
restaurant,
went to the insurance company,
the doctor got $7 a month to treat me.
Somehow incentivized are that are run a
bunch of big expensive tests.
So it looks at anybody on an Hmo is like
aids.
You got a,
you get aids,
get them to run out of my office.
Hopefully the goal just do drugs and
die,
which is drink himself to death.
It was ugly.
Wow,
that's crazy.
So this was a long time ago when line
wasn't nearly as prevalent.
Now with lyme is a God damn scary
disease because I don't know when it
originated and they just started sorta
treating people for it over the last few
decades.
Right.
I don't,
um,
I don't know if this is still true,
but there was a period of time where it
was the first or the second biggest
communicable disease,
your viral diseases in the world.
I,
it was second to AIDS.
Well,
one of the things I studied,
I did this show called the Joe Rogan
questions.
Everything for Psi Phi and one of the
things that we looked into with
something called more jealous,
do you know what more jealous or Jones
is a very controversial disease where
people feel like they have fibers
growing out of their skin and they
scratched themselves and develop these,
like open sores from itching and then
they think that they'll get like carpet
fibers and their skin.
They'll think it's coming out of their
body like they have like fibers from
their clothes that they'll detect on
their skin.
And so it has this sort of weird
psychological aspect to it.
What's interesting about it is a
disproportionate number of people who
have more gentleman's or believed they
haven't tested positive for lyme
disease.
So I was talking to a doctor who had
more jealous,
who also has lyme.
And he was very candid and honest about
it.
He and he thinks that there's a direct
risk,
there's something going on,
there's a neurotoxic effect that's
happening with the lyme disease that's
twisting his mind doesn't.
I mean I went crazy.
I'll tell you I was at.
That's why I wanted to talk to them
about Fairfax and sunset.
I was driving my car.
It was just stick.
And it was,
I was coming back from the doctors.
This was a typical lyme.
What happens to your brain?
And I'm the light's red and it's rush
hour.
You know what Fairfax in sunset is like
at rush hour and uh,
the light turns from red to green.
And I no longer know what green means.
My brain is just like.
And I'm like,
what am I supposed to do?
What am I supposed to do?
People are flocking and hugging and
finally I'm like,
Oh crap.
Green means go,
and I looked down to the stick shift and
I no longer had not remember how to
drive stick.
I had to literally get out and people
had to push my car into whatever that
little grocery store is right there to
the bar.
You crazy.
So like,
you know,
fundamental skills that I'd had since I
was 16 years old.
And you know,
the ability to go when the light turns
green.
I mean you watch yourself go crazy.
Wow.
That must be insane.
But you knew how to walk.
You knew how to talk.
You knew to say there's something wrong.
You had full access to the language that
had full access to land that couldn't
write.
I started developing like scrabble words
up when I was writing,
but I could talk.
I don't think I ever lost my powers of
speech that I remember.
What a scary little fucking disease.
Lyme is,
was weird,
scary,
creepy disease.
Well,
this doctor,
he was absolutely convinced that the two
of them were correlated.
He said that there's something going on
with lyme disease that produces this
thing where you start seeing these
fibers coming out of your body and uh,
you know,
we had a ton of people like the sending
videos and show us images and they had
slides that they had prepared.
They were convinced these fibers were
coming out of their skin and so doctors
oftentimes just completely label it as a
psychosomatic disorder.
But this one doctor who had it said,
I believe that the correlation is lyme
disease and it completely makes sense.
Listen to what you're saying.
The other thing is everything has a
psychosomatic disease,
right?
I mean,
there's not a wealth of mine.
All I was saying is,
I don't mean it.
That was kind of funny now because it's
a,
it's like you could kind of avoid.
It used to be,
we were all worried everybody's going to
die.
Like you can joke around about aids now,
which is rare,
you know,
if you look at like the time when Magic
Johnson came out as HIV positive,
everybody was terrified we're all going
to die.
You know,
I lost a lot of friends during that
period.
I'm sure you,
because they thought you had aids.
No,
because I might have lost some friends
that way too.
But uh,
because of the.
Yeah,
yeah.
I mean it was a death sentence for a lot
of people,
you know.
Um,
I had a guy on who,
um,
is a super controversial character.
He's a biologist at the University of
California,
Berkeley.
And have you ever heard of him?
His name's Peter Duesberg.
He's a weird guy,
man,
because I'm,
he's,
first of all,
his credentials are rock solid.
He's done some amazing work with cancer
research.
He's in me.
He's a legitimate tenured biologist.
Right.
And he believes that HIV does not cause
aids.
He believes that AIDS is,
cause he believes that it's not a
communicable disease that is caused by
rampant drug abuse and that people
taking crystal meth and,
uh,
amyl nitrate and that in the gay
community there's so much partying that
they're destroying their immune system.
And that's why HIV is showing up.
He believes that HIV is a very weak
virus and it only shows up in the,
in the immune systems are in the bodies
of people who have compromised immune
systems already,
that it's not the cause of the immune
system,
but it's a symptom of a compromised
immune system.
It can't just be because like abuse
obviously,
because there's tons of people who have
aids who never used drugs in their life,
right?
Like Africa,
Yeah.
Right.
Here's what's weird about that.
They don't test them for HIV.
When you get money from AIDS
organizations,
um,
they,
they're not,
they're not spending a ton of money to
test people for HIV.
They're just looking at their t cell
count.
They're looking at people with
compromised immune systems.
Aids meaning acquired immune deficiency
syndrome.
So they're seeing these people that have
obviously compromised immune systems and
they look at the t cell count.
Oh yeah,
you have aids,
but it doesn't mean they have HIV and
what he.
I mean,
he's fucking super controversial and no
one agrees with them and no one wants to
debate him either because I had him on
it.
People were really angry with me for
having a lawn like,
Hey,
I have zero background in biology.
This guy's a fucking professor at the
University of California,
Berkeley.
He's written all these articles about
it.
He's talked to all these people about
I want to hear what he has to say.
People are so angry at all,
but as you look into it deeper and
deeper,
it demands that someone shot them down
like some.
Some biologist should have a debate with
them and show step by step wise,
wrong,
because if he's just running around,
they're saying that and everybody avoids
him.
A lot of people gonna get sucked into
that rabbit hole.
You know?
I don't.
I don't obviously don't know who's
right.
I doubt he's right.
I highly,
highly,
highly doubt that all those other
biologists are wrong.
And this one guy is correct,
but it might be both.
It might be that HIV does cause aids at
AIDS is a communicable disease and also
that drug abuse accentuates it.
That makes it much worse.
So instead,
you know,
he's looking at this one factor when
this one factor,
which absolutely everybody knows when
you're doing crystal meth and you're
doing a meal nitrate and all these crazy
drugs,
these people are doing anybody doing
that stuff,
you're going to have a fucked up body.
Like it's going to compromise your
immune system.
You drink every night,
it compromises your immune system.
Any drug abuse is not good.
So if that drug abuse is going on and
it's coinciding with an infectious
disease,
it just makes sense that it would
accentuate it.
That's what I probably think it is.
But his path,
the path that he's chosen to pursue is
just extremely controversial.
And you know,
people think that he's antisemitic and
then he's anti gay anti this and anti
that because of it.
So a lot of,
a lot of weird stuff gets tossed around
a crazy.
Yeah.
Interesting.
I'm sure he's wrong.
Dunno.
Fuck.
Do I know.
But for you,
what did they have to do to you to get
you off the lyme disease and isn't lyme
something you keep semi-permanently?
So I mean,
I,
you know,
I was in bed for three,
I mean I'll tell you,
the year it was in bed for about three
years,
they had to pull me off antibiotics
because my stomach lining started
bleeding out.
There was nothing else maybe you could
for me and
just tell you the full story and I was
going to end my life.
I like,
I was at that point I was functional but
10 percent of the time,
maybe like an hour a day I couldn't
work.
The only thing I was going to be was
burdening my friends and my family and I
was just like,
alright,
at the time,
30 m and a in the middle of this,
I was,
it was,
it was when I was still living in Los
Angeles,
a friend of mine showed up my door and
said,
we're going surfing your fucking mind.
I can't walk across the room.
I mean I literally,
I couldn't do it and she wouldn't shut
up and wouldn't leave,
wouldn't leave and wouldn't leave.
And after like it just hard to make
compliant.
It's going to drown me four hours of
this or three hours.
I was like,
fuck it,
let's go surfing today.
I mean,
what's the worst that can happen?
Right?
I'll always kill myself tomorrow and a
drag matt to sunset beach and they
literally sort of had to walk me to the
car,
right.
Take you by the shoulders because I was
really weak and you know,
they gave me a board the size of a
Cadillac and the bigger the board,
the easier it is to serve and this was
enormous and it was a tiny day.
Like waves were like two feet at best
and it was so crappy.
Nobody was even out,
but the water was warm and they sort of
like,
they took me by the elbow and they
walked me out to the break and I was out
there and I knew how to surf a little
bit.
Had been a long time side surfed at that
point,
but 30 seconds later a wave came in.
You know,
I don't know what happened.
Muscle memory took over,
whatever.
But I spun my board.
I paddled a couple of times and I popped
up and I just popped up in a dimension I
didn't even know existed.
Right.
So in the eye panoramic vision I felt
like I could see out of the back of my
head and I felt amazing.
Felt like that kind of full throttle of
lifetime and slowed down.
None of it made any sense.
It felt so good.
I caught like four more waves that day
and by the fifth wave I was,
I was disassembled it Kinda put me back
into the car and drove me home.
And uh,
I was so sick after that that I was,
I got into bed and people had to bring
me food for like two weeks because I
couldn't walk to my kitchen which is
like 60 feet away and I was exhausted.
But on the Fifteenth Day,
which the day I could walk again,
caught another ride back to the beach
and I did it again and again.
I had this crazy altered state of
consciousness experience.
And you know,
again,
I was disassembled this time.
Maybe it was like 13 days that I was in
bed and I did it again and over the
course of about six to eight months with
the only thing I was doing differently
in my life was surfing.
I went from about 10 percent
functionality to about 80 percent
functionality.
So my first question is the fuck is
going on,
right?
Like as I said earlier,
surfing is not a known cure for chronic
autoimmune.
Right?
So I laid out on a John Question.
The other thing was I backgrounds is a
science writer,
so like I don't have quasi mystical
experiences and I sure as hell don't
have them while surfing,
which has got to be the flakest thing
ever.
And I'm so.
I really believed that even though I was
feeling better lives,
only fatal if it gets into your brain
and I was.
I was pretty sure that even though I was
starting to feel physically better that
the disease had crept into my brain
because why else would I be having these
mystical experiences?
I must be totally losing my mind about
to die.
And I lit out on a giant quest beer.
At what the hell happened and you know,
very quickly discovered that these
states of consciousness have names.
We called them flow states and the
version of what happened to me health
wise,
and this is her Benson did some of the
work on the neurobiology of this.
He's at Harvard,
he wrote about it in his book,
the breakout principle,
but uh,
all the neurochemicals that show up in
flow to things happen.
So one,
when you move into flow,
there's a global release of nitric
oxide.
It's a gas as signaling molecules
anywhere in the body.
What it does is it flushes all the
stress hormones out of your system and
it pumps you full of these kind of feel
good performance.
Tangent line is an essentially any
autoimmune conditions you nervous system
gone haywire.
So when you go into flow,
it resets.
Your nervous system,
calms everything down.
It gets rid of all the stress hormones,
all that stuff and it.
And when.
The worst part about lyme is you don't
even know what normal is.
Like it has been so long since you have
felt normal,
like you don't even.
You can't even find it on a map,
so suddenly like I was like,
oh,
this is what normal feels like.
Again,
the other thing is,
you know,
the positive neurochemicals that show up
and float dopamine,
Serotonin and Nanda [inaudible] see
towson.
Those are all immune system boosters.
I mean they do a ton of other stuff,
enhance cognitive performance and
whatever,
but her Benson at Harvard,
and I think this may be overstretching,
it will have a budget,
but he has kind of gone on record and
said he thinks most cases of so called
spontaneous healing actually have a flow
state at their heart and it's this
particular process that's doing it.
Wow.
It almost.
It makes sense if you look at it,
look at the opposite,
right?
What?
What is the big diminisher of people's
health?
It's stress,
right?
It's stress and depression,
bad feelings,
and it's always followed by degrading of
the immune system.
Health goes poor.
That totally makes sense.
If you're happy and either achieve that.
That's what I meant earlier when I said
every disease is psychosomatic,
right?
Like I'm not saying there aren't
physical causes,
but like,
you know,
whatever
I used to think about the mind body
split is absolute complete nonsense,
right?
We now know that there's as many kind of
neurons in your heart and your stomach
as you had in your brain until
body system.
Yeah.
I'm sure you have concentrated on
probiotics and the probiotics have
unconsciousness and the way you feel way
I feel.
Yes.
Consciousness.
How they think it even forms your
personality.
That's interesting.
The microbiome.
Yeah.
Well,
one thing.
So you know,
candy,
which is another one of those diseases
nobody believes you have.
Um,
when you're on antibiotics for three
years,
you've totally throw off the human
microbiome.
And one of the things that happens when,
when candidate,
when you get overrun by yeast,
right,
is you get extremely,
extremely anxious and paranoid.
Why?
Because yeast feeds on sugar,
which is fast
energy.
So if I make you super anxious and
paranoid,
you're gonna want to eat sugar because
you're going to want the fast energy
because you might have to fight or do
something so you can get taken over.
It's a chemical imbalance and it makes
you paranoid and anxious.
And what it really is is is the east set
craving sugar,
but it totally takes over your
consciousness and I always thought that
was interesting because if you were to
really poke at people and you're like,
well,
what is really you?
What is the,
what do you see?
They're gunna often come back to their
emotions.
Will I am my emotions?
Right?
And here's this tilting your microbiome
with.
The first thing that happens is they
hijack your emotions,
right?
So it can get the food at once,
but you're definitely not completely in
control of your emotions.
What's so difficult?
When we look in the mirror,
we see an individual,
we see a unique thing,
but what we are is we're not.
Yeah,
you're a hybrid.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I will.
I mean,
so one of the questions,
and nobody has an answer to this
question,
but I think it's really,
really neat,
so if you study flow,
if you study optimal performance,
and I've been asking people this
question,
well,
okay,
I can tell you how it works in the brain
for sure and some of the body,
but like if I'm going to drop into flow,
does my microbiome help?
Is it's a collective experience or if
it's optimal performance,
is it everything in the system?
Nobody can even start to poke at those
questions but would super interesting to
me if they think it affects your
personality and they think it affects
your moods and it they think it effects
your intelligence level,
your Iq level.
I mean there's,
there's all these new things are
constantly correlating on a daily basis
with your gut biome,
the mean and,
and taking in probiotics.
For me it's,
it's vastly improved my sick to healthy
days.
Oh yeah.
That for sure that for sure without yet
without a question.
No question whatsoever.
Once I started eating Kimchi,
the Kimchi is a big one for me.
I eat that stuff all the time.
I drink Kombucha daily every day.
I drink that stuff.
I eat a lot of yogurt and I'm constantly
taking in different kinds of probiotics.
Once I started,
they also did this thing called total
gut health.
It's an audit,
a thing that we sell.
I just try to get as many different
forms of probiotics and as possible and
because of that I'm fucking constantly
traveling.
I travel constantly.
I rarely get sick and if I do it's like
a day or two and then it's gone and I
really.
I credit.
I think it's the probiotics.
I think it's Kimchi and Kombucha.
I think those are two big ones.
I also noticed in this could we meet
talking about but because there might be
no science here,
but I stopped once I started taking
probiotics regularly.
I stopped tearing things as much,
tearing muscles for whatever reason,
and I could be done to the core of that.
I've never read anything about it,
but it's one thing that I noticed.
Maybe you're just not doing stupid shit.
Maybe you're not as anxious.
Oh No,
I'm doing stupid shit.
That doesn't stop.
Yeah.
I wonder,
man,
I just,
it's,
it is incredible to think of yourself as
a community.
It's incredible to think of yourself as
some sort of a weird ecosystem.
I read an article.
I think you could.
I think it's unfair.
Yeah.
I think it's on Forbes that I wrote a
called you or not you.
Is that on your website
now?
But it was an article I wrote for my,
for my blog.
So if you go to,
I wrote a blog for Forbes for like four
or five years called far from tears.
Um,
and I think the piece is called you are
not you,
but it wasn't until recently that we had
the knowledge to understand this and
also the time to actually sit down and
contemplate it.
Most people for the last,
you know,
whatever,
100,000
years people have been people.
It's been a fucking tooth and nail claw,
the struggle to stay alive.
You haven't had time to contemplate on
your gut biome,
you know,
this is all like really new stuff to
human beings for us to be even
considering.
So are cemented observations and ideas
of who we are now being challenged by
this notion that no,
there's a community of fucking weird
bacteria that you need.
Like that's the thing that kills you the
most about those antibiotics.
Right?
It kills all the good stuff too.
Like you feel like,
well that was A.
Yeah.
No,
I mean I,
I often think that one of the hardest
parts,
I'm sure this happens with a lot of
other diseases,
but I've noticed it with lime and I've
talked to a lot of other lyme patients,
is the antibiotics fuck you up so much.
And they mimic when your microbiome gets
that scurry,
it mimics the symptoms of lyme.
So sometimes you can't even tell you the
antibiotics actually might be making you
feel better,
but you can't tell the lie.
Maybe dying not,
but you still feel so crappy because of
what the antibiotics have done to your
symptoms and it feels like the same kind
of ailment.
Whoa,
wow.
I had staff a few years back and I took
a really strong antibiotic for it.
And uh,
the first thing I felt like was a light
headed.
And weak,
I was like,
this is a weird feeling.
I just felt really like,
how long were you on antibiotics?
I don't remember.
It wasn't that long because I caught it
really early.
My friend take caught it.
I was super lucky.
We were at the airport and I was wearing
shorts and he just looked down at my
calf and he's like,
what's that on your leg?
And I go,
no.
And he goes,
it got a little zip seals,
little zits.
I go,
yeah.
He goes,
I think you have staff like,
are you fucking serious?
I go,
it's just like little zits.
He's like,
go get it.
Checked out.
It checked out.
Yep.
Staff immediately,
boom.
Antibiotics and when it was gone pretty
far pretty quickly.
But I remember feeling like a shell for
four weeks.
I just felt like,
like there was like,
I was probably down to like 50 or 60
percent of what I used to be until it
all sort of built back up.
But luckily I was super on the ball when
it comes to probiotics and replenishing
my gut biome because I know some people
that just don't know.
They just sort of try to keep on keeping
on and you know,
you're eating cheeseburgers and fries
and you don't ever get probiotics in
your system and your gut biome suffers
and you know,
you go on this sort of spiral of
deterioration because of that.
Health wise
it's critical.
We did that.
So why did your lyme gets so bad?
Like I've never heard of anybody having
it for three years like that.
Well it took them,
I don't know,
so it took them almost a year
to find it.
So that's really what it is.
It's how long do you have it before you
get there?
So it took them,
you know,
I,
I was tested for everything because they
just didn't like the guy,
you know,
the guy didn't believe I have line.
Nobody believed that I had lyme since
the AIDS guy.
The same guy.
Same Guy.
You didn't get a second opinion.
I was,
it was,
was 30.
I was poor.
I didn't have,
I always say this,
my healthcare,
this was my doctor that,
you know,
fuck.
Wow.
So because of that,
because by the way I did when I finally
was like,
okay,
I gotta like just go out and network and
find infectious disease doctor.
I remember walking in,
I told him all my symptoms and I was
like,
you don't think I'm crazy,
do you like I,
I'm certainly wondering my
hypochondriac.
Am I making this shit up?
Like,
what's going on?
He looked right at me and said,
no,
I don't think you're making it up.
I think you have lyme.
Let's test you for it.
And sure enough.
So did you call the other guy up and go,
hey,
fuck face,
I don't have aids.
Something like that.
I'd be so mad.
Yeah.
I mean the incentive of someone getting
$77,
$7 to treat you,
you know,
not a lot.
So they put you on.
Yeah,
I blame the insurance company is much
more than the doctors on that one.
I'm sure.
So they put you on these hardcore
antibiotics.
Um,
and I mean how is that how one year
without diagnosing become two years of
treatment?
Well,
it,
I couldn't get better.
I just was not getting better.
I,
in fact,
I got,
even after they found it,
I,
you know,
it took me a long,
I was probably on the antibiotics for
like four or five months before I even
started getting made it to the better
and then yeah,
it was just a long,
slow process that scares the shit out of
me.
That's all coming from a tick.
A buddy of mine,
his,
um,
his son got it.
And is the same thing.
Took him to a pediatrician.
Not,
I don't think so.
I don't think it's long and he starts
getting bell's Palsy.
We're half his face was paralyzed and
then finally they test them for it.
It's interesting.
I met a,
a uh,
uh,
I guess this happens,
you know,
it produces really bad arthritis,
right?
Um,
but,
and I guess it can go either it gets
into your,
it goes either towards your brain or in
that direction.
But I'm,
I met a woman.
Beautiful,
beautiful,
beautiful.
Probably late twenties.
But if you looked at her hands,
look like they had the hands of like a
hundred year old woman.
Her fingers had literally twisted almost
into circles.
I'd never seen anything like it.
It was insane.
And again it was,
it was,
it was live.
It was really a strange thing.
How long did she have it before the same
kind of thing.
God Damn.
So now you don't suffer any
repercussions?
No,
I'm one of the,
I've totally back to normal.
I,
you know,
a lot of people,
um,
don't ever recover.
I,
it took me,
so it was the surfing and the flow and
all that.
All that work got me back to about 80.
It took a long time to go from 80 all
the way to 100 percent and I worked with
Mark Gordon then.
So we,
we,
you know,
I always,
people always ask,
what did you
do to,
to caroline,
can I use your protocol?
And I'm like,
you won't do it.
And people like,
what do you mean?
I was like,
well,
I used action sports and flow states.
I took steroids and medical marijuana
and those were the three things that
really worked for me.
So steroids,
pot and action sports,
that's like a party man.
Magic healing protocol for lyme.
Um,
so what other,
was it just the surfing or what other,
um,
action sports.
Did you engage in the put in the truck
at the time it was mostly,
it was mostly surfing though.
I was doing,
uh,
you know,
as I was recovering after like the
surfing was what I was doing and it
would knock me on my ass for a long
time,
but after I started to get a little more
physical,
I started,
um,
you know,
I was,
I would do long hikes with my dog
through the woods,
which to me will produce a low grade
flow state for sure.
Being out in nature obviously does that
to me a lot.
Um,
and being with being with my dog at that
time did it.
So there was that also,
once I got enough of my brain back and I
started writing at that point it was,
I was writing the west to Jesus when my
second book,
which was the book that sort of covered
this,
a little bit of this stuff that started
producing massive amounts of flow.
One of the things about flow is the more
flow you have,
the more flow you haven't float will
cross domains if you end up with a lot
of flow while surfing or fighting or
whatever,
it'll start bleeding into your other
work because it's just a focusing skill,
right?
It's training the brain to focus in a
particular way and you can train it up
so the more flow you have,
the more flow you have.
So those used boots and performance that
you start getting in surfing will start
bleeding into your writing.
And suddenly,
you know,
everything in my life just started
clicking in the writing started
producing a lot of flow.
Um,
and eventually I started skiing has
always been my,
my,
my core deep sport.
But that it took a while till I was
strong enough.
It's a hell of a lot easier to ride a
long board in the waves and it is to try
to go hurdling down a mountain on skis
really isn't for me.
It was for me in terms of energy
expenditure.
I can't speak for everybody else,
but for me,
um,
because I already knew how to surf.
I didn't have to learn how to surf and
once you know how to surf,
riding a long board,
especially if you're writing super
friendly wave,
sunset or Malibu,
places like that.
Not
severely taxing.
I've never served,
but have always been compelled or just
there's something about it being on that
water and it's grieving and its own
thing,
but the whole monsters in the water
thing.
I can't get over that to everybody.
It's amazing how many people have this
phobia.
It is astounding how many people are.
We're afraid of sharks.
Where do you think that comes from?
The fucking sharks,
man.
That's what it comes from.
This is millions of them.
They're out there fucking swimming
around.
You're getting hit by lightening are
greater than getting eaten by a shark.
Next time you say that to someone,
I want you to recognize that your
chances of getting eaten by a shark or
zero,
if you don't go in the ocean,
zero percent,
it will never fucking happened,
but that's one thing you never have to
worry about.
Very few things
on this planet that feel as good or as
uniquely good as surfing.
Believe you and you'll never get that
experience for an experience junkie such
as yourself.
I don't know about that,
man.
I think you're missing something.
Might be right.
You might be right,
but I ain't skydiving.
I have a buddy of mine who's a fucking.
He does one of those squirrel suits from
Andy.
He's always sending me videos.
Is Crazy.
Fuck.
He's like,
he holds the world record.
Doesn't hold the world record for like
the longest.
A squirrel fucking flying squirrel.
Suit jumping.
He's crazy.
I think that's the official term to
fucking squirrels.
But he's a.
he's a legit wildman.
What's Sandy's last name?
Stump former navy seal and you know,
he,
he's just super type a Alpha needs that
risk and he sends me videos of him with
a gopro looking down.
What does this area.
Yeah,
18 miles.
Yeah.
What in the fuck.
Eighteen miles.
Come on son.
That's awesome.
He sent me a video the other day of him
like looking over the edge of a cliff,
like from his perspective,
and then he just slowly tips forward and
jumps off of it and starts flying.
You're like,
fuck that.
I threw my phone across the room,
like,
I don't even want to look at that man.
Like,
why do you do that?
You know,
it must be fun.
Must Be.
Well,
it's.
I mean,
you know,
Dean Potter before it,
before he died,
he was a climber and a,
uh,
another wind suit guy and he,
you know,
he died.
See the guy that slammed into the
bridge,
not the bridge.
Oh,
body slamming into a notch,
a notch and rock.
And he was flying.
It was a new cemetery.
He slammed into a cliff called lost
brother.
I want to say fast.
Were you going terminal velocity?
So 30,
3,140
miles an hour is coming to holy shit.
Wrong.
Why they call it terminal velocity
because everybody dies.
Is that what they call a terminal?
That maximum that you can.
You can hit it.
Oh,
if you're not a pair of Jean Falcon.
Exactly.
Is this handy?
Fucking crazy asshole.
Look at this.
God Damn.
That must be fun though,
right?
Would you that?
Yeah,
I've skydived before.
What'd you do this?
A hesitation.
The hesitation.
So it's only because I'm married and I
run a dog that like when I get cancer.
Hail,
yes,
you won't just cure it with flow state.
I May,
but you're not going to give that.
And by the way,
if you know that's a beaut flow trigger.
Oh,
I want to flip one like crazy when
you're flying 18 miles and a squirrel
suit,
we now know there we think there are,
we know of 20 flow triggers right there.
Probably would.
Are there.
Can you list them off?
No,
but I can list off some of them.
I mean I could probably list them all
but it would give me a couple of,
uh,
so,
but think about all these ones that.
So these are all things that grab hold
of your attention and sort of drive it
into the now.
So risk.
And it's not just physical risk,
right?
You emotional or a spiritual risk.
Arrests.
Social risk is phenomenal.
Your social risks,
your brain can't tell the difference
between social fear and physical fear.
So when people have unsafe sex,
when they have sent some strangers that
flow state thing,
maybe flip some Weirdo at a bar and just
come on,
let's do it.
Take them back to your house,
you anything.
Now they know where you live.
Oh,
I don't even know you.
I like how your role.
Yeah.
No.
Uh,
that's not,
that's not a flow state.
It may be,
it may be.
Um,
no,
I was just talking about this with
somebody a couple days ago.
We haven't,
I mean obviously there's all kinds of
sexual flow triggers because obviously
sex grabs hold of your attention.
We just haven't.
It hasn't been looked at,
but novelty,
complexity,
unpredictability,
a deep embodiment,
which is when you're paying attention to
multiple sensory streams.
One,
so not just like,
you know,
a head on a stick looking at a computer
screen,
but you're,
you know,
instead of learning through that way,
you're learning through doing so often.
Give you an example.
Montessori education,
when they went looking for nonsports
examples of really high flow
environments,
a Montessori education is very high on
the list.
Um,
and uh,
one of the reasons is Montessori
education is often talked about is
embodied education and they emphasize
learning through doing.
So don't just read about the windmill.
Go out and build one when you're going
out and building one,
you're engaging multiple sensory
streams.
You're working with your hands,
working with your eyes.
Obviously.
Drive attention into the now tends to
drive flow.
Yeah.
A lot of like super successful and
creative people came from Montessori
education.
Yeah.
There was a Wall Street Journal article
about the Montessori Mafia,
but all the ceos in Silicon Valley were
Montessori educated.
Wow.
That's.
My friend went.
He took his son to Montessori,
but who's like,
why is my kid like who's six in school
with a bunch of 14 year olds?
They're all in the same class.
He's like the,
they have different age kids all hang
out together.
Yeah,
because it's self directed learning.
Yeah.
He didn't like that.
Makes Sense.
I mean,
it makes sense that,
look,
I would imagine that having all these
different things,
examples of,
you know,
oh,
that's what a 16 year old girls like,
you know,
when you're six,
that's what a 12 year old boys like,
you know,
the greatest.
I mean,
for me,
I don't know about six,
but I was a 10 on.
I was a magician.
That was my first job.
I was pressed to digitor.
I did birthday parties and misses and
yeah.
And uh,
um,
you got hired.
Yeah,
I know.
11.
Arthur Benjamin,
who lived a crazy.
If I have lived a crazy life.
This guy was Arthur Benjamin who became
a mathematics genius.
He's the guy.
He's got a Ted famous Ted talk where he
squares numbers faster than calculators
and whatever.
I knew him.
He was from Cleveland,
Ohio with me.
And he was a magician.
He hit the ground round restaurant.
He was doing birthday parties on
Saturday and Sunday.
He went to college and he,
I was one of the only other magicians he
knew.
So he gave me the job.
I was 11 or 12 at the time.
So I,
you know,
I was every weekend I was,
and I was making a ton of cash for it,
like an 11,
12 year old.
I was making 40 bucks a day for doing
like three birthday parties on Saturday
and three on Sunday.
Tiny money for her kid.
I think I bought a car in cash when I
was 16 with it,
which they bought a bunch of it,
the most obnoxious thing of the world,
the 16 year old kid walking in with a
big role.
But I don't know how we got in to the
magic word restart.
I don't know.
Close date risks.
How do we get the Magicians Jamie?
First job.
There's no,
we're still not getting back there.
I don't know.
Okay.
So interesting tidbit about Steven that
not many people now now they do to,
we'll call it,
that we're discussing is all the various
flow triggers and we're talking about
unsafe sex.
Maybe that's what it is.
You're having unsafe sex,
sex.
He wrote lots of lots of.
I'm going to leave that one alone.
Those other.
I'm not going there with you pulling
rabbits out of your hat and found me
out.
So when,
when you document all these years,
various flow states,
you know,
whether they're social flow state,
what,
whatever it is or triggers rather social
triggers,
environmental danger,
risk.
You were talking about a bunch of
different stimuli that's happening
simultaneously.
You were talking about not just one form
of information coming at you,
but several.
And that's when he started talking about
the being a magician,
wasn't it?
Am I?
Right.
Thanks.
So I think so.
Yeah.
That was it.
Uh,
yeah.
I'm not going to be able to rewind it
back.
It doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter to magic.
Sorry.
Not.
There's all these different factors and
all these different forms of stimulation
that can sort of trigger this optimal
state,
its optimal state of consciousness.
And you've sort of documented cities and
studied these.
And what is your take out of it?
Like what,
what,
what is like when you step back and you
look at the book you wrote and you look
at all the research that you've done,
you look at all the talks you've given
and all the conversations that you've
had about it.
What can you impart on people that would
allow them to sort of be able to absorb
some of this into their life?
Does that make sense?
Meaning what can average people do?
What can the average person do to sort
of.
I feel like most things require a step.
Most things require like a little
dipping your toe into the water as it
were to sort of get,
get stimulated or get excited about
doing something like this.
What do you think like the average
person should do just to try to feel
what a flow state could be?
Is there any one thing?
Yeah,
that's an interesting question.
It's kind of a.
it's a.
it's a great question.
I think there's lots of stuff.
How do you.
I mean yoga is a pretty good one,
right?
Yeah.
A lot of,
a lot of people can
use yoga as a great kind of gateway into
flow.
It's really easy because it,
it combines,
you know,
a lot of,
like we'll do really simple things when
we start working with people.
Like if we're working in a corporate
environment,
for example,
people,
you know,
Mckinsey did a 10 year study and they
found that top executives in flow are
five times more productive than out of
flow.
So that's 500 percent more.
How do they decide that you're in
Florida?
They were,
this was a survey.
They surveyed thousands of top
executives and just ask them how much
more productive are you in flow?
Um,
but you,
there are psychological questionnaires
is kind of a sampling bias there though,
because the people that are successful,
like,
yeah,
it was flowing,
bro.
It might be you,
you might be right about that.
I haven't,
I haven't dug deep enough into that.
That's an interesting point.
Okay.
So this may be,
maybe,
maybe it's not that,
right?
That said,
first thing we do when we start working
with corporations is tell people that
you don't turn off your cellphone.
Turn off,
he like flower quarters,
I don't know.
No concentration.
So shut everything off,
you know,
have you.
If you can't,
you know,
you can't.
It's hard to sort of tack flow onto your
life.
You sort of got to put it the center of
what you do.
And for most people that seems like the
state is,
there's so much creativity,
there's so much motivation,
there's learning,
accelerates,
all the,
all that stuff to the upside is,
is worth it,
that people will start to build their
lives around the state.
Um,
you know,
I.
Yoga is a pretty easy way in.
I think it,
I think a lot of people can kind of
taste it that way.
Um,
you know,
it's interesting.
So in,
in stealing fire in my,
in my next book and the book that comes
out.
And what is it about worry word stealing
fire is a,
bout a $4,000,000,000,000
underground revolution in altered states
of consciousness that is,
you know,
involves kind of the top performance
from pretty much every domain and no
one's talking about it.
And yet if you know where to look,
it's everywhere you look.
So it's a book about a revolution and
people utilizing altered states of
consciousness.
I'm to massively drive performance and
across all different kinds of altered
states.
Wow.
Did that piece of shit crash again?
How dare you try castor?
Whoever the fuck is making the tricaster
you fucking mutts.
Your machine sucks.
What is it goes down every time.
It's the video switcher.
So now we're still.
We're still recording,
but the audio version,
Jamie will have to splice the audio
recording into the video recording now
and we're going to have to a yell at
these tricaster people.
This has been happening on a regular
basis.
Now.
Only the best thing you can buy.
It's only the best fucking piece of
equipment you could buy anyway.
This,
this,
um,
altered states of consciousness
research,
like what are they concentrating on?
All the different,
various altered states of consciousness.
So what
one of the interesting things is,
and we talk about this in stealing fire,
is a lot of.
We use the term Iq status.
It's a,
it's a Greek term and it's what ecstatic
comes from ecstasy from,
from.
But it originally means if you go back
to Plato,
it means estate beyond your normal sense
of self,
where you tend to be filled with
information and inspiration or intuition
like.
So that was the classic Greek definition
of extensive if you.
So we are interested in those altered
states that tend to produce this,
this particular experience and that's
everything from contemplated and
mystical states flow states of,
of all kinds of psychedelic states fall
into this category as well in the.
I mean the interesting thing is we've
been talking a lot about the
neurobiology of flow,
right?
What goes on under the hood.
But the interesting thing,
and this is what sort of like,
if you go back 100 years,
William James,
who kind of early Harvard psychologists
you know,
bought,
flow states,
mystical experiences,
contemplate of experiences,
psychedelic experiences.
He thought they were all the same thing,
right?
They weren't split apart over the course
of the past hundred years.
We split those things apart.
But what's happening now is we can look
under the hood and when you look under
the hood and you look at flow versus say
a near death experiences versus a
psychedelic state,
very,
very similar things are happening in the
brain in all these states,
prefrontal Cortex,
parts of the brain,
or deactivating and get the same five or
six neurochemicals.
You have brainwave moving towards Alpha
Theta.
They're all very similar.
They may get you there in different ways
like psychedelics,
for example,
a inflow.
It's an efficiency exchange,
right?
So what happens is we trade and our
brain has a fixed energy budget.
It's an energy hog,
right?
Uses about 25 percent of your energy,
yet two percent of your mass,
20,
25 percent of your energy.
It's got a fixed energy budget.
So what happens in flow is we allocate
more and more energy for focus and
attention,
and then the brain starts shutting down
noncritical structures,
right?
That's what happens.
That's why your sense of self
disappears.
That's why time passes strangely.
It's that efficiency exchange.
Psychedelics also downregulate the
prefrontal cortex.
They do it by overwhelming,
right?
They let in so much stimuli that you can
no longer process it with your conscious
mind.
It sort of kicks things over to the
subconscious,
but the end result is the same.
You get this sense of selflessness and
timelessness,
effortlessness and information richness
that shows up in all these states.
All these states,
they have different names,
but you look under the hood and the
neurobiology is the same.
And the experience like how we feel in
the estates,
well,
we feel like our sense of self has
disappeared.
We feel like time is passing strangely.
There all effortless effort.
Like when you're in flow,
every decision,
every action follows seamlessly,
fluidly,
perfectly from the next.
That's sort of the definition of flow.
And they're all information rich states.
So we tend to think.
I tend to think about these things I'm
saying we,
because I co wrote this book with my
partner Jamie Wheal,
who I started the flow genome project
with.
Um,
I tend to think of all these states is
sort of like big data for the mind to
access to a much more information
inspiration,
but they seem to be all the same
experience under the hood.
So what this means is why is this giant
revolution will cause.
There's all these different subcultures
that are doing different things and it's
not,
you know,
you can get the same effects
technologically transcranial
stimulation.
You can,
you,
you can use weak magnetic pulses to
knock out the prefrontal cortex.
And they're now doing that.
I don't like,
I don't know if you're following this,
but um,
you know,
in,
in stealing fire we did a lot of work
with,
with the Navy seals and you know,
if you dig under the hood with seal
training,
they'll tell you that,
you know,
obviously there's levels of physical
skills and you know,
tactical sales that you have to have.
But most everything else that we think
of as seal training is a giant group
flow filtration system.
So they can get,
you know,
the screening for people who can drop
into glue group flow together at the
click of a hat.
Because it's how you work best work at a
team,
you see the same kind of things across
the boards and all of these high
performing groups,
but the seals don't think of themselves
in the same way that the yoga moms think
of themselves.
They would never say we're doing the
same thing,
or you know,
the hippies and Ravers who were taken
acts or drive.
You would never think that these people
are involved in the same revolution they
were in this world than say moon is
absolutely the same thing.
They're seeking the same ability to
change the channel.
And the reason is there are certain
quote unquote skills.
Twenty first century skills,
whether it's healing,
massive trauma,
anxiety,
um,
or creativity,
cooperation in these kinds of things
were the way we've been built from an
evolutionary standpoint to optimize
those things is through altered states,
is through changing the channel and
utilizing non ordinary states of
consciousness.
So the book is about getting the giant
revolution that's going on with this and
kind of four emerging forces that are
driving this forward and making it go
faster and wider.
Have you concentrated on holotropic
breathing or meditation practices?
Are Kundalini or any of those things?
We focus on.
We looked at,
we looked at all that stuff and
obviously,
you know,
respiration breathing stuff is easiest
possible way in the world that change
your consciousness.
Right?
And I mean in everybody,
you know,
whether it's on the vm off side with his
kind of crazy version of,
of breath,
of fire,
which has a long history in yoga,
you know,
everybody sort or whether it's,
you know what Laird Hamilton and Brian
Mackenzie are doing,
you know,
what are they doing on the pool
training?
They're just a different version they're
using.
It's different versions of apnea
training where they're using various
breath holds and things along those
lines to alter consciousness in abet.
Performance seems to be kind of going on
across the boards everywhere.
Well,
the respiration stuff,
Hixon Gracie,
who's probably the greatest Jujitsu
practitioner of all time,
at least he certainly wasn't his era,
recognized by everyone as being the
best,
was a massive yoga practitioner who is a
Yogi and one
of the things that he was really deeply,
deeply invested in his breath work and
he would do that crazy shit where he
sucks his stomach up deep into his rib
cage.
Have you ever seen,
I know extent do that.
When he does it,
it's super bizarre because he's got
amazing control so his stomach is like
going in and also the people say it's
the secret.
If you want the lower kind of add band,
you have to learn to suck it in.
I don't know.
I never really played with lots of
static.
I mean it is aesthetic thing he's not
doing.
I mean he's trying to do is achieve this
complete control of the breath for sure.
And in Jujitsu that's really important
because there's many times where you're
locked up on something and you're,
you're panicking and when you're
panicking,
you're heartbeats too fast.
You need more oxygen and you can't
breathe and you freak out,
and the ability to stay calm and
controlled is directly related to your
ability to control your breathing.
One of the first things you know we
train people to do is,
so if you,
if your exhale is about seven seconds or
longer,
you probably know this.
You can't have a fight or flight
response because your brain goes,
oh,
look at this long,
luxurious exhale.
You must be calm so you won't panic.
So one of the,
you know,
with when working with action sport
athletes or people you know,
I guess you could do with fighters as
well,
we've done it with some of the,
some of the special forces guys just
really slowing down the breathing,
the exhale a little bit in most
situations,
probably couldn't do it mid fight,
probably certain sports situation can't
do it,
but you can always usually get like a
three second inhale and a seven second
exhale and you know,
you do about three of those and you will
really calm down your central nervous
system really quickly.
That's really interesting.
There's a thing that happens in a
bowhunting they called target panic and
it's the dealing,
the difference between a closed loop
system and an open loop system,
meaning when you are in the middle of
doing something and you're when you're
drawing back on an animal,
you panic and you just slam the trigger
and you freak out and your emotions and
your,
your anxiety gets carried away with you,
but if you follow a certain protocol and
pay attention to all your movements and
have everything in a row,
then your concentration on your movement
sort of overtakes your anxiety and all
the issues that you would have and it
allows you to carry through with this
very difficult thing in this very
intense and sort of like pressure field
filled situation.
That makes sense.
Did it go down again?
It's completely acting way up.
I can't even look.
Click on anything right now.
I've tried to reset it five times so.
Well.
Well we'll splice in the audio to the
video.
This fucking piece of shit.
Um,
when you guys went,
you know,
concentrating on these different altered
states of consciousness,
do you have like a hierarchy of them?
Do you just,
uh,
examine all of them?
Are some of them more beneficial than
others?
So let me get it.
Let's get it.
Let's talk about,
let's,
let's look at trauma for example.
Okay.
So what
they all seem to do the same thing.
It's timescale.
So we know Michael Mithoefer hoffer's
work used mgma for to treat ptsd in
victims of child abuse and sexual abuse
and trauma from the wars in Iraq and
Afghanistan.
Right?
This is the work that went down in South
Carolina that lead right there was the
foundational work.
And what they discovered,
what he's discovered is one to three
sessions with Mtma therapy is enough to
significantly reduce or completely
remove ptsd symptoms.
Right?
And they've done a lot of this.
So they redid that at Camp Pendleton
with about a thousand soldiers and
instead of Mtma,
they replaced it with flow.
They used surfing as a flow trigger and
talk therapy.
And they've done this with about a
thousand soldiers this,
this point.
So.
And they're getting the same end
results,
but it takes about five weeks of surfing
and talk therapy.
So the MTMA get to these results in
about one to three sessions,
so three days tops,
five weeks with the surfing,
with the surfing and talk therapy.
And then they redid it again,
different different scientists with
meditation and it takes about 12 weeks
with meditation and they can't get it.
I don't think they've gotten a total
reduction of ptsd symptoms with
meditation,
but for sure people's with meds drop.
So it's the same sort of result,
different timescales.
Right.
So it's the interventions are doing the
same thing inside the brain,
right?
The same thing as sort of happening.
It's a question and it's really how much
risk you want to take Mtma.
Well you got to put an amphetamine into
your system surfing.
There's a little bit of risk out there.
And the waves,
not particularly dangerous meditation.
There's almost no risk.
So where,
where are your risk tolerances?
How much time do you have?
Those are the kinds of questions you can
ask around this.
It sounds like the MTMA also would be
way easier for it to be effective,
whereas with surfing or something like
that,
you'd have to really stick to some sort
of a protocol here.
Have stick.
They're constantly doing it.
Really getting involved in staying
engaged in it where if you do ecstasy,
you kind of have to be engaged.
So just takes what hunter said right by
the ticket.
Take the ride.
Yeah,
it just takes you.
Look,
here we go.
Come on.
Let me write that.
When I talk about effortlessness,
right?
With flow,
it's every action,
every decision leads seamlessly,
perfectly.
The next one,
you talking about the effortlessness of
a psychedelic experience,
you know,
drop the pill,
take the hit,
and you are effortlessly in another
altar.
You know what I mean?
You're there.
Well,
I'm.
I'm really excited about the fact that
marijuana has been legalized in
California and now I hopefully I hope
we're going to start to see some headway
being moved into other psychedelic
drugs,
whether it's mushrooms or Lsd.
I think there's a lot of drugs that
could be incredibly beneficial to people
that aren't being utilized where it's
Ibogaine.
I believe we were talking about that
before the.
We were talking
about animals that target various,
various ways of altering their states of
consciousness.
You know,
I know dolphins find puffer fish and get
high upper fish puff,
puff pass our goats,
gobble,
locoweed loco,
loco loco.
We'd is cows.
Cats are catnip.
Baboons,
as we talked about where I boga,
um,
the reindeer obviously are going after
the mushrooms,
many to ms Dot Kara.
Dogs are gone for silicide.
Been is what they found.
But there are probably other things.
Elephants pretty much at any animals
found a way to alter their
consciousness.
Elephants will drink fermented bog
water.
There's otters if they can't,
and I can't remember what their drug of
choice is,
but if they can't find it,
they will actually hit themselves in the
head with a rock to alter their
consciousness.
Right?
Oh my God,
I've done that personally on,
uh,
on occasion a couple of times.
You know,
you know what,
I'm going to be hard outs,
but I watched a hotter kill a monkey the
other day online.
Otter drowned a monkey.
It was fucking crazy.
Like in the other markets to trying to
rescue them,
the monkey.
And he's like,
fuck you.
And the audit took the monkey and was
holding on him when drowning them.
Wow.
Yeah.
Otters are murderers.
I had no idea.
Yeah.
Um,
I had no idea the,
yeah,
they're uh,
they're crazy little animals.
But you were listing before the podcast
started all the various animals that
have found some way to alter their
consciousness and it's almost all of
them.
Yeah.
So this is not.
This is the guy who did this original
work.
Let's give credit where credit is due.
It's Ronald K Siegel.
He's at Ucla.
And if you really want to read the
cortext on this,
it's a book called intoxication.
And it covers kind of everything.
But at this point they believe that
pretty much every,
you know,
at least mammalian species and earth,
the birds do it.
Two birds will go crazy for marijuana
seeds if they can get them,
has found a way to alter their
consciousness and there's very few,
we were talking about this earlier,
but there's very good reasons for it and
it's animals,
like humans get stuck in ruts and they,
you know,
you,
you keep doing the same pattern over and
over and you're getting no results and
you have to be to kind of shift your
state,
changed the channel.
And so using the Edward Edward de Bono,
uh,
talks about psychedelics in these kinds
of substances,
d patterning instruments,
they allow us to break out of our
patterns and they allow us to innovate.
Basically they put us in,
you know,
innovative Switzerland,
which for survival is critical.
So every species seems to have found one
way or the other to alter their
consciousness to upc kind of cognitive
performance and creativity.
Problem solve.
This is fascinating that these animals
would want that.
You would think that what they would
want is to be constantly,
hey,
look at that.
We're on TV,
we're back up.
No,
you would think that these animals would
want to be constantly aware of their
surroundings and constantly alert.
Yes.
So that was the question,
right?
That was the big question that they
started to ask is like with the fuck
with this come from like how if,
if,
if it's red in tooth and claw
out there,
why would you possibly,
you know,
want to take a psychedelic like Iboga
where you're talking about the Jaguars
taking Iowasca where the effects are
significant and long lasting.
So,
and the,
the,
the answer seems to be that the creative
problem solving boost you get from
psychedelics is worth.
It could just be that the highfields so
good that everybody wants it.
But yeah.
Well it also could be like some sort of
a stress alleviation mechanism for a lot
of these animals that are dealing with
the Tooth Fang and clogs assistance of
being a wild animal.
It just distress if at all.
Like sometimes I just need a little
break,
so drink some fermented fruit,
fermented Bhagwat water whacked out and
chill out.
For Awhile we were talking about the
Jaguars that take a dmt rich plants is.
So here's the thing I don't understand,
isn't Ios is a blend of two different
plants.
Right.
So how did the Jaguars get both?
That's a good question.
Well,
the question would be whether or not
Jaguars have monoamine oxidase and your
stomach.
Okay.
Yeah,
that's the exact question that they
don't.
That would make sense.
Yeah.
So what if they don't?
That means that it's active to them.
Right.
So we,
you know,
we eat plants and we meet,
we're omnivores.
They are obligate predators so they
don't need any plants.
So when they do eat plants,
they're just eating them for a goof.
So if they do eat them,
they probably don't have the
compensatory mechanisms in their system
to process the DMT rich plants.
And we do,
you know,
that's what model amy knock stays does.
That's why Mao inhibitors or you know,
they use harming,
they mix it up with the.
But people that have taken actual,
like pharmaceutical grade Mao inhibitors
to have horrible experiences.
Like if you,
if you try to use an,
a real Mao inhibitor,
like from a pharmaceutical company and
then throw some dmt in there as well.
Apparently it's a real bad time.
Oh Wow.
Yeah,
and it's super dangerous and you know,
you could break your fucking brain.
There's some would story,
some horror stories.
It might be or what it might be some
other website where the people were
documenting trips.
Hyperspace lexicon.
Yeah.
And they were just saying,
hey,
don't do this important safety tip.
I've also heard horrible experiences of
people mixing mushrooms and DMT.
I've heard really bad experiences with
that as well.
That's interesting.
And it seems like it has a habit not to
get metaphysical about DMT,
but it has a habit of smacking down
certain users.
A lot of people tell those stories that
something about the substance doesn't
allow itself to be abused.
You find that a lot in our wood and the
hyperspace lexicon,
places like that.
That sort of gets to a point and then it
warns you and cutting out the other.
Interesting.
I don't have any idea what the hell that
means,
and I just said it,
but like it's interesting.
That's the exact description of a
tattooist that I know who had done it
like 100 days in a row and then finally
he said like literally when he tripped,
he went into this dimension and they
were,
they were kicking them.
They were like,
listen,
you fuck you gotta.
Stop doing this.
They were very adamant,
damaged,
exact story happened to a friend of mine
who was just.
He was told he was,
you know,
whatever.
He's tripping balls and they were like,
you're not to do this again.
Wow,
okay.
That completely makes sense.
I mean,
if it seems to me like something that
you can only really handle in small
doses.
Occasionally he'd go in,
you get your brains blown out and he
come back,
sort of regroup.
Try to assess what,
if anything you could take out of that
and learn,
get humbled by the fact that this exists
at all and then sort of try to reassess
your life.
We talk about that a lot in stealing
fire in that,
in the book that's coming out in
February,
whereas it seems like if you've never
had any experiences with altered states,
with,
you know,
any of these flow states or you know,
whatever,
you need,
some kind of reality shattering first
experience.
So just so you know,
that this domain exists and maybe go
skydiving and have that kind of a flow
state experience or you know,
do a psycho and then you need it less
and less and less than you can get a lot
farther with less and there seems to be
some something there with that.
What about
the idea of mixing up a bunch of
different modalities?
I mean,
is there any benefit in.
Yeah,
that's.
So that's,
you're right.
What's interesting,
and this is when I'm really happy about,
and uh,
you know,
I was talking to a Rick Doblin if you
had a longtime friend of mine.
I've known him for awhile.
He is so important.
Is Awesome.
Yeah,
he's a great,
great girl.
He's dealing with maps is just so
wonderful.
So huge.
So we were talking about,
you know,
a psychedelic medicine at this point is
kind of,
you know,
everybody knows it's gone on,
but uh,
you know,
what's interesting going on at the
cutting edge and it's so basic,
it's almost stupid.
You can't even believe this,
but lo and behold,
they're discovering that if you combine
the occasional mtma session with
meditation,
occasionally you get farther,
faster,
big surprise,
right?
Yeah.
I'm this and,
and,
and you know,
the truth of the matter is once you move
into these cultures effort,
he's blending state changing
technologies.
You're using your martial arts for flow
states.
You're using your yoga breathing
techniques,
you're having the occasional psychedelic
experience at burning man.
Maybe you're smoking pot,
blah,
blah.
I mean,
everybody's blending all this stuff
together.
It's very rare that you find somebody
who's like,
okay,
I,
I only do one thing.
You know,
that they do.
If they're so rigid and they're probably
not getting the same benefits out of it,
that they would if they were just more
open and loose about it.
I think that's probably true too.
I think there's so many different ways
to endogenously a trigger,
these chemicals that I think we need to
explore more and one of the ones that
I've been talking about for so long and
I've really never get off my ass and do
it.
I've talked to so many people that get
into Kundalini,
couldn't any of that and that Kundalini
Yoga,
once you practice it for long periods of
time and once you get really good at it,
you figure out a way or your brain
figures out a way to access these
dimensions that you would normally only
achieve if you were on psychedelic
drugs.
States of minds that were very similar
to the DMT state and you can do it
through Kundalini Yoga,
but it 45 minutes of intense practice
for long periods of time.
Many,
many weeks in a row.
And then you can kind of get there.
I will say that in talking to a Brian
Mackenzie and layered with about their
kind of what they're doing and it's this
blend of a kind of like box breathing
coupled by sort of like the Wim Hoff
protocol for the breathing protocol.
But they've,
they've developed into a system,
they claim that they're getting full on
dmt experiences.
Laird Hamilton's tripping balls lot
through the,
through the breath holding work.
Yeah.
I don't know if he said,
I don't think he's doing the substance.
It doesn't have to.
I mean the brain produces the.
Which was one of the most fascinating
thing about it,
the most potent psychedelic drug known
to man.
And it's made in the body.
It's in pretty much every cell in your
body.
What it,
uh,
maybe it was Mckenna.
He was probably was Dennis Dennis,
who I think he pointed out that every
one of us is walking around with enough
of an illegal substance in our system to
go to jail forever.
You go buy an orange.
Yeah,
right.
There's enough dmt and an orange to send
you to jail for the rest of your life.
Is it real?
It's everywhere in orange.
I didn't even know they hadn't been
oranges.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
It's a weird drug when your whole.
I mean,
it's like making saliva illegal or
water.
It's,
it's so common.
It's very,
very strange.
But the fact that you can make your
brain produce large dumps of it,
that you can figure out a way.
And apparently Kundalini Yoga is the big
one.
That's interesting.
My wife practices Kundalini Yoga.
I've never asked her.
She's tripping.
No,
she hasn't.
She hasn't reported it.
She,
I mean,
she certainly gets her into flow states.
Right story of my life.
Yeah,
it is a,
it.
I think what,
what we're saying before about marijuana
being legalized and the fact that it
took until 2016 in California.
It's hilarious.
Really filled with folly.
I really hope that this opens up the
door to all these other non toxic drugs
like,
like psilocybin,
which has this ridiculously high ld 50
rate where you would literally have to
eat pounds of it to die.
And I'm,
I'm really hoping that we're going to
get more and more research and more and
more understanding things like I began
that we were talking about before the
podcast where,
um,
my friend Ed,
who has a center down in Mexico,
he was hooked on pills and he got one to
Mexico,
took an,
uh,
went on Ibogaine trip,
completely cured him of his addiction to
opiates and now he runs the center and
so many people that have had these
problems with pills,
which is a gigantic problem in our
culture today because they're so
prevalent.
I think
so much of that could be cured with
Ibogaine,
the Ibogaine hair,
you know,
opiate addiction research,
that's where the,
how the drug got interesting.
If people in the first place,
right?
They going all called the movie back to
the fifties or sixties when they first
started realizing it.
I'm certainly,
I,
you know,
I just,
there's so many great questions that you
can start asking.
You can ask when we talk about
consciousness earlier,
right there.
These are phenomenally good tools.
And you know,
I'm really,
uh,
in stealing fire where you write about
the work of Robin Card Harris,
who is the first person to use f Mri to
do visualizations of the brain on
psychedelics.
So we now know what the brain looks like
on Lsd.
We know what the world looks like on,
you know,
psilocybin as he says,
we're,
you know,
we're starting to understand where all
this mind expansion is coming from.
And we actually,
you know,
the heightened creativity that we've
been talking about,
we now know what that looks like and why
that happens.
I think we're at the front edge of
starting to ask the interesting
questions,
right?
A lot of what we've done in,
in kind of psychedelic research,
you know,
in this renaissance that we're going
through is rerun all the experiments
they ran back in the sixties and
fifties,
right?
Because nobody trusts those damn hippies
in their research.
So we've just done a lot of that work.
Yes,
we've done it more rigorously and was
slightly better tools.
But if you think about,
you know,
the classic suicide instead of the Good
Friday experiment,
you know,
it was done in the marsh chapel in 1962
and this was,
this was the first study that said,
hey,
do psychedelics produce valid quote
unquote mystical experiences.
Right.
And the and the,
the,
the study and then Rick Doblin redid it
and then Roland Griffith at Johns
Hopkins read it and then it's been.
So this one study has been redone four
times to get the exact same result
because nobody wants to believe it
because they don't trust me because
these substances are so volatile and
scare,
scare us so much.
Well not in.
Here's one thing I think also to suck
the concentrate on not just substances
but also states of mind that can be
achieved consciously,
like on purpose,
like mindfulness,
like concentrating on being in the
moment like that.
You can alter the way you view the world
by the way you concentrate on the actual
moment that you,
you're existing in right now.
Her.
Sure.
It also,
the combination of stuff as you brought
up is where also this is going to start
to get interesting when you,
when we start really figuring out how to
skillfully blend these things together,
turn them into protocols to that stuff.
A little bit of
Dma,
a little bit of meditation.
Yeah.
A little bit of this for flow a little
bit.
Uh,
you know,
and the other thing is,
psychedelics are the technology we're
talking about most now,
but most of these things are achievable
with actual technology,
right?
Do you know,
different than.
And we're going to get more of that.
For example,
there's a company called Palo Alto
Neuroscience,
Palo Alto,
neuroscience,
and this is early stages,
so we're not there yet,
but what they're working towards
figuring out is say you are a trained to
Benton Lama and you can meditate and
drop your brain down to that Alpha Theta
borderline.
They can record various biomarkers,
galvanic skin response,
you know,
a couple of these,
a bunch of other things while you're in
that meditative state.
And then they can take that recording
and an egg,
put it on somebody who's an absolute
novice and use that as neurofeedback to
guide somebody else into your state,
into the state you were in.
This is worth the front edge of that.
Right?
But more and more,
this is really starting to come some of
this stuff with,
you know,
with flow states.
We've got use neurofeedback to drive
people in the flow.
That's all the work that Chris Burkard
did it advanced brain monitoring and I
don't know if you've seen her ted talk.
She's got a great ted talk.
She did a lot of work with the navy on
it.
So you know,
we're using,
we've got technology that'll drive you
into flow.
We've got technology that is going to be
able to mimic.
So I mean,
you know,
right now today,
2016,
we're talking about psychedelics and you
know,
these pills that affect these molecules.
But we've got technology coming that's
coming,
that's letting us,
you know,
just to interface directly with the
brain.
And that's coming.
So I'm a little confused.
How are you experiencing someone else's
flow state?
What is the mechanism like if someone,
if they're recording something.
Oh,
I'm sorry,
a,
what would Chris Burke and what the guys
did it.
Advanced brain monitoring is there.
We're working with archers for example,
marksman,
um,
but they will record kind of what is
going on in the brain of an expert
marksman as at the moment they're drawn
and firing,
right?
And then they're using neurofeedback
with other participants to drive them
toward that same brain wave state.
And what they've done is they've cut
learning times in half.
So let me do it.
They can,
you can train up an APP.
They've managed to train up absolute
novices to expert performance and 50
percent less time using using this and,
but what are the novices experiencing?
Like what,
what are they doing to them?
They're novices are just using
neurofeedback,
right?
So what does that mean though?
A neurofeedback means,
I don't know how our system.
I can't remember exactly how our system
works.
We will have to pull up the ted talks so
I can see it again.
But uh,
let's say it's a tone,
right?
Let's like let's say expert performance
takes place at this borderline Alpha
Theta borderline brainwave wise.
There's a whole bunch of other things
going on and being just crunching it
down,
but you know when you're closer to there
you hear a low pitch sound and when
you're farther away,
the pitch gets higher and higher and
higher,
so you just,
you don't know what you're aiming for.
Ed's brainwaves,
you can't control your brainwaves
consciously,
but just by providing the feedback and
none,
oh,
this is the wrong state of this,
is the right to your brain will start to
learn.
That's how neurofeedback works with
trains.
You just trains your brain to move to
this brainwave state just by giving it a
little bit of a little feedback loop to
playoff
and doing this during the actual
activity itself is what accentuates the
learning.
So are they doing the archery themselves
while they're being inundated with these
tones?
Yes.
Wow,
that's fascinating.
So they're not even consciously
thinking.
What I've always wondered,
and this is why I'm bringing this up,
I've always wondered,
how far away are we from actually
recording memories?
Like you say,
if you decided to get on your snowboard
and go down a mountain and you're
wearing some sort of a device or some
you're interfacing with some sort of
device that can record all of your
physical experiences,
your emotions,
your nerves,
your immune.
You might slip a little bit and have a
little little,
little,
little scary moment and that that also
can be related and those memories and
then someone else going to be sitting
here.
You can put your whatever device it is
on them and they can interface with your
memory and they could experience your
memory.
I mean,
how far away are we from doing
something?
I feel like that I don't know.
My friend Selena smell and he does this
in a speech he gave a and I'm going to.
I'm blanking the name of the company
that's doing this,
but they are trying to figure out how to
record what goes on in the visual cortex
while you dream.
Oh,
so their ultimate goal is to be able to
play your dreams but get arrested.
What if you get arrested for your
dreams?
If you're doing horrible shit and your
dreams,
this is precog right where you were in
minority report.
It's happening.
Well,
we've got,
you know,
you can now go to jail in what should be
fined $250,000
in New York for using the wrong pronoun.
So that's probably coming to.
Yeah,
I would imagine.
I mean,
if you really can find the people who
have a higher propensity for violence
and they,
you know,
they're,
they're closer to committing violent
crimes.
They haven't done it yet,
but they're pretty close.
Well,
what do you mean?
We talked about this earlier,
what do you do with the five percent of
the population that is sociopathic?
Yeah.
What do you do?
It's a good question.
Hitler had a couple of ideas.
I don't think,
uh,
I don't think that's the way we should
go.
I think
maybe there's a way to fix them.
I mean,
maybe a cognitive research is going to
lead down past where you can understand
how to,
how to increase empathy.
Well,
yeah.
I was going to say how to cause it,
you know,
how to actually unlock it.
Maybe there's some sort of a biochemical
roadblock in the mind and they can
figure out how to unleash that and make
people understand what it is that their
actions do to other people and have them
feel it.
You know,
for whatever reason,
if someone doesn't feel empathy,
it doesn't have any feelings for anybody
else other than themselves.
There's a lot of people amongst us that
they believe are just acting like they
care.
Like they're mimicking actual emotions
and I think we've been around.
I think you've probably been around
people like that and it's weird,
you know,
like you'll,
they'll talk about something,
some horrible tragedy and they have some
weird sort of disingenuous take on it
and it's just very awkward and you're
like,
well,
I think that guy's a robot.
You know?
And then you get out of there and you're
like,
I think we might've been around a
sociopath.
You know,
that someone doesn't feel it.
They just don't feel it.
Maybe there's something in the brain
that can be unlocked and we could
eliminate that.
It might be as simple as,
you know,
like some people have asberger's,
some people have Alzheimer's,
some,
maybe some people have a lack of
empathy.
Maybe there's a doorway.
Well,
for sure they've,
they're having some success.
You know,
this is anybody on the spectrum of
autism and asperger's empathy's in
issue,
right?
Yeah.
Um,
and it,
you know,
a lot of that is their mirror neurons
aren't mirror owings,
so they're not,
um,
that.
The last time I said that out loud in
public,
I got screamed at for a very,
very long time.
Somebody screamed at you seems to be
fairly well established.
I was,
well,
I wrote a little bit about autism in a
small,
furry prayer and people whose people
really got upset when I,
when I said,
you know,
one of the things is going on with
autism,
whether we think is that your mirror
neurons are mirroring,
you can't,
you're not reading facial expressions
and emotions in people in that
community.
Got very upset with me.
Why?
I don't know.
But it was this established science
pretty much at this point.
Yeah.
Sexual was baron cone and you know,
he's,
he's a smart dude.
Um,
their take was,
I was wrong and I shouldn't be talking
about it in public.
Sacha Baron Cohen,
the not,
not,
no,
no.
He's a.
no,
not boring.
Same name.
Neuroscientists.
So he was upset at you?
No,
no.
He was the guy who did the research and
so he feels no people in the people in
that community.
I got,
I got letters and email and things along
those lines.
People posted stuff online.
They were offended that I had.
I had written about their disease
apparently.
Just because you had written about it
and you don't suffer from it.
Yeah,
I,
you're asking big why questions and I
can answer them,
but I don't know.
That's weird.
I thought so too.
Yeah.
Because if,
if some established neuroscientists has
made some sort of a connection between
that issue and you know,
you're not allowed to discuss it.
That seems really bizarre.
There's a,
there's a lot of that garden room.
Yeah.
There's a lot of that going around it.
I think there's also a,
obviously they call it the spectrum.
You know,
for a reason,
you know,
when you say someone's on the spectrum,
I mean I know people that are probably
mildly autistic,
that I know some folks that are just
Gonzo full blown,
you know,
so the prop,
it's some people that were,
they don't recognize that in themselves
or maybe they don't want to admit it.
You know,
I spent a lot of time in silicon valley
where there's a lot of that,
a lot of that.
And you know,
in fact normally used to be,
you know,
if you were on the spectrum,
you weren't
procreating as much.
Right.
But in Silicon Valley they're rich,
they're rich,
they're on the spectrum and they're
banging hot up there.
A couple of nuts.
So it's one autistic people are having
sex with other autistic animals.
One of the places we're looking at their
phone.
It's an interesting question because one
of the,
I mean,
one of the questions that this raises is
will it start to splinter the species?
Are we looking when that starts
happening,
are you looking at a new that like the
first step towards something because
there's definitely something going on
differently in their brains.
They can.
There's all kinds of superpowers and
there's all kinds of limitations right
on.
It's,
you know,
it doesn't take much to start
speciation.
Hm.
Well,
totally a good point because if you
think about it,
at one point in time we had to develop
emotions and empathy in order to unite
ourselves and to stayed together
connected in the community.
But uh,
other animals don't have that.
Like ants don't have.
That was the,
as far as we know,
right.
You know,
they,
they seem to be pretty robotic and they
also don't have any free will
whatsoever,
which is why they have those crazy aunt
spirals where they never seen the ant
death spiral.
Never seen that.
What happens is the female,
somehow or another we'll get separated
from the rest of the colony and the
males are still trying to follow the
female scent and they can't follow it.
So they're following each other and they
follow each other and what looks like a
hurricane where there's an eye of a
hurricane and the center and it's an ant
death spiral.
See that right there.
See though they're spinning around in a
circle and they will do that until they
die.
Wow.
Yeah.
They can't find the female for the
Queen.
They can't find the queen and they're
confused.
There's some sort of a disruption in the
signal that they get the pheromones that
they've.
They're getting and they're just
wandering around all fucking crazy.
And the ones in that center,
I mean that.
That mimics exactly what a hurricane
looks like.
Yeah.
Nuts.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
Non Empathetic.
Little no fucking free will have in
bitches who do you to circle?
Nothing.
They're important here in an hater.
I'm a lover of ants because without them
we wouldn't be alive.
I'm just joking around.
There's as much biomass of ants as all
the other animals combined.
It's awesome,
right?
Think of that.
Yeah.
Are.
It's a weird animal,
but they exist alongside us,
but they have completely different rules
of engagement.
You know,
their,
their world is very strange and almost
almost like mechanical.
They're almost like some weird bio
mechanisms,
you know,
she was like,
it's a collective consciousness,
right?
It's a shared consciousness,
which,
you know,
how do you even Grok that?
How do you get your head around that?
Well,
in our little world,
I don't think we have,
you know,
but we step on them.
We don't mind,
you know,
they're,
there's so little.
We don't mind squishing them.
Like you can squish them in your kitchen
and you just brush them off your pants.
Like if you kill an ant on your pants
and your kitchen,
like most people don't pick that fucker
up and he just let it drop to the,
to the proper burial you think?
Yeah.
You don't dig a hole and say your
prayers and light a candle and put up a
picture of the amt before it died.
No,
be weird if I did that too.
It would.
But there's a certain size,
like if you,
if you kill the tiniest little Gnat,
you're not really gonna do anything with
the body.
But if you stop a rat,
he had to clean that up.
You can dispose it.
Yeah.
We,
we,
you know,
there's a line.
Yeah,
there's lines is a biomass line where
animals become like super significant
and important to us.
That's interesting.
You think it's totally size related?
It's some of it's size related,
but it's also a appearance.
We like little cute mice more than we
like big fucking scary spiders.
Is he a big scary spider?
Crush that fucker with a hammer.
And I really liked spiders.
Oh yeah.
One of those weird guys.
Yeah.
I mean most people don't.
Most people suffer from at least some
form of Arachnophobia where they see
some creepy spider walking tours and be
like,
ah,
because not a lot of spiders will kill
you.
It's true.
We go specifically out hunting for like
the Tarantula migrations in New Mexico.
Do you really know when that's going on?
It's really cool if you've never seen
it,
you can see if you go to pinnacle's
National Monument,
which is up kind of around Gilroy,
um,
you can see them.
They have trashed on migrations up there
too.
And it's amazing.
Just huge column.
How many of them?
Hundreds.
Hundreds of Tarantulas.
You freaking out.
Jamie has got a rack to phobia.
Look at him.
He's covered his mouth through.
Throw up who that he's like,
like you've seen a vampire.
Did you pull up?
You pull up a tranche.
The migration.
He's terrified.
Look at him.
He's literally covering his mouth like
they're pulling out.
Cross on them.
My favorite spiders,
that Brazilian wondering spider.
You don't want that one.
It bites you.
It stings you,
and it gives you a raging hard on that
will kill you and if it doesn't kill
you,
your Dick is broken.
You'll it will break your sexuality will
literally wreck your Dick like a fucking
ballpark,
frank,
that you left on a on a,
on a grill for too long.
You know they plump.
When you cook them,
then they pop.
Yeah,
that's your Dick.
It literally,
it makes your body somehow or another
through it's injection of venom,
makes your body have this overflowing.
What is the name of the alien wandering
spider?
Why it's doing that?
Why does it have a scarier name?
No,
no.
Right?
That's what I'm saying.
It's scary looking,
but um,
they're looking at it for a,
an erectile dysfunction drug because
it's a,
it's so fucking potent and it makes
Viagra like a joke.
Jesus.
Yeah.
That's interesting.
Fascinating.
Yeah.
And it apparently does it to all the
muscles in your body.
It's something to do with everything
goes Richard.
Yeah.
Something to do with nitric oxide,
nitric,
nitric or nitrix one of those and did a,
you know,
the same sort of stuff that exists in,
like,
um,
those,
uh,
pump up workout pre,
pre workout formulas.
It give people all this energy and pump
your muscles up.
Yeah,
it does.
That nitric oxide has some sort of an
effect on muscles and it's also the same
sort of an effect that you get from
taking a Viagra,
which is why those vasodilators are
illegal in the Olympics.
You can't take Viagra has a performance
enhancing effect on muscular.
Like I did not know that.
Muscular.
That's important.
Yeah.
It's illegal in the Olympics.
I had no idea.
Yeah.
I'm by Agra.
It actually enhances endurance.
That's the reason why you get so much
blood flow to your penis is because you
know,
you just got this crazy blood flow
throughout all your muscles,
so it gives you more strength and more
endurance.
Uh,
I don't know how much of it is digital
boost energy?
It's a good question.
I'd have to look into it.
But this Brazilian wondering spider
apparently that times a fucking thousand
and 11.
Funny,
funny story.
I did some work with a woman named
Patricia Wright.
She's a macarthur genius award winning
conservationists.
She helped start a to on a national park
in Madagascar and they had these huge
hairy spiders in moment.
I found a national park.
How big you are showing me like a
football.
I'm showing this like this big.
Oh my God.
They're big.
They're huge and bigger than a softball.
Big trenchless like big translates big
crabs.
Not Quite,
but yes,
we're in the right vicinity.
They're harmless though.
There's no docks in two minutes.
I'm gonna kill him.
Anyway,
she was dumped on them.
There was a researcher,
she was at,
I want to say she was at Duke at the
time and one of the researchers there
asked if she would,
you know,
kind of bring these spiders back for her
to do some research on and a hat,
kind of fill the container with it and
it was under her seat on the airplane.
Oh my God.
And she's wearing a skirt and she
sitting on the airplane and she suddenly
starts to feel something walking up her
skirt and she's not.
She looks down.
She was like,
Whoa,
crap.
And they're all over the first class.
Oh my God.
It was literally spiders.
Spiders on the played.
Did she get arrested?
No,
I don't think she got arrested.
She got it.
She got them all back in.
Think it was like eight.
Oh,
eight.
I could have the number I need to ask as
scientists.
Lady,
what are you doing?
Seriously?
She couldn't put those things down in
the hub or the.
Wow.
So she had to take them like a little
poodle.
Spiders on the plane.
What'd you got?
Huntsman spider.
That was going around the Internet last
week.
Oh God,
it's so big.
How big is that?
What does that thing that it's on?
I need something to compare that to.
What is that thing?
It's those babies.
It's an Australian spot.
Oh boy.
There's a person you get.
Oh my God.
It's a crab.
That's like one of those,
um,
those uh,
crab people.
What is the deadliest catch?
Like a,
the thing John Carpenter
thing or the thing from alien.
The face hugger for the face hugger from
alien.
That's what I was trying to get at.
But similar.
The thing is the one,
you know that the head had the crab
legs,
he came out of a fucking a man.
Boy,
you know,
I've always said that about insects.
We're so lucky they're little because if
bees was size of horses,
they're just flying through the air.
Just giant bees everywhere.
You mentioned a colony of horse size
bees.
Isn't there a movie?
We're either.
The insects get bigger.
We get small.
Probably probably like some 19 fifties.
Moving 60 zap array or something that
you could follow the people's shark late
night.
Yeah,
man,
they,
they're,
they're fucking terrifying.
We're just really lucky.
They're little hero,
most of them.
Yeah.
Anyway,
our time's almost done.
So a Haiti leave with leave within
insects,
spiders and bugs.
Let's close it out with something
exciting.
Okay.
I don't know.
I don't know where we're going here.
What is the conclusion to your book?
This,
this new one?
Fire where we're going with it.
There's obviously tremendous
opportunities and upset.
There's also some dangerous for sure.
Um,
commercialization militarization,
hedonism.
These are all dangers that come with,
you know,
exploring aneurysm,
overindulgence over indulgence,
but commercialization to.
Because the same impulses can be really
harnessed to sell us stuff.
Um,
and
is there also an issue in
commercialization in the same issue that
has been with opiates?
Opiates have a real benefit for people
that are in chronic pain,
but they've been sold so many times and
they're so available and so over
prescribed that you're dealing with is
massive amount of people that have
addictions to them.
Now
we're living.
Just put it this way,
I.
One of the things we tell people,
you know,
the flow genome project is don't ever go
shopping in a flow state because you've
got massively heightened pattern
recognition,
information processing and everything
looks great.
It's gonna,
you're going to write it,
it can get very,
very expensive like going to the
supermarket when you're hungry,
right?
Same sort of thing.
Everything looks great on you and you
know,
because it's optimal performance,
you feel great,
you know,
but it's in those,
we can abuse those for commercial ends
for sure.
And um,
and you know,
this is not wild speculation.
A two or three years ago,
the flow genome project presented the
Advertising Research Foundation,
which is a collection of pretty much
every major media and ad company in the
world and they brought us in to talk
about kind of flow and advertising and
could you start to harness non ordinary
states of consciousness as to,
you know,
drive buying behavior.
And the answer is yes,
for sure.
Um,
so they're,
you know,
they're,
this stuff requires a massive amount of
responsibility.
We feel that open source in the research
and open sourcing the exploration is,
is the best way to kind of keep it free
and tamp down those impulses.
So,
but ultimately I,
you know,
where do I think it's going is I,
I think most of the skills that we need
in the 21st century,
whether it's kind of,
as I said earlier,
dealing with trauma,
anxiety,
those kinds of things or create the
heights of creativity and cooperation
and all that stuff.
Those are best accessed through altered
states of consciousness during non
ordinary states of consciousness.
In a sense.
These are the tools evolution gave us
for ultimate performance and I think,
you know,
whether it's,
sometimes for a long time we didn't have
the science to understand what was all
going on with.
There's a whole bunch of kind of moral
issues that got layered on top of it.
I think some of the moral issues are
getting kind of peeled back in.
The science is showing up.
So I think we're gonna see a huge kind
of revolution in this stuff.
And you look at the numbers,
just,
just talking about flow,
um,
depending on,
we talked about this crazy boost and
learning,
you know,
that that Darpa and advanced brain
monitoring achieved with it with the
military 400 to $400 or 230 to 500
percent increase in accelerated
learning.
You see a similar spike in motivation.
You see a similar spike in creativity.
Um,
this,
these are huge step functions
difference,
right?
If you're in self help and I can get a
five percent improvement over like six
months and it'll stick.
Oh my God,
it's a miracle.
It's giant,
right?
It's giant.
And you're talking about,
you know,
creativity spiking 400 percent.
And it's not even just in the moment.
Teresa Amabile at Harvard discovered
that the heightened creativity that
shows up in a flow state can outlast the
flow state by a day,
sometimes two days,
and it suggests more research needs to
be done.
But it suggests that flow actually
rewires the brain to think more
creatively overtime,
which is amazing because it's really
hard to train people up in creativity.
But we're not talking about a five
percent increase,
you're talking about a to a step
function worth a difference and we're
just starting to kind of tap it into
this function,
you know,
and I'm sure you've had similar
conversations with the people in the
high performance world about this,
but anybody you talk to has done much
work on high performance,
will tell you we think we've,
you know,
tap five percent of what we know and
what's actually possible.
So,
you know,
I think what's coming is going to be
incredibly exciting and incredibly
interesting.
How's that?
How's that for a final test where you
fucking nailed it,
dude.
Just knocked it out of the park.
Thank you so much for coming on here.
Where,
where can people get Ahold of you?
Give out your website,
give out your twitter,
instagram,
all that stuff.
Absolutely.
You can find me@StevenKotler.com.
S T E v e n k o t l e r Dot com.
I'm Steven Underscore Kotler on twitter
and I'm really responsive on twitter.
So if you want to follow me,
want to ask me questions,
whatever are flow,
genome project.com.
One resource I want to give people is if
you go to the flow genome project,
a.com,
there's a free flow profile of the
anybody can take and it basically says
if your trait tology says if you're this
kind of person,
you're likely to find flow in the
instruction.
So you asked what's the easiest entrance
place for people?
The flow profiles are really easy
entrance place.
It'll tell you what direction to go.
And and it's actually interesting point.
It's become one of the largest studies
that anybody's ever run.
An optimal psych.
It sort of happened accidentally.
We didn't expect to,
but like 40 some thousand people have
taken this thing.
And the weird fact that I will leave you
with is even though we normally
associate flow with athletic achievement
or artistic achievement,
the vast majority of our respondents,
I think it's 47 percent of our study
group find the most flow.
They fall into what we call the deep
thinker category.
Essentially they're knowledge workers,
they're finding flow,
doing contemplate of creative tasks,
so even though we associate this with
artistic athletic performance,
it seems like most people get the post
flow in their lives really just working
and things like that,
which is interesting.
That is awesome.
And your book is out in February,
February.
It's called stealing fire.
You can preorder it now.
It's popped up on Amazon.
Um,
and uh,
yeah,
when it comes out,
let me know.
We'll tweet it will put it out there.
Thank you so much.
Really,
really appreciate it.
I really enjoyed this conversation.
It was fucking awesome.
I've got a lot out of it.
All right folks,
we'll be back tomorrow with Scott Adams
trump's supporter.
Whoa.