Oh,
we're live.
Will you guys betting on look,
look around real quick.
Do you know what's new?
Hm?
Easy.
It's easier than you think.
Bruce Lee.
Yeah,
but still.
But still though.
He didn't say it.
He goes,
I wonder if he'll say rise.
He gets out.
I said,
no,
I should have bet you money.
I was going to say it this way.
You've seen it right away.
No,
I saw it immediately.
Pretty Dope.
That is dope.
Just sent those in.
This guy's a bad motherfucker.
Plastic.
Sell this shit.
There's a great.
As a great hip hop album I listened to
in high school and they use one of his
quotes,
one of my favorites.
He says,
honestly,
expressing oneself is really hard to do.
I can use.
I can use really fancy movements and
show you really crazy things,
but to honestly express myself,
that is really hard to do.
It's a.
it's like a beautiful little sound clip
before they start the song,
but it's like just him talking to
someone isn't an humbling when someone
dies really young like he does and they
did way more in their life than you ever
will.
Makes me sad.
I'm like,
what am I going to do?
You stop and think about it.
Like who the fuck else has had that kind
of an impact and you know,
he died in what,
1970 something in the seventies.
Yeah.
And he was young.
Yeah,
I think he was like 30 or 31 or 32 or
something like that.
Find out how old Bruce Lee was when he
died.
It's not like I was listening to Hendrix
last night on the way the studio or a
lot of the comedy store.
You have one of my 33 and he died when
he was 27.
How much Hendrix music is there out
there and he died when he was 27 here.
But then you think,
do you think he'd be happy with what's
going on?
Like I always find that like what would
they be doing today?
That trips me up.
Yeah.
Well you can't do that.
No,
I know,
but that'll be like,
oh,
they had such like a because right.
There's guys that lasted a long time and
they either like or making garbage or
they're slowly still making cool shit
here and there whenever they want to.
Yeah.
There's the variety.
So.
And then there's people that just,
nobody wants to hear their new shit.
Right.
It's like the rolling stones.
Yeah.
You're like,
Nah,
start me up.
Come on.
Nobody wants to hear like new rolling
stones.
One's called car tire.
Don't play that.
Isn't that weird though?
Because they're all time greats.
Yeah.
But if they started playing some song
you haven't heard,
you're like,
fuck is all this.
That's kind of like A.
Yes.
Yesterday I was,
when I was running,
they had this thing called the big
three.
It's a,
it's a post NBA League for players to
play in once,
once I retire it was just three on
three,
but it's really sad to watch guys that
have been retired for like 10 years
who've been because you're like,
this is just bad.
It's like,
it's like say you want to just remember
them when they were amazing,
but now they're just old,
too old to be.
It's like,
it's like circusy,
you know what I mean?
Like people are showing up just to like
see those names,
but they're there.
It's really bad to watch how old they
are.
I mean there is no minimum.
I just think it's,
you have to be retired from the league
to play in it.
But like,
I mean the average age has got to be 40.
Maybe seat.
It depends on the.
And the athlete.
Like Hopkins was fighting in his forties
at his best.
Different though.
Yeah.
Basketball is just,
it's such a young man's game.
I mean it was boxing.
I know,
but there's something about it that's
like a hard to watch and I'll do with
gray hair missing free throws.
That's a weird guy who used to be
phenomenal.
I understand what you're saying,
but I disagree in the fact that it's
even sadder watching an old guy get the
fuck beat out.
Used to be good.
Yeah.
That's sad.
But fighting.
But.
But he's still probably fights because
he loves it.
No,
no,
just for the money.
It's for money.
Yeah.
I mean they fight because they love the
competition,
but they get paid.
They're doing it from us.
But these guys are doing the big three.
There's no way they enjoy it anymore.
Oh,
how do you know?
There's no way.
It just looked so sad.
So sad.
Do you think that.
I think with basketball too,
it's wear and tear on the knees so that
your back,
your knees,
everything left.
Right?
Left.
Right when you walked.
There's a guy named Glen Davis,
Big Baby Davis and he was.
He always had like big problems in
league being so heavy on his,
on his knees and his back and it's even
worse there.
He fell once during it and rolled around
for like five minutes.
I was like,
this is so sad to watch like this.
And their cameras are just focusing on
him.
And rapaport is doing the announcing.
Michael Rob Portman.
Man,
he's doing.
He's doing the interview.
It's so weird,
man.
It's so weird.
He's like a 80 year old,
20 year old yet.
He's just,
his career is on this crazy revival
train and it's almost like he is going
back to young rappaport style.
He's a funny dude,
man.
Oh,
he's hilarious.
Interviewing.
Um,
I guess it was,
I forget what it was,
but he was interviewing these guys and
he's like Kinda hunched over,
like talking to him and he's a big guy
and he's got this look on his face.
He's interviewed them.
Like this is such a weird combination of
like an old guy at a young guy.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
He,
but he,
but he's connected with the youth so
heavily.
Oh yeah.
Well he did that,
but things.
He did that documentary for a tribe
called quest,
like he still wants.
He still is in like that,
that youthful world of like music and
sports.
And do you ever see the rent that he
went on after Charlottesville?
But those Tiki torch carrier and white
guy did Tiki torch motherfuckers,
but he's loose,
you know,
I mean he's out there.
He's,
he's very funny on the fighter and the
kid too.
He goes on,
he's hysterical and he,
you know,
he goes and he fights with the whole
Howard stern staff.
He loves fight with those guys because
they all do like fantasy football and
all that stuff.
He's,
he's vocally a massive sports fan,
which I think him that keeps him in that
youth circle so much that he just loves
sports and loves talking sports to
everybody.
Yeah.
He hosts sports shows sometimes,
like he's hosted different peoples.
One of those radio TV shows,
those radio shows.
They constantly,
they show on TV occasionally.
One of those who does those.
They're like a Dan.
Patrick and Patrick has one.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Those are the guys that left espn.
I don't know Jack Shit about sports man.
Yeah,
you do.
I don't know about sports that you know
about,
but that's all I know about.
Like the problem is people try to talk
to me about other sports because I
fucking believe that game.
Like that's everybody.
Like some like Ian Edwards loved soccer.
I can't tell you.
I couldn't tell you a position other
than goalie.
Yeah.
You named one forward.
See,
but I think that then I think about
hockey because I'm like,
I know hockey,
but I had no idea about isn't talking to
the same soccer just with like know very
close.
They're pretty close as a midfielder.
Did Senator Defense forward and defense?
Yeah.
Are They all defense?
SORTA when you're on defense?
Yeah.
Same as hockey.
I can't.
I'm sorry I couldn't.
I was in Italy when the World Cup was
going on and it was amazing to watch
Europeans watched that shit because they
love it rather go crazy.
Check the APP.
Totally checked out.
I was talking about this before would
ruin it for me.
It was.
I was in boulder when the World Cup was
happening and these dorky white guys
pretending to be way too enthusiastic
about the World Cup dude.
Because the World Cup.
Yeah.
You know,
it's that thing not into it.
He knew that fake thing that people do.
They're like fucking yes,
but it's not real.
The Olympics does that to.
The Olympics has this thing when people
get into like,
it's cool to cheer for your country or
whatever,
but it's so funny when people get into
the Olympics and they're like,
do you watch us and lose?
Did you watch us rip it up and loose?
No,
I don't fucking why?
What are you talking about?
That's not where we rip it up.
Was I asleep?
We were fucking shit up and loose
yesterday.
I didn't know.
I had no idea.
Like the Winter Olympics,
everyone freaks out and they have sports
that you would never even think about
wanting to watch.
Like the cross country ski and then you
shoot on the ground in the ski some
more.
You would never.
I would never do again through
basketball is going to be in the summer
Olympics.
Is it really?
This big three thing is a big three.
That's it.
That's the.
That's the big three is the three on
three tournament we were talking about
with the ex NBA players,
but wait a minute,
they put them in an Olympics.
Yeah,
dude,
I looked this up and I was so surprised.
I was like,
what the fuck?
I don't even,
I don't know what kind of competition
it's going to be,
but the big three success has led to it
being included in the next summer
Olympic.
How many people are in a normal
basketball game?
Ten,
five and five.
Five on five.
This three on three and it's half court
and they have a four point shot,
which doesn't exist it.
Yeah.
So you could shoot it.
I have a weird rule to it at once.
It gets down to four minutes that like
there are no,
I'm sorry.
This was the basketball tournament has a
weird Rolando.
I just confuse the two things.
There's another tournament going on
which is like amateur players and teams
and it's a $1,000,000
tournament taste.
Actually 2 million,
2 million bucks.
So it's a tournament going on all across
the country.
We could have edited if we wanted to.
We should.
Would have lost,
but we wouldn't it be fun.
Just don't talk negative to me bro Bro.
You don't know my heart.
You know we would have been trading goes
on of my head Bro.
This former NBA guys,
former college players,
whatever broke.
Don't put limitations on us.
We would have had an average height of
five,
10.
We'd be killing,
but they have six,
nine black dudes.
And these three white heads just.
Hey,
we're here to play.
Hi fellas.
Hey guys.
Just tying my shoes.
So,
um,
what are the rules?
There's a four point.
Oh,
Joe just hugs the ball.
Just started fucking head money people
out of the way.
Why can't we do that?
Why can,
why can't we play like that guys,
you got to go.
Well,
we tried.
I don't have any sports skills.
I don't know if you fell out,
so maybe you could just use you as the
bowl and fall out.
You just feel what happens when you fall
out.
You kick you out,
you're done.
You can't play anymore else other than
this.
Then the game's over now.
But they have two other players on their
bench that they rotate.
Oh Jesus.
But we would have you fall as hard as
you can to really fuck up their best
players.
Oh,
you know what I mean?
That strategy.
And then Jamie and I would have to bang
it out way to Dickie.
Do they have that?
They have that in hockey.
The NBA,
same thing.
The Mba and guys get pissed because it
ruins their career.
It costs millions of dollars.
I mean heck heck.
A shack was the original,
like they used to foul shack so because
they knew what would they can do to stop
him.
He's a fucking truck,
so he would just get the ball.
They would tomahawk them as hard as they
could.
Oh my God.
Yeah man.
It was.
And he used to complain about it.
It was funny because because you know,
couch sports fans are always like,
oh,
shut the fuck up.
You're huge.
You have no idea how he.
He is big.
But another huge dude that's just
throwing their arms as hard as they can
all gain duty.
He gets totally fucked up from that.
Wow.
Your handcuffs check was like the.
He was like the beginning.
It happened before that old NBA people
will be like,
that's bullshit.
They didn't the 70,
but Shaq was just the biggest guy that's
ever played with so much agility.
Whenever I shake his hand,
I'm like,
what is that?
It's absurd.
It's like a desk.
It's like shit.
He's like,
hey man,
what's up Joe?
He did fear factor with me and him.
Him and I were like,
he was a huge fear factor fan.
So he did like a whole episode where he
co hosted it with me and he stood next
to me and he like,
he would do this.
I'm going to do to Carol Boone.
Shocker ta,
Ta.
And when he would do the countdown,
almost standing next to him like this is
like an eight year old hanging out with
his.
His Dad.
Oh all I hear stories like that that
he's like,
he's a big kid on set.
They can like,
you can't stop fucking around.
I felt an eight year old nephew who
grown up pig.
Yeah.
He's so,
he's a big kid.
That's all I ever hear.
Anybody that works with him.
Like he fucked.
He loves fucking around.
He loves not taking it serious.
Super Fun guy.
Very friendly.
No,
he's so dynamic.
He's like a cop.
Yeah.
He,
he wants to do undercover work for in
Miami or something.
Right.
Workflow for Lord or some shit like
that.
He,
he,
uh,
he would be involved in raids and Shit
and pretty hard to be undercover when
you're 6:11
black dude.
He's,
he's got to be one of the biggest guys
it's ever played,
right.
Not the tallest,
but probably one of the most.
Probably the most mass.
Yeah.
And Muscle.
I mean,
you know,
when you get up next to his arm,
it's,
it's this,
it's like two of my thighs.
He got into MMA for awhile.
Did the,
I don't know if he's doing it.
Yeah,
training,
but there was videos of him training and
I'm just like,
look,
if there was no weight limitations,
a key.
So got,
look at him.
So fucking big.
That does look like a man in his buddy.
Yeah.
Child child and a grown man.
I have a picture.
I have a picture of me at the MTV.
Was it at movie awards or something like
that with him next to me and where I was
interviewing him for this thing and he
will always be the roast one of the
road,
a Bieber and I'm in and I'm doing this
with a microphone,
like full extension with it and he's
bending down still.
You still have to doug?
I'm like it checked.
It's kind of weird that like the UFC has
a weight limit.
What's the top out to 65?
Yeah.
Isn't that weird?
Why is that?
I don't know.
Does it get these super heavy,
super heavy?
We've never had a super heavy fight,
but super heavyweight is to 65 and
above.
Well,
who's the heaviest fighter that's ever
fought to 65 when they weigh in after
that,
probably brock brock was cut and wait to
make to 65.
Wasn't he around 300 pounds?
That.
That's fucking insane.
And it's a different kind of 300 pounds
to 37 foot one.
His shoes are 22,
22.
They're almost to.
His foot is two feet.
That's his foot.
That's all fucking bit.
Yeah.
His foot to two feet,
Jesus,
but like a guy like that could never
fight in the UFC because you probably
can't make two 65.
No.
If he did,
he'd be fucking zero.
Zero fat.
I want.
But I wonder about how because he's so
big.
He didn't have to lose 75 pounds.
Right?
Is it?
They say 3:30.
Is that what he weighed?
Yeah,
3:30.
It looked like as a rookie.
Oh my God.
He was so big.
So big.
And he's a kid right there,
by the way.
He's.
He's 20 or 19 or 20 years old,
right?
That God.
Damn.
That's crazy.
It's a fucking full grown man at 20.
I mean,
what?
Did you ever see this?
Do you ever see the movie blue chips?
Do you ever see that?
No.
That's a great movie.
What she like about,
about Shaq mcnulty,
he's recruiting him.
Shaq.
Yeah.
It's fun.
It's a phenomenal book.
You would have.
You would love old tea.
What?
How good is that guy?
Oh,
that's awesome.
he's so good in this fucking movie.
You know what?
He's amazing in.
It wasn't even a good movie,
but that movie warrior ever that.
Oh yeah,
he's fucking cook.
So the movie wasn't that good.
It was flawed.
Yeah.
But he's good.
You Know Brian Coulombs in that movie,
he played me,
literally did my role in the UFC and
that movie.
Oh yeah.
He,
the,
he's the announcer.
He was telling me this.
I'm just going to.
Do you want to pretend I'm you?
Except for like the skill and the talent
and all that stuff.
Burn.
Listen,
I'm coming after you.
You son of a bitch.
Fight me Brian.
There he is right there.
But Nick Nolte,
ds in that fucking movie.
Nick naulty plays the dad of one of the
guys that's fighting and dairy is like
total fucking.
I ran into him once,
man at FRY's.
I was so happy that he knew my name
because he used to date Vicky Lewis,
who's a friend of mine.
She was on news radio.
Very talented girl.
She's that girl.
Extremely talented.
She's young,
Huh?
Vicky?
Not Anymore.
Compared to him though,
because that was a big age gap.
It was a big age gap.
But um,
so I knew him from the set,
you know,
he'd come to the set and hanging out and
I'm going to fry's and he's got his
reading glasses on and I said,
hey nick,
what's up?
He'll told Joe,
I'm only,
I'm trying to get a computer from my
kid.
Things that's really good.
Hey Joe.
It was weird.
It's like I'm talking to nick naulty.
Should I get a Mac?
So I was only like 27.
They'll still confused.
I'm still like,
I can't believe I'm really talking to
Nick Nolte ended up right now.
No real.
This is real.
We're at FRY's.
Hey Man.
Nicknames Electronics too.
That was during my um,
my quake days when I was addicted to
quake and I'd make my own computers.
You,
you did all that shit.
I'll do 15 screens and all that shit.
Like everyone does that.
I had a room in my house where it had a,
like a conference table and it was lined
up with computer monitors and computers.
I used to build computers.
But you play,
you don't play any games anymore while
we're going to.
We just got,
when we set up his origin pcs,
we got to land room,
set up local area.
Network Room.
Oh Shit.
All over the world.
Fire down.
Well,
you know what man,
now that we have the studio,
there's so much room here and my kids
come here and play too.
You know,
there's plenty of stuff to do.
Yeah,
this is a lot.
Lots of.
So I'm just going to fuck it.
Put some games on for them,
put some games on for me.
Yeah,
that works.
I never got.
I never got into it for some reason.
Video Games,
like I loved him when I was a kid and
then there was this weird cutoff then I
was growing up now.
But so many people still play.
Yeah,
the non grownups,
those,
those non growing up guy.
But I wish I could play like I shamed me
looking at him over there.
He's a sweet kid.
Ultimate watershed.
It's like ultimate warrior shirt is
fully grown.
Mad Chicks love ultimate warrior.
Did they love guys to play video games
too,
right?
Yeah.
To sit inside all day.
Fuck yes dude.
Like just putting out just I want to get
pale more pale.
I want to Paler and Paler.
Jamie the Paler.
You know what scares the shit out of me
though.
Those multi role player,
what does it multi those giant role
player go to work and I call them
border.
What's the name?
Massively massive multiplayer online
role playing.
Is that what fortnight is?
No,
I sound like a fucking dad.
They'll laugh at me shooter.
It's a third person.
Third Person.
That's their parents,
but isn't there but aren't you with a
massive community of people?
Yeah.
People.
That's fucking 100 people in the game
with you.
That's a lot to.
Yeah,
well that's a death match.
A quake death match.
A lot of times you're not really a
hundred,
but it can be 100.
100.
Seems like it's absurd.
How many people are on your squat,
on your team up to four.
Oh,
50 on 50 match.
Which is like a special.
Is it random assignments to teams or you
go in picking your team or you can.
You actually can go in random to it.
You can do everything you want.
God,
I can't wait to hear the comments on
this video,
but I do not know about fort night.
Dude,
I'm so mad that I have idea.
I see so many references online to it
and I know what it is,
but I have no idea what it is.
I remember when people would call you a
noob and they used to for ohs.
Yeah,
new fucking knew.
It still goes on.
Does it still goes on?
Shit.
Like today,
they're like brave.
Even right now there's $2,000,000
tournaments going on.
There's one there.
I think they're both for charity today,
but one for fortnight and then another
one another.
Again,
that's just like a called [inaudible],
which we've talked about before,
a million bucks.
How long do they have to play?
It might be like a two or three hour
tournament.
That's fucking unreal.
So much money in video games now.
Parents used to tell their kids and not
play video games like you don't.
Don't be a loser and they still have
that shit in their head,
but it's.
There's more money in it.
Then like most games,
then you make people make careers out of
it.
What if there were a tennis player?
Oh,
bobby's a pro tennis player,
but will might blow his fucking ankles
out timmy.
Over there I was making a billion
dollars playing fortnite hands.
Yeah.
This all day.
I do it all at Iowa guys.
I got a friend of my old roommate,
my first roommate in La.
He was like a PR professional online
Gamer,
and I thought I was like,
what?
That dude fatality reached out to us,
Jonathan Wendell tonality.
I'm going to try to get them on.
I figured out he's still playing.
He was the greatest quick player or one
of the.
It's hard to say.
It's hard to say the greatest.
There was a few of those guys.
He was one of them.
How old is he now?
Probably in his late thirties.
Something like that.
Yeah,
that sounds great.
What is he doing?
I always know what the.
I want to know what they do when they
quit all that shit.
Just just breathe.
Just chilling,
trying to figure out how to deal with
all the radiation they'd been absorbing.
He's working at FRY's,
sat in front of that screen is.
Hi Joe.
All your cells are mutated.
Some of them now I think.
I think some of them are smart enough
now that they realized the uh,
how quick arises and how quick the fall
might be that they're just sort of
banking money and just riding it out to
see how long it goes.
Yeah.
But it's Kinda like Kinda like how
engulf you only get paid paid if you
win.
Now not a lot of these guys can bank all
that money.
Right?
They still got to have something to do
after it's done.
That's the best bank.
But time majority of guys are just
making a lady I just said,
and this the way.
It's different though.
They don't have to pay a coach.
They don't.
They're just at home in their part.
In some cases their parent's house still
most cases where it might just by their
parent's new house.
That might be their goal.
They buy their parents house and kick
them the fuck out that's happening by
their parent's house.
The.
Yeah.
You remember when you were playing video
games,
Mike?
Getting the fuck out and take care of in
with you.
Pack our shit up too.
Ryan's kicking us out.
Yeah.
Get the fuck out.
You should have been so mean to him.
Yeah.
Know the mom's bitching at him.
I didn't fucking know he could have
bought us this nice.
Tom Toughening them up.
His wife became such a good player twice
when they're fucking assholes.
They take credit for it.
Did that toughened you up and that's why
you liked this?
Like a UC I tonya.
No I didn't and I can't do that.
But that's what that is.
Is it?
Her mom was,
you saw that shit of her mom was fucking
atrocious.
And then when every time she got
something she's like,
you know why that is because I made you
that way.
So she,
she mind fucked her her whole life into
being like even at her,
even when she,
even after the,
after the incident,
you know,
even after the Kerrigan thing,
she was like,
I was always the one that made you the
killer.
That's why we do this.
Oh she fucked her.
So I mean she fucked with her head.
So deep.
Someone she was boxing.
Oh yeah man.
Tonya harding was boxed.
They talk about it unboxed and hope she
bucks here.
And I was his coach.
She was actually all right.
She looked all right.
Well she's an athlete man.
Yeah,
like a legit.
And when she bulked up to I remember and
she was doing it because she was trying
to cash check because she lost all her
money,
man.
She lost all her machine.
Made much.
And what do you think she does now?
They talk about at the end of the film
and I don't remember.
They tell you where,
you know,
when they're like in the Chi,
run with it,
like she lives in so and so with her new
husband and none of them.
She'll never talk to Jeff Gillooly
again.
And who's Jeff Gillooly?
The Guy,
her boyfriend,
the one that was like the head Nancy
Kerrigan's legs work the.
He is the kingpin.
Jesus Christ.
That's a dark thing to do,
man.
To have some fucking Dumbo.
And the way they describe it,
the movie,
it's even funnier that the guy.
He's the guy is he hires are fucking
brain dead.
Fucking brain dead dudes.
Imagine thinking there's nothing go
wrong with that plan.
That plan is going to go off.
They they claim in the movie and then
their story I think to the courts were
always.
They were supposed to threaten her and
these two dumbbells went up there and
they were like,
yeah,
we'll threatened her.
And they were like,
no,
no.
Threatened her.
You're like her.
They fucking shows up with a police
baton.
You believe that?
No Dude,
no chance,
no chance.
You know what I believe?
I believe if I'm going to believe that
guy side,
I bet he said,
go up there and and scare and do what
you need to do.
Right?
I bet he left it vague and was like,
these fucking idiots.
We'll figure it out.
I bet they were on meth and there were
all good.
Yeah.
Fucking geeked out.
They're all just geeking out going,
dude.
You know what?
Fucking skaters need.
Knees will fuck up her knees and they're
just like,
yeah,
I'm taking a math.
Did you see the video?
That guy who drove into the parking lot
of the comedy store and smash into a car
and almost hit one of the guys that were
there.
When was this real recently?
Some fucking dude tweaked out of his
mind.
He came driving through the back of the
parking lot in the store during the day,
slammed into a car,
slammed into one of the employees
because it was parked back there.
They got security camera footage of
it.
Guys are jumping out of the way.
This guy's just like completely out of
his mind.
Holy Shit.
It turns out the guy,
um,
years ago killed a kid driving.
Yeah.
Slammed his car into some fucking kid
and killed him like a young girl.
Fuck.
And then many years later is still
driving fucked up.
Holy Shit.
Tried to back out.
Tried to get out of there.
That stopped.
Grabbed him?
Yeah.
What is this?
This the guy arrested after vehicle
collision at the comedy store?
Yeah.
That guy killed a kid driving and he's
still doing it.
He killed.
He was peeling off a sunset and it
smashed into the comedy store.
He was out of his mind,
man out of his mind,
came in sideways,
went around the corner,
and we went through the driveway,
went around the corner to the lot and
came in like literally turned sideways
and slammed into a car.
What the fuck drugs do to the wrong kind
of drugs or who knows what kind of pills
that's fucking assholes on,
but that same guy had killed a kid.
He's still driving like that pump.
Imagine.
Imagine you kill a kid driving fucked
up.
You get out of jail and then you're
still doing it.
Yeah.
What the fuck?
He's not even that old.
He looked at me.
He looked like a lot of young.
Here's the thing,
man.
Somebody made that kid so many made that
kid.
Somebody somebody fuck somebody and the
man,
the woman got together,
they got pregnant,
the girl got pregnant,
gave birth.
Raise that kid and this is what you got.
What a bad deal.
But you can't tell me that.
That's not part of their fault too.
There's got to be some shit that they
fucking did have that kid.
Yeah.
Oh,
for sure.
There's got to be something.
I mean,
that's a.
that's a collective effort.
You get someone that's that fucking
stupid that you kill a kid and you don't
learn like that's not enough of a
lesson.
You're still driving fucked up.
How did Caitlin Jenner get away with
killing that dude?
What was the turned into a woman that
was the best?
Just slice off your Dick.
That's it.
If us,
they can't get.
You know what it is,
man.
In this day and age,
it's like she entered into this category
of the most marginalized group in
America currently,
which is transgender people and doing
that by becoming a transgender person.
That became the entire focus of the
nation.
She got exonerated for all of these
things though,
so I wasn't paying attention and she
slammed into the back.
All we can say he because it was still a
Bruce Jenner.
He slammed into the back of this
person's car.
It was a dude,
but it was a single.
Oh,
it was a woman.
Woman slammed into an old lady and
pushed her into traffic.
Fuck.
Than they hit a car with a family of
five members.
Two kids and a grandma and way they live
the same family,
but the grandma sued because she like
broke her hip and pelvis or something
like 79 year old woman.
Yeah.
It's a fucked up story and it was almost
like it just disappeared.
Crazy thing is Caitlin doesn't even
address it.
Like it's like some horrific moment in
their life.
No,
completely irresponsible,
but it shows you the type of person.
Do you ever see Kyle Dunnigan staying on
it?
Nigger,
it's
the funniest.
But have you ever see the one he did on
that will engender CBF finance?
Oh No.
Where he's driving fucking fucked up and
killed that lady.
But now Caitlin has got a clean record.
Hey Dude.
Done again.
That is such a fucking hysterical
character character that he does on his
instagram everyday.
I watched that shit.
Yeah,
here it is.
Play it.
I got my driver's license back.
Fuck me when he killed that lady with
the Chicago.
Carolyn's got a clean record.
Bad Man.
I'm a much better driver then bro.
Show.
Don't be afraid to hit the streets.
Look,
I just hit a retarded kid.
He's such an odd guy.
I love it.
He's very,
very funny.
That's where that comes from,
man.
There's beauty in that fucking oddity.
Oh,
I love that.
Well,
he found his groove groove is instagram
with face swap.
Yup.
He's brilliant.
He's got the funniest instagram page by
far.
I do.
When he fucks with his mom,
it makes me.
It kills.
Maybe you seen him do that,
Craig,
is that.
Guess what?
Get she.
You can tell she's so fucking.
She's on the phone like on a business
call and she's like,
I'm on the phone.
He doesn't give a fuck.
He keeps bugging.
It's so funny,
man.
Chicken.
But it does it.
That great character.
You know,
people are mad at him for that Craig
character.
Why?
Of course,
with the flux new.
He's being an ableist.
Oh my God.
Oh my list.
You being unable list passed by chick
fil a new chick filet near me this
morning.
Uh,
the vegans are protesting.
Oh wait,
this sim destroying his mother's pain.
But handbag dealer call her the
hamburglar in case you're in that.
Sorry,
I'm just fixing the painting.
Painting the dough on that doesn't make
any sense.
You haven't even seen it yet.
Maybe you'll like it better.
Sure.
Does the smartstack much.
I'm just going to cut out the cookie.
Men look pretty much the same
drugs did school.
I wish it hadn't every podcast here that
sell drugs to school.
Oh my God.
These kids.
That kills it.
Kills me every fucking time already.
So funny man.
Every time you post something with that,
great fuck.
It rips me up.
But it's funny how he found this niche
and that,
that this,
this new thing of like face swap with a
character.
It's Pr.
It's perfect.
Well,
it's perfect because his impressions are
so good.
Oh,
that's so fucking Bill Maher is insane.
Oh my God.
It's so good.
It's really creepy when I see.
When you see it,
you're like,
that's bill Maher behind the face.
Swap doing the voice when he does the
Kim and Kanye talking,
talking to each other with Caitlin.
Yeah.
It's brilliant,
man.
He's a fucking.
He.
He found he found the perfect group,
but I love the fact that there's this
new thing that people can do.
You know,
the,
this face swap thing is like a
completely new way of doing sketches,
making characters.
Yeah.
It's wild.
It's almost funny earlier because you
know that he's behind it.
You know what I mean?
It's like you're in on it so you know,
but yet it's so good.
Like when he does like Kim and Kanye
West,
Dad,
dad,
I'm lost in my house.
Oh Shit,
look around you.
What do you say?
There's a washing machine is a weird
white box.
What is that white box?
But it's so perfect.
It's like clueless family that's so
wealthy that they completely detached
from.
What is that white box?
Really mad now
I just love that these technologies
created.
There's a bunch of youtube people that
do that.
They're doing ladies weird youtube
videos.
There's so many people doing it now,
but it's like he but he's found a,
like a real specifically funny niche
because he's.
Because he's related to the characters,
like a lot of times when people are
thrown characters together and sketches
and they're just kinda so cheaply done
and they don't have any.
Like they don't mean comedic base that
just like weird to be fucking goofy and
it's like,
ah,
you got to have some kind of basement.
There's a few people that do it right.
My kid loves this lady,
Miranda sings.
Do you know that?
That is.
She's this.
She's got this show called the fuck.
We'll show a picture.
Miranda sings.
Yeah.
I think that's her name.
Isn't that her name?
What does she do?
I try to get her on the podcast.
Did Not respond at all.
That's so fun.
Do it just for my daughter.
She's so into this lady's show,
but it's a show that's not for kids.
That's her.
It's a weird show.
Like the show.
I'm like.
She had.
She had a Netflix show.
She.
Yeah.
Is it over?
Did they cancel it?
I don't know if it was a movie or a
show.
Actually I might bunk Ronkin kid loved
that show and I was.
I was watching it with a gun.
The movie one?
Yeah.
What does that haters back back off?
That's what it's called.
Haters back off.
Is that a movie or a show?
It's a show.
Yeah.
Play the trailer,
Ben,
humiliating.
They whole family left you sure this
time?
I'm sure he'll be fine.
Right?
Right now you're just a boring famous
person.
We need to get you to.
Great.
It's where mentions are boring.
I don't let him slap her daughter who's
eight.
We'll do an impression.
Not Thought Mermaids.
She'll like.
She does that voice,
that voice that she does to show like.
It's almost like a tim and Eric type
show.
It's not really a show for eight year
olds.
It's just a mind fuck show.
Yeah.
So I'm like letting her watch and like,
I don't even think you should be
watching this,
but then again she lives with me.
Yeah,
no shit.
He's going to say what?
But what did you watch that you knew you
shouldn't have been watching when you
were a kid?
To try to not swear for the first five
years of their life and then I'm like,
impossible.
Stop.
My wife would get mad.
I'm like,
what are they going to learn about
something early?
He has a shit.
I'm nice.
They'll just showcasing I say shit or
fuck,
what's the big deal?
I don't say like,
I'm going to fuck you to my wife.
I'm real.
Fuck you lady.
I don't say that in front of your kids
are eating dinner.
I'm going to fuck your late night.
I'm fucking you guys.
Your mom fucking ghetto.
I made you.
You're upset.
It's how I fucking made you.
That's where you came from.
My Duck.
There was a moment when my daughter was
three.
We were skiing and we packed up all the
stuff.
We're getting ready to leave,
but we didn't pack up her helmet and so
we got all that stuff back.
We got everything.
Got Everything.
Oh,
the helmet.
I go,
we haven't packed the helmet and my
three year old daughter looks at the
helmet,
looks at her bag and goes,
shit,
that's great.
But there's a moment where like,
oh no.
And we're laughing,
but we try not to look at it like,
Oh,
turn it away laughing.
Listen.
It's like those videos on the Internet.
Always funny when there's a kid trying
to say duck and they're like,
what is he like,
fuck,
fuck.
And you're like,
it's fine.
I don't give a fuck.
It's funny.
There was no way the parent can't not
laugh,
but he's like,
fuck the fuck.
And they're like,
yeah,
the dog is a girl told me he tried to
kiss his son is his three year old and
he's like,
he goes up,
like give daddy a kiss and it says no,
no,
no push.
He pushes him away.
But as he pushes him away,
says push.
No,
no,
no.
Push,
push,
push.
Get away from me.
Homo Baghdad.
Push Push.
What are you going to make?
Little Sandino's try and man,
are you shooting some loads in there
pumping?
Why not?
What's the difference?
Live rounds.
So you guys doing the thing where you
like checking the calendar should have.
So that's such a weird thing too.
I think it's a mental thing as well that
gets in the way.
Banger every night.
Pump banger every night.
Yeah,
let the fucking chips fall where they
may.
True.
You know what you gotta do?
Eat mixed nuts.
Literally nuts make you nuts.
Grow nuts.
Yeah.
I'm fucking Dr Rhonda.
Patrick posted something on our twitter
page the other day about it.
She was like,
just fucking nuts.
Help help sperm production.
Say it that way.
She's like scientific.
She's like,
yo,
bro,
fucking nuts.
You fucking just flow.
You want juice,
you got to eat a lot of nuts.
But apparently if you eat a certain
amount of grams of see if he could find
the tweet.
Certain a certain percentage helps you
out.
Certain like quantity of mixed nuts
makes your balls grow,
literally makes your sperm increase.
What makes your ball shrink?
There's got to be a food that does the
opposite of steroids.
Yeah.
I stopped eating those,
uh,
years ago.
It makes your uh,
your balls shrink because your balls
aren't making any testosterone anymore.
But my,
I asked the doctor and he said that it
doesn't,
it doesn't reduce the amount of semen
you produce.
It makes your physical nuts smaller.
Does your doctor son?
He said you can.
Yeah,
because I asked him about a different
doctor.
Yeah,
I met him at trader Joe's parking lot.
He was a good doctor.
He had like one of those little stands.
This is why you're nuts or swallow.
He made me show.
I showed him my nuts.
He maybe I let him hold him.
He had to inspect them.
Are put gloves on.
She put the.
Put them in my mouth and I'll tell you
what.
What's wrong
mom?
Do you have a girl that put.
Put your nuts in her mouth in the and
home.
Look,
a monk makes your brain.
She put my nuts like a wildebeest.
Oh.
Oh,
nutmeg.
It will make you feel weird because it's
such a deep sound.
You'd be like,
why am I coming to this deep sound?
No.
Then he'd get an imprint like deep sound
coming noises like baby.
Then it's Pamela noise for me.
Deeper,
deeper,
deeper.
Once you make a deal,
what the fuck do you mean?
Like I dude sound like a dude like a
dog.
And you shoot the hardest loads,
man.
That supplemented their diet with 60
grams of mixed nuts daily for 14 weeks,
increased their sperm count by 16
percent of the shit sperm vitality by
four percent and sperm motility by six
percent according to a randomized
controlled trial.
This controlled trial was.
My husband does a cup and dudes just
into it every day for 14 weeks.
What you got going on this week,
man,
badge isn't into cup with mixed.
I mean mixed nuts and shit tight you
get.
Instead,
let's make a deal with this guy in this
study.
Like you can't come at all except for
the study in the cup or otherwise we're
not going to know because if you're
banging all day one day and the next day
you don't do anything.
You're tired.
Come Sad.
Lazy Cup comes,
comes out different.
I don't know if anybody knows,
but you ever take a few days off,
beaten off.
Hey and then you beat off and it's like,
Hey,
put a hole in the ceiling.
It's flying all over the place.
If I'm jerking off too much and it just
kind of dribbles out,
you feel like I'll lose or hey,
I feel very depressed if my com volumes
low.
Like if I beat off and it's just like
think she said why did I do?
Why?
I find it always depends on how much I
build up.
If I'm building up to it,
I get a big one.
Build A.
Oh,
you edge fucking pervert.
I didn't know about etching.
It's fucking awesome.
Norton had.
Tell me about it.
Does he edges he edge with prostitutes?
He'd get a prostitute and you'd get
right to the porn and come and go.
All right,
thanks for call another one next.
Yeah.
Why not get another prostitute?
When was this?
How long ago?
Like yesterday.
Now.
When was this one?
Was the prostitutes?
Oh,
Norton's.
Still similar.
Yeah,
still.
Yeah.
Darden's an animal bro.
That doesn't give a fuck.
He does give a fuck,
but he doesn't give a fuck at the same
time.
Like secretly.
Secretly when they leave.
Yeah,
he's been the fuck out.
Yeah.
He gets disgusted with themselves,
but that's what he enjoys.
I feel like he should be free.
You know the,
the,
there's like a,
there's some guy I was reading
something.
Some guy was doing something on anti
shame things as a doctor.
Like fuck.
Shame was like is his thing.
But that shame is a weird thing.
Like there's things that people are
ashamed of that we're not ashamed of.
It all like sex,
like it,
like normal sex,
like say if your wife's walking around
the house at a pair of shorts and you
grab her ass and she,
you know,
and she turns around,
she smiles at you and the two of you
start banging.
That's fine.
Yes.
No.
Are you married?
You're going to love each other.
You've,
you're attracted to each other.
It's all normal.
Right?
But if you lived in like a crazy
religious household where she supposed
to be dressed like a fucking table
cloth,
that would be a real problem.
He would,
she would feel awful.
She would feel ashamed.
So it's like what causes shame?
Cultural acceptance.
Right.
And well,
and the building blocks of how your
race,
right?
Like some people get shamed for from
their parents for stuff that's they
shouldn't feel ashamed about.
Oh yeah,
for sure.
Yeah.
And for Norton.
So he pays these nice ladies to touch
his penis and that's why they don't have
to work at Denny's.
But they still do.
Yeah.
That's their shifting their break.
They go on a smoke break and go to edge
him for an hour and a half dishwasher.
Hands Kinda like real rink,
like really,
really strong fingerprints,
you know what I mean?
Fucking indentation on his really
strong,
like the,
you know,
the lines and the fingerprints that
deeper than normal.
The grooved all chemicals.
Dishwasher,
washing all day.
What did,
what does he tell you or cost of?
How much money do you spend on hookers?
I'm,
well,
I don't know.
He's never really.
He's a wealthy guy,
so it's not a problem.
That's the.
That's part of the problem.
Part of the problem is that it's not a
problem.
He's so successful.
You know,
Jim sells out comedy shows everywhere.
He's got a Sirius xm show.
He's written books.
He's got plenty of money for hookers.
So he's like,
fuck it here.
He's like the most free guy that I know.
In terms of like talking about his
weirdness and his perversion.
Is he sober?
Yes,
he has been since he was like really
young.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
He had a problem and he got sober I
think when he was 19.
Holy Shit.
He's been sober the entire time.
That's fucking mile.
Yeah.
Everyone's got advice.
Well his vices.
It's a strong one,
but it's like trannies.
He's really into trannies for real.
Yeah.
Good for him.
Whatever.
Whatever the fuck.
He says it like you're not supposed to
say it anymore.
Like I just,
I guess just got in trouble.
Oh Dude.
I got fucking lit up for that online.
I,
I didn't,
I was with gay friends at a.
What I put online,
having the most fun at a Mexican,
20 bucks.
People leave me the fuck up that it's
not,
that's not a word.
We.
I was like,
okay.
I was with gay dudes that they joked
about it with me.
I thought it was okay.
It's a,
you can say transvestite.
You can't say tranny.
Justin Martin.
Dale can say whatever he wants.
He does.
He can.
Yeah.
Yeah,
he does.
He says whatever the fuck he wants
because he's a flamboyant gay guy.
Yeah.
He can get away with it.
He does.
He gets away with.
He says fucking every.
Yeah,
but like a flamboyant gay guy could say
that no one says shit,
but a straight white guy from Chicago
done you asshole.
You piece of shit.
Fucking ask Justin Mernda.
He yells the n word all the time
constantly.
I didn't know that.
No he doesn't,
but I just wanted to put that up there.
Tell him stop.
No,
I don't think you'd get that kind of
freedom just by being gay,
but if you were gay black guy.
Yeah.
Then you can't.
Then you.
I think you're good.
A black transgender God could do
whatever you want with no legs and one
eye.
He's disabled.
Gay,
black,
trans.
You know what's interesting?
Nobody.
I mean,
no one accepts transracial can't do it.
No one except transracial.
That is the one thing that woman won.
Yeah.
Rachel Doles out.
Just that one line that we're not
willing to cross no fucking way,
which is meanwhile it is one of the most
realistic lines.
This is why totally human beings came
from Africa.
All of them will also.
Race.
Race has a lot to do with culture.
Oh yeah,
for sure.
But I mean,
literally all human beings came from
Africa.
That is the cradle of civilization.
Yeah.
So we're all African.
So why can't you pretend to be African?
Why can't,
why can't you just be it?
That's really what it is.
His name pretending.
If you just say,
that's what I identify with.
I get it.
That to me is that,
that's more on the other side of when
people say like,
you can't,
you can't be a gender other than a male
or a female.
And people say yes you can.
And that's accepted.
But if you said identify as Puerto
Rican,
they're like,
no fucking way.
Is there any race that would let you in?
Like that is anyways?
Uh,
yeah.
Come on.
You could be a radiant.
I feel like redheads or like the.
I think I've got a little bit of a pass.
He should have a pet.
We have a passengers maligned.
Yeah.
We have a pass ginger's.
Just kick a ginger dance.
South Park.
We're dead.
We're,
we're,
we're going to be gone in like 50 years.
Everything a dying your hair now.
I knew a dude who had red hair.
He used to dies.
Eyebrows.
What a fucking Weirdo man.
That's a weird fucking thing.
Did hair dyed his eyebrows look
different because he was that sad about
having red hair when I was a kid.
When I was a kid it bothered me like
crazy and then I got and didn't give a
fuck.
And then when you get older there are
some women that like it that like that,
that,
that think that's a more attractive
because it's real bad for them.
Yeah,
I think they're dumb fucking idiots.
I know something went wrong.
It's funny.
Like what people,
like some people like thick ankles.
Oh yeah,
girl.
Gang.
What's your weirdest specific thing that
you.
When you like when you first started
getting into checks,
when you find it figured out what your
style was,
what was the one thing you're like,
that's weird and most people don't like
that about girls.
I don't have one.
You don't have any of that shit?
No.
Like some guys love cellulite.
You know?
Some girls like,
like,
like Chunky bitches,
Jamie over there.
He's like,
Hey,
don't talk.
He'll put that evil on me.
He's going to have so many dms from
these bad chicks.
It didn't bump.
Yeah.
You get your cellulite picks.
Do you know that there's a new show on
Netflix and they're trying to take off
the air.
It's about a girl who used to be fat and
then she got skinny and she's getting
revenge on everybody.
That's fucking.
What's that called?
I want to watch.
How would they take that off?
That sounds even if you find it as some
really pretty girl.
She's going back to all the people that
talk shit to her when she was young
about being fast.
I don't really pay attention to 100
percent,
but uh,
people were very angry about it.
About the premise.
Why fat shaming.
Oh Gosh.
Don't you know about fat shaming?
What is it called?
God.
That girl Debbie Ryan fat phobic.
Disney is.
Oh,
it's a fat foot.
Hold on a second.
Hold on.
Let me read that.
Fat phobic Netflix series supports
damaging stereotypes for young women.
Well,
listen,
I'm going to tell you guys this really,
really clearly.
If your children are fat,
they're eating too much sugar.
Okay,
so that's a fact.
Fix that.
Yeah.
Or try but don't.
Don't just call people fat phobic of
your children.
There's a lot of nonsense that's
involved in people's bodies and
education and the.
The big one is what they eat has no
bearing on what they look like.
That is horseshit.
Yeah,
it's bullshit.
You didn't have giant fat people in the
twenties and you go back and look at
fucking people in the twenties.
They were all starving to death.
They were all skinny and the bread they
was,
you know what someone fucking told me,
Jordan Peterson told me this.
We got to look up.
Look this up.
I'm emulsifiers.
I'm also fires.
And he was reading something about a
most of fires that are used in fast
rising yeast and in a lot of bread
products are responsible for leaky gut
and they have an impact on people's,
uh,
sensitivities to gluten.
And he was saying that like emulsifiers
or basically like fucking shampoo,
you know,
you have oil in the water of your,
your wash some dishes and all that
greasy oil and you pour some dishwashing
soap in there and the water he goes,
that's in food.
Like that's a similar quality
and that's a cost.
That's what's causing all these like a
gluten allergies and just a bunch of
different that are causing it.
One
of them is the more complex glutens
because it used to be that you would get
like a,
like if you had wheat you would have,
it's like old wheat was like a small
little sort of grain.
It was a smaller plant and then they,
they started changing it and as they
started changing and selectively
breeding it,
what they started doing it as making it
thicker and more dense and,
and that way you get a much higher yield
per acre.
But in doing so they also made it more
difficult for your body to process.
Yeah.
So,
but he was saying that it's also the
uses fast rising yeast and that there's
emulsifiers in it.
And then I'm also,
fires are apparently terrible for your
body,
which makes sense because you go to
fucking Italy and I know you like to go
to Italy and you eat some of that funk
and pasta over there.
It doesn't make you feel the same.
No,
it doesn't.
No.
You actually don't feel as thick.
I feel like you.
I feel way thicker when I feel dumpy
when I eat it back home.
Yeah,
positive that I can buy online.
That's from Italy.
Fresh made pasta from there and what's
not fresh made,
but it's using it.
It tastes
better if you feel better when you need
it.
Now you do.
Actually.
I know that sounds like a thing and an
American traveler would say it's better
over there,
but it's.
But it is true.
You know,
you go over there,
they're not fat.
It's us.
If there there's someone fat,
it's an American.
That's what.
Every time I see a fat burners have a
thousand bucks and they're from the
state.
They've got Tiramisu,
they've got spaghetti,
good dessert,
and have coffee every fucking night.
Why aren't they fat and live for.
They live their lifestyle.
And their food choices,
fat,
fat phobic.
I'm going to,
I'm going to purposely have two kids and
I'm going to feed one of them very
healthy food.
And the other one I'm just going to have
sugary diet and just fat in the fuck out
of them just to show society what's up.
Dress them on to seal.
And Paul had a boat and I'm going to
have a rope.
You don't have a rope through the
premise of the show.
Know like the plot I guess would be one
of the fat show used to be fat.
And then she lost weight.
She got punched in the face.
Now target or Walmart.
Her jaw wired shut.
That's all she lost the weight.
Oh my God.
That is so fucked up.
That's fucked up.
Wait a minute.
Who punched her in the face?
Her Dad's eating cake.
Stop eating cake.
You fucking cunt.
It worked.
Watch stupid.
That's just stupid premise.
And then.
But she's getting revenge on people that
talk shit.
That's it,
right?
She's going back for vengeance on the
people who hurt her.
So the idea is that girls are going to
watch that and they're gonna want to get
their jaw wired shut.
They're gonna tell their friends to
punch them,
break their fucking hit me with a bat,
right in my head.
I'm going to jump off my roof.
There'll be a kyle dunnigan sketch that
would be a great dentist that had hit
me,
hit me in the face while weight got my
fucking God summer body.
But people do lose weight when they get
the award.
Well,
yeah,
you can only liquid drunk drunk her.
It was a conflict.
Kanye,
when he shattered his,
you want to get in that car accident.
He lost all that weight and he talked it
because he couldn't eat
anything and he was so fucked up on
painkillers and shit.
Oh No,
no.
Thanks dude.
Fuck that shit.
It's weird how vulnerable your jaws
feel.
That gold coast side of Saudi jaw.
Yeah.
It breaks so easy.
Uh,
so vulnerable.
I can't be more.
People don't crack their fucking jaw.
When I was fighting,
I was always.
My jaw was always sore.
Like you always get dinged.
Like you'd always get.
Inspiring.
So like you'd be chewing and eating like
this,
like Oh,
it's painful.
Jaw was always sore.
You feel it in your teeth.
Do you feel it?
And you're like where the joint is?
You gotta realize your jaw is in many
ways.
Like your knee.
Yeah.
Right.
Like you know your knee,
your knee gets sore,
like Ah.
It hurts when you do that.
When you get punched a bunch,
your jaw gets sore.
Like when you're chewing it hurts.
What is that the worst?
Or is like rib,
rib content read punching worse.
The worst is your head always by far by
far because it's scary and your ribs
aren't scary.
It's like I've had broken ribs,
like one of my ribs,
like on this side like sticks out more
because it's been cracked and it's all
fucked up.
I probably broke at least three ribs,
maybe more.
I think I broke.
I probably broke at least three.
I don't know.
I've,
I've definitely had some tears in the
cartilage in between the ribs to
promise.
They don't really do much about it.
When you get a broken rib,
they don't put you in a cast.
You can't do shit.
I don't really do much about it.
You're just in fucking agony for awhile
until it heals up.
I never broke ribs.
I don't know that.
I don't know if that painful and rip
suck.
But you're still okay.
When your head hurts,
you're scared.
Oh yeah.
I've had three concussions.
I fucking.
How'd you get concussions?
So all sports.
One football to basketball,
basketball,
basketball was bad.
Basketball as twice the same way.
Because you fall.
Yeah.
Bam.
Got My legs taken out from under me.
Both toes.
Jesus Christ on my neck.
I'll never forget my mom tells this
story.
I'll never forget my friend who's now
passed away.
Sadly,
he,
uh,
he's gone.
But he called my mom and was like,
don't freak out,
but don't freak out.
The first words to apparent.
Don't freak out.
But Andrew's in the hospital and of
course my mom
is it.
I got my fucking knees.
I went up to get a rebound.
And on my way down all I just remember
seeing the ceiling.
That's the last thing I remember.
My legs were oof right out from under me
and I hit my head so hard on the ground
that I bounced up.
Everyone playing was like standing
around in shock and I was blacking in
and out,
but I was so.
It was so strange because you don't
really,
you don't really know it right away.
You're like,
what's going?
I'm good.
I'm walking,
I'm good,
I'm good.
And everybody's like,
sit down.
Are you okay?
Like,
are you fucking,
you know,
you hurt me.
You could hear it from outside.
And then I sat down,
they had ems come and I remember like
clear as day when the emt fucking
grabbed my hand and he started to walk
and I go,
I'm going to follow this.
I'm going to fall down and pass out.
I said,
I don't feel good.
I'm not going to go to a black.
And I remember I threw up.
I barfed everywhere all over this.
I puked and then I woke up again in the
hospital.
That was bad.
That was the worst one I ever had.
I had bruised a bruise all these
vertebrae and the doctor kept saying how
was inches of pressure away from
cracking from bringing my fucking neck
because all of my weight went one way.
That was bad.
Football was bad.
Football was helmet to helmet.
Shit.
That shit sucks.
I was a kid.
I was kicking the ball because our
kicker was hurt and the kid over snapped
and went right over my head.
I went and grabbed me.
Soon as I turned around,
I got fucking locked and then a guy in
the sideline goes,
you got your bell wrong boy.
I mean,
I got,
fuck it.
I mean,
everyone was okay.
They were loving it.
Fucking smart.
I got smoked.
I look like a fucking rag.
Sure.
It's.
It's a weird thing when people cheer.
When someone gets gravely injured.
Oh yeah.
People love it because it's because you
[inaudible] the force of it is like,
Oh shit.
It looks incredible to see.
Let me think about fights.
Same thing.
Yeah.
I mean when someone gets head kick
fucking insane,
you can't believe you're watching it.
That's why the human,
the human emotion of like
it could be fucking dead soon.
Like the most disturbing ones I ever saw
was Francis and knocked out Alistair
overeem with this fucking left hook
uppercut combination.
Sent his head like literally he was like
looking at his asshole,
snapped his head back so far it was
fucking her.
And he literally flatlined.
Yeah.
I just flatlined leg legs,
spread out,
toes curled one punch.
And it was,
it was so powerful and so horrific that
I was like,
yeah,
you can't help but go,
Oh God,
yeah.
And,
but see,
people are cheering for someone getting
horribly injured.
Well,
I had a moment at,
at UFC two to five and that's what it
was in Chicago.
I had a moment where I'm sitting on the
floor and I was looking around and Tony
and I were um,
you know,
it was uh,
it was,
it was between fights and Tony and Tony
goes,
this fucking awesome man.
And I go,
it is.
And as I'm looking around it like soaked
for a second in me that I was like,
this is so a hit like historic in nature
of like people gathering to watch people
fight.
It was so like,
it brought me to this weird place of
like,
isn't this insane to think that all
these humans are just coming to watch
these two athletes just grapple at one
another?
It was just,
it was interesting because the other
sporting events don't,
don't hit,
didn't hit me like that.
But when remember when you were a kid
and the kids would decide we're going to
fight,
one wants to watch.
Fuck.
Everybody gathered around.
Yeah.
It was way more exciting than what was
going on in the stupid classrooms.
There was,
there was little,
there was a little area in,
in my high school that people fought at
this like little secret guard.
It was like a place that you could get
to,
you know what I mean?
And people love.
They do.
They set up fighting.
Two dudes fought over this one girl.
They were both fucking and,
and she was there.
That was,
that was even more fucking brutal.
The the kid that they thought was going
to win,
he was.
He was.
I mean he was just a tough kid,
but he had.
He had,
it was the middle of winter.
I'll,
I'll never forget,
and he had really bad acne and the other
kid,
every time landed a punch.
You would see the redness get worse in
his acne,
in the blood start coming out of his
face,
zit blood as rough as it was,
the fight.
It was zip blood.
One blood,
one fighting over a girl.
Not only do you lose the girl,
but you also get your ass kicked.
He was,
and she was there,
which was even more fucking brash
occurred.
That's how girls are such assholes.
She stood there and watched these two
dickheads fight over her shit.
Did she say,
don't stop.
Cut it out guys,
please.
Now she.
No,
she didn't say shit.
She said and she knows she did the
triangle.
Yeah,
she watched them do it and the whole
fucking school watching and then
somebody would probably wasn't that
fight,
but one fight.
I remember somebody taped and tapes were
getting passed around.
Oh Jesus.
But this is what's fucked about school.
The school rule things like athletes,
we always had this uh,
guilty by association shit,
if you're there you get suspended even
if you had nothing to do with it because
athlete code of conduct.
Wait a minute.
So,
so,
so if I'm at a party and it gets busted
up by the cops and I don't have alcohol
or drugs on me or nothing,
but I'm at that party and it gets back
to the school and the coaches I get
suspended from whatever.
Oh.
Speaking of which,
Bursa me.
This one,
there's a code of conduct at Netflix.
Yeah.
In like an internal thing.
I'm sorry,
just for laughs rather.
Oh Shit.
Yeah.
Just for.
I'm going to send you this young Jamie a
Netflix has a or why don't we keep
saying Netflix just laughs Montreal.
Yeah.
Has a code of conduct that they posted
everywhere,
I'm sure.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
of course.
Yeah.
Hold on one second.
For artists or for people.
It's got to be for artists,
for the comics here.
That's so jamie.
Yeah,
a code of conduct,
how to behave for comic,
for adults grown people.
Listen,
you sell what fucked up people make?
Yep.
Okay.
But we're going to take it as a code.
Oh Shit.
Can you make that bigger?
In order to accomplish our purpose?
The just for laughs festival must be
exempt of abuse.
Inappropriate or vexatious.
I've never read that before.
Have you ever heard that word before?
To Vex two VEC,
somebody vexatious behaviors.
Everyone participating in the just for
laughs festival must treat artists,
festival goers and employees with
equality,
respect and dignity.
No matter the gender,
sexual identity,
sexual orientation,
disability,
physical appearance,
race or religion.
I hope they love it.
About out.
Yeah.
What about cognitive function?
Right?
It sounds like you can pick on really
stupid people.
Still JFL adopt a zero tolerance policy
on harassment in all its forms.
Whether it is verbal comments,
actions,
or gestures that are repeated,
hostile,
that,
uh,
affect a person's dignity or
psychological or physical.
Oh,
so you can't talk shit anymore.
That's what we do.
What we,
what do we do?
And we're hanging around.
Fuck Shit.
That's the whole thing.
You've been harassing me.
You've been vexatious with me,
sir.
Nothing in this policy should be
interpreted as a barrier to artistic
freedom too late,
less heroin days.
They got,
they had to put a French word and that
motherfucker.
Discussion teams and security squads,
what?
Hold on.
Intervention teams and security squads
of specialized responders with the
mission of increasing the safety of
women and vulnerable persons during the
outdoor events will be on street
festival site every day between seven
and 11,
so if you want to molest,
here's your hours after 11 up to seven,
they'll be wearing pink armbands and
luminous bracelets for v.
better visibility in the dark.
They will also have a tent located on a
plus last bottom between bone mode,
bumble news,
God French's.
Awesome.
What were the streets?
We were.
They're trying to remember if we can,
we can molest on these streets boys,
so it's branch out.
We're going to go into the forest lesson
on a road safety.
Catherine,
in addition,
if you are the victim of a witness,
a prohibited act.
Okay,
well,
it's a prohibited act.
Anything listed above.
It seems like everything.
Yeah,
it is zero conduct.
I mean them for no rape,
no touching,
no harassment model of that,
but it seems like they're just covering
their ass.
Let's go back up to that.
What you can't do.
Again,
I want to know what vexatious is.
What's vexations?
Inappropriate,
abusive,
inappropriate or vexatious behaved.
That everything we do is inappropriate.
Yeah.
Okay.
The idea of what we do for a living is
inappropriate.
That whole back alley where everybody
goes and smokes.
Yes.
An inappropriate zone.
Every single time.
It's.
Every time you go back there,
people would just say an annoyance,
frustration or worry,
Huh?
Wow.
Who was the thesaurus holder that pulled
that fuck that bad boy out.
Have you heard that word before?
No,
never heard that.
We're covering up their.
Their shit.
This is them being so overly cautious
because whatever insurance they've got
on fucking whatever is like,
you have to give fair warning that we
have security for this,
this and this.
What's amazing is think about how long
it's been going on where they didn't
have that.
Yeah.
I was in just for laughs in [inaudible]
93.
That your first.
What was your first year and just for
JFL?
Nineteen 93 was your first year?
Yeah,
93.
Yeah.
So how the fuck?
Ninety three,
but they're pulling this out now.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
it's been around for forever,
but I also love that it said on it that
you shouldn't.
You have to immediately email you.
Imagine and we'll get back to you.
You get molested,
you go to email.
Your Pussy still hurts.
Someone grabbing it.
You fucking assholes.
I got email now.
You know what?
I'm going to fucking send this in.
Yeah.
You got an ice zero tolerance
at A.
Hey,
if you get physically abused,
the email you have to email is.
Ha Ha.
You probably shouldn't put that email
online.
Gone.
Sorry.
Listen,
what do you mean?
That's,
that's public.
That's public.
Don't get us wrong,
but this is really public.
No.
Well,
you know,
you get what you get with it.
Yes,
but I mean,
look,
we're not pro harassment,
don't get us wrong,
but this just seems like a little over
the top.
But see this,
this in some semblance of irony.
This is harassing.
It's just like poking the bear at people
to be like,
these are all the things you can't do.
All it's doing is like steering people
to go.
I wasn't going to do any of that shit
anyway.
Why are you fucking.
Why are you,
why are you employing people to walk
around and armbands to,
to make sure I'm not doing a thing that
I was never going to do?
Well,
was it an issue?
If it was a huge issue than that,
then I'd like to know.
Well drunk him comedians can be gross,
so drunk and are pieces of shit.
But you've created a festival where
there's drunken animals walking the
streets all night long.
Right?
So w w,
I mean you need a shirt that says
vexatious vexatious fixation vex me
baby.
If exit up,
going it up and it up.
I've been vexing all over him.
All vexatious over here.
I'm all inappropriate stuff being
vexatious inappropriate to weird word
too,
because by WHO's definitions?
But all that stuff is all subjective.
Who standards of anything.
It's to vex main means to annoy or to
like poke and prod annoyances.
Such a commonality in our fucking daily
life.
Yeah.
I'm annoyed by that comment.
That's vexed.
Vexed by the vexatious fucking the
signed document.
But what burst that all over?
He said it to me today.
Yeah,
I'm sure.
I'm sure they posted them all over and
people walking around trying to protect
people who.
What is that about?
It's weird.
It's like you want.
You need fucked up people to make rock
and roll and comedy and rap music.
Yep.
Like you need it,
but in this day and age,
nobody.
Everybody wants no one to be fucked up.
I think when people love,
when people like reminisce about a time
when a amazing artist who was a Weirdo,
they do that because they don't.
They didn't realize what also came along
with it.
You know,
like they're like fucking,
you know,
whatever.
An amazing musician.
They were like,
they were totally fucked up.
They did crazy,
fucked up shit all the time.
It's like they couldn't do that today.
Yeah.
You mentioned Jim Morrison fucked be
fine.
You'd be fucked.
He couldn't do any of the things he did.
Fuck.
They fucked.
I mean that guy used to pull his dick
out on stage.
All the tested for it.
Piss on.
She piss on people.
He pull out his dick and piss on someone
and people think that like tea today.
It'd be.
That'd be the end of times for him.
The end.
That's all.
I want to kill you.
Pissing off people on the front row.
But that's the thing.
It's like,
that's,
that's the whole irony of this whole
performers getting unbridled.
I had a buddy of mine who loved music
who's really into like old bands but did
not like Jim Morrison.
He's like,
please anything,
but why did he not like the doors?
Because he was a good looking guy.
I've got tons of pussy.
It bothered him.
I guarantee you that was part of it.
I'm like,
wait a minute.
You don't think that Jim Morrison and
the doors were good music?
You don't think that break on through to
the other side is a good song.
Yeah.
What do you look me in the eyes?
You tell me.
Break on through to the other side isn't
a fucking amazing song and it was in
1968 or some shit.
Yeah.
Fuck you man.
And he's like,
that's just not.
It's not good music,
man.
Yeah.
I'm fucking Jim Morrison and the doors
locked because he just slinging dick
half out of it.
It's so hot.
So hot,
so high.
So gone.
No shirt on.
Still making phenomenal fucking music
lunch out on like a scarecrow beads
everywhere.
Certified.
Get this cocksucker candles,
riders on the storm.
He made that intro so long so he could
finish when he was getting blown up to
this house.
Come on,
man.
Break on through to the other side of
the fucking amazing.
So good.
He had.
They had so many amazing songs,
but that era of music had so much good
music.
I think it was also another part of the
problem was when Val kilmer played them,
that was a big fucking issue.
I mean,
yeah,
that was a big bummer for me.
I'll kilmer who is a beautiful man at
the time.
He added all the beautiful men who are
not beautiful men who fell so far.
Woo,
what happened?
Val?
Val just got into cake and heroin looks
like pull up a picture,
but it makes me sad every time I see it.
Like I'm like,
that guy was fucking bat.
He was a batman.
He was one of the best path man.
And now you're like,
what did he do?
Did you just start drinking booze?
I don't quite remember what I remember.
There was rumors about he had,
he was like covering up papers,
really sick.
He had cancer,
right?
But then he denies it doesn't even deny
it.
I thought he denied it for years.
I thought it was like a thing where
people were like,
he's,
he that he said he was sick,
but it wasn't cancer that he was like
val cameras and comeback and the top
guns sequel.
Oh.
So he got throat cancer.
Oh man,
he's,
he's thin again.
Yeah,
he's looking better there.
Let me see that.
Don't scrawl.
Stopped with the flashes.
You assholes.
Can't even see what it looks like.
That's what it used to look like.
The actor revealed the news on Reddit
during an ask me anything.
Q and a.
Oh,
how weird.
Red,
it's so funny,
but that shit,
one commenter said awhile ago,
Michael Douglas claimed you have
terminal cancer.
What was the story behind that?
And he said,
killer responded.
Okay.
We can read that quicker.
He was probably trying to help me
because.
Oh,
what the fuck,
what the fuck folks,
because the screen got filled
with all of these popups for possibly
new videos that you want to watch while
you're watching a video.
Uh,
I did have a healing of cancer,
but my tongue is still swollen,
although healing all the time because I
don't sound my normal self yet.
People think I may still be under the
weather.
I like to refer to cancer as under the
That's a fucking,
that's a pretty bold leap.
But when he got really fat,
but it's,
that's one of the reasons why I got
cancer,
but he was really unhealthy because I
think it wasn't just see what.
I don't think it was just that he got
cancer.
I think he also was like really fucked
up for awhile health wise in terms of he
just looked so different.
Bu's and chant.
Yeah.
Two Thousand 15.
He was rushed to the hospital.
Yeah,
but this is before that,
but see before 2015,
he looks so strange there.
That doesn't look like the same guy.
Well,
it looks like he's got a Bandana.
It looks and it looks like he's got to
look at his left eye,
but that's what.
What,
what does that say?
Scroll up to what is his left eye
looking at and as you're looking at
someone choose.
Someone's got a nice tip.
Someone's got great shoes.
Looking at one ticket.
Left it.
Geez,
I'd love just that left head.
Left to the juicy.
I'm running errands and London without
his trick.
A tracheotomy.
Trey.
Trey,
how do you say that?
Tracheotomy.
Craig asked me to.
Oh,
so he did.
He had a whole.
Yeah,
that's why he's it out.
Wow.
But see,
that's what I mean when they say rumors.
Right.
I do remember that he had denied it
heavily that he had cancer.
It was like a whole 2013.
Oh,
Michael Douglas for oral cancer.
Woo.
Fuck me.
I could douglas do them now.
It wasn't that whole thing about him
saying that he went down on his,
on his wife too much,
wasn't it like a big thing that he was
like,
he said that there was a rumor that he
said find out what the story about that
is.
We should probably should clarify
because I want to know what she got
really mad at that apparently.
I mean,
yeah,
because she's like,
I don't got cancer pussy.
Imagine your wise pussies.
So funky.
But people do get a lot of cancer from
throat cancer,
from HPV apparently.
Well,
that's real shit.
Yeah.
That's really from Lincoln.
Even,
uh,
even,
even a lot of pussy venereal diseases
are so weird because diseases that
specifically come from sex.
Michael Douglas.
Sorry,
I was sorry for the effect of oral sex
cancer comments on my wife.
Okay.
What did he say though?
Inside regretted the embarrassment
caused to his wife Catherine Zeta Jones
by the revelation two years ago that has
cancer may have been caused by
performing oral sex.
Probably just joking.
No,
I don't think it was that his illness
was a result of contracting the human
papilloma virus,
which experts believe can be brought on
by Cunnilingus.
I love that word.
The store made headlines around the
world when Douglas was promoting his
emmy winning role in liberace bio pic
behind the candelabra after being
declared free of cancer.
By the way,
did you ever see that movie,
Diaz and a fucking bit on that.
That unfortunately has been lost because
Joey Diaz has never really done a
special other than he didn't one special
couple of years back,
but you to do a special on Joey Diaz,
what you really do need to have joey do
like five nights in a row and just turn
the cameras on every night and just let
them go loose and then fill it all and
then eventually you'll get that Joey
Diaz mom 100 percent.
Get that experience.
But when you say,
okay,
Joey,
be yourself now,
get on camera and guys clap it in.
It's just hard for a guy who's that wild
and loose to be wild and loose on demand
with a bunch of lighting on and they
want to put makeup on him and everything
becomes artificial and it ruins the vibe
of what standup is.
One hundred percent.
So unfortunately,
you know joey being the wild man that
is.
He's never a lot of his greatest bits
are never been captured,
but he had a Michael Douglas doing
liberace bit.
That was so good.
It was so good because if you're
watching that documentary,
I watched it yet.
We're not documentary movie drama.
What is it?
Bio Pick.
What would you call it?
Bio Pic.
Yeah.
It's so good.
Yeah,
it's phenomenal.
You realize like,
wow,
crazy.
Liberace was.
He ended up like a pump for his dick
couldn't get hard anymore.
She had like a little Dick was just
always ready to rock and he's just
banging his boy and his boyfriend was
like,
what is going on?
Like,
why don't you ever get solved?
He's like,
no,
ain't no fucking explained to Canada
with his Dick thing,
thing,
thing.
And you know,
he would always do this thing where
ladies would be like liberace.
When are you gonna?
Find a woman soon date that was really
famous that they cut,
that he dated someone super,
super famous.
Liberace.
And who he dated.
Like a really famous actress.
There's a great song.
Pull.
Pull up the video for the song.
When liberace winks at me.
It is.
What will we get kicked off youtube for
that one trouble before?
Yeah.
Can we play it?
And so we can hear it with the people at
home can't.
Unfortunately.
Folks that you can look it up yourself.
Well we can play.
Would that,
would the people on Youtube and not hear
it?
That's the problem yet.
But Youtube,
itunes would hear it,
right?
Or RSS feeds if you're android.
Do you know this more android phones.
There are phones.
Yeah.
Good fucking iphone.
Shit.
So annoying.
Now it's annoying.
I'm getting second.
We're going Andrew.
One too,
man.
I'm tired of the bullshit.
Let's do it.
Let's go together.
Let's go.
Every listener switch.
Switch switches me.
Crazy.
Here it is.
Let's listen to this song.
So it's peggy king.
I found a brand new idol.
He's charming as can be.
This is a different world,
a different world back then,
man.
Oh,
get liberace.
Hi.
Like sucking Dick guy like that.
I like to again,
my bud.
Uh,
I started to shake.
I started to shiver and every fiber in
my being begins to quiver and she's
smoking,
right?
Yeah.
Actually writing.
I don't know.
It's a pencil when liberace winks and
queuing sent me.
You hear the clink.
When he winks clink,
I just tell people to go to it.
Go to go to youtube.
Google Peggy King.
When liberace winks at me,
it's a crazy video.
I imagine he would like.
He would sing that to him while he was
pumping some dude.
He was whatever.
Visit boyfriend at that time when they
have a.
He winks at me.
He didn't really.
He Sang,
but he was more known for playing the
piano.
But he was a singer too.
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
But he was what?
That song.
He's not saying it at all.
I don't know.
He's winking when liberace winks at me.
She was a huge star.
Mass piano players.
Fucking massive.
Imagine if you were a kid today and
you're like,
I'm going to get famous.
Playing the piano was like,
fuck you and get the fuck out.
Fuck you and fuck Kenny g,
she's the last.
Who's kidding?
Geez.
The last guy to get famous for an
instructor for one solo into one single.
Instruments it fuck off.
Well now because now you've got them.
If you'd like playing the violin,
you got also had like a hip hop beat to
it or something like they have to do
like a layer of something.
No one does one thing and then that's
it,
but it's like,
imagine if you're a kid today and you're
like,
I'm going to get famous riding the bike
like Lance Armstrong,
belkoff no.
Chunk off.
Get outta here.
There's no no one now,
no one liberace used.
Judy Garland's West as Jesus Christ.
Fucking popups today are so annoying.
Mae West,
Midwest West as least convincing beards
ever.
Yeah,
right there.
If you looked at them,
they're looking at him right there.
Make that picture bigger.
He looks so good.
I mean there's just people that look
gay.
Well,
you know,
here's the problem.
Those other guys would gay to.
Well,
they're all presented to people just
look gay or back then he's on her left.
Yes.
That's him right there.
Yeah,
right there.
Let me look at that smile.
That's gay,
but so's the guy on her right eye.
Got Gaze is probably one of his buddies.
Yeah.
One of his roommates.
Midwest is like,
I'm so confused.
Nobody wants to affect me.
It's just been typed in weight so we're
liberace.
Had no trouble getting all the dates he
wanted and he gloried in escorting.
Well known entertainers to parties.
Getting his picture taken with Susan
Hayward Stone.
Rosemary Clooney?
Yeah.
May West was a pure garland.
May West was the only one of his so
called lady friends that I actually met
as they say in Texas.
May was a hoot.
Who wrote this?
She was a drunk.
Hmm.
This is a gay website because what's up
with that guy in the lower right hand
corner from his boyfriend?
Oh.
The website's called Queer Queer.
Queer.
That's the name of the website.
Jamie's this on a favorites.
He's got that Shit bookmarked,
so we'll get.
Look that fucking Michael Douglas
playing them.
Look how good that is.
Look,
he looked exactly like him behind the
candelabra.
Well,
they'll you that.
Scroll down where they go side by side.
Look at that one right there in the red
with the Red Hue.
Yeah.
Look at that.
Well,
didn't they put makeup on him and shit
and make them look more likely.
I know what it still does.
Structurally.
Still kind of looks at.
He has the same kind of close enough.
Yeah.
But I think they did something with his
chin.
Chin.
The lower the upper right hand one.
Where the,
the,
the upper right hand.
Upper right hand or lumps.
Lumpski.
I'm sorry.
Upper lefthand.
The one with the uh,
the guy that actually got the work done.
Yeah.
Look,
he,
he made him get plate fat.
Facial plastic surgery.
So he resembled liberace.
So he gets his face looked like
liberace.
His boyfriend,
he wanted him to look like himself.
And he made his boyfriend looked like
him.
How crazy is that?
Yeah.
Because liberace had a wig.
So.
And part of the movie liberace takes the
wig off.
Rob Lowe,
Rob Lowe was amazing in that movie.
That's a great book.
What years that movie from.
I was just gonna say it's not too long
ago,
dude.
Let me tell you something.
Joey Diaz had one of the best bits of
all time about that movie.
I'd like to get jude.
Joey d is high and make them watch it
again.
He should read.
He should read birth.
That video.
I want to know this bit.
So fucking it was so committed to beg
them to do it,
but he won't do it.
Good.
Don't do that shit anymore.
The problem is you would have to.
He would have to want to do it.
You really couldn't talk him into doing
it and he would also have to be
enthusiastic about it again,
like why he'd want to want.
He'd want to tell a half to want to tell
the joke.
Yeah.
What was the whole bit?
So it was.
The story was he was watching the you
drama.
He can't eat pussy with asthma behind
the candelabra by joy.
Is this it?
I don't know.
It's a 10 minute rant about it came from
his podcast.
Jesus play this.
I didn't even know this existed.
Look at that.
That should be a shirt.
What was the last good movie?
The last good movie I seen the last one.
He was with men on fire that said,
why don't go to Mexico because Mexico.
Have you made friends with Denzel
Washington?
Don't go to Mexico.
You understand me if you don't about
watch fucking man on fire.
Play this.
Who did this?
And the second best movie.
I've seen this movie on Hbo called
behind the Candelabra,
behind the candelabras.
Liberace scoring.
Some of you guys are very young.
You don't remember liberace.
There's a lot of people that are long in
the tooth.
You know what the fuck?
Liberace.
Liberace was a piano player from the
sixties or seventies that was very
popular.
He was flaming and he had a fucking wig,
but he,
he,
he pulled a Michael Jackson.
He told people he was engaged,
so nobody really believed that he was
gay.
I don't give a fuck either way if you're
gay and that I.
It makes no difference to me.
He was a good piano player.
They did this movie about them and the
funny thing about this movie that he was
played by Gecko,
Michael Douglas Played Liberace,
so we came home one day and I'm like,
fuck it,
let's watch this thing.
Right?
So I'm watching this liberace dude,
and he's playing the piano and shit and
whatnot.
When you watched a movie,
you're like,
look at this fucking old guy.
He's got game old guys.
Got Damn okay.
A lot of people don't realize.
It's like the DOS equis fucking guy.
You ever see him hanging out with Betty
White and a bunch of old hags do you
know?
He's hanging out with 19 year old chants
at the mall and there's always like two
of them,
but there's always a third one that
comes and she's like,
why are you hanging out with this creepy
guy?
He's old little girls like he's not
creepy.
He's just lonely.
His wife died.
He just wants to conversation.
He doesn't want none from us.
He's like your grandpa and all of a
sudden there's that one girl that goes,
grandpa,
he fucking around with these old guys.
You will suck one of their fucking dicks
because patient,
they're very patient and like young guys
go right for you.
A little vagina on old guy throws you in
a web and they play you like they
fucking call on you.
You ladies have been taken by an old guy
at one point your fucking life.
They rock your world and they'll fuck
your brains out.
You catch them with some good old blood
transfusion or they been eating that
shit.
I had a friend who was a stripper that
said she went home with a 50 year old
guy one night.
She didn't walk for three fucking days.
I'd go again.
That's not me.
I come in a minute and a half,
but it's not me at all.
I'm just talking about that.
There's guys out there that will rock
your fucking world and liberace was
probably one of them.
The other guy that played,
the guy that fell in love with him was
played by Matt Damon.
Now I love Matt Damon.
I'm watching this and I'm like,
this is going to be fucked up.
Matt Damon plays a confused kid that
he's bisexual and one night he goes to
see liberace play the fucking piano at
EDC,
gets impressed by liberace.
He goes,
oh my God,
look at the way he's moving his head
that an afterward he sneaks into vip,
at least sneaks in with this little
blonde hair.
He looks beautiful.
Matt Damon,
he's all yoked up and shit and liberace.
He's got his robe on with his sandals
and he looks and he sees Matt Damon and
you could see he loses his fucking mind.
He's just looking at them with that gay.
Looked to him like,
I'm going to fucking kill this pork chop
when I get my hand.
No,
Matt Damon sees this.
Andrew Santina was a dig and he's
looking at me.
He walks over to him.
He goes,
oh my God,
Linda playing something.
He started texting people or I was
taking selfies.
I'm pushing the show.
Oh you,
thank you.
When I was a kid and I can't shut it
off,
I'll go,
we'll go listen to the bit folks to run
the candelabra.
The problem with like planning a bit,
everybody stops and then you pull your
phone out while I was checking to see
about the shit to be there for it there
and forgot to put it back up.
So that was on youtube.
Either half of it was.
Oh well that's a problem.
I'll fix the board just for a second
day.
The fuck are you listening to you just
stand there staring.
We're watching Santina play with his
phone.
You're,
you're one of those no cases on your
phone.
Fuck that.
What's the difference in risk taking
move.
But.
But what,
what?
What's gonna Happen?
That's gonna break.
But then I get a new one.
So first world,
but the apple care shit.
It's 90 bucks and you get a new one.
But do you want it to get a new one?
Don't you want to just protect your
phone so you have to go to the fucking
apple store when you drop your phone.
Here's my argument.
You have an argument for that here?
Yeah,
because everyone says it's white.
Look.
Okay.
This is why I liked the sleekness.
The design,
the feel is beautiful.
Then we put cases on them and fuck them
up.
They brag about how thin and one of them
they are.
Then you shove a fucking case on it.
It loses all the beauty and the
architecture of why I like the from
Steve Jobs was in love with the idea of
like the design of the phone and that's
what apple's whole stance used to be.
Sleekness design could thin like
everything about it was how sexy it was
and then we're like,
yeah,
put a fucking case on it.
So it never breaks.
Still succeed with this case.
No chunky.
This sounds classist,
but like I have enough money.
You obviously way more than me,
but like you can afford to break it,
so I just don't care if I.
most Americans that like breaking a
phone is a big deal.
I get it.
I can afford to buy a new phone.
I don't care.
I know you're so first world.
Yeah,
but that's fucking honest.
That's like saying,
you know,
I get it dude.
Some people treat shit.
Some people treat it like it's also
everyone will go.
Knock on wood,
I've never broken a phone.
I've never had a case watts.
This is my fifth iphone.
Come on.
You never broken A.
I swear on my fucking mother's life.
I've never shattered a phone in my life.
Never once.
I've never had a case.
You Ever Shit your pants twice?
Once,
once in Japan.
Once here ever.
I Shit my pants.
Ever once in Japan.
Once,
here,
here.
Not here,
here and right here in the studio.
I'm shitting my pants.
I Shit my pants in Japan.
That's a real fucking story.
Yeah.
What happened?
We,
we,
we went out the night before.
I had the most fun I've ever had in my
entire life and my stomach was not
having a good time with whatever we ate
for breakfast and I was walking the
street.
We were going to a temple and I and I
had,
I just had a little,
a little far came out and I and I
stopped and I thought,
no,
no way.
No Way.
Really.
I couldn't.
Like,
I couldn't comprehend it.
Actually it happened.
I had to go to like a little seven,
11 type place and in this little tiny
room,
take off my pants,
take off my shit,
underwear leaving in the fucking in the
bathroom and then and then go wrong.
Even shit underwear and bathrooms brewed
move.
And now I know those people have to go
in there and smell that underwear.
I just posted in the trashcan and I
covered up as much as I could.
You coming up the smell?
Shit.
The trashcan out.
Why don't you throw it in the garbage
can outside.
Carried out.
Carried out two fingers.
My poop.
When my shit.
My Shit underwear.
Yeah.
No,
just go like this.
no.
I had shit.
I had to throw it right in the trash can
and disappear.
That's kind of like.
Yeah,
but that's not okay.
Okay.
This isn't that uncommon like in a lot
of places around the world.
You can't throw toilet paper in the
toilet.
You have to put it in the trash can.
What?
Yeah.
Fuck.
You go to central and South America.
You can't.
They don't.
They say please no toilet paper.
So people shit in the toilet and then
they throw the fuck.
They're asked wipes in the trash.
Jamie say,
alright,
I'm not playing.
You've never been to a country like
that.
Maybe I didn't read their sign because
they don't because the pipes are old.
They can't handle all that.
People pay.
Fix your pipes.
You fucking cave people.
Fucking cave.
Monks get pvc.
Cheap.
Fuck Dude.
In Thailand,
every bathroom that I went to right next
to the toilet has a goddamn garden hose.
Like you would use to wash your car on
your ass.
Yeah,
like nothing.
Not a gentle,
but day like we have those toilets.
Those.
What do they bond Dell's.
Those are so dope.
Yeah,
they're amazing.
Yeah.
The seats warm.
When you sit down,
you press the button,
a gentle warm jet of air hits your butt
hole and like,
oh,
that's so nice.
Yeah.
This wasn't like that at all.
This was a Goddamn like you'd clean an
elephant with a green.
Whoa.
A garden hose.
No.
It's like one of those guns.
You know,
you,
you have a lot of pressure on it.
That's what it was.
You can't flush the toilet paper down
the loo and these European countries.
You go my friend or look at all these
different ones.
Bulgaria,
Turkey,
Greece,
Macedonia.
You can't flush toilet paper.
You can.
It'll fucking break a pipe though.
What kind of thin walled pipes they have
over there?
That toilet paper's breaking big.
No,
that doesn't make any sense.
The mass amount,
it clogs up.
The pipes are too many people.
Shit.
No one seems so crazy.
Like what?
Have you have a lot of fiber in your
pool?
Like what if you're eating a lot of
Broccoli and you have like elephant type
who?
Riley in rock shit.
Another thing in Thailand,
they sell poop paper.
They sell paper that they make out of
elephant shit.
Yeah,
because elephant shit is all fiber.
So what they do is they take that
elephant shit.
They wash out the fecal bacteria and
they use the actual plant fiber
material.
They turned that into the toilet paper
and you.
It's a novelty.
You wipe your ass with elephant shit.
So you wipe your shit with Shit.
You're wiping horseshit.
Yeah.
How does it.
It can't smell good even if they've done
by the smell and it.
Bro.
What is this poop paper park?
Yeah,
that's it.
Elephant who?
Paper poop paper.
The poop poop poop.
Yeah.
Paypal.
They take it and they break it down.
Building a future in which humans live
in harmony with nature.
Okay.
And they sell this stuff and wipe your
butt
with it.
Who sold here?
Funny.
I get all of it.
Uh,
it's like when someone has a clever
family reunion shirt and it's just like,
okay,
I got it.
Fuck it.
You know what?
I'm sick and fucking tired of who by the
way,
people that make shitty slide jokes.
I think they're funny flight attendants
now that are trying to make her like
funny little jokes that that's like a
culture now.
Do you know what I'm talking about on
the fucking Internet started it.
Yeah.
But a lot of other airlines are doing
because they think it's cute,
like southwest does it all the time
because their trash,
they don't give a fuck fucking trash
cans and this guy,
but no seriously unlike maybe delta,
but like they make little cute jokes.
Like if you don't know what we have to
drink,
maybe you've never flown before because
it's been the same thing for 20 years
and then a few people like few idiots on
the plane that you're.
Don't make jokes.
Did fucking this isn't the time.
Just tell me that bullshit and go sit
the fuck down and shut up.
Dude.
I don't like the jokes.
This is coming from a guy who makes
jokes for a living for money.
That's not their job.
Their job is to make sure I get my
fucking sprite.
Let them in my peanuts.
A little rush.
Fuck them,
Jo.
I don't like them.
Do you remember the first thing that you
ever did in front of a group of people
that got a laugh?
Like a little inappropriate laugh?
Yeah.
My Buddy's sleepover type of shit.
Little thrill that you get with that.
Inappropriate.
Yeah,
but it's not my job.
Their job is to be the flight of 10.
I don't need the job from the flight
attendant.
She's so rude.
Fuck them.
He was so mean.
They're fucking mean.
Use their man.
Most of them are assholes.
One Lady told me that I had to put my
fanny pack in the overhead compartment,
fine,
shake it off and how to use it as a bag.
I a stored as a bag.
I'm like,
why should I go?
What if I take everything out of the bag
and put it in my pockets you could do,
and then she couldn't say.
She just take the bag off.
I'm like,
this is a power move.
No one's ever told me that before.
One Lady told me to take the fanny pack
off.
I think she was just anti fanny pack,
but you don't see.
But you know this and Americans that
have experienced that know when you fly
in business or first they treat you like
a fucking king and when you fly in the
bud of the plane,
they don't give a fuck about true.
This was in first class?
Yeah,
but she was doing that because she's fed
up with whatever her day was,
but most time they let you get away with
anything.
I think she was Chubby and she wasn't
getting Dick and that fancy.
I felt at the time to fanny packs,
you get snack and I just asked you a
question,
are you chubby and do not get any dick?
Is that why you're doing this?
Imagine if you said that.
I just need to know before I put my
fanny pack away just because of a lack
of Dick.
It'd be great if she goes,
you know what?
Yes.
And then just walked away.
You want to give me some deck you can
wear the fact that you fucked me with
just the fatty package.
Back Click taking it off overhead
apartment.
It is.
I'll be right back with liberace winks
sent me today.
I can't wait till everyone at home has
that stuck in their fucking heads.
I started to shake.
I was articulate the things that people
thought were entertaining and like the
fifties,
it's so strange.
You go back now and watch that stuff,
but that was like a.
That was almost like sultry to back.
Then you know that she's like with our
pen,
like this innocent girl writing note.
What the fuck was she even writing down?
And then she's,
she's gone.
Oh,
just when the piano man winks at me,
like that's the naughtiest shit of the
day.
If I had a time machine,
what I would love to do is take like all
these old folks that are like in,
in the audience watching that weren't
even old folks at the time.
Right.
Young people like in their thirties
thought that was wonderful and put on
like a modern day mumble rapper.
Have 20 people on stage with them,
puff and blow,
you know,
freaking fucking lean and trap,
trap,
trap music and just give it a hobby.
The booze were already did the,
about who these people.
Just like,
like the kid with the hair,
the rainbow hair kid.
What's his fucking name?
Is he a mumble rapper guy got beat up in
New York.
He got pistol whipped right?
Allegedly.
You never know when a guy like that you
made it up himself was just gonna say
that's a great promo.
Yeah.
He might have punched himself in the
head because I saw a photo online.
It didn't look like he got.
Why can't I think of his name?
A friend of mine was breaking up with
her husband at the time and they were
screaming and yell at each other and
dude starts clawing at himself,
start to scratch marks on him saying
that she was attacking him,
ripped his clothes.
He called the police,
a guy did it.
Listen,
it's not outside the realm of
possibility.
A mumble rapper took that fucking dunked
himself at the head,
the security to call,
call the ambulance right away when in
this day and age,
people are just doing anything to stay
relevant,
to stay relevant,
to get attention.
They'll do anything.
Well,
that's what the.
That's what instagram has become.
That's what the Internet has become.
It's just become the way to be like what
it's become,
but it's certainly a venue for people
that don't have any other options.
It's big.
It works.
A lot of people make,
make actual careers on just on
Instagram,
but there's people that like Kendrick
Lamar is not doing that.
Yeah,
he's.
but what I'm saying,
he doesn't need that shit where he
doesn't need that shit,
but some people do need that shit.
Then they're tattooing their face and
mumble rap and pistol whipping
themselves.
Face Tattoo blows.
It blows my mind.
Do you know that Travis Barker just got
a new one?
She got a face.
Tattoos says blessed where on his cheek
we doin,
Bro.
He's just.
He's covered man.
He's got a little more room.
I see and yeah,
he's had his whole name.
I know his whole.
All of his neck has done.
He's done.
Is he heads done but he stopped at one
point,
right?
He doesn't.
He never did his face.
Yeah,
he's done.
He's doing his face now.
Shit.
Yeah.
It's on his instagram.
Says blessed right below his cheeks.
No.
Who's the guy who wrote?
Always tired.
Post Malone.
Yeah.
Above his eyebrow.
Right.
It's not on his eyebrow.
Below his eyebrow.
Somebody had a great meme of post Malone
and in high school his high school
yearbook photo and they wrote pre
malone.
I thought that was hilarious.
That was not the face tattoo thing is.
It's a bummer because there was no
authorities.
Look shared dude.
What the fuck he had done.
He's blessed bro.
How blessed,
what got on top of his head to his whole
head.
The entire head.
Right.
But if you grow out his hair,
you wouldn't see it.
Right?
That's the thing.
Yeah,
he.
But that is fucking come on the head.
The full head tattoos a trip.
You one man.
The top of your head.
Like could you ever get one on your
head?
I'm sure my whole arms are done,
I'm sure.
But I mean,
would you.
Would you ever want to know?
Never.
I don't think so.
Maybe.
Maybe the back of my head.
A Bake Eagle for a big.
That's him when he was young.
Look at that.
Is that him?
No tattoos.
It's not come on really,
really younger.
Say Wow.
Oh Wow.
Is that a cigar?
A blunt?
I think it's got to be.
God The knows that bold thing.
Septum don't like that one on chicks.
It's kind of sexy.
It's grow.
Some chicks.
The chicks with the nostril one I think
is sexy right here.
You don't like this weird except them
can be.
Cool.
Listen,
the one thing that's cool about it as a
girl with a tattoo will definitely suck
your Dick.
She's not scared of controversy or get
it yet.
What's that one?
What's that?
Video?
What?
Oh,
see that.
Go there to that video with him where
you see his shirts off.
It's all the way up his neck and his
face and shit.
Yeah.
He's tatted the fuck out.
I mean his whole body.
He's completely covered.
Front and back.
Jesus.
That's a strange thing.
Then people do that coming from a guy
with two sleeves.
Yeah,
but how.
But what do you think the.
What do you think the movement is to get
another one at this point?
Because you have a lot.
Do you want to get more?
I'd like to finish my right sleeve.
Yeah,
but I'm saying Brent,
branching away from the sleeves.
Like is it now the next thing you'd be
like,
you know,
I'll fuck with my neck now.
I don't know man.
Maybe he'll leg.
Maybe a calf.
Get a calf done.
Yeah,
I have zero.
How come?
I don't know.
I think we've talked about this before.
I think you get across your stomach a
gangland style.
Ginger's rule.
Rope.
Yeah.
Ginge the Gel,
right?
Joe?
The ginger on my chest.
How about suck?
Not Carrot Shelf.
Eat My carrot right above my dick.
Get your vitamin K right.
If I.
What if I did a.
What if I did a bunny rabbit?
Right?
Right next to my cock.
Yeah.
Nice.
Do you know a.
do you know?
This article came out about redheads.
We produce our own vitamin D.
You have to at like twice the rate of a
normal human being.
In fact,
while you're so white.
Thanks.
I'm not that white for a redhead.
I'm not that bad.
He's fucking more pale than I.
Am you guys getting angry?
He does.
That's the thing.
Irish.
Yeah.
That's the whole reason why people got
white in the first place.
We don't,
but I read redheads,
pacifically producers more than any
other.
We produce twice as much.
Vitamin D is anybody else on the planet?
Wow.
Yeah.
I wonder if there's a correlation,
but you read heads.
Been happy because vitamin D is one of
the things that fucks people up like in
Seattle.
It does.
Yeah,
it does.
That's why they tell people the most red
heads are happy.
You think there's.
Do you think there's a correlation
between A.
I don't know,
a lot of funny,
mean Burger.
You Louie.
Three really funny redheads.
Yeah,
but I would say this though,
the majority of American red had
different than European red heads
because they grew up in dreary shit.
Right?
So their conditions are different.
Will you have sun?
You live in California.
Every state probably have massive
amounts of vitamin D.
probably too much.
Like if someone checked you out,
they'd be like,
this guy's dying a vitamin D.
he's overdosing on vitamin D and d here.
Santino data,
vitamin D,
Man,
it's fucking terrible.
That is a weird thing that we have a
vitamin that we get from the star.
Yeah.
That's star.
That gives us a vitamin.
Yeah.
I mean we make it ourselves,
but we get it from exposure to a star.
You've read about these people that just
like eat sunlight for breakfast.
You know this shit,
you've never heard of this shit,
Joe.
This is real.
He knows me.
No,
they eat sunlight for breakfast.
They say that they get supplemental
stay.
Get enough supplemental nutrition from
taking in the sun from certain hours of
the day.
That's real.
I swear to God they live by it.
When I was doing that Scifi show,
Joe Rogan questions,
everything.
One of the things we did,
we went to this guy who was.
He had some cockamamie device that he
was claiming did something that it
really didn't do,
but when we went over to the guy's
house,
one of the things he shows me this
picture on the wall,
some Indian guy from India with like his
face is covered in white makeup and I
go,
what is this guy's deal?
And he goes like,
oh,
that's shrieked Bali,
Gaga.
You know,
he hasn't eaten any food or drinking any
water in 10 years and impossible.
Literally impossible is.
I said to him,
I go,
that's not true.
What does this Guy Henry called eat the
sun?
He bought this bullshit.
Eat The sun.
He weighs a puny hundred and 35 pounds.
What does that say?
But he could lift weights.
What does,
what does it?
But he can.
He weighs 100,
but they can hoist 965 now knowing
fucking impossible.
No,
he can't look at them with a socks.
Are Those old school gym socks?
Old School gym socks or coming back to
the other girls?
Yeah.
Hot Girl with like old school gym shorts
and old school gym socks that go up to
the knee.
Why is that sexy?
Because it's raw.
It's reminiscent of like sexy youth does
something youthful about a teen teen
summer moving.
Yeah.
There's something about that.
Like the hot chick with long socks and a
short skirt.
Socks with Stripes,
stripes.
Blue Stripe at the top.
Hot chunky shoes.
Big chunky white shoes underneath.
Yeah.
What's with the stripes at the top of
the sock?
Like the socks are good,
but you know to make it all perfect.
Fucking stripes of color.
You know that was an accident and
threading and they just leave it.
Yeah.
Come that side.
It's so fucking hot.
Look at that girl.
Woo.
The diary of Jane?
Yeah.
Keep your socks on,
baby.
Really?
Yeah.
Your feet are fucking garbage.
Cover those fucking hooves up.
Yeah.
That's a look.
Gym,
socks and pigtails.
Entire threads dedicated to it.
It's.
Yeah.
That's weird.
That's a weird thing that people in see.
Well,
this is a tube.
Socks.
Compression socks is a big thing in.
Girls will wear them out out of the.
Out of cross fit and all that shit.
Now that's a big thing too.
Why do they wear compression socks?
What's the benefit of compression socks?
It's the same thing as compression
sleeves.
It's exact same thing.
She keep the muscles warm.
Was that war?
That would.
It does.
Athletes.
Certain athletes claim that it helps
keep their muscles in between place.
See I've where rash guards for Jujitsu.
Functional,
but it's compressed.
It's like,
you know,
it's compression.
It's like it's tight.
It's the main functionalities not to get
your skin super fucked up right now.
There's this for,
for to keep the muscle tightened warm.
That's weird.
That's fucking weird man.
Like it's marketing,
but I don't know the science behind it.
Fucking weird.
I mean,
listen,
there's.
I mean there's something to be said
about keeping muscles warm when you're
working out,
when muscles get cold,
but is that what it does?
Lets lets google.
What are the benefits of compression
clothes for athletics?
There's going to be some,
some compression.
A salesman that fucking hit us up and
just give rights to nine.
Our paragraph.
I started to shake for compression
socks,
ties quick,
properly designed and fitted compression
like we're prevent venous blood pooling
in the legs and improve leg symptoms and
decrease the risk of blood clots.
Yeah,
but there's so much blood flow when
you're working out.
I,
I highly doubt there's a lot of pooling
and athletes.
One of the things that I saw when I was
in Thailand where they had stores,
stores,
stores that were was all compression
clothing including face masks and
gloves.
It's just a.
that's just like a leather daddy suit
with that was like.
It was tan skin card.
It was fucking strange,
man.
Weird.
We're outside the store.
I was like,
what is this?
What is this?
Oppression shops through.
They had it for little kids.
No little masks.
A little kid.
Now you're getting into a weird
territory,
little pants,
little masks,
little shirts.
It was real strange shit.
That shit is gross.
Then you get into a territory of
something pervy.
I think it's people that eat too many
noodles.
You just eat all those carbs.
He's just fed down.
See,
I know people that travel.
My Dad used to work with this guy and he
would travel a lot and he always wore
compression.
He was a bigger dude.
He wore compression sleeves and socks
and stuff on planes because traveling a
lot.
That's why that piece.
Some people like it for that.
I think some people use compression
socks when they travel up there on
planes all the time because you do pool
and clot on planes.
Yeah.
It happens to people all the time.
You Pool and clot blood can pool on
planes very easily.
Don't you need to just go to the gym?
You Lazy.
Fuck fact.
God damn fact fucking compression
shorts.
It's not going to fix it.
That's just wrong with your body,
bro.
It's pooled and pooling.
They could.
You just sunk in the seat.
You're gelatinous membrane.
Would you like it?
If they,
if they,
if they had an airline that you could
work out on the fly and play a pay a
premium and had a gym in the back of the
plane,
like on a commercial jet,
dickheads doing cleans and he drops the
bar and it goes right through the be
fucking hilarious.
Kids start getting sucked through the
list.
All your own risk and you're in the
middle of the perfect bit.
You're writing and you're like,
yes,
I got it.
You clap your hands together and you'd
show your lab.
Cop goes flying through the whole floor
because some dickhead wants to do is
cross fit workout on the crossfit gym in
the sky.
You couldn't,
um,
couldn't lift weights there,
but maybe you can have machines.
Yeah,
that'd be a cool machine.
You could do or presented those
resistance bands.
Machines.
Those was like a cable cable machines,
right?
Those three 60 machines.
What does this,
Jamie.
It's on its way.
What's Santina knows ahead of the curve
ahead of the modular modular planes.
I think that they've sort of the fuck
out of here in the flight exercise
project.
Hold on,
let's go up.
So we could read that inflight exercise.
Your next flight abroad could include a
Jim.
When's this article published?
May,
may pose an Airbus project.
Is displaying a prototype flying jim
module,
the San Jose airport.
The modules can be used for spas,
napping pods or gaming center.
That's tight trans.
Stop,
stop,
stop scrolling.
Transpose isn't the first to suggest
using cabin space for activities that
promote wellness.
Although such ideas are intriguing.
A lot of these concepts don't really
account for the business model of air
travel.
Says Devin Lidl principle behind
strategist of fatigue.
Yet he's what's called the fund stopper.
Devin,
you fucking fuck head.
What does that.
Those are sleep.
Oh,
that's like a,
um,
like rubber bands.
Like you do like yoga mats or something
like that.
That's Kinda cool man.
See that seems reasonable,
but I feel like so few people are going
to use it that it's going to be one of
those things where after awhile it's
just like,
hey,
remember when we used to have a smoking
port at the back of the plane?
That's what's going to be like.
Remember that used to have a fucking.
Oh,
so these are the napping pods.
That shit's awesome.
When we were flying to Thailand,
there was this one dude that went to
sleep immediately and he was an enormous
guy.
Andy,
who's the loudest I've ever heard in
your life.
Wake the fuck up.
I go,
no.
Hey,
hey,
you're young.
You're fucking.
You're loud.
I'll wait cheap.
Allowed you wake them up.
I do it.
I've done it before.
I'm playing with you.
Say I go,
excuse me,
and they,
you're,
you're fucking,
you're snoring.
Just want to let you know you're
snoring.
And they give me.
They give you like a fuck.
You look,
but it's fuck them.
I don't want to sit there while the
plane is quite here.
You having fucking apnea.
I don't need to hear it.
Yeah,
it was bad.
it's fucking gross.
Went,
went on for hours.
See people covering their head with
pillow.
How long is that flight?
Fifteen hours.
Twelve hours.
Thirteen hours to Taipei.
Fuck.
That shit was gray.
Rome.
Rome from here is 14.
One fifth,
something like that.
Yeah.
So no mother fucking listening to think
about.
Think about that.
They put a gym on there for a premium.
People might pay man for long flights
and not in that,
not
in the US,
but overseas flights.
People might be like,
man,
I can fucking get a workout in before I
land.
Take that snoring guy,
bring them back there and goes,
well,
you're still on a machine.
Yeah,
you fat.
Fuck you fucking heads to fat.
That's the sign that says p,
everyone pays fat.
Fat,
head,
fun.
Workout for free.
I want to know like what?
When did people start getting fat?
Fat?
Well,
I'm,
I mean,
I mean that sugar documentary claims
that it's in the revolution of corn
syrups.
Introduction into the fucking.
I would like to know though,
like when people,
when the transition,
what was a rare person like way back in
the day they got that fat,
like what do you think?
Like the six sixties in the seventies,
things started to change.
I don't know.
I imagine when our technology boom
happened in the eighties as probably
when it all started.
Well it happened before that for sure,
but it was also like sugary cereals and
stuff.
Right?
And doesn't that stuff introducing the
eighties,
seventies were like that.
That was the end of like natural cereal?
No,
they had those sugary cereals in the
seventies for sure because I was a
little kid,
a little kid in the seventies where they
like they are today.
Oh yeah.
Cocoa puffs in like.
But I mean the amount of hunger,
I wonder what it is comparatively
because.
Because now it's like 40 grams of
fucking cup.
It's,
it's absurd.
I think it was the same.
He do.
But then do you think it's because they
were using cane sugar then?
In different times?
I think people got fat even back then.
But I think it's expanded.
It's expanded to everything.
Well,
convenience to write those.
You can get any fast food everywhere all
the time.
Twenty four hours is brilliant.
It doesn't.
Mcdonald's really put sugar in their
fries.
Yeah,
man.
They put them in their fucking buns.
They put in everything.
Sugar's in everything and everything.
They make their buttons.
The buttons have sugar in them.
They add sugar to the bottle.
Yeah.
Wow.
Dextrose?
It's dextrose.
Sugar,
sugar.
Howard taft.
The president was 340 pounds and that
was a long time ago.
Three 40.
How tall was.
He was trying to look up more
information on that,
but it was all come,
just loved come.
He just drank a gallon of come.
I'm ready to address the state of the
union,
but first I need my kids,
you know,
task.
There's a big juggernaut.
That was this thing.
My fellow Americans burp Kennedy.
Same thing.
Kennedy was a little,
little,
little teacups.
Kennedy apparently was on all sorts of
drugs,
including crystal Meth,
the meth them up.
He was a,
he was in a meth.
Yeah.
Kennedy apparently had some serious
physical ailments and um,
he was in dire straights.
Is that true?
He was a big pill head who's in massive
pain.
They said that in the,
like,
it's like if he didn't get assassinated,
he would've never done two terms.
He would have been dead just from
whatever the fuck was going on was going
on with them.
Yeah.
He had some serious back problems and so
he was such a young fit guy.
Like he didn't look,
he didn't look.
He looked in shape.
Not really.
He looked young,
but compared to most presidents,
anything.
He looked in shape.
Here's a picture of taft.
Look at that fat.
Fuck that Walrus.
Looking at motherfucker.
What year was this?
Nineteen.
He's got.
He's got food in that hat.
Maybe 19,
19,
but I can't say.
Well,
I bet it's booze,
right?
He was solid.
Serious booze.
That's so big.
That's crazy.
How big he was so easy.
Our fattest president,
who's our skinny as President Lincoln,
that tall,
skinny motherfucker.
Lincoln's pretty God damn skinny.
He was a rail wirey.
How would that look?
Three 40.
That's what's funny.
Those pictures make him look to $50.
I was gonna show you this one.
Photoshop,
and in 1929.
This is White House portrait.
Oh yeah.
They skinned him.
Skinning him up for that.
Yeah,
they did the trim them up a little bit
because it's a portrait.
Because they made that chair look big.
It was smart.
Move on.
The artists.
Yeah.
They shrunk them up a little bit there
and make them look a little bit more
regal.
Like Obama may have been one of our
skinny.
He was skinny as shit.
He was fit even though he smoked
cigarettes.
George Bush,
I guess was our most recent Bush was was
not out of shape.
He wasn't just a big.
He wasn't a big guy.
Reagan was thin for an old guy.
He's saying he was like in the
seventies,
right?
James Madison was five,
four and 100 pounds.
Damn.
Not even a real guy for $100.
That's not even a real guy.
That's a fake number.
What year was that?
James Madison.
Boy.
That's tiny.
Five for a 100 pound or pound grown man.
What did he eat?
Presidential term?
18.
Oh,
nine slash 18 slash 17 people back then.
Didn't have any food.
I think the average height person
probably five,
five,
six.
When they were always just dodge and
Indians.
If you were a smaller,
the arrows that go over your head.
If we didn't have to duck,
you can just stand there.
Well,
what do you think?
That's not funny though.
I bet you if you.
If you had a sliding scale of the height
of the presidents,
but there was a thing about the civil
war where they said that,
uh,
the average soldier in the civil war
weighed 125 pounds because they were
like 17,
16,
17 years since they were kids.
Right.
Most of the soldiers were like children.
Yeah,
I'm sure.
Well,
most of the soldiers today or young,
same thing,
we use 18 as a standard,
but back in the day there wasn't a
fucking number.
Wow.
Wonder what the number was?
Google the average size of a soldier in
the civil war.
I'm pretty sure it was 125 pounds,
you know,
that I have are so tiny.
I got a picture out there of Sinatra.
His mugshot.
You weighed 125 pounds.
Yeah,
he was.
He was a skinny,
tiny,
tiny dude.
Five eight.
One 43.
The average.
I look up the Ed.
I'm sorry.
I spoke to quick.
This was a no.
Yeah,
civil war.
An average civil war soldier was white,
native born farmer,
Protestants single between 18 and 29 and
he stood about five,
eight,
1:43.
That's weird.
One of the.
It was smaller than that.
That also sounds very under 43.
Seems like a reasonable size for that
time when there's no food,
but you're also talking about it.
There wasn't this like how could they
have been that organized?
I'm sure people were just fighting who
were around.
I'm sure people just join the ranks and
they weren't like,
you got to go through the process.
They were like,
here's a gun.
Go fucking kill somebody.
Do you think they didn't measure their
size?
I think they've.
I think they took anything they could
get.
I think they were like,
fuck this.
We need everyone we can get.
Especially in the south,
Metro,
southwest,
the southwest.
Just all against be.
Everybody wanted to join in the south
and the north people were like,
alright,
I guess we'll fuck you guys up if we
have two soldiers was 12 told you?
Look at the little drummer boy,
common age was 19.
Holy Shit old.
His age was 80.
You imagine you're 80 and you're.
You're in Gettysburg.
What are you doing,
man?
Just go sit down fucking 80.
You have to fight,
man.
You want to keep that stupid flag flying
to the fact that they still bitch about
it.
Did you watch fucking Sasha Baron cones
thing it.
It's a holy shit of him getting this
Georgia.
This is Georgia state representative to
be like fucking huck and the n word out
like 10 times saying why did he say it?
What was the,
cause you know it.
Sasha.
Sasha finagles him into doing these fake
psa ads or whatever of like
antiterrorism shit without be given.
I don't want to give away Stacie's
Oscars.
One of the head writers over there,
he was telling me he was,
he was,
he was.
He says it gets crazier.
Oh Dude.
You could tell it that you could tell
them just tipping you.
They're like,
man,
here's a little something for you.
It gets really crazy at the last episode
from this.
This care.
The one character that's like,
uh,
the Israeli guy.
Yeah.
Too fucking good.
As I care.
It's great.
Pull up a video of that character when
he was talking the a second amendment
guy like making like cute guns for kids.
They do.
They do ads for guns,
but the character is so crazy.
This is the most sugar is the Israeli
commandment.
And tell the kid that have safety gun
and it's got big,
big plush doll on top.
They put like little plush towels on
kids,
guns and shit.
Pull his mouth.
Eat,
shoot gun.
Apparently they like those really
hardcore Christian Second Amendment
cause they love Israelis of course.
So they love Israeli soldiers.
Man.
This is why he decided to have.
This is really character.
This dude is hilarious.
Gop lawmakers who enjoys giving,
endorse,
giving three-year-olds,
guns,
stuffed animal.
The stuffed animals surrounds the gun.
You're not gonna.
See any day,
but see if you can get a video of him
doing the character.
Yeah,
see click.
That's just going to be the full
trailer.
They won't show you,
but play it.
Play it,
play it,
play it.
No,
that's it.
That's it.
My next guest is a gun rights advocate
and he the bushmaster semiology
rifle.
The type of rifle Adam Lanza used to
killed 20 children and six mile ride is
quite a blast to shoot with tons of fun.
Some of them are much more cool than
others.
Are you proud of what you said?
It's just a fact.
In America there have been a lot of
shootings in the school and into
university.
What do the liberal say is the solution?
Well,
they blame it on guns because the guns.
Yes,
we've got sugar.
It is.
We started a program in Israel for
kindle guardians.
Okay.
We train them from the age 16 down to
the age three.
Yeah.
Well I.
I think it would be a good idea.
We'd been pushing something along this
line for years,
but really haven't gotten any traction
with it.
We were thinking seventh or eighth
grade.
You're talking much younger than that.
My son was in the very first program.
May he rest in peace night doing what I
love.
Quite developed a conscious where you
you feel guilty about doing something
wrong that's developing that you're
learning right and wrong.
If they don't,
haven't developed that yet.
They could be very effective soldiers.
This year in our state government,
they had a bill put in that would have
made it illegal for someone four years
old to 12 years old and have access to a
gun.
Uh,
we,
we killed it.
We killed the bill.
They tried to stop.
Four year old children benefit from
having access to guns.
Yes.
What is the logic that these people come
up with?
May just think that children can't
handle them.
We want players who are really experts
at what they doing not play.
Also a checklist and we don't teach
toilets because they call it the
terrible twos for me.
Do Instructional video to show you?
Yeah,
well you should folks watch that.
But what's really crazy is the makeup
man.
Let's look at the makeup that he's
wearing.
He does one where he's like a,
an NPR type of cat and he goes to
Kingman,
Arizona and he tries to build a mosque
and they,
the initiative that comes out of their
mouth off on it.
The one dude goes,
there's blacks in this town and we
don't.
They don't belong here either.
And the guys.
And of course he's,
he makes a joke and then he goes,
no,
what I'm telling you is we tolerate
them.
We tolerate the blacks.
It like sit and it sits in the room for
a second.
You're like,
good fucking God.
These are real people that exist there
exist.
Take tolerate the blacks.
Great.
Great name of his show too.
This is America.
Yeah,
this is it.
This is the guy from new mosque per
gigabit,
Mpr guy with the wooden beads around his
neck.
He nailed it.
His intro was hilarious because he goes,
I'm a self hating white man plays at
play that video.
Try to find that video.
It's really fucking funny.
And then you.
And he's a genius.
He,
he,
uh,
he lays us.
What is this,
this,
this
huge economic growth here.
Wants to see an investment of
$385,000,000.
Guess what?
You guys are going to get it here to
tell you chosen as the location of a
brand.
You state of the art mosque.
I know some of you are thinking,
okay,
this is just another typical mosque.
This guys is going to be the world's
largest mosque outside of the Middle
East.
The word alone scares you,
Jimmy.
When I hear the word mosque,
I think of terrorism.
This guy,
is there a need for this and kingman?
Yes,
there is.
Your town will become for the whole
thing for tourism,
but the character,
the character is this guy right there.
That guy that.
The toothless dude that was just on him
too,
but the other dude,
he's the one that's like the fucking
blacks we tolerate.
It's a.
We have to.
We do it because we have to look at his
shoes.
Ready fucking outfit.
This is amazing.
Every detail of every character he does
the clothing is is some of the funniest
shit.
It's real specific.
Hilarious is he kind of had to do this
because everybody knew what he looked
like.
He could just do just do Ali g except
for people in these.
You don't want someone goes.
Someone will notice she's famous.
Not In those worlds.
They don't.
They.
If he'd had no makeup on,
no money in King Lewin who?
Sacha Baron Cohen is.
Do you know what I mean?
The crazy thing is these people must.
Must've had to signed releases.
Yeah.
And I did hidden camera shit,
so I know how that works.
I've done that too.
How did they get us?
Two ways.
There's money,
which is always the best way.
And you make them sign before.
That's,
that's it.
There's two ways to get rewards the way.
Yeah.
You'd make them sign,
you know,
we're going to be featuring you on this
thing.
We did this bit.
Ian Edwards and I did this bit for
comedy central for the show that never
went.
Um,
I don't know if I've ever told you this,
but we,
this bit was so fun to do.
We made a thing called Melanin Mayo
Mayonnaise,
mayonnaise,
that,
that made you darker,
real shit.
And we put food coloring in Mayo,
but we introduced it as new Brown Mayo.
It's a new generation of Mayo.
And so we got people in this test group.
We know that real people in a real test
group,
they go and take tests all the time and
they emanate sample shit.
We put them in a room,
we made them eat the sandwiches,
just fucking mail is the eat the
sandwiches,
all these white people eat the
sandwiches and then when they're done,
we sent in this black dude al and she
shows them a video and it was a pre tape
video basically of white people
confessionals who have turned.
We've,
you know,
we photoshop them to have turned more
brown to start to turn black online and
we're like in three to five weeks you
start to see results.
You start to see cultural results,
mental results you're getting,
you're getting more black by culture,
you're getting smarter,
black,
you're getting cooler black and your
neighborhood to your friends.
Like their faces.
Their faces were perfect.
If we didn't have any volume,
you'd have laughed.
Everyone's like,
wait a minute.
No one said we be black.
We'd be turning black.
I mean,
they lost their fucking minds.
People got so scared.
It was amazing.
That was incredible.
They MTV,
comedy central never aired to any of
that.
Is it comedy central?
Probably hasn't fucking vault.
They throw away.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
That was one of our favorite bits that
we,
that made us laugh so fucking hard.
They're faces.
One woman,
one woman to her credit,
she goes,
she,
you know,
people are freaking out and the route
people started yelling at him and
they're like,
this is,
I'm going to fucking show you.
I'm going to and he's black.
And he said,
Yep,
I'm going to fucking sue your ass if I'm
black.
Kids like the flooding to watch him go.
It's not as bad as you're making it out
to be.
I mean,
I was,
I was born black and I'm liking it a lot
and one woman goes,
you know,
it's disturbing because it's shocking
just to spring this on me,
but I don't,
I'm,
I'm not scared I could take on being
black.
I'll just,
let's,
we'll see what happens.
I mean,
she was like,
turn credit.
She goes,
we'll just,
I'll just live with.
We'll just figure this out.
I guess.
I mean,
it was insane that they bought into it,
but also that that's how we did it.
We fucking made him sign beforehand and
then you paid them out and when it's
over we broke them off more money so
they wouldn't say no because they still
have the legal right to be like,
I'm pulling that up.
You,
you pull it or I'm suing you.
So once it was over,
did they understand that it was for
comedy central after,
after everything was said and done,
and then do they laugh?
A few did not laugh a few laps if you
people are not,
but that was one of my favorite bits.
Melanin Mayo and man didn't work like a
charm.
People were like,
this man needs is delicious.
It was fucking almonds or whatever with
a little brown dye in it.
It's unconventional,
but I really like so stupid.
That's so funny.
Yeah,
that was a funny bit,
man.
They killed,
murdered a bit.
Seeing people think they're about to
turn black and they panic and the black
guys a presenter.
That was the best part.
We put our,
you know,
Al's up there and this guy named Al
sheer is a great improv and he's in a
room filled with fucking white people
telling them they don't want to go
black.
Oh my God.
It was awesome.
It was fun.
So he was saying that he used to be
white.
No,
no,
he's saying he was the representative
for the company.
We loved the idea.
We had images and video of people who
had turned black white people who had
turned black.
But you didn't tell him till after the
eight.
That's exactly right.
The food first.
Then we showed them how we said it was a
commercial because that was whole thing
is like a new commercial campaign for,
for whatever fake mayonnaise company we
made up.
And then we had said,
here's the commercial,
we're going to run along with it.
What do you guys think?
And we played the course.
They were supposed to rate the
commercial.
That's what they do in those test
groups,
you know?
Oh my God.
Now what did comedy central?
Why did they not?
They did.
You know what's so funny is they,
they,
we overshot this pilot because I think
they wanted way more bits for the sketch
show and I just don't.
They a lot of things they said they
couldn't,
they didn't want to air,
they couldn't there.
There's a few things that were just,
he did some fucking great bits.
I just think comedy central legal
department was just having trouble with
it because he,
he was balls out.
He did this thing called gangster
gardener where we went to bel air where
he just started.
I'm like clipping people's lawns and
planting trees with a group of Mexican
dudes.
And they were like,
looked like there were thug the fuck out
and these white dudes would come out
like,
what are you,
what are you doing in my yard?
So we planted trees.
Motherfucking we try to get this
motherfucker looking nice and these
white dudes are like,
no,
I don't want it.
He's like,
we landscaping.
And then he was,
he would hand them bills.
He'd be like,
yeah,
that's 50 bucks,
50 bucks would that Bush?
And these dudes were like,
I'm not giving you money.
You can't.
You can't just like renegade do my lawn.
He was like,
that's how we make money out here these
days in bed layer.
It was like,
Ooh,
we got fucking.
That was a tough day because everyone's
like,
I'm going to fuck it so you.
I'm going to sue every motherfucker in
that truck.
I mean it was like.
I mean there were fun days but a lot of
days and that shit was like going
through.
You just feel people's anger bubbling
over and they're going to murder
somebody,
but al was ruthless.
He didn't give a fighting of a fuck.
You don't have to be a certain type of
person.
He would go do any bit.
He would go to any bar he loved in
racial shit was always his favorite was
making white people feel uncomfortable
to do a hidden camera show.
You've got to be a different kind of
person.
Yeah.
It's a beastly thing.
I you to be a fucked up.
You gotta be fucked up and he and he was
fucking good.
But yeah,
Ian,
Ian and I and another person wrote a
bunch of those.
Fucking weird stupid.
It's got to be really hard to do
something like that today,
which is the interesting thing about the
Sarah,
Sacha Baron Cohen thing.
Oh yeah.
His head.
He like showtimes take some chances.
Yeah,
but you know what?
They took a chance because he is such a
good horse to bet on and look at on
that.
Just on your youtube clip.
That's not even a showtime clip.
That was somebody else as 150,000
views on just a sec.
A clip and it's just really recent.
Yeah,
just they just put it out.
I mean his.
They're circulating all over the
Internet.
It will just get way more traction as
time goes on because it's so fun.
Yeah.
He's a killer.
Free Pr to buy all the politicians
saying that like before they even put
out the shows,
they're all like,
we got duped.
I got duped by them.
I got duped.
Dick Cheney,
Sarah Pailin.
They all came out and were like,
they thought he fucked me over data and
then they had a billboard that somebody
said he was doing stolen valor.
Did you see that?
Yeah.
What was that about?
Because you said that he was,
uh,
an injured soldier and an X.
Right.
There was an ad for him as an ex soldier
or something.
And so that got a ton of fucking press.
A ton of press wasn't at the Sarah Palin
One?
No,
I wasn't.
I don't know.
You'd have to look it up.
I don't remember which one it was.
I think it was a Sarah Pailin
one.
He was a disabled veteran,
but they were saying right.
Stolen Valor.
Selling them out all the shit.
Yeah.
They were trying anything to discredit
it.
Well,
but if it's a comedy series,
it's a sketch comedy series.
You tell me a sketch character can't
play whatever they want.
I mean,
that's,
that's what it is.
That's,
that's like people get mad.
Say No.
I mean if it's.
If you can play a character on a fee,
if you can play a war hero in a film,
why can you play the opposite?
Like born on the fourth of July.
Tom Cruise.
Okay.
What's so funny?
I was just thinking that I think the
character,
he has what he is.
That is the the outright type guy.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Saying is a bunch of stuff like that.
And showtime countered the claim here
with the showtime counter.
Sacha Baron Cohen stolen valor claim.
Yeah,
the counter.
Well,
because they.
Because it was made public as long
statement about it,
but widespread misinformation over the
past week about the character of Billy
Wayne Reddick junior phd performed by
section.
What is the counter?
I think they explained what happened.
They sort of said that they didn't
misrepresent themselves.
They probably thought he was someone
riddick.
Riddick was asked by the senator.
He was disabled and he stated that he is
not an uses,
a mobility scooter to conserve energy.
In addition,
Bear Cohen never presented himself as a
veteran of the US military,
former Alaskan governor,
Sarah Palin during the booking process
or during the filming of her interview.
Okay,
so there you go.
Okay.
Scroll down a little bit lower.
Says on Monday a conservative street
artists replaced a billboard near CBS
television city complex in the Los
Angeles with a doctored image of Cohen
in a wheelchair wearing an army tee
shirt.
The new billboard was kept caption sa,
Sacha Baron Cohen walks away with a hit
and a touch of stolen valor.
Touch.
Yeah.
He's trying to say that it's a slight.
It's a slight at the.
At the troops.
Yeah.
Okay,
but how dare you mock those who have
fought and served our country.
Truly sick.
Mock politicians and innocent
personalities.
All you want
get balanced,
pale and said,
Pailin wrote on facebook.
You run a disrespect of our US military
and middle class Americans via Cohen.
She's so stupid and middle class
Americans.
Fuck you.
You're disrespectful to.
That's.
That's the disrespect,
but just that,
that trick.
She's just trying to game the system by
state and middle class Americans.
Just get as many people in there as you
can.
Prevent Cohen's foreign commentaries
under the guise of interview questions,
foreign commentaries.
What does that mean?
Under the guise of she's so dumb because
you imagine that lady almost became our
vice president.
Like what?
What the fuck would they think?
And they had mccain could have won.
Yeah,
yeah.
He could have one.
Yeah,
she was the anchor that fucking sunk
that book.
But the idea that they thought that that
was a good idea.
Well,
she was a pawn man.
She was such an easy fucking pawn.
I don't think so.
I think shavers,
I think she was used as this little,
this good looking cute item,
a
female,
this middle American gun shooting she
was upon.
I think she was a play and it went too
far.
It was almost like they didn't know what
they had gotten themselves into.
They,
I think they thought that was a.
could been the.
It's one of those ingredients that could
have been brilliant or fucking the
dumbest Shit on earth.
She was the governor of Alaska.
Right.
They figured,
hey,
she's a good looking woman.
She's the governor of a state.
She's a mom.
She shoots guns,
disabled child.
She had all the things that was like,
wow,
what a good pr push.
Yeah.
There was a disabled child while she was
running.
I'm almost positive.
Right.
She gave birth like almost like while
she was.
No,
no,
I think she already had had a disabled
child.
I think she had had a disabled kid.
Her,
her other son was a veteran,
right or,
or right.
And so she had all these things lined up
that were perfect for America.
So crazy.
It was so good when they started
interviewing her.
So what,
what newspapers do you read?
All of them.
I can see Russia from my front porch.
Remember though,
a second.
See Russia?
That was right.
I look right across.
I see Russia from my porch.
I mean that.
Those were like soundbites for,
for America to be like she fucked.
But trump does the same thing.
He just does it in a.
no,
he,
he does.
I heard about that again the other day
because I was listening to,
uh,
the,
it's called the satire paradox.
Revisionist history.
Malcolm Gladwell,
and they were talking about this,
the therapy incident and a Tina fey
actually said that and everyone thinks
that's their appeal and actually said
it.
It came from the snl spoof and
completely got attributed to her.
And genius also ruined that whole thing
that she could see it from her front
porch.
That was from a sketch.
That's not what she did.
Say something about,
she said something about Russia being
there.
Her neighbor,
she did say something about Russia being
closely.
If they're going to come through Alaska.
She did say something preposterous like
that.
If Russia came,
they would go through her right on
snopes,
which isn't the best place to not be
looking things up,
but like they have the article about it
and it says that this came from an snl
skit.
Okay.
Well instead of googling that,
just google Peyton's comment on being
close to Russia.
Right.
She said it sounds like what?
I googled.
I googled Sarah Pailin restaurant from
my house,
but no,
no,
not that statement.
Russia from my house say Pailin on
Russia,
being close to Alaska because she did
say something.
She didn't say something that
ridiculous.
Yeah.
It wasn't as toy said something
ridiculous enough that people were like,
what?
What are you saying that?
And that's where through your
neighborhood they got the influence to
make that sketch.
They're going to fly in jets,
dummy.
Take a walk right across thinking here's
what's in Alaska.
But I think she.
But I think that was just,
you know,
I suppose as she tweeted,
remember I can keep an eye on them from
here that her being like,
let's basically that's the statement.
But also.
But I think this comes on the heels of
her publicly during at press at some
point had said something about it.
It was kind of like how when trump says
something once he repeats it over and
over.
Like if you have watched those clips,
he'll say the same.
The same anecdote because it,
it,
it starts to drain.
The swamp wasn't once I was a thousand
times.
I've to Tom Arnold last night.
I know Tom Arnold was backstage and he
just got the trump tapes.
He said we got a gang of tapes.
He said there's some crazy shit.
Yeah,
I can't.
I don't want to disclose anything.
But yeah,
he's.
He said there is a tape.
Yeah.
He said there's a tape of him saying the
heart and word is repeated.
I just made you a face.
Like I was surprised at that for some
reason your brain.
He said it's crazy.
He said that the tapes are crazy and not
putting them out again.
It's vice vice.
Yeah.
And he said people are turning on him
left and right because he doesn't have
loyalty to those people that are around
him.
So apparently those people are turning
on him left and right.
And testifying and,
and you know,
giving up evidence and information.
Like everybody realizes it's a sinking
ship.
We were talking last night,
we're like,
dude,
it's only a year end.
Yeah.
One fucking year.
One year.
This guy's got three more years of this.
Saw The news yesterday about the call
that Colin has the tape and he said that
trump knew about it.
Oh yeah.
And that's supposedly proves the
collusion.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Does that work?
What does that mean?
Timing did know about the meeting with
Russia.
Collusion is,
is,
is proven.
Proven.
Yeah.
Then.
And then it can be.
He can be prosecuted.
Kenny be a sitting president.
Yeah.
Right.
If colluding.
I think you have to be impeached before
you can be like,
well yeah,
you wasn't president.
Sure.
Week,
comfortable with President Pence.
No fucking way.
Is that happen?
Do they just,
can we have another election?
Do it again.
Can we do it again?
We could.
I mean,
I don't know if a TA.
It obviously hasn't happened,
but I don't know if Congress can call an
emergency election.
This is the thing.
Hillary has been ramping up the
publicity lately.
It's almost like she's ready to get back
in there.
Well,
because she recognized because there's
so much going on to try to.
People are trying to bury him.
Dude,
pence will be scary to me.
Man.
That kind of scary.
Scary now.
He's not a good.
I agree candidate,
but I'm second in line as him and that
does freak me out to this kind of be a
good Democrat out there.
Yeah.
Where it's not a compromised completely
corrupt person has been embedded in the
system forever and might've killed a
bunch of portable.
I think everyone that you would want to
run wouldn't.
I think you're right.
I think that's how I always feel when
I'm like,
Oh,
you know,
it'd be great.
It's like I'm not fucking running.
What a nightmare gig to 100 grand a year
to B to b.
They make more than that now.
What is it?
Two 50,
400,
maybe,
maybe half a million,
half a million,
whatever before taxes.
Which trump won't pay.
Yeah,
man,
it's a.
it's a terrible job.
Terrible job and awful.
Really.
It should be a job that many,
many,
many people do.
You one person's involved in the
economy,
ecology environments,
everything.
Military shake.
You play God.
You're playing God.
You have to puppeteer everything.
That doesn't make sense.
It wouldn't even work if you had a
village.
Yeah,
and that would.
That would collapse because one farmer
you had allegiance to would get mad.
Yeah.
You had to control all the crops.
You outta to control all the weapons you
had to control all the.
All the laws.
What the fuck?
Yeah.
Get out of control at even a micro
level.
The weird thing is while he's president,
can he start pardoning people?
Will has had Disney.
Did he decides to pardon a bunch of
people while he's president?
If he does that,
what is it still good?
If they put them in jail,
if he pardons while he's in office,
then there.
Then there scot free.
But you're saying after.
Yeah.
I don't know.
Like if he goes to jail,
Pardon?
People already already pardoned.
Yeah,
but he's saying like once I did a bunch
of them,
right?
Yeah.
He has a bunch of.
Pardon?
Jack Johnson,
which is like a.
that's not really going to help Cat
Stevens.
Still not.
Pardon man.
Peace train.
Still not finished to Susan.
Yeah.
Dinesh D'souza.
Right?
He pardoned.
Not Pardoned Cat Stevens.
Don't know what I'm saying.
But what is Cat Stevens in trouble for?
You remember this?
This was years and years ago.
Cat Stevens,
like a said,
now he's a part of Muslim faith and he
left the United States and another,
but he also wanted a death for Salmon
Rushdie.
Salman Rushdie,
and they wouldn't let him back in United
States.
They took away.
They've.
They took away his entry.
Right?
I don't even know if he's here now.
He does.
He goes concerts in Mexico.
People go down to Mexico to watch Cat
Stevens concert.
Yeah.
Where you can get them down in Cabo.
Is that true?
Look it up with Cat Stevens is a lot of
back in the United States.
I don't think so.
We're.
Let's look up cat Stevens tour dates
because he went to go see him.
Let's go see if I'm being followed by a
moon shadow.
Shadow shadow will go see him in
Tiawana.
He's playing the border tour.
Could you imagine if we went to see him?
That'd be fucking fun.
It'd be a fun piece to do.
Events currently booked.
Yeah,
he's having a tough time.
I think he did it because he needed some
money.
Oh totally.
He didn't have his publishing rights or
something like that.
He lost money,
so we went on a tour,
try to get some checks,
got some chatter,
and then went back to the mosque.
All that chatter.
Bought some Hamas.
Pass it around.
Pita Pita,
you guys.
And you know.
That's one thing that an artist can do.
That's a musician that a comic can't do.
A musician can go back and do all their
old hits and still raking it in mean the
beach boys.
They're not.
They could still go on tour and at a
drop of a hat and make a ton of money.
Yeah.
Well they also.
They also bands now reconvened with new
members and they make.
They still do that shit.
I mean the dead tour with John Mayer
than fucking.
They're big ships because hair.
Yeah.
John Mayer,
the John Mayer handsome guy that hangs
out with Dave chappelle tours with the
dead.
He tours with sing.
Yes.
Get the fuck were to God on my life,
man.
Get the fuck dead.
Has that because he wants hippie pussy
and deadheads.
Love it.
Why do they love it?
I don't know.
I got a couple of friends that are dead
heads and I never was into the dead,
but they were like,
it's.
There were skeptic.
There were skeptics at the beginning.
They're in fucking love with that guy
because he paid.
Paid does it right man.
He fucking pays homage to the right way.
He's fucking God.
Fucking insane.
John.
Fucking.
Your body's a wonderland is playing
dead.
So that's the world where it can't get
any more absurd.
No,
it can't.
What does,
what does it say about cat?
He played some concerts in America in
the last couple of days.
A lot back recently.
Who let them back in Obama,
the Muslim,
the Muslim hope that Kenyon article in
the New Yorker about his comeback last
year.
So last year he got let back in.
Wow.
Maybe a couple of years ago.
I'm much so it was before trump,
so it was probably one of Obama's last
moves and office for sure.
Let them back in from on.
Fuck them.
Fuck the Donald.
We gotta go.
We gotta go to a cat.
It's shown up knowing God,
you got to go cat.
So it was within a year.
Maybe you won't come back now that
trump's president.
I mean for money.
He'll fucking go anywhere.
I'm sure it's your last year.
Maybe it was the last.
The last year was last year.
Yeah.
He's saying now the trump is around.
He probably won't come back.
That's so funny.
Where was he living?
Did it say where he was?
Just doesn't say specifically.
Yeah,
he was on the fucking news on the Lam.
That cat was gone.
Yeah,
he's in Libya or some shit.
Fuck yeah.
Hold up in a compound in a cave and
shit.
What a weird move.
Huh?
A guy who sings,
he's like really?
Pc Sof.
He's trained.
Whole fucking shit was out of picking up
people from coast to coast of the peace
train.
Well,
there's people that believe that Islam
is the religion of peace.
Totally.
The southern.
A lot of people believe in that shit,
so maybe he thinks he's on the path to
peace and I think Islam is probably like
every other religion,
right?
There's factions of Christianity that
are wonderful people.
Sure.
Really calm and sweet and loving and
they get a lot out of it.
And then just people that are just
fucking loons and the serpent handlers.
Yeah man.
Those fucking people as Christians.
Those are my favorite Christians.
The ones with the snake protect me from
the serpent.
The snake,
the snake.
My whole family had been surfing
handlers.
Sense Wade was sweater.
We've been a part of the serpent culture
serpent or serpent?
Paypal and they use poisonous snakes
too.
Oh yeah.
Wasn't there a documentary on serpent
handlers?
I feel like there's a documentary that I
have on my queue.
I have so much shit.
I'm supposed to watch the students.
I'm so behind on the.
I got to walk away.
I'm only in wild wild country.
I'm only on episode four.
I need to.
It's good,
but it's slow at the big chunks of slow
days where you're like,
people say that it could have been done
in three,
could have easily.
There's a lot of drag out that you're
like,
didn't we go over this already?
But that's just them being like,
fuck,
come on Netflix.
Netflix wants six.
I want six.
You want six?
Six netflix.
They don't need more fucking money.
They own Hollywood there.
I couldn't get out 30 comedy specials
just from just for laughs.
That's nothing that bill sent me.
They can't even.
They weren't even sniff.
One of my fucking far.
I can't even fucking get near them for
some reason.
Netflix wants nothing to do with me.
I don't know what the fuck they're thing
is with me.
Maybe I did something wrong years ago.
They're doing putting out so many
specials.
I'm like,
how come I can't get anything to do with
you?
I don't know.
They probably haven't seen you.
You know,
the thing is,
man can keep up.
Yeah.
No,
I think there's too much going on.
The only thing keep up.
Did they have enough people?
I really don't.
I mean,
I feel like there's so much comedy going
on right now.
Have you ever seen more standup?
Never in my life.
It's,
it's overwhelming.
There's a lot more shit comedy being put
out than I've ever seen or,
or not shit comedy in terms of my
opinion in terms of like,
just see just comedy for the sake of
comedy.
Then I'm like,
this isn't a fucking well put together.
Special people didn't take time for.
Some of these things are pumping them
out.
Yeah,
there's definitely that too.
And there's people that are taking
advantage of an opportunity,
right?
Somebody offers you a shitload of money
and you don't really have a set ready.
Oh,
they just fucking want to do that.
That's the one thing that happens with
people when they start doing movies.
When you start doing movies,
you're on a set 16 hours a day.
You don't really have enough time to
write and you're definitely not
performing every no way.
That is a crazy move to be doing all
these films and then do an hour special
when you.
You're barely.
Yeah,
they can do 30 and they're pushing 30 on
fun shit in between maybe even 30 men
because not even 30,
like a real rock 'em sock.
'Em robots 30 know a really know it's
probably not a back to back 30,
like bang,
Bang,
Bang.
It's more thin than that.
There's a lot of shit out there.
Louis said this to me once backstage and
I think he's right.
He's like,
in order to do comedy,
to really do it.
You can't do anything else.
That's probably the only way to be the
best at it was you could do it and you
can do it good,
but to be at your best,
you really can't be doing anything else.
I believe that.
I believe that wholeheartedly.
Yeah.
Miami thinking you have podcasts because
podcasts are just talking.
Yeah.
This,
this is working out for working out at
comedy to do a special like podcasting
and comedic relationships and us still
moving in whatever realm that is for
comedy,
if it's all branching for it,
but other things.
Acting that takes totally away from it.
Yeah,
because when I go do acting shit,
I'm totally disconnected.
Comedy loses its breath for awhile.
Well,
what about when you were doing acting
on?
I'm dying up here.
I performed them almost every night.
Right?
I didn't give a fuck.
I was burning the candle at both ends.
I didn't care because you had to.
Because I know because I also know that
I don't want to lose steps.
I was like,
I don't want to fucking lose steps.
Yeah.
I care about acting.
Not as much as I care about standup.
Yeah.
You care about it like.
That's cool.
I like it a lot.
It's not your thing.
No.
I'm in love with stand up.
Acting is like.
Yeah,
I like it.
I like it a lot.
It's very rewarding.
I'm not.
I'm not and I'm not disrespecting the
art.
I'm just saying it doesn't do the same
thing for me that stand up does.
Right,
but what if I don't go out at night and
try to make sure I'm on booking shows
late night
to do you lose.
You definitely get disconnected.
Peep and they people who do it know who
they are.
They know when it happens.
Sure.
Tend to do sitcoms to the sitcoms will
do it to youtube because you're on set.
I killed it for me,
man,
when I was on news radio,
there was a stretch where I was doing
set.
I was doing standup for a couple of
years where I was from writing any
jokes,
just doing the same shit shit and I was
getting disconnected with the jokes and
I was starting to bomb.
And then you hate him.
You hate the material.
Well,
you talked to jeff to a couple of days
ago in Garland.
You know he does it.
He just goes in wings it all the time
because he loves it.
He doesn't want to fuck because he's on
set all fucking day,
so I don't know where he's finding time
to write stuff anyway because Jeff's
like,
no,
I just like to have fun because he
doesn't.
He doesn't have any time.
He's.
He's doing 50 things at once.
He doesn't have time to sit down and go,
all right,
let me try to pump out some new
material.
He's not on a plane,
on the road to shows today's on to hit
to hit shows.
Isn't it funny too?
He's saying that he doesn't want to do
15 minutes sets.
I just do like an hour on Friday and see
items now or.
I disagree with it too.
I didn't understand it when he said it's
a waste of my time to leave the house.
The first thing I said,
I'm in my kitchen listening to it and if
he's gone,
I'm not gonna.
Leave my house.
Fifteen minutes ago.
Fucking joe sitting right across your.
He leaves his house for fucking 15
minutes.
I did it last night.
Yeah,
no shit.
Constantly talking about.
Yeah.
I think it's a different.
I think it's just a different breed of
certain people are like that,
that they're like,
Nah,
on maximize that time and only do it at
this chunk,
but certain people you meet,
if I.
That is the maximizing of the chunk of
being.
Like if it's just 15,
I'm going to.
I'm going to make sure that 15 is.
He doesn't have bits though.
Not the same way.
Like he's just a funny guy.
He raves and Improv in Improv.
Yeah,
but he doesn't have like a chunk on lava
lamps and they're gone wristwatches,
you know,
he doesn't have that like I to open up
with lava lamps.
That's not this what he does.
Well No,
like he did a fallon set a couple of
years ago.
Maybe it was a year ago,
two years ago,
and it was all about lotion at the
airport and that was like a bit.
That was the first time I'd seen jeff do
a.
because you know,
again,
this is obviously no disrespect to Jeff.
I Love Jeff.
Jeff's a great guy to me,
but what he does is,
yeah,
it's that it's much more like free form
and unfailing.
He did like a bit.
I was like,
oh,
that's like a bit.
And I.
Jeff doesn't really do bits.
It doesn't chunk out bits.
He's like,
if he finds a bit it'll be great.
You know what I mean?
But he usually just fucking around.
I watched him in Atlanta.
We were both playing Atlanta at the same
time.
He was just,
he was shitting on like a one of the
other comics and it was,
it was hysterical.
He was just fucking around with the
other conflict.
One of the other comics that went on
before,
but the,
that took up 15 minutes of him just
fucking around and then got into like
talking to them while he's loose.
Oh.
So I mean,
one of the funny things that he said was
that he's so comfortable with just being
funny.
Oh,
and I have to tell Andrew dice clay,
he was not disrespecting you.
Dice dice went on this whole rant about
fat.
Jeff given them a hard time,
he thinks because garland was saying
that it was Rick Rubin's idea to do the
day.
The laughter died.
Dice is like,
no,
it was my fucking.
I fucking was very upset.
He was very happy.
He get really mad.
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
Dice kits map like that though.
That's so strange.
I know he got.
I know he goes.
I know.
There was all sorts of a dicer.
Sebastian.
Weird,
strange fucking beat.
What happened there?
I don't know dude.
It was like Sebastian dice had said
something online I guess on instagram
about Sebastian stealing his act or
doing his shit.
Emulating him or something like he was
going after Sebastian for some fucking
reason.
So passion is very original.
He's him.
No one is Sebastian,
but that's who he is.
Well,
I think sometimes can use to open for
him years and years and years ago is um,
if I'm not wrong people.
Correct.
You're right.
And I think maybe dice felt like he's
not giving them as do.
It's like dissecting,
like I fucking raised you and you're not
even going to kiss the ring a little
bit.
First of all,
grown ass man who's built his own career
completely on his own and brilliantly so
he has no anybody shit,
wasn't it that he didn't talk about
Dyson as book perhaps?
That's probably the crux of it.
I think it's the layers for the for,
for,
for old friendships like that that have
gone sour.
Maybe it's layers.
It's that.
It's why don't you go to my fucking
dinner party?
You know what I mean?
It's bullshit.
It's all bullshit piled up when you get
a guy opening for you for years and then
he's smashing it.
Now he's a fucking superstar.
Yeah.
That's got to feel weird.
It's got to feel it.
It's got to feel weird.
I'm envious of what Sebastian's done
because Sebastian can kind of go
anywhere.
Yeah.
It does anything,
but I mean,
he's like,
he's really successful,
but he's also like this weird kind of
famous.
Well,
he could like go to the movies.
He's famous restaurants famous.
He's famous,
but buddy sells out tickets like he's
mega famous.
Well,
we talked about this when I was in
Vegas.
I walked by.
Gaffigan was playing one of the things,
one of the arenas there and had a
billboard up that said,
you know,
Jim Gaffigan,
28,
29,
whatever,
and I was saying to the comic that I was
with,
I was like,
isn't that funny that like if Gavin was
just like walking through the casino,
there's a good chance a lot of people
just wouldn't see him see him.
Do you know what I mean?
They might,
they might,
but in that fucking arena sold out five
shows.
Sold out like unmistakably famous and
standup.
Yeah.
But he's the Kinda guy that could go to
Ralph's and you'd be like,
uh,
someone will go.
I think that that guy he looks like
maybe he's not.
I don't know.
Do you know what I mean?
Like these songs,
but hey,
hot pockets.
Hot pockets.
Yeah.
Be it.
Can I get a selfie selfie bro?
Come on,
man.
I like going.
I like going with you to watch how
people ask you for selfies.
My favorite thing is when I'm with Joe
and somebody asked me if they can take a
picture of Joe.
That's the.
No,
look at me.
We're talking,
hey,
do you mind to me?
I'm not his fucking hand.
Why are you asking me?
That's the.
That's so annoying to me.
Don't look at me dude,
if you want to converse with a grown
man,
do it and not your through line to get
to Joe Gaffigan's doing an interesting
thing.
He decided to.
He on his own to not put a special on
Netflix.
It was a conscious because
he felt like there's so many digital
platforms on who's going to offer it
among all the other platforms,
so he's got it on.
Amazon's got it on Hulu.
Who's got it everywhere?
We're where the see find out the places.
Gaffigan put out his special on.
I've seen the billboard and it
mentioned.
Is that on the bottom it says available
on all platforms.
I have seen that Amazon platform.
Replatform step.
Netflix.
Yeah.
He has been kind of crazy.
I get that he wants to.
He stood out his whole career as being a
clean.
You know what I mean?
Like I think this is another way of him
being like,
I'm also not grouped like that as well.
I think that he made the decision was
that there's just so many other
platforms available that he didn't want
to limit it to Netflix and be one of the
many on Netflix already.
You know,
may.
I mean it might be actually a smarter,
more lucrative move.
Although the access that people have
probably isn't as good as you think.
Netflix is a global brand.
That's the problem with giant huge.
It's just the thing.
Yeah.
But if you have it on youtube,
youtube is probably bigger than
anything,
right?
More people watched this.
Youtube has a bigger reach,
but it's just way more content on
youtube.
Right.
But here's the other thing.
Who's watching youtube on television at
home,
the new gender.
There's a lot of kids that are due
because now youtube TV is like a big
thing,
but how many in comparison to to watch
Netflix and I'm sure Netflix to launch
that ass Netflix at home.
Netflix owns that ass.
I would think about the mobile though.
How many people watch Netflix on their
phone?
A lot.
I think there's one netflix or one.
I just did my special.
They said half the people,
so it is on youtube too.
Yeah.
Have people found a netflix watching on
their phone?
Well,
look at it like this.
I've never pulled up youtube on my,
on my computer.
I mean I,
I,
I rarely.
I'm saying I put it on my phone every
fucking day.
There's something on my phone that I'm
looking up on Youtube.
Yeah,
that's true.
Always,
always,
always on the phone and if I'm at the
house,
if I had watching something on my phone
and I'll flick it to my apple tv or
whatever,
he put it in movie theaters for a day
too.
That's cool.
That's a cool move.
While it's on the move.
Well how many,
how long is it?
Seventy minutes.
That seems like annoying to go to the
movies for 70 minutes.
Yeah.
However you have an opening act.
You fuck.
He's got a warm up guy that just stands
up there on a 90 minute show.
Come on.
When we were backstage last night,
we were like,
you know,
because we had a lot of guys on the show
last night,
the late show.
We're like,
this show's going to go long.
We're like fucking scorsese movies at
three hours trying matches.
Scorsese movie that.
That fucking main room needs a new AC
unit though was drenched.
I was soaked through a tit sweat when
you gave me a hug when I brought you on,
I didn't want to hug you because my
fucking shirt was stuck to my body and
my mind was minutes.
I was totally drenched by the time I got
upstairs and just fix it.
Well,
they are struggling with money over
there.
Fucking money.
It's a money pit.
Isn't it crazy that that place used to
be struggling for money and now they
just.
They sold out two shows in the main room
yesterday.
Showing the,
Oh,
are showing
the fucking bell.
It was just people constantly running
through that place.
Last night,
every room was sold out.
There's not a club like that on the
planet or.
Nope.
Doesn't exist.
Well,
that's what the dude runs.
The social media was saying last night.
He was like,
you gotta understand like just for
laughs is going on right now.
This has a way better lineup.
Yeah,
and when just for laughs used to go on
at the store,
it was like ghost towns,
ghost town.
It was like no,
comics were in town anymore.
Audience people weren't even coming out.
Now just relapse.
You wouldn't even know what's happening.
There's still so many bangers in town.
It doesn't even fucking matter.
It's just
weird time.
Weird time for standup.
Best time it's popping.
Would you know,
I wonder what is the.
I mean there's so many different.
It's so you can't really have one
factor.
There's not just one factor,
but these,
the Internet for sure is the underlying
machines,
like more people have access to standup
comedy through youtube and all these
other different ways.
Netflix and then on top of that it's
podcast,
like comics get together and people.
Those podcasts become a part of people's
lives daily live their drive and then on
top of that that podcasts are talking
about the store.
Like everyone's talked the store,
the store was taught and that because
you go to the laugh factory tonight.
Yeah,
you hear crickets.
Tumbleweeds.
It's just different because the laugh
factory doesn't have the same kind of
talk that comics talk about the store.
The store is romanticized by Comedians.
It's just like that.
It's that spot.
I mean,
Shit,
when you look at the Echo,
look at the instagram for the comedy
store.
Every time they put a lineup,
read almost every single comment.
We'll have someone go,
fuck man,
I wish I didn't live in Xyz.
I would kill to be there.
It's crazy and it's Wednesday.
It's Wednesday night,
Thursday night,
and they're like,
dude,
if I could fucking pay for a flight,
I would do it right now.
If I could afford it,
kill.
We have this virtual reality thing.
The htc vive.
You put the headphones on and you ever
seen that?
Yeah,
it headset.
You put the goggles on earplug.
They're going to do standup in that
thing.
One hundred percent,
100 percent.
There's no doubt.
But in thinking about that a lot lately,
when you put that fucker on and you feel
like you're in the room with that,
like that would be an amazing way to
broadcast.
Stand up into your living room.
Fuck,
yeah,
you could be at the store,
on your fucking couch.
Just standing up.
Might even be better.
It might be kind of cooler than actually
be in there.
Not Cool will be in there now being
there's always going to be cooler,
but cool in a unique different way.
Well,
it's an.
I think it's just another ad,
right?
Like to me you're always gonna want live
performance because we always have in
the history of humanity,
we love watching performance live and
that's just another way for people to
access who physically can't get there.
It's always going to be sexier to be
there because you feel like you're a
part of it.
But to actually be someone in there in
the virtual world that will be justice.
I mean for people that can't physically
be here,
I think that's just,
that's the closest you can get.
That's the best you can get when you're
there.
It's live,
you know,
it's just a different kind of thing.
No,
stand up to me on tape.
Has ever been as funny as it is live?
No,
no,
no.
Not even close you the best you can hope
on a television show,
so it's just kind of capture a feel
of it.
When you're doing a special for
television,
what is this is as close as they are
getting right now.
Holy Shit.
This is like a virtual audience and like
a almost like fake movie theater type
situation and you're all watching the
screen together.
You can look around and see people and
you watching the World Cup.
This was for the World Cup.
Well to start with what sets?
So you sit down and you feel like you're
in awesome seats at the World Cup.
This happening at the same time that a
couple of websites are starting with
their calling.
Watch parties where you watch videos?
No,
my friends together online at the same
time.
This is the actual World Cup.
This was for the World Cup.
So you actually watched the real game
with those goggles on and you're fucking
in the third row.
Look how good that looks to and then
look at the hard rock ad so they can put
ads up.
Well,
that's where they're going to start
making all their money.
Damn,
that looks amazing because like,
you know,
you've seen it.
A lot of sporting events.
They use green screen on their ads girls
so that they can change for television.
I mean that'll just be that.
It'd be the same thing,
dude.
How dope would that be for UFC fights?
Fuck the HTC vive one wasn't the UFC do
that.
Call them up.
They do do experimental things all the
time.
Right?
That they try out and then they don't
always use them.
Yes.
Yes,
but that seems like the best one with
those guys on.
And that way you could be in the cage.
You put a camera on the fucking guy who
was a referee,
the ref ref cam to shoulder camps and
some hip cams put cameras all over him.
Cam circling him a camera.
Make the fucking ref cameras to do that
in pride and pride to Gopro and Gopros.
Yeah,
and you'd be able to see it from the Ref
Cam,
but those are just shit.
You'd have to get really good cameras.
They used to be shitty.
They're pretty God damn good now for Vr,
they got to be really good cameras.
Right?
Don't take Gopros.
They can get it now.
It's.
I mean,
yeah,
I think they could probably could do it.
I bet someone could pull this,
our gopros always with that fish
islands.
Sort of.
Yeah.
You got to use some software to.
To not have that,
if you will,
because they're built like that.
They're built with the fish eye on.
Why do they do that?
Just for perspective angle field of
view,
because it's because it was originally
intended for extreme sports and so that
that's always the best view in every.
Every extreme sport is the fish.
I looked great.
I think you're trying to recreate your
eyes like you have a,
you know you have 180 degree or probably
more than that,
but it's not all just stored it.
That's the problem.
Everything's gets all stretched out and
weird at the edge of class.
I don't think anyone's figured out that
yet too hard,
you know,
but that's why the.
That's why they're like that.
Like what four K is is inching towards
live,
live broadcast in four k is crazy.
They say four k is more clear than the
human eye.
Can see there's elements to it that are
clearer than what human I can actually
see.
And they're going higher than 14.
Yeah man.
What are they doing now?
Are they doing something?
Eight k cameras.
What is that camera that you're getting
that phone with?
The red phone.
The red got.
Damn.
I always forget the name of it,
but it's a reds.
So it's a cell phone.
Like with the red,
the camera,
the Red Technology Company read,
made a phone and explained.
Read that.
It's like a super high end camera.
They ferry fees with
just for all high end things.
They,
I think they based started like $20,000
or something like that.
That's just,
that's not even the lens.
That's just the physical fucking camera
itself.
Yeah.
The bulk of $5,000.
Battery or not really but.
So it gets really expensive.
But anyway.
So this is supposed to be like a modular
piece that's supposed to work with some
systems they have coming in the future.
This like the base of the,
of the phone might connect to a camera
or my connect to a series of other
things it might replace.
Um,
I think they actually said that says two
cameras on the back.
So anyway,
the other cool part of it is the display
is holographic,
which no one's actually seen yet because
it's a new technology like playback can
be in the warrant.
They supposed to release his phone over
a year ago.
They showed it a year ago.
And when did you buy it then?
On preorder?
I think I bought it last about a year.
What do they clip you for?
How much we're,
that's the same price as a iphone and
the 1200 bucks I just had to prepay it,
get 1200 bucks so they can advance the
technology they needed.
The money I imagined.
So yeah,
we all paid for.
I think so,
yeah.
And then just trusting read because it's
not,
you know,
it's a fly by night,
but they're also getting,
I'm sure tons of a VC investors to keep
pumping money to keep that going.
That's the kind of thing that the
technology is so far ahead,
they're trying hard to get the hardware
to a place where it works.
And when is this supposed to come out?
I'm supposed to be shipped next month.
So in the next four weeks have some
people.
There might be the testers out.
Imagine some magical day,
like they're not going to tell you,
but like August eighth for instance.
Well August,
August ninth is when the Samsung Galaxy
note nine comes in matching.
That's probably gonna come up with
similar ads coming out.
Now apparently it's going to have the
most storage of any phone.
The biggest battery,
it's going to $4,000,
million amp battery.
It's going to have insane cameras.
This is Samsung's last hurrah with the
note and the note doesn't work this
time.
They're just gonna stick with the
galaxies because the galaxy s nine did
not do well.
It didn't sell well,
but it was an amazing phone,
but it was too close to the galaxy.
S eight.
It wasn't much different.
It was just like a.
An incremental step better as opposed to
like the iphone 10 is kind of way better
than the iphone seven,
you know,
the seven and eight.
It's just like the shape is better.
The fact that all it has is this little
tiny little notch at the top.
It's all screen.
It's pretty dope.
Camera.
I don't know who I was.
I don't know who was talking about it.
I think it would maybe be a comic,
but they were like,
man,
if Steve Jobs was alive,
that would have never been up there that
notch.
He was such a meticulous fucking dude.
Weiwei has an amazing phone called the
mate are or the [inaudible] pro.
This is the always the company that
trump is keeping from selling cell
phones.
Oh yes.
States.
And there was an article here.
I'll send it to Jamie.
There was an article that we were
talking about this yesterday with Dr
Deborah.
So.
And then there's an article on a,
I think it's on bg are here,
I'll send you this right now.
But they were saying there's no reason
why they shouldn't have this phone for
sale.
Like there's some fucking weirdness
going on.
But this,
um,
this one,
uh,
porsche design made their own version of
it.
Porsche design made a mate 10 rs.
They caught like rally sport,
like their cars,
the cars like my gt three Rs.
And they,
um,
they took away the notch,
like fuck that notch.
Like we're just going to have a thin
bezel on the top.
And then one on the bottom,
you can't have a notch.
No Porsche designs.
Like,
nope,
no,
fuck that fucking nuts.
But that's what I feel about what that
guy.
I got mad at a guy at apple and I said,
I said they fucked me over on an
appointment or something that was being
a dick.
And I go,
you know,
if that guy was alive,
this company will still be doing better.
And he was like,
okay,
that's me.
And I was like,
I'm just saying,
I mean,
yeah,
they took a tank when that guy died.
It's definitely gone.
So down to laptops are dog shit,
dog shit.
They're so bad.
They're beaten.
They're getting class action lawsuits
about the keyboards fucking up new small
smartphone.
Trump tried to ban drop to its lowest
price ever on Amazon.
But this is the problem is it's the best
camera in any smartphone is three
cameras on the back.
It's fucking amazing.
40 megapixel camera.
Holy Shit.
But the problem is it won't work on all
bands in the United States because it's
European design.
It's not,
it's not built for this and it's only,
it's only gsm.
So you have to use it on a and t or t
mobile 10 by one by one for 800 bucks.
But it's supposed to be the fucking shit
and the,
the screens.
Amazing.
You've got to be able to jailbreak and
manipulate those films and make them
easier to,
you know,
because they're not designed for the
same bands.
He says right there,
you could buy it right now.
Seven hundred 95 bucks.
But the thing is,
it's just,
I don't think it works exactly the same.
I think if you have an at and t phone.
Let's see.
That's a SIM factory unlocked.
So you can use any international Sim Sim
on those.
Yeah,
but the problem is the radio,
the frequencies that it picks up,
it doesn't pick up the same.
All the same bands.
It's like 18 t or t mobile has does not
work with sprint,
verizon,
US cellular and other cma cameras.
Those are cdma because it's a GSM phone.
But the thing they're saying is that
even if you get a GSM network like t and
t or I'm going to have to ask one of the
dudes that I know like Lewis from unbox
therapy or a flossy Carter,
those guys that do those videos,
they would know.
40 megapixel camera for my first digital
camera that I ever had was like five.
I think mine was one thing that I was
like,
that's fucking bad.
I was.
It was bullet,
but back then I remember being like,
Christmas,
look at these fucking Christmas photos.
That point I was trying to make us sit
with the Wifi like that without making a
phone call and dialing the numbers.
There are so many other ways you could
communicate with the people you need to
communicate with and still make a phone
call.
Yeah,
that point's not valid because the
places where you can use that Wifi,
you also get signaled that you could use
that phone on.
The real issue is in the places where
signal sketchy.
Like
weird rural areas from Mississippi
tweeted me and said he's been doing it
for years so he has no cell service or
Wifi,
Wifi phone.
He gets around.
He's like are you could probably do it
better and larger cities than I do in
Mississippi,
but I've been doing it for a long time.
Right.
But so he's going off of like starbucks
sell Wifi or what's he doing?
Or your house or like all the places you
go to.
I did that in Japan,
but when you're in your car driving down
a rural road,
this is the point.
You're not going to get a service.
Nope.
You're not going to get Wifi and you're
not going to get cell phone service,
but with a t and t or t mobile,
they would have some service in these
weird areas.
That's the only place where these phones
to be a problem is the weird areas.
Spots in la it would work fine.
Yeah.
Yeah,
and those weird areas than like that.
There's more problems than just not
being able to connect to beans in a
weird area.
Exactly.
See you there,
Bro.
Maybe you're hunting.
You know,
put your phone away.
They're looking for fucking looking for
pussy.
Looking for forest.
I'll look for obscure.
Pushy.
I don't like pussy.
Were low density environments like
kitchen.
Gayle out.
Camping her up.
Anita come.
No.
Bring them a poetry.
Forced her to listen.
Can I read you something?
Oh,
it was that the worst.
Somebody wanted to read you their
poetry.
That might be the worst thing other than
I want you to listen to my music and
have a seat.
No.
Play my music for you.
Nah.
I'm going to jump out the window of this
place.
Not even play the music,
but play a recording.
You listened to my shit.
You listen,
you're going to put this record on this
record.
I got to go.
Where's your bathroom?
I'm leaving now.
Fuck out.
I did that.
That's really funny.
There's a.
This is my buddy and I.
We got into.
We got kicked out of a party for being
fucking rude and obnoxious and this
famous chick took us back to her place
with her boyfriend and we're all hanging
out and he's like,
dude,
let me put on my shit now.
I'm not kidding.
He's playing his music.
My Buddy's looking at me like,
how are we going to get the fuck out of
here?
I go,
I got to go to the bathroom,
went to the bathroom,
left my buddy there.
Did.
I did.
I was like,
I'm not.
Listen to this bullshit.
I don't care if they're fucking famous.
I'm out.
I went home.
If you did that to me,
I would cry laughing if you left me in
the living room and they were like,
where's Andrew?
I'd be like,
did he texted me like six times.
I didn't respond.
I was like,
no,
I will be howling left.
That motherfucker left me because you've
put on that music bullshit as you put it
on the music.
Hey,
I think the music's great,
but Andrew like throw me under the bus.
He's a big music fan.
He doesn't like that Shit and handle it.
All right,
let's,
let's bring this bitch home.
Andrew Santina will be with me Saturday
night in Temecula all day,
but Django casino two shows.
Sold the fuck out.
Sold out hard
the next weekend.
Come see me in Philly.
If you're out in Philly,
come see me next weekend.
We had a good God damn time the Chicago
Theater to Kansas City and St Louis.
Let's go.
Kansas City August 10th.
St Louis is something other than August
10th the next day.
Figure it out,
Joe Rogan.
Love you guys.
Bye.