Hello Freak bitches.
You said some billionaires make you
uncomfortable.
Have you been in the room with a
billionaire who said something or done
something that made you uncomfortable to
meet babies,
but that's normal.
That's what everybody does.
They marinate with that 48 percent tax
bracket.
Was there any barbecue sauce or would
they know that?
I've met.
I've met quite a few over my years of
working for the UFC and I think the
weird thing about human beings is yos
expect,
well these people are going to be
fucking different.
I've met royal people.
I've met royalty in a,
especially in the Arab Emirates,
United Arab Emirates,
and a normal regular folks like you talk
to them.
Super friendly,
super normal.
I know a dude who's,
you know,
he's royalty and he listens to my
podcast like weird shit,
but when you're around him after like a
minute,
you forget that he's royalty.
He wants to talk mma right now,
wants to talk.
Techniques,
You know what happened with that?
Why did this go wrong?
What do you think his prospects are
like?
Dudes like a super fan.
So we have these awesome like technical
conversations about strategies and
stuff.
So like can I check in with
can,
I mean he's mad because I have large
rope,
gold rope.
Getting neck and octagon chopper on him.
That's for gentlemen,
sir.
This is a gentleman's podcast.
We are in fact on itunes.
I don't know if you know this with your
dainty gold watch.
What's up with that?
Watch when that shit with one of those
cranes at the fucking carnival.
Almost didn't wear it today because I
was like Joe fucking notice this parking
lot of strange watch.
It's also has a club wristband on
seventies.
No,
it's a.
it's from the hospital.
Can I tell you something?
I was scared to fuck it.
I'm like,
if you're scared to what?
Nothing.
To show somebody that myself.
Sometimes what happens around you is I
get so fucking open that I ended up bad.
I'll probably get scared.
I get scared because
you have one drink and you're hammered.
You drink that whole bottle of champagne
first.
Yeah.
Oh,
I didn't see that
before.
He got to celebrate way.
That's how you know someone's,
an alcoholic.
Not a word,
not a word of what anybody likes.
Some champagne.
Literally open up a bottle of champagne.
He didn't offer any anyone.
No one has had any of the champagne.
Burt Open.
That shit twisted a thing.
Pop the cork.
Oh
Duh.
To first grade.
You don't know that we have a lot of
liquor here.
You don't need to bring your own boat.
It was so panicked and he was going to
do this show sober.
Pop the cork and didn't tell anyone.
You didn't bring it up.
You didn't even talk about like you shot
up in front of us.
She like fucking tied off with a rubber
band.
Put it in your tooth.
You can just fucking and,
and we're just starting
trying to pretend that it's not even
happening.
I'm coming in hot.
I told you that.
That's not hot.
You came and you had to open it.
You got to fucking court in front of
you.
This is coming in.
Rude.
Coming in.
Selfish.
Rude.
Dude.
I got to tell you,
I watched one of your videos of your,
um,
your podcast and I'm jealous of your man
cave.
You know what,
I'm jealous.
I'm ready for this.
The wood on your walls.
What's that?