Johnson,
what's happening buddy?
Joe Rogan,
thanks for coming to border.
Appreciate it man.
Other way around.
You're on the short list of people that
folks consider a rational person that's
running for president.
We're in a very strange time.
Would you agree?
I think we're in the strangest time,
Evers,
um,
maybe in the history of politics,
certainly in my lifetime.
Yeah.
It doesn't seem to make a lot of,
it almost seems like this is the last
gasp of the idea of running for
president.
You know,
when you just do the mathematics of a,
the fact that,
uh,
Hillary and Donald Trump are arguably
the two most polarizing figures in
American politics today,
that trump has to go out and get 30% of
the far right to get the nomination.
Hillary has to go out and get 30% of the
far left when 50% of my of Americans
right now who are registering to vote
are independent at the end of the day.
Don't.
The two major parties represent about
30% of the electorate.
And so where is,
um,
where the interests is the
representation for the majority of
interest in America?
I think it's the libertarian party.
I think it's libertarian.
Um,
people just don't know it.
And speaking with a broad brushstroke,
libertarian,
fiscally conservative,
socially liberal.
Yeah.
That seems to be where most people hang
their hat.
But it's not something that most people
identify with when they talk about their
actual political persuasion.
They usually say there on the left or
right there on the right when you,
someone says they're a libertarian.
That's that dude at the office.
It has guns,
you know what I mean?
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
The what?
The dude at the office,
the crazy dude at the office,
you know.
Well,
so we hit this,
we w w we hit the streets the other day
in New York,
a film crew and asked 40 people what a
libertarian was and it was zero.
No one knew.
So I,
you know,
I,
I'm,
I'm with you.
I understand the crazy guy with the
guns,
but for the most part,
libertarian is just undefined.
No,
nobody knows.
I'm not saying there's anything wrong
with being a libertarian.
I'm just saying when you think about
libertarian,
it's the guy who is fed up and is like
sort of on the fringes.
That seems to be with a lot of people
associate with being a libertarian.
I would,
and I carry that a little bit further
and say that the baggage that the
Libertarians Carrie is survival of the
fittest.
You know,
the notion that you're about no
government whatsoever,
people are going to die in the streets.
[inaudible] yeah,
no governor.
Well that's the wrap.
Yeah,
that is a wrap.
And it's almost like everyone knows that
the two party system is kind of stupid,
but everyone seems to think that any
other party other than the two party
system is unrealistic or any other
party,
like a Libertarian Green party somewhere
along anything independent is
unrealistic.
Well,
um,
I'm back to right now 50% of all people
that are registering to vote or are
registering
as independent.
Statistically right now,
43% of America is independent but new
registrations,
50%.
So I don't,
uh,
I don't know as the,
as people do identify with the two
parties,
the rigged game of the system is,
is that we're only presented with two
choices.
And that really starts with just being
in the polls.
Look right now,
if Mickey Mouse,
where the third name in any poll,
Mickey would be pulling it 30%,
but Mickey's not on the ballot in all 50
states.
And if I'm the libertarian nominee and I
hope to be the libertarian nominee that
happens next weekend,
um,
I'm going to be the only other candidate
on the ballot in all 50 states.
So polling,
I,
I just want to beat in the polls.
There is no way a third party wins
without being in the presidential
debates.
That's just not going to happen.
The superbowl of politics to get in the
presidential debates,
you have to be at 15% in the polls,
Joe.
The rig game is,
is that if you're not in the polls,
there's no way that you can pull at 15%,
but it has to be a consistent polling.
Um,
starting now.
I was in the first national poll that
I've been in a month ago.
I haven't been in a national poll since,
but in a month,
a month ago,
I was at 11% against Hillary and trump.
And was this all established back when
Ross Perot sort of shook up the
political establishment because that
there was a lower percentage required to
get involved in debates before that?
Actually,
well actually there was no percentage
points prior to Ross Perot.
That was something that got established
after Ross Perot.
And what,
what is amazing to me is Ross Perot
after having gotten 19% of the general
election vote the first time,
the second time he ran,
they did not allow him in the
presidential debates,
which is just,
I mean that's the rigged nature of the
game.
The rig nature of the game is,
is come this fall,
if my name does not appear in another
single pole,
the presidential debate commission,
we'll say a Gary Johnson.
He just didn't pull high enough.
What they've,
what they won't say is that he wasn't in
the polls and the Commission for
presidents of the basis of privately
funded institution,
private Democrats and Republicans were
suing the presidential debate
commission.
Also,
we,
we think that it's a antitrust,
we think that,
uh,
not think it's Democrats and Republicans
and they collude with one another to
exclude everyone else.
Bruce Fein is suing the presidential
debate commission.
Bruce finds claim to fame is that he
brought Nixon down in Watergate.
But in the next sentence,
he will tell you that the biggest thing
he's ever done in his life is suing the
presidential debate commission because
this has the opportunity of changing
politics in America.
I mean,
this is really at the heart of this rig
game.
You can't
win the presidency if you're not in the
super bowl of politics.
We've,
we figured the dollar value alone of
being in the presidential debates is
several hundred million dollars.
Just think of the Super Bowl and the ads
that sell during the super bowl.
And imagine being a,
having our second biggest audience.
You don't have like 75 million people
for,
you know,
90 minutes,
two hours.
That's,
that's a couple of hundred million
dollars worth of advertising.
Yeah.
That is the show.
And if you're not in the show,
people don't consider your vote like it.
They think of,
even if you have 50% of these people
that are registering and saying they're
independent,
what they're really saying is they're
not committing to a left or a right.
They're not committing to a democratic
Republican,
but are they gonna vote independent?
That's a lot of people.
They have this idea that if you vote
independent,
you're throwing away your vote.
That's,
that is a stigma that has to be
overcome.
Right?
No,
no,
no.
I,
I agree.
But,
but for those people that they do vote,
right,
and they ended up voting on the basis of
the lesser of two evils,
but since they're registering to vote
and they're registering to vote as
independent,
they end up at the polls.
I mean,
for the most part,
most pick,
most people don't even go to the polls.
Most people don't even vote.
Yeah.
It's,
is there a way to fix it?
Do you think that there's a way to maybe
somehow or another allow people to vote
online and change the way it's set up?
Now?
We don't have to physically go to a
location.
You don't have to sign up physically in
a place that you can actually just do it
from your computer the same way we bank.
That has to be the future.
Um,
that does not exist now.
But that has to be the future.
And from a legislative standpoint,
meaning,
okay,
you're president of the United States or
governor of New Mexico,
you could sign legislation that,
um,
and,
and these are the things that are going
to happen.
It's going to be easier and easier to
vote.
And that's what should be the case,
which should be the case if the system
isn't totally rick.
Cause the problem is people like
Hillary,
um,
the people that are long time
established,
when people that had been a part of
politics forever,
the last thing they want to do is turn
over the reins to the Internet because
she's had what,
how much they send.
They say they were spending spending
over a million dollars just to combat
online trolls just to go on reddit and
forums and correct people.
Yes,
and I would,
I would be surprised if the number was
that low.
I would be surprised too.
Yeah.
I think they're probably being pretty
conservative about that,
but the idea is that the internet
doesn't like the establishment.
They know that there's a real problem
with the system,
the system in place as is and the
Internet.
When I say the Internet of the broad
stroke that you're painting is obviously
young people who are a little bit more
aware of how screwy this whole system
that they're sort of born into is and
that the people that are in charge don't
want to change it.
They want to keep it a two party system.
They want to keep this silly white hat,
black hat,
goofy game going on forever and keep of
the power
right on this.
But this cycle for the first time in my
lifetime,
this might change.
I mean this because of just how
polarizing the two of them are.
And I think Bernie Sanders is what a lot
of people think of as the alternative
right now.
Mainstream alternative.
And he stands pretty far out there from
the other guys.
So have you seen the website I side
with.com you gotta write it down.
You've got to take,
take this political quiz I side and
everybody listening take this political
quiz.
I side with the com,
it's about 60 questions.
It's really easy.
You don't have to,
you know,
you,
you don't have to sign up on the
website,
but you take this quiz and at the end of
the quiz you get paired up with a
presidential candidate most in line with
your views.
It just makes real sense.
I think everybody should take the quiz
and whoever you line up with,
um,
I think you should knock yourself out
supporting that person.
Well,
for me,
taking the I side with quiz,
amazingly,
the next politician that I aligned with
outside of the libertarians that are
running for president is Bernie Sanders.
Um,
I aligned with Bernie Sanders 73% of
what he says.
Now when it comes to economics,
we come to a t in the road,
uh,
when it comes to the socialism versus,
um,
you know,
being an entrepreneur when it comes to
big government versus small government,
we come to that t in the road.
But,
uh,
on the issues of legalizing marijuana,
same sex marriage,
a woman's right to choose,
hey,
let's stop with these military
interventions.
This is just,
this is just crazy.
We're in line.
So,
um,
I,
I pushed this website because,
um,
it should work the other way around.
Okay.
I side with Bernie most of the time,
but oh my gosh,
the libertarian candidate,
Gary Johnson,
I side with next in line and I do
believe that,
um,
Bernie is not going to get the
nomination.
I don't think that's going to happen.
And where do all those voters go?
Where does 50% of Republicans go?
That really are at the end of the day.
And I was socially tolerant and fiscally
conservative and I think that is the
majority of Republican voters.
But,
uh,
they've been co opted by the social
conservatives that have an agenda that I
think is really a turnoff to most of
America.
And it's okay to be a social
conservative.
There's nothing wrong with being a
social conservative,
but if you,
if you equate or if you make that public
policy,
if you pass laws regarding social
conservatism,
you end up putting people in jail for
personal choices.
And we do have the highest incarceration
rate of any country in the world.
And I think that starts with the drug
war.
The word conservative is interesting
too,
when you apply it to social issues like
social conservativism cause
conservatives really wa the original
conservatives were stay out of my
business.
I'll stay out of yours.
So social conservative really wouldn't
apply to like things along the of gay
marriage
or same sex unions or anything along
those lines.
You would,
you'd say we'll leave those people
alone.
That would be the conservative approach
that government should stay out of those
people's lives.
Right.
Well,
it started out as classical liberal.
Classical liberal is being fiscally
conservative and socially liberal,
which got co-opted.
I mean that,
that used to be what a conservative was
and that got co opted.
And,
um,
like I said,
I think we're a little bit of both.
You've heard the old adage that if in
college you weren't a Democrat,
you didn't have a heart.
And if a,
as an adult,
you weren't a Republican,
you didn't have a brain.
Well,
I think we've got both.
All of us have got both of those things.
Yeah.
It's just real polarizing to have only
two choices.
Well,
and it's,
and it's so polarizing because the,
those issues,
um,
at the,
at the end of the day,
um,
why can't Democrats and Republicans come
together on some very common sense
issues that would move the country
before
ward?
Well,
decades ago,
the term libertarian was very,
very rarely used.
When was it invented?
And I think we would all agree that it's
at least something discussed today.
So 71 is when the libertarian party was
established.
And I remember in [inaudible] 71 and,
uh,
I graduated from high school in
[inaudible] 71 and I remember getting a
book that said,
here's what it is to be a libertarian.
And it was a very short read,
uh,
read the book.
And,
uh,
clearly I was a libertarian.
I've identified myself as a libertarian
since now have I registered as a
libertarian?
Um,
no,
but back to the book or read the book,
it said pass the book on as I had had it
passed on to me and for me,
uh,
I've identified myself as such since I
think it's very typical that,
um,
well in New Mexico,
I remember in the eighties,
early eighties,
there was a congressional debate,
Republican,
Democrat and the Libertarian and the
discussion in the bar afterwards when
something like this who won the debate,
well,
there's just this overall consensus was
the libertarian won the debate,
but who are we going to vote for?
Because the libertarian never wins,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
That's the real rub,
right?
The,
throwing your vote away,
throwing your vote away and how can you,
uh,
I mean,
throwing your vote away is voting for
somebody that you don't believe in.
That's throwing your vote away.
You vote for somebody you believe in and
that's how you change the system.
Yeah.
It's really become a stigma that has to
somehow or another be removed publicly.
And um,
I just keep thinking that with each one
of these fiasco elections,
that this idea of a third party will
slowly but surely emerge and it seems to
be gaining ground
and it could be this cycle,
but so far,
no,
I mean it hasn't had what happened.
Yeah,
well it's the TV,
it's the TV thing,
man.
I those
debates,
they're so bizarre.
It's such a strange show.
Or one person says something and the
other person standing there shaking
their head and not agreeing and then
they enter jacked or they go over their
time and the other person jumps in.
It's one of the worst ways ever to get
your point across and,
but it,
I agree,
but if you're not in those debates,
you,
you were a non entity.
You have no chance.
I mean that's a,
that's a,
you know,
a seal of approval if you will.
It's a seal of credibility that you're
on the stage in the first place.
And if you're not on the stage,
you don't have a chance.
So a lot is riding on this Bruce Fein
lawsuit,
you believe?
No,
I'm actually,
what everything is riding on for me is
being in the polls.
If I am in the national polls,
I'm back to the Mickey analogy,
but Mickey's not on the ballot in all 50
states.
So the justification of having me in the
polls is it then I am on the ballot in
all 50 states.
And I really do think that I represent
the majority of Americans.
I'm offering up proof of that with this
ice side website.
People say to me,
why should I vote for you?
Well,
how about about getting online and
seeing where you're,
where you are at philosophically with
those people running for president.
I mean,
don't you owe it to yourself to find
out,
um,
who lines up with what it is that you
believe in?
That's a rational approach.
It's a very rational approach and people
owe it to themselves.
It's just fascinating that we look,
nobody really knew who Bernie Sanders
was until this election.
It wasn't something that was in the
public eye.
I mean,
if you knew about him,
he knew of him as a senator,
but no one knew a lot about him until
this cycle.
Yup.
And then when you,
when you go down the litany of his
issues,
like I say,
I,
I agree with the guy three quarters of
what he has to say,
but what I'm saying to the exit,
to the point of a economics,
that's,
that's the real proof that this is a
locked up system.
Because if you were in those debates
with all those people,
and during the same time,
most likely a lot of people would be
looking at you and go,
you know,
this Gary Johnson guy makes a lot of
sense.
And what you point out is,
is absolutely correct in that every
single republican on stage was a social
conservative.
And when it comes to the Democrats,
um,
look,
well both parties are well intentioned,
but when it comes to Democrats,
look,
they do grow government.
And I really believe that a bigger
government,
although it's well intentioned,
at the end of the day,
it takes tax money out of my pocket that
I could be spending on my life as
opposed to the government spending that
money.
Ideally you'd,
you know,
you'd,
you'd take your money and you'd be able
to donate it to a,
just exactly where,
where you wanted that money to be spent
ideally.
And I realized that that's not practical
at all,
but that's a really good point that the
fact that the larger the government
gets,
the more money it cost to keep that
going.
So the idea that it's going to do
better,
who's going to do more,
there's more government is more people,
there's more programs,
but they cost more money and then then
it just,
it becomes a point of diminishing
returns.
And at the end of the day,
statistically it doesn't help.
Um,
and,
and that isn't to say,
you know,
I'm in the camp that believes that there
are those people that are truly in need,
but I think we've gone way over the line
when it comes to people in need.
And at the end of the day,
if we continue the growth of government
and taxation,
uh,
at the end and printing money,
at the end of the day,
we're going to suffer from horrible
inflation at some point.
This is my belief.
Do we have a fighting chance against
what,
what is the worst,
most insidious tax of all,
which is inflation,
which erodes the,
you know,
you're,
you're buying capacity for the money
that you earn.
There's nothing worse than inflation,
but that's what we're looking at if we
don't actually just get some common
sense a at the helm.
Now when you say,
um,
those in need,
like particularly or specifically what,
what programs are,
what's in place right now that you don't
agree with?
Don't agree with.
Yes.
I don't know.
Is there's anything that I really don't
agree with.
It's just within the context of those
programs,
you have lines drawn for eligibility.
Should there be cell phones?
And I just use this as an example.
Should those people on welfare have cell
phones?
While the argument is,
is that uh,
without a cell phone,
you can't be connected to a job well,
is it,
does it really mean a job?
And I,
I point that out just as a,
this was a line drawn that this is now
a,
um,
uh,
a benefit of being on welfare.
A benefit of being on welfare is that
you get a cell phone of benefit of
welfare is,
is that yeah,
you get a cell phone.
So there's an allotment or an allowance
for cell phone usage or something like
the federal government spends multi
billions of dollars a year on cell
phones for those on welfare.
Hmm.
No,
I,
I just point that out as,
gee,
is that really,
is that really a function of government
and a,
wouldn't people be connected?
Uh,
the notion that if you can work,
you should work.
The notion that if,
let's say the government is giving you
$100,
these are very theoretical figures,
but let's just say the government's
giving them $100 a month and,
and you can't work.
If you work,
you're going to lose the hundred dollars
a month.
What about the notion of if you work,
the government will give you 75 bucks
and you can make a hundred bucks.
So at the end of the day you're working
and you make $175.
Um,
it doesn't that make sense.
Little less money from the government
incentivizing you to actually go out and
get a job.
It is as simple as what I'm talking
about having done the exact same thing
in New Mexico.
Um,
the supreme court ruled that what I did
administratively was unconstitutional
and,
and what did,
what was the exact ruling?
Like what did you do?
Well,
what we did is just exactly what I just
now said is,
okay,
so the government is giving you $100 a
month.
How about the notion that if few there
that there's a requirement that if you
can work,
you will work.
So now you can go out and make $100
without getting penalize.
We,
so you were,
but without getting penalize,
you make $100 and instead of the
government paying use $100 a month,
the government pays you $75 a month.
At the end of the day you've got a job
and now you're getting $175 and I'm
making sense here.
Yes.
Yeah.
So that's what we implemented.
All the help wanted signs in the state
went down because everybody had to go
out and get a job.
Now the legislature sued me immediately
on the basis that what I was doing was
unconstitutional,
that what I was doing needed to be
passed by the legislature,
that it couldn't be an executive order.
And after six weeks of implementing this
program,
uh,
the Supreme Court in New Mexico ruled
that what I had done was
unconstitutional.
I'm not,
I'm not here to debate that,
but you know,
we kind of proved that what I was saying
was correct.
They never did a back it up with
legislation.
They could have overridden the courts by
just caudifying what we did in
legislation.
Uh,
but they never did that.
So what you're saying is what you did
was effective,
but they just ruled it unconstitutional
and they never changed any of the rules.
Exactly.
Is that frustrating for,
you know,
I mean it's a,
it's the three branches of government.
I am very,
I'm very reality based.
Um,
you know,
this is,
this is the power that the executive
has,
the power power of the executives.
The executive gets to run government now
within the bounds of a legislation.
You know,
it is three branches of government.
And I,
I respect that and I understand it.
Um,
it's just,
it is the nature of the beast,
but you should,
that shouldn't,
that should never dissuade you as an
executive from doing what you think is
right.
Uh,
and,
um,
in many cases,
like I say,
that's where the court step in and
that's where the legislature will step
in.
It should have been legislated.
So if,
if it was effective and it was proven to
be effective.
Yeah.
Well w all the help wanted signs in the
state went down for six weeks and then
immediately on this ruling,
all the help wanted,
signs went back up.
But I mean,
realistically though with a real actual
numbers of like unemployment being down
and you could show it and bring it to
them.
Well,
if you did,
what was the argument against what you
did well that,
uh,
that they did not that what I did needed
to be legislated as opposed to executive
action,
but once it was proven to be effective,
what would you would think that that
would be?
So I was a Republican governor in New
Mexico,
two to one democrat.
Uh,
one of the big surprises I've had a
having served as governors,
I,
oh,
really naive Lee thought at the end of
the day,
Democrats and Republicans would come
together over issues that were right,
meaning do the right thing as opposed to
lining up politically.
So in this case,
um,
they lined up politically and um,
and,
and never pass the legislation that,
and six weeks was not,
I mean,
I,
I say anecdotally,
all the help wanted,
signs went down.
They did go down,
but really not enough time to garner the
statistics that could have made that in
fact a national program emulated by
other states because we would have shown
success doing it.
Here's one for you,
Joe.
So,
so welfare in New Mexico,
um,
I had a health insurance policy as
governor of New Mexico.
Okay.
I mean,
this is given to me.
This is,
this is a perk.
Being governor,
I have a health insurance policy covers
me and my family is governor of New
Mexico.
We took all the welfare recipients in
the state and uh,
which were a quarter of a million and,
um,
200,000 people.
And did the math,
gee,
what if we gave all of them my health
insurance policy as opposed to just
paying the bills when it came to
welfare?
Get it.
I mean,
everybody on welfare would receive my
insurance policy as governor of New
Mexico.
Would we really save 20%?
Uh,
yes,
we did that.
We did that.
And that's what happened.
And as comedy saved 20%.
Yeah.
And Save 20%.
Um,
and to this day that is still,
that is still in place.
That was moving from a fee for service.
Meaning if you were on welfare and you
went to the hospital or you went to the
emergency room,
uh,
Bill was sent to the State Medicaid and
the state paid that bill.
Three quarters of that bill got picked
up by the federal government and one
quarter of it gets picked up by the
state,
but that's a medicaid.
Um,
and by switching to a,
an insurance model or a managed care
model,
um,
we save 20% on the whole bill.
I mean,
it's just common sense,
uh,
to the Max.
I mean just really flabbergasting
now when you look at things like
obamacare and the criticism of obamacare
and you look at what you were trying to
implement in your own state,
wha what do you think could have been
done differently?
Well,
um,
I think that a welfare,
uh,
and uh,
medicare,
so healthcare for those over 65,
I think the federal government needs to
devolve both of these services to the
states.
Now,
currently of course,
um,
healthcare for those over 65 is
completely federal.
But in my heart of hearts,
if the government would have
blocked granted,
New Mexico,
a fixed amount of money,
uh,
just kept,
by the way,
this is just runaway expenditure.
This is the worst runaway expenditures
in federal government today is Medicaid
and Medicare.
But if they would have just kept it or
the historical increased being 7%,
if they'd had just given a couple of
percent increase to the state of New
Mexico as opposed to let's say 7% and
said New Mexico,
Governor Johnson,
you are in charge of healthcare delivery
to those that are poor,
uh,
welfare and those,
health care to those that are over 65 in
my heart of hearts,
I believe that I could have delivered
that are seen over the administration of
the delivery of that healthcare.
So if you did,
if the federal government did that,
and that's the only way to reform
Medicaid and Medicare is devolve it to
the states,
50 laboratories of innovation,
best practice,
there would be some fabulous success
that would get emulated.
There'd be horrible failure that would
get avoided.
But as opposed to one size fits all the
federal government,
we'd actually,
we'd actually come up with solutions on
how to cap and,
and how to,
uh,
main or contain the costs within,
within the system talking about Obama
care.
Um,
what we really need when it comes to
healthcare is just free market solutions
to healthcare.
And by in healthcare is as far removed
from free market right now as it
possibly can be in a free market system
for healthcare,
we would have,
we would not have health insurance to
cover ourselves for ongoing medical
need.
We would have health insurance to cover
ourselves for catastrophic injury and
illness.
And we would pay as you go in his
system,
that would probably cost about one fifth
of what it currently costs.
We would have gallbladders are us,
we'd have gallbladder surgery for
thousands of dollars as opposed to tens
of thousands of dollars.
We'd have stitches are us,
we'd have x-ray's Aros,
we'd have the radiologist's,
next two s x rays are us to read those
x-rays.
Um,
and at the end of the day we would pay
out of pocket for those services and
they would be a fifth of what they
currently are.
So in a sense,
what you're saying is that right now the
medical health care is kind of being
subsidized by the government?
Well right now it's almost like an
unrealistic amount of money is being
spent on it.
Is that what you're saying?
Well,
right now health insurance would be like
having grocery and insurance.
Hey,
you got grocery insurance,
a I go to the,
uh,
I go to the supermarket and there's no
prices on any of the shelves cause I got
grocery insurance.
It doesn't matter what anything costs.
Am I going to buy a hamburger?
Well,
why you,
why should I buy hamburger when I have
grocery insurance and I can buy a,
right.
But in the one of that logic,
like what does anyone doing differently
because they have health insurance.
It's not like they're getting extra
treatments.
Well,
so in the,
well right now,
um,
chief justice Roberts when he said that,
that uh,
obamacare was attacks on people.
My personal insurance premiums have
quadrupled and I have not been to see a
doctor in three years.
I mean,
I,
so it's a tax for me.
I'm subsidizing those that aren't
healthy.
Um,
I wish I didn't have to have insurance
to cover myself for ongoing medical
need.
Look,
we go into the hospital right now.
There's no advertised pricing.
You have no idea what you're going to
pay.
There is no statistics on,
on the wall that say,
Hey,
if you're here for gallbladder surgery,
you can expect a 99% outcome.
There's none of that.
If you had a free market approach to
healthcare,
you would have all of that.
You'd have advertised pricing and you
would have a,
um,
outcomes based on,
on,
uh,
on prior,
patients that had gone in.
But there is an issue with people that
do have injuries,
whether it's a catastrophic injury,
whether it's some sort of a disease that
comes up where the amount of money that
they're going to have to spend for
healthcare can be catastrophic and
astronomical.
And that's,
I started out by saying we would not
have insurance to cover ourselves for
ongoing need,
but we would have insurance to cover
ourselves for catastrophic injury and
illness.
But how do you define what's
catastrophic and what's not?
Like if you get cancer and dollar
amount,
dollar amount.
Yeah.
What about the health consequences of
avoiding or not avoiding treatment?
Because there's going to be a lot of
people that don't have the money and are
going to just deal with certain issues
like a surgery perhaps that you need and
you're just going to avoid it.
Knee surgery,
things along those lines,
like I said,
considered catastrophic.
Well,
yes,
absolutely.
Beyond a certain dollar amount.
I mean these,
these are the things that you could
choose in a,
in a genuine free market approach to
health care.
What about like a meniscus scope,
like a meniscus scope?
Meniscus tears can be incredibly painful
if you,
you know,
get scoped a few thousand dollars,
would that be considered catastrophic?
It's not really catastrophic engine.
Well today it's a few thousand dollars
because it's one of those no advertise
pricing for meniscus tear.
And having had several meniscus tears
myself,
uh,
if you had a free market approach to
healthcare,
you would have meniscus.
Tears are us,
we specialize in meniscus tears,
here are our outcomes.
And uh,
you can come in and get a meniscus tear
surgery for what would end up to be
hundreds of dollars as opposed to
thousands of.
So sort of like the way they do like
lasik eye surgery today.
Great example.
Advertise pricing,
cosmetic surgery,
uh,
you know,
dentistry now,
I mean you're starting to see advertised
pricing and as opposed to the hundred
dollar ass than that,
when you go into the hospital,
when you read the fine print,
but of course you're not paying for it
so you don't care.
So in that sense,
you would essentially go to a hospital,
they would diagnose
you,
they would tell you,
here's the issue.
You have to get a gallbladder and then
you'd go to gallbladders are us.
Well or just from the very beginning,
right?
What's wrong?
What's wrong with me?
I mean you,
you'd man with the Internet today and
there could be so much innovation.
Why,
why do we even,
and I'm,
I am talking about a utopia,
if you will,
and I don't want to say utopia.
This is very doable.
This is something that a government
could really lay the groundwork for a,
but that it's like I say,
as far removed from what I'm talking
about,
fiscally conservative.
When you say fiscally conservative,
when you talk about issues like welfare
and things along those lines,
people get a sense,
a lot of people do,
um,
that you are perhaps callous or uncaring
about poor people.
That that's the route.
I'm not saying
no,
but that is,
but in our own lives,
look its best pr in our own lives as
best product.
It's best service at the lowest price.
That's,
that's how we,
that's how we analyze things.
We don't give away our own money.
Why?
Why should government be giving?
Why shouldn't government have the same
credo?
Well,
what I was going to get at was what
you're saying as far as like the 50
states.
That is probably one of the most
interesting thing about having 50 states
is that you can have 50 different
experiments and you have 50 different,
and we're seeing that of course with
legalized marijuana in Colorado bringing
in more tax revenue than alcohol for the
first time ever.
I mean this is a huge thing that's
happening right now in Colorado and
experiment in government.
And the federal government tried to
block it at one point and they were very
concerned with it,
but now they're letting it go and it's
proving to be incredibly financially
beneficial to that state.
Now you're seeing Seattle or Washington
state,
Washington,
DC,
other states are starting to join in and
it's going probably go nationwide within
the next decade or so.
Yeah.
This is a perfect example,
right,
of states coming up with an experiment,
the experiment proven to be fiscally
effective and then moving forward with
it
and Colorado probably have,
has done the best job when it comes to
the recreational states.
Washington state has done the worst job.
Uh,
meaning that the taxes are so high in
Washington state,
uh,
that the black market is alive and well.
How hard is the taxes in Washington
state to Colorado's 39% in Washington
state?
Well,
a Washington state,
they'll have an whatever the rate is
though it applies four times.
It,
it applies to growing,
it applies to processing.
It applies to every single.
So that at one point,
two summers ago,
right after Washington state implemented
it and that a pot went on sale at one
point,
marijuana in,
uh,
in Washington state was selling for 26
grand a pound.
What?
$65 a gram.
That's insane.
Well,
for
what you had,
you had people lined up around,
not around the block.
People who'd never used marijuana
before.
Well everybody that had been using
marijuana continued to get it on the
black market because that was and is
insane.
Well,
and these are the regulations as far as
personal growing.
Yeah.
In some states.
But,
uh,
to me that's also a common sense.
I'm,
I'm caveat to this legislation is they
need to allow for home grow this the
same way you get your groceries.
I mean,
it really should be no different if you
want to grow your own tomatoes.
Exactly.
And grow your own standards.
And,
and I've always said that this,
you know,
we always talk about,
or everybody is talking about the tax
revenue,
which is,
which is correct.
It's significant,
but more significant than the tax
revenue is the savings in law
enforcement.
The courts.
And the prisons.
We have the highest incarceration rate
of any country in the world and the
reason behind that is that the war on
drugs,
we've got tens of millions of convicted
felons in this country that,
but for our dog drug laws would
otherwise be tax paying law abiding
citizens and the drug war.
That is a,
that's a huge factor.
That's a huge factor in distrust and law
enforcement.
It's a huge factor in frustration with
the system feeling disenfranchised with
the the very system that's supposed to
be governing us.
You just feel like it's your enemy.
Black lives matter.
At the heart of that is the drug war.
That's the heart of that.
At the heart of the militarization of
our police forces is breaking down doors
in the name of confiscating drugs and a
lot of that has been recently revealed
with started off during the Nixon
administration as just trying to control
the civil rights movement and trying to
control the antiwar movement the way
they did it.
They recognize that these people using
marijuana,
let's go after them.
Let's make it a big deal.
Well,
one of those political boogeyman that a
as a politician elect me and I will save
you from the ills of marijuana right
now.
Another one of those political boogeyman
is immigration and it's a political
boogeyman look.
Immigration is really a good thing.
They're not taking jobs that US citizens
want and it's not an issue of lower pay
unless it's an issue of language and
they're the first ones that recognize
that.
And building a wall across the border is
just crazy.
What can be done at this point?
Like if someone became a president,
what could be done to stop this influx
of private prisons,
this,
this prison industrial complex that we
were finding ourselves in this horrible
quagmire with?
Well,
so don't,
don't mistake.
Look,
it's not just private prisons.
It's public prisons.
That number one opposition to legalizing
pot in California was the public prison
union.
So yeah.
You know it's guards union,
correct?
Yes.
It's keep jobs.
They want to keep jobs.
We've got 2.3 million people bars.
Um,
that's terrifying.
That's terrifying.
That guards would want to keep jobs so
that they would want more people locked
up for things that no one agrees with.
That's really scary.
I'll,
I'll just,
I'll just say it's a bad rap for private
prisons as opposed to just prisons,
period.
There's a,
there's a big,
I said,
as governor of New Mexico,
um,
and I privatized half the state prisons
in New Mexico,
apples to apples,
oranges to oranges.
The private prisons offered up the same
goods and services for two thirds.
The price and all that because they're
not the government because they can do
it for less money,
just like every aspect of life.
Private to can do it better than public.
Every aspect of life isn't the issue
though with something like a private
prison.
So this is a private corporation that
profits from incarcerating people,
amazing that they,
that they can even profit and offer.
So in New Mexico,
if I may,
when I took office,
there were 800 prisoners housed out of
state.
There had been massive prison riots in
New Mexico so that the federal courts
were in charge of the prisons in New
Mexico is called the Duran consent
decree.
The legislature refused to appropriate
money to build new prisons.
It was a huge problem that we had.
So the private prison camp,
private prisons,
Wac,
and Hud in particular came in and said,
and the federal courts were running the
prisons in New Mexico.
So if what I'm about to tell you,
if you think that we were going to get
away with any less goods or services
being delivered to the prison industry
guests,
again,
federal courts are running the prisons
in New Mexico on an apples to apples,
oranges to oranges basis.
Instead of 100 bucks a day,
they offered it up for 66 bucks a day,
two thirds,
the cost.
If that isn't good government,
I don't know what is.
And in New Mexico I constantly said if
we would adopt rational drug laws,
if we could let people out of prison,
it will be a lot easier to empty the
private prisons than it will be the
public prisons.
Well,
excuse my ignorance on this,
I'm not sure if I'm right,
but I would imagine that something like
a private prison,
which is a company and it's a company
that companies 10 to aspire towards
growth,
and when you have a private prison that
profits off of people being in jail,
you would attend to think that they
would try to maximize their potential
for growth or versus the government,
right?
It's logical.
But May,
maybe the component in here that you're
missing is,
is as opposed to growth.
Just think of it as,
as stepping in and taking over the
services that are currently being
provided for a lot less money,
meaning taking over all the prisons and
that would be their growth.
So all presents.
Exactly.
And,
and assuming,
and this is,
this is my experience now,
and don't get me wrong.
I mean there's,
it's,
there's just logic
behind,
gee,
if you're a private prison,
then you're in it for the money.
Right?
That's logical.
But it's,
in my experience,
it's completely removed from the
reality.
But just in your experience in New
Mexico,
in New Mexico,
fairly small state,
well not small,
but it doesn't have a large population.
Right.
And,
and excuse me,
have there been,
um,
you know,
a private prisons that lobby for more
prisoners?
I'm not going to say that that hasn't
happened.
Didn't happen.
Did Not happen in New Mexico,
but just don't discount that,
that's not happening on the public side
also
of course.
Right,
exactly what you're talking about with
the unions,
the guard unions,
they are trying to somehow another
maximize their potential and maximize
their growth
and this mandatory sentencing,
which really starts,
uh,
with the drug laws that we have.
I mean,
this is the reason why we have this high
incarceration rate.
Yeah.
That we have.
How is it legal that these prison unions
actually do that?
Well,
what's that squeak?
Is that you?
Yes,
it is.
Let's try to figure out what it was.
Yeah,
no legal though.
That,
how is it legal?
Guardians can try to change laws and
which where it's so transparent.
It's not like they're trying to lock bad
people up because they're really
concerned about the safety of the
public.
They're worried about their jobs.
So they want to incarcerate people that
may or may not be incarcerated without
their,
their input.
Joe,
you,
you nailed it.
Just extend that to other things that we
see also.
For example,
you see ads on television that say,
um,
increase the expenditures for education
that's being paid for from a tax
dollars,
from mud,
from teachers,
right?
That will advertise for that.
We see advertisements all the time from
public institutions that in essence
we're paying for,
for increased funding all the time.
Every time we turn around.
How is that fair?
How is that legal?
Isn't that a manipulation of our brains?
Uh,
you know,
in a,
in a way that,
uh,
many times just belies the underlying
logic that no,
they shouldn't get more money,
they should get more efficient.
Well,
the issue though is this is very
different because you're talking about
people lobbying to try to lock up other
human beings for their own profit.
Well,
um,
like I say,
your logical,
what you're saying is logical.
It's,
it's got a perfect logic,
kind of it's evil.
I mean,
if you really think about it,
if they,
if there's a brewpub,
people of the massive amount of the
general public doesn't believe that
people should be in jail for a lot of
the drug crimes are in jail for,
especially marijuana.
If you look at the statistics,
you look at the amount of money that's
being spent on it.
Most people would say,
this is fucking crazy.
We've got to stop this.
Right?
I'd say I've been more vocal about this
than anybody in an elected office.
So when prison unions lobby contrary to
prison unions,
yeah,
now you're public or either side of it,
lobbies
four,
four more lock.
Contrary to public opinion,
there should be an investigation and it
should be criminal.
I mean,
what you're doing is you're lobbying to
try to go against the,
the wishes of the general public to put
people in jail,
and there's only one reason it's to
maximize profit.
You're not talking about any threat to
the public.
You're not talking about any healthcare
threat.
You're not talking about any tax burden
from people out there smoking marijuana
was selling marijuana.
What you're talking about is maximizing
your profit as a guard.
That should be illegal
spot on.
Uh,
I would just ask everybody listening to
just apply that same argument to a whole
lot of other things that we're exposed
to when it comes to.
So let's talk about if you,
if you apply that same argument to
education,
what is it,
what's your take on that?
Well fit back to 50 laboratories of
innovation and best practice.
The federal government should not be
involved in education at all.
And very quickly,
federal government gives each state 11
cents out of every school dollar that
every state spends,
but it comes with 15 cents where the
strings attached.
The federal government says,
here,
we're going to give you 11 cents and you
have to do a,
b,
c,
and d to get the 11 cents.
What are those?
What are those steps they have to do?
Well,
one of those steps is now providing
transgender bathrooms.
Um,
as the Obama administration has now
stated,
if you don't,
if you,
well this is,
this is reality.
Now if you,
if you don't provide these bathrooms,
you're not going to get your 11 cents.
So do they have to have a third
bathroom?
Was that the,
it was that this well make,
make accommodation.
Now this perfect example is they say
that you have to do a,
b,
c and d,
Use the transgender bathroom as the,
as the latest and greatest front page.
Here's what the federal government is
requiring,
but it costs you as a state 15 cents to
deliver on getting the 11 cents.
It actually is a negative to take
federal money.
So abolishing the Federal Department of
Education,
which I think people think was
established under George Washington when
it was established under Jimmy Carter.
Um,
tell me what really has been value added
when it comes to the Federal Department
of Education since,
uh,
since the 80s.
And so when it was him,
well let's talk about that one step
because it,
is there any benefit at all to being
open minded and trying to get people to
discriminate against transgender people
last,
or is this some sort of a political hot
topic that the government has latched on
to try to get people to think that
they're progressive and they're moving
towards the right direction?
Because I mean,
how many people are we,
well,
it's the latter.
It's,
it,
it's been
a nonissue.
It's not been an issue our entire lives
for certain individuals in certain
environments
and they've been accommodating
themselves this whole time throughout,
throughout our lifetimes.
Um,
there should be,
I think there's absolute a heightened
awareness.
But,
um,
look,
this is,
this is overkill.
This should,
this should be an issue that,
uh,
Los Angeles deals with the state of
California deal.
Correct me if I'm wrong,
cause we were actually discussing this
yesterday.
I believe what North Carolina has said
was that you have to use the bathroom
that corresponds to the gender on your
birth certificate.
However,
if Gary Johnson,
you decide at 50,
how old are you,
sir?
63 63 if you decide at 63 years old,
you want to be a woman that's a Bruce
Jenner did,
right?
Yeah.
If you decide you want to be a woman,
you could change your birth certificate.
Your birth certificate literally can be
changed to say that you're a woman,
then you can use the women's room.
So that's all they're requiring.
And so this up in arms is really like,
they want it commitment,
I think before you decide to go and use
the women's room,
like you literally have to just go and
get your paperwork changed.
Is that correct?
No,
no.
I no disagreement,
but I'm,
am I am a correct technically.
Yeah.
That's it.
That is what they're requiring.
Right.
But when I think of of that bullshit,
if you will,
a over an issue that has never been an
issue before.
As governor of New Mexico Joe,
I may have vetoed more legislation and
the other 49 governors in the country
combined.
Where's this coming from?
Where's it coming from?
So if I,
well,
it's,
uh,
it's discrimination against the lbgt
community.
That's the heart of all of it.
As governor of North Carolina,
if I had had been governor of North
Carolina,
I'd have vetoed that legislation.
This is much to do about nothing.
This is not an issue.
Um,
and certainly the federal government
shouldn't be stepping in and doing this
because North Carolina right now is
suffering the wrath,
if you will,
or the whole country that says,
we're going to boycott North Carolina.
We're going to have nothing to do with
North Carolina as a result of them
having passed this legislation.
But again,
what they're saying in passing this
legislation is not that complicated.
They're just saying that you have to
change your gender on your birth
certificate.
Right?
I mean,
it may be discriminatory at heart,
but when you look at the actual
paperwork,
like what's required in order to use the
women's room,
like it's not saying that you have to
have an x,
y chromosome to use the men's room.
They're saying you have to identify as a
male on your birth certificate.
So if a woman decides to become a man of
transition to a man,
she decided she's a man at heart and she
changes that under birth certificate.
They don't do a chromosomal test on her.
So it's just a matter of a paperwork
change.
I'm not,
I'm not really sure how much less you
could require of someone to use a
different bathroom that corresponds to
the gender of their birth.
Well,
I would just,
I would just disagree that the
government taken a role here that I
agree we never had to be established.
Right.
I agree with that.
But if you do want to discourage
discriminate against discrimination
against transgender people,
how would you go about encouraging that?
Or is that just a social issue,
social issue that needs to be worked out
with people?
Well,
it's a,
it's an issue that needs to be worked
out,
uh,
municipality state wide.
But,
uh,
at the end of the day,
um,
this issue has existed our entire
lifetimes.
And have there been any reported
incidents of anything anywhere?
I'm not aware of any incidents any,
well,
I'm sure there's been something and I'm
sure some people feel maligned,
but,
uh,
I just don't know if necessarily there's
enough demand to require a law change
and what all this Hullabaloo is about,
about this law change.
When I discuss it with people and I'm,
I try to be as open minded as humanly
possible when it comes to people's
choices and what they want to do,
whether it's regarding gender or sex or
whatever you want to do.
Me Too.
I'm just,
I'm,
I'm fine with it,
but my,
my issue with this is I feel like it's a
chance for people to jump up and say
that they're outraged.
I think it's almost like a recreational
outreach thing.
Like when I heard that Bruce springsteen
was boycotting North Carolina,
all these people jumping up and like,
is that really the way to go about this?
Yeah,
I think so.
I mean that is the way to go about it.
Just stop.
So you're saying it in terms of like
government's gotten too big,
you want to stop this law?
Yeah.
The way to go about is to boycott.
The still way to go about it is boy cat.
The stage,
just like a happened in Arizona when Jan
brewer started to talk about vilifying
Mexican immigration and uh,
and conventions and the whole country
was boycotting Arizona.
And when it came to,
um,
you know,
traveling there,
I mean,
it happened right?
And,
and it,
and because of that,
uh,
you know,
the change took place.
North Carolina,
same thing.
So,
so really what's unnecessary in your
eyes?
You're a small government guy.
What's unnecessary?
Is the government getting involved at
all
at all,
at all?
In this case,
and don't get me wrong,
government has a fundamental role to
protect us against individuals,
groups,
corporations,
foreign governments that would do us
harm.
And,
uh,
I'm running for president of United
States.
Um,
I'd like to think that a,
at the end of the day,
I'm going to,
I'm going to sign on to anything that
makes things better.
Uh,
transgender law in front of me as
governor and the state of North Carolina
or president of United States.
You know,
you make that analysis.
Is this going to make things better or
at the end of the day is it just going
to add time and money to our lives and
not really do anything to plays devil's
advocate?
Is there any benefit in having it in the
news is any benefit?
Absolutely.
Right.
So people,
you'll
become more and more aware of it.
I mean,
I think whether or not you look at
Caitlyn Jenner as a,
a real issue in this country.
I think what the issue is is that people
were becoming more aware that there are
folks out there that don't necessarily
fit necessarily with our standard
idea of what gender is.
They,
they're,
they're all over the place.
There's people on the far right and the
far left just like politically.
Yup.
And a,
at the end of the day,
aren't most of us absolutely tolerant of
that?
Most of us.
Yeah.
And then people start there.
The real issue,
right?
Yeah.
The people that are intolerant of other
people's choices that don't affect you
at all.
And the intolerant folks are the ones
that are passing this legislation.
Okay.
So the intolerant ones,
the ones who are saying enough is enough
with all this transgender nonsense.
You can't use the women's room if you're
a man much to do about and nothing but
the seed.
There's some men,
it's,
it's so,
it's so confusing in some ways because
they were as outliers on both sides.
Like I have met transgender women who
without a doubt,
I would consider them a woman.
I mean,
it looks like a woman.
She talks like a woman has sensibility
is like a woman dresses like a woman.
Whatever the fuck that means.
Right?
But then on the other side,
I've seen there's this guy that
identified,
we were talking about this guy recently
identifies as a woman,
has a beard,
a has a penis,
doesn't want to have a sex change,
doesn't take hormones,
identifies as a woman.
Once it,
we use the women's room and he's been
doing it.
No,
no he hasn't.
But he wants to.
And it was one of the,
it's an outlier.
But you know,
you're dealing with,
there's all sorts of people when any
issue like this comes up,
right?
And you're going to have rational,
logical,
obvious choices.
And then you have like,
what do you do with that guy choices
and where does that decision making best
lie,
that decision making best lies in the
municipality,
um,
where that person lives.
And if it's an issue,
let's say an albuquerque and I'm the
mayor of Albuquerque,
um,
welcome to come into the boys room.
If you're welcome to come into the boys
room,
boys room can be labeled transgender and
boy's room as far as I'm concerned.
Hmm.
So the only worry there would be if they
went into the boys room,
they were discriminated against,
but then show how many people going the
males
boys room though.
See,
I think it'd be less of an issue.
This,
this is,
this is knee jerk of course.
And,
and it's,
and it's based on,
uh,
let's,
let's have,
instead of having a one size fits all,
uh,
how about let's work this out at the
absolute lowest level.
We can work it out and maybe we'll come
to some real,
you know,
a monumental,
uh,
oh,
you know,
epiphany's on how to do this.
What would possibly be the epiphany.
I think that's one of the problems with
this issue.
Yeah.
Okay.
But,
but um,
you know,
that's you and I thinking about this and
if you had a municipalities thinking
about it all across the country,
some of them would come up with
solution.
You'd be some best practices that would
emerge from this.
That would make sense for everyone.
Well,
the,
the all the only suggested than I've
ever heard.
That makes any sense at all.
Is it three bathroom rule like male,
female,
whatever.
Well,
but male,
female and go for it.
Well,
and imagine,
um,
imagine all schools in this country
having to be ref retrofitted with that
third bathroom.
I'm talking billion.
$100 billion.
I'm just guessing.
Well yeah,
it's a lot of money.
Let's just say a lot of money and the
federal government's going to give you a
11 cents for you to accomplish their 15
cents where the mandate.
Yeah,
it's,
I liked the issue.
You know why I liked the issue?
Cause it's so bizarre and there's no
answer.
I love when something has no answer.
When you just sit around going,
man,
I don't know.
Right.
Cause people will take sides and they'll
run with their side and make sure that
you think that their side is the only
solution whatsoever when there really
isn't an only solution.
Profound.
Yeah,
it's,
it's a weird one,
right?
You're back this weekend back to fiddle.
Well it's,
it's something to fiddle with.
I mean,
this is a fiddling sort of a
conversation because it's,
it's polarizing.
It's confusing.
And again,
I'm not right.
You're not right.
There's no right on this.
This is a weird thing.
Look,
the whole transgender thing is weird.
It's very rare.
I mean,
you're talking about,
is it even 1% of people that become
transgender?
I doubt it.
It's probably far less than it's 0.03%
of.
So it's,
yeah,
it's,
it's a very small amount of 3% of 1%.
Very,
very small amount.
It varies.
So a mandate,
because
Hola kids,
couple of kids out of thousands of
students.
That's kind of a cheesy way to look.
And wouldn't it be better for everyone
if we just became more open minded and
more friendly and loving and let people
do whatever the fuck they want to do.
Let,
let the,
the,
the man who identifies as a woman,
let them,
you know,
use the woman's room if he actually
looks like a woman.
But if you have a beard,
maybe we should play aside and go,
dude,
you can use the men's room.
Just your freaking people out.
You probably spent as much time or more
time than I have in Europe,
but uh,
you know what the showers are.
Um,
showers are men and women.
It's men and women.
Bathrooms.
I don't shower in Europe and some
gigantic prison,
prison showers.
You going to serve men and women
showers.
Yes.
Open showers.
These recreational facilities in
virtually every single,
uh,
a mountain community in a,
in the Alps for example,
like skiing communities,
like they have open showers.
Well,
in this case,
you know,
they've got,
they've got the,
they've got these marvelous,
um,
recreational facilities.
It seems like in every town and in those
towns,
you know you've got a swimming pool and
you got the showers and the showers are
men and women both.
Now as a person who has got,
there's no choice.
There's no choice.
I'm back to Europe now.
I mean this is a really different,
it's just this kind of a thing is not an
issue in Europe.
I'm going to imagine.
Well,
that would require a gigantic cultural
shift though.
We're very used to segregating male and
female,
but awareness.
So here it is.
We're spreading awareness that,
oh shoot.
Uh,
Europe,
they shower together.
Your wife has to shower with some dude.
Like trust me,
that's not going to fly.
Well let that go and fly.
It flies.
It flies in Europe,
a lot of stuff flies and you're right,
it doesn't fly over here.
Might not necessarily be a good thing.
You can't trust American men with
American women in a shower together.
Well,
but in Europe where you've grown up with
that your whole life,
there aren't any incidents.
We're not going to grow up with that
though.
Right?
Well,
we haven't grown up.
It's not going to change.
You're not going to,
that would be even more ridiculous to
adjust the way children growing up and
say,
listen kids,
everyone's gonna shower together.
Parents would freak out.
They'd be like,
what kind of government is this?
J Well,
Gary Johnson's a psychopath awareness,
you know,
as you were talking about earlier,
just that people be aware that there are
all sorts of different ways of doing
things.
There's also drink drinking.
I mean we can go down several
cul-de-sacs here,
but in Europe,
you know,
uh,
you can kids start drinking at the
earliest of age.
I mean like as in four or five years old
and so and so.
They know what alcohol is from a very
young age and so they don't have near
the issues with alcohol abuse.
They ended up getting their driver's
licenses at 21 but they can drink,
you know,
with the,
with the consent of their parents,
you know,
at four years old.
And so they understand the impact of
alcohol and now they drive a 21 well,
here in this country you can drive at 14
and I'm 14
in this country.
It's 15,
you get a learner's permit at 16 drivers
license.
Is that what it is?
It's close to New Mexico.
I mean it was 14 in New Mexico.
Really 13.
I had that motorcycle license at 13.
You could drive a motorcycle in New
Mexico at 13.
Now as a person
governance state.
Um,
and you look at the,
what happens when someone gets an
office,
when,
when Obama gets an office,
he promises all these things,
gets an office,
changes almost everything.
Um,
what are the hurdles,
I mean,
what are the differences between the
hurdles of someone who governs a state
versus someone who governs the United
States?
And how much more difficult is it to
change things?
It seems like the United States is like,
like a gigantic ship that takes so much
effort to shift even slightly that these
presidents get out of office eight years
later exhausted looking like they've
aged 50 years and very little gets done.
Well,
uh,
I think there is a silver bullet to the
system and I,
I hope I'm tying into what you're
saying,
but I do think there's a silver bullet
to the system and that would be term
limits.
Um,
I think that for the most part of
politicians,
once they get an office,
the main concern is to stay in off.
Right.
And if you had term limits,
I think that people would do the right
thing as opposed to whatever it takes to
get to me for Congress and for the
Senate Congress,
Senate shipping point,
even anywhere,
right.
Well,
supreme court's a,
another topic,
but uh,
but certainly elected office agreed that
we have it for the president one have it
for all elected offices.
I think I'm the best example of term
limits.
I really enjoyed the job.
I had the opportunity to serve for two
terms.
So I,
in my estimation,
I pressed the limits term one,
but not to the point where I wasn't
going to get reelected.
And then when I get reelected,
I started off by saying,
you know,
let's examine the drug war in this
country.
I started off by saying that the
marijuana should be legalized taking on
what I thought at the time was,
and it still remains.
So as one of those really fixable things
in our lives,
um,
that would make the world a better
place.
Um,
but because of term limits,
um,
I was emboldened because I,
man,
I was getting out of office and there
was no return.
Right.
Um,
what are your thoughts on all the other
recreational drugs?
Not just marijuana,
but the more controversial ones,
like maybe cocaine or Psilocybin,
lsd,
things along those lines.
So when I was governor of New Mexico,
I had a,
um,
uh,
I went to Portland,
Oregon and judges in Portland,
Oregon.
There were judges that wanted to meet
with me in Portland.
And so I went to meet with these judges
and I didn't know what the,
what it was going to be about,
but it was six judges,
Portland,
Oregon State district judges.
I'm sure I'm getting the wrong label.
But what they said was,
was,
hey,
governor Johnson,
we just,
we're here to tell you,
we completely agree with everything it
is that you're saying,
but we would like to share with you some
stories here that,
um,
maybe you can pass on to others that
will allow others to better understand
the drug issue.
They said that the really horrible drug
out there as methamphetamine,
that people that use methamphetamine,
I'm really have their behavior altered
and not in a good way.
So it's really the Boogie drug out
there.
They said,
um,
methamphetamine is the best example that
we can think of of a prohibition drug.
It exists because it's cheap and it's
easy to make.
And what they said was,
was that,
hey,
we're not suggesting the following,
but if cocaine were legal,
these people would be using cocaine
instead of methamphetamine without the
negative behavioral consequence.
And that's true.
But if the government were to tell the
truth when it comes to cocaine,
cocaine puts holes in your heart.
People that use cocaine their entire
lives are stereotypically Whitney
Houston,
the die before they're 50 because they
die of a heart attack from using
cocaine.
Now will there still be people that will
use cocaine knowing that they might die
of a heart attack?
Um,
I think,
I think there'd be less cocaine use if
people actually knew the truth and could
trust government when it comes to the
truth,
I just maintain that 90% of the drug
problem is prohibition,
unrelated,
not use related.
And that is not to discount the with use
and abuse,
but that should be the focus.
When you have 8,000 deaths a year in
this country,
8,000,
which is staggeringly low due to cocaine
and heroin overdose.
And people will immediately say,
well yeah,
the number is so low because it's
illegal.
No.
Um,
you can argue that if it were legal,
if quality quantity was known,
uh,
it's arguable that those desks would
significantly decrease.
Although there will always be people
that will commit suicide.
Always
be people that will push the limits.
Yes,
you're,
you're always going to have people that
abuse everything.
Everything,
everything.
Everything.
I mean we're,
we're living in a culture that has
alcohol available at every block all
over the world.
I mean,
everywhere you go,
there's a restaurant or a bar or
somewhere that you can buy enough
alcohol to drink yourself to death.
It's readily available.
Yet when you consider the amount of
people that actually drink alcohol,
the,
the low number of deaths is pretty
incredible.
And it's because we're aware of the
effects of alcohol and it's pretty,
when you get a bottle of Jack Daniel's,
it is pretty consistent.
Well,
uh,
but there are 100,000 deaths a year that
are contributed,
uh,
that,
get contributed to alcohol consumption.
And I'm not talking about drinking and
driving or,
or violence committed under the alcohol
abuse,
alcohol,
alcohol abuse.
Statistically,
no one dies
from marijuana.
So that was what I was going to get to
was that when you look at what's
happening in Colorado,
one of the more interesting things is
the lesson of violent crime and drunk
driving.
Those are two effects that have dropped
pretty drastically,
noticeably,
statistically because of the
legalization of marijuana that you would
reduce because of the legalization of a
less harmful,
more peaceful drug.
You'd reduce the effects of uh,
what's right now a readily available and
incredibly prevalent drug.
I have always maintained that legalizing
marijuana will make for a better planet
on the medicinal side of marijuana.
Um,
marijuana products directly compete with
legal prescription drugs,
pain killers,
antidepressants that statistically kill
100,000 people a year.
No,
no documented death due to marijuana on
the recreational side.
I've always maintained that legalizing
marijuana will lead to less overall
substance abuse because people are going
to find it as such a safer alternative
than everything else that's out there.
Starting with alcohol,
the campaign to legalize marijuana in
Colorado,
uh,
was a campaign based on marijuana is
safer than alcohol.
And Joe,
as you were pointing out all the
statistics that all the naysayers were
going to go south,
I have gone have gone better.
They're less traffic incidents.
There's less overall crime in the state
of Colorado.
Colorado is vibrant and does
it have to do with marijuana?
I think that that's an ingredient,
uh,
comprised in why Colorado is so vibrant
right now.
Question,
blame,
unquestionable.
And I think a prime example of how
screwy the system gets when people lobby
against the legalization of things that
don't harm anyone is the fact that hemp
is illegal federally and that we're
trying to make it legal and trying to
make it legal statewide and in various
states and start production of hemp.
But hemp is not psychoactive.
It's crazy.
We,
we,
we can sell hemp products in this
country,
but they come from China.
My company,
we buy it or my company on it.
We buy it from Canada.
We buy hemp protein from Canada and they
can't grow it in America.
We can import it,
but we can't grow it.
CBD,
CBD oil.
Yes.
Same thing.
Not psychoactive helps pain.
Very effective for people.
It's not getting people hire,
it's not ruining lives is not doing
anything.
But there's a lot of people that are
concerned that are making money off of
the alternatives,
especially with hemp.
I mean,
that was the reason why marijuana was
made illegal in the first place.
That's the reason it was about hemp,
the conspiracy of dupont to promote
nylon as opposed to,
uh,
and,
and of course they,
Randolph hearst,
they per factories,
they made a,
they made a marijuana illegal,
but because the marijuana plant and the
hemp plant look the same,
then hence hemp was also made illegal.
I mean,
that was the,
the conspiracy.
Yeah.
Well that's a,
I mean,
that's all been proven.
So it's,
we're in a strange time that it's 2016
it's still illegal getting slowly
starting to become legal and people
starting to,
I believe in Kentucky and a few other
states,
they're allowing farmers to profit off
of this incredibly vibrant plant that's
easy to grow,
doesn't require pesticides,
has a variety of uses as a textile,
as a commodity for food,
a full amino acid profile.
It makes amazing clothes and making this
jacket,
this is made out of hemp.
I mean,
if it's,
if,
if the marijuana plant were discovered
today in the Amazon,
it would be hailed as the greatest
discovery of humankind in 1999.
Good News.
Bad News here.
In 1999 I was the highest elected
official in the United States to call
for the legalization of marijuana in
2016 bad news,
I'm still the highest elected official
in the United States to call for the
legalization of marijuana.
Although Bernie Sanders apparently
rolled out of bed,
hit his head,
and now he's come to that same epiphany.
Wonderful.
I'm glad.
But in 1999 rolled out of bed and hit
his head aw,
well that he came to this epiphany at
this point in his life.
He's never said it before.
Uh,
no.
Not until he's been running for a,
for Senate.
So you think it's like one of those,
Lick your finger,
put it up in the air,
check where the breeze is going.
I'm glad that he's joined the big crowd,
but,
but in 1999,
30% of Americans supported legalizing
marijuana in 2016,
60% of Americans now are supporting the
legalization of marijuana and not one
politician outside of Bernie Sanders in
office.
Um,
is,
and when I say elected official at the
congressional,
senatorial or gubernatorial level,
not one politician in that group outside
of Bernie Sanders,
myself have a spouse legalizing
marijuana.
I think what a disconnect.
What an incredible disconnect between
what people think and our elected
officials.
It's,
it's also because when people take a
stand on something that's controversial,
it's,
it's risky and politics are about
minimizing risk.
It's about getting people to like you as
much as possible,
going down the middle as much as
possible term limits,
term limits.
I want to stay in office more than I
want to do the right thing.
Do you think that ultimately the idea of
having one individual that's the
figurehead of an entire nation is
archaic?
No,
no.
I,
you know,
I'm certainly is,
is our system perfect?
Uh,
no,
but is it
perhaps the best system?
So if we woke up to today and there was
no government at all,
would you think that we would possibly
create one guy that runs the whole
thing?
We would,
we would agree that that would be the
best way to run things.
Um,
I have a theory that the best way to run
things would be that,
uh,
every 16 years we would have a
benevolent dictator takeover for two
years.
So what would happen,
and those are the days,
the other 14 years,
well,
the other six,
16 years you'd have elected officials
and then for two years you'd have a
benevolent dictator step in and right.
All the wrongs that,
but of course the problem is,
is well then how do you,
how not sizeable someone could fake
being benevolent,
trying to be funny here,
but trying to bring out a point that,
that actually,
that if you could have that benevolent
dictator step in and right the wrongs
that elect,
we don't live in a democracy in this
country.
It's not a democracy.
We live in a constitutional republic.
We are a republic,
were governed by laws.
The laws are the constitution.
We democratically elect our
representatives.
But in a democracy,
the demise of every democracy is,
is that,
uh,
at some point in a democracy,
people vote themselves a raise and it
becomes unaffordable.
Um,
Nazi Germany was a democracy before it
became,
before Hitler took power.
So what would be the,
I mean,
besides your 16 year to year benevolent
dictator,
thanks.
What would be the way to fix the current
system?
Like say if Gary Johnson gets an office,
what would you do?
What would be one of the first things
you did?
Well,
I,
I do think that government is too,
that it tries to
accomplish too much,
uh,
if,
if at a minimum a Gary Johnson were able
to just put a cap on spending the,
uh,
the impact of that.
When you consider,
um,
when you consider the ultimate impact of
inflation and how that's going to kick
in and how that's going to so adversely
affect our lives,
that would write a lot of wrongs because
you do have economic growth.
You tie that with the fact that you just
put a,
just,
I'm trying to,
I'm trying to put the most minimal bars
out there possible that would really
have a positive impact going forward
from a,
uh,
for my financial standpoint.
And it isn't just financial,
it is about liberty and freedom.
It's about your liberty.
It's about your freedom.
It's about you making decisions in your
own lives.
It's about the fact that the government,
that crony capitalism is alive and well,
that there are favors granted to those
that have money as opposed to a level
playing field that everybody would
actually have an equal shot at the
opportunity that,
uh,
that there currently is unavailable
because of government and the actual
protections that exist for those that do
have money as opposed to those that
don't.
So once you get into office,
how would you go about minimizing
government?
Well,
uh,
without any legislation whatsoever.
Um,
and I am speaking now having been
governor in New Mexico for eight years,
I ran all of state government.
I pointed the heads of all the agencies.
And from that standpoint,
the idea was was just to make things
better.
And what's the definition of better?
Well,
that uh,
the average person on the street would
have to spend less time and less money
dealing with government.
And by spending less time and less money
on government,
that means that you would actually be
able to pursue the things that were
important in your life.
And that is not to minimize government's
role,
which fundamentally is to protect us
against individuals,
groups,
corporations,
foreign governments that would
do us harm.
So going back to what we had discussed
earlier,
that when government gets too big,
you reach a point of diminishing
returns.
When it becomes to so swollen that it
requires so much money to stay up,
that it's just,
it doesn't,
it doesn't support itself.
You,
you,
it gets too large.
So what do you cut?
So say you get into office and you look
at the current system we have right now.
You look at all the bureaucracy and the
red tape.
What do you start to Chapo?
Well what I did in New Mexico,
and I said I would do this when I went
in New Mexico,
is that I wasn't going to fire anybody,
but let's just manage attrition.
Let's just have some common sense here.
Let's not grow it anymore.
Let's just at a minimum it's not going
to grow anymore and it will shrink
because there will be attrition.
So how about the notion of a,
as people leave,
as people,
you know,
quit retire that you just not backfill
those positions.
And as so when I left off us,
there were 1200 fewer state employees.
And when I got there,
I think it was a testament to better
government because people were doing
more,
um,
with,
with less resource.
And I think everybody saw that New
Mexico was a state that's two to one
democrat.
Um,
I made a name for myself,
pinching pennies,
being frugal,
just like we're frugal in our lives at
least.
I certainly am,
um,
difference between cheap and frugal,
but I'm pretty frugal cat.
So what do you do with something that's
very controversial and often criticized?
Like Homeland Security?
Like there was an article that came out
yesterday about homeland security going
after the using homeland security to go
after massage parlors for uh,
giving sex to people for,
you know,
handjobs yeah,
I would have never in the f in the first
place,
I would have never established the
Department of Homeland Security.
Now as president,
um,
I either get to sign or veto
legislation,
I would sign legislation that would
abolish the Department of Homeland
Security or I would merge it with the
FBI.
Just think we do have too many agencies
and when you hear about a story like
homeland security going into a massage
parlor,
I,
I just get outraged.
What causes that?
This is what I wanted to get to.
Like what,
how does that happen?
How does homeland security,
something that's set up to prevent
terrorist attacks?
How does it eventually get bastardized
and distorted to the point where they're
utilizing the legislation that was put
in place to protect people from
terrorist attacks to stop guys getting
handjobs.
It's human nature.
It's the Peter Principle.
It's when you're assigned to a job in
government,
the more important you are is the more
work that you have.
So you literally create your,
you,
you create the work that you have,
you try and expand.
You try and grow.
Well,
that's the private sector,
not the public sector,
public sector.
People that get involved in the public
sector.
They think that success is,
is growing their mandate.
I mean it's just,
that's,
it's that simple,
but someone has to approve that.
Like someone has to say,
well,
after the massage parlors,
sadly in this case,
where's the president of the United
States,
the president of United States could
step into this in a nanosecond and say,
Whoa,
stop.
But is it possible that he's not aware
of it because you're looking at it is
possible,
but so many things to be aware of.
Well,
it has governor of New Mexico.
Here's something I did as governor in
New Mexico on.
It's something I would do as president
of the United States as governor of New
Mexico.
I set up this open door after four
policy where the third Thursday of every
month I saw anyone in the state of New
Mexico starting at four o'clock in the
afternoon until 10 o'clock at the
evening in the evening on five minute
increments.
And it was amazing Joe,
the stories of people that came in and
what they had to say,
now they could come in for anything,
come in for a picture with me.
They come in to visit me with me for
five minutes.
They could come in and talk about here's
a government atrocity that's happening
to me and I'd like you to fix it.
And I always viewed it from the
standpoint of,
well,
this is one person that's come in,
but you know what?
Everybody that's dealing with this same
situation is having the same outcomes as
this person.
It was an incredibly valuable tool.
As president of the United States,
I would set up an open door after four
policy for atrocities in government for
a waste,
fraud and abuse atrocities.
So door after four but you're talking
about 300 million people,
right?
So we have an open door for five minutes
available for 300 million people in six
door.
Well this would,
this,
this would be,
there would be a criteria for it and it
would be,
um,
you,
you could,
I,
I'm,
I'm certain I could make this happen,
but yes,
I'm certain that,
I mean I think that's a great idea for a
governor.
Maybe a better idea for a mayor.
But when you get to a precedent,
is that really a way to what handles
some things?
So what is the mechanism?
I'm just saying I think I can make this
mechanism work that as a result of
having this mechanism,
I'm going to find out in a very short
amount of time that the Department of
homeland security is busting massage
parlors.
I'm gonna,
I'm gonna put,
find that out just as easily through
twitter.
Yes.
And so I'm going to be connected that
way too.
But waste,
fraud and abuse.
The Marine One helicopter,
I was more thinking in terms of the
Marine One helicopter was,
well it was a contract that went from $4
billion to $16 billion without a single
helicopter being delivered because you
had a,
you had,
um,
the military a hierarchy on a committee
that determined that a,
they wanted this helicopter to be steel
instead of aluminum.
And this was a boost of Westland.
And in a nutshell,
they come up with a completely
redesigned helicopter as opposed to the
original bid,
which was off the shelf.
Uh,
that would have been 4 billion.
Now it's 16 billion and they haven't,
uh,
they haven't flown a helicopter.
Well,
if you had a waste fraud and abuse,
um,
open door after four,
I'd,
if I'd have known about it and I
would've stepped right in the middle of
it.
But is that waste fraud or abuse or is
it just innovation and the expenses
involved and changing a design.
But the Pid,
the bid originally was for off the shelf
helicopters that they were building,
uh,
and that there was going to be bolt on
avionics.
And the first thing that this military
procurement committee said was,
we don't want an aluminum frame.
We want to steel frame,
well steel frame that meant that,
um,
that uh,
everything had to be redesigned,
the engines had to be bigger.
The fuel,
the right,
so is that waste.
You would go into waste.
It wouldn't be fraud or abuse
necessarily waste total to work.
You know what,
where's the logic behind that?
But as an engineering decision based on
like real knowledge that we have about
the rigidity of steel versus aluminum or
what does,
what does the,
she would think that a Gustaf Westland,
a helicopter manufacturing,
um,
business with an off the shelf Heloc,
a helicopter that exists,
that existed.
That's what the government want this
and,
and it transformed into a completely new
helicopter that has yet to fly.
That sounds insane.
It's insane.
It is insane.
Is that there was originally agreed upon
without,
I mean if they had like an order and the
initial order,
they had an initial order,
what was the reasoning for making the
steel frame?
What was the reasoning for changing?
Did it that,
uh,
that the,
that the order then had to go to this
pure cureman committee for any tweaks
and you'd have to think that there are
tweaks,
but this wasn't a tweak as an enzyme
tweak that's redesigning an incredibly
new,
it's about as nutty as it gets.
Flint water,
uh,
you know,
the,
the flint water crisis.
Why didn't I tell you what that just
sounds about as a troche's as it gets
when it comes to government turning its
back on,
on an obvious situation.
I think about,
um,
so I'm reading about it and as governor
of New Mexico,
I guarantee you that residents from
flint would have been at my open door
after four saying,
look,
I got dirty water and I would have got
into the middle of,
I'd like to think Joe,
that I would've gotten into the middle
of it immediately.
But you know what,
if I didn't get into it immediately,
I'm guessing my second door open door
after four,
instead of having four people show up
from flint,
would have 80 people showing up from
flint point is it would not have gone
unnoticed by me as governor.
And I had gotten right into the middle
of it and I had a mechanism for doing
it.
And there needs to be a mechanism for
the president of United States to stay
in touch.
The imperial presidency of the,
the notion that the president,
whenever the president travels,
it's,
it's tens of millions of dollars every
time he travels.
Well,
that's,
if I'm elected president United States,
that's going to change dramatically.
Does Air Force One really need to fly a
everywhere?
Gosh,
you wouldn't think so.
Why can't the prison,
the United States come into Los Angeles,
uh,
in a,
in a very stealth way and uh,
and travel without having to block a all
of traffic in Los Angeles,
which you have to f experience many
times.
Yeah,
that's pretty gross.
Well also,
why do they have to fly in Air Force
One?
How come they can't just get an American
airlines all
come well or how bout,
how bout one of those?
Uh,
how about one of those corporate
aircraft that,
uh,
are in the military that would cost a
10th of what the Air Force One causes
the benefits
of Air Force One is air force one of
some sort of a pod where the president
can parachute to,
saves you.
They tried to shoot it down or something
crazy like that.
You wonder about that one.
But,
uh,
what about a,
what about an ejection seat?
I mean,
James Bond's goes on and on and on.
yeah,
I can handle the objection.
You get handled being rejected.
I could handle being ejected.
I'm uncertain about it.
I mean,
we could go on and on about things.
One of those lines,
it seems a little,
a little silly,
but it's a little silly.
The whole thing has become not just a
little silly.
It's become pretty crazy.
Well.
Also when you isolate the president and
you make them this person,
they have to shut down all the city
streets and bring in a gigantic parade
of storm troopers that have to stand by
his side and you know what it would be?
It'd be great to,
as President United States to just
shuttle around in an f 16 I'm going to
let him shoot me down and an f 16 I'll
just take the back seat and I'm speaking
now as well.
They don't go very far,
you know that they don't go very far,
but they go really fast and when we're
talking about,
we're talking about money and dollars as
opposed to have 16 Ra.
Actually it sounds like you just want to
be in enough 16 no,
no.
I just want to,
I just want to spend less money.
I want to be a frugal cat in the White
House.
What kind of odds do you think there
are?
I mean this,
this election is a very tricky
obviously,
but what kind of odds do you believe
there are for 2020 I think,
first of all,
I would not be doing this if there
weren't the opportunity to win,
but the only opportunity that there is
of winning is to be in the presidential
debates.
That's the only chance.
Now,
what's the keys into the presidential
debates?
Kind of where we started off.
I used to be in the pole.
Doesn't that seem insane?
That what you have to get in this one
thing,
this presidential debates is thing that
is [inaudible].
It is the reality.
Yeah.
No,
no,
maybe not.
I mean maybe that's not the insane part.
Does it?
Does it not seem logical that anyone who
can mathematically be elected president
in 2012 that would have included the
Libertarian Party and the Green Party?
Does it not seem logical that anyone
capable of being mathematically elected
president in United States,
270 electoral votes should at a minimum
be included in the polls,
that there'd be a requirement that,
and you know that I'm in a 2016 there
are like 1600 people that registered to
run for president.
Wasn't Roseanne Barr one of them.
Uh,
that was,
that was 2012.
That was 2012 but anybody can run for
president.
You got to do is sign up with the
Federal Elections Commission and you can
run for president.
But at the end of the day,
in 2012 there were only four people that
could have mathematically been elected.
Doesn't that
seem fair?
Well,
it doesn't seem well,
the two party system is the biggest
hurdle right now for it.
I think most people,
when you think about the potential of
running for president,
the biggest hurdle is that you have to
be accepted and you have to be the
nominee of one of these two parties,
right?
Oh.
Or that you'll be included in the polls.
And right now because of just how
polarizing hillary and a trump are,
that just being in the polls,
that that will register enough,
a dissatisfaction with any third party
name in this case me.
Um,
that,
um,
I'd,
I'd like to think that all the things
that we've talked about right now,
you,
you were,
you wouldn't hear out of the mouths of
either hillary or
trump.
I don't believe you would.
I don't believe you would even hear it
from the mouth of Obama.
I think everybody would be much more
measured.
What I've said about Obama from the very
beginning,
and I'll still say it today,
is there anything that he says that you
can really disagree with?
I've always said that everything that
comes out of his mouth is like music.
It's just the reality hasn't matched up
with the words so,
well,
the real problem is a lot of the stuff
that he said running versus what he's
done in office,
right?
The hope and change website that talks
about whistle blowers and then you look
at his actual actions towards whistle
blowers and actual actions towards the
press.
It's,
it's pretty disturbing that,
well,
back to my open door after four or for
whistle blowers,
look,
come on in and talk to me.
Tell me,
tell me about what's going on.
Well,
that was what I wanted to get to next.
Maybe I can jump into the middle of it.
That's what I wanted to get to next.
So you're president,
how do you handle Julian assange?
How do you handle Edward Snowden?
What do you do about these two very high
profile situations where most people
believe that the information that they
released was very important to the
American public.
Very important to understanding what the
government is actually doing.
So,
um,
I'm,
I believe in dreams.
Well,
Julian asage is not been charged.
I don't think by the US government.
We know what's really going on though.
Well,
we know what's really going on.
I mean,
Julia was on Snowden.
Yes.
You Pardon?
Snowden.
I,
you know that he has brought to the
forefront this,
uh,
you know,
this mass surveillance,
but just but to play Sozo Joe,
so,
okay,
go ahead.
Yeah.
The entire NSA is an executive order 12,
three,
three under truman.
Uh,
you could repeal that executive order to
simply turn the satellites.
So wave from you and I this if they,
if you do 10 million,
verizon uses this metadata collection,
you can,
it's my understanding that you,
by executive order,
you could actually turn the satellites,
uh,
on the bad guys as to US citizens.
But don't you think that if someone
actually did that,
they'd probably put you in a convertible
and roll you through Dallas.
Uh,
that's also a possibility to say you're
going to get rid of the NSA or diminish
the NSA or the CIA or the FBI.
You,
you would be in a bad place.
It's,
it's kind of work with them,
right?
Isn't that the best way to handle it and
still keep your head?
Or how bout,
how bout the notion of really just doing
the right thing?
And so the Edward Snowden situation,
did you see the snowden movie that,
uh,
what was it called,
citizen for citizen for everybody
listening got a c it,
Edward Snowden.
I mean,
he laid it all out there.
It wasn't about him,
it was about the information.
He gave all the information to media
saying,
I do not in any way have the resources
to release this data because if I
release this data,
maybe I'm going to put people in harm's
way.
I don't want to put people's in people
in harm's way.
So I'm giving this up to a,
I can't remember the institutions that
he gave it up too,
but he said,
I,
I'm sure they have the resources that,
uh,
they will be able to disseminate this
information.
And um,
and not pete put p uh,
it was just an excellent,
excellent documentary on what I will say
is a real American Patriot
was a docu drama writers dramatization.
No,
it was,
which one was the drama?
Doesn't it?
One wasn't there one that was a
dramatization.
It coming out soon.
That's a dramatization.
Okay.
So citizen four was the actual
documentary.
It was the actual documentary.
Where were,
when they showed up,
it was Edward Snowden and they showed
up.
They didn't know who Edward Snowden was.
They didn't,
it was amazing.
You've got,
you've got to see it.
You've got to see.
I'll definitely say it.
Yeah.
Um,
to play devil's advocate,
if you do pardon Snowden,
that means that if there was a crime
being committed at all,
that crime is being committed by the
NSA.
If you,
if you demonize snowden,
as soon as they arrest Doden or they try
to rest snowden and they say the
snowdens a bad guy,
what he's done is terrible.
If it comes the United States,
we're absolutely going to arrest him.
What you're saying is,
and they're putting the,
the focus on him as a potential
criminal.
Well,
if,
if somehow or another he is exonerated
and he's really,
well,
what happened then?
Well,
is there a crime?
if he's exonerated,
if he's done something that violates the
whatever agreement that he had to sign
in order to work for the NSA,
that means that the crime that he
exposed was so significant that it was
valid for him to violate whatever
agreement he signed with the federal
government.
That right now they're pursuing him as a
criminal for which means someone needs
to go to jail for the crime if they're,
if they're not going to put him in jail
and prosecute him.
Interesting way of looking at it.
I look at it from the standpoint of this
is a mistake that we've made.
Let's acknowledge the mistake and let's,
uh,
let's move forward.
Let's correct as so I'm
not knocking that simple,
right?
We had,
may not be,
but,
um,
I'm not looking at this from,
uh,
from the standpoint of prosecuting
people as much as we've made a mistake.
Let's correct it is this is what this
country is really about.
They're still moving forward with this
data collection thing in Utah unabated.
And when you have testimony before
Congress,
it says,
are you spying on the American people?
And the response is,
uh,
well,
let's see.
Are,
is their mass surveillance of the
American public going on?
And when they said,
no,
the question should have been total
surveillance as mass surveillance.
What does that mean?
Thousands of people?
Well,
no,
we're talking about a hundred.
So he says no,
the answer being hundreds of millions of
total surveillance,
master males surveillance as far as mass
surveillance.
So it's correct.
It's actually honest.
If they know we're,
we're pursing,
we're parsing things here,
but come on,
we're,
we've been misled.
This is,
this is not the country that uh,
we fought wars to preserve.
Does this go back to what we're talking
about before?
Were businesses tend to lean towards
growth?
So the NSA is involved in growth and
they don't want to stop?
I think so.
It's the Peter Principle.
It's a,
I'm,
I want to justify my life and button to
justify my,
and these are,
I'm talking about bureaucrats,
nows justify my life.
I need to grow what it is I'm doing.
I need to prove that what I'm doing so
important that I need people working for
me.
I need to expand what I'm doing because
it's so important.
So what would you be able to do if
anything,
as a president?
So you get into office and with Ensa.
Yes.
It's,
it just came to my,
this just came to my attention like 10
days ago,
that the NSA is an executive order under
truman,
that the president of the United States
could repeal immediately.
God,
that would be ugly.
Why would it be,
they wouldn't let you do that?
Why wouldn't they say,
well,
nothing is simple.
Nothing is simple.
I do not want to downplay on,
on the complexity of what this might
entail,
but at the end of the day,
um,
is it possible to turn the satellites
away from you?
And I will.
That would be the thing be that we would
want to get rid of the NSA.
What would it want to be as maybe
redirect their efforts?
Wow.
Like,
as in protecting us again,
having an indigo,
uh,
having a,
an impenetrable national defense is an
impenetrable national defense.
Does that,
I mean,
this is,
or William,
this is 1984 they've got the satellites
on to us.
Yeah.
It is bizarre.
It's bizarre that they've just randomly
decided to get the entire country under
surveillance when there's no evidence to
point that you know,
you're,
you're stopping anything or eliminating
anything,
but you are putting people in a
compromised because
if people know that the government has
been paying attention to all of their
emails and voicemails and all that jazz,
then people will adjust their behavior.
They'll be a little bit more cautious
that a little bit more cautious with
their criticism and if you are ever in a
situation,
yes,
exactly.
And if you're ever in a situation where
you are against the government in any
way,
they will have so much data on you.
Like if you,
if you're one of those people that
decides to Edward Snowden it from here
on out,
boy,
good luck with that.
I mean they will instantly be pulling up
emails and voicemails and,
and you've got a real problem on your
hands because it's not just met a data,
right.
I mean that's also been proven.
We don't even know.
We don't know.
Nobody knows.
You remember the guy who initially was
the whistle blower?
Many,
many areas.
There are many of them.
There are many of them that are in
prison for
the same,
yeah,
well there's a gentleman that was one of
the original whistle blowers who was
actually one of the coders who was
working with the NSA when they first
started designing this sort of program
and he resigned and went public with all
of this and he was,
um,
when he was vilified and when Edward
Snowden came out with all of this
information,
this guy started doing interviews again
and he started saying like,
listen,
this is,
I was talking about this in the early
two thousands I,
this is something they'd been putting
into play for a long time during the
Bush administration.
They started us all off
the NSA.
The,
yeah.
Yeah.
I think it goes back further than that.
Yeah,
I think it does too.
It's a true,
here's the guy,
Bill,
Bill Binney,
the original NSA whistleblower unstowed
in nine 11 and illegal surveillance.
It's a very,
very interesting story.
There's,
there's several interviews with this
guy.
This one is from computer weekly,
but there's several interviews with is
this gentleman,
he was the original blowing what was a
year of this Jamie?
Cause I want to say 2007 but I might be
wrong.
It doesn't say,
um,
what does it matter?
Bill Binney is the guy and I've seen him
interviewed several times and he
realized while this was all going on,
he's like,
you're not looking for criminals.
You're trying to spy on everyone.
You can't do this.
And I think we all agree that you
shouldn't be able to do that.
But right now that's happening.
And,
and very simply,
there is a process.
The fourth amendment there is due
process.
So if there's a bad guy out there that
the,
uh,
the federal government wants to spy on,
you get a warrant,
got to get a warrant.
It's how it should be.
But this,
uh,
Pfizer court where the government goes
before the Pfizer court and says,
we want authority to,
uh,
to collect metadata on 110 million
verizon users.
I fail to see where that's due process
in any way shape
I have no one has made an argument
against that.
No one,
no one has made an argument that makes
any sense whatsoever supporting that.
So if that's the case,
why is it president allow it?
Good question.
Good.
If he's the guy that has all this music
coming out of his mouth,
what are his words that are so beautiful
and melodic about this?
A lot of water.
What's the word?
Well
that's the,
that's the big go.
Obama disappointment is,
um,
I'm sure if we went into the archives he
would have been addressed.
Well maybe he wouldn't have,
cause he wouldn't have even known about
this metadata collection.
But
I do.
Well,
he was the,
in the hope and change website when he
was running for president,
one of the things he was talking about
was supporting whistleblowers that are
revealing criminal activity.
Well,
he's directly contradicted that.
I mean,
he's everything he's done in regards to
people blowing whistles and revealing
government problems.
He's,
he's prosecuted them.
They'd been worse on freedom of the
press than any other president.
We will look at Bush as being like this
really terrible like a draconian guy,
but the Bush administration was easier
on whistle blowers and easier on press
and trying to get pressed to reveal
their sources.
Then the Obama administration back to
back to the reality.
Not matching up at all.
Exactly.
Yeah.
The reality,
not matching up at all,
not just with the words but with the,
the appearance,
like it's the appearance of this,
this really educated like socially aware
guy who gets into play black.
Finally,
we've got this articulate,
intelligent,
well read president.
This is a relief from the guy who,
you know,
stumbles through words and says a bunch
of stupid shit.
Like this is our guy.
This is our guy.
Finally.
But then same practices,
in fact,
worse,
more drone attacks,
more.
I mean,
what do you do about that?
What do you do about a program that the
drone attacks have resulted in?
I believe the numbers,
like more than 80% accidental death or
more than 80% civilians being killed
versus the intended target.
Well,
this is the unintended consequence of
our military interventions,
that they're making things worse,
not better.
And I am talking about boots on the
ground.
I'm talking about dropping bombs and the
fact that drones do fly and kill
thousands of innocent people.
And when I had Mike Baker on,
who was a former CIA operative,
when he,
when he and I were discussing this,
he,
he was saying that,
look,
what you're seeing is lawyers make those
decisions,
these decisions of whether to bomb or
not to bomb.
They're being done by lawyers.
They sit down,
they let go over the possibilities,
they go over the risks versus reward,
and they make the call.
What the fuck kind of world is that?
That's the world that I'm with.
That's the world that can be changed,
I think.
So here's the big battle ship.
It's the United States.
Well,
yeah,
super tank or whatever you would call
it.
Well first you got your cruiser first.
You know,
it's,
what is it?
What is it at six months it takes six
miles to turn the six super tanker
around.
Turn it around 180 degrees.
Well first you got to stop the engines
first.
First you got to actually start the
process.
Yeah.
And,
okay,
so it's six miles before you can
actually pull the uturn.
Well,
we're,
we're full steam ahead.
We're still full steam ahead.
Okay.
So let's talk military.
So you're,
you're in office,
obviously you need to protect people.
Obviously there's threats out there,
both a broad and locally.
What do you do in terms of minimizing
the amount of money that we spend on the
military?
Minimizing the amount of invasion of
privacy that the branches of the
military,
like things like the NSA,
which I guess you consider the military,
some sort of security apparatus for us.
Right.
What would you consider the NSA?
Is that military?
What would you consider it?
I don't know.
National Security Administration,
but I mean,
obviously it's,
some has to do with the military,
right?
Has To be oversight or has to,
has to be,
has to be some transparency.
So when you're talking about the
military,
how do you go about minimizing the
impact or minimizing the negative
aspects of it?
Well,
um,
make no bones.
If we're attacked,
we're going to attack back,
that we should have an impenetrable
national defense,
but we're anything but defense.
Whereas Congress in all of this,
uh,
they've abdicated their responsibility
to declare war for the American people
to have a discussion and debate over how
the military should proceed.
They've abdicated that responsibility to
the president of the United States who's
doing this,
uh,
on executive.
Yeah.
Border along with the military.
That's where I rack got really weird,
right?
Where it wasn't an actual act of war.
Wasn't that right?
That
congress had allowed,
had,
well,
the Congress has allowed the president
to carry on this,
um,
uh,
to do what the president sees fit.
Well,
that,
that is,
that's my opinion.
That's an abdication of,
of constitutional responsibility by
Congress.
So let's reestablish that.
I think the biggest threat in the world
right now is,
um,
is North Korea and the fact that at some
point,
uh,
Kim,
is at some point these intercontinental
ballistic missiles are going to work.
And this guy isn't not so hot about the
notion of,
um,
really getting together with China
because this is in China's best interest
to,
uh,
to get rid of Kim unify the Koreas,
um,
get American troops out of South Korea.
Um,
if Cuba,
look,
we didn't,
we didn't put up for a second that,
uh,
that Russia was going to occupy or have
missiles in,
uh,
in Cuba.
Do you think China likes the fact that
we got 40,000 troops in Korea?
Uh,
no.
They don't like it a bit.
Well,
do we not make the world a lot more
secure if we can't come to terms with,
uh,
with China on how we can,
with what I will argue the biggest
threat in the world right now in China
is an ally of North Korea,
correct?
They are,
but they're an embarrassment to from all
that I can glean.
They're an embarrassment.
A 70% of South Korea's trade export goes
to China.
None of North Korea's export goes to
China because there is no product to
export.
Um,
it's,
well,
but it's turned that ship around.
Boy,
you want to talk about turning a tough
ship around the North Korea ship when
you're talking about an entire brainwash
country.
It's a very sad,
sad state.
China is not blind to that.
Let's take advantage of,
um,
let's take advantage of,
uh,
of establishing a partnership and
alliance with China to deal with that,
but there are already so poor and so
screwed over.
What do you do as opposed metairie
intervention as opposed to us as opposed
to us dealing with it.
It's in China's best interest to deal
with this and so that China has,
what are,
they have this island that they build 40
miles off their coast or whatever it is.
What's,
what's the big deal?
The United States does this all the
time.
What's the big deal?
Big Deal.
In what way?
Like what do you say?
Well,
this is somehow a threat to US security
that a,
you know,
that they've built an island 40 miles
off of their mainland.
Um,
I don't get it.
We're spending more on out.
We're spending as much money on our
military as the all the other nations in
the world combined.
What does that say?
Does that say maybe we're spending more
than our fair share talk about?
Well that's also were the number one
superpower in the world.
And in order to maintain that position
and be the benevolent dictators,
well,
and to what,
to what end,
to what end are we maintaining that
position?
What,
what,
what is the end game here where the end
game is to provide national,
impenetrable national defense for our
country?
I mean,
um,
I don't want to put troops in harm's
way.
I don't,
I don't want,
I don't want men and women dying in
situations where that does not have to
take place.
You know,
that fact they get injured,
they come back here,
the rest of their lives there.
They're affected by
stop.
I agree with you.
But to play devil's advocate and take
their point of view,
they would say that what they're doing
overseas is saving things from happening
here and keeping people safe by
intervening in other countries,
by blocking things from taking place.
I mean,
this would be the argument for a large
prevalent military that is this all
right.
The world.
That is always the argument.
But the reality is,
is that these interventions at best make
things the same or leave things the same
but versus get worse.
That's what their argument would be like
if they weren't doing this,
that you would have the superpowers
developed in these other countries and
it would become a gigantic issue.
Whether it's Iran,
whether it's Russia,
whether it's whatever it is,
take it rock for an example,
we intervene in Iraq.
Um,
the biggest threat to Iran was Iraq with
Saddam Hussein.
That that's all their concern was,
was how,
how did they deal with Saddam Hussein in
Iraq?
We go in and we'd take out Saddam
Hussein.
Well,
now all of a sudden we cut the head of
that hydro off.
Now all of a sudden we have to deal with
Iran.
Something that we weren't having to deal
with before.
That's an unintended consequence.
Do we need to deal with Iran?
I mean,
what is the reason why we have to deal
with Iran?
They're the biggest funder of terrorism
in the world.
They fund terrorism.
Um,
there's,
it's undeniable.
So at first I was in support of this
treaty and naively,
meaning the treaty that we signed with
Iran that,
uh,
ended up releasing however much money it
was,
$160 billion in by secretary Kerry's own
image admission,
uh,
question was,
will,
will there not be funds that will get
directed at terrorism?
And he said,
yes,
there will be funds that will be
directed at terrorism.
So how on earth could we have signed
that agreement with Iran given the fact
that they are the biggest funder of
terrorism
world?
What is their motivation of fund
terrorism?
Is their motivation to fund terrorism
because they're concerned with the
United States continuing to develop
power in the Middle East?
Like what is there?
Well,
it could be a common devil's advocate.
Yeah.
No,
no,
no.
It could be a con.
I don't want to
discount anything that's being said by
anyone,
but from our standpoint,
um,
this is w we're,
we're contributing to what will be,
um,
more terrorism because terrorism will
get funded from some of this money that
got freed up.
Now when you say that,
when you say funding terrorism
specifically,
what do you mean?
Well,
where were we at some point the these
terrorist groups and I'm not,
and who's to say,
where are the connection using Brussels
as an example?
Who's to say where those guys were
getting their funds from their support
from?
Well,
um,
it's not a stretch to say that it may
have come from Iran,
but isn't that a big statement that
should be qualified?
Well,
regardless of whether it's Brussels or,
or wherever,
at some point the funding for terrorism
has results.
And in this case,
if you are allowing a contributor to
terrorism to have funds to contribute as
the United States,
um,
are,
are we not making the situation worse
when we go in and militarily intervene
and leave equipment,
uh,
Afghanistan,
we leave equipment,
we ended up arming the Taliban when the,
when the Russians leave,
the Taliban is equipped to,
they're equipped with a US arms because
we use the Taliban to fight,
um,
the Russians.
Right.
But to bring them back to Iran.
What if any evidence is available that
shows that I ran funded terrorism,
uh,
unequivocal.
Uh,
I,
I can't state for you the ABC's of it,
but,
um,
unequivocal sec,
secretary of State,
um,
Carrie,
uh,
was asked the question,
well,
isn't some of this money,
some of it going to get directed at
funding terrorism?
And his response was,
yeah,
you,
yes,
some of it unquestionably is going to
get directed toward terrorism.
I don't know how we can,
how we could have a okayed that given,
given what has been acknowledged,
what is the benefit of giving them
money?
You know,
uh,
I'm,
I'm all for the free trade.
Um,
I think that free trade at the end of
the day is a really powerful tool.
Um,
I don't have the answer to this and I
don't want to,
I don't want to misstate anything,
but this is a conversation that we're
having a could we have not opened up
free trade with Iran and still kept
their assets frozen.
And by that,
that uh,
assets that,
that now they enter into the world
community that they can sell their oil
and on an ongoing basis,
um,
w we'll have free trade with Iran.
They can spend the money as they see
fit.
But with regard to the money that's been
frozen,
um,
if,
if we believe that any of that's going
to be redirected or directed at
terrorism,
why did we do that?
I don't,
I,
I'm just saying I W I don't get it.
Well,
what has been the response by the
administration?
I mean there's this question been
brought up and what have they,
how have they answered it?
Well,
that was the,
this was,
gosh,
maybe,
I don't know,
six months ago and Carrie was asked
cause and you know,
it was very matter of factly.
Yes.
Some of it's going to get redirected to,
you know,
you have to I think is,
I'm a secondhand or firsthand.
I mean I'm repeating what I thought I
heard him say,
which was,
yeah,
unquestionably,
some of this is going to go to
terrorism.
I don't get it.
Okay,
well we don't have specifics to discuss
when it comes to that,
like specific facts.
So it gets,
it gets it.
And we got,
we got the Internet and going.
Yeah,
we definitely do.
Um,
I wonder what,
if anything can be done to calm some of
the areas down in the world.
Um,
and how much of what's going on in the
world is about controlling resources and
how much of that would change if we had
less reliance on fossil fuels?
Well,
we're not getting any of our oil right
now from a,
from the Middle East.
We're not getting the enacting well,
we are fracking and,
and,
uh,
that statement is not completely true.
We are getting oil from all over the
world,
but,
so our refineries here in the United
States,
so,
so there's a,
there's a trade off where we're x
sporting really clean oil or oil that
doesn't need as much refining and we're
importing oil that is dirty so it's
cheaper.
So there's a more of a profit margin to
bring in dirty oil,
refine it,
and make more money by exporting cleaner
oil that refineries overseas can handle
as opposed to the United States.
So there is that going on.
But for the most part,
we are,
we're energy sufficient,
uh,
at the moment because of fracking.
But when we entered into Iraq,
one of the more cynical concerns was
that we were doing it because we were
trying to control natural resources.
We were sure.
Yes.
And at that time,
I think that that,
I mean,
did that not play a part in the
equation?
Certainly the administration denied
that,
but,
um,
everybody I think saw that for what it
was to,
that that was the case.
So when you look at the world in terms
of threats and,
Ooh,
imminent danger to the United States,
like what could be done to try to lessen
that?
Well,
first and foremost,
and this is where the Obama
administration has concentrated on,
and I couldn't tell you the status of
how effective it is a,
but it is to cut off funding to
terrorism.
I mean that's the,
that's the,
uh,
that's the goal.
The,
Eh,
um,
Saudi Arabia,
terrorism.
Such a weird word because it's such a
blanket statement.
If you're not talking about an
individual nation with an individual
motive,
you know,
you say terrorism,
it's like we have a war on terror.
What does that really mean?
You know,
I mean,
well they talking about
in groups and Muslim,
the Muslims get extremely offended when
you use the term Islamic terrorism or
Moose,
uh,
you know,
um,
Islamic terrorism,
which looking at it from the outside,
it does appear as though there is that
constant.
Um,
but,
um,
Muslims would say that,
look,
that's not inherent in the Muslim
religion,
which I more than agree with.
Um,
so this is the political correctness
about saying terrorism as opposed to
Islamic terrorists.
Right?
Right.
But the terrorist just happened to be
Islamic does seem to be that common
element,
but is that something that's taught?
Um,
is that something that most,
uh,
most of,
Muslim religion believes in you?
No.
No,
no,
but it does seem to be a common thread.
And,
um,
but that's the political,
I'm repeating myself here.
I,
how do calm that down?
I mean,
what do you,
how do you,
is there any way to appease people that
are so upset at the United States?
I mean,
what is their major gripe?
What does her major reason for being
upset with us?
And as a president,
what would you do to try to stop that or
well,
that you would contain it for at a
minimum,
you'd try and contain it to where it's
at and not allow it to spread.
And now I'm back to,
uh,
military policy defense,
um,
having an impenetrable national defense
that the notion of somehow a dirty bomb
getting over here into the United
States.
I mean,
that should be a real,
a real live concern.
Just getting military operatives though
they believe that a proactive attack or
proactive action is much more likely to
stop isis or anything nice or,
well,
and that's,
and that's been our tact to date.
And,
um,
I'm going to say that,
uh,
without exception that every one of
those military interventions have had an
unintended consequence of at best,
you know,
we,
we go,
we're,
we always deal with atrocity,
their atrocities going on.
We go in to deal with that atrocity.
And at the end of the day,
the new dictator,
the new desperate that we put into place
to replace the bad,
desperate at the end of the day is just
as bad or in many cases worse.
We cut off the head of the Hydra and Lo
and behold,
they're more heads.
So how does one stop that?
I mean it,
I mean,
if you ever tried to come up with some
sort of a solution or look at some sort
of a long term plan that would somehow
or another calm the world,
or at least allow the United States to
make peace.
You know,
one of the reasons that I'm seeking to
become president of United States is I
think I do a really good job of
presiding over over all the intelligence
that we do have regarding all of this.
And I don't want to,
I don't want to present myself as having
the answers as much as you know,
what,
give me,
give me the Intel,
uh,
let me be part of this discussion and
um,
but I'm going to enter into this
discussion as a real skeptic,
um,
on what we've done to this point and a
real skeptic on what appears to be,
what we're going to do in the future
regarding all of this.
And isn't there a more effective way of
dealing with this?
I wouldn't be seeking this job if I'm,
if I didn't think that I could make a
difference in it and I,
I do not want to misstate.
I don't want to,
I don't want to play cards.
Obama draws lines in the sand.
I'm not going to draw lines in the sand.
If you draw any lines in the sand,
you better be prepared to back up what
you've said,
uh,
with action.
And that's also been an issue with
Obama.
How much different do you think
perspective changes once you get into
office?
Once you get into office and you sit
down with military leaders and you sit
down with someone,
explains to you
the,
the actual landscape you're dealing
with.
I think he pushed himself too.
I think that perspective can change a
lot.
But how about being transparent?
How about saying how bout,
how bout being transparent with the
American public?
How about educating the American public
to um,
to the Intel that does exist.
It's a wooden,
they possibly alert the enemy that we
have knowledge of.
Some things they may or may not know we
have knowledge of
and that you certain danger,
you certainly wouldn't want to cross
over that line in any way whatsoever.
But uh,
if,
if you've got elected to office saying
that we should not militarily intervene,
that military interventions have an
unintended consequence and then the next
day you militarily intervene somewhere,
you better darn well get up in front of
the American public and take the,
take the eggs and tomatoes or,
or worse.
What was your take when Obama went on
television and was talking about how we
needed to invade Syria and Syria was a
huge issue.
And then the American public was up in
arms,
both the right and the left people like,
what are you talking about?
This is craziness.
And then the,
the administration backed off and we
was,
to me,
my opinion,
it was one of the first that was
drawing,
I'm sorry.
Yeah,
that's okay.
But it was one of the first examples of
the United States,
like sort of collectively the will of
the people like being openly expressed
that the idea of entering Syria was
outrageous.
Nobody wanted to do it.
They didn't make any sense to people.
This gas attack.
Like how is this any more horrible than
a lot of shit that's going on all over
the world all the time.
What is that?
What is it about Syria that all of a
sudden we have to go and invade Syria?
One more intervention in one more
country in the United States.
Admit the administration backed off.
Great.
Great example.
People,
people are fed up with this and the fact
that,
uh,
you know,
22 million people in Syria and 11
million of them have been displaced,
don't we?
Don't we have a share?
And in that consequence,
well,
what was the motivation?
What was the motivation for the United
States wanted to invade their in the
first place?
Well,
it wasn't it a mccain going over there
and beating his chest and,
uh,
along with,
Lindsey Graham and,
uh,
and let's go over there and support the
good guys.
Well,
the good guys are the minority and the
good guys at the end of the day,
um,
look,
this is where the somehow we're going to
determine the outcomes,
uh,
in other countries.
I mean,
that's just,
it's preposterous that,
uh,
as individuals we can do that.
But this seems so contrary to what Obama
stood for before he got an office.
So when he gets on television and talks
about intervening,
going over to Syria about,
you know,
there's gas attacks and all this jazz,
like where,
where's that motivation coming from?
Like,
who's behind him pushing him into this
direction?
Or is this just how he's been the entire
time?
And we just,
he just sold us a song and dance before
he got into office.
You,
you,
you off this,
this kind of line of thought by saying
we're,
this is where I thought you were headed
was can you get in and not be co opted
by the system?
Um,
based on my ex only experience having
been governor of New Mexico.
Yeah,
you can't,
meaning you can go that good government
was easy.
It wasn't hard that you,
that you weren't co-opted.
There was plenty of cooption that uh,
you know,
that tried to wield itself.
But you know what?
You're the president of the United
States.
You're the governor of a state.
You know,
you're,
you're at the top of the pyramid.
You,
yes,
you do have limited powers,
but even with those limited powers,
you're still the most powerful human
being on earth.
Don't you think?
There's a pretty radical difference
between being a governor of a state
without a military and being the
president of the United States dealing
not just with the same sort of problems
that you dealt with as a governor,
but on a much larger scale,
plus the problems of the world,
plus the military plus the weird stuff
like the NSA and the CIA.
And the NSA.
Yeah.
And it has to be extremely more complex.
But at the end of the day,
do you,
can you still tell the truth?
Can you still admit mistakes?
Um,
and you know,
if,
if you're willing to tell the truth and
you're willing to admit mistakes,
mistakes seemed to have a way of
compounding themselves when you don't
admit the mistakes as in lieu of
admitting the mistakes and then taking
corrective action.
But really at the end of the day,
doesn't it boil down to telling the
truth and um,
and fessing up to mistakes and fixing
it?
I would think so.
But it seems to me that the,
the wiring of the office is so complex
and there's so much craziness going on
that no one gets in office and does what
they said they were going to do before
they got an office because I'm almost
seem insurmountable.
That was not my experience.
That was not mine.
As a governor,
governors have done what they've,
they've pledged.
Well.
So would you rather,
would you rather elect someone who has
had the experience of not having been
co-opted,
uh,
as opposed to somebody who has been
cooptive want one wants someone that's
been cooptive at the end of the day.
Will I be,
would I,
if I'm elected president United States
at the end of the day,
would I be able to make that same
statement?
I hope so.
So
that's the best way to put it.
That's an honest way to put it.
You hope so.
Cause it just,
I,
I really would like to know.
I would love it if you became president
and we could stay friends and I could
go,
hey man,
I won't tell anybody.
No,
no.
We'll tell.
We'll tell the world,
tell them on back here.
We'll tell the world I don't want to get
shot with you.
I'm to run away.
I just,
it's just the whole thing seems so
almost impossibly intertwined that it's
like a,
you go fishing.
You ever go fishing?
No,
I'm,
I'm on my mountain bike as opposed to
fishing.
I do have a,
just a sidelight.
I do have a stream running through my,
uh,
right by my house.
I have 1600 feet of frontage on the
Hondo River and it's loaded with
taxpayer trout.
So give me,
give you an invitation to come.
Yeah.
Beautiful Stream.
That would be like probably fly fishing,
right?
Um,
what I'm talking about is,
um,
there's a thing called the bird's nest
with a business is when you use a bait
casting reel and the line spools quicker
than it can roll over it and it gets it,
it becomes this gigantic tangle.
And when you,
when you use a bait casting really
supposed to sort of regulate it,
at least the old school ones,
you regulate the amount of pressure with
your thumb as to like,
uh,
how fast the,
the wheel turns.
The wheel turns too quick.
That line gets so tangled and it almost
becomes impossible.
You look at it and you go,
shit,
what am I going to do with it?
There's,
there's a perfect image.
That's what a bird's nest looks like.
You see how all the line is all just
deal with it.
Good.
Try getting through that.
That's a mess.
See when I think of the government,
I think of like that with bullets that
like,
this is almost like the analogy branches
and it's almost like it's so tangled and
with all the other variables that you
discussed,
terms,
term limitations that are,
that aren't in place,
um,
ideological blockades on the left and
the right supporting your constituents
on the left and the right special
interest groups,
lobbyists,
the fact that there's,
I mean there's this one area outside of
Washington dc that is just all
lobbyists,
this,
these neighborhoods and it's one of the
wealthiest parts of the area and it's
just because people are making insane
amounts of money manipulating the
system.
So,
uh,
I am advocating eliminating income tax
and corporate tax and as a result of
that,
wait a minute,
hit the brakes.
Did you just say you were talking about
lobbyists?
Yeah,
yeah.
How are you going to do that?
Eliminate income tax.
Eliminate corporate tax because you're
going to do that.
You're going to also be able to abolish
the irs and you can read,
Oh,
you just hear me out here.
Just a radical boulevard.
You hear me out a couple more minutes
and we would replace all of that with
one federal consumption tax.
Now how do you do that?
While there's an actual proposal out
there,
it's called the fair tax.
Uh,
and it's uh,
how you dot the i's and cross the t's
when it comes to establishing one
federal consumption tax.
If we had zero corporate tax in this
country,
I believe tens of millions of jobs would
get created if we did not have corporate
tax.
If we did not have income tax,
I believe that pink slips would get
issued to 80 of Washington
lobbyists because that's why they're
there to garner special tax favor.
At the end of the day,
it's all about,
uh,
advantage and really that amounts to tax
money spent.
So how does this consumption tax work
and how would you possibly implement and
how would you possibly get anyone to
agree to do this?
To get rid of the irs,
to get rid of the,
yeah,
actually come to a couple hundred,
a couple hundred congressmen and women,
maybe 160 have actually signed on to
this proposal.
So this proposal's been around for quite
a while.
And how many oppose it?
Well,
you got what,
how many?
400 f well by pose,
not necessarily opposed,
but you know,
you haven't signed on,
haven't signed on.
Well that would be more than half have
not signed on,
but a significant number have.
So it's uh,
it's been vetted.
It's,
it's out there.
Okay.
So this consumption tax,
yeah.
How does this work?
It would be a 28% consumption,
tossed the board on,
on all new goods and services,
not used goods and services.
And before you fall off the chair,
the theory,
the theory is that it wouldn't
necessarily,
it would be cost neutral.
So if I could use a can of coke as an
example,
can of coke that sells for a buck today,
um,
has a corporate tax contained in that
book.
It has unemployment,
a contained in that book.
It has social security match contained
in that book.
It has medicare a contained in that
dollar.
It has the accounting fees and the legal
fees that go along with complying with
the irs and the filing with the irs.
So arguably the can of coke would not
sell for a buck.
It would sell for 73 cents and then the
28% tax would get applied to the can of
coke.
So you'd still end up paying a buck for
the can of coke.
That's the theory.
So by doing this and eliminating income
tax,
how much different would the amount be
that the government receives?
This is intended to be revenue neutral,
revenue neutral.
So governments still gonna receive the
same amount of money.
That's the,
that's also the projection that how's
that possible?
The people are not paying income tax.
I say if someone's wealthy filling out
$1 million a year and you know $1
million a year,
you're probably in a 48% tax bracket.
Take away all your tax shelters and all
the various ways,
corporations,
llcs,
all that jazz.
You're,
you're in the 30s probably,
right?
That's a lot of money.
That's $300,000 so how much money are
you?
How are you going to welding that?
Well that if you're making a lot of
money,
you spend a lot of money,
so you're going to pay that money and
consumption tax,
scrooge mcduck and you just hanging
back.
Whoa.
Then that's a way that you can,
uh,
isn't there a fairness in that?
But the reality is the more people make
when it comes to money,
the more people spend.
But if you want to save your money,
when you say new and used,
does that apply to homes?
Yup.
So a new home,
you would have to pay 38% that would
want to uphold the whole market,
28% that would cripple the home market
because no one would want to buy a new
home.
No,
but I'm back to back to the theory.
The right now you've got the,
when you,
when you enlist the aid of the plumbing
company,
the plumbing company has,
so first of all,
no more payroll deductions.
Um,
the social security,
uh,
unemployment,
um,
medicare,
all of that would come out of the
proceeds of one federal consumption tax.
So all government proceeds would come
from this new pot of money.
So it's just a sales tax.
So instead of the plumber on your home,
uh,
giving you a $100,000 bill for the
plumbing,
uh,
theoretically the bill will be 73 grand
with me.
So it's not the,
the,
the theory is the house really isn't
going to cost you any more.
Um,
uh,
because,
all these hidden taxes that exist are
going to go away.
Hmm.
That sounds cute.
It's theory.
Well,
and let me,
let me also just say,
uh,
I'm looking to get elected president of
the United States.
Um,
I'm going to sign on to what I think is
going to make anything better.
But when you talk about making things
really better,
I think this is a proposal that
simplifies all of our lives in a,
in a huge way.
Imagine not having to
deal with the irs.
It would be tremendous,
but you would also put all those people
out of jobs and they're going to fight
for that.
They're going to,
they're going to charge it against that.
That'd be a job.
That would be
the accounting and the,
and the,
uh,
attorney fees that go along with
complying with the irs and the irs
employees themselves.
And if you think about the pressure that
the police unions or the,
the guard unions rather prison guard
unions put to make sure that marijuana
is still remains illegal and drug laws
remained in place,
imagine the kind of pressure that
lobbyists and the irs and anyone else
that might be affected by these
decisions are going to put to try to
stop this from happening.
Well,
this is,
this though would be a dialogue if you
had a,
in this case,
Gary Johnson onstage in the presidential
debates talking about something like
this.
Um,
wouldn't,
that I'm maybe open people's eyes to the
fact that Whoa,
life could change dramatically.
Some would argue for the better.
I think at the end of the day you would,
you can argue that this would make life
a lot better for everybody.
Um,
we'll certainly stimulate a dialogue,
but I wonder if you can get that point
across and those little soundbites it do
in those debates.
I think so.
Um,
tens of millions of jobs would get
created overnight here in the United
States because of a zero tax rate.
Why?
So why would you,
why would you create a job anywhere in
the world other than the United States
given zero corporate taxes?
So you think that like apple would move,
their iphone factors are paying people 5
cents an hour.
They'd move into the United States and
have to pay a working wage because they
don't have to pay corporate taxes.
Wouldn't they cancel each other out?
Wouldn't it be more profitable to still
invoke foreign labor and use third world
countries,
but they would have to pay that
corporate tax in that foreign country?
I mean,
right,
but it's minimal,
right?
I mean,
no,
it's not me.
It's not minimal,
but it's less so now.
But now I'm back to,
hey,
I get elected president of United States
and I'm sue and I get legislation
submitted to reduce corporate tax.
Yeah,
I'm going to sign on to that because I
think it really is a hindrance to job
creation when we have the highest
corporate tax rate.
But imagine instead of having a debate
over,
should we reduce the corporate tax rate
to 28% or 29% and Republicans and
Democrats both get their peacock
feathers all up in arms,
about 29 or 28 or 27 well,
how about zero?
How about doing away with the irs?
Oh my gosh.
Imagine the,
I mean if,
if,
if lowering it is good.
How about eliminating it?
Well,
I think you would get universal support
from the United States.
I mean from people in the country.
If you ask people how much do they love
the United States irs system,
they would say zero.
I mean,
I don't think there's a single person
other than people who work for the irs
and says,
I love them.
They're awesome.
I love when they go after your bank
account.
I love when they take all your money.
Yeah,
no,
you're right.
You're right.
No,
no,
no.
I,
I'll drop the,
I'll drop the thought completely because
of the love that does exist for the irs.
You're right.
No what I'm saying,
no one loves,
no,
don't know what I'm saying.
I do mean everyone hates it.
So everyone wouldn't hate you would get
a hundred percent support.
Well,
no,
there's nothing.
There's no such thing as a hundred
percent,
but obviously,
but how about the how,
how about,
you know,
how about this entering into the,
uh,
the debate?
Yeah.
What would be a great thing to talk
about?
Because the system is not good and no
one thinks it is.
So the idea of keeping it exactly the
way it is seems pretty ridiculous,
right?
I mean,
that's like the definition of insanity,
doing the same thing over and over
again,
expecting different results.
It's crony capitalism.
It's,
you know,
those that have money pay less of their
share.
Um,
this really at the,
at the end of the day is very fair.
Right.
So thinking of that,
and along those lines,
how do you feel about corporations
donating to political candidates?
I have no issue with corporations
donating to political candidates.
But the problem today is,
are these super pacs that are 100%
nontransparent.
You have no idea who's contributing to
these superpacs make,
make for unlimited contribution.
Just make the contributions hundred
percent transparent.
I'm the one that said candidate should
wear,
um,
nascar like jackets with that was Robin
Williams.
Actually,
I actually,
that was me.
Maybe.
Maybe he got it from me.
He used to do a hit a bit about it on
hbo show.
He didn't go to sleep with the TV on.
No,
I think I had this first.
I think I do have this first.
Tell me what the year was.
Let's do google it.
Well,
uh,
yeah,
no deal.
Google it.
You know,
it's Robin Williams ripped you off.
That would be brutal.
No,
I'm not.
There's no rip off.
You might have,
but this would have been,
I had been saying this in 2009.
I think he might've got ya.
Well maybe so,
but,
but I'm not,
I'm not infringing on his stuff.
I thought it was original.
I want to think of special was in 2006.
I want to think,
I wonder if you might be parallel
thinking it doesn't mean yes,
that's the problem with intellectual
property is a weight look.
If it's parallel thinking,
certainly I'm not the only other one
either.
I mean,
I'm sure there are probably a hundred
people listening right now that are
going,
no,
I said that first 100%.
Well,
it's a pretty obvious connection,
right?
You see Nascar,
they're all covered with logos.
It stands out and you know who's
sponsoring or the logo.
The more money,
the more money was controlling the
direct.
I mean this,
the,
the direct comparison because they're
the most obvious sponsor thing.
The car sponsored,
their jackets are sponsored,
everything's covered in logos.
They're like,
if you look at basketball players,
you don't see that,
you know,
it's very rare that you see any sort of
a sporting event where they're covered
with logos like that.
So what,
what year that's coming this next
season,
what the NBA is adding all those logos
to all their things.
I'm writing one.
Yeah,
they're earning one logo.
And this is a way was actually argued
against the reebok deal for the UFC.
Um,
I,
I get real concerned with a superpacs
for sure.
I get real concerned with money and
politics and that is a,
I think one of the reasons why Bernie
Sanders has stood out.
It's cause he's the only guy that is not
really accepting money from these giant
corporations and he's fairly self
funded.
One of them.
One of the misconceptions about a
campaign finances is that one of the
misconceptions is that if you limit
campaign contribution that um,
that things are going to get better and
you're going to eliminate the influence
of big money when the reality is by
limiting campaign contribution.
You basically,
that's an incumbency protection act.
So limiting campaign contribution is all
about reelecting incumbents.
That's what it's all about.
Look,
if you,
if you could get,
if somebody would finance me to the tune
of $1 billion,
they might change this country in a
really big way.
Should the billion dollars be anonymous?
I don't think so.
I think that it should be front and
center and whom ever contributed.
That should be known
completely.
And that a,
their goal was to change America and by
giving Gary Johnson a billion bucks,
um,
I have the opportunity to do that,
that it just be transparent as opposed
to having to take 500,000 contributions
at $2,000.
Um,
which has,
which at the end of the day has more of
a corrupting influence,
more of a corrupting influence and one
super rich person that wants to
influence your decision making.
Well,
uh,
as an example,
governor of New Mexico,
my number one contributor of for two for
two terms,
uh,
gave me $150,000.
May sound cheap too.
A lot of people,
but that doesn't sound cheap.
It sounds like a guy with a lot of money
you can throw 150 grand your way.
Yeah.
Eh,
and Eh,
over an eight year old girl over an
eight year period.
Um,
he was,
he was never,
not once did he call for anything.
There was never any requests.
That's about rare though.
No.
Well,
maybe,
but my point is,
is it,
if I would have had a thousand
contributors,
uh,
giving me 150.
Right,
I see what you're saying.
$1,500 get a hundred people giving me
$1,500.
I guarantee a Joe that 10 of them at
some point would have been on the phone
wanting something.
Right.
Guarantee it.
Uh,
okay.
I,
this is,
um,
it's pretty anecdotal.
Don't know.
I mean,
you're talking about one contributor
versus if you're looking at someone
who's,
or who's trying to contribute though to
the United States,
to someone running for the United States
and if they give you $1 billion,
one person who gives you $1 billion,
that guy's going to want some,
he's gonna want something.
I don't think,
I really don't think it's that.
So let's,
let's,
let's use a more realistic term.
A billionaire that wants a,
you know,
a multibillionaire that wants to give
$10 million bill gates or someone like
someone like that.
Yeah.
Is it,
is it,
is it inconceivable that there is that
there aren't a whole bunch of those
people out there that would just be
looking for good government and just be
looking to back that the candidate of
their choice based on what it was they
were saying?
Not On,
not on.
I don't think it's inconceivable at all,
but just let's all know who that
contributor was and how much money.
Well,
I understand that the transparency
aspect,
that sort of makes sense.
But boy,
having one person that influences
politics that much,
it's concerning.
It concerns people.
And I think rightly so,
because someone who has that much money,
who they are,
they're already in this very strong,
advantageous position.
And the only reason why you would
rationally give someone $1 billion is if
you thought that it was going to be an
advantage to you.
You are going to somehow or another reap
the rewards of giving them that money.
Good government.
So,
um,
in my,
I'd never been involved in politics
before,
running for governor of New Mexico.
Never knew businessman,
successful,
but never,
never even pounded in a campaign sign.
Well,
how did I get elected?
I paid for my own campaign.
Uh,
my primary,
this is gonna sound really cheap,
but my primary,
the first time was $540,000.
510 of it was mine and 30 and
motivation,
just good government.
The note it,
the notion of life and what do you do
with your life?
And for me,
my entire life,
um,
politics,
I,
I viewed it as a high calling.
You know,
the notion of being in a position to
make things better.
Now,
look,
I'm the first person to also admit that
if you had people lined up,
or if you ask,
asked how many,
how many are going to line up here to
say Gary Johnson was a scourge of the
earth.
Hey,
you know,
there'd be,
there'd be lines blocks long out out
here.
I get it.
But you try and do their main criticism
be no.
Um,
I don't think,
I don't think you'd actually have that
happen,
but there's always criticism regardless
of what you do.
And the motivation for what I've done
always is to make things better.
But there are always people that,
um,
have something contrary to say,
no matter what.
I mean,
you could write an article about soccer
and you're going to have 100 people,
man.
Well,
so I didn't have to go out and raise any
money.
I,
I gave him the money to myself.
Well,
why can't you extend that argument and
say that if somebody would've given me,
if one person would have given me that
same $510,000,
that that person wouldn't have changed
the uh,
uh,
okay.
My contributor that gave me 150 grand
for good government.
Well he,
he had the ability to write,
you know,
he had the ability to give 510 grand
and,
and essentially get me elected.
Wouldn't
been.
Isn't that a good thing?
Well,
it's only a good thing if it's a good
guy,
but we don't know that it's a good guy.
We just know it's a rich guy.
And the amount of influence of that one
rich person has is very problematic to
regular pan should be part of the
equation on the analysis of is this
having an impact and who is it and how
much money have they given,
which currently,
um,
these super pacs,
100% non transparent.
Right?
But do you think the transparency
protects you from influence?
Like if it is transparent and you have
like one of the Koch brothers,
it's given all the money up.
You,
even if it's transparent,
you know what the hell their motivation
is.
They want to continue to extract massive
amounts of money.
Right.
Well,
if,
if it's one person that's giving all the
money,
then there's that much more scrutiny
that goes along with that person giving
that much more money.
And um,
and you,
you'd have to think,
uh,
that,
the influence wouldn't be as blatant as
it was if it was completely
nontransparent.
Yeah,
I'm a little skeptical.
I'm also right.
That's okay.
Wait,
what did you think when the Supreme
Court,
the decision to allow
corporations to donate as if they were
individuals?
It doesn't make much sense to me.
No,
it doesn't make much sense.
What do you think the motivation was for
that though?
Why would they pass something like that?
You know,
I am too far in the weeds,
but they did it and it just doesn't make
any sense.
It's kind of creepy though,
isn't it?
A little,
yeah,
I think so.
I like what you're saying.
I really liked this idea of abolishing
the irs a consumption tax.
I love the Iga of the fair tax,
check out the fair tax and,
and there are no fair taxes,
but like I say,
dot the i's and cross the t's on how you
accomplish one federal consumption tax.
To wrap this up,
I'm just going to give you the floor.
Just sell it,
sell it to the American people.
What is wrong,
what can be fixed and what can Gary
Johnson do to fix it?
I
want to make a pitch for myself and that
is,
is that I think I really am a unique
package.
Uh,
I am fiscally conservative.
Um,
I'm,
I'm as frugal a human being as you've
ever met,
but that doesn't mean that I'm cheap.
It just means that I spend my money
wisely.
I got to serve as governor of New Mexico
for two terms.
Uh,
I served as governor of New Mexico for
two terms as a Republican in the state
that's two to one democrat.
I got reelected by a bigger margin the
second time than the first time.
Made a name for myself as a real
government skeptic vetoing legislation.
I may have vetoed more legislation than
the other 49 governors in the country
combined.
Coupled with that,
um,
I'm socially tolerant.
I'm socially liberal.
Look,
you and I should be able to make
decisions in our own lives that only
affect our own lives as long as those
decisions don't adversely affect others.
And then there is a very real terrorist
threat out there.
It exists.
Um,
but I do believe that our military
interventions have resulted in making
situations worse,
not better.
So I'm a real skeptic when it comes to
government and the fact that government
is too big.
Uh,
I've been an entrepreneur my entire
life.
I know what it is to a hire and fire.
I know what it is to share in the
profits.
And what a magic formula that is that
when you share in the profits,
amazingly the profit pie grows
significantly.
Uh,
I've been an athlete my entire life.
Bit of an oxymoron is a 63 year old,
but what athletics has taught me is,
you know,
life is putting one foot in front of the
other.
Athletics has taught me that anything
that can go wrong will go wrong.
It's how you deal with failure that
ultimately determines your success.
Look,
things go wrong all the time.
You can crawl up on the couch,
uh,
you can declare yourself a victim.
You can give up,
or you can recognize that that's just
part of life and wake up the next day
with a smile on your face and continue
to move forward and just do your
best.
I've told,
I've told the truth.
Uh,
I think it's really hard to do any
damage to somebody who's willing to tell
the truth,
regardless of the consequences.
And then I admit mistakes.
I think mistakes have a way of,
so compounding themselves just because
people don't acknowledge those mistakes.
So given this pitch,
all I want to do is just get in,
uh,
the polls that determines who is in the
presidential debates.
I think that if I'm in the presidential
debates,
I have an opportunity of actually
winning because of this package that
you've allowed me to present here today.
Oh,
thank you.
Well,
I appreciate you coming on,
sir.
I really do.
It was a very enjoyable talking to you.
And,
uh,
I hope you win,
man.
I really do.
I hope you,
I hope you at least at the very least,
make enough headway to get people paying
attention to you and to get into the
Poles and just to listen to your
message.
And if I'm in the presidential debates,
that means I'm representing 25 million
people.
So what comes out of my mouth if I don't
end up getting more votes than the other
two candidates,
the one that does,
you know what?
They're not blind to the fact that,
Whoa,
this guy's sitting over here.
He's representing 25 million people
because he's in the debates.
So we better pick up a little bit on
what he has to say,
cause they're going to see some sense in
it also.
Anyway,
thank you,
Gary Johnson.
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you very much,
sir.
I really appreciate that.
Thank you.
Okay.
Yeah.