Isn't,
aren't they making James Bond a woman?
I think they are magazines by a woman.
I hope it's a black woman who's queer.
The only way for justice to be served
and nonbinary.
Yes,
but what does that mean?
She's.
Her gender can switch throughout the
film depending on,
on Binary gender flux.
Gender fluid.
I thought that was gender fluid.
Sorry,
what's your Pronoun Today?
Uh,
I'm always wanting to have a z in there.
Caesar.
Cool.
Yeah,
I feel like your highness.
Oh,
that's good.
That's good.
Yeah.
Your Highness can be a guy or a girl.
Whoa.
It's gender neutral.
Your Highness.
Now if you said I'm a princess,
I would go,
okay,
well you're gendering yourself.
That's true.
And I refused to do that.
I have two little boys and you know,
we forced them to be gender neutral.
They don't always watch a show on that.
A legit show on that from Cambridge.
This couple was raising their kid gender
neutral.
They have two kids and they're both like
wearing like whatever.
They're wearing weird clothes.
Like it didn't necessarily agree they're
wearing boys clothes or girls' clothes.
When they didn't call them girls or
boys,
they let them play with anything they
wanted and they didn't call them boys.
What would they say?
It was fucking weird.
It was just some poor guy who stuck with
some crazy bitch and she's,
you know,
and he was probably trying really hard
to be like progressive and like figure
out,
uh,
what,
you know,
how do we not gender our children and.
Yeah,
and it's interesting you do that voice
because they all do up speak at do the
only way to show your progressive
because if you didn't know it is
conservative,
people just don't talk like that.
No need to stop the caravan before it
gets to the wall.
Donald trumps our savior because he's
like the one who really appreciates like
American values and never hear that.
It's only,
it's only,
it's a super liberal calling.
It is.
Back to this non binary.
We,
we did a clip on your mom's house.
There was a couple somewhere in the
Netherlands and they had a three year
old zamzar child and another and every
day they would ask the three year old,
what gender do you feel like today?
And I'm talking about the pressure and
I'm like,
I have a almost three year old.
I'm pretty sure he doesn't know.
He doesn't think in terms of,
yeah,
he's like,
I don't know,
I'm whatever.
But to put the pressure like,
what are you today,
what are you feeling?
My eight year old loves to play with
things like race cars and she used to
love to play with trucks and she still
loves it.
She's a
friend.
She,
she,
she loves to play with superheroes and
things like that.
Like some of them are like very.
But then again she loves pink and she
likes getting her nails done and she
likes looking pretty and she's,
there's some cool shit that boys like
that girls like to like she's pretty
aggressive,
which takes MMA classes and she throws
boys around.
She gets like super hyped up when she
has to wrestle with boys.
She,
she,
it's crazy to watch,
like a little psycho aggressive eight
year old,
but she's also like really sweet,
like the sweetest kid.
Everybody just gets like real
competitive with that kind of stuff.
Yeah,
they say that that's the magic age
eight,
nine and girls and then a where they're
very confident.
It's like the end of the confidence era
and then puberty strikes and the
hormones takeover and the pressure.
Yeah.
To be sexy.
So Pippi longstocking that coolest
character.
Who was doing that shit.
Remember Pippi longstocking beating up
cops.
Shannon.
She had like a treasure trove.
So she was like,
she was a millionaire on her own.
Her Dad was a pirate.
Really?
Yeah,
I do remember those old Pippi
longstocking.
He's longstockings very much.
And remember the name.
I don't remember the narrative.
Oh,
she was great.
And it was subtitled,
poorly in her lips,
you know,
didn't match up with what she was
saying.
It was on channel five and la every
Sunday afternoon.
Where's it from?
Originally?
A Sweden,
I believe.
Astrid Lindgren wrote these books about
her daughter who was that age,
eight,
eight years old as a magic age.
There she is,
the original one who'd be long stockings
and she said,
girls are kind of smelly,
kind of awkward,
and that's before puberty robs you of
your,
uh,
you know,
fuck this new school I'm talking about.
Oh,
there she goes.
Just got a monkey.
Hey,
had a monkey.
I know you love monkeys.
Monkeys.
Is that a monkey?
A scarf?
Yeah,
I do choose bad.
She beat the shit out of people.
Wow.
But yeah,
I think I play with a boy stuff to my
dad.
I was raised by a single dad somewhat,
so he gave me like a bmx dirt bike and I
would write it in the La River,
you know?
And then I liked dolls too.
And that's what makes a female comics.
So you might have,
there's always something fucked up
because none of us,
none of us are normal.
That's a fact.
Find one that is.
I never met one
as much.
My husband.
I'm sorry.
Mr Polowski do you love it?
Garth Brooks is doing that.
Have you seen.
It's fucking hilarious.
What is that?
It's.
I think it's somebody.
People don't know what we're talking
about.
Okay,
so garth brooks,
who is infinitely talented.
I'm not saying the guy's not talented.
He's a mega,
mega,
mega star is he started doing social
media and it's
his fucking strange as can be.
It's so strange.
Yeah.
He doesn't quite know how to do.
I think someone was telling him like,
Hey,
just be personable,
be fun.
He just seemed so weird.
And Tom is like constantly on it.
Oh yeah.
We make fun of him relentlessly.
It is nonstop because he'll be like,
he'll be like,
hey everybody.
It's me garden.
I studio g and he has a thing called
studio g for golf.
Forgot our.
Her dog studio g cassette tape cassette
tape at his audience.
So in some fucking China as places he
really is.
And so he does these posts where he's
like,
it's a,
it's tricia's birthday.
That's why everybody's sent her pictures
of your favorite cupcakes.
Cupcakes with Hashtag Fun.
Hashtag Mr.
Hashtag gear it.
Doing him doing the Hashtag was rough.
Like what the fuck garth.
Your Mom's house is a fun show.
When I,
whenever I want just silly.
I tune in to you guys.
Thank you.
Because you rarely deviate from silly
nose.
It just just goofing off on shit all the
time.
It's always completely preposterous.
And this new guy that you guys have been
following the try it out.
Guy,
what the fuck can we play him?
Yes,
we can play out,
man.
This guy's guys.
This is a real guy.
I thousand percent real and by the way,
we loved you on your mom's house.
You fit right in.
Thank you and I hope you come back.
I would love to do it anytime.
Please.
Oh,
we're all in the neighborhood.
We're all close by.
Yeah.
It's only about farts and dicks and guys
who don't know how to ask for a lady's
affection properly.
Will you also find people online that
are just the most preposterous people?
So this is the guy.
Give me some volume in this guy,
this guy.
I think this is the right clip he's
looking for love.
There's also on,
if you type in,
I'm it.
I'm looking for hardcore guys to come to
my show.
Go play this guy.
If you're a hot black guy,
you want to fuck me at $23?
Ninety five.
If you want to move in,
you come move in with you gotta.
Fuck the I have any.
I need to be fucked a lot.
Then you get free food.
Free Rent and everything else,
man.
Here's the deal,
Men from jail,
homeless or um,
your thug.
Want to come?
Move in.
Frankenmuth man.
Free radical release in a k.
fuck me.
Piss.
Somebody beat me.
I'm home.
Yeah.
Now you see me when I come up with today
and try it out.
Try it out man.
It's my bills and try it out.
You gonna fucking pissed.
Let me try it out.
Has applied only as fuck,
man.
I'm looking at hard rock and ice and
Munich want to do it and I want to
deliver it.
I'm hot.
Buy
Trash.
Come dump.
Let's fuck white church.
Fuck.
Oh my God.
You got to see them folks just
listening.
You gotta see this guy,
the fucking sincerity in his eyes and
he's saying this thing needs to.
Watching your face.
Watch the tryout was probably my
favorite thing in life.
What did I do?
It was like a look of like,
oh,
like it made you sad.
Did it for him?
It didn't make you feel like it made you
feel.
I didn't feel sad.
It's weird that I looked sad.
Maybe I.
Maybe I'm hiding that.
I'm sad to myself.
Maybe I'm hiding it from myself,
but this guy really needs it and he
really puts it out there.
Try it out.
I'm pissed off.
I'm a white trash.
Like,
whoa buddy.
Anybody men from jail.
Just an animated version of it.
So it started a flurry of animated.
Try it out guys.
And then people started to submit their
own.
Takes these.
There's Tommy.
Don't try stupid.
I don't care how many fucking free food.
Free writes from jail,
man.
Dog want to come.
True,
man.
Free.
Radical.
Lisa Kay.
Fuck me.
Piss.
Somebody beat me at home.
Yeah.
Now you can rewind it just a little bit.
Jamie.
He goes,
he goes,
piss on me.
Pissed off.
Beat me home.
You know what's that?
What's that?
Homey.
Mel,
what do you think he said?
Good question.
One more time.
Right?
Fuck me.
Piss somebody beat me home.
You know,
you see me more?
What does it?
We'd have to go through that.
Like this approved or film?
Well,
what do you hear?
My now seem like a word to me.
Home home.
Home.
Man.
Out.
Fuck me.
But somebody beat me.
I know right now.
What is that?
Whoa.
Whoa,
whoa man.
Whoa.
A man out is one that again,
maybe that's it.
Fuck me.
Piss.
Somebody beat me home.
Yeah.
Now these could be anything.
Now.
Just another language.
Holeman.
Yet we were like working for the
government and we're trying to decipher
the tape.
Like we have to find out where the
kidnappers are being held home and now
they have to like strip the audio.
I hear a train in the distance.
We will be audio experts in a room
somewhere.
We've got it.
We've got whole man out.
Whole man out hold,
man man.
Oh Man.
Out Prostitute.
It could be or it could be.
I'm home.
I'm home here now because he gives out
his address.
He goes,
no.
One more time at 23,
95 and we cut it off.
We cut it out for beat me home now.
These could be anything.
I'm home,
homey on now.
Anyway,
huge debate in my mom's house community.
Um,
there's no final answer on.
You'd have to talk to him.
Have you reached out to him?
We've tried,
yeah.
There's a few of your mom's house stars
I believe in.
Um,
oh my gosh.
Maybe on the east coast somewhere.
Sorry,
I don't sleep very much.
Yeah.
Um,
we've reached out to him.
I'm three months deep in the game,
Bro.
I'm going crazy.
Him and I can't ask.
Rubber won't respond and we've reached
out with offers of money and really not
there.
You won't do it.
And it's so weird.
It's always the ones we want the most.
That never quite the king would be just
farting in your room though in.
Oh yeah.
Would you want that?
I'd like to talk to him in the room.
What it does,
right?
He farts all the time.
Yeah.
But I'm curious,
what's the drive like?
He's clearly not driven by sex because
that's really re repellent to women or
maybe maybe like for him it's a turn on
to fart.
Like even though it's probably
disgusting to women,
maybe for him it's a turn on to be
disgusting.
Ah,
the repulsion.
Thanks.
So she's like,
oh my God,
you're so nasty.
And then she's.
Yeah,
there's like some boys who were spanked
for shitting their pants and stuff when
they were young,
they developed this weird thing about
shit like being naughty and they even
connect sexually.
Being Naughty was shit and farts and
things like that.
Fetish.
That's.
They say that's how the fetish starts,
right?
Chris Ryan was trying to explain it to
me.
So one day Dr Chris Ryan from a sex at
dawn,
the book,
and he was saying that there's an
imprinting stage in young men's lives
were like the a young man that's not
gay,
like say during this imprinting stage
when they're very young,
if they get their dick sucked by a guy
and they,
they orgasm,
they could potentially get turned on by
guy sucking their dick even if they're
not gay because it's imprinted on them
at a very early age.
Like by them getting molested at an
early age.
It fucks with their sexual,
like what in their mind is considered
sexual pleasure.
Yeah.
I can see that the wires get crossed
early and maybe you're attracted and
repulsive at the same time to the man.
And I don't know if I'm gay or I kind of
want to do this,
but I don't want to do you.
You were molested,
but yet you're also turned on.
Yeah,
shame a lot of fame,
I'm sure attached to that too.
Oh,
for sure.
Yeah.
And a lot of anger.
You know what's really strange is when
you go back through history,
how often men were having sex with young
boys.
I know the Greeks love to do that.
Romans,
Greeks,
many,
many different ancient civilizations
thought it was normal for men to have
young boys,
as you know,
as sex partners.
Fucking the fucking strange.
Yeah.
And then the Christians right in the
Christians come along and they're like,
wait a minute,
we will show you how to do this.
Only with priests.
Only the elite gets a rape children.
Uh,
it is crazy.
To this day,
my most shocked that I ever am when
people get upset at me is want to shit
on.
Catholicism is want to shit on child
molesting.
I'm like,
what are we pretending that this shit
isn't happening constantly.
I mean,
if,
if they were anything else,
like say it was the NBA,
the NBA was traveling around just
fucking kids.
They're playing basketball.
They're fucking kids.
Like who would say,
yeah,
but the man,
they played good basketball,
fucking Dunkin that lay out show three
pointers from the outside.
They are playing some serious basketball
and sometimes they fucked some kids.
Oh,
I typed in with Catholic priests.
There's three different stories in three
different spots.
Buffalo,
Catholic diocese.
How do you say the diocese diocese,
new list of priests accused of sexual
abuse.
Yup.
Catholic priest react to clergy sex
abuse.
Meeting with Bishop Malone,
Catholic priests removed from ministry
in Oklahoma.
This is just one day's worth.
Then there was that thing in
Philadelphia that was just last month.
Where was it?
A thousand different kids had been
molested by these priests.
Yeah.
Thousand different children in
Pennsylvania.
Like what in the fuck folks,
so why are they protected from law?
Like I know,
because in the church you said they
moved them around,
right?
Yeah.
The archdiocese or whoever goes,
yeah,
that guy's a pedophile and let's just
move them to a different thing.
They're protected because people believe
in God.
in Christianity.
Yeah,
and they.
They don't.
They don't want to attack priests
because they feel like that's an attack
on the church and they feel like there's
going to be blow back politically and
they're worried about it because people
have this need for church and they're,
they're.
They're terrified.
If someone comes along and says,
hey,
we're going to do like as the
international is going to do a full
scale investigation into the Catholic
Church and we're going to lock people
up.
That's the reason why the Vatican has
its own country.
You know the Vatican,
you have to have a fucking passport.
Like it's an actual country separate
entities,
little tiny ass place filled with kid
fuckers.
Like if you looked at the per capita kid
fuckers of people in the Vatican,
you'd be like,
oh my God,
it's a nation of kid fuckers so fucked
up and they're in untouchable.
Well for now,
but eventually people are gonna.
Realize how irrelevant a lot of these
ancient fucking cults actually are.
Whether you believe in whether you
believe in God or not.
Those are cults are ancient cults.
Whether you believe in the scripture or
not,
the Catholic church is clearly a cult.
It's a cult that I was a part of.
I mean,
I went to Catholic school.
My,
my family was Catholic.
I'd been around it my whole life.
Nobody ever molested me and the church,
but I got lucky.
I know I got lucky,
I know people that got molested.
I have friends that told me stories,
but being chased by priests and I have
friends that told me stories about a guy
that they knew that got molested,
like damn,
he got them.
He got them like they knew about this
priest and he got one of their friends
and this is just all across the country
and the,
the numbers that went to justice so
small,
so small in comparison to the actual
acts.
It's,
it's really crazy that people would get
upset at you saying this.
Like it's,
it's crazy,
right?
Like,
let me defend my pedophile priests.
Like I love this guy.
Like,
what?
Why are we still invested in this?
And you know,
I have been ever since I had kids too,
I,
I kind of see the world a lot
differently,
you know?
And I,
before I had children I was like,
sure,
you know,
God could exist.
I'm spiritual and now I'm like,
I just got to defend my children from
the fucking evil and insanity of this
world.
And it's jungle law.
And like I,
I don't know,
I don't,
I'm not spiritual really.
People can go bad for sure.
There's,
there's something about people that when
it goes wrong,
you know,
whatever,
for whatever reason,
people can go back,
they can go bad serial killer style,
they can go bad rapist style.
I mean,
how many guys are out there dropping
pills into girls drinks,
still still,
still hundred,
100 percent.
It's happening all across the country,
all across the world.
All the time.
There's just fucking disgusting human
beings.
There's bad people out there and there's
people that got fucked over and they
want to pay people back.
You know,
they're upset,
they're upset that they got a shit deal
and they want,
they want other people to suffer.
Yeah,
it's traumatized people,
right?
Doing all this shit traumatize people.
It was definitely some of that.
But that makes me also too,
like I always laugh at the,
uh,
the anti bullying stuff.
Like I'm not pro bullying clearly,
but it's such a misguided effort to try
to completely eradicate the world of
bullet.
We're going to stop like,
no,
you're not dude,
because you have to stop stupid if
you're going to stop the bullying
because stupid people have kids.
They don't raise the kids.
Well,
those kids are angry because they have
stupid parents and they're being abused
at home and then they hit your kid and
so what'd you can do is teach your kid
to not be a victim and to fucking kick a
guy in the nuts,
but now we don't teach that to children
to defend yourself and then your kid
would be the problem.
You have to show a reason to express
violence.
God dammit.
Yeah,
there's,
there's a time for violence and that
time is when you're defending yourself
because someone is fucking with you and
if you don't do something,
they're gonna do something to you.
There's times when no one's there to
save you.
That's real,
and if you don't teach your kids that,
they're going to be real confused.
If that moment does arise,
they're going to look around for someone
to save them and there's no one there.
Exactly,
and that's very unfortunate.
No one wants it,
you know?
No one wants that to be the case,
but it is the case.
It's a reality.
You know,
if you just,
if you're just around a bunch of bad
people and you hope that nothing goes
wrong,
it's,
that's not an effective way to prepare
yourself for what could happen.
That's the thing about having kids,
right?
You start thinking of the world.
It's been like this like danger written
place.
It's,
it becomes a different world.
Fucking cess pool.
Yeah,
and especially with the Internet now you
can see exactly who's crazy before you
were like,
I don't know,
people are generally okay and then
you'll see the fucking try it out guy
and you're like,
oh my gosh,
beat on me.
Try it out.
Bring your friends.
They can live here to doug asking for
thugs to fuck them and piss on them,
but you get a and a key.
Yeah.
But he also wants him to beat them.
Beat me,
piss on me.
That's the problem.
Like how much of that do I have to do to
have to fuck you?
Or can I just go over and kick your ass?
You take anything,
he would take it as a guy.
You can go over his house and just fuck
them up.
There is,
but yeah,
but once you punch hima couple times
going to go,
fuck me.
Now.
They're like,
no,
no.
I'm just going to beat you up.
I'm just here for the beating man.
Fuck you up.
Have you ever.
I mean,
not at that level.
We're talking about goes lately on your
mom's house.
We've been featuring desperate dude who
are like making videos like this to try
to court a lady or a gentleman,
but maybe kind of misguided,
like not,
yeah,
let's try it out or whatever.
Whatever.
I'm fucking horny.
Like we know you're horny bro.
You can't just come out and say I'm
really horny coming fog maybe with other
dudes.
Yeah.
Like,
but a woman's not going to respond.
Yeah.
Women.
That's why.
Why playgirl didn't really work.
We don't want to look at Dick's.
Playgirl was for Dudes,
right?
Scores.
What were those dating services like in
the eighties where you'd pay?
I mean it was like a joke on mad TV.
Your snl were like the past tapes and I
could make a video,
a video dating profile.
Did that ever work or is it only keep
the guys too?
Yeah.
People that need a dating services.
Back in the eighties,
those people were losers.
I mean people.
Most people just found somebody.
Okay.
Bars go somewhere like a normal fucking
person.
You meet people fucking Weirdo,
but nowadays it's way more common
because of like tinder and normal folks
do.
A Chris Rock was talking about being on
dating apps.
Chris Rock's on dance.
Well,
I think he has a girlfriend now,
but for a while,
yeah,
he was on dating apps and someone was
like,
why would you do that?
You're Chris Rock.
He goes,
because I'm Chris Rock was like.
He was joking around about it.
It's like the how.
This is a great way to meet them.
Now they know who I am.
Pam.
That's right.
And there's like celebrity ones,
right?
Like you just.
You just exclusive to celebrities.
So there's some celebrity,
one where you just date and gold
diggers.
Just girls to get same as future reality
stars,
future housewives of Beverly Hills.
Those fucking crazy bitches.
So my mother,
her second husband,
they met on a dating ad in the back of
like an Indian newspaper.
My mother,
like Indian guys Indian.
Like,
like from Punjab.
Yeah.
I always answered you in Hungarian.
Yes.
Enza.
So she put an ad,
Indian guys,
Indian men.
So her thing was she,
she believed that Indian men were more
educated overall.
She liked them.
I liked them.
Tall,
dark and handsome.
She was a Hungarian lady and uh,
she,
she just thought that they had more,
more money and more smarts,
so show me the money and she wanted to
be wiped up and taken care of.
So she put an ad in the back of the hunt
Indian newspaper.
She said Buxom some European woman
looking for.
Was it wealthy?
Indian guy from marriage?
Dude,
we got a bag of letters,
like a bag from every Indian dude in the
La County.
And she sent a picture of himself in an
Armani suit.
This is like 1989 with his Mercedes.
All school cell phones like that big ass
one.
And she was like,
that's the one they were married one
month later.
That's my boy fucking cell phone for the
Wall Street movie.
I remember Michael Douglas Walking
around with that brick on the beach
balling so hard.
He's talking to people.
He didn't give a fuck about his cell
phone.
Bill was just talking to people on the
beach.
Yeah.
Did you have one of those memory in your
car?
The old school had one that was in the
car.
It was connected to the car.
It was like permanently in the car.
It was on the floor.
It was bolted in.
And then I would,
I could make a phone call from the
Indian.
That speakerphone.
I can talk.
I driving speakerphone in 1988 Honda
crx.
I was a little tiny thing.
Michael Douglas.
I didn't have one of those.
That was two baller from me.
I think mine,
uh,
I could take out and put in a suitcase
too,
if I remember correctly.
Yeah,
that's pretty dope.
Maybe not.
Maybe another one.
Maybe I got another one afterwards.
It was like a suitcase one.
Do you?
My Dad had a Jag in the eighties and the
he had like a tiny tv,
put it on the radio.
They had tiny little square television
is black and white and I could watch
watch cartoons
on the way to school and I was like,
this is the future.
We're all going to have tvs in our cars
and my kids zone out when they get in my
car because
my lexus has these things in the back
seat where there's like a little ipad on
the back screen and watch a screen.
It's like a 10 inch screen on the back
headrest.
So they.
They watch movies.
It's the for kids like those rear
entertainment systems.
If you have a long trip like see if you
got to drive to San Francisco.
That's three movies.
That's all that is.
What do you guys want to watch now?
You guys hungry.
Who has to pee?
We got to pull over.
There's no fighting is watching movies.
Otherwise it would be.
She's touching me with her feet.
Stop it.
Stop touching me.
I can't wait for all that.
Yeah,
that's great.
I can't wait.
It's fascinating.
You know,
and then you see like other people's
really shitty handiwork in terms of like
the way they're raising their kids,
like oh my goodness,
tell me about it because I'm only at a
three year old and a three month old,
so I'm just now in the kind of the
preschool and I see other parents and
I'm like,
this is what you got to be careful of.
You've got to be careful of the parents
that liked to go to parties and they
leave their kid outside with other kids
and they go inside and drink and they
don't watch their kid at all and it's
usually,
it's usually boys.
People are boys and the boys usually
wind up hitting kids and what's going on
is that kid is not getting any fucking
attention and not getting any parental
guidance and they're just loose and
wild.
And I've had this incident happened more
than once,
but one of them agreed honestly with
this kid hit both of my kids and one of
them more than once and the parents are
still inside drinking,
pulling hair in their little.
They're like six.
And they're like,
Yo man,
you got to watch your kid.
He's aggressive.
He's a good kid.
He's always a good kid.
You don't even know you're in here.
Drunk your kids out there jumping around
in a fucking trampoline,
beaten kids in the head,
stepping on their hair like literally
the kid was like a little aggressive kid
called another kid a loser and pushed
him,
called him a loser.
What kid call someone a loser.
Someone who gets called to loser at
home.
Yes.
Will someone's calling someone a loser
in front of that kid.
Six year old calling people losers.
And every now and then I see the
parents.
I'm like,
Jesus Christ,
just kind of get the fuck away from
them.
I had to have a conversation with the
dad and he's trying to tell me his kid's
a good kid.
I'm like,
okay,
your kid's a good kid.
I tell them,
you,
your kid pushed kid and called him a
loser at that didn't happen.
Oh,
it didn't happen.
All right man,
I don't know what to do other than what
I want to do,
which is freak out.
I want to freak out.
And start yelling at you,
you fucking asshole.
You drunk piece of shit in here.
You're not even paying attention to your
kid.
You got a bad kid.
You got a kid that you haven't been
paying attention to your.
These are older people and they had a
kid late in life.
They are barely paying attention.
One kid not really into it.
Let's just roam.
Just let them roam.
Yeah,
that ain't cool.
Especially get a lot of that shit and
I'm going to go get kids that have cell
phones at like six years old.
I've heard this.
And then these little fucking sluts.
Send your boys a naked picture picks and
then my boys
accountable.
If he sends it to another kid,
got dirty little slots.
Now how am I going to get these stuff?
These hoes I got stopped the boys.
That's what to stop the boys from
sending pictures.
Tell them,
tell them about the law and definitely
tell them no pictures of your Dick.
Fuck,
I don't even know who's doing it as an
adult sending your dick to a fuck.
I don't know.
There's not one way to find them because
how long have you been with your lady
now?
Long enough to not send her any
pictures.
If I sent her dicks.
It's other people's like,
what do you think of that?
Do you get sent Dick Pics from Tom?
Tom will send me whatever red hen or a
girl.
It's.
I think that that is one of the most
misguided things ever.
Like the random Dick pick the guys that
don't even know a girl will send,
but that's the thing too is like it goes
back to what women don't want.
Like I'm not like sweet cock,
like get over it and also like if a girl
just sends you a picture of her pussy,
like Whoa,
how many people she's sending that
picture to paint that picture.
If you could like go,
go through her phone and if there's a
record of how many times have pictures
been?
Said a girl says pussy pictures.
She's sending them to everybody.
She's just,
she's just scattershot.
Just shooting into the cosmos.
Bang,
Bang.
Someone's gonna.
Someone's gonna be into it.
Some chick.
Is that the thing?
He does it because it's worked.
Some somebodies going to be like,
oh yeah,
that's the one.
How many.
There are so many thirsty girl pages of
like girls sticking their butts out,
girls in underwear.
There's so many of those pages,
like thirst traps,
but there's not that many for guys.
Just like a few guy bodybuilder type.
Third laughter show me right now.
You know,
they're people.
They're real people who know their
thirst traps,
like dudes looking for Dick or dudes
looking for girls.
The ones I've seen,
it's,
there's.
Yeah.
Okay,
I'll,
we'll do it on.
There's a few choice ones kind of outing
these losers.
Well,
my favorite.
Okay.
My favorite trap though is the girl that
puts it out there and then when the guys
are like nice to it would,
you know,
and in some respects and then they get
mad.
Like don't just look at me for my tits.
Like well probably,
you know,
you kinda didn't.
She is not the reaction you were kind of
looking for and it's like you put your
boobs out there.
I mean,
I don't do that because I don't want
people to write that stuff,
you know,
it's kind of not on my agenda.
Well,
we want a very specific reaction,
which you don't necessarily.
You're not entitled to a specific
reaction.
You're entitled to nothing.
You get reactions,
you're entitled to nothing distinction.
When you put photos of your tests,
your ass on the Internet,
you're not entitled to anything.
You're not entitled to respect.
Do you mean total to anything?
And I want to give away your bit,
but you'd discuss Megan Kelly,
you can give it away.
It's already out,
right?
Okay.
I just didn't know.
Some people haven't watched it yet,
which is a fan.
It's an amazing special.
But uh,
yeah,
but she's on a news channel,
not dressed like a newsperson vagina.
Kurt and I have a friend who,
I didn't know this until after the
special came out,
she came up to me and said that she used
to work with Meghan Kelly Fox News shoes
to be one of her assistants.
And she was like,
she would tell the,
the wardrobe people to make the dress is
shorter.
Like that's too long.
Make that dress shorter.
Wow.
Well she knew that she.
But she was cute.
She knew.
I wish I could tell she was so hot back
then.
I mean,
she's still a beautiful woman,
but God damn,
during like 10,
15 years ago,
she was a fucking smoke show,
man.
She's a gorgeous woman and I don't hate
on women for being 30 and bought hate.
I don't hate on him for fucking using it
either.
Just like I don't hate on Arnold
Schwartzenegger for being a bodybuilder,
you know,
depending on how you present yourself,
that's kind of what you are.
You're not entitled to any specific
reaction.
You're going to get reactions and people
are entitled look,
as long as they're not threatening you
or you know,
physically doing anything to what
they're doing is reacting to what you're
putting out.
They don't have any obligation to react
the way that you would like.
No,
no,
not at all.
Look,
tits and ass.
I'd like to just those ass tits and your
mouth right now.
You're a picture on my phone and I'm
jerking off to like,
what's wrong with you?
You don't,
you don't know.
I just,
I,
yeah,
I guess I never,
I never led with that.
Good.
But not because I'm A.
I'm not.
Listen,
I'm just as thirsty as is that bitch.
Were strippers to comedians are fucking
strippers,
like we want the attention,
but I don't want it for this.
I prefer to get it for my mind or
wherever.
Whatever it is.
I'd prefer to get it from.
Well,
it's,
it's a difference,
right?
It's this,
this tripper thing comes from for sure,
a variety of different places.
There's definitely women that are
strippers that are doing it just because
they're pretty and it's a good way to
make a lot of money.
It's a great way to make a lot of money
fast from what I understand.
Nothing wrong with it.
The other wrong with it,
but there's also ones that are doing it
because they have sorbent need for
attention,
an extraordinary need for sexual
attention and a lot of them had been
molested and that's more the case with a
porn stars.
Apparently.
There's some crazy study on porn.
Stars were there,
there were going over,
just,
you know,
they did like a random survey and went
to them and ask them how many of them
have been molested.
It was like 10.
It was like some crazy number.
It's like when you,
when you're watching people fuck on
camera and you know,
a lot of people watch it.
I mean,
I would,
I would imagine the vast majority of
males specifically watch porn or some
kind of porn and you're,
you're essentially watching the product
of either a completely sexually
liberated,
liberated woman who likes doing that,
which is possible.
Sure.
Allegedly,
some like Dr.
drew doesn't believe it's possible at
all.
Can I tell you?
Yeah,
I,
I've heard this argument,
the impairment.
I read a book even from a woman who who
said yeah,
this is from an empowerment angle.
She'd gotten into an ivy league school
and wanted to pay for it.
It definitely exists in the world.
However,
in my experience,
experience and estimation,
I would say it's likely lasted and then
that's what you mean.
It's possible,
right?
It's not probable.
So if you're a woman out there that's so
sexually liberated person who enjoys
doing porn is you don't have any more
molestations and your past,
you're getting upset right now,
will we knowledge we acknowledge that
you exist,
not trying to diminish your perspective,
but it's just,
it's an odd thing that,
that leads to all this sex.
And then it's also an odd thing when you
look at the sheer volume of people
fucking uh,
like for a living that's a lot of
foreign born and I have to say it can't
be that lucrative anymore because of the
Internet to have a joke about it where I
was like,
I need to bring it back and figured out
how to do it correctly because I kind of
abandoned it.
But the premise was who's seen all the
porn?
Like why are they making new porn porn?
Like,
what are you guys doing?
You fucking,
you suck everybody's fucking sucking.
Like if you are you just looking to beat
off,
are you wasting your whole life will
look like super specific scenes.
Doggish down.
I want to be able to see her feet,
the back of her feet.
I wonder if in a certain position like
take a break,
take a week off,
but apparently there is a need for it
because they're making it and people are
consuming this really these niche lanes.
Right.
Well I think it has to do with the fact
that people are always ramping up and
like if you,
if you give person a car that has 150
horsepower,
they want a car that is 200 horsepower
and then next year that car better be
faster than the year after that.
A better breathe better.
And then he after that and they were
constantly trying to get that new
charge,
like the iphone.
And so if it's just regular sex.
Okay.
Wow.
I can't believe I'm watching this
regular sex.
Wow.
I'd like to see in an hd.
Okay,
why don't you come in her face?
Okay.
What's tickling her ass?
Then come her face.
Whoa.
Now we're getting crazy and this is
where it all goes.
Like asked to mouth and gagging,
gagging,
all that crazy shit comes from people
like watching so much porn than just
regular stuff's not doing it anymore.
They want to.
They want to grow to be smacked.
They want to come out of her mouth,
tears to come out of her eyes.
They want all that stuff that's.
And like,
I don't fucking get it,
but it,
it's,
it's this psychological trait that
people have is ramping up the bigger,
better deal.
Constantly wanting something more
extreme violent movies today,
like Julie and I were talking about the
extra sister the other day,
which is extremely violent,
terrifying movie for the time,
but stay.
It would be so boring.
Wasn't he talking about the girl,
Linda Blair who played that Shit fucked
up now.
A dog.
There's no way.
He was thinking crucifixes in your pussy
and your normal now.
God,
he always has the best take on share.
Right?
I think Linda Blair was kind of fucked
up from that.
Admittedly force let me.
She was like 12 years old doing that
movie,
Ram it up across in her pussy.
Of course,
John Jesus.
Jesus traumatize me and it was sound and
the King of the Greens and you forget
how slow that movie is.
Like watch it now and the pacing of it,
you're like,
holy,
let's get to something.
You know,
because now it's,
I don't even watch the shit now.
Scary movies,
but it's way more.
Uh,
did you see the new Halloween?
No,
it didn't,
but I heard it's good.
Who saw Tony?
Tony Hinchcliffe loved it.
He said it was awesome.
He said she's a bad ass and she's a
Jamie Lee Curtis is like preparing for
when he returns and she lives in a
compound box,
got fucking guns and shit.
And she's like the locked and loaded
ready to fuck up.
Michael Myers becomes out of the grave
again.
I love it.
Like that.
Terminator check.
Remember when she was working out
waiting for him.
The names everybody.
Linda Hamilton.
I have a,
a millennial babysitter who works for us
and I was like,
Hey,
did you,
did you know that Jamie Lee Curtis was a
Hermaphrodite?
And she goes,
it's intersects now.
And I was like,
oh,
interesting.
But is that true about Jamie Lee?
Curtis,
my gynecologist says it is true.
Go to college.
This might be a piece of shit.
Allegedly I actually knew was like,
yeah,
tell everybody.
Well tell everybody I saw it.
It's a guy and he says,
yeah,
that she in fact was and they cut off
the painter and she was so hot when she
was young.
She was a hot,
gorgeous,
statuesque,
gorgeous wiggle and google,
Google real.
The problem with the real estates is
then you have a couple of kids and you
breastfeed.
Then they turn into sloppy hangers,
which is what I got.
I got to do something about it.
You're going to fill them up.
Am I going to fill them up?
I'm going again.
I'm a lifted and just put in the same
place they were and maybe reduce steven.
Yeah.
I don't like big.
It's no fun when you really have an ex
who had a big old today's.
She was born with them and they were so
bad,
but when I met her she had already had a
breast reduction.
She is still a pretty big old titties,
but she just was,
you know,
she had like double f's just naturally.
Those are big.
Yeah.
But they were also like,
it was so annoying because it's all guys
would see big giant tits coming their
way.
Poor girl.
Yeah.
She said she had back problems to do a
lot of pilots to strengthen the back,
to keep my tits up,
keep them strong.
Yeah.
You got to keep going to keep the frame
that holds the tits.
Keep all that frame locked up every
place.
There's nothing like that for dudes.
Right?
With kids too big.
Like no dudes are out there getting Dick
Reduction.
So you know what dudes do get though.
Here's the thing,
man.
I've been fucking.
I got a pro.
I turn on TV once,
just a couple months ago and I just
stumbled upon this show called botched.
Yes.
I like this.
This is on the channel.
Yes.
Pretty sure.
Yeah.
So maybe maybe I want to these.
What is it on?
Seems More Bravo because it's super
good.
I know,
I love it.
There's a lot.
There's,
there's this one guy who was on who was
helping the guy that got like surgery.
Yeah,
and the guy who was helping,
the guy who got started,
one guy was getting surgery because he
got his peck replaced.
He had to like a peck problem.
That seems crazy to me.
Well he,
he was actually,
he had like some sort of an accident
where he lost his pack.
So the game of Pec implant seemed pretty
normal.
He looked better.
He was pretty happy,
but the guy who he was working with him,
I don't know what relationship they had
in the scene where this guy was the
doctor or what it was.
This guy was like a plastic man,
like his forehead was locked down.
It wasn't going nowhere.
It was botox to the oblivion.
He had cheek shots and his facial
fillers.
His eyebrows had been done.
He had fake Tan.
He had.
That's.
There you go.
That's the guy.
Definitely heterosexual.
Well,
whatever he is,
he has all these implants.
He has implants in his chest and
implants in his biceps and he was doing
all that like to look good.
Somebody was joking around about how
even though it has all these implants,
he's still not strong so it couldn't do
a chin up.
I'm like,
this is so crazy.
Like this person is this.
But he was the one that was helping the
other guy through plastic surgery.
He was helping the other guy,
the other guy who had a problem,
peck implant came out normal,
just had a peck problem and then filled
it in and then it looked like,
oh yeah,
look at the guys got to Pex now.
Boy.
But that show is insane.
You see these people that get this sort
of,
um,
what's that word for it?
This morphea bodybuilders get it and
erect six,
get
it.
You know,
girls who have double f tits and then
want a bigger.
I haven't,
I've done botox twice in my life.
I'm always reluctant to go back just
because like,
who am I fooling?
I'm 42 years old.
It's okay.
I'm not.
What is it doing to you?
What does it,
what does.
So they paralyzed.
They put botulism in your face,
which is why I'm also reluctant because,
you know,
that shit's not been studied really.
I mean,
come on.
How do we know what's going to happen?
So I got a wrinkle here,
so they'll put it here and they freeze
the muscle at paralyzes it.
So you can't make,
you can't scowl scour.
Scour.
That's my.
What the fuck is going online?
I got the same one.
Got It.
Uh,
so at paralyze it.
So you can't do the gesture that creates
the wrinkles.
So it's more of a preemptive measure.
So you should start doing early is what
they say,
right?
But what about being a comic and making
expressions?
That's the problem.
So when you're on stage,
you end up getting migraines because you
can't because you.
Yeah.
Move your eyebrows.
I'm surprised with squares on welcome.
I make my eyes water.
You want to see a show?
There's a show on netflix where people
go to Thailand for cheap plastic
surgery.
Don't do it.
Have you been in Thailand?
Never have yelled.
Awesome.
Yeah,
it just went to summer camp,
the whole family.
Where did you go?
Chiang Mai.
Where's that?
It is a northern Thailand.
It's really close to where those kids
got trapped in the cave.
Oh yeah.
We got there right after they got
rescued,
so it's happy times.
Thailand is dope though.
The people are so friendly and the food
was amazing.
That's what I hear.
We took cooking classes.
We hung out with elephants and an
elephant sanctuary.
That was pretty bad ass on your
instagram.
Elephants are sweet.
They're so nice.
They're so kind.
You get super nervous around him when
you first around them because they're so
goddamn big.
But then afterwards you realize like
they're just gentle giants there.
They're so sweet.
And these animals at this one place that
we went to,
it's a rehabilitation place,
so they would take animals that had been
to the circus and they'd been harmed or
mistreated and they'd bring them back
and they even released them into the
wild.
Wow.
That's cool.
Yeah,
because they wander around with them in
the woods,
like we took them for this long hike
where you ride them all through the
woods,
so it was like a couple miles who went
and they just stop and eat things so
they don't have to worry about feeding
them.
They're are fucking pretty confident
that they know what to eat.
They just grab leaves and starts shoving
them in the trunk and then they shit and
piss and you can't believe the volume.
The you hear the logs hit the ground.
You're like,
what is happening?
And then you look down there shit and
you're like,
oh my God.
It was just was just bushels of shit.
Boom,
boom,
boom clubs,
heavy.
Just giant clumps of broken down.
Vegetable matter.
They're herbivores.
Yeah,
that's all they eat.
They're so sweet though.
Dillard up to you rub their head and
they like,
you actually kind of bond with them
because you feed them sugar cane.
Like when you get to know them,
you wash them.
The first thing they have you do is you
wash them and you feed them.
So we're,
I think we fed them first.
Then washed them and we have these like
just big piles of sugarcane and you hand
them these pieces of sugarcane is
chewing,
crunch it and swallow it,
and then they and they take it from you,
like real gentle.
It was a fucking 2000 plus pound animal,
whatever the hell it is.
Probably bigger than that and there's so
kind,
just like real easy.
They know they walk around you,
they don't try to knock you over there.
Just real relaxed.
They help you get up if you want to ride
them,
lift their arm up so you can step on the
arm and then you climb onto their back.
Are you going to get a pet elephant?
No,
but they're.
They're interesting animals.
They really are.
They're.
They're really sweet and this area that
we're at,
they.
They actually have elephants that live
in Thailand.
They actually live in the wild because
not that many of them,
but they've introduced,
I think they said seven new ones to the
wild from this sanctuary,
so it was pretty.
It was pretty bad ass,
but it's interesting that you get to see
them where they're.
They're free,
they're free roaming,
they roam all around that area.
They're not in pens,
they're not captive.
They're basically just freely roaming
and then they feed them and take care of
them and they know the food's going to
be there and then they just eventually
get them to the point where they can be
free again.
Oh Nice.
That was pretty bad ass.
But.
But the people were so friendly,
so nice.
See this on that show because they're
always smiling.
They're super,
they're really friendly.
Like you run into that all,
all throughout the country.
People super friendly.
Like don't elephants gestate for like
years.
Yeah.
Long time something.
Something like that.
To be pregnant for that long.
I Know God count myself.
How about getting fucked by another
elephant?
Could you have never seen it?
Have I seen an elephant deck?
I don't think so.
Does it come out of a sheet?
I'm sure.
Like that head and the alien with
Whitley strieber.
Not Whitley strieber.
Sigourney weaver,
striper.
Willis' driver's Whitley strieber.
As the guy who was behind,
he wrote,
he's an author.
It's the whole store is really suspect.
He wrote,
uh,
that movie,
what was the movie?
He wrote it.
He wrote up one of those alien movies,
an alien abduction movies,
and he wrote it that it was based on his
own life that it actually happened.
The problem was he was already this
fiction novelist who's writing these
wild stories and they decided to say
this one's real and it got all sorts of
traction,
but you know,
it's all like being abducted in the
middle of the night and taken out of his
bed by aliens and brought to ships and
scientific experiments like that kind of
stuff.
Cool.
Do you think there's aliens doing that
kind of stuff?
I don't think they care about your,
but
that's the weirdest thing is that they
have to go up your butt.
It's always a homoerotic sort of fantasy
and anal fantasy with the alien.
Why does it always turn sexual?
I think because if you're paralyzed,
the number one fear is that someone's
going to put something up.
Your bought
were out at the time.
I,
yeah,
I don't,
I don't do,
but stuff for that re unlike.
The other thing is,
um,
I think a combined with the other thing
is I think they worry people worry about
being impregnated or having their baby
taken them.
Oh yeah.
The aliens.
That's a common theme too.
I'd be afraid of that.
Have you been to Roswell,
New Mexico?
No,
I have not.
I went there for some TV show I worked
on like a decade ago.
And they,
you know,
they claim that's where the,
the aliens is that they live with.
That's where the crash happened in 1947.
When I say that there's like a museum
you can go to and see.
I don't know,
whenever I bought a tee shirt,
it was great.
Yeah.
The whole story is super suspect.
The story of what happened.
It's like a,
there was some records they found.
They flew the wreckage in two separate
planes to Wright Patterson Air Force
Base and Truman actually met them.
They're like,
whatever the fuck did crash.
It was,
have enough importance that Truman flew
out and they flew it in two separate
planes in case one of the planes went
down.
This was the,
this is the folk lore and then the next
day they had this press conference and
they're like,
oh,
we made a mistake.
It was just a balloon and then you know
my joke that I used to do it was like,
well,
what about the aliens?
Those are Mexicans.
Theory got drunk.
There were mistook the balloon for Jada.
Everyone's fine,
but the.
The whole story behind it.
The problem was it got put in the
Roswell daily record that the military
is recovered,
a crashed flying disc and then everybody
went fucking bananas,
so no one,
no one really knows what actually
happened,
obviously.
No.
Did you ever hear why they picked right
pat?
Because it's in the middle of Ohio.
I don't know.
In Roswell is pretty far.
I think he's just a big air force base.
Isn't that right?
Patterson Air Force Base where I'm
hanger 18 was.
Yeah,
I guess that Dayton,
but I don't like,
but hang on a team was another famous
thing and Ufo folklore,
folklore.
There was like this,
suppose it hanger 18 and find out where
that is.
Hangar 18 was supposed to be this place
where they stored all of the crashed
wreckage from various ufo over the last
few decades because apparently there's
been numerous crashed Ufo,
great on alien planets.
That's what it says.
Is that right?
18.
There's like a website about it.
Yeah.
But yeah,
so it's that right pat.
Long as there's a website about it
traces a squarespace website.
We believe Jerry.
No,
it's uh,
what was the ones?
Cities remember those with the animated
little gifts school?
Yeah.
What about the moon landing?
Did you see the movie Ryan Gosling?
No,
I did not.
I heard it was good though.
I heard it was really good.
Did you love.
It wasn't controversial,
like they didn't put the American flag
down.
It was something so cool.
Right to listen.
Music video.
There was something.
He brought his daughter's necklace up.
He has his young daughter.
I want to give it all away,
but then he put his daughter's necklace
there and I don't know,
based on real life that the.
Yes,
loosely.
That's what they're saying.
It's probable that that happened.
The flag thing,
I don't even.
I don't remember.
I'm sure there was some sort of
controversy,
didn't plant the US flag,
people were upset and they were saying
that,
you know,
in this climate they just thought it
wouldn't be a good idea to express
nationalism or something.
So I remember reading some cockamamie
reason why they didn't have the flag.
They actually had the flag.
You fuck there actually,
if you believe in the moon landing,
you believe it happened and you want to
show you a movie of it.
You got to show the flag.
They put it in the ground is a big part
of the program.
Here's our flag.
It's in the,
in the fucking dirt on the moon.
So that's right.
It's there.
And now he also paid brown on the way up
on the 40 day journey.
And I heard you just Pete Brown,
uh,
Pete,
a little brown.
It was more like amber colored ice tea
colored while I was a little worried
about.
There's something called rhabdomyolysis
that when you do crossfit or actually a
couple of fighters have died from it.
I actually just found out about that
this weekend,
that fighters who had been overtrained
going into fights and then exerted
themselves to extreme during the fight
and then died afterwards.
A couple of them turned out to have had
rhabdo my locis,
which is,
uh,
the,
your,
your muscle tissue breaks down your
liver crashes or your kidneys crash
rather.
I didn't have that.
I just,
I was just dehydrated.
Oh yeah.
That was pretty gnarly.
I was sweating at a rate that I couldn't
possibly keep up with.
Just trying to rehydrate.
Normally you guys and the sober fucking
October man when crazy.
Right.
What was it like being the wife of a
person who was involved in this?
I hate it so much.
I hate that you guys do this shit.
You know what we're doing next year?
Uh,
yeah.
And I heard you guys talking about it
because I caught that part of the show
surfing.
Yep.
We're gonna.
We're gonna stay on a board longer,
like who stays on the board for the most
amount of time in the month.
I love this challenge because I love
surfing.
I learned to do it in my twenties.
I'm terrible at it,
but that's like that's why it's so
incredibly difficult.
Have you served?
Not at all and I'm not going to.
I'm not even going to touch it until
October and this is.
None of us can practice.
We can practice.
Yeah.
We got to wait until October and then do
it.
I will say the ocean is very in
October.
That's the one you're going to get a
special suit.
I'm sure there are.
Yeah.
I'm going to get one with fucking.
It's gonna have Kevlar and it's the
sharks can't eat me.
Oh,
that's another thing though.
Not getting aided by no big fish.
This is a tablet that does a tentative
challenge,
but I have to say this last one,
your husband Tommy bonds is the one that
came up with the fitness challenge and
there was only like the last couple of
days before October,
like we hadn't really decided on what
we're going to do.
In fact,
we were even thinking about repeating
our 15 yoga class thing.
Like we'd kind of settled into that.
I was like,
okay,
I can do 15 yoga classes,
and we kind of had decided that that's
what we're going to do,
and then I know where your husband goes,
Hey,
I've been doing this fitness thing,
I wear this app.
Maybe we could just see who gets the
most points for a month.
I'm like,
okay.
I didn't think anything of it.
You weren't excited about that idea.
I thought it would be fun,
like whatever.
It'd be fine,
but I didn't think it would be a psycho
battle to the death when it became
really quick.
I'll tell you what's,
what was D as a spouse of the sober?
Is the sobriety parts not too difficult
for Tommy?
Yeah,
it's the time away from the family.
It's like he would go and be like,
bye.
I'm going to go hike for six hours in
and we live near hills and I'm like,
there's fucking rattle snakes and
cougars and you better be back before
sundown,
do you know?
Um,
yeah.
And then he got sick.
So he was doing it on antibiotics,
which was crazy.
I didn't want them to be doing that
shit.
Thirteen miles on antibiotics.
Crazy has bananas.
No,
that is so hard to do.
I know and.
But we were like talking about it at
breakfast and he was like,
well Joe is gonna be first?
There's no question like.
So it was more about who's going to be
second and third.
He was
trying to take that first place spot now
what?
He was doing all sorts of sneaky tricks.
He was trying to bank up as points and
try to pretend that I know that he
wasn't a threat.
He really was sneaky.
He was.
Oh,
he's super sneaky.
He came close.
He was the closest to me and he was.
He was the most sneaky.
He's definitely the most sneaky.
What do you mean?
Like what's his,
how has he sneaky like what we would say
things to me like you should just work
out normal and see if you beat us.
I mean if you just try to beat us,
be too easy.
Like one on one I do that are like,
yeah.
I had decided early on that I was going
to beat them,
but I decided that I was.
At first I was like,
this is so stupid.
Who gives a shit about this competition
really ruined my life for this thing.
I could not live with myself.
If burt one.
That was a big part of the problem with
that really have happened though.
Could have happened.
I have all of you guys.
You never know if we fucked off.
Yeah,
see,
no one fucked off.
Everybody went hard.
Even burt burt's wife was probably used
to him being gone 10 abandoning the
family.
She's like,
whatever.
It's just not here.
I did lot of my workout
at home,
you know,
because I have a gym in my house.
Yeah.
So it wasn't.
They knew where to find me.
So your wife and your.
They would come in and make fun of me.
Whoa.
Why are you still doing this?
Like my eight year old,
especially if she thinks it's hilarious.
She's like,
you better when you're better.
When she'd walk away.
Like so fun.
She's a little comedian.
She's a funny little fucker.
Really is.
You got to raise them Sassy.
Girls can't raise them.
That princess shits horrible.
You're a princess.
Like,
oh no,
don't raise girls to think they're
princesses because now always waiting to
be rescued for shit.
Donnelly.
Not only that,
like that means you're a part of a
monarchy and you're oppressing all those
peasants.
Like this whole,
like I talked to a friend once who was
like,
this is back in the nineties,
and he was.
He was very pro black,
black guy who's very pro and he said one
of the most ridiculous things any
person's ever said,
he was talking about black people today
goes,
black people have got to understand back
in the day we will kings and I go,
you will.
You couldn't be all kings.
I go,
listen,
listen.
Do you understand that king's work?
There's one person and that person
dominates all these other people with
power,
and the way they do it is through threat
and military and kill people who oppress
them.
Like you don't want to be a king man.
You don't.
Yeah.
It's one of the most terrible things to
be is a king.
You don't even get elected into office,
you just to king.
You have ultimate power.
You abuse the shit out of you.
You weren't all kings like you can't be
all.
You can't say we were kings.
No,
God.
Damn.
That's a stupid thing to say because
God,
God ordains the king.
Henry the.
I love those historical things aside.
Netflix.
Do you ever watch vikings?
I started to,
yeah.
It's a good.
It's fucking good.
Yeah,
it's surprisingly good.
Give it four episodes because right
around episode four it really kicks in.
So one of our friends had told us,
so I've watched the first episode of
this show is kind of clunky and episode
two comes around by episode four rolls
around.
You're like,
oh shit.
Oh,
it's good to just get executed back then
the way he looked at him,
fuck him up and that would get people
scared and that's how you keep power.
That's what Putin's doing.
Yeah.
That's what they do in North Korea,
you know,
are,
could just be like,
you're going to be my new hoe.
Do you know about that?
Because Shogi guy that the journalists
that got assassinated,
do you know about this?
No,
I've been in a bubble.
Journalists got assassinated by the
Saudis.
He went to the,
uh,
the embassy in Istanbul because his wife
who went to the Turkish embassy because
his wife was Turkish and he was trying
to get married to her and the Saudis had
sent 15 hit men to meet him there.
They strangled him and dismembered him
with bone saws,
carry him out in suitcases.
And they brought in a guy who was a
forensics expert.
He was one of the 15 people.
So they brought in someone who would
know how to manipulate the data.
And the Turkish apparently they said
that they have all,
they have video and audio evidence that
he was murdered there,
but they can't release it because then
it'll show the people how they spy on
them.
Oh my God,
this is today in 2018.
It killed a journalist.
They didn't like what he was saying.
That smell is Saudi though.
I did a military gig in Saudi Arabia
right before I,
uh,
2007.
And I actually had two passports when I
went to go do this military tour and I
didn't know why,
and we get to Riyadh and they go give
them this passport,
the second one that we gave you,
which was completely blank and just had
my personal information.
I know.
And we go in there and they go,
oh,
it's Thursday,
it's chop chop Thursday.
It's a public execution day.
Do you guys want to go see it?
And I was like,
I don't know.
Like on the one hand kind of curious.
On the one hand,
no,
we couldn't do it because somebody,
some guy had put a bomb up as buttoned
blown up of a prince or something so we
couldn't go.
But yeah,
public executions,
they want you to see the,
you know,
to keep people in line.
And it's terrifying.
Women can,
women can drive now
guy.
They'll get stoned to death in front of
her buddy.
Sure.
Yeah,
sure.
They behead people.
They do all kinds of crazy shit to
journalist.
Yeah.
The only locked bloggers up for life.
People have disrespected the crown.
Crazy shit.
Yeah.
Women can't even,
you can't go to the mall unless I'm a
male.
Family member accompanies you
2018.
Yeah.
Clock and try getting out of there.
You know,
you weren't talking about this.
How crazy it is that it's so easy to
come here from some countries like Cuba.
All you have to do is get on a raft.
You make it to Miami like you're in,
Bro.
That's all you have to do to survive.
They don't send you back to Cuba ever.
That's true,
Huh?
We don't.
What about that alien?
Gonzales and he gets sent back
eventually.
That was his parents wanted him back.
Right?
It remember they had a gun.
They fucking machine guns.
The kid was in the closet like what the
fuck?
Why did they send him home?
There was some circumstances to that.
Dad was,
was it dad in the old country and mom in
this country and there was a them back.
Some some something like that.
But for the most part they don't deport
you when you make it from Miami or to
Miami rather from.
From Cuba.
You're good bro.
Thank God.
Crazy though,
right?
It is crazy.
I have to do is get on a raft and
survive 90 miles high.
That's it.
How long would that take?
Could take a long ass time.
If you're doing a mile an hour,
taking 90 minutes a mile,
an hour,
take you 90 hours rather than ours.
Okay.
That's still a red mile an hour,
which is like how fast do you pedal?
You're paddling like how fast can you
pass fast as I can paddle a mile an
hour.
I have no idea.
What's a good question,
right?
Yeah.
Depends on whether or not you'd go in
with the tide against the tide dude,
and then the sun goes down.
It's cold as shit.
I mean sharks.
You've seen Malana sharks.
Sure.
Fresh water.
What are you drinking?
Drinking and shit.
You can.
You're going to try to keep it together.
Drink as much as you can before and then
you got to drink your pis.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You can.
Once it separates,
right?
You let it sit,
drink it.
Just drink it right out.
Fresh out.
Yeah.
You will do as you lie on your back and
you bring your ass to years,
you grabbed your hands behind your ass,
bring it to yourself in your mouth.
Don't want to lose any of its precious
moisture in and out,
in and out.
Your wife's that TV show.
Is it navy seals who can survive?
One guy goes to the beach,
one guy has to go to the mountains or
some shit.
I've seen a lot of those shows.
Survivor.
That was one of them.
I'd like to learn how to survive.
I wouldn't be good at it.
Would you do naked and afraid?
The stupidest one.
That's the stupidest fucking show.
Why would you want to be naked?
You don't need to know in your butthole.
Well,
there's something about that.
This like,
okay,
this is a.
they've taken it as far as you can take
it.
Like,
okay,
we're going to have people survive.
Yeah.
Like survivor man.
Hey a kid without people that do that,
don't know what they're doing.
Hey,
good idea and I'm fucking mad.
Let's make them naked.
Like,
okay,
Jesus.
You don't care about people at all.
Why would you do that?
Tanks now you get people and one of them
is hot and the other one's fat.
Disgusting.
Then you have naked together.
Well,
I like to watch.
I used to like survivor when they put
the fat people on the island and then
they get real skinny by the end of the
show.
That was Kinda cool.
Right?
Weight loss show that is legit.
You get on a fucking island with nothing
to eat.
You will lose weight.
If you're fat,
you actually have an advantage.
Weight to lose.
That's you're really skinny and you
can't.
I remember one time someone killed
something like a rabbit or something and
everybody freaked out.
People were so mad.
Meanwhile,
they could be serving them chicken out
of a bucket.
No one said a word.
So stupid.
Oh my God.
He killed a rabbit with a knife.
Are you supposed to eat?
You don't want them to do that.
What do you want that rabbit to live
forever and become an angel?
What the fuck is wrong with you have
rabbits lived two years.
My kids had a pet rabbit.
They live for like the worst.
Gerbils.
Hamsters Hampshire's to live for two
years.
We had one that lived.
Two or three was a miracle.
Yeah,
amazing.
The last 12 months were incredible.
It was an extra year.
They didn't give a fuck about that
thing.
It's like they.
They say they want a hamster.
I like,
oh,
we want a hamster wheel.
The hamster.
Okay,
let's get a hamster.
We're going to play with it all the
time.
We promised.
Okay.
They get it.
They pick it up a couple times.
I'm like,
fuck this little rat rat bag.
They have cats and dogs,
which are,
which are real pants.
Everything else is bullshit.
Pet a bullshit pet.
He can't really play with it.
You can't snuggle with a hamster.
You can't teach it to do anything.
The worst.
I think his birds.
Oh,
did you have a fucking burst or little
cut?
Diaz done.
Don't give a fuck about this shit all
over your house if you let them out.
One thing we did do is we raised a
hummingbird.
We,
uh,
we brought it back to health and then
released it.
We found a hummingbird.
There was a baby humming bird that had
fallen out of the nest and it was really
tiny and so we took it in and uh,
we didn't know how long it was going to
live.
I was like,
man,
this thing might die on us,
like what do we do?
And then we had a google what they eat
and basically the sugar water,
so we basically put sugar and mix it in
with water and put it in as his or her
little Balaji gender that,
yeah,
I'm going to call it us or in a box in a
box.
And we fed them and they,
they them pronouns and the Diet sugar
water.
Could you imagine?
We kept it for a month and then
eventually it got to a point where it
was kind of hopping around inside the
box and it seemed to be healthy and
would let us hold it and everything.
It was really crazy,
like totally attached to us.
And then we let it go and flew away.
Like it was fucked up in the beginning.
He couldn't move his wings.
Right.
We didn't know what to do,
whether it was wounded to the point
we're going to have to take it and get
it fixed somewhere and we didn't know.
Damn,
but it lived.
Hey,
sorry.
How long did you have it?
About a month or so.
Crazy.
I have a theater outside the kitchen
window and I love to watch them.
I get so excited when they have strange
bird makes my day so fast,
so fast.
Those little tiny wings to their wings
are so small.
That's what's odd.
Like every bird has like a wingspan,
but their wingspan is like half the size
of a normal births.
Wingspan and they just go a million
miles an hour and they go left and right
and up and down and they just.
So their ability to change direction is
so strange and hover.
I think it just hover perfectly in the
air and then turn it off and then come
back and hover.
Yeah,
it's very unusual design.
right.
They're so tiny,
but I guess that's why they have to move
so fast because the wings are so tiny.
You ever seen one get fucked up by
praying mantis?
No.
That's the dark shit.
Praying mantis will hide underneath a
bird feeder and just sit there.
Just sit there like this and wait.
And you're like,
how the praying Mantis can't fuck up
that bird.
It's smaller than the bird.
Oh yes.
They can never seen it.
We'll put it up.
Yeah.
Praying mantises regularly kill.
I did not climb up to the nest.
They climb up to the theater and they
just sit and wait and [inaudible] they
look like sticks,
you know,
and they blend in with the color of the
tree they're on,
you know,
because they camouflage their color here
at.
Watch this.
Look at this mother fucker.
Look at him just hanging out there.
Totally frozen.
And these birds when any idea what's
going on,
it seems like he's kind of.
He wrap son.
They're crazy.
The hummingbird is so much faster than
him.
It doesn't matter.
It doesn't.
It only has to be fast for a second.
The only has to clamp down those jaws.
Persons saving it.
Person saved it.
What?
That person's an asshole.
He right order of things.
We kind of gave away his punch.
He's really like telegraphing his moves
and they're supposed to get out of
there.
You see this shit happening.
Just had a stupid ass bird.
We have an owl in our backyard and one
of the coolest things is when the sun
goes down,
we sit in the backyard and we launched
that fucker come out of the big tree
that it lives in.
Ohio just swoops through the backyard
and you're like,
that's gonna do it.
He's out.
He's going to catch some shit tonight.
Rabbits,
you're going to put your dogs away.
They keep the rat population down to.
We got lots of those because we have
fruit trees,
so the fucking rats.
Look at this praying mantises tracking
this hummingbird regularly eat
hummingbirds,
but the thing is if you look at the size
of the hummingbird and the size of the
praying Mantis,
he would go,
there's no way.
Where's it going to eat it?
I can't even.
There's not even enough room and its
body.
That's a good point.
And the beak,
it's so hard.
They don't give a fuck praying.
Mantises just.
We are so lucky.
They're little,
if there are big German shepherds,
we will be fucked.
They're just eat us.
We're lucky dogs are as adobe as they
are.
You know,
and your specialty.
Talk about how to dumb.
They're afraid of your judgment,
your dogs big enough.
He's a golden retriever.
He's not eating anybody,
but if his brain were more.
Yeah,
I wonder if like if he was a rat that
big versus that big and he was a
ferocious rat and I was in the subway
and I saw him.
I wouldn't be so scared till we got
rats.
Do you have rats in your.
Oh,
we definitely get rats.
Yeah.
I hate them so much.
I have a guy that comes.
My rag guy puts down all the fucking
traps.
We had one get into an AC unit in one of
our guest bedroom and it stunk like
shit.
Yeah.
We had went to a dyed in the wall and we
started having all these flies that,
that came in through the room and we
were trying to figure out how does this
fly getting in here.
We realize there's something dead in the
wall because it was stinking and we had
to just wait for it to rot away.
Oh yeah.
Well,
I guess what's the alternative you
punched through the wall?
Fuck that.
You don't want to do that.
Yeah.
It was the only alternative rat on the
wall.
Sons.
So nasty.
They're caught one with the trap.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
I love it.
A lot of them.
Yeah.
What kind of traveler you use?
Kind of hurt.
Snappers the snapper to the best
actually fucked up story.
I was in encino and I was renting this
house for awhile and uh,
killed a rat and it was a big boy.
Big,
big fat boy.
And I was like,
Jesus.
So the thing.
And I was like,
Eh,
I'm going to go to bed in the morning of
cleaned it up.
I went to bed.
I came back in the morning.
He was eating.
The only thing that was left is his
tail.
They ate the entire rat.
That rats are full on.
Cannibals.
I didn't know that the other rats will
eat the dead guy 100 percent.
Instantly.
They hate him down to the tail.
No,
there was nothing left down to the tail.
Even rats will need a rat's tail.
Right?
This shit's nasty.
We should serve tails on fear factor.
Even rats will need it to like,
Nah,
Bro.
Stick with garbage and assholes.
They ate everything.
That guts.
They hate the head.
Everything is chewed through the rat
head.
There was almost nothing left.
Yeah,
they were eating.
We're eating bones.
Who was almost nothing left.
It was so disturbing.
Yeah.
There's a rat eating another wrap.
Cannibal rats filmed eating fellow
rodents.
Yeah.
They eat the shit out of each other.
They have no problem with that.
And once they're in your house,
you're screwed.
Once you see those droppings,
now you're fucked.
You got to find out how they're getting
into the house.
You gotTa caulk it up or whatever.
But that shit.
That's the worst man.
Yeah.
Well it was one of the reasons why it's
good to have coyotes around is why it's
good to have owls.
All those things.
Hawks,
all those things.
Keep the rat population down.
So people run around killing hawks and
owls and.
And there was also a problem with people
that leave out poison because he leave
out poison for the rats and the rats eat
the poison.
Then the owls eat the rats and they get
poisoned.
They die out here.
Yeah,
that's an issue.
That's no good.
We have coyotes too.
They come out in broad daylight.
Yeah,
you gotta be careful.
Those little fuckers running kids were.
Yes.
And around small little dogs.
Tillium little shitty dogs if you need
to.
Yup.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
They'll,
they'll,
they'll bite your fucking kids.
I mean,
if no one's around,
you know,
if you leave a kid in the yard,
three year old kid,
I'm just going to take a shit right
back,
back out.
Come back onto the half eaten kid.
I take my kid with me to take a shit.
I put them on my lap when they shit.
You have to.
Of course I'm not going to let my kid be
alone.
Three year olds get into everything,
especially with fucking animals.
Animals out there.
That's dark.
That's the weird thing.
Like those coyotes are really.
They're predators that are wandering.
We know we had a big issue with them
because we have chickens and they
started killing our chickens,
but then we realized we targeted like
our yard is targeted by these little
tiny
wolves.
It's very strange,
sort of wild creatures that are sneaky.
Oh,
smart.
And they can jump over walls to forget
it,
man.
Jump over walls like nothing.
Like six foot fence.
They bounced to the top of the fence.
Then bounce over it like it's not even
there.
Don't give a fuck.
They're elegant.
The way they move,
it's really kind of beautiful to watch.
They look like just dogs.
Like I'll see them in the neighborhood.
Oh Shit.
That's a coyote do like at first you're
like excited someone's dog and then you
just see them kind of skulking.
They just.
Yeah.
Like,
um,
do you like looking at him?
But then I know what they're capable of
and you're like,
get the fuck out of here.
They will eat your dog for sure.
Are a lot of dogs.
I had a friend,
um,
she had her dog and right in front of
her shell,
a little Maltese lived out in Westlake
village in the broad daylight.
She was just standing in the backyard
with a little Maltese and a coyote just
came and snatched it up right in front
of her and just bring it.
Just went away with it.
And you're like,
there's my,
there goes my dog.
Broad daylight.
Wow.
We've got two little shits.
I don't let them run around and the
charge out.
Of course,
she was devastated.
She was traumatized.
Love that dog.
You know,
it's the Maltese is essentially a lap
dog.
You're not training that thing to do my
gel.
So other than sleep with you and love
you.
So.
So it's a member of the family and so
fucking coyote snatches it up.
It's crazy.
It's hard out there for coyote though,
just to eat fat dogs slipping.
Stupid County dog getting fed by these
people.
That's right.
But they won't fuck with Marshall.
Right?
Like he's too big.
He's too big.
Maybe two of them could try to take him
now.
They might.
Yeah.
I mean,
if they felt like he wasn't going to do
anything about it,
they felt like he was submissive or it
felt like they could just get a hold of
him,
know,
who knows.
They have definitely killed dogs as big
as him before
or you know,
mount minds love them.
They would love a dog that size for
sure.
It's a lot of food.
Yeah,
we think I sense that submissiveness
that I don't know.
I think um,
you know,
I used to have a much bigger dog,
but he died.
He,
uh,
he was a master.
He was 13 years old.
We just,
we just put them asleep a few months
ago.
Sorry.
It was bad at the end.
We probably should've done it earlier
because the end,
he literally couldn't walk into the
house to eat,
like he was in the yard.
And when I tried to call them in for
dinner,
he,
he couldn't walk like it was awful.
He would struggle to stand up and they
would take like a half a step and pause
another half a step.
And paws and his legs were shaking.
I mean he was,
is a beautiful dog,
like,
like so sweet,
like such a con,
like mastiffs are so kind that like so
calm.
It was so hard watching him struggle,
you know,
because he was like breathing heavy and
his mouth was open,
like hey,
take a step.
And he'd be in agony and just he was
just so old from massive.
13 is old.
The bigger dogs,
they don't live as long as they live
like eight,
eight,
nine years old.
For him to be 13,
like the vet was pretty shocked.
Like wow,
this dog is old from massive.
They're big.
Buy Burt's got one of those right?
Yeah.
He's got one.
Priscilla,
they guard vampires.
Do that.
They protect you from vampires.
Are they per guard for the vampires?
Rice books.
They're always guarding family.
They guard the vampires while they sleep
and then as.
That's right,
those books were fucking good,
you know?
And Rice went wacky and became a
Christian at the end of the time.
No,
I've heard this.
I saw her on a flight once and then I
googled her and she's writing a
Christian stuff and she also wrote a
bunch of snm books under a pseudonym.
Uh,
it's all about spanking a lot of
spanking.
It's very odd.
Yes.
I had to read it.
Let me ask you this.
What is it about women and Vampires?
Oh sure.
What's that?
I'll tell Ya.
It's the same.
Uh,
well it's,
it's controlling power and I think
similar to 50 shades of gray,
which I tried giving that to read too.
And I was like,
Nah,
that's kind of stupid.
I'm too smart for that man.
I don't know.
I,
I like dumb shit.
Believe me,
you don't like shit that dumb though.
I tried,
I really tried.
I tried to see what the deal is.
I always try to see what,
why people are drawn to stuff.
I think it's a power thing.
So the vampire comes and takes control
of you and you're totally submissive and
somewhere I think in the female,
whatever DNA in our,
in our makeup,
to have someone totally care for you and
give your power to them.
I think is part of that I have freedom.
It's also a metaphor for sexual
liberation,
so maybe in a time when women couldn't
be sexually free,
the vampire is a metaphor for a loss of
control and sexual desire and stuff.
I don't know.
That's my theory.
Same with the shades of gray.
Mostly it was right,
like housewives,
kind of a repressed,
repressed sexual thing because it wasn't
that risky.
I think it was like a billionaire guy
who liked to.
You'd like to spit in their mouth and
shit and I don't.
I just know she had a 500 orgasms the
first time she ever had sex with.
Yeah,
I know.
That is right.
Go ahead.
Try it up,
but I'll piss on me.
Be Me.
Was that word,
the word that he said?
Danielle man.
Yeah.
Her Pen name wrote a book in 1985 called
exit to Eden.
That was one of the sadomasochist books
that was turned into a movie.
Do you remember this movie starring Dan
Akroyd?
Dan Akroyd didn't do with Rosie
O'donnell.
That's right.
It was a comedy,
right?
Was it supposed to be a comedy?
I mean,
it's,
it was based off the story of,
so I think Gary Marshal might've turned
it into a comedy.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
That's hilarious.
Bizarre.
She played a slow person.
Yes.
Have you discussed this on?
No,
I haven't,
but Sean Penn has also played a slow
person,
but no one has quite done at the way.
Ben Stiller did.
Did you see the people were getting mad
because people.
Because some football player when a
simple Jack Shaun white snowboard.
That's right.
Yeah,
but not just him.
There's a couple other people that went
to simple jack for Halloween and they
were getting like,
you can't go a simple jacket anymore.
You can't be a simple person.
A simple character like dumb characters
are now out the window.
You can't be that anymore.
What happened?
What's going on with us?
Some weird new rules like popping up out
of nowhere.
Like,
wait,
what?
But it wasn't simple jack a parody of
the thing like it was.
It's a joke on a joke,
Jack.
It's not that he's actually portraying a
realistic portrayal of simple.
Jack was a character.
Yeah.
Even in the movie,
Simple Jack was a character in a movie,
wasn't like an actual person,
right?
Yeah.
There it is.
Once upon a time there was a retard.
Wow.
Is that what it says in the movie?
Yeah.
It's a fake movie though,
but wow.
I liked the scene.
That's not that long ago,
and here's the thing.
That movie also.
That's all from tropic thunder,
that movies also the last time anyone's
allowed to wear black face.
That's it.
That's right.
It's over now.
Like Robert Downey Jr.
Try to wear black face in tropic thunder
to imagine.
JusT imagine back.
Oh boy.
All the hurt feelings.
What happened?
They fused this enormous question of
what happened.
Yeah.
I'm hoping you have a fresh take on it.
I'll tell you want to know what I think
it is.
Really?
Yes.
I think since Donald Trump became the
leader,
and I think some people are so triggered
by daddy,
daddy's a little narcissistic at times.
Daddy's not very socially conscious at
times and I think that's affected
because if you say anything kind of
insensitive than it's in align with that
regime,
maybe.
You know what I mean?
Even though you're.
Maybe you don't.
I don't identify with everything trump
stands for.
I like inappropriate humor.
It doesn't mean I aligned with him,
but I think because he doesn't give any
sensitivity to these groups that are
marginalized,
it makes the marginalized people upset.
I also think that people realize that
you can get people in trouble by
pointing out the factor insensitive and
you can come down on them hard and when
you do,
they move.
Things happen.
There's a reaction.
Yeah,
this is happening.
What's interesting is the impulse to
destroy it started with shaming.
Fire them,
take away their income.
Take.
Yeah.
Make them lose their house,
disappear.
Louis ck banished away forever.
Right?
I'm not ready for you to come back yet.
Redemption and how's.
When is redemption allowed?
How soon has he repented enough?
Do we feel like he's earned that?
There's all kinds of stuff.
And then who was accused?
What are the grounds for accusation?
What's enough?
What's enough evidence?
Just somebody saying something good
enough,
believe all women,
which I believe obviously.
I mean,
who the fuck,
you know?
But then again,
there are.
Yeah,
there are people who are alive who do
say for sure,
but that believe all women thing.
Like what about casey?
Anthony,
you know,
what about tonya harding?
Believe her.
NO.
Right.
You saw the movie.
Did you see the movie funny?
There's a lot of them you shouldn't
believe.
Yeah.
other people.
yeah,
exactly.
Better liAr with a vagina.
That's outrageous.
They have wires.
There's a whole separate breed.
They're non gender specific.
That's right.
Oh,
that's interesting.
Binary.
They are not binary.
The wires are just liars.
You know?
It's like.
Yeah.
I mean it's not like murderers.
Murderers are predominantly male.
This is true.
This is fucking true.
What's up with that testosterone?
Yeah.
A long history of killing people.
It's only been within the last couple
hundred years.
You get in trouble for it.
Testosterone.
That's true actually.
Yes,
that's true.
He used to be not that big a deal.
We kill people.
They killed each other.
People at duals.
I mean,
there was a president of the dual,
which one,
don't forget which one,
jackson,
one of the presidents had a fucking dual
while he was in the office.
That's pretty rad.
Yeah,
but I think you guys killed because you
can physically you can.
Like right now you could reach across
the table and snapped my neck because
you're way bigger than me and way
stronger than me.
I could poison and kill each other too.
They killed each other.
When each other are the same size.
They kill people that are bigger than
them.
There's a lot of.
It's a history of people killing people.
People getting in the way.
There are problem throws there,
car starting,
all sorts of shit.
They won't let you sleep and you're
like,
god it.
I want to just stab this motherfucker.
And that's.
That's how men handle things or have
handled associate paths,
right?
Yes.
This Was pathic ones.
Yes,
but I think particularly when it's more
common,
like it becomes a cultural sort of
artifact like murder and violence
becomes a part of life.
Like if you lived in ancient rome for
instance,
and you got to the colosseum and you
watch people get chopped up with swords
and eaten by lions and most people were
a lot of murder taking place out in the
streets and very few people got caught
for anything like what kind of meat you
have to be like right there to catch
someone doing something to actually
catch no fingerprints,
no
dna,
no understanding of anything.
I mean,
who the fuck knows who killed
[inaudible] but.
And people were just getting away with
it left and right.
I mean,
well,
what does this.
Was this Alexander Hamilton and aaron
burr was the sitting vice president at
the time.
He fought the vice president.
Aaron burr was.
Yeah.
And Alexander Hamilton was the former
secretary of the treasury,
I believe at the time.
And there were political rivals.
Well,
political rivals.
They had a dual.
And who won one?
Yeah.
And how did he win?
MorTally wounded.
Shot him.
Killed him.
yeah.
Dad.
You like art artists,
renderings of whatever it looked like.
I don't know how crazy they would stand,
like 10 paces.
They would walk away from each other and
then shoot each other.
Yeah.
That's betsy.
Does that seem like a fair thing?
It's just really who's quicker on the
draw?
It's not really who's stronger or more
like an elegant fighter.
I don't know you,
you judge fights all the time.
Well,
they wanted to kill each other.
That's the thing.
It's like,
so let's,
let's figure out a way where we can kill
each other or try to kill each other and
we make an agreement on how it works.
It's really stupid.
Yeah,
right.
Yeah.
It's really stupid.
Like you shouldn't tell someone that you
want to kill.
The idea was to make it
so that either guy had a fair chance.
It's fair killing.
Right.
Do you know that some states,
like particularly Washington state,
I have a mutually agreed combat laws.
No.
Yeah,
so like if you and jamie just decided
fuck each other up.
I think he might have to be grown girl
or boy on boy.
But if jamie just said to me like,
dude,
I'm tired of your bullshit.
I want to fuck you up.
And I'm like,
I don't want to fuck you up to.
And we just decided and agreed.
Cops will stand by and let them beat the
shit out of each other.
I kind of respect that.
Some,
some old west type shit about that.
Well,
I will say knowing what I know about
males,
it's kind of the way,
at least growing up in the time I did.
That's how guys sorted shit out,
right?
Yeah.
Some guy was giving you some static.
You put him in his place and then the
beef is over,
right?
Yeah.
But you don't want to have to do that.
The problem with that kind of shit is
what if that guy can kick your ass and
he's given you some static.
Like what are you going to let them beat
you up?
Now?
It's true.
You know,
like you don't want to have to fight
someone or even have to know how to
fight or have to be in a position where
you might get fucked up by a god just
because he likes to talk a lot like god
damn shit.
Talking me into some sort of a beef and
he doesn't mind if he gets his brains
punched in these already stupid stuff
like that.
Being a man's terrible.
What's better being a mentor being.
Well,
I will say in terms of power being a
dude.
Listen,
white guys rule everything.
It's going to be that way for a minute.
Longer until these fucking old supreme
court guys kick it.
You know what I mean?
Do you think that's gonna change
everything.
Well,
here's I think,
I think whoever controls the money and
the power for government and then you
get the power.
Yes,
it's actually true,
right?
That's real power.
You know what I'm saying?
Who controls industry and who controls
the government.
So until that changes,
do you think those supreme court guys
and gals get together and go to one of
the eyes wide shut party?
Yes.
What is that?
The bohemian grove illuminati.
The bilderberg group?
Yeah.
I started to watch a documentary on the
free masons on netflix.
Most boring fucking thing I ever saw.
I had to tap out after five minutes
because it's like a legit organization
where a bunch of nerds get together and
like,
yeah,
it's not even exciting.
Freemason in houston was telling me all
about her fall asleep.
Yeah.
We had a handshake and you're like,
secret pyramid inside of that parent was
not.
I remember the eye of horus.
Where's the witchcraft?
Let's get weird man.
But you know about that egg,
the public execution stuff you were
talking about earlier.
Uh,
there's that book by fuko,
you know,
that old french philosopher,
he talked about the scaffold scenes and
whether or not they worked as deterrent
for people committing crimes.
So now we don't have public execution,
but we do shit behind closed doors,
right?
We don't hang somebody,
but we quietly give somebody a lethal
injection and it's all very civilized.
Right?
To kill somebody.
But I wonder which worked better is the
public deterrent thing of like,
hey dude,
you steal some shit because look at
Saudi Arabia,
they,
they'll cut your fucking hand off.
Right?
If you,
uh,
you know,
steel.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I wonder if the public versus the
private punishment,
if that ever really works on weirdos,
who would it stop men from murdering?
I mean,
I think people that do it get caught up
and when they would call crimes of
passion.
Right?
I don't like that.
Like theY get caught up in this moment
and they just can't help themselves and
they want to kill someone more than they
want to be free.
I just want to kill this motherfucker
the deal without law shit later.
Right now I've got a rock and that
dude's got ahead.
Need to connect this rock to that guy's
fucking hood.
What's this last public hanging and
Kentucky in 1936.
She's like,
how many people showed up?
That's the.
See humans like that stuff.
We love to see it.
They love it.
Look at those guys climbing up on trees
and shit.
We can see one too.
Is this is in France in 1939.
It's a guillotine on this and you know
what the guillotine that it wasn't a
clean cut the first time and they'd have
to do it a few times.
Oh really?
Huh?
Not always a good bad that you always
hoped for.
A sharp blade.
Yeah.
That's the last
public execution in France.
Yeah,
that's what it says.
What year was that?
Nineteen 39.
Whoa.
Recent.
Thirty nine.
Whoa.
Is there video of this as he was a
german criminal?
I don't say shit.
Cut his hand off.
Wow,
that's crazy.
Just have the box standing there to
people's ago.
Joe was.
Yeah.
The United States was founded three
people's ago.
That's true.
That's crazy.
That's what's hard to really understand
how much cultural evolution is taking
place just during our lifetime.
It's hard to imagine.
it's hard to imagine what.
What year were you born?
70 sIx.
Could you imagine if you had a time
machine and you can go back to 1976 and
just wander around the streets and see
what people were like,
oh my god,
you guys are children who don't know
shit.
You have no internet.
You barely read.
I know.
What do you do?
I'm sorry.
What's that?
There's a video of the video,
but let's say it didn't.
All these people gather around,
gather around fixing to drop the hammer.
Oh,
here it is.
they get them in there.
Get in there,
bitch.
The gentleman ready and.
oh,
and one take a job.
We'll do that again.
Show that again.
Right.
Get him in there.
And that is a crazy way to kill someone.
Yes.
Leave it to the french.
Well,
it's efficient.
I think that's why teen.
Yeah.
This is what we do to make you wanna do
is with our hands with the machine.
Yeah.
Wow.
Well,
back to your statement,
I,
I often find myself because I'm 42 years
old and I do find myself being like the
world has changed completely sInce I was
a kid growing up in the eighties in the
nineties,
especially in the last decade.
Even just from the time I started doing
standup and the audiences and how you
have to adjust kind of how you're doing
comedy to how it's received.
Yeah,
I mean just even
this thing.
Phones.
Because this has bananas.
Yeah.
I have a computeR right here and I can
watch movies.
I can google anything I want.
I can find my way home.
I remember we had to like remember how
to get home.
How about when it tells you you're 20
minutes from her?
I'm like,
bitch,
You don't know where I live.
Yeah.
How do you know's going there?
Tells you where you stop every night.
That aIn't my home.
That's my side piece.
Yeah.
Like what if your husband looked through
it?
Hey,
why does it say you're only 15 minutes
from home?
We live in half an hour from here
because that says siDe dick,
dick.
Fifteen minutes away.
I mean cheating.
Now you've got to be.
You've got to have a burner,
right?
I mean,
because your wife could just fucking.
I think if you're cheating today,
you're just.
You're a reckless,
reckless individual phone.
Yeah.
If you're using your phone and cheating.
Reckless person.
Crazy talk.
Yeah.
But if you've got it,
burner phone.
People are like,
what's up with that kmart phone.
Oh,
your wife's going to find that as you
get that fucking cvs flip phone you got.
Oh,
and by the way,
I heard you guys talking about me not
being right or die with sigora.
Yeah.
Well,
you're going to turn them in a
tournament in a hot second.
Crime of passion.
Yeah.
No,
no,
no.
Here's my problem.
I,
I would,
uh,
I'd be ride or die when it came to
premeditated under the condition of
somebody's threatening my family,
but let's say he goes to starbucks and
the barista gets his order wrong,
which is the scenario we discussed.
And then he snaps and kIlls the barista.
That's the shit I'm talking about where
I'm like,
oh,
this person's crazy.
Like you've turned a corner mentally.
Well,
how bad the guy fuck up the order.
Good point.
Yeah.
I mean,
what have you said?
Sugar free and it clearly a sugar on it,
right?
Right.
Or nonfat gives you a whole fat half
cap.
How much anxiety do you get when you go
to starbucks and the barista makes
someone else's ordered before yours,
that ordered after.
You know what I mean?
Like they call that person's name.
I get so fucking angry.
Drink
coffee.
Yeah.
Oh,
just drip.
Yeah.
Give me a grand a coffee please.
You know,
roast the dark one wherever.
Just give me a fucking coffee.
That's all I get.
I get a cup of coffee,
I put some cream in it and I'm good.
You don't do pumpkin spice fuck with.
Wow.
Yeah.
but yeah,
my wife Does drink vanilla lattes that
are sugar free with heavy cream heavy
cream instead of milk.
That's interesting.
Pretty god damn good.
And there's sugar free.
Oh,
that's your god damn good.
Those are good,
but they're not coffee.
It's like a drink.
You're drinking a drink.
It's like a milkshake.
Yes.
Yeah,
a lot of calories.
It's good.
Before you work out.
We drank one of those.
I drank one of those this morning before
you at the hit the hills.
She on the same day at your.
She's a,
she was on keto for awhile,
but now she's,
she got off of that but she might get
back on it again.
We uh,
we were here last night.
I went running today and I was hobbling
because,
uh,
we were drunk bench pressing last night
and while drunk benchpressing pulled a
muscle in my leg of course was like,
they had like,
how many times do you think you can
press to 25?
I'm like a lot to give me that you
pussies like we were so drunk,
so drunk and I,
I bench pressed 225 pounds,
like 11 times and on the 11th time I've
felt something on my leg,
but I ignored it seemed fine.
I was walking arounD,
everything is fine,
but then running today was not fun.
As soon as I was running,
as soon as I got on the hills and then I
was pushing it,
I was like,
oh,
I fucked something up in my leg.
Drunk benchpressing crazier back to
exercising already.
Oh,
I was exercising two days afterwards.
Yeah,
but not as much.
I mean,
I ran the hills today.
That was kind of hard,
but now I'm fucked.
I really am limping.
I got to figure out what this is.
Well,
plus on hills,
it's uneven terrain and there's rocks
and shit.
Right.
That can't be good for your knees and
no,
that's not a problem
for my needs were.
They were sore for.
My knees were a little sore.
My feet were sore.
My ankles are sore because it was a lot
of pounding.
A lot of running.
Yes,
and uh,
that's,
I take my dog.
That's his,
that's how he stays chill.
That's right.
If he,
if he runs with me a couple miles a day,
he's so chill.
He's just relaxed.
If he doesn't,
he's like,
what
are we doing man?
We can't just sit around the fucking
house and go do something.
So cesar millan says you got to tire
them out,
call them sub museum energies when they
order,
says calm,
submissive energy.
And if they work out then they're chill
and you can tell them what to do.
Yeah,
no,
that's definitely true for especially.
He's my dogs pretty young.
He's only a,
he'll turn to next month.
So he's,
he's basically a pup still super sweet.
Yeah,
he's a gorgeous dog.
He's a sweetie.
He's the sweetest of sweeties is a
really good dog.
You know,
I was uh,
I was listening to ari talk some shit on
the uh,
your wrap up show whatever from sober
october.
So funny when he's like,
well these two are obese,
like just eat normal,
which is so true.
Needs what is fucking red z on the
keyboard?
No,
he's normal.
He was fat at one point in time.
No.
Yeah,
he had a sugar problem.
He was eatIng candy like all the time
and then he realized he had a candy
problem.
Ours is very smart.
He recognizes he has problems and fixes
them and that's something that a fat
burt doesn't do.
That's why already better than all.
Right.
He did change his life.
I mean,
like I,
we kind of started at the same time in
comedy.
I didn't really know him,
know him until much later.
But yeah,
I remember him being kind of a fuck up
and then he like turned to shit around
and it's amazing.
Well,
he um,
um,
he,
he did a lot of different things.
Sorry.
No disrespect,
no successful now.
So he's,
he's also doing it his way,
like lou really truly doing it his way.
Like he doesn't,
he's got no one tells him what to do and
then he's going to keep it that way.
He doesn't have any expensive taste at
all.
You wear normal clothes.
He doesn't even own a fucking watch,
you know,
he's like,
whoa,
chill time.
It's on my phone.
Sorry,
what was the last time you're somewhere
where you couldn't find the time on his
flip phone?
Yeah.
Doesn't even have like a nice phone.
He doesn't want one because if you,
as you realized as he gets addicted to
social media,
it gets addicted to like googling things
and tweeting and all that shit.
Just,
you just can't do it.
He can't handle it.
yeah.
You said I get it,
but you just have to have discipline.
I agree.
Yeah.
For me,
I can,
you know,
I don't have a problem not looking at my
phone for hours at a time.
I think you got to just that.
That's
how you live.
You don't just live checking your phone
constantly
because it's so.
You and I grew up in a time where we
didn't compulsively check our phones and
now I've had to learn to give a shit
about it.
Like the email came in.
Woo.
What?
Imagine our children who are.
This is just an.
I was listening to you talk to elon musk
about how this is like an extension
technology will just grow into a human
being.
Right?
Well,
my daughter's friends,
my 10 year old daughter's friend,
are all of them have phones except for
two or three of them?
10.
Yeah.
What are they doing at 10?
Is it social media is one girl.
My mom,
my wife always jokes.
She goes,
when you see her,
she'll have a phone in her hand.
She always has a phone in her hand.
She never puts that fucking phone down.
She stares at that phone while she's
talking to her friend.
She's playing with things.
She was,
this is why I don't want our kids to
have phones.
And then we'd meet her at starbucks.
She's looking at her phone.
Oh,
hi.
It's like a scene in a movie.
She's like,
hi,
how are you?
I was just looking at her phone,
checking things like the texting each
other back and forth.
Constantly intent.
They manipulate and each other like one
of them will say something to get the
other ones go and then she'll go radio
silent on her
all.
You can learn how to do that at 10.
Oh girls,
they're fucking with each other at 10.
That's normal though.
That girl,
evil shit.
You learned to you do that stuff early,
but with this it's even more insidious.
You can have a group of three girls
because one's going to be out all the
time.
It's just what girls do.
It's even.
Why is that?
Why girls do that?
Well,
what's the evolutionary biology solution
like?
What is the cause?
The root right one is your ally.
One is Your enemy.
Well,
no,
you're going to fuck her husband because
you want that new dick and you want
those for the eggs.
Fuck that other.
My frIend's husband.
No,
no,
I think it's a threat.
The other bitches are a threat,
right?
Yeah.
Other bitches are threat,
but there are a threat because they want
to fuck your husband.
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
So you got to like figure out a way to
manipulate them.
Keep those hoes and check.
That's right.
Make them make them fuck up.
So you keep one click,
one hold close to you.
Trust each other bitches out.
Right?
I'm talking.
YEah,
psychology is fascinating.
But with men too,
you know,
there's guys that will fuck your wife.
You know guys that will move on them.
Say yeah,
you know,
look,
I don't want to be that guy,
but you deserve better than tom.
Just bad god friends.
I've had friends in the past.
Do that lady.
Yeah.
And then I,
I did go straight to me and tell me,
go to the guy.
I go,
I guess we're not friends.
Huh?
I thought we were friends.
You fucking weasel dude.
Listen,
i'M friends with her too far.
you.
There's certain guys that are like that.
There's certain guys that just work.
I had a friend when I was growing up who
always wanted to fuck the girlfriends of
other,
and then if those guys broke up with the
girl,
he would immediately fuck them.
I'm like,
dude,
he's your friend.
You know,
she's fucking,
she's free.
She's free.
No free market.
What else?
Color those hyenas.
Are they prey on the carcass?
What anImal preys on the carcass?
Injures scavenger.
They're waiting.
They're just waiting for that breakup.
That guy is always around and he's the
guy you're friends with for awhile,
for like a few years and he acts cool
and then the minute you break up,
moves in.
Yeah,
dude,
he's the shoulder you cry on.
it took me a few years to learn that
guy.
Yeah.
Oh shit.
You're not my friend.
How about the ones that are supposed to
be your friend?
That's.
Yeah,
and they're playing like they're your
friend,
but really they just wait for a moment
to slip it in.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's gonna be a time which is
vulnerable.
yeah.
Yeah,
it's gonna be a.
I always saw it shows if there's a guy
and a girl together and I'm like,
oh,
are you?
Are you on a date?
No,
he's just my friend.
I'm like,
oh
bitch,
fuck you does.
But some girls know it and they just
keep that guy around because it'll drive
them to the mall and he'll fucking take
them to dinner and we just went out with
mike.
He's a sweetie.
Mom.
Mike has just beaten off his finger up
his ass thinking about you and for my.
Well thIs finger in his ass.
Yeah.
I just fucking went in.
Two of them are grabbing the ball,
like a bowling ball.
One's neat.
He's angry when he's come.
Much shit.
Fuck men are so nasty.
Yellow is so damn nasty,
angry that's not working out and shit.
And then she texts him after he comes,
just looking at it as like,
no,
we're not friends,
not friends.
It's terrible.
I can't wait to shut it down though,
you know,
shut it down.
I can't wait to hit menopause.
Just show how much work it is.
Like especially when you hit your
forties.
I do pull out.
He's twice a week.
I got to eat the fucking prime on the
primal type.
I don't need anything.
I'm a blueprint diet.
Yeah.
He's a sponsor of this show has been on
the podcast for a couple of times.
Yes.
I guy,
I tried to,
I was trying to have like baby brands
trying to listen to the vegan doctor
versus the.
That's a good one.
ThIs crusher.
Yeah.
I just,
I had to listen in pieces because it's
pretty intricate,
you know?
It's very intense.
Yeah.
But like my hand anyway,
the point being I can't waIt to shut it
the fuck down and just.
Yeah.
And just were like,
cool.
Lots and birkenstocks.
Are you going to wear crocs ever?
Fuck am.
Want to wear crocs with socks or no
socks?
Socks,
because my feet get real sweaty now and
I'm going to get real short haircut
should just above the ears.
The nanette?
Yes.
Ashley rose.
what's her name?
Amber rose.
Oh,
she's so pretty though.
the other one.
Amber rose is the hot one.
But then the other one.
Ruby rose.
I don't know that one.
She's the one who played the hitman and
the john wick movie.
John wick.
Those movies alive,
man.
I love john wayne movies.
No man's dog.
Can't kill a man's dog.
It's going to kill everybody.
You know?
I respect you.
A lIttle puppy.
Beat it to death.
Yeah.
She's gorgeous.
Yeah,
she.
She had the same acting teacher.
I've seen her acting teacher.
I have a coach that I go to before I
auditioned.
Oh,
that's a good move.
I'm not great,
but at this point,
like with the terrible.
What's he talking about?
I'm not good at acting here.
Fantastic.
Hello.
What have you ever seen me active news
radio.
That shit's easy.
Sitcom.
Want to do,
but that's all I want.
So very easy.
Just tell me.
Give me the tutorial on sitcom acting.
You just do it.
Just pretend you that person.
The end.
Wait a minute.
There's no method.
You don't have to run in character for
memorize what you're supposed to say.
Pretend to be that person.
Do it a bunch of times so you know how
to do it the right way and then go in
and don't be nervous.
That's the thing is not not choking.
That's a big part of it.
A big part of auditions is ready go and
you got to be normal.
You got to be normal in that.
Especially if it's like a calm scene or
weird scene or a love scene or something
like that.
So always these asshole staring at you
with fucking notepads and stacks of
other people's bios and head shots and
they don't know.
The whole thing is bizarre.
The worst.
It's so different than actual acting too
because it's like you're doing it in
this weird environment.
There's a conference table.
The person is reading with you as
probably like I did one and it was the
person who read with me was so
insultingly bad at it that I was really
frustrated.
I was like some a pa and he was like,
I just don't know if this is what was
supposed to happen with us.
And I was like,
c'mon man,
if you're going to fucking just say the
word so I can respond to this.
I can't skate.
What the fuck is wrong?
This is what I want to say.
If you were talking to me like that,
I'd be like,
what is wrong with you?
Why can't you talk?
Are you on drugs?
You get hit in the head.
It's a coconut fall out of a tree and
almost kill you.
See,
this is why you're so successful.
This is why.
Well,
because in a world of bullshit,
you know what I mean?
You gotta keep it 100.
I don't think the world is.
I don't think there's a world of
bullshit.
I think there's a lot of bullshit,
but I think there's more reality today I
think we've ever experienced ever
before,
but what there is is a bunch of people
that are scared.
That's what it is.
They're scared of getting called out or
they're scared of getting fired.
Fired.
One's a big one.
They'll take away your income.
Shit.
Now I got to find another job after I
talked about blackface.
Megan,
megan over and she was loving it where
she was at fox she worked at before.
She could say all kinds of crazy shit.
They don't care about blackface
at fox was like,
yeah,
why can't you give her a raise for that
one?
You should be able to.
You should be able to have a bone in
your nose.
And then she goes over to,
was it nbc?
Why would you go there?
You know that's not for you,
dude.
Apparently they did not like her from
the jump.
The inside word is that she was not a
nice person.
They did not like her to be around.
They were looking for reasons to get rid
of her.
That's the word.
That's the inside word,
but don't you hate that?
When you hear that someone's not nice
and they're making millions of dollars,
that's true,
but who's saying she's not nice?
How about someone who's annoying to her?
Maybe she's not nice because you're
annoying.
She's out there trying to educate people
about blackface.
You motherfuckers try to share again,
people,
black person.
It's just color.
What's the big deal that.
Didn't she say that santa claus isn't
black too?
Awesome.
Yeah.
That was a part of the extended Megan
Kelly bit that I edit down.
Oh,
I had a guy in the office who was
working with her.
I was like,
have you worked with kelly after about a
year?
You're not doing any work all day long.
All you're thinking of is someone gets
the fucker.
Why can't it be me?
Like if you're in the cubicle right
there and you run into your time,
your time,
your trips to the coffee machine.
When you see her walking.
Not yet.
Go.
Megan,
just want to let you know.
Santa claus,
definitely white.
Like you'd say,
things like you more kind of how
horrible this.
A lot of guys,
a lot of guys working in offices,
oh,
but you're not supposed to hit on your
coworkers.
Now.
Isn't that considered a microaggression
or toxic masculinity or some of those
things,
but then what if you love her,
what does she loves you?
Hang on so it works out.
What if her husband is a jerk?
You'll take care of her kids.
Oh my god.
No way.
I can't even imagine.
I mean,
I've been with tommy for so long,
being with,
oh my god,
this is what I think.
I think when people work together,
if you work together for eight hours a
day,
you're spending as much,
if not more time with that person that
you work with every day.
Then you do with your spouse.
Absolutely,
and you're only home like,
look,
if you're home in the morning,
how much do you get to see your,
your wife or your husband?
Fucking an hour,
two hours in the morning and most you
get up,
you run into the shower,
excuse me,
brush teeth when eat breakfast and see
progress.
What you got going on today,
blah,
blah.
Then we're playing basketball with mike,
blah blah,
blah,
and then for eight hours,
eight hours of the day,
you're with some other people.
You don't spend eight hours flat with
anybody other than the people that you
work with.
You get home.
It's what?
Seven 30,
8:00.
You watch tv,
you have dinner.
By the time it's 10,
you're asleep.
That's three hours.
You got like three hours with that
person there.
Eight hours with this guy who was trying
to fuck them high.
Now
you're right.
You're right.
Because I worked at a company I had.
This guy was.
He ended up marrying his assistant,
but he did that thing where like,
this is my work life.
That's what they start by doing.
They break you down slowly and they're
like,
this is my work wife.
This is my work husband.
Ha.
It's a joke.
It's a joke and then exploring.
When is the fire happened after?
Oh,
that was.
sorry.
Yeah,
because tommy always like.
I held in a fart that whole time we were
doing it.
Are you proud of me?
That's his latest cabin.
It's real romantic,
but they're,
they're married now actually,
but that's how he courted her and she
was way out of his league.
She was a hot 20 something gorgeous
girl.
Married.
Now they have,
you know,
how many kids I don't remember,
but what happened?
How did he do after he.
He broke her hip,
so she was dating some guy that wouldn't
call her.
It was kind of like dipping out on her
and stuff.
So he'd be like,
I'm here for you.
Let's go out after work.
Let's go get some drinks.
Right.
It's your friend.
I'm the guy that's going to show up for
you everyday.
Dumped that guy.
I'm saying,
even though he's just saying he's the
work husband who's saying I can be a
real husband.
Uh,
yeah,
yes.
Yeah.
And,
and to her,
yeah,
that's what she wanted.
She wanted to be wiped up.
Why?
A lot of girls want to be wiped up.
Yeah.
That's great.
What would you work?
That's the best.
I'm an idiot.
I want to go on the road.
We want to make a career has while your
craft.
Yeah.
Right.
It's really sad when guys wife up,
I know a guy that's wifed up,
you mean?
Oh,
when the woman takes care of the man,
got all the money beyond that,
that's awesome.
Like to stay home and he looks miserable
because he doesn't have any say.
He doesn't have any income and money.
So who has the money?
Has the power in the relationship.
She didn't even earn the money.
Came from the family.
Fantastic.
And they're involved too.
They're always around.
Oh no,
that's not good.
He's a weak,
weak,
weak.
So that's a dark place for a man to be.
No sovereignty,
no control of your existence,
no real financial decision making
ability because you don't bring in any
money.
She's scaring me right now.
Feeling that they settle for that.
Well,
you know,
let's little egalitarianism.
Horrible.
You know,
everything's great work.
Why should I work?
You know,
wilma makes all the money,
her name,
that relationship can't ever work that
dynamic.
Does it make sense to you?
Why would it work?
And it's like,
yeah,
I mean maybe the alligator and the cat
can be friends course and shit ain't
gonna work.
It's just not going to work.
It will work if it's not a real man and
the woman likes that scenario and the
guy's just like this spineless little
cheese head.
I think you're totally on pc and I think
you're right because I think he's got to
be kind of a beta male.
He's the guy who likes his balls busted
a little bit.
Maybe.
Maybe he likes his nuts squished.
He likes to be heard.
He's just scared.
Yeah.
You know,
look,
it's if you're in a relationship with
someone and that someone is a woman and
she makes far more money than you and
you just decided to let her pay all the
bills.
That is a squirrely proposition.
It may work.
It's entirely possible.
You might find the perfect woman and the
perfect man were their personalities gel
together.
Neither one of them gives a fuck about
money and yet the guy still a man and
the woman is still a woman,
is just that she makes all the money and
you know,
he kinda like does the dishes and takes
it in the ass.
She pegs him.
She puts out a strap on.
She,
she pisses his face and that's how he
gets money for food or beats or try it
out.
Try it out.
Equality.
She does whatever she wants.
She smacks him.
You can't leave.
It's like you think that's what's going
on?
Yeah,
I think so.
They have no power.
Well,
let's see.
What about oprah and stedman,
but steadman makes a living too.
Like he did what his steadman is like
one of those
pirate beers that you glue on at a party
and everybody knows it's not a real
beer.
I didn't even know.
It never really occurred to me.
I don't.
I don't know.
I just.
They've been together forever.
But could you picture opiate and pushed
me?
Yes,
a thousand percent.
But I think gail gail for her isn't so
much a lover as a mom.
I don't even know who gail is.
That's her best friend.
Guilt.
Come on.
Come on now.
Come on now for her bff.
That's the one they think.
Just friends.
No,
I don't know.
I don't know you.
I mean I don't possible.
That's not the case.
Yeah,
it's possible,
but they know.
I don't want to assume.
Oh,
she looks good there.
Oprah skinny.
I was skinny.
Oprah for all them stickers.
That's one thing.
Steadman's just steady and then go
nowhere.
What does it.
It doesn't even make a good living
though.
Doesn't he have a job
thing?
I think steadman does have stuff going.
Yeah.
I think he's like,
oh,
I want to say he's a lawyer or something
like that.
I googled them and said,
american educator,
so I don't know.
Well,
here's the thing or something.
Wouldn't you say that when someone
regardless of male,
female has nothing else in life going.
You know what I'm saying?
They have no drive,
no focus,
no,
no goal.
Yeah.
That in and of itself is a bad thing.
It's a bad thing regardless of being the
man or gender.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
People with no hobbies like you don't.
You don't enjoy doing anything.
Even if it's just like reading.
You don't.
You don't like doing it to do,
but you don't want you to do anything.
You don't want to do anything.
You don't do anything.
What do you do?
You watch tv and eat.
Oh yeah.
Billy say,
tell jokes.
That's true.
When they're not telling jokes,
they watch tv and eat.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I do that a lot.
Where are fucking weird group of people,
you know?
I mean if you really stop and think
about how odd our group is,
I'll have a little of that.
I don't want you to drink alone.
There you go.
Plus are probably should have a little
alcohol after all the alcohol I'd.
Yes,
yes.
Written 11 self help books.
Steadman bottom.
How to marry rich hose cope when your
wife is way more successful.
How to get,
get some rich policy.
I know you know as feminist as I am
because I obviously I'm down for the
cause.
What is the cause?
Well,
a quality to the choice.
To have choice.
To do what the fuck you want.
Do you want to stay home?
Raise your kids to home,
raise your kids.
You want to go have a job,
a fucking job.
I agree with that as well.
Yeah.
Maybe I'm a feminist.
I don't know it.
I think you are actually a weird.
I think you are.
What'd you get the ice this whole
fucking time.
It's been right here.
God damn it was a high class operation
stuff.
I put my fingers in there,
get in there.
Okay.
I trust you.
Oh gosh.
But here's the deal.
You know,
my mother was a european lady and as a
female comic,
I'm an alpha in the streets,
but I'm kind of a beta and the sheets,
you know what I'm saying?
I like to take care of my husband and I
think that's why tommy and I workout
because I like to bake fucking rice
krispie treats.
I have shit.
I food in the house.
I'm kind of a traditional wife.
Well you're powerful,
but you're also still a woman and
there's nothing wrong with that if
that's how you like to be.
The idea that there's something wrong
with that because you're supposed to be
even with him.
So you supposed to be treating each
other,
not like your traditional male versus
female role,
even if that's what you like,
that becomes a problem because it's like
a pressure problem that women will put
on other women to behave in a different
way because they don't want to reinforce
traditional gender roles.
Oh,
right.
Yeah,
sure,
sure.
Given that role feels right to you need
to do like it.
I like it.
I like taking care of my kids.
There's some dirty cops out there,
they'll tell you that's bad.
Angry bitches.
Yes,
that's true.
No,
you're right.
I've had some people say stuff to me
about it and I'm like,
well,
it makes me happy and if that's all that
matters and it's my choice to do that
stuff.
I'm not saying I do it every night.
One hundred percent.
Yeah.
Whatever makes you happy.
As long as you're not hurting anybody.
That's all that matters.
And the idea that there's something
wrong with you doing that.
Like this is fucking stupid.
It really is.
It's just stupid.
It is silly already talking about you
had a lot of that though.
What a lot of that stupid out there.
People telling people the way they
shouldn't.
Shouldn't live.
You know you,
you don't have much time.
I mean,
you and I are halfway done.
Basically almost dead when you think
about it,
when you turned 40,
you were like,
oh this is it dude.
Like yeah,
how much time you got left?
Hopefully another 30 years of good
living.
I'm saying before you really start to
break down,
shit starts falling apart.
Yeah,
we'll start coming off.
Yes.
Some people are worried about dumb shit,
like whether or not this woman works or
she should have a career.
She should do this.
She should.
She's happy.
She likes eating cheese and getting her
toes done.
Leave her alone.
Yeah.
That's funny.
I think that is a middle aged revelation
though.
You go like,
oh,
there's only so much time left.
I don't give a fuck about all this.
Like I'm gonna do me bro.
The guy that I know that stuck,
that's the wife makes all the money.
You could see it in his face though.
I could just see this quiet anxiety.
It's like a lion at the zoo where
they're kind of broken and they're like,
you know that they're a hunter inside
and out,
but you take that instinct away and they
get the meat thrown at them and they're
just like,
sadly,
kinda just eat the meat off the tray.
It's like a vegan cat.
Right?
Did you bother looking it up by looking
up and they're all skinny and shit like
just laying down?
A lot of them are fat as fuck.
All they eat is carbs.
I know that's the problem and down
fucking bloated kidney failure.
I know eyes are gray and dull.
A model.
That can be the problem with the vegan
diet,
right?
Is you're eating macaroni and cheese and
stuff.
Oh yeah.
If you go wrong,
that's why the healthy people call it
plant based because they want it to be
plant based.
Is this pasta all the time?
Yes.
Yes,
but you have to get a lot.
From what I understand that that plant
based protein,
a lot of it.
Yeah.
Well in,
in terms of protein,
there's some foods that are pretty rich
and protein.
The real problem is bio availability.
It's not just that there's protein in
it.
It's like how much of that protein is
absorbed in comparison to like a similar
amount of beef protein.
It's not as easily absorbed.
You can definitely do it though.
You could definitely live a vegan life
and be healthy.
You just have to really watch your p's
and q's.
You gotta really mind what you eat.
You have to take be 12 supplements.
You have to make sure that you're
getting the correct amount of essential
fatty acids and there's just,
but you can do it.
It can be done,
but it's not as effective.
It's not.
It's not as easy,
I should say.
It's just meat and vegetables.
You eat meat and vegetables,
you got your bases covered,
but if you just decided to just going to
be vegan,
like,
whew,
boy,
you gotta,
make sure you have keen our hemp protein
or in.
There's like certain plants that have
some amount of protein but they don't
have a complete amino acid profile.
It's tricky,
you know,
but the people who want the people who
live it,
they live that vegan life.
Boy,
they want you to think that that's the
only way to go.
You don't.
You don't live that way.
You're going to be sick and you're going
to be unhealthy.
And my favorite thing is when one of
those motherfuckers jumped ship living,
they've singing the praises
of vegan this and that.
I had a friend who lasted six months,
lasted six months,
and during that time he was telling me,
well,
the ethical thing to do,
you know,
I felt like I was a hypocrite if I
didn't eat vegan and then he ate vegan.
He started getting sick as fuck.
He got his blood lipids back,
body falling apart.
I was like,
bitch,
you need some meat.
I need some meat now.
He eats meat like crazy.
It's hilarious.
Six months later I ran into him at a
steakhouse.
Is he like,
fuck,
listen that the diet is just a lot of
work.
you can do it,
you can do it if you decide it can be
done,
but I have a friend who was a.
It was actually a doctor who was in a
motorcycle accident,
got really badly banged up and he was
vegan at the time and his wife made him
eat a hamburger.
She's like,
just do me a favor.
I just want you to eat some meat.
Like it wasn't recovering because I kept
really struggling to get over these
injuries.
He ate a cheeseburger and he said,
literally,
I was so overwhelmed with energy.
I wanted to jump out of bed.
He goes,
I never was vegan again.
He goes after that one juicy
cheeseburger,
he goes to eight.
I felt so good.
And the protein like my body was like
crying out for it.
Mcdonald's,
is that what you think is a good one?
I think it was a real cheeseburger with
real.
Mcdonald's is like prison style.
Cheeseburger,
juicy fat boy.
So good,
isn't it?
I know and I'm pregnant,
but uh,
but what I found interesting when those
guys were on talking about it is because
I like to eat salami.
I do like the process shit.
And he is like,
the processed meats are the no,
now that's what's going to give you.
But cancer,
unless you get a ton of vegetables to
offset the damage right in your colon.
Nitrites.
So I try to get the nitrite free
wholefoods shit.
Yeah.
Is that cool?
Yeah,
you can.
I mean there's,
there's organically grow organically
created chart shooter charcuterie
learned this word chart chart,
charcuterie,
charcuterie.
It's basically salami,
mortadella,
that kind of stuff.
But there's,
there's companies that make it
organically,
it just doesn't last very long,
doesn't have any preservatives in it.
Like that's really what you want.
But that's what gives you the.
But cancer is.
I'm sure that the real problem with all
these,
these assumptions is that these are
correlations based on mostly based on
people filling out questionnaires.
That was fascinating.
And how much do you recall what you ate
yesterday?
Accurately.
That's what's really interesting.
Good.
That's part of the problem.
And people tend to make themselves look
like the better than they actually do
the kind of lie because they feel bad
about being a fucking gluttonous slobs.
I'll ask my trainer because that lady I
do pilates with,
she put me on this primal diet and
that's my last baby.
Wait the first time I was like,
how many of your clients just stay fat
for years?
And then you ask them what they eat and
they just lie to you.
If she's like,
oh that's a lot of people.
Like they don't really have an
awareness.
You know what I mean?
Like you think you're doing one thing,
but the reality is completely different.
It's hard
for women when they get real big.
You know what your body wants to keep on
that.
Fucking wait is that your body is not
want to let that go.
It's easier for a man to lose weight.
Definitely believe that more muscular
your body has more caloric requirements
because there's all this muscle burn up
fat.
And then if you do lift weights,
which,
uh,
everybody who wants to get lean,
I always recommend you got to lift some
weights because if you lift weights,
your body is burning more fat because
it's adding more muscle so it's burning
more calories.
If you eat the same amount of food but
you just lift weights,
you're going to lose body fat and the
reason is because your body's going to
build up muscle tissue and that muscle
tissue is gonna have a caloric
requirement.
NoT that those calories,
if you eat the exact same amount of
calories,
but now you're eating,
you're eating all this food,
but lifting weights,
your body is going to get leaner.
As long as you're consistent,
you stay consistent.
And continue lifting weights.
You can eat like a fat ass and still
say that,
but I'm saying if you,
if you are on a diet like a sustainable
diet,
like eat a normal amount of food,
but you lift weights,
lifting weights is a great way to lose
weight.
It's a great way to lose body fat.
You won't necessarily lose weight
because you'll put on muscle mass,
but your body will burn off more fat.
particularly if you're a guy,
because it's easier to put on weight,
muscle weight.
No fuckin a man.
This fucking does this thing that we did
this month.
One thing that it did teach me is,
boy,
you can do a lot more than you think you
can.
I bet a lot more.
I bet tom loves it,
that the challenge aspect of it,
he loves to push himself.
The the.
Is it the sadist where you hurt yourself
or the massive cast?
Masochist.
You hurt yourself.
Say this,
you hurt other people.
Oh,
so the masochist in him,
the.
I don't know.
He.
He loves to challenge himself and do
these things with you guys.
I think it gives them a big charge.
He's a,
um,
I was a sadist when I was trying to hurt
burt Australia,
trying to get bird to try to keep up
with me so he would die.
Oh,
birds.
Everybody wanted to make sure that burke
came in last.
That's what everybody was super
concerned with.
Super conservative
going.
Well,
it didn't come in.
Last
mission accomplished came in last Year
when he was starting to pull where,
where am I going to put the bill on my
shelf?
I was like,
you're never getting that belt.
Oh,
bert will take you on a road through
hell.
You're not getting that belt
motherfucker.
So wait,
how did he go wrong?
He just wasn't consistent.
Um,
well there's a lot of things for sure.
He is overweight,
which makes it far more difficult to
keep up that amount of cardio because
your joints are going to hurt and you're
running,
you know?
I mean,
he's,
he's real heavy.
You knoW what I mean?
I think he lost some weight during the
program,
but he was two,
six,
something like that.
When he,
when he did it and he got down to 2:16
for the weight loss challenge,
right to 19 tommy,
two to 16,
so that's a significant amount of
weight.
We're talking about a good solid 20 plus
pounds,
30 pounds of weight that he put on,
you know,
that's a lot of weight.
It's fat.
It's just the stakes of fat.
When you look at what a pound of fat is,
because I've had to lose weight from the
second pregnancy.
I've gotten more efficient at it because
I learned how to do it,
but I have another 20 to go to where I'm
comfortable,
but god damn man,
that's a lot.
One pound lift up one of your kettle
bells.
What is it?
Ten pounds.
Thirty five pounds.
the the little chimp ones.
Those are 35 pounds.
That's what burt had to lose.
His carrying that 35 pound kettle bell
everywhere he goes.
that's a tremendous strain on your knees
on.
Also.
Body's just not used to exercise and he
has to take high blood pressure
medication which are guaranteed makes
you weak.
That's the fucks with you.
I mean he's.
He's taken something that's lowering his
blood pressure.
What else is it doing?
It's not just low on your bread.
Boozy using angels to do that with using
pixie dust to make sure that you're
super healthy and you don't have a
stroke.
Who knows what the Fuck that stuff's
doing to you and that's from like
cholesterol and his blood causing fat
and lazy and drinking from drinking.
Look,
I love her to death,
but he needs to hear this.
Got to stop drinking every night.
You can't drink every night.
You can't do that.
That's too much.
You know,
you look at tom,
tom lost all that weight and the weight
loss challenge and kept it off.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
I kept it off.
Oh yes.
Burton and keep it off.
well,
what's the difference?
Well,
burt ran a marathon.
burt burt does those tough mudder races.
Burt runs all the time.
How come birders and skinny because
birds drinking a fucking case of vodka
every night.
Well,
well,
how much is a glass?
I mean,
okay,
a glass of vodka,
glass of wine.
What is it?
300 calories,
let's say glass of wine.
Is it on there?
So you drink,
let's say you drink.
Those are two glasses a night or a
bottle of wine a night.
Jesus christ burt drank a whole box of
wine.
What do you mean when of those wine
boxes?
Like a whole box of one when he was self
here at night.
Oh no,
he was Talking to us about it.
Remember we talked,
we talked about.
Oh,
You drank a box.
It's a lot.
Well,
how many glasses are in that?
There's got to be like 20 glasses in
that.
So what is that?
Like a Milkshake and,
and,
and a cheeseburger.
Double cheeseburger.
Five liters.
Drank five liters to one.
Could have a small one I guess.
But fuck,
he did.
Why would you have a small one?
We could have a big one.
Five.
And it's like shit.
Shit.
Hawaiian sugary boxed one.
Not even the good shit.
Yeah.
Well I'm hoping that through this.
Um,
everybody kind of keeps up a certain
amount of fitness because it seems like
we,
uh,
we kinda boxed wine so much class.
So few calories.
I don't doubt that jesus was this one.
A few cows.
It.
Is it a spurt?
They're talking about that specific type
of wine.
Friends.
Ia is at a low calorie one.
WeLl,
there's that skinny,
skinny,
skinny one.
Yeah,
that one of the housewives.
Worst one.
I'm 10.
White wine.
Ryan has 110 calories.
Five grams of sugar.
Shiraz read 110 calories.
Ten grams of sugar just for a five ounce
serving.
So that's a small glass of wine or a
regular sized glass of wine,
right?
That's not that bad.
One hundred 10 calories.
So if you can keep yourself to one glass
of wine,
bad,
that's a big no,
no,
but you're doing the whole bottle.
Yeah,
that's not good.
If you were drinking a case of it,
if they're backing up one of those oil
trucks to your house,
just sucking on that dick of death,
all that.
All that wind dick jews coming down your
fat phase.
Especially if I do pilates,
that's where like 300 calories,
that's all for an hour.
Jesus,
you can drink that shit up and you know
what I mean?
One of the workouts that we did,
you know,
because I did,
I decided about,
I don't know,
I guess close to two weeks out that I
was going to start really pressure in
these guys and just doing workouts to
like five hour workout,
like doing shit.
That's just insane.
I was like,
let's see wheRe we're going.
Let's see how far we go.
One workout I did,
I burned 4,700
calories.
That's bananas.
It was crazy.
I was eating boxes of graham crackers or
animal crackers.
Ate a whole box of animal crackers.
Apples.
I drank a a cream soda,
sugar.
I just want sugar.
While I was doing it,
I was like,
I'm so taxed out,
but I'm gonna.
Keep going.
I'm like,
I need some sugar.
So I just ate these animal crackers and
drank soda.
Got right back on.
Yeah,
puppet master.
I just kept thinking about getting
tired.
How's he going to serve man?
So waIt,
where are you guys going?
Where are you guys going to do this?
I guess we would have to do it in like
malibu or santa monica or wherever you
could serve.
You know?
And we would have to figure out a way
that the app registers how much time
you're standing on the board.
So like you would have to be how much
time you're actually surfing,
not just go.
Just get on with believe.
No,
no,
no.
It has to be standing.
Standing on the surf board.
We have to figure out a way.
did you say was some sort of an app?
There's something that I passed.
I was trying to figure out what it's
tracking.
It's tracking like the board's movement.
I think so.
If you're doing side decide stuff,
it knows that you're probably up and is,
is it?
No.
If you're lying on your stomach,
just paddling.
I feel like a slob.
I don't think it would tell you that.
Tell you how hard that shit is though.
It's hard.
And tell you what the hardest,
at least from when I learned how to surf
a decade ago,
the hardest part is paddling out on that
fucking bored.
you're,
I mean,
you're going against the current,
right against the waves,
bang,
bang.
TuRned that board around.
You finally see the wave coming and then
you got to paddle,
paddle,
and then the pop up.
So right,
you're on your belly and you got a pop
up from your belly to standing like this
dude.
Like you got to go fast.
I don't know.
For me that was an and the board's
heavy.
At least if you're learning on a banana
board,
like When it was big ones,
you're probably not going to start on
like the one that fucking what's his
name was shane dorian.
Yeah.
Kelly's like,
you're not doing those boards right now.
You're going to learn on a big clunky
banana board.
Probably heavy as fuck.
And then if that thing hits you on the
head because you're.
Yeah,
settlements,
kill anybody.
That's the thing.
I was,
I was legit worried this year.
Like when my,
uh,
at the end of the thing when I was doing
like several,
a $5,000
or 500 point days I was doing,
I do like three or four in a row,
500 days,
which is like three and a half hours of
exercise.
There's a lot of work.
So much.
It was crazy,
but I was like,
ooh,
there comes a point where your body
starts failing.
Like I don't want anybody to die like
legit die.
Like this is a real issue.
Like you can,
you can have organ failure.
Have you just decided to push too hard
or.
We were getting really psycho about it
because I was so sad.
See somebody posting like big numbers
when you get real anxiety.
Even when you're ahead you'd see like
tom,
tom ran 13 miles when he was on the
antibiotics and everybody freaked out
and I was like,
what the fuck tom,
like angry at him because he posted like
600 points in one workout.
What the fuck?
Well I was concerned witH burt at the
11th hour pulling some crazy shit.
Not october 30.
First was halloween.
So tom was like,
oh,
he's with his kids.
He's trick or treating like he's not
going to go do some crazy.
What could he do though?
He was so far behind.
How far behind was he the last day?
I don't know the number.
He was pretty far behind tom,
like I think 700 points behind tom.
Oh,
he was like more than a thousand behind
ari.
Oh,
way more than a thousand.
Which you can.
I got an a day once you can get a
thousand dollars a day,
but you have to almost kill yourself.
You gotta you gotta knock on heaven's
door so far will you guys.
It's the worst.
And watching my spouse go through it.
I'm like,
ugh,
stop.
Well,
here's the thing.
When we started doing it,
no one thought we were going to do this.
No one thought we were going to try to
kill each other like this.
We're just joking around about it and I
always thought like my first couple of
workouts,
like an hour,
hour and a half,
200 points.
But then our,
he figured out that you could watch a
movie and be on the elliptical machine
and he got 479 points one day and
wrecked his body.
Could barely walk the next day.
But the fact that he did that and I
went,
oh,
and then I realized like we talked about
this,
you,
you get the same amount of points for 80
percent of your max heart rate as you do
for 90.
So I kept trying to go as hard as I can,
thinking that you would get more points,
but you don't get more points for that.
There's no path.
Yeah.
Slow and steady wins the race,
right?
Yeah.
Which that's not how I work out.
So I was like,
shit,
what am I going to Do?
So time on the board time standing on
the board over a month.
It's fucking hard.
Fucking hard.
It's so hard.
That should be hard and no,
none of us know how to surf at all.
How are you going to have like do like a
class,
like a quarter.
So we'll go and bird was like,
whoa.
Hey kelly's busy and you don't need a
world champion teaching you.
You fuck.
You need to like a regular surf
instructor.
What do you like?
Some prodigy that needs to be coached by
the best.
The fuck outta here.
Kelly slater is just dying to tutor
kelly's my friend you piece of shit.
First of all,
I think that's really talented.
Dude.
I'm closer to shane.
I'm pretty close with shane when shane
and I've been on a bunch of hunting
trips together now,
but uh,
I wouldn't go to him.
He's busy.
Super busy.
It's like if you said,
I want to learn how to kickbox and we
don't have the time to teach you how to
fight,
like I'm not doing that man.
Go find a coach because that's what they
do for a living.
Yeah.
There's a bunch of schools you can go
to.
Yeah.
I actually wanted to rent a house by the
beach next summer and just devoted to
learning how to surf again,
like really good at it.
I love the ocean.
I love rent a house by the beat,
like you super dedicated just to wake up
and go do it and then wow,
that'd be rad.
Right?
I wanT it.
That's,
that's a bucket list thing before I get
too fucking old to do.
Well,
it is something that you can do no
matter how old you are.
Yeah.
You can just ride waves.
One of the things that shane was talking
about that was really kinda interesting,
he's like,
everybody has the same amount of fun if
you suck at surfing or if you're really
good at it,
it's still fun.
I was like,
oh,
you know what else told me about kooks?
Do you know what a kook is?
Hooks lambs on instagram.
douchebags that wipe out cooks or people
who don't know what they're doing.
Yeah.
It's an instagram account called slams.
Oh,
it's surfing like people suck at it.
It's just what burt,
tom and ra are all going to be on.
Kooks slams was next year.
We're all going to be on that because
we're going to fuck up with.
The thing is like finding a spot where
you're allowed to serve,
where you can get in there where you
don't know what you're doing and you
don't get in anybody's way.
I don't wAnt to fuck up and his buddies
experience because according to all the
surf movies and stuff,
they got turfs,
bro.
You can't just roll up on the dudes that
are in malibu.
I don't want anybody to get mad at me.
You got to find because you know,
like I see them,
I go to watch them,
you know,
or that mastro's is and in malibu they,
there's a little thing where all the
surfers go and that's like one area and
then there's redondo.
You go down there and there's that area.
We'd have to learn surf etiquette for
sure,
but if they listened to the gre,
maybe there'll be cool,
maybe.
Yeah.
But maybe they'll be like,
hey dickhead,
you're going to get more people out here
surfing.
Fuck this up for us.
You know,
people have said that to me about
bowhunting.
Really.
You're getting more people out into the
woods,
you know,
that's annoying.
They were joking around about it.
I go,
are you serious?
He goes,
Well,
it's good because then we'll have more
people hunting,
but it's bad because I honestly see more
people hunting and I really think it's
because of you and because of cameron
hanes and steve rinella and John Dudley
and all these hunters that are
interesting,
cool people that more people are trying
it.
I believe that.
I believe it.
I think so too.
It's like I'm going to do.
It's like when taco bell chihuahua for
ellie's fucking douche bags are buying
chihuahuas for their kids for christmas
and then they'd throw them into the
pounds or whatever because they couldn't
take care of them.
They didn't know.
That happens every time there's a
talking dog moving.
Yes,
I do know that.
And then that popular breed [inaudible].
Everyone gets it and they don't like the
breed and then stopped talking to him.
Wow.
Why aren't you.
When she talks about chalupas,
meanwhile a chihuahua for the most part,
from the ones I've known,
the temperament,
they're very nervous.
High strung,
high energy dogs,
very skittish.
Not not the ideal family pet.
If your bones were made a toothpicks and
you're around a bunch of fucking clumsy
kids like kids are always stepping on,
wasn't breaking their leg,
happens all the time to cast a little
fat kid eating this candy,
not looking stomps on his poor dog's
leg.
Snapped it like a twig.
Fuck.
Imagine ogres around you.
Giant.
Huge,
enormous,
ogres eating candy.
Terrifying or dalmatians like every time
100,
one dalmatians comes out,
every fuckface beizer kidded dalmatian
for christmas and then aren't they
stupid?
Don't their brains to groW bigger than
their brains grow bigger than the skull
or something was out of the head of
school,
but the brain's otherwise they go too
much brains.
They had headaches.
You've got to kill him.
Was the brains out?
Weren't they like fire people?
Dogs?
Yeah.
Why is it.
Why is it dalmatian wide?
Wherever they connected to firetrucks
and shit.
No fucking idea.
Yeah.
You think you'd have like a smart dog?
Like a german shepherd?
I don't know.
The dalmatians are dying or they're dumb
or a dare damaged while his german
shepherds are super smart.
I know that's a highly trainable dog.
They're also like,
they're sizing you up.
Like when a german shepherd looks at
you,
he's like freaking out.
Like,
what's going on here?
What do you about you pussy.
How about if I show my teeth,
what are you going to do?
Scared of me.
Oh look,
you smell like fear.
Faggot it like a comedy audience.
Dude,
have a german shepherd could talk.
They would say some creepy shit to you.
They would.
It would be like,
what would happen if I bit you?
What would you do?
Wind fire departments have dalmatians.
Dalmatians and horses are very
compatible.
Oh.
So the dogs were easily trained to run
in front of the engines to help clear a
path and guide the horses in the
firefighters to fire as quickly.
There's still chosen by mary,
many firefighters as pets in honor of
their heroism in the past.
Oh,
so fucking heroic dogs.
You asshole calling them stupid.
The worst human being ever.
I'm always the person like,
oh,
they're crippled.
Okay,
great.
Yeah,
they're fucking stupid brain come out of
that is they're all dumb shit.
Worst person,
um,
their deaf.
Why are genetic predisposition for
deafness?
It's a serious problem for dalmatians.
Only about 70 percent of them have
normal hearing.
Depthness was not recognized by early
breeder.
So the breed was thought to be
unintelligent.
Oh,
that's interesting.
They're cute as shit though.
Crazy thoughts and shit.
Yeah.
I feel like if you're going to have a
dog,
a german shepherd,
you,
but you got to be around that fucking
dog all the time.
That work.
The dogs.
Yeah,
they're working dogs because if you
don't.
My dad got one from the past when I was
a kid and he didn't put in the time and
that dog tore everything apart and was
Just bored out of its mind.
You can't take a smart fucking dog and
just throw it in the backyard.
That's when they get in.
They jump out and they escape.
Escape.
yes.
Escape that.
A mother fucking.
No,
I can't hold me in with your bullshit
ass boats.
That's right.
For the rottweiler too.
That's a good one.
That's a smart dog to her mean dogs too.
They're good at being mean or that rock
wilder cup.
A rock.
The rock wild.
My rock wild.
I remember one time when I.
I adopted our first dog and there was a
guy next
to me and he was getting a rottweiler
and I remember the lady behind the
counter saying,
well sir,
you're,
you're.
You know that these dogs are highly
intelligent and they require hours and
hours of training.
You're going to do that.
Right?
And he was like,
oh yeah,
sure,
sure.
It's like,
you know,
he's not going to plug in.
This guy's not going to.
He's gonna paraded around the
neighborhood with a fucking dumb chain
around its neck and.
And that's it.
That's it for that though.
Yeah.
Dog's going to go nuts.
They go nuts.
Dogs need fucking exercise.
They need.
They need stuff to do.
like my dog becomes a different person
or different thing.
Rather,
when I take him running for purse,
he gets so excited when he runs,
he's like,
he runs,
he just,
he's got a big giant smile on his face.
He runs around.
He's like,
he's like,
yes.
He runs the hills.
He comes back,
everything cool.
Okay.
I'll say it takes off again,
but then when the end of the day comes,
you know,
an hour and a half later when we're done
running,
he's like,
ah,
he's just chIll the fuck out.
Fairly jumped in the truck.
He puts his paws up.
What's going to help them?
Some dogs,
if we do a mile,
he jumps in easy.
We do two miles.
It gets a little sketchy.
Two miles in the hills.
Hills make two miles a long way.
It's a hard time to get back in.
That truck is like,
come on dude.
You know you can pick me up.
I'll put my paws up here.
You know what?
Do you sleep with them?
No,
no,
no.
He's crate trained or what?
He didn't know.
He just sleeps outside the door of the
house.
I mean not outside,
outside,
outside the door.
The bedroom in the hallway.
Just,
he's,
he doesn't like beds.
He's weird.
I got him a bunch of dog beds.
It just throws his toys in that and
sleeps on the ground.
Well,
I actually had a dog trainer tell me
that the dogs don't need the beds.
That's a convenient thing to us.
He goes,
yeah,
but look at dogs.
They'll lay on the floor.
They don't.
They don't give a fuck about the bed.
That's you.
And you're definitely true with my dog.
He just doesn't use them.
I had beds like in three different spots
in the house and he would never choose
him.
I was like,
come on buddy,
lie down,
and I'm like,
what are we doing?
I don't want to come on buddy,
here's your bed,
and he'd step on the bed.
He's lIke,
what is this stupid thing?
Or they would climb off the bed and lie
down,
lie down on the wood floor.
I was like,
okay.
It's like that documentary about that
guy that got out of North Korea and the
camp and then they gave him an apartment
and they gave him a bed and he was like,
no thanks.
And he would just sleep on the floor.
Really?
Yeah.
There was some documentary I forget,
but he was in a camp in North Korea and
they finally,
they got them to soul and they're like,
here's your iphone,
here's the subway,
here's your apartment with all this cool
shit.
And he was like,
I'm good.
And he would lay on the floor and sleep
because he was so used to being in
prison essentially,
which is interesting how the human mind,
right?
When you're traumatized in that way of
thinking,
you don't even see what you have.
The human mind is so adaptaBle.
Right?
There's so many different ways to be
person.
So many different ways to live.
No.
um,
I was listening to a thing about trauma
and,
uh,
you know,
Vietnam war vets and how all that shit
works when you've gone through trauma,
it,
the rest of your life,
you're living in the past.
That's what that is.
To get locked in that one thing.
Yeah.
Just locked into the horrific memories
that,
that's not just the case for people that
have gone through war.
It's also the case for people that have
gone the grown up in really bad
neighborhoods.
Yeah.
Ptsd from the hood.
Sure.
Ptsd from violence that made it.
They saw at home domestic violence.
Yep.
Yeah.
And then I was listening to a podcast
about,
um,
about microaggressions,
social justice warrior podcast.
Well,
initially I didn't know.
It was like I stumbled and no on
apparently because I just was
interested.
I'm like,
what the fuck is,
what is a micro?
Like,
what is this?
You know what I'm going to learn about
it.
And uh,
and she was like,
I'm,
I'm a therapist and I treat people with
microaggressions,
you know,
there's like a million little paper cuts
over time.
And I was like,
okay,
well what's that?
And she's like,
you know,
if you're like an asian woman and people
are like,
they fetishize you and they're like the
hit on you,
let's say because you're an asian woman,
that's a microaggression.
So a year,
a lifetime of those little things you
need is trauma.
The trauma counseling,
they hit on you because you're asian,
like,
you know,
there's dudes out there that are just
strictly into asian girls or whatever.
Let's say for instance,
and you're an asian woman and a guy
comes onto you and it's traumatic
because you're like,
oh,
it's fucking pervert is,
you know,
just washed his feet and shit.
Right?
Or let's say a woman,
okay,
right,
I'm in a meeting just me and a guy
interrupts me and I want to talk.
That's a microaggression.
And I've suffered the trauma of that and
I need to be in.
What if the guy interrupted guy?
So that's still a microaggression.
Thank you.
I didn't get that far,
man.
I don't know.
Yeah,
it could be like a microaggression,
right?
Maybe.
Maybe,
maybe,
but that's,
that's a form of.
No,
there's a bunch of them,
you know,
compliments,
holding doors open for someone could be
a microaggression.
[inaudible] you're,
you're saying that the woman can't open
the door by herself.
Even just simple politeness becomes
chivalry isn't microaggression.
Right?
Right.
And again,
that's a form of trauma that needs
counseling.
well,
there's just a bunch of weak bitches out
there that can handle regular life.
So they want everything on nerfed up.
They went all language language,
nerfed up all behavior nerved up.
And then we're also encouraging people
that just can't let things off their
back,
which
is very dangerous.
Like the more people don't get offended,
the better off we are.
You know,
who fucking handled something absolutely
spectacularly.
That navy seaL,
who is a politician who.
I'm the guy from sarah live,
pete.
Uh,
ariana grande's was pete davidson.
They broke up after they got several
tattoos.
Pete was talking about him on saturday
night live and he said he looked like a
villain and a porno film and then he
joked around.
He goes,
yeah,
you mean,
I guess you shouldn't joke around about
it beCause he lost his eye and war or
whatever.
He's like laughing the whole time.
It's was like,
wow.
Like is one thing about joking around
about the guy looking like a villain and
a porno film,
but the joking around saying he lost his
eye and war,
like whatever.
I'm like,
man,
that is surprising that snl let that go
and they did it because the guys right
wing,
which is really fascinating.
Their bias towards the left and against
the right is so.
It's so obvious.
It's so crazy.
I mean that they didn't think that it
would be a problem to make fun of a war
veteran who lost his eye in combat
because the man in front of them was
blown up by an ied torres face apart and
ruined one of his eyes and he handled it
so well.
He said that he.
He said something about he works hard
not to offend an even harder to not be
offended.
It's cool.
Yeah.
But he also said that he really didn't
think it was a good idea to make jokes
about someone who said something.
I'm paraphrasing someone who,
uh,
who was disfigured in,
in combat.
Right.
Which that seems to be a pretty fair
line.
Yeah.
I don't think that's unreasonable.
No,
it's not unreasonable and I think he
handled it as good as you can handle it
when you're on television,
national television,
they're laughing and joking about you
having one.
I mean,
while you lost your eye in the service
of the country and an incredibly
dangerous thing that only the people who
have done it really truly understand.
And here's this young kid was bleached
hair laughing with you only having one
eye and he's doing it on a national
comedy show and people are laughing
along with them because you're a
republican.
Right.
And that's the interesting point is
because he is a republican,
it's kind of okay.
It's okay.
It's fucking weird.
That's weird.
Yeah.
But the guy handled it well and they
probably actually probably won them the
election.
That's probably how that shit goes.
Right?
People going to find out About it.
You know,
you make fun of the guy because you
think it's funny and then you're giving
them all this press.
He handles it well,
and then people are like,
oh,
that guy's a navy seal.
well,
I like what he says.
Listen to him talk.
Seems like a good guy.
Next thing you know,
he wins now.
So valiant.
I kind of wished mccain had a better,
better rap.
Really fucked up that sarah palin,
she was a ding dong.
That was preposterous.
Hey man and I,
I would love to see a woman in the white
house that was not.
Yeah,
no,
not that one.
She was real.
I'd take 10 hillary clinton for take one
and I don't want hillary clinton to win.
I think she's ridiculously awful too.
I think a lot of people really disliked
hillary.
Really disliked her.
They should,
yeah.
She got a shitload of money from banks.
She's completely full of shit.
She didn'T like gay marriage until 2013.
She wouldn't.
She didn't agree with gay marriage until
2013.
Like,
what are you a dinosaur?
what the fuck is wrong with you?
Why would you even care?
Because it's she's not real.
She doesn't.
She didn't care.
She just was doing what she thought was
support her position politically.
She was leaning right when obama was
leaning more left and she was trying to
center herself as a or position herself
as a a wiser choice for people who were
unhappy with the choices on the right
but really unhappy with obama and then
she was.
She was a better option.
She's more sensible.
She's a little more hawkish with a more
prone to go to war,
a little more pro military or at least
military action,
but meanwhile just a puppet of banks and
just those people make shit piles of
money from speeches and his major
problems with the clinton foundation.
It's not even around anymore.
Shut it down.
It's dark,
dark,
dark legion.
I mean,
while she's doing all this meat to talk,
her husband's had goddamn predator.
He's beeN a predator forever that I
think for women,
at least for me,
I was like,
stay with this bro.
Like come on nicole lewinsky thing.
She said that monica lewinsky was a
gRown woman and it wasn't an abusive
power.
get the fuck out of here.
She was twentY.
He was the president.
20.
Is there a kid?
He was the president.
There is no more powerful person on
earth.
That's not an abusive power.
What is an abusive power?
You're banging someone who works for you
and you run the world.
Did I know and I get it.
If I were 20,
do this sucked.
That sucked us all operating.
What's still operating the clinton
foundation?
What didn't they shut down?
Part of it?
Something shut down.
Um,
clinton foundation shuts down or cease
operations.
Look that up because there was some
article that I read about it.
I think for me,
just the whole stand by her man thing no
matter what,
it's just so antiquated.
Just going back to this,
tommy been stuff.
Read a tournament for killing satirical
site.
Oh,
did you?
Well,
so it didn't shut down at all.
Nothing.
Mama loser me according to fact
check.work.
Google a story
though.
See if there's a google,
a clinton foundation that these baseless
claims are made up by a self-describe
satirical website.
Oh,
so then I didn't reduce operations or
anything.
There's another thing that says from
2017,
they shut down the clinton global
initiative,
but would.
That was the thing.
It was right after the election,
which is two thousanD 16.
That's what I read that after the
election,
after it was all over.
I don't know either way.
I mean the,
the,
the clinton foundation,
super sketch,
one of the reasons that super sketches,
a lot of people that donate,
there's just a lot of weird shit going
on with donators and then them doing
speeches for these huge organizations
like banks getting paid hundreds of
thousands of dollars,
some boring ass speech,
which is essentially
bribe.
Right?
Right.
It's all it is.
Those people aren't pumped to see her
talk.
I don't think any of these people are
legit.
I mean,
no,
a lot of it too.
He's done a lot of those paid speeches,
but they get hundreds of thousands of
dollars to talk,
but I guess,
I mean,
look,
I don't want to fucking get into it,
but isn't that why people love trump
because he's outside of the whole
system?
Theoretically,
that's probably the part.
Oh,
here it goes.
Let's say end of an era.
The clinton global initiative shut
just part of the error.
End of an error,
not an error.
E r,
r o r,
when they asked him,
there was a.
There was an interview where they asked
him about monica lewinsky like,
do you owe her an apology?
IT's like,
well,
anybody who thinks so I got out of that
clean is crazy.
No,
the I call it cost me millions of
dollars.
I left the white house in debt and all
of a sudden that's not when anybody asks
you,
you fucking sociopath.
He has.
She thinks she deserves an apology
because he never spoke
to of course,
and meanwhile she was one of the first
people to be publicly shamed for
something of this nature.
This was a huge scandal and this is back
before the 24 hour news cycle really
stuck forever.
Forever for this poor woman's life was
over.
Done.
Just done.
Monica lewinsky synonymous with dick.
Sucker.
That's it.
Isn't that fucked up cloud.
You said it,
not me.
Oh shit.
Here we go.
Now I'm going to dare you.
I dare you.
I'm empathize.
I have sympathy for this poor girl.
Makes one mistake as a 20 year olds and
now her whole life is this scandal.
If you remember,
there was a town
hall thing that did on hbo many years
later where she was talking to a group
of people about the president about the
whole situation and in the middle of
like,
you know,
people would ask questions and talk to
her and one guy goes,
you know,
it just seems to me like you just
milking this for attention.
Like why even still talking about this?
But.
And she was like,
uh.
And he was like,
whY are you still talking about this?
If this is so horrific?
Like why?
Why do you keep bringing this up?
What,
what does she want to do?
Ha,
yeah,
what is she supposed to do?
But imagine being that person who was 20
years old.
So essentiallY you're a kid and the
whole world knows you suck the
president's dick.
SO everywhere you go people are like,
oh,
you presidents didn't like she's.
She said that it sticks like tar.
That's,
that was her description that the shame
sticks to you.
Like tar.
I believe it.
And what about Marilyn Monroe?
Was she second kennedy?
Everybody's dead kennedys.
Robert and bobby.
Bobby and jack.
But there is no evidence.
I guess there was no dress.
There was no.
Why was that?
The world was a different place,
but I didn't even have dna.
Right.
And then she,
she air quotes died.
TheY killed up itch.
Rude percent.
Hundred percent.
apparently she was all yap,
yap,
yap.
And she was getting older and nobody
wanted to bang her anymore.
Like I'm to do it the right thing.
You want to tell everybody?
Well,
jack,
I met with,
she was bobbing,
but she.
Yeah,
well at least from what I've heard read,
maybe bipolar.
Um,
she came from a lot of trauma,
severely abused as a child.
We got the orphanage really making shit
up.
No,
no,
she was.
She was pretty bad childhood man.
From what I know.
Makes sense.
Actress.
Yeah.
Exorbitant need for attention.
I'm converting it.
Comedians at least write their own
stuff,
right?
The actors,
like comedians with no punchlines but
here's but crazier because they always
have to get audition for stuff on a
nightmare.
However,
here's what I do admire aBout actors.
I feel like they're more in touch with
their feelings than we are.
Like that's accessing feeling like I'm
talking a real actors and shit.
Yeah.
wow.
I.
At least me,
I don't like.
I don't like feeling things too much
healing.
Did you know what I'm saying?
I get very last hole.
It gets very itchy and when talking
about feeling like I don't do that.
RighT.
I admire that you can access feelings
and in and show people feelings and
stuff,
I guess.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
I guess,
but I think the fake feelings,
I think this is the feelings they think
they should have,
so they just start crying.
I shouldn't be sad here.
I think they're sociopaths for the most
part.
The vast majority of actors,
what do you think about the actors when
they're making a movie and they have to
stay in character the whole time?
Oh,
those are the big associate sociopaths,
but the best actors to,
you know,
like the,
the best.
Yeah.
I saw The documentary,
the man on the moon about jim carrey
doing a,
what's the guy's fucking name,
you know,
andy kaufman,
calvin,
and apparently,
you know,
he stayed in character the whole time
and he.
And so he would annoy the shit out of
people the whole time and,
and throw tantrums and stuff.
And I was like,
well,
That sounds fucking terrible.
Yeah.
Just how about just act,
bro?
Other actors have broken that down and
made fun of people who do that.
I'm like,
I love jim carey.
I think he's so talented and so funny,
but I'd be really annoyed.
That would be annoying if you had to
work with them for six months and you
just.
Calvin.
Yeah.
Only annoying asshole.
And then do things like hold up
production and,
and you know what I mean?
Those are union people.
These are dudes that are up at like four
in the morning putting sets up and
lighting and that guy and that guy has
got to wait for you because you're on
your trailer pretending to be somebody
else.
You know whaT I'm saying?
Like she would hold up produce that.
That to me is district.
What he really did.
That's what this documentary is about.
Trying to remember.
I don't know if he officially set it in
it,
but I think he wanted that whole part
because they were filming it to be part
of the movie too.
And at some point they decided to not do
that and make the movie.
Oh,
okay.
So you wanted it included in there.
But he also has an to say he,
uh,
jerry lawler was really mad at him
because the rest of it was not the
relationship that according to him,
that was not the relationship they had.
They're like,
it was,
it was all a ruse.
It was like a wrestling type deal.
Did worked it all out.
Yeah.
But that's not how jim carrey was
acting.
He was just being addicted to them over
and over and over again,
pissing them off.
Oh,
that's unfortunate.
Well,
even not specific to this one person.
I jusT.
That seems absurd to me to pretend to
be,
but if you do it and it works and that
makes an awesome movie.
I don't know.
I mean like one of them Daniel Day lewis
characters.
He does that shit and he's the best.
Yeah.
His movies are all pretty good,
you know,
I mean just a few that I haven't seen,
but most of them that I've seen it
pretty goddamn killer.
That's pretty rad.
Is crazy thOugh mean you got to leave
him alone.
Let him do that stupid thing where he
pretends to be lincoln shit.
Did you try to watch that one?
We talked about it yesterday.
I was like,
jesus,
terrible.
Oh,
I couldn't do it.
Everything that white people like and
they give fucking awards to like these
white bomber movies.
I can't do it.
I can't watch the movie about.
The guy was fucking aids.
I can't watch the movie about lincoln.
I can't.
What about musicals?
Get the fuck.
Fuck your mother.
Fuck your life with a musical.
Can I tell you that the one I don't want
to see the most and I'm in a lot of hate
over.
Yes.
Yes,
because I found out it was wrapped.
Did you know that?
It's fucking rap.
What do you mean?
It's the music of hamilton.
It's rap music,
so it's not even traditional.
Listen to jim.
Wait a minute.
Doing rap music.
I can't do this.
No,
I refused to see that shit.
I was in manhattan last weekend and we
were passing By broadway and all these
old dead white people are stumbling out
of this theater.
Pretending they just enjoyed what
nonsense.
They just saw.
Pretty woman.
The musical fucking rubes are staring so
good.
the way she saying about sucking his
dick when she was a prostitute,
he was a rich guy.
HamilTon.
The story of tonight,
just a song playing.
I play to play me some of it.
Give me some song.
Is this white people or black people?
Both.
Cultural appropriation.
That's what I think.
Microaggression.
Is this supposed to be good?
Okay.
Kill it.
See just that hurt me.
I think they are a murderous assault
near your attention span.
That's what I think.
I've been to two musicals,
which now I've been to more.
I've been to more because I went to
where the book of mormon,
which is I guess technically a musical,
but awesome.
Like this book of mormon.
It's hilarious.
The south park guYs,
it's really,
really,
really funny,
but that doesn't count.
Doesn't count.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it's really good.
But uh,
I also went to see a chicago because a
friend of mine was in it.
It was death,
it was death,
it was death.
We all got together in the.
I'm in the fucking,
like,
there was the,
you know,
the,
the intermission and we all got to drink
during the intermission and I got three
drinks during the intermission.
I was just throwing them down and I was
like,
I can't believe I have to sit through
more of this shit.
And I'm like,
I can't believe you guys are sitting
here pretending that you like it.
I go,
fuck all of you.
And then they started laughing and break
it down because it was our friend.
I go,
she's great.
She's so talented.
I go,
this is death is death.
This is just a slow chip away.
The fucking worse dude.
I get people like it.
I get,
don't get mad at me if he like something
that I don't like.
Don't get mad.
You allowed to like whatever you like
and you're talking to a person who
watches professional pool.
I watch it on youtube.
I watch it.
I'll watch it live.
I'll go to see a match live.
I will.
Uh,
I,
you know,
I'm a fucking dummy.
Alright.
Don't,
don't listen to me.
I like dumber shit.
But if you have a world championship
pool matches right next to a musical.
Yeah,
I did musicals.
Let's talk the worst musicals.
I don't know the worst.
I've only seen three.
I saw cats.
Anything.
Andrew lloyd weber school that's cats
did.
Oh,
what did he,
how did he do that?
How dId he sneak that in?
An entertaining piece of shit through
peoples faces
for years,
for years and years and years.
People have for years,
for years.
I know.
I saw it in the eighties as a kid.
I saw it when I was 19 years old.
A girl that I was dating.
Yes.
She took me to see it like we were going
to pretend we were both 19.
We're going to pretend we're grownups
who went to see a musical and then what?
When it was halfway over,
I couldn't believe that it was only
halfway over.
I was like,
you mean this is halfway done?
This is the intermission.
Just like,
Yes,
the intermission.
I go,
do you want to get the fuck out of here?
She goes,
yeah,
I guess we can.
I was like,
you like this?
She goes,
no.
I was hoping it was going to get better.
I go,
how can we get better though?
How could it get better?
Like what are they going to do?
Is it all of a sudden going to be a
movie?
We're going to see aliens and fucking
laser beams and you got to stay tuned
because then they go into this spaceship
and they go to the grand cat in the sky,
the grand wizard of the cats,
but they don't talk,
right?
Yeah.
No,
the grand wizard comes down and talks.
oh,
I forget what the good part.
I think he talks.
He's like,
ma'am ma'am,
I don't even remember if they sing in
words,
but I remember them crawling around.
I was like,
what in the fuck is this?
Oh,
that's the thing I can access as a,
as an entertainer that like dorky
theatery the feet.
Like,
yes,
the theater thing would really be into
that.
Great.
He's so sMart.
He's very smart.
God dammit.
Okay.
What other.
There's more Andrew Lloyd webber's.
There's like the roller skating one.
Jesus christ superstar.
That one's not terrible.
Is that jesus christ superstar where you
are up here,
but I don't know tv last year too.
And john legend one for.
Wow,
you got.
Okay.
There's a thing that's gross awards for
art.
I agree.
Yeah,
it's a trick.
It's just a dirty trick to pump up
whatever fucking thing it is.
Whatever movie,
whatever television show.
Yes.
And I don't understand why people want
to watch these things.
I think it will be a nightmare to go to
one.
Um,
it,
you know,
god,
I hope my husband winds one if he ever
wants to for acting or whatever and it
gives a fuck.
Yeah.
I don't think he's here,
but uh,
I would hate to have to sit through that
horse shit for six,
seven hours in a gown and clapping for
nonsense.
Gone to the emmy's.
I went to the emmy's.
Uh,
right after,
uh,
phil hartman died because he was up for
an emmy.
So we all wenT and he,
he didn't win and when he didn't win,
the guy from frasier one and we didn't
win.
Dave foley turns to me and goes,
the flux you have to do to win,
right?
Was the last shot.
He's dead still didn't give it to him.
Well,
because what group of cons decides who
wins the condo board.
We were looking for a gay guy in The
outrage olympics.
That's like,
you got serious fucking score.
You got like a built in score.
Yeah.
If a guy plays a gay guy that's,
you have built in score like milk.
Yeah.
I liked that movie.
I liked it.
Could Win an oscar.
Did it?
Went in Russia?
I don't fucking know should win an
oscar.
He is playing a gay guy,
you know,
you know when you never went in Austria,
play a slow guy.
He can't even do it anymore.
I get mad that you didn't hire an actual
slow guy,
right?
Don't you think?
Thousand percent.
Yeah.
well there was the problem with jeffrey
tambor when he was on that training
show,
the problem was he wasn't an actual
transgender person and they got mad at
him right towards what the fuck is this?
That's what they were making fun of.
And simple.
Oh,
I thought it was a type of award award.
He got a nominee for the best actor.
Then I'm like,
no,
bro.
When I thought he didn't know his
nominee.
I know,
but I thought maybe you could in 2000,
2002,
you could.
You could play someone who the fuck he
want back then.
Yeah.
Well you were saying that they got mad
at the rock because he played an amputee
in a movie.
It's not really an api to scraper.
Yeah.
Stop.
He just,
they love being outraged,
but they do.
Yes.
Love it.
Yes,
they do because they're given a voice
now platform on social media and people
pay attention to it.
That's the biggest problem.
That's actually the problem to paying
attention to it operations and what has
helped pay attention.
Yes.
Which is why podcasts are so great
because you could do whatever the fuck
you want and you don't have a boss.
He'll everybody telling me you to.
You can never have the try it out.
Guy.
There he is trying.
Guy would never fly guy.
You could never.
If you had a radio show and he tried to
play that,
they'd pull you aside and go,
tom,
christina,
this is not what we do here at wk.
Rip and yeah,
I love that.
Yeah,
that was good.
Show.
Tell me what your time on a sitcom
please.
Um,
it was,
uh,
it was good because it was,
it was a job,
it was money and I never worked before
and never acted before.
It was fascinating.
Did you ever take a class or anything?
I took a couple of classes when I got a
development deal,
I had to take some acting classes and I
had a mean acting ladY that was trying
to
be my mom.
If I ever got a mom and she was like
telling me that I was going to have her
cast as my mom if there was.
I wAs like,
yeah,
the fuck she.
She one thing she said to me once,
she's like trying to mind,
fuck me.
It was really weird.
She was like,
I'm worried.
You going to go out there and you're
going to fail.
I go,
why are you worried about that?
Like,
what do you,
what are you talking about?
She's like,
because you don't seem invested in this
material.
I go,
this,
this sitcom that never went because it
fucking sucks that we're reading now and
it's not that I'm not invested.
It's just terrible.
If you want me to pretend that it's
good,
you want me to act it up like it's good.
I like what?
What kind of conversation we have in
here,
and she was like,
well,
you might get a script like this.
I go,
well,
let's hope.
I don't know either way.
I'm a fucking comedian.
Okay,
I'm doing this for money.
They they.
They offered me some money.
I to tell him that drives him crazy when
they find out that you're a comedian,
you don't even give a shit about acting.
I'm like,
yeah,
they're going to give me some acting
gigs.
I'll take it.
And she's like,
when she would.
it was real weird man.
Like really weird.
The acting world,
the coaching world is so weird,
but it's weird because the people that
are acting coaches,
almost all of them are failed actors.
They just didn't make it.
Otherwise.
If they made it,
they wouldn't be teaching.
They'd be out there doing it.
They don't want to teach it for the most
part.
Some of them do,
but so I did a few liberal was gross.
As soon as I didn't have to do it
anymore,
I stopped doing it.
Oh yeah.
The classes are terrible and I did a
terrible sitcom for six episodes called
hardball on fox.
It was a baseball sitcom that got
canceled and then I got a development
deal and then I got cast on news radio.
Next thing you know,
it's so crazy.
I had gone on to auditions ever.
One was for the hardball show,
one or news radio was the only two
auditions had ever been on for sitcoms.
Yeah,
it was bizarre.
Yeah.
I mean you're working with what andy
deck was on that show.
Yeah.
Candy,
alexander.
Stephen root,
dave foley.
More tiernan.
Phil hartman.
Yeah.
No,
it was awesome.
The cast was amazing.
That was like in terms of sitcoms,
it was like a best case scenario for a
sitcom.
Like in terms of like the,
the,
the writing in terms of like the
situation where you're.
I mean it was on there with phil
hartman,
you know,
I was like 26 years old and I'm 27
maybe,
and I'm working with phil hartman and
I'm like,
I can't believe I'm next to this guy.
Like I'm seeing you on tv and movies and
all the sudden we're in the same room
and we're doing a scene together so this
is so and then become his friend.
It was so strange.
That is surreal.
It was so surreal for someone with zero
intent on ever acting.
Then all of a sudden I'm acting,
you know,
and I'm like,
okay.
I guess some acting like that was.
That was part of it though,
was one of the reasons why I was
successful at auditions and stuff like
that because I'd never planned on being
an actor.
Didn't care
as much.
My world doesn't everything.
To me it was like,
well this would be cool.
Similar,
make some money here.
You know,
that was the whole thing.
It's like I didn't want to worry about
bills.
Like what made more money doing it,
how much,
how much can I make?
And I would literally ask like,
whenever something would come up,
how much does this pay?
How much?
How much can I get if I do this thing
that's always thinking.
Meanwhile was stand up,
I'm sure you were doing what,
you know,
$300 a weeks for how many years just to
just to do it just to,
well yeah,
but you get worried about money coming
in,
right?
Because if you don't get booked for a
couple of weeks you don't have any
money.
So I didn'T save any money.
I had like a thousand dollars in the
bank or something and I'm like,
gosh,
you know,
so if anything went wrong I was fucked.
So coming ouT here and doing sitcoms.
But the thing about sitcoms is it's
really hard in the beginning,
like the early days of news radio were
hard long as ours we,
we,
it was hard trying to figure out the
direction of the show.
There was a lot of rewrites.
There was a lot of work.
It was a lot,
a lot of long days on the set.
But then once it got going like season
three,
four,
five,
boy,
it was easy.
Really easy.
Like You'd come in,
we rehearsed for a couple of hours,
go home.
We were down two,
sometimes three days a week,
one day a week.
Have a table read one day blocking,
one day shooting.
Bam.
Yeah,
we did that a few times.
Fantastic.
Yeah.
Three,
four days.
Four days was common.
Very rarely will we do five whole days.
That's fucking great.
Fear factor.
What was the work schedule like for
that?
One?
Three days a week,
but constant.
We did one year,
tHirty four episodes I think.
Maybe 36.
Oh,
we just shitted out.
Well,
America was eating.
We're shitting shitting on that plate,
which they should though,
because that show was so clean.
She set up the game.
It was very lazy.
It was very easy to do initially,
but then the second version of it,
when it came back in 2011 or something
like that,
that burden was a real problem because
that version that we're ramping it up
there.
The stents were way more difficult.
Way more dangerous.
It was.
I was freaking out,
but a couple of them I was like,
this is getting rough.
Like bungee jumps off a fucking
helicopters in the middle of a canyon.
You launching people on these bungee
jumps.
It Was some crazy shit.
You know,
eating stuff always got to me know
people eating the bugs.
I was always like,
how much money did you win on that show?
I can't remember.
You could win.
Well there was a couple of shows where
people want a million dollars,
but even when you win a million dollars,
you don't really want a million dollars.
You win a million dollars for The
government comes in,
steals everything,
right?
Yeah.
Plus it.
Is there something for winning and on a
game show,
like do you have some more taken out
because it's a winning or something.
I don't know.
It's a lot like if someone won $50,000,
which was a normal week,
that would really take home 34.
The government doesn't eat any animal.
Dick's jump off any buildings and they
just steal 16 grand for you animal.
I remember the animal decks now.
That was my favorite.
The we,
we did that in griffith Park.
Camped out.
Served up animal dicks.
Fucking crazy.
What a crazy show.
Thinking back the liability on that
fucking thing.
What's really crazy is it all happened
post september 11,
like right afterwards.
That's when it aired and um,
it was a preposterous show like from the
jump and I always thought it was going
to be canceled and it was a giant hit
was a giant hit and be able to like
immediately it was a hit.
I was like,
this is so stupid.
The show is so stupid and the reason why
it's awesome I got the gig was because I
made fun of it.
Like everybody else was trying to like
be spooky.
Like they're like,
you know,
the fear is fear a factor for you.
And I came into this meeting,
I was high as fuck.
I came into this meeting and they were
telling me what they wanted to do.
One of the casting directors got jeff
from nbc hooked up the meeting.
He thought it would be a good,
good fit for it because it was,
you know,
I've just been on nbc for news radio
that I came into this meeting.
I was like,
what are you going to do?
I'm like,
you're going to sic dogs on people.
this is like,
I'm like,
this is like a bit in an act.
And he's like,
like a bit of like where it goes
terribly wrong.
You going to make people eat animal
dick's just sick dogs on people and get
to throw people off buildings.
I'm like,
this is.
This is like the running man.
It was before here.
Idiocracy was even a movie.
I was like,
this is.
This is the most insane idea for
television show I've ever heard.
This is going to be cancelled
immediately and I'm going to have all
this material about.
Remember when I used to host fear
factor,
meanwhile a hundred and 60 fucking
episodes later,
we did 148 episodes and then we did
another.
I think we did six or seven but only six
aired because one of them was the one
when they had a drink come.
Yeah,
a jug of come.
Who made it a donkey?
Donkey.
Yeah.
My mom took me a year to fill up
everyone's stein.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Donkey come cattle prod up a donkey's
ass hole.
And they would come like they'd zap,
zap them in the old testes and they just
shoot buckets.
Yeah.
And they played horseshoes.
So they played horseshoes and you could
never win like even if you made like a
ringer and you like made the,
you would have to drink one ounce,
but if you fucked up and we were
drinking like 11,
ounces.
he was a jugs jugs.
Yeah.
So what happened was,
I remember,
yeah,
I remember this.
What happened was um,
the uh,
tmz folks got ahold of the fucking.
They got ahold of the pictures of these
people drink and come early and then it
became this giant fear that like,
people like what?
Like there's no way.
This is real.
Like this is a Joke,
right?
No.
It turns out they really can't make them
drink.
Come,
chug down.
Yeah.
I encouraged this girls.
one of them had a drink piss and the
other one had a drink come.
This is crap.
It was in st louis.
These guys are drinking coffee or
drinking a jug.
Oh come.
And he just choked it down.
His brother is right next to his twin
brother helping him choke down,
come how much money and not enough.
Thirty four grand,
whatever they want.
Even if they want a billion dollars,
if warren buffett's sucks and then look
immediately you get to throw up and
these poor girls would jump in.
Here's this interesting girls chose to
come over the urine.
I mean,
yeah,
we're come drinkers.
You learn to do the shit when you're 15.
Man,
she's been training her whole life for
this moment.
It's so hard,
so hard to imagine that.
That was real show.
I know looking back now,
but at the time everybody watched this.
Every.
It was normal.
Well,
this was the one that killed it.
That episode killed it and now ludicrous
took it over.
Alluded.
Damn.
But ludicrous is doing like a like,
whoa,
woo.
Is it fear factor if you leave your
house without your phone like.
Right?
Like what are the.
What do they do?
They don't do anything.
Nothing scary.
Is it still on there doing season two
now?
There's definitely no.
I figured something would be updated
recently.
Maybe it was a hit.
Maybe.
I don't know.
Lulu they came to me though before this.
I'm like,
bitch,
there's not enough money.
You don't have enough money to go.
You wouldn't ever a hosted again.
It's over.
I did it.
I'm so not interested,
but I'm glad I did do it.
It was,
it was great for the time.
I mean that was a good memory thing and
it's good.
It was good because it was money.
That's what it was good.
It was good because I didn't have to
worry about money.
And then when you have to worry about
money,
like you don't worry about your choices
comedically,
like I didn't worry like,
oh,
if I say something then they're going to
cancel me or fire me from the show and
then I can't do it anymore.
IT didn't.
That wasn't,
that wasn't my concern at all.
My concern was like,
okay,
now I have enough money so I don't have
to worry about not having money and I
already make money doing standup.
So now I put some money away.
So now you're free.
Now I can do whatever you can create
whatever the fuck you want,
just just fRee to do standup and free do
it however I want and no worries about
tonight.
Show sets or anY of that fucking
nonsense.
So wait,
so that when you were doing,
excuse me,
fear factor,
was there a thing where you couldn't
kind of deer stand up the way you wanted
to say before that?
Yeah,
and there was some concern with that to
go there.
Talk to me once about drugs.
They talk too much about drugs.
LIke,
like one of the producers pulled me
aside and it's like,
you know,
you're doing these interviews.
We're talking about like,
these,
these are illegal drugs.
I go,
yeah,
you should do them.
Should do dmt.
It's good for you.
A lot of people do.
They're also sacraments that have
existed throughout history that people
have been using religious ceremonies to
become one with the creator because you
want to fire me,
fire me,
go,
go call mario lopez.
He's ready.
What a career.
That guy's hat on that stuff go.
Yeah,
he's great at it though.
How about adam corolla?
He could to take an over fear factor
problems like that.
But now look at your.
Your to,
to quote adam,
curl your pirate ship,
right?
Adam carolla calls it a pirate ship.
That podcasting,
is that what he calls it?
His podcast,
a pirate ship.
Pirate ship.
He's,
you're out in the middle of nowhere and
doing your thing.
You got your signal.
Oh no one's regulating this shit.
Oh,
because it's like pirate radio?
yeah.
Well he was one of the first ones to do
it.
I mean I remember doing his show
thinking,
wow,
this guy's got a setup because he had
this place and he had like a booth and
there was guys working behind the booth
and you know,
you had a real ad copy and a desk.
I was like,
this looks so professional.
And he would do like ad reads just like
a radio show.
Wow.
But then that's how tom and I would look
at you and be like,
fuck,
you see joe set up.
This guy's got like cameras and he's got
like a producer we had.
If I can do all that.
He does have that now.
Chairs and shit.
you got to get some ergonomic chairs.
Got those.
yeah.
Was a company fully that send it to us?
I think it's called fully.
These are the best ergonomic chairs by
far.
I've tried every one of them.
This cup pisco,
these things are the shit.
They're so good.
They just,
they never hurt your back.
When you sit in them.
There's something about the way they
designed it where your posture is just
posture's good.
Good.
It's better when you're on camera
because you're not hunched over,
Like slumped can't.
You can't slump in these things.
They figured it out.
I did do.
Fucking nailed it right jamie bro.
nailed it.
So your netflix special.
Yes sir.
Probably talk about that before this.
That's what we're here for.
you.
You got your second netflix special.
I did a half hour cause I was um,
I was building my,
my first hour is mother inferior.
It's on the service now.
You can see it on netflix and I was
building my second hour and I was
talking about me to all the time and I
found myself just obsessed with telling,
talking shit about all these
motherfuckers who are getting,
you know,
whenever pulled left and right for me to
sound like by the time my next hour
comes out it's all going to be
irrelevant.
I just want to put it out there now,
so they offered me a half hour and it
was five months pregnant or something
like that.
So you only have a couple months to
throw something together and that's it,
man.
I went to vegas.
Pregnant is fuck.
It was like a hundred and 20 degrees.
Joey diaz in me in the desert with these
crazy fucks in fremont.
A lot of women are doing specials
pregnant.
So it's a stupid question,
allie.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I know.
I throw out a joke to allie in the
beginning of the oge of all that she is
pregnant.
She is.
do we really appreciate is the pregnant
standup?
Because if you think about it before
that nobody ever did a special where
they were pregnant and now a bunch of
chicks are doing it.
Well.
Yeah.
And I think what happened was we are all
of the age where we're more established
in our careers and it's a time where
you,
it's last call for all of us older
bitches to have babies,
you know what I mean?
Like now's the time.
So yeah,
it all kind of the timing of it,
but it's also like there's something
cool about filming it while you're
actually pregnant.
Yeah,
yeah.
It's a.
Well,
right,
because the assumption is you should be
laying at home eating bon bons and you
know,
my second pregnancy I did polities up
until about two weeks before I delivered
and I was eating well and really doing
it right the second time because I
fucked up my first pregnancy.
I was eating carl's jr twice a week,
getting those extra onion rings,
eating in the parking lot and shit
again.
Like,
oh my god,
I gained like 60 pounds 60.
Yasmin.
I was real fucked up after that one.
So how long does it take you to lose
that weight?
A year.
Took me a year because I didn't know how
to lose weight and I didn't know how to
exercise until I found this woman I'm
with now.
My trainer put me on the primal diet.
Uh,
but anyway.
Yeah.
So I talk a lot of shit about the me
too.
I wanted to just get it out there and
uh,
it's on netflix now.
I'm number six after Mr.
Diaz.
I'm just.
Yeah,
number six.
So it's cool though that you've got to
out right now too.
So fun.
It's so special.
It's such a.
It's such a good time for standing up.
It's such a golden age and where I'm so
excited to be where I am in my career
to,
to ride this wave,
to be at the comedy store now amongst
legends amongst you and bert and you
know,
my husband and all these great people.
It's very rare that a comedy couple has
two people that are really good.
RIght?
You guys are one of the very few things.
It's usually one that stands out.
One that's like,
what is she going to do when he
divorced,
when we talk about that tom second wife,
but she going to be like,
what is she going to be going to be a
dalmatian white sweeney fucking 20 years
old.
Not,
not a lot of ideas.
Not very mouthy.
Not like me.
Keep it shut.
Yeah,
just carries water.
dude,
she's fit.
It looks good to the gym.
She's gonna be a trainer.
Course can be trained or body.
Right,
right.
no bullshit.
You are one of my favorite comedians.
Stop it.
You're not saying that because I know
you really are.
You're,
you're,
you're really good.
You're really good.
And it's,
it's,
uh,
it's very odd that two really good
people,
uh,
are not just married but actually get
along together and are both really funny
and work together on a hilarious
podcast.
I mean,
you guys have a very unusual
relaTionship because the thought was
never dated a comedian.
Like that's what every comedian always
said.
Don't ever date a comedian just doesn't
ever work out.
And uh,
I know,
but you guys are.
We're like motion natasha.
That seems to work too.
Yes.
Yeah,
I think,
but I can't speak for them.
I don't know.
Probably just motions.
A little bitch.
And then tasha just runs right.
If you had to guess.
Just kidding.
I love both of them.
Both of them.
I can't say.
I don't know,
but there seems sweet.
They're great.
I'm just kidding.
I'll tell you what,
the motion's a smart motherfucker.
They both are brilliant.
They're brilliant.
I think my husband is one of the
funniest human beings on the planet and
Was always supportive and we started at
the same time and there was something in
being an open miker.
We were in the trenches together from
day one and we never did that shit where
I opened for my husband because
it's also a trap for women for female
comics because then you're just your
husband's opener.
You never establish her own thing can
happen.
Yeah.
That's happened for people that we know,
but the people that we know when it
happens for the opening acts always
terrible.
The wife that always opens for the.
See,
that's the difference between.
Well,
it's you guys,
it works.
Like I said,
moshe and natasha,
those two are very funny.
They're both really smart.
That works.
Yeah.
I'm rich vos and bonding with pharrell
and those two are really funny.
That works.
Yes.
And then who else?
I don't.
That's it.
I think that's it.
Very rare.
Yeah.
But I think we,
uh,
he's very supportive of me and,
and this is not politically correct
either,
but I think that there's a hierarchy.
He's way more famous than me and,
and that's fine and that's good.
Do you know?
It doesn't,
that doesn't fuck with you at all.
Do you ever think about channeling them
in to sleep?
Put the pillow over his funny jokes,
but I think that can be a problem if the
other person has an issue with the mr.
Um,
mr harwood that horseshit.
Yeah.
Right,
right.
And I,
I,
uh,
I've seen other couples where one is
more famous and the other one doesn't
accept it in.
That fucks with them for.
Yeah,
I'm happy where I'm at,
put it that way.
All I ever wanted was to sell enough
tickets to tell jokes to people who knew
who I was when I showed up and I'm there
and that's all I've ever wanted is just
not to be doing like the dinner.
Quite honestly.
That is all anything ever.
That's all it ever is.
It just gets bigger in terms of the
numbers,
but that's all it ever is.
That when you get to that,
that's the best.
Like if you get to that at a comedy club
or you get to that where you're doing a
giant ass arena,
it kinda feels the same.
Yeah.
Because you're at,
you're at fucking arena,
which is crazy to have watched you go
through.
I mean,
I don'T know.
It's weird.
Don't get diarrhea.
No,
no,
no.
The last arena that I did was the
biggest one,
the,
the um,
we used to be the air Canada center,
now it's called the scotia bank arena.
And in Canada that fuck that the ufc is
there next month.
That's places giant.
And when I did that one,
it was bananas.
Like I'm standing out there looking at
all these people make this is fucking
insane.
But once the show started rolling,
it was like a regular show.
Right.
you don't look at all of that.
it was just fun.
It was just fun.
But it was fun.
And so as a club,
like if you go to the funny bone,
you know,
that's just as you go to columbus
funnybone just as fun punchline in
sacramento.
Yes,
I agree.
And there's something.
I love clubs,
I love small rooms.
I also think too about my husband,
which is amazing,
is that it never gets to him.
Like he never sweats himself.
Right?
Like he sold out the fucking we'll turn.
This is a year ago and I got to open for
him,
which I sold them to you and I was like,
tommy and I grew up in la,
so selling out the wiltern to me is
like,
you just ban your.
Yeah dude.
Like I grew up going to shows there.
I'm like,
tommy,
you sold out the fucking wheel turn.
and he literally was like,
yeah,
it's cool.
Anyways.
What's for dinner?
Like it doesn't even phase him.
Now he,
he understood
stands traps and he doesn't allow his
brain to go on any mental traps.
Hell no.
Whereas like burke crash,
we'll be making
the wiltern.
What's the trap there,
joe?
I'm the ego just to eat.
You got to the,
the,
the most important thing is being in the
state of mind that you could be in to do
great comedy and that that is not a
congratulatory state of mind.
That is the opposite.
No,
that's so interesting.
Yeah,
because I,
I sold out carbs like a,
like a while,
right?
And I was like,
oh my god,
like I can't,
I can't believe these people are here to
see me now.
like,
oh the pressure because I'm finally,
you know,
moving the tickets and this and that.
And,
and then I was like,
I don't,
don't even think like that.
Like get into your self-loathing cause
that's where you're funnier,
right?
Don't think about,
yeah,
get into whatever state of mind that it
takes for you to do your best.
That's what you're doIng.
You want to go out there and rock that
crowd.
That's exactly.
That's all it is.
And whatever you need to do to do that.
But you definitely don't need to be self
congratulatory.
Let's say that's the worst
instinct.
No,
because I've done stand up for people
who didn't give a shit for years and who
would sit in the front row with their
arms crossed and who the fuck is this
bitch?
Fuck you.
That's,
you do it.
Right.
And also those moments are fucking
critical.
You know,
that's why I feel bad for people that
are famous that try stand up as a famous
person like jesus.
That's a hard thing to do.
Oh yeah.
Like I've watched people do it that like
charlie murphy,
he that guy.
I mean I love that guy to death,
but one of the things I resPected about
him more than anything was that he
literally was an open miker.
While he was famous,
mean he was just starting out doing
standup while he was on the chappelle
show.
He'd been an actor all these years.
So for him,
like he realized,
hey,
this is.
I'll host a show and bring up these
comedians and I'll tell a story or two
because this is a good way to make some
money.
And then he realized like,
wow,
there's a lot of money on for me,
I need to just do some standup.
JusT started writing,
stand up.
And he and I went on the road when he
had been doing standup for two years and
we co headline together was bananas two
years.
It's two years and already famous as
fuck,
you know,
and famous for being one of the most
famous comedian of all times,
brother,
which is a huge deficit.
Yeah.
Yes.
Giant.
And he had a joke about it and he's
like,
does it bother you?
You know,
that uh,
you know,
the people know you from,
uh,
the,
you know,
dave chappelle's show.
They're always saying that.
He goes,
he goes,
no motherfucker.
He goes,
for years.
well,
it does bother you.
People yell at me.
He goes,
no motherfuckers.
For years I was just eddie murphy's
brother joke around about it onstage,
you know,
that's very self aware.
He was great.
He was such a good dude.
Imagine the courage to start standing
up.
Fuck that.
So much harder and to go on the road
like immediately he was on the road like
immediately.
Even like brendan schaub,
who I love so much,
the courage to start standing up and to
get out and do it the right way.
You're like,
damn,
that's so good.
But at least brendan came through
podcasting,
which is a lot of shit.
Talking like ad libbing and getting
laughs,
you know,
you're getting laughs with comedians and
he had a lot of comedians telling him
that he was funny,
you know,
and then he tried it just dipped his toe
in there and they just ran with it.
Yeah.
IT's amazing.
he's about to do a showtime special.
He's filming the showtime special in
january.
Brandon?
Yeah.
Okay.
Mr.
Shot two years in sometimes he kills.
He fucking kills people.
Like how good is he?
I am telling you that mother fucker
works hard.
He's funny.
He's naturally funny.
He's a great guy and he kills.
He really does.
Yes he does.
It's ridiculous.
It is ridiculous.
But I tell a lot of comedians,
I go see that's what happens when you've
got an athlete's mindset like an
athlete's determination and discipline
and apply it to an art form.
I keep,
makes himself work.
Either you fuckers,
he just like get high and go to carnies.
Get fucking chili dogs because I think
that's the assumption.
Assumptionist as a stand up comedian,
people are like,
you just lay around and jack your deck
all day and do work.
You're like,
well,
those of us that actually want to
produce ours that are worth a shit.
We this as a job,
dude.
Yeah.
Have to.
Especially once you start poundinG out
stuff like tommy does what?
He's doing one,
then he does another one two years
later.
Does another one,
two years later.
Bar does that.
I do it that way now.
the way to do it,
the only way to do,
and you have to be writing all the
fucking time.
It'd be performing all the fucking time.
There's no other way.
I know I loved watching you work out the
megan.
Megan kelly.
That's her name.
Sorry.
Megan.
Megan,
it sounds weird,
right?
Again,
you see like a word where it is.
Yes.
Can I,
can I just tell you what,
you know,
el torito my whole life I was,
I was going to el cerrito and then um,
one day you're like,
oh fuck,
that's like the little bowl dude.
that means the little bull,
el torito stupid fucking dumb.
Uh,
but watching you work that stuff out is
so exciting.
I love your last special because you say
so many risky things,
which 10 years ago,
not that risky in terms of the climate
and now like I was like,
where's he going
do with this shit.
Just going to navigate the waters just
more effectively and more carefully and
then just set things up better and your
writing has to be better.
I think for me,
especially with the subjects that I
cover,
but I also felt like this was my most
virtual special.
Absolutely.
Well,
the title strange times.
Great.
Yeah.
I felt it was the most controversial
because I felt like I needed to be.
I needed to touch on the things that
seemed to be dangerous to touch on.
Like he said it best.
He's like,
standup is dangerous again,
like this is.
This is a fun time for standup because
it's actually dangerous.
I agree.
This is why I wanted that meet my me to
shit to get out there first time I'm
going to do this.
I'm not.
I'm not here.
Not said the other female comics aren't
talking about it.
I don't know because I literally go to.
I do the early show at the store.
I'm home in bed by 9:30
because I got babies,
so I don't know what everyone else is
doing.
I it,
but I want to put it out there.
I had that impulsive need to like just
fucking walk the line and let's see and
let's.
Let's stir some shit up.
Beautiful.
Start some shit up.
All right.
Let's just wrap this fucker up.
Christine.
Thank you for everything.
appreciate you.
Is always awesome having young.
Tell everybody your instagram is
christina.
P two p
christina,
p on twitter,
the degenerates.
I'm after joey ads on netflix and mother
inferior and mother and fear during the
ride or die tour,
bro.
January.
Check it out.
That's it.
shows up.