We're here,
ladies and gentlemen,
the Party's already started with
drinking something that my friend Ben
O'brian invented.
It's called an right brain.
It's a whiskey and Alpha brain and it's
delicious in a Yeti Tumbler.
Cheers.
My brother.
Good to see you,
buddy.
Yeah,
man,
it's been a while.
You're living the good life and I'm
still kicking.
You know,
it's another good day.
I'm still vertical.
Yeah,
but you live in the good life,
man.
You're,
you're,
you're out doing what I want to do.
You're out there in the fucking great
state of Montana.
Did escaped.
I landed on Saturday and yeah,
I lived in San Diego for I think almost
10 years.
Love San Diego.
No,
no complaints about California.
It's beautiful.
The beaches,
there's mountains.
All that stuff.
I love it.
Landed San Diego,
got in the rental car,
was going out to skydive and couldn't
even see the mountains out by where I'm
going.
A good job because it was all hazy and
smoggy and it took me longer to get out
of the parking lot than it does to like
get back to my house.
Go shoot the bow in the back yard,
go do a workout.
I was still in the San Diego
international parking lot so I can't
wait to go back.
Yeah,
there's good and bad.
You know,
there's good things about the big city
life,
you know,
you get a lot of great restaurants,
a lot of cool shit,
but you've already done that.
You know,
we moved to a town that has 22,000
people.
Wow.
From a subdivision of San Diego that at
260,000
people and I honestly,
my only regret is that it took us so
long to pull the trigger on doing it.
It is unbelievable.
And have you done the winter?
Yeah.
That there yet?
Winter's coming.
So you haven't done it yet?
Yeah.
Once I visited the winter last year,
we were there for the whole month of
December.
There was a few days it was negative 10.
Okay.
Which I found a few stand close enough
to the fire.
It feels just fine.
Yeah man.
I just wear a nice thick,
like a real good jacket,
you know,
were good,
will undergarments.
I know it'd be all right.
I know some people who work in the
industry have to make the cold weather
gear just from my old job and they sent
me some stuff so it's really not that
bad and there's some things in life that
I will spend good money on.
Cold weather gear,
rain gear,
just pony up and pay the extra money
because it's going to pay off for you in
the end.
Yeah,
it get some real shit.
My friend Tony Lives in Columbus,
Ohio,
and he.
The way he put it,
he goes like,
look.
He's like,
here's the deal.
He goes,
you can't really dress for hot weather.
well,
you could dress for cold weather.
Those you wear warm clothes and cold
weather,
you're fine.
And he goes,
but when it's hot out,
it's just fucking hot out.
You got to go indoors or you can meet
up,
but then once you get to that level,
you're done.
Yeah,
but even when you knew that hot,
but it's like La has no.
Whether it gets,
it gets hot and that's it.
It rarely rains.
If it rains 20 days a year,
it's crazy.
Nobody knows what to do inside.
I'm not going to lie.
I was,
I was laughing and very happy when you
were posting about.
It was like 100 and 506 and Epa we live
is like 60 beautiful bluebird skies,
a little bit of a breeze.
I bet you get sick,
nighttime starve or looking to right.
Look at what's The star gazing up there.
It's not hard to get out of that light
pollution you drive.
You know,
we were fortunate.
We have a,
probably the reason we moved up there as
we bought an investment property in 2016
and it's in the middle of nowhere,
like probably 15 miles out and you want
to talk about no light pollution and the
ability just to look up and it doesn't
look anything unless you've experienced
that.
You can't describe how much you're
missing out if you live in a city
looking up.
It's unbelievable.
Yeah,
it's weird,
right?
It's one of the weirdest things about
civilization that we've chosen to do
that.
I know that a lot of,
um,
there's,
there's a lot of talk about people
having like,
um,
nights or like one time of the year
where everybody shut their lights off
and they have like a,
just a viewing of the stars,
like a no light night who's talking
about doing a step before online.
I've heard people organizing light
pollution observance day or some shit.
Yeah,
I've heard some crazy things online.
I try to try to avoid most of the things
that I hear about online gatherings that
started online.
If I know the picture that I put a view
with,
you're flying squirrel suit flying over
the fucking earth.
I purposely chose it because you could
see the curvature of the earth,
the background,
or can you based on the comex.
It's a bro.
Was that shot with the Fisher islands?
Whatever the Gopro comes with,
that's probably felons.
It's got a little bit of a curvature to
it.
I look at that.
There you go.
I love that suit.
I was jumping that suit on Saturday.
It some interesting comments in there.
The Internet is a very interesting
environment that has no consequences and
allows people to interact in a way they
never would if they were sitting across
like we are right now.
Yeah,
and it also requires discipline in that
regard.
Like the way that people communicate
with people.
It just,
there's no discipline in terms of like
conserve,
like just think about what you're going
to say.
Think about if a person was in front of
you,
think about how it's gonna affect that
person and then proceed.
Nobody does that.
There's none of that.
There's not,
I wouldn't say nobody does that,
but it's few and far between.
No consequences.
Especially if you're an anonymous
person.
She just a regular Joe Blow and you got
an egg and it's like,
Dick,
fuck,
six,
nine,
five,
two,
whatever your name is and you just feel
like talking shit.
I mean I understand it.
If you.
If you put a quarter inch piece of glass
in between me and another driver on the
road,
I've been known to say some interesting
things that I wouldn't say to somebody
in a line at starbucks if they bumped
into me.
Do you know what that's from though,
what they say?
Um,
they,
the scientists have studied the human
response to critical situations where
you're,
you have to make split second maneuvers,
like high stress situations and you
don't think of a car as being a high
stress situation,
but when you're going 70 miles an hour
and every little thing,
it's like you're,
you're way more tuned in than you think
you are.
So anything that happens like this
motherfucker like you,
you're way more ramped up.
That's where road rage comes from.
It comes from the fact that your brain
is very aware that you're going to have
to make split second decisions.
So even though you don't realize it,
you're at seven all the time.
He just ready to flip to 11 when a guy's
crazy.
You motherfucker.
Yeah,
I mean I've seen people just lose their
shit.
And by the way,
here's the really crazy thing.
I've seen people lose their shit and if,
if it advert physically escalated,
like they did pull over,
they got out of the car.
I've seen that be helpless,
be helpless.
They don't know how I've been with
people.
I'm like,
listen man,
you don't know how to fight it all.
What are you doing?
You're starting a fight.
That's crazy.
Don't do that.
You're starting a fight and you're
praying to God or whatever you believe
in that this person doesn't actually
follow you or pull over.
Yeah,
they're in a car version of the egg on
twitter.
They just assume like,
fuck you,
you're never gonna.
See me again and this isn't real piece
of shit,
but sometimes it is real.
You know?
I've seen people duking it out on the
side of the road and then it's pretty
ugly.
It doesn't go well for both parties.
Generally.
A buddy of mine from Jujitsu pulled over
to the side of the road with a guy once
and they start doing it now and they
both knew how to fight and it was crazy.
They were hitting doubles and sprawling
and the guy goes for a Doris,
he reverses them.
He gets side control knees and in the
body.
That guy fucking hits them at triangle.
They fucking,
he passes the guard like the whole
thing.
Go back and forth on that meeting,
on the fucking grass.
They were on the grass on the side of
the road and then when it's,
they're both exhausted.
They high fived each other and then got
back in their car.
They were laughing like,
you know how to fight man.
Like it both actually they both rug,
I'm going to fuck this dude up.
And then they both were not just,
not just did they both know how to
fight.
They were both at like a purple belt
level,
little impromptu grappling session.
Car and punches and kicks and the whole
deal.
But they have both actually knew how to
fight.
It was pretty funny the way he was
telling it was pretty hilarious.
I mean,
I mean I can't,
I can't lie.
I get,
I get excited when I see people upset in
their cars.
Like if they get cut off accidentally
and I see them getting pissed.
Like the footage is slowly rolls off the
gas.
They get really close and I'm doing 40
on the freeway and I don't know.
I mean I don't know.
My problem is probably just an asshole,
but as the more upset they get,
the more warmth I feel in my soul as I'm
going down the road,
watching them lose their shit in their
car.
Well,
don't you think that a guy like you
who's been through so much actual real
combat probably relishes a little
elevation of the normal day to day life?
Just a little turn that bitch up a
little bit.
Let's just crank it up a little bit.
I'm probably the last person that would
ever fight like I just.
And I bet you it's the same with the UFC
guys,
right?
Who make their living in that insane
octagon like you think.
Some of the things I do are a little bit
atypical.
I think people who live in the octagon
are absolutely out of their mind,
but I bet you
you flew 18 miles and a squirrel suit.
The suit did most of the work,
man,
I just laid in that bed.
It doesn't matter the fucking all this
shit that can go wrong.
What did you say what the temperature
was when he jumped out?
50 below zero.
50 below.
With the wind chill and I was rocking a
tee shirt,
not smart.
How cold did that get?
I couldn't feel my hands.
I had hand warmers.
The chemical know the ones that you
crack open just for like skiing,
but I didn't.
I didn't open the bag until 20,000
feet,
you know,
didn't really think that through.
It needs oxygen,
open the bag while you're flying,
like up on the way up.
It was an hour flight to altitude and I
knew it was going to be cold so I opened
up the things and I put them on my hands
and put my gloves on and send them like
why am I not feeling these heat up?
And then I realized that they need
oxygen for the chemical reaction.
So I jumped out and I buy probably
halfway down.
I couldn't feel my hand so I just had
them like tucked up behind the wing and
I know where the little small parachute
is that you have to pull to deploy your
parachute.
And I'm like,
all right,
be all right.
I know where this is.
I've done this before.
Pulled the parachute and I get on the
ground and then my hands started burning
because the chemical started reacting,
so it went from freezing cold hand to
feeling like I had my hands dipped into
law so I couldn't get the gloves off.
Also,
probably a little
hypothermia,
right.
Approximately.
Say they found a guy recently.
I'm in,
I want to say Oregon or Idaho,
I don't know,
one of them cold places.
And uh,
he went elk hunting and they couldn't
find him.
He got lost and when they found him he
was dead and he was only like a couple
hundred yards from his truck and they
think he got snowed out and couldn't see
where he was going.
And he had taken his jacket off and he'd
taken his gloves and his hat off and
they say that's one of the signs of
hypothermia is you started people in
naked.
A lot of the time they take all the
while your fork,
it just start.
You know,
you hit hot too.
Apparently.
It's not just euphoria the,
I don't know if you get hot or
Washington state.
Yeah.
Missing elk hunter recovered in
Washington.
I'd heard about another guy who died in
Oregon who was a.
He was a tech guy.
He used to be on this tech show that I
used to watch and he would review like
gadgets.
This was like early two thousands and he
went up with his family and they didn't
have a car that can handle like serious
snow and they got stuck and they were
there for nine days with no food and he
went walking off to get help and froze
to death in his family was eventually
rescued.
How far did you make it?
I don't think he made it very far.
I mean he wasn't wearing the right
clothes.
You're wearing regular clothes,
you know,
and he just,
he was just desperate and he was trying
to save his family and it's just so sad
because I had seen that guy on TV.
It was so weird because you see a guy on
tv,
we're reviewing gadgets,
like here's the latest laptop,
like look at the,
here's the ether net port and what we've
got here is a,
you know,
the blah blah blah,
blah blah and
all this different stuff.
He review like the most technical of
technical things and in terms of like
the highest level of electronic
achievements so far,
right?
Like the newest gadgets that people
love,
like,
like the,
when you think about society and
civilization,
you think about those things and
meanwhile the guy froze to death in the
forest.
Like the real life.
All the tech in the world isn't going to
save you because you get out into the
wild.
If you rely on something that has
batteries for your sustainment of your
life,
you're going to be in trouble at some
point.
Yeah.
You gotta have baseline skills.
They say that like when people go into
the forest,
people are afraid of grizzly bears and
all sorts of different things.
But hypothermia kills more people than
anything.
Yeah.
It doesn't surprise me.
It's slow too.
I mean,
that's the insidious onset of,
you know,
your feet get a little bit cold.
And from what I've,
uh,
I've talked to some guys who work like
up in Alaska,
right?
Where's Mckinley Mckinley's in Alaska,
wherever McKinley is.
And it's not uncommon for them to find
people basically missing,
but they're naked because it's that slow
that thought process degrades.
I'm sweating or take my jacket off and
they just lay down and go to sleep.
Like it's just that one percent of the
time until you are basically a popsicle
and doesn't your brain pump morphine or
some equivalent to morphine through your
body when you're near death.
I think when you're in severe pain or
near death,
every literally make something.
I think you just go into shock,
you know?
Yeah.
I don't know the,
the physical process of what happens
when you go into shock.
But I've seen some people that are in a
lot of pain and they would have liked to
have their brain pumping some morphine
one happening.
Maybe they weren't pumping enough.
Perhaps.
You know,
I'd read something about that,
that there were,
there was someone who was trying to
explain I'm near death experiences and
like why when people have near death
experiences,
they have all these freaky visions and
some of it they think could be connected
to psychedelic chemicals that your brain
produces,
which are that day.
Definitely know that's true,
but I think there was also some talk
about some morphine like substance that
your brain makes.
I wouldn't surprise me if your body
recognizes it was on the downhill slide.
That'll be the little.
This dude doesn't need these.
Keep screaming.
Yeah,
probably.
It probably just a protection mechanism
if anything.
Yeah.
Well,
when you're out there,
man,
I think one of the cool things about
being in the wilderness is that most
people,
most people just never experienced that
for long stretches and when you do get
to experience it,
it gives you sort of a like,
oh,
I always thought the world was this.
I always thought the world was Phoenix,
Arizona,
where they drive down the street and you
go to see your friend and you're in the
car and you go to the movies and there's
the restaurant and then you go to
Montana,
go wandering through the forest and you
see deer and bears and you see the
mountains and the quiet and your cell
phone doesn't work and you're like,
oh yeah,
this is the actual world.
I have found that it's that in that
people and including myself,
think that I am this,
and then you go out into that
environment where you're detached and
then you have to rely upon yourself and
your knowledge and your grid or your
fortitude and you kind of figure out
more of who you are as well too.
I don't think people really.
You don't figure out who you are if you
live in the greater Los Angeles area.
Do you know who you are in Los Angeles?
Correct.
But I don't think he wore in Los Angeles
is who you really are?
I don't think so either.
I think you'd get to go out and outside
of that and either rely on yourself or
maybe even more importantly,
rely on somebody else and have that
dynamic outside of you mean you
couldn't,
I guess you could starve to death
obviously,
or you know,
not have enough water,
but the places to get those things in
La,
you could solve in a block in either
direction,
go far enough out in the woods and
you're on your own.
And to me that's where you find out who
you are.
I do.
I like being out there because I get to
think about me a lot.
Yeah.
I think that's a real good point that
you're not who you think you are,
who you are.
You think you know yourself,
but you know yourself in the
environments that you know.
Correct.
The way you really find out who you are
is to experience a lot of different
environments and a lot of different
difficult things.
Like you don't really know someone until
you see them tired to see them
exhausted.
Hungry.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
Well,
the John Dudley is always said that
about hunting,
like you think you know a guy take him
hunting.
His litmus test is hunting camp.
Yeah,
I believe he says you'll either be
friends for life or I'm never going to
want to spend another moment with you.
Yeah,
it was pretty accurate.
It come off the rails.
People.
I don't want to get up at five in the
morning.
I just went to bed at 11.
All right,
well you're not on the invite list for
next year.
You're missing out on this thing we're
doing here.
You can go hunt that pb andj and the
refrigerator.
There's a line where you got to learn
though,
like there is a line.
We're like,
okay,
we could die today.
This is not.
We should.
We should really be careful if we go out
today,
you know this is.
This is not the like my friend Adam
Green Tree.
Do you know Adam?
You got to meet him.
First off,
I don't know him,
but I definitely follow him.
Yeah,
that motherfucker skirts the line.
That's his water buffalo up there,
by the way,
right above the old glory as Paul.
Awesome.
Is that your elk from?
Yeah,
because that one is.
That's from to hone ranch.
God,
look at that rack on that thing.
Um,
but Adam,
he,
he crosses that line.
He gets to the edge that pushes that
line is how I would describe it.
He goes out by himself a month at a
time.
Nothing but a tent runs out of water all
the time.
Drinks funky water coming out.
He's got that weird Australia gut
though.
We could just drink water and like,
because some microbes going on or
whatever he's eating in this life.
It's like it's festering inside of his
body,
kills off everything else.
He doesn't get sick at the fucking guy
drinks at it creaks all the time.
He's probably always just sick and
that's his normal.
Maybe is sick.
It's happy though.
Yeah.
But he,
uh,
he
gets close,
like he gets close to that edge like
that.
Do you ever see that when you watch the
intro instagram story,
when the grizzly bear kept charging him
and he's fucking filming it all for
Instagram?
Yeah,
but he's also got an unloaded gun.
I was very upset with.
No,
it was loaded,
but he had never shot it.
So was out of battery.
The bullets were the wrong size for the
gun so he could.
Well,
you can barely see the top of the gun.
I'm looking at it and you can see the
barrel at the angle.
So the slide is back in like your,
your.
You can tell your.
Oh yeah,
like you're pointing your finger at a
bad a bear.
You're going to pull on that as it each
your face.
He said the bear ran to 10 yards.
No thank you.
Clip 10 yards.
Past false charge.
Ten yards.
He said when you see it running and you
see the muscles rippling under the hair
and the hair and the snow and the
masters of that claw ripping through the
ground.
No thank you.
And it's huge.
You know,
he said it was like a nine foot bear.
She's running around and if so if he.
I mean obviously he's got a ton of
interactions with animals in the wild,
but if he had run instead of standing
his ground,
he had been fucked.
It would have attacked him,
right?
100 percent.
Oh my God.
He would have been fucked.
You can't because they just have an
instinct.
It would just take you out.
It's like you're weak.
You're.
You're moving away.
Not only you,
not a threat.
Now,
now the bear has the opportunity to
close the distance and the bears don't
exactly know what the fuck you are.
They don't exactly know what the fuck a
person.
If they might've seen a person a few
times before,
but they don't eat a person and they
don't fuck a person.
The problem is when a bear does eat,
a person wants a bear,
eats a person like,
oh,
I could just fucking eat people
delicious.
They can't run it like a bear chases on
elk.
Like it's.
It's kind of a hustle.
There's a lot of running.
I can't imagine a baird catching an elk.
They do this really crazy video,
but they're eating a moose.
He's chasing this moose and it's a big
fucking.
Barron's chased him around a circle in
there.
It looks like they're filling it from a
helicopter and the bear is just this.
This Mousse is hauling ass.
See if you can find that Jamie bear.
The fucked up thing is when bears catch
you.
They just eat you.
They don't kill you first just start.
They just start eating just like they do
a salmon or they grab a salmon and just
bite into it and pull it apart.
They do that to your guts.
See,
that's where I'm really hoping that
morphine thing from your brain is true.
Can you imagine looking up and seeing
your lower torso inside of the mouth of
a massive imagining it?
That's what's so scary.
Do you ever see the movie grizzly man?
No.
How dare you?
How dare you miss out on the intentional
comedy in the history of the watch it
tonight.
It's fucking great.
You want to talk?
We were talking about this before the
show,
but people who are gay who don't want to
admit they're gay run.
That's this guy,
and he decided to go live with the
grizzly bears to protect them in the
forest.
He got to eat.
I,
I know this story.
Yeah.
Okay.
Now,
but it's a werner herzog film and I
don't know if Werner Herzog was trying
to make it funny,
but.
And I mean maybe it's just funny.
It's funny,
but it's funny to me because I have this
crazy appreciation for wildlife and
respect for it and there's part of me
that like,
like Steve Rinell had a funny way of
talking about this guy.
He goes,
hey,
you say all you want about that guy.
He goes,
that guy was a hard camper.
that guy did some hard fucking camp and
he was out there for six months at a
time.
My guy got to give respect.
You really did live with the bears for
six months at a time,
but we're Herzog.
The way he filmed it,
he filmed like the way he would have
people talking about the guy,
like they go to a sheriff and the
sheriff's like,
I thought he was retarded.
Just really digging into that character
and plot development.
Yeah,
the guy,
I mean it's just he shows you this guy's
ex girlfriend who's crazy and they're
talking about his life and they
interviewed one of his past roommates or
some guy who knew him in La and he's
talking about how crazy he is and how he
kind of made up a path for himself and
it was just like this really had fake
accents that he would use sometimes.
Just a really bizarre character who
found his identity in taking care air
quotes,
taking care of these bears that didn't
need taken care of and he was going to
protect these barriers and these
barriers.
Just they didn't give a fuck about him.
We had don't think they wanted his
protection.
Oh,
it was amazing.
It's amazing.
But anyway,
the film of him getting eaten,
he was filming.
Bears had the cover on the camera,
but the audio ran and the audio ran for
seven minutes.
By the way,
if you try to find that audio online,
it's not there,
but there's some fake audio online that
people attribute to it,
but if you listen to it with a
discerning year,
you tell those people aren't really
screaming,
fake screaming,
but it was seven minutes long of the
bear eating.
Him and his girlfriend,
his girlfriend hit the bare,
his girlfriend to the bear.
The bear was eating him and the
girlfriend hit the bear in the head with
a frying pan.
Didn't do Jack Shit.
The bear tears her apart.
You know,
I'm not going to lie.
I'm more surprised that he had a
girlfriend who wasn't really a
girlfriend.
It was a girl.
There was a friend who thought she was
referring to worlds.
Two words.
Yeah.
I've had friends that are gay,
that have wives and these poor wives.
They walk around looking like this all
day long like feels like,
what the fuck's wrong?
How can this guy doesn't fuck me?
Like man,
there's a lot of poor bastards out there
that are just deep in the closet and
they don't.
That's not cool.
That's when we hit that point now where
you can just kind of do and be a wish.
We were.
I wish we were.
I know a couple guys that are deep,
deep in the.
Let me say.
I like,
oh,
I talked to them.
I talked to them in brief brief chunks
because I'm,
I,
I get this feeling from them where I'm
talking to them where they just want to
end the conversation before I go,
hey man,
are you gay?
Like every conversation is like this
really quick,
really quick.
Hey,
good to see.
All right.
Hey,
take it easy man.
See you next time.
Hold on.
Hey,
before you go.
Are you good?
Are you guys.
It's just,
it's a bomber man.
It's a bummer.
Yeah.
I mean to get to get to 2017 and not
have that worked out.
It seems to me to be a travesty that the
fact that people give a shit.
Yeah.
Why does anybody care what other choices
that they make in their life?
Well,
my theory has been there's two types of
people that care about gay marriage in
that is people who are really dumb,
or people that are secretly worried that
digs are delicious.
I can get behind that campaign.
That's my theory.
That was one of my old bits and I think
that when you know,
there's a lot of it,
there are people are afraid that other
people gonna think they're gay.
A lot of it is people who grew up where
they hear terrible things about gay
people or prejudice people around them
tell them crazy things about gay people.
They don't realize that gay people were
just people that like guys,
that's it.
And there's other guys that like guys
too.
And if everything was open,
they wouldn't feel so creepy.
They feel creepy because they have to
hide it and be secretive and always be
like,
it's forbidden or there.
Yeah.
So that's where the weirdness comes
from.
But if you go to Santa Monica Boulevard,
there's these fucking.
There's this area of like three blocks
in West Hollywood and Santa Monica
Boulevard that I don't get out of my
car.
It's not worth it because you're just
loading the scenario up.
I'm already thinking in my head like,
I'm never going here.
Do you ever go to willow's wild animal
parks where we stay in the car and the
monkeys jumped on your car and rip your
fucking windshield wipers off?
No.
Have those New Jersey went?
Yeah.
The monkeys jumped on your car.
I don't know if it happens anymore,
but they used to.
We used to be there and you know,
you'd have to like agree that the monkey
might fuck your car,
can sign a waiver when you get in,
like don't go there with a Ferrari until
connect with a car that could get jacked
because these monkeys,
my Jack your car,
but you would be around these animals
and you'd stay in your vehicle the
entire time.
They have one in China and it's a great
story.
Uh,
about a year ago this lady was in an
argument with her boyfriend.
She's like,
fuck you.
And she got out of the car and she went
around the car and she was yelling at
him in a fucking tiger came.
You posted that video.
I saw that and just yanked her away.
And then the tiger.
Then someone else chased after and
apparently she lived,
but her mom died.
Her mom was going out trying to save her
saber from the tiger and the tiger
killed her mom.
Stumped bitch just thought she was.
She's like,
I have it in my head.
I'm going to fucking say what I want and
I'm going to get out of this car.
Fuck you.
And she gets out of her car and she does
it in a wild animal park filled with 800
pound tigers.
If you do stupid things,
you're going to win stupid prizes.
It's amazing how quick the tiger seizes
the opportunity though from that video.
She was only on the driver's side of the
car for a few seconds so them lights
out.
Pull that out,
pull that up.
It's a great video to watch.
One of my favorite videos,
it's just like I don't want anybody to
get killed by a tire.
I really don't,
but I do want,
if someone gets killed by a tiger doing
something really fucking stupid,
I do want everybody to watch that and
go,
hey,
don't do that.
This ain't the lion king motherfucker.
This shit's real like it.
Here it is.
Oh God.
She gets out of the car,
the Wildlife Zoo.
She gets out.
Watch passenger side.
Back seat.
Fuck you.
Just imagine the argument going on in
front of you.
I'm Outta here.
Yeah.
She's like,
I'm so tired of your bullshit.
She runs around the other side.
Going to make one more point,
and the guy's like,
hey,
will you just fucking relaxed?
Bitch.
Just don't hit me.
Don't hit me.
God Damn it.
Get back in your car.
Pat.
Jason just drags her lead.
He runs out of the car.
Oh God.
And then the mom ones out and that
lady's dead.
The third lady Dayton is a rangers come
out.
They're going to try to save her.
See,
I think the move is close.
All doors roll up.
Windows think grabs are so quick.
It's like,
this is what I've wanted.
I'm so tired of eating a whole meat
served on an aluminum tray.
Fuck you.
Fuck you for keeping me here.
Here's the thing,
man.
I think if they fed those tigers wild
animals,
they probably wouldn't do that.
They probably wouldn't give a shit about
that lady,
but what they do is they give the Tigers
no animal reward to have an animal
reward system right there.
The tigers jobs to clean up the
population of this one.
This tiger flying through the fucking
cool.
Are you kidding me?
Rip.
This guy's hand apart.
Just flew up to the top of and he
listened some fingers.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
That's what I'm talking to his hand
apart.
That tigers don't play,
but if you let that tiger killed things
like if they let a bunch of axis deer
Lewis,
which that demands,
that would be what they look for.
They would chase down the deer,
eat them.
They live like natural,
but so they have this overwhelming
desire.
It's like,
here's a way to put it.
If you.
Yeah.
If like if you were a guy,
that's not a good way to put it.
I was going to say,
if you're a guy and they extracted all
the come from your balls,
but they kept you horny,
but that wouldn't make sense.
Absolutely no sense.
I bailed on it.
Right?
What else?
I was like,
that's a bad analogy.
Do don't run with that one,
but these animals,
they get their appetite satisfied but
not their appetite to kill their deal.
They're born like you roll a yarn,
roll a ball of yarn in front of a
kitten.
Fucking cat dives on it because that's
what they're supposed to do.
This supposed to attack things.
They have a bill.
Even little flirt,
fluffy little kittens.
They have a built in desire to attack
things.
I think that's why people are the way
they are and social media.
They don't have the release that the
human body,
soul,
Spirit,
however you want to describe it,
is designed to get somewhere else and if
all you get it from as a device through
other people's pictures are selected
posts,
I think you go crazy.
I think that
is why I don't trust nearly every human
being on the face of the planet.
It's just they're not,
I don't think they get the chance to
express who they want to be.
I agree.
One hundred percent.
I agree 100 percent.
And I think um,
I've been thinking a lot about this
whole boss,
employee sexual assault,
sexual harassment thing that's been
going on every day.
Something else comes on and it's always
the same thing.
It's always a man in power in a woman
who works for him and something goes
down and it's never the opposite.
It's never chicks getting their pussy by
some dude who works in the office.
It's never.
There's a lot of women that are ceos or
it hasn't been reported yet.
Those guys can keep their mouth shut.
Right?
Or the guy doesn't consider that to be
harassment.
It's not.
She's,
yeah,
she lets you fuck her and she buys your
car.
Damn,
we got a mustang the fuck you go to the
New York Post for.
Oh my God,
that almost came out of my nose.
But if it's a.
But I think this is what I think.
I think that a lot of males right in a
male in a position of power,
like the chief of the village,
like that guy would probably have his
choice.
He was the war Lord.
He had this choice of women and the
women would respond to him in a
favorable way,
which would let him know.
It would indicate to him that it's time
to fuck right,
this girl wants it,
I'm going to give it to her.
So when a guy is like some Harvey
Weinstein guy or someone who's at the
front of some giant company and everyone
in the office kisses his ass when he's
there and everyone's so happy to talk to
him and people are angling for,
for raises and they're angling for
promotions and they're always nice to
him and they treated him like royalty.
I think the guy start thinking that
these girls are attracted to him,
that they.
That he's going to fuck them.
Like it's a power thing,
but it's also like a trick on the reward
system that the brain has and then it's
a scumbag thing to.
There's like a lot of factors in there.
I think,
I think it's a lot tied to the power
side.
I cannot think of an example of any
occupation that doesn't have that
problem somewhere near the apex,
right?
When a man gets in power,
just power.
I think power.
I think that as
humans we're only capable of dealing
with so much fill in the blank when it
comes to that,
whether it's the money or the fame or
people throwing themselves at you.
I think at some point,
depending on the moral compass that you
have and how it's calibrated,
it ends up swinging in the wrong
direction because you can look at
physicians,
you could look at religion,
you can look at people in the military,
generals in the number of sexual assault
cases and the generals like a one to
four star generals in the US in 2017 was
insanely high to comedy.
Bill Cosby to,
you know,
just fill in the blank.
You can find an example everywhere.
Once you start getting to the apex,
I think there's just a disconnect on how
much,
depending on who you are going into that
position,
I think there's a disconnect on how much
you can handle
because we was a really weird one
because I.
I've had this theory for a while,
but I think that during cosby's era,
the 19 sixties,
I think it was not just common to drug
women,
but it was almost like a joke like that.
People thought it was funny because
drugs were fairly fairly new and the
consequences of sexual assault warrant
talked about and it wasn't thought about
the same way and I think that those
during that day,
like he used to joke around about it in
his act.
I remember you saying that before.
Yeah.
He had these Spanish Florida.
Yeah,
and he even had a section,
a segment or a scene on the cosby show
where someone would give something to
someone that would make them have sex
with them or he would put them to sleep
with something.
Like he would joke around about it and
he had joked around about it on talk
shows and stuff.
I mean,
this is,
but I think that when you talked to
someone who was around during the 19
sixties,
they used to call it slip and so under
Mickey.
You have heard the term before?
Yeah,
I think they just once and shit started
coming out and they start giving them to
people just slip it in tow so fucked up.
So fucked up.
But it still happens,
man.
To this day it's still happens.
You know?
I had these girls on the podcast the
other day.
I'm,
I'm Korean and Christina from the
podcast guys we fucked and one of them
was saying that she was hanging out with
this guy and she had a drink and then
all of a sudden she just couldn't
fucking controllers got into a cab or
something like that.
Right.
And rescued her.
You had your hands full with those two.
That was like crazy.
It seemed to me like you had to wet cats
in a paper bag when she was talking
about I had an anal anal orgasms with a
vibrator.
I'm like,
well,
okay.
Yes,
yes.
Tell me more.
No,
I was listening to that at my house.
I think folding laundry in my head,
I'm like,
damn,
you got your hands full with those two.
Well,
they're fun.
It was an entertaining podcast for sure.
They are girls that talk publicly the
way girls talk privately when they have
a couple drinks in them.
One hundred percent.
Yeah,
and that's what's so attractive about
their podcast.
I wish I had there.
I don't know what the term to use.
Bravery or whatever it is to be that
open and honest and like just fuck it.
Here I am.
Blank slate.
Here's what I like.
Here's what I don't like.
Here's what I might like.
I don't know.
Well it's appealing though.
When someone does do it.
Like if someone you can tell you like,
okay,
this person is actually there.
They're being completely balls out
honest with no repercussions or horses.
So like say if they were an actress,
like let's find some famous who is a
famous current actress.
Good.
Give me like a hot.
Who's a hot Jennifer Lawrence.
Yeah,
but she's already had that scandal.
She had that scandal where people got a
hold of her pictures and you know,
was without her permission and shit like
that.
Yeah.
I'm out of my legal and this one,
Scarlett Johansson.
Okay.
Let's say Scarlett Johansson and
Scarlett Johansson.
If somebody like filmed her talking
about how she had had an anal orgasms
with a vibrator and how she likes having
her boyfriend get his dick sucked in
front of her.
That was it.
She didn't know that people are going to
like,
it would be horrific.
She like,
oh my God.
She'd have to stay home for days.
You have to pop advils and sleep on the
couch with a fucking blanket overhead.
You know what I mean?
She'd be horrified.
I can't believe that got out.
This is so awful.
Or she could go on and be like,
yeah,
you're goddamn right.
Yeah.
But these girls just like blurted out
and then move onto the next thing.
I like Tacos just one thing after the
other,
but they're,
that's their free,
you know?
And that's what people like.
This is what people liked about Charlie
Sheen until they found out he had aids.
Yeah.
That was an interesting development in
that particular store.
It's like,
oh,
well this story takes a fucking terrible
term.
Yeah.
Now I gotta change the lenses out on the
glasses that I view you through.
Yeah.
I thought you were winning.
I thought you had tiger blood just
fricking winning at every turn.
I didn't realize.
Didn't realize you had the high five and
the old tiger blood.
Yeah.
The,
the high five that he got.
Um,
apparently is what started that whole
thing off.
What is insanity?
Yeah,
sure it is.
Yeah.
Well,
when he,
it turns out that when he was diagnosed
with HIV was right when he started going
wild and talking about,
you know,
snorting and smoking,
eight grams of crack and that's how I
roll and all that shit.
Yeah.
Okay.
And I'm sure when you start off bat shit
crazy,
it doesn't help and that's your
baseline,
but you remember how people reacted to
that though.
They will like,
yes,
tell us what you're doing,
Charlie.
I mean,
he did a Goddamn tour of theaters and he
didn't have,
he didn't even sit down.
He would sit down and just be like,
all right,
so just got done smoking an eight ball.
Well he would tell stories,
but they had to craft what the thing
would be.
See what started out was he was just
going to go in this theater tour and
he's probably on copd if I talk to the
people,
they're gonna love us and he didn't know
really what to do.
So the first couple of shows were a
total disaster and then he started
bringing comics in there with them.
So like my friend Russell Peters did a
bunch of them with him.
So he would go up for a little bit then
go up or like what kind of host the
thing.
Oh,
so it was comic and then trolley and
they were sitting down talking and this
way you get to hear Charlie's wild
stories and talking crazy shit.
But the comic would frame it all with
some actual comedy and comedy and
comedic relaxed reaction to this maniac.
So they keep it on the rails and
Russell's great comic and he's
particularly great at talking like
talking shit and ad libbing.
Like Russell's a great.
He does a lot of crowd work and his act,
so he's like super fast and speedy and
Russell brand's.
Russell Peters,
Russell brand,
who is another guy he's an absolute
hands full with on the podcast.
Yeah,
he's.
He's a character.
Don't get that guy coffee.
Yeah,
he had a lot of coffee.
Well,
he's a.
he's a drug free character.
Choke Free Soda of.
Yeah.
Now,
now drug free.
That guy did enough drugs to kill all
three of us in this room probably.
He lived.
Yeah.
God bless him.
Now he's got a story to tell.
Yeah,
but he's another guy.
He's pretty free,
you know,
even like with who he is now,
he's free and he's all.
I cannot believe the transparency.
Like I said,
I don't have,
I don't have the,
the courage to just be like,
boom,
here it is.
Let's just unzip the fly,
lay it out and here we are.
People like,
you just don't try.
I bet you did.
I try.
I try my luck.
So for the podcast,
my rule is I just try to be honest.
That's all I try to do is just be honest
and portray myself as I am and say the
things that I actually believe and not
try to add one percent to it,
but there's still some people were,
if they were to ask me some questions,
I'd be like,
yeah,
that's for another day.
You know,
I'm not going to answer every single
question.
Well also,
especially if it comes to like military
shit,
there's stuff you can answer,
we'll then you just make stuff up.
Oh,
is that what you do?
Pretty much is.
There's a lot of that going on,
right?
There's a ton of that going on,
which is why most of the time I try to
dispel misconceptions.
The reality is no,
there's really nothing that I've ever
done that you can't talk about.
Is there any books or anything that's
ever come out where you knew one story
and then you saw come on and you're
like,
I have gone to the bookstore and read
books written by an individual who said
they were on a combat operation that I
was on and don't remember seeing them
there.
It's problematic.
Yeah.
That seems like a real issue.
It's a huge issue.
Um,
I would say 99 point nine percent of
books that have a trident on them should
be purchased and then put next to your
toilet paper roll.
So when you run out of toilet paper,
you can just start ripping pages out of
the books,
wipe your ass with pride and just
showing that symbol is the symbol that
is associated with being a seal.
It's,
you know,
you get,
when you get that symbol,
they change your designator inside of
the navy system and it registers as a 53
slash 26,
which is why do you think you see them
using that trident?
Because it's recognizable.
So they're doing it because they're
bullshit artists.
They're doing it.
Um,
I can't say exactly why they're doing
it.
I know some people are doing it purely
to make money.
Some people got out or a little bit
early and have used the recognizability
of that mark to further their own
motives down the road and a purely 100
percent profit seeking other people are
there trying to tell I guess would be
their story or their version of a story
and that would be the people in the
middle and then I guess on the other
end,
the best example I point people at as
generally Jockos book,
it's not a book about hey,
no shit.
There I was,
which is the number one indicator of a
store at this completely false as la.
There we were like,
no,
you're done.
Why is that be?
People want to romanticize and embellish
the reality of,
of what actually happened and I don't
know if it's the desire to make it seem
like it's
more than it was.
I don't know if it's because most of the
time when you're coming from a military
background,
you don't.
You're not.
You're not used to any level with people
really.
I would call it fan ship I guess or you
know what I mean?
Like it's you.
It's the military and being in the
military is not about money,
you know,
I could,
you can pull up online and see exactly
how much every individual in the
military is making based off what rank
they are and how many years they've been
in.
So people will be approached and like,
look,
this is how much money you could make if
you wrote a book and they're like,
holy shit,
that's the.
And so they will and they'll make
millions of dollars.
The problem is is if you start
embellishing those stories,
in my mind at least it starts tarnishing
the reality of what the occupation
actually is and the in the good and
sometimes amazing things that happen
lose a lot of their value in my mind and
I just think it's an enticement that
guys are not used to inside of the
military.
It's very.
When I was in the military,
I mean I feel like I was talking to
Jamie before we started.
I feel like I'm late to everything and
late to social media.
I'm late to.
I had never listened to a podcast
before.
I sat down and met you with tate.
Really?
I had never listened to one.
I had no idea.
I had no idea that diversity of
information that is out there and you
can go and,
and I mean you can almost get like a,
a,
an advanced degree in whatever it is you
want to get by just going.
I had no idea.
Never listened to one because I was so
focused on something else.
And then you lift your head up from that
world and you're like,
what the fuck is going on around here?
And you know,
if you post the right pictures on social
media that you and your outfit with your
thousand yard stare off into the
distance,
then you get more followers and then
people,
oh,
come and speak and say.
And it just,
it's an enticing thing to individuals in
my opinion,
that are just not used to that.
And it can really.
It can really.
I think it can take you down a path that
I would recommend most people don't
take,
which is why I like the way Jocko,
when as he has experiences,
but he's trying to take those
experiences in,
portray them in a way that people can
make use of them.
It's not about the story,
it's about what he learned during the
story and how you can implement that in
your life.
So there's a broad spectrum of
everything from literally rip off pages
and wipe your ass to recommend to
anybody that I encounter that asked
about [inaudible].
New Book is fantastic and it's so short.
It's like it's an easy read.
That's what makes it so fantastic book
could change your life because if those.
Those quotes are from a real
inspirational guy,
he's.
He's really trying to really be.
I would say he's not trying to be
inspirational.
He's.
He wrote down in committed to paper the
principles that he uses to live his
life,
his passion and his enthusiasm for
getting up at 4:30
in the morning and working out
unprecedented for like a week.
I was getting up a few minutes before
him and I would just post on twitter
like up before Jocko,
Hashtag don't be lazy,
and then I got fucking tired and I had
to stop.
Don't do that.
He'll get up earlier.
He will,
but he,
of course he was liking him.
I was like,
God damn it.
I'm trying to elicit
a response out of you.
Jocko.
It's falling.
He led.
Absolutely.
I mean because if people were asked you,
they will still ask me are I think I'll
still ask them if we know each other and
I've known him forever and they don't.
You can't.
You can't call how Jocko like that.
I'm like,
I think it's okay.
I think it's gonna be all right.
If I make funky Jocko on twitter,
it's going to be all right.
He's got a good sense of humor.
Yeah.
Well especially if you know the guy.
He's not going to get pissed about it,
but his father was like,
this is a funny man just because you
have at for 29.
Hey Man,
if you want to be a lazy bitch ahead and
then I have to stop myself,
that's as far as I can go on twitter
because I will lose my mind and I don't
want to be that person.
Yeah,
you can't respond to many people.
You have like a minimum or a maximum
requirement per day.
Just give yourself like a threshold.
I've looked at three different comments
about.
I don't understand how you could
possibly keep track or even tabs.
I mean your numbers are astronomical.
No,
I don't keep track.
Occasionally I dip my toe into the water
of social media,
but for the most part I don't.
It's got to be like an abstract painting
rolling by.
They're like 60 miles an hour.
You can probably just catch one or two
things that comes by.
We'll also,
between working out,
writing comedy,
doing stand up,
be with my family,
archery.
Anything else I'm doing at the time?
I don't have the fucking time.
Podcasts.
Yeah,
UFC duties.
Whatever I have to do with doc.
I don't have the dime.
It doesn't exist.
So you're tapped out?
Yeah,
so I do what I can.
I post stuff and then I get out of there
and plus I don't the turmoil,
the P,
I don't want to like,
you can engage.
Like,
what's that?
That if you,
uh,
what's that?
If you respond to every barking dog and
ever get where you're going,
if you ever heard that.
Sounds good.
I'm with you.
I think I paraphrased it,
but that's the idea behind this.
Like there's no way you don't have the
time.
And I have friends that have less
followers who will go like my friend
Owen Benjamin.
He's fucking crazy.
He'll,
he'll have twitter fights all day long.
And I told him the other day,
I'm like,
Bro,
it's gonna.
Stop engaging.
We got to stop doing this.
It entice people.
Once they recognize that you engage,
it would entice them to hit you up more.
Exactly.
And then your time is you're done.
Yeah.
And then they'll try to piss you off and
then you'd go back and forth with them,
oh,
well fuck you.
And then next thing you know,
you're up at 3:00
in the morning checking your twitter
exhausted the rest of the day.
Just compliment people when they say
mean things just right back.
I think you're an amazing human being.
Heart emoticon sent.
Thanks.
Thanks Sweetie.
Because they don't know how to take
that.
Oh,
how long do you think you're going to
last?
The winter to the end up keeping the
place in San Diego and just coming back
here in November?
No,
I have really not thought about San
Diego since the day that we left and I
am with tickets.
Snowed in will be like a good five feet
cold weather stuff and I got guys truck.
I do have a truck.
I have a F150.
Nice.
Slightly modified though.
Jacked.
Jacked up.
A little lift.
It's came tested.
Thirty five big 750 horsepower.
Mud and snow tires.
Probably 750 horsepower.
Jesus Christ.
What the fuck do you have in the hood?
Shelby supercharger.
Oh,
you went.
You went deep.
It came that way.
My wife was so pissed at me because I
went in with my other f-150 to get an
oil change and I technically did get an
oil change because I came home with this
truck and she walked outside and she was
just like God.
But a lot of those like super sport
performance trucks,
they,
they have street tires on them.
Mine have massive knobby tires.
I literally went in,
uh,
I got very fortunate and I got a great
deal on a Ford on like a pseudo
endorsement sponsorship thing earlier.
So I had a bunch of equity in my truck.
I literally went in to get an oil change
and right next to me in this spot was
this Ford f150 black ops model,
like the Tuscan Tuscany so hard.
And I get out of my truck,
which I usually feel good and then I'm
looking up at this other truck and now I
immediately feel like bitch.
And I'm just an eye.
So I climbed up on the wheel and I'm
just reading the sticker because I
couldn't read it from the ground.
I'm just looking at like,
all right,
well that price is totally outside of my
range and I go inside and of course the
salesman happened to see me and he comes
over to the service side of the,
you know what I'm getting now given the
guy my keys,
and he was like,
what do you think about that truck?
Like,
I think that thing's awesome man.
He's like,
well,
let's just.
Let's just run the numbers.
Like okay.
Four hours later I'm going home and the
new truck for hours,
it took you four hours in the
dealership.
You wives call it up,
where the fuck are you?
Well,
she does that because that's not the
first time it's happened.
Oh,
you've done that?
I buy.
I tried to buy her a car one time.
I told her I was taking her minivan in
Honda Odyssey.
Best urban assault vehicle ever dual
open doors.
You can just take down a compound and
that thing.
Yeah,
as long as you have blacked out windows,
they don't store some rocket launchers
on top of that bitch and just roll.
So I was like,
hey,
how do you want me to take you in and
take your car and get an oil change?
I was getting her a Tahoe and like three
hours and she starts calling me,
what are you doing?
I'm like,
oh,
they found a leak in your flux
capacitor.
It's going to be a few more minutes.
Shit shit about cars,
but the future.
Yeah.
And uh,
so I come home and she's like,
oh,
I like that car.
It's the wrong color and the different
seats.
And I'm like,
God damn it.
So she went back and picked out her own.
So after a couple hours,
the dealership,
I think she realized something was up
and I got in trouble for that.
Yeah.
I saw a video where they were comparing
that shelby supercharged f-150 to the
raptor.
They were trying to figure out which one
was better.
I don't know,
but I think that truck is ready to go
for the winter time.
It's got some big old tires,
uh,
an entirely too much torque and power
for me.
Yeah,
it's a little bit loose,
you know,
break loose,
locking differentials and all that jazz.
We don't even know what that means.
I'm locking differentials means you can
like you have an arb locking
differential and what you do is you set
it so that all wheels will always spin
together no matter what.
So it locks together,
so if you're,
if you're in a place where one wheel is
spinning,
it doesn't
work that way.
All wheel spin together and it's not
good for driving down the road,
but it's good for getting you out of
places and for traversing very difficult
terrain.
It might have that.
I might have fucked that up,
but locking differentials are a.
it's a must on any sort of off road
vehicle.
I never planned to tick it off road even
though I think it's designed for the
Zombie apocalypse.
I tried to baby that thing and just park
it in the garage.
Yeah,
but what if you have to like what if you
have to go into the forest to get your
elk.
If you're packing out,
it's called somebody else who's a trail,
some sort of logging trail.
Call somebody else,
bring their truck.
I don't think you can use it in Montana.
No,
I was actually thinking about that to
wind.
Now.
I don't even know what I'd use it for,
but I feel like to have it,
I feel like I would be more prepared for
life in general with the window.
My Bronco has a wrench,
doesn't suck and that thing's bad ass.
Never going to use that.
When they were telling me how the winch,
where's my Yay.
I'm fucking thinking.
The confidence that you have gay
climbing into.
You're like,
I got a winch,
a winch.
Nothing can stop me.
What the folks got stomped me.
Nothing to winch.
Yeah.
You can pull something out of a ditch.
That's like a man thing.
Like men want equipment.
They're never going to use liquid.
Should always have a chainsaw.
Just in case 100 percent.
You live in a fucking apartment in New
York City.
Why do you have a chainsaw?
Never know.
Might have to cut down the door.
Shit goes wrong.
Straight goes sideways.
Now trees start growing everywhere,
but we're ready for winter,
man.
If we got the ski pass is ready to go,
I can see worldclass skiing from my
son's bedroom mountain.
We live just south of white fish.
So in white fish the mountain is called
big mountain.
It's not big sky.
Most people confuse the two big skies in
Bozeman.
I think you said you had been to big sky
before.
I've been to Bozeman.
Bozeman has big sky makes guys like
right outside of Bose,
just south of incorrect and white fish
is just north of where we live in
Kalispell.
And a big mountain is,
it should be open in four days.
We went to Bozeman and we were there
when they have this,
uh,
this grizzly sanctuary.
We took a ride to yellowstone and we
stopped the grizzly sanctuary.
And the other bucket bears,
they're so big they don't even look like
they're real and they throw them frozen
watermelons and that's what they're
eating.
A whole frozen watermelon.
So they throw this frozen because it was
hot out and we went in the summer and
the bear just this giant block of ice,
you know,
that's what it is.
It's a,
it's a huge beach ball of ice that's
like a 20 pounder.
The bear just opens his mouth and
crushes it with one bite,
just cuts through the frozen watermelon
like it's nothing.
It's so sobering when you watch a bear
lying on the water,
right.
He was in the water,
like lying on its back holding this
frozen watermelon in his paws and just
chomping on it and eating it.
It's not a Disney movie.
Don't mean when Disney movie bitch by.
My brother in law who has never hunted
before,
has purchased a read works one nice
already has the yard.
He's got the whole eight.
He's already got a silverback sitting in
his house.
He's already got an elevate rest in his
bill.
Comes in and like two weeks and he was
trying to explain.
I was uh,
had dinner with them last night and he's
trying to explain to his son and his
daughter like,
it's not Bambi that I'm going to go
hunting with.
And they're just like,
no damage.
No Daddy,
you can't get.
But it's,
it's funny.
[inaudible] my kids were like,
why would you kill a bear dad?
Or why would you kill a deer?
Why would you kill an elk?
Well,
to eat it 100 percent.
Yeah.
It's.
It's interesting though,
help people in my limited super limited
experience into the hunting world.
Very entrenched in in it's either no.
These animals like these is,
this is Bambi,
how could you do that?
Or they have an understanding of what's
going on.
I'm like,
oh,
okay.
I have a friend who's a hardcore Vegan
and these kind of an asshole about it,
but he's got dogs and he feeds him dog
food and dog food from the dog food
store and it's got animals chopped up,
ground up,
stuffed into these bags and he's good
with that and I'm like,
you're a hypocrite.
Like you're a fucking hypocrite.
You really are.
He's like,
well,
the dogs are carnivores.
We're not.
No,
you choose to not be a carnivore.
You choose to be an herbivore.
Okay.
But most humans are omnivores.
That was going to say that we evolved.
We evolved to eat a wide variety of
foods and this,
this thing that you're doing is just,
you're standing out and he's an asshole.
He's a nice guy,
but he's an asshole and he's always been
like a really negative guy,
like he's nice to me,
but he's.
He's nice to his friends,
but he's always had this propensity for
negativity,
pessimistic attitude towards people be
successful as a human being,
but shitty to people like for whatever
weird reason just has this aggressive
attitude and now he uses it against,
against people that are involved in
hunting and he gets off on it.
He thinks it's fun.
You know,
it's just,
it's a weird thing that you can sort of
justify the torturing and killing of
these animals to feed your dogs,
but when someone wants to go out and
hunt an animal to eat it,
like I get all the people that are
pissed off that people go out and hunt
lions and don't eat 'em and hunt
elephants and don't eat them.
I'm drafts and stuff and I'm with you
100 percent,
but here's the thing that's not eating
deer.
That's not hunting buffalo,
a bison and eating bison.
That's not counting and eating things
that we're talking about.
Two totally different things and then
when you get to like the lions and the
elephants and there's a real problem and
the real problem is that there's not
enough money in conservation to ensure
the safety of these animals unless these
animals are valuable and the most
valuable way that you can present these
animals.
This is fucked up,
but when they're hunting targets,
and I'm not.
I'm not saying this is the only way to
do it and I think it's not,
but Africa is a crazy in the best
documentary about it is Louis Theroux
who's a British documentary and did this
trip where he went to one of those high
fence hunting camps in Africa.
You know those things.
I've never been to Africa.
I was in a.
It was in Kenya,
but I've never been around.
And you weren't hunting people where I
was actually.
They're building schools.
Oh,
let me give you.
I'm a humanitarian at.
You're a sweetheart.
I am a sweetie,
but luther rose documentary.
Louis through his documentary is amazing
because you kind of get the sense of
what it's all about.
Like these animals.
A lot of them were going extinct just a
couple of decades ago because there's
massive poverty all throughout Africa
and there's no money and they figured
out that if you take these animals,
protect them,
put them inside a fenced area in,
in talking about these enormous,
like 10,000
Acre reserves preserves and then people
fly in to hunt them on a daily basis.
They get a tremendous amount of money,
so then these animals that populations
are booming,
there are higher than they've ever been
and the animals are protected.
They're no longer in any danger of being
extinct,
but a lot of people are super
uncomfortable with the circumstances and
I get that too.
I'm in the same boat as you would like
to me.
I don't like hunting a giraffe.
Not not into it personally.
Not going to make a character judgment
against somebody who is or the the
elephant or whatever animal that you may
go to call it trophy hunting.
Like I don't know enough about it.
I would assume and hope that the
situation is exactly like you described
where the people who live in the area
are managing and monitoring.
The species and making sure it's good to
go and if they're doing that,
I have no issue with it and in the same
breath I totally understand why it's
very off putting to individual who see a
picture of that and just loses their
shit.
Yeah,
I completely get the elephant thing and
particular elephants to me or this kind
of majestic sweet animal,
but the reality of people living in
Africa is different.
People that live in Africa,
elephants destroy their crops,
trample them.
It really becomes a big issue of
elephants move into areas where they're
farming and they have to do something
about it and sometimes they'll.
They'll have to hire hunters or have
someone come in and do it and then once
someone does shoot one of those
elephants,
the amount of people that come in.
Have you ever seen what happened?
She posted a picture or you posted a
picture of.
I think it was an elephant and it was a
line of people outside of the border of
the picture.
I'm assuming they were waiting to come
and get their share of the bank or
whatever it was from that animal.
Yeah,
I mean these are people that have a
really hard time getting meat.
An elephant meet is gross as it sounds
to people listening to this.
It's supposed to be unbelievably
delicious if you were raised on it.
I mean it's supposed to taste really
good.
I'm not saying you go out and get an
elephant burger folks,
but I'm just saying please don't.
The soul thing is it's very complicated
and you could say,
well,
these people shouldn't be raising crops
where the elephants live.
The problem is this is not like any
other thing,
like it's not like an encroachment
issue.
Like these people are living in a
fucking village in Africa.
I mean this is like literally where
humans evolved.
So this is,
this is a real situation of humans and a
very small tribal situation encountering
elephants that just decide that,
hey,
I'm an elephant.
I'm fucking 10,000
pounds.
I'm just going to eat your food,
bitch.
You Ain't gonna do shit and these people
don't know what to do about it.
There's a lot of that and there's,
that's the other thing.
People say,
well,
elephants are going extinct.
So yes and no.
In some places in the world you go to
Iowa,
there's no elephants,
right?
Content as well.
They're extended no elephants.
Yep.
But there's parts of Africa that have a
lot of elephants and they actually have
to control the populations and it's the
same thing with deer.
Like people in California will tell you,
you know,
hey,
you shouldn't shoot a deer.
He talked to people in Iowa and you're
like,
please,
you've got to shoot these deer.
My wife Rector fucking car.
She's in the hospital.
Same thing in Montana.
There's deer on the side of the road,
everywhere,
everywhere.
And you can see for on the bumper,
bumper is in windshield smashed.
It's doesn't take a rocket surgeon to
put two and two to get an advanced
degree.
I love how people in Montana have those
fucking road warrior grills.
So I got one.
You got bring it.
Come on dear.
Apparently if you hit a deer in Montana,
you can call the fish and game.
Let them know what happened.
Throw it in the trunk.
Yeah,
I like that.
That's good because then you get to keep
the meat.
The meat doesn't just go to waste.
I like that.
As long as you're not driving around
looking for a deer,
that's what someone said,
but the problem with that is the odds of
you hitting a deer on purpose or like
fucking zero.
I know,
but if you try to avoid them,
it's a pretty high percentage.
I'd almost hit a few like I don't want
to hit a deer in this truck.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
I remember I was coming home once.
I had a Gig in upstate New York and I
was driving down to where I lived in new
Rochelle and I hit this one patch that
had so many deer.
I had to drive like 20 miles an hour on
the highway.
It was fucking insane.
It probably wouldn't even get out of the
way.
They were just darting in front of the
road,
like left and right,
left and right,
and I'm talking like an infestation.
It was crazy.
And this is what happens when there's no
predators and no hunters and you know
you don't want wolves in your backyard.
People once you live in Montana,
kind of cool.
I would still take a strong pass on
wolves in the backyard.
No,
I would like to see them.
When I was up there,
this lady who lived up there was talking
to us and she said,
um,
she lives in this canyon and they had
wolves come through a couple of nights
before.
And I said,
what is that like?
She goes,
well,
it's two things.
She's like,
it's beautiful and you also have to be
cautious.
She's,
Oh,
so it's this thing where you like,
I'll really love it.
They're there and I loved looking at
them,
but I want them to go away.
I love looking at them from the safety
and security of inside of my house.
She's like,
well,
people get a little nervous about their
livestock and definitely their pets.
I go their pets.
She's like,
yes,
that's number one.
They will kill dogs
real quick.
I bet.
It sounds amazing though,
to hear a pack of wolves in the wild.
I have no,
no experience with that.
It's got to be.
I had never heard an elk bugle until
September.
Oh.
And I also thought that they,
after I heard them bugling,
I assumed that they did that all year
round.
I just thought,
okay,
I'll communicate by bugling.
I had no idea that for basically a month
you can hear them communicating like
that and then they zip it and start
working together as a little probably
not heard.
I had no idea.
And it was in a valley had when I was in
the middle of my,
other than optimal hunting experience
and just surrounded by it,
we couldn't have had this conversation
at this volume.
Yeah,
like you got to be shitting me.
There's a film that's coming out Friday,
me and Cam went to Utah and we're a
hunting elk in Utah and there's one
scene in it where we just every now and
then if you go elk hunting,
and especially this one place in Utah is
enormous ranch.
It's a private ranch and it's 240,000
acres.
Where were you in relationship to Salt
Lake City?
Couple hours drive.
I wasn't paying attention.
Jed was driving,
you don't know southeast West.
My phone.
So it was a new.
I got to,
you get off twitter joke.
I had to do email.
I was behind.
So,
um,
uh,
anyway,
there's this one part of the film while
we're in there and you literally,
you might hear 100 bugles around us.
There's screaming left.
Yeah.
And you know,
the audio,
even if you were in like an Imax theater
would not do a justice.
No,
I couldn't.
I couldn't believe it.
I,
the one thing I know,
I don't have enough of his interactions
around animals to understand behavior
and patterns and what to expect,
but I mean in that day was a
reinforcement that I was sitting at my
jaw was on the floor.
I could not believe what it sounded
like.
It's like a,
like a mystical animal with the sound it
makes.
It's almost like a lord of the rings
character and when you watch them do it
to just like,
we watched this one elk fuck this cow.
And it's crazy the way they do it,
the way they do it as like a brock
lesnar double leg take down.
Like he,
he got on top of her from behind and
then boom,
he hits her one time,
just shoves her forward and she
collapses on her front legs and he kinda
wobbles off of her,
but he is,
he's a one pump chump.
Maybe that's what they're into,
what they're into one bank,
get it done,
move on to the next.
And he's doing it all day long and
protecting month?
Yeah,
draining himself.
They lose like 30 slash 40 pounds.
Oh,
do they really?
Probably more.
Well,
I'm saying 30,
40 pounds,
but they're,
you know,
seven,
800 pound animal.
I bet they lose a lot more than that.
They get real skinny.
They stop eating.
They just fuck like crazy for two
months.
Unbelievable animal,
but probably the most majestic animal
that I've ever been around.
I cannot wait until next September.
Yeah.
There's a
real controversy in Montana about wolves
because the wolves that are in Montana
right now have been reintroduced from
Canada.
They captured them from Canada and then
reintroduced them to the yellowstone
area and there's a really interesting
video about it called the wolves changed
the walls.
Changing rivers.
I think it's called,
it's like a short film,
a short film.
I think it's called how wolves changed
the river and it all just talks about
how the introduction of the wolves
changed the way the river flowed.
Because is this how wolves change
rivers?
Yeah.
It's pretty bad ass because it.
It shows the need for predators.
It shows that you can't just have this
overabundance of wildlife,
like a undulates cows and elk and things
because they eat all the grass when they
eat all the grass.
The trees never grow a strong root
system.
So there's a lot of things happen.
Like ECO system on its head.
Yeah,
and some birds don't survive and you
know,
there's like,
songbirds have been spotted in like
really high numbers in yellowstone now.
There's a bunch of stuff.
They documented it.
A lot of it is because the wolves chase
down the elk and made the elk and it
decimated the elk population,
like knocked it down to like half.
But in the process made those elk like
just a little bit more wary,
a little smarter.
Still a healthy population,
but that's Kinda how it's supposed to
be.
It's not supposed to be like these
hunters that lived there.
They got super spoiled because they were
used to like seeing hundreds of hours of
bed,
like slide open the door and get the
laser range finder out.
Well,
especially if you're a rifle hunter,
which a lot of them are.
There's way more rifle hunter.
I can't get behind that.
I get behind me.
I mean
no,
I can't need meat.
It's the way you did it.
I get it.
I'm saying me,
myself personally,
it has no draw or interest whatsoever.
Yeah.
Bow Hunting on the other hand,
now we're now we're talking.
What's the difference to you?
One I absolutely suck at and the other
one,
uh,
generally can hit what I'm aiming at and
it's easier with the rifle.
Like wind is the perfect example.
You take a shot with a rifle in high
wind.
The wind when you're thinking of rifle
is from the ballistic effect of the
round,
you know,
left or right or in the temperature and
all that stuff.
When with a bow,
your crawl on your belly.
And being a Ninja and then it's like
animals gone.
I got a completely different ball game.
You could sit with a rifle with a cooler
and a bowl of Chili and get an elk.
Well,
you know the other thing that gets me
with rifles and I don't think you should
make it any more difficult.
That's not my point.
I think the most effective and efficient
and ethical way you should kill an
animal should be the way you do it.
But there's these pods that people have
these that they set
up a tripod with a bench.
It's essentially God like a mobile rifle
bench sitting there on.
So it's got a you lena,
like a lead sled attached.
You can just bring your finger in from
the outside and just bring it back and
it doesn't move at all.
You don't even have to have it in your
shoulder.
You lock it in place,
you screw it down so you have the
perfect angle.
You set it on the vitals and you squeeze
it off and boom,
and exactly where you want it.
In that setup,
you could actually not even have it
shoulder.
You could go sit in a chair to the side
of it and people do it all the time.
To be clear,
I support hunting whether you want to,
however you want to do it.
I'm a full fan.
For me personally,
I just can't get into rifle hunting gets
too easy.
If you put an elk anywhere from zero to
1500 yards in front of me,
it's game over Sun.
Right?
Well,
you're an expert marksman though.
I mean,
I would say I'm a marksman.
I don't know if I would add expert to
it,
but I can sometimes hit things humble.
I missed.
Sometimes I guess I'm good Miss Story,
but when you see an animal and you're
hunting with a bow,
so the thing is the difficulty and the
challenge and the connection to the
animals way more intense because you're
trying to get inside a 40 yards.
The whole thing to me is it's not a
matter of how much I feel like I can do,
right?
It's a matter of how few things I can
mess up and I love fighting against the
odds like that.
I love the challenge of having to worry
about not only cover and concealment and
you know,
high ground versus low ground,
but shadows and light and moving and
noise inside of that moving and
monitoring the wind and then the fact
that the animal might just want to go
take a piss and you're screwed.
You get the best stock in the woods.
I got,
I gotta take a Wiz.
I love,
I love the challenge of it and I suck at
it.
So I,
I just,
it is a draw to me that and my wife has
already shaking her head at me.
She's like,
God damn it.
You're going hunting again.
Yeah.
So I think for,
for some people they're.
The issue that they have is that they
think that killing an animal should not
be this pleasurable challenge that it
should be.
If you are going to eat animals,
you should be shooting him in the head
with a high powered rifle where you
can't miss and they die instantaneously
and there's no suffering.
If only that situation actually existed.
Well it can.
If you shoot them from five yards,
well you know you missed some big
targets with a rifle from pretty damn
close.
How close?
Seven feet.
Hey Man.
When you're running it through a hallway
and stuff,
sometimes that's a different animal.
It's a different animal both
figuratively and literally.
I missed,
you know,
if there is no 100 percent solution,
that's true.
I get it right.
But if an animal doesn't know you're
there and you're setting up and it's 100
yard shot and you have a 30 year,
you've done 300 win mag or you don't
even need to get to 100 yards.
Real estate,
you can be at 300 or $500.
Whatever.
You feel comfortable shooting at a.
If you want meat though.
Yeah,
it's the way to go.
But also why not
enjoy the experience?
I don't think there's anything wrong
with.
To me it's a challenge in more than a
challenge in of whatever it sounds gay,
but it's a journey.
I,
I enjoy Sanga.
I Dunno.
Just journeys.
Okay.
It depends.
I guess on the type of journey.
How do you feel about the Lord of the
rings was a journey.
It was a journey.
I've watched all those movies about the
books.
I didn't read the books.
I want to go to New Zealand and jump off
the cliffs in that movie.
Uh,
but the,
the journey is like why not enjoy it?
I enjoy,
I enjoy the struggle.
I enjoy that.
It's hard to hit what you're aiming at
with a bow and exponentially more so
that every time you add a yard to the
distance,
I enjoy that the animals are,
they have instincts that are amazing and
that you cannot defeat their nose and
that you can't control the and joy all
of that.
That to me is I think,
and I'm enjoying that experience.
And then again,
this is my first bow hunting season.
I started bowhunting and late August,
so I have almost no experience under my
belt,
but I do enjoy the,
the final aspect of that as well too,
in getting into position and being able
to perform in that moment.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with enjoying killing an animal that
you're doing so respectfully and like my
freezer right now,
my house,
my goal is to never go to the grocery
store and buy meat again for the entire
year and I think our freezer is full
enough to do that.
My kids love it.
I've made.
I got maple elk sausage,
I got Italian elk sausage.
I got brought worst.
I get steaks.
I got roast like we're not going to the
grocery store.
Yeah.
That to me like so why not enjoy that
whole process,
that whole story arc doing it ethically
and enjoying the journey along.
No,
I,
I agree with you,
but I just wanted to hear you spell it
out because that's the issue that a lot
of people that are sort of in the animal
rights activist side of things,
one of the things that they would have
an issue with is the enjoyment part of
it,
but I can't help it if some people are
pussies.
It's just the challenge of like doing
things that are hard is enjoyable and
and succeeding at things that are
difficult to do.
It was also enjoyable.
Yeah.
Why can't you be happy about winning?
Why can't you be happy about accepting a
challenge willingly and nobody's forcing
you into it and when you're successful,
you're not only happy with that success,
but you're happy with every step along
the way.
I don't see any problem with that.
Well,
because they're Bernie Sanders
supporters.
I'm not qualified to talk on that topic.
People are fucking with you right up
until that point.
I fucking love Bernie relaxed.
Joking around here folks.
Yeah.
I love it,
man.
Even if you're not a hunter,
I mean,
if someone doesn't want a Holland,
I think to take prolong trips to the
wilderness,
I think it's fucking great for you.
I think I started doing it in 2012 and
has changed my life.
I whole heartedly agree.
I was dead serious when I say I don't
think he figured out who you are until
you get into those environments.
I have taken a sounding on the depth of
who I am as a human being in the worst,
most
physically arduous moments of my life
and I,
and I wish that more people would
willingly go to that point.
I think that it would,
it changes my perspective for sure.
It changes my appreciation for things.
Nothing will make you appreciate the
little things in your life more than
nearly dying and having,
you know,
and like,
oh wow.
Like I have all of these things that I
wasn't paying attention to and people
don't know that.
People who didn't listen to your earlier
podcasts don't know your story.
So tell,
tell people what happened when he almost
died on the jumping side of the house.
Let's go to the military first and then
we'll go to the jumping side.
Yeah,
I mean,
I don't know if it seems like to me like
you might be supplementing your need for
danger with this jumping thing.
Talk about how you described me as a
psychopath.
Every time you have this fucking Grazie
nude,
you,
you're crazy person that I know.
Then I texted you that once and you
responded that crazier than,
you know,
I said I think on the.
Yeah.
What?
Yeah,
because like,
well for one you willingly used to enter
into fights and you have said before
that you would have gone into the
octagon and earlier age.
To me that's insane.
It just,
for whatever reason,
like going in there and did willingly go
in and just getting into a fistfight
with somebody.
How much martial arts experience do you
have?
Exactly.
Zero.
Yeah,
that's martial arts a lot.
Like bowhunting.
How many of you got into base jumping
experience?
Do you have fucking zero.
You're making my point zero on the
ledger.
Look at that fucking picture.
That suit got.
Damn.
It looks weird.
Fish islands,
Joe Thailand's.
What I've been able to determine from my
jumping is that yes,
people,
the world is round.
You sought from the sky.
You could tell me.
Sure when I jumped from pretty high.
Here's something you little curve.
Here's something that someone pointed
out that's a really good point on,
uh,
reiterate it.
I retweeted it.
You could look at the moon with the
telescope.
I was going to go to the same place
because I read that.
Yeah,
clearly.
Right folks.
Okay.
Try to look and find Mount Everest with
a telescope and then explain why you
can't.
You can't because it's on the other side
of the fucking planet.
You dummies crazy people.
It's so sad to me.
It is.
People love mysteries though.
They love things that are hidden,
hidden,
hidden information.
Anyway,
that's why the seal books right there.
You answered why people will buy because
of that symbol they look at.
They're like,
oh,
I want to know the secret.
Of course it's.
Yeah,
and there is no secret.
That's what I.
that's the point I can get.
I want to get to that definitely,
but what?
How did almost martial art thing,
but the martial art thing I think is a
lot like the bow hunting thing and that
it's very,
very difficult and once you start doing
it you get better at it and then you get
addicted to it and it's not crazy.
People like I'm not even talking about
like actual competing and fighting,
but just training because when you're
training you're competing.
Like when you go onto the mat,
you train,
you're trying to improve yourself,
but you're also
trying to tap someone who's trying to
tap you and you go,
you're both going at it and when you do
it and you get better at it and you get
better at it,
you develop this kind of understanding
of what it is and it becomes this like
very addictive thing.
Like guys are addicted hard to Jujitsu.
Well,
is it possible to master or is it a
never ending evolution?
Well,
you'll be a master in comparison to
someone who doesn't know what the fuck
they're doing,
but yeah,
we'll definitely.
Physically,
the only problem is your body starts to
break down as you get into your older
ages.
Like most guys that I know that are in
their forties and for sure in their
fifties,
like I was in Hawaii recently with Ed
O'neil,
who's a black belt in Brazilian Jujitsu.
A lot of people don't know big Ed
O'neill from married with children and a
modern family.
That guy,
he's a beast.
Seriously?
Yes.
Legit black belt in Jujitsu.
Under the gracies.
Yeah.
Would have never guessed that.
We'd never done so many fucks with them
and getting thrown in their head and
choked unconscious.
But he was telling me this.
He was there.
He is right there at o'neill black belt
training with Horian Gracie.
That what's the average journey to a
black belt years was I'd say 10.
Ten is average and that's grinding like
getting after.
Not Thursday.
Every other week.
Yeah.
But some,
some people get there quicker than 10.
You know,
Bj Penn got his three.
I was a brown belt for eight years.
Eight years of brown belt.
I like your stone job.
I was fuming.
I can train together.
Let's train him like twice a week and
you know,
trying to have a career,
but you know,
for,
for the people that really get into it,
they really get obsessed with it.
It becomes just as addictive as archery,
hunting.
Anything else?
It's.
I and I think what we were talking about
earlier when we were talking about
people being angry and like on social
media because they're not getting those
natural rewards and the natural struggle
of life and their life is very muted in
that regard.
No struggle or no struggle.
I think that's one of the reasons why
Jujitsu is so appealing to people and
even though you get injured in Jujitsu,
but most of the injuries like a tweak my
back or I fucked up my elbow or my knee
gets screwed up.
It's not like brain injuries.
The brain injuries were the ones that
were the most disturbing to me because I
was.
I was recognizing at like 21 that I was
having some issues.
You were talking about this recently
about this,
the headaches laying in bed.
I have and I know a lot of guys from
previous career who are suffering from
we're discovering or the military is
doing research into the causes of the
brain injury issue.
It's not.
It's not awesome to read your future
when you get diagnosed with that and
like,
okay,
so what does it look like when I'm 60?
What does it look like when I'm 78,
late?
That's not good at all.
Those aren't good Tarot cards to read.
My good friend Dr.
Mark Gordon,
who is an expert in traumatic brain
injury and does a lot of work with
soldiers and uh,
Andrew Morris Foundation,
he
has a warrior Angel Foundation and Dr
Gordon does a lot of work with him and
they,
they have developed some really good
protocols for helping guys and these
helped a shit ton of guys and he does a
lot of the work for like nothing.
Just trying to help as many people as he
can because you know,
he's,
he's doing well financially,
you know,
he doesn't,
he's not desperate for money to eat.
He does a lot of charity works.
My point.
He's dedicated a significant amount of
his professional time to try to find
solutions for soldiers.
And also he's done a lot of work with
football players and boxers and
fighters.
Anybody who's going to get that enclosed
brain trauma it at the end of the day,
I think on the chart it ends up looking
the same.
It doesn't matter how he necessarily got
it.
The UFC is in involved in some new
protocols now too.
They.
They've developed some stuff in San
Diego.
In fact,
I forget what the.
A medical institution that's doing it,
but they've got something.
They're dealing with some sort of
electro magnetic therapy,
magnetic resonation with touch.
I have heard there is a.
It may well be the same clinic.
There's a couple of buddies that I have
who came to San Diego,
La Jolla area.
They would go in once a day or twice a
day for a quick session.
I'm pretty sure it was magnets placed
either across from each other,
whatever.
It was a protocol.
I think it was for a month and to a
person.
They all actually said that they had a
significant benefit,
whether that be.
Most of them were saying they were
sleeping better and I don't know the
causality or correlation there,
but they had improvement.
It could have been their mood function,
whatever it may be,
but so how did the fighters,
what do they think about if you get
knocked out in the UFC,
like you're just flatlined,
do you have a minimum amount of time
before you can back?
I think most of the time they give them
a 90 day suspension,
which in my opinion is way too short.
I was going to.
Yeah,
because first of all they say like 90
days,
no contact,
but those guys are going to be sparring
before then.
That is the issue that I've heard with
some of the active duty guys now.
They'll go in and from a perspective
that they kind of want to preempt and
get an idea of where their head is at
currently.
They'll go in and they'll get a scan or
however they.
They couldn't give me the scans because
I have retained metal in my body,
but I think a lot of it is based off of
Mris and the magnets and stuff and
they'll recognize that they have the
precursors or they'll.
They'll have damage to their head and
the guys,
they don't want to take any time off.
They went,
just want to get back into it.
It's,
it's,
it's a struggle.
They're like,
hey,
listen,
this is could be what it could look like
for you in the coming years.
And the guy's like,
yeah,
I get it,
but put me back in coach.
It's a struggle to get them to take time
off,
which that doesn't surprise me that the
UFC guys were the same way.
No,
that's,
that's absolutely the way they are.
Especially the real savages.
The ones where the winners like Michael
Bisping,
you know,
he lost the George St Pierre and then
three weeks later fought against Calvin
gasoline and got stopped and a lot of
people criticize
that,
me included,
and they shouldn't let them in there.
You know what I mean?
He needs time to recover.
You got battered in that fight,
got choked unconscious.
Then you've got them fighting again
three weeks later.
It's just not smart,
but he
probably a not knowing a thing about it.
Fought tooth and nail to get into that
ring with you.
I guess 102 weeks later it's a fucking
animal until you're,
until you're done 60 and then you're
drooling on yourself and you know,
you're thinking or the Easter bunny.
I mean,
that's not,
that's not a good look.
No.
And it's possible.
Yeah,
for sure.
Yeah.
You have to almost protect people from
themselves or may be.
There could be an argument that there
should be sort of a comprehensive
education for fighters at least because
this is an elective thing,
right?
And which you're definitely going to get
hit for soldiers.
My good argument as well,
but there should be some sort of
elective or uh,
you know,
um,
some sort of an education thing.
That's the word I was going to say.
At least at least educate to the,
just go in,
go into whatever situation you're going
to go into,
whether it's the UFC or the nfl or the
military,
whatever it just go in with an educated
perspective instead of going in blank
and,
and at the end of it not understanding
where you're at and why it happened.
So what do you think it is that makes
you want to jump out of planes?
Perfectly.
Good.
Airplane.
You put a squirrel suit on a.
do you think this is what I asked you
before?
Do you think that this is like your
fulfilling some sort of a desire for
excitement?
Some.
Some need for extreme situations?
Well,
so skydiving,
jumping out of an airplane,
is it to me,
if you,
if you follow some very basic principles
of being current and maintaining your
gear and taking your time to pack your
parachute the most difficult or not most
difficult.
The most dangerous portion of a day
skydiving will be your drive to the drop
zone and your drive home from,
uh,
what happens to those people that fuck
up and die?
Well,
there's two.
So you get a separate two categories.
There's jumping out of an airplane with
a parachute and a reserve parachute and
a lot of altitude and a lot of time.
And then there's base jumping which is
off of a static object with one
parachute generally closer to the
ground.
And that lack of altitude and separation
from the ground gives you less time,
less options.
You got to be really tight on your,
a game in both of those worlds.
What I think in my opinion is that kills
the most people is complacency.
There has not been a gear related
fatality is far back as I can really
find it,
at least in the last 10 to 15 years.
It's people killing themselves,
not the gear killing them.
How's that work?
What do you mean?
How did they kill themselves?
Uh,
getting in over your head,
attempting a maneuver that you have no
ability to recover from if it were to go
wrong,
uh,
in the skydiving world.
So to use the,
the wingsuit as an example,
if you keep the suit flying straight,
it feels incredibly stable.
It feels like you're laying in an air
mattress.
It's not hard at all that you literally
get out of the aircraft and you spread
your arms and legs out.
There's Ram air inlets that inflate the
suit and you can lay on it.
You can literally just relax and lay in
the suit and you'd fly at 60 percent of
your performance to make up a number
that's probably somewhat accurate,
but then you know,
maybe you want a flat on your back,
you know Jesus.
Then maybe you want to fly next to
people.
Then maybe you want to do an intricate
formation that's both vertically and
horizontally separated.
I've heard of people colliding while Sky
Dot yes.
Has catastrophic results.
Like Louise get ripped off a.
yeah.
There was a pair of Golden Knights that
guide to capitate and it didn't
decapitate the guy from the pelvis down.
Cut off both legs,
but you can get yourself going 100 miles
an hour forward speed.
So you got off both.
Yup.
What hit his head?
Hit his shoulder head is a,
I believe the lower portion of his legs.
And what happened to the guys shoulder?
He had a vacation in the hospital for a
little bit and the other guy died.
Yeah.
Actually knew what I think.
I might be wrong on that.
I think the dude with no legs,
I think the dude with no legs is the one
who lived because he jumped again.
The guy who hit him is the one that
died.
Fuck,
it's a.
it's jumped again after that.
Yeah,
nearly.
of course.
Of course he did.
It's like when you text me like,
would you do this shit and France into
the planet?
I'm like,
don't ask me rhetorical questions.
I'm gonna.
Ask you a guy was trying to get into the
plane.
He was doing the squirrel suit into the
plane,
but he missed.
Yeah.
Sometimes you miss.
He bounced off the plane and it didn't
look good,
so that was a the same red bull dudes
and that is probably the worst situation
you could get into because you could see
he was spinning in the suit and that is
how you can kill yourself in a wing suit
if you try some crazy maneuver that
you're not capable of doing,
essentially stole the suit and then you
end up on your back spinning out of
control.
You'll black out in,
you know,
whatever happens happens.
What happened to that guy that bounced
off the plane?
He pulled it out.
He did.
Because you know later on that day.
Yeah.
I mean,
but those.
So that guy that is fred invents their
red bull dudes,
they are at the absolute apex of what's
possible and yeah,
I mean he hit it.
He was able to recover because later in
that video they were both able to
successfully get in,
but that guy has been jumping for
decades in tens of thousands of jumps.
So of course he can recover from that.
If you've got 10 jumps,
you're dead.
But the problem is people see that video
and they're like,
I know what I'm doing on Thursday,
and he died.
They do stupid shit and they're not.
They're not aware of their ability or
their skill or they're just not looking
in the mirror and being honest with
themselves.
They attempt something crazy,
but most common in skydiving thing is
somebody to die under perfectly
functioning equipment.
They'll have a really small main canopy,
like most main canopy.
The canopy or suspended under in your
harness when you're learning is about
300 to 360 feet.
It's like driving a school bus.
It really slow turns.
It doesn't dive,
and a lot of people try to get to these
little postage stamp parachutes.
There are 71 square feet,
69 square feet,
and in those canopies,
if you initiate a turn,
regardless of what you do after that
turn,
you cannot pull the canopy out of the
dive until it goes through its natural
recovery arc,
so if you initiate that turn 300 feet
low,
you're done.
You'd be.
You'd be lucky to walk away with a set
of powdered femurs,
which is exciting to watch from the
ground.
It's a very interesting noise to hear
happen.
That's best case scenario.
Middle of the ground would be wheelchair
with a colostomy bag for the rest of
your life.
Worst case scenario,
you're getting carted off in an
ambulance and you're dead and it's just
a rush to get to that super small canopy
or you just started jumping,
so this is like a status thing.
Guys want to show you that they're
jumping on the super small up.
You ever see people in the mixed martial
arts world who just started and they
think they're ready for the cage?
Yes.
It's the exact same thing.
I bet you would happens in Motorcross as
surfing guy learns to serve as like
north shore.
Let's go like.
Excuse me,
sir.
You're using a foam surfboard that's 12
feet long to go to the north shore.
You're going to die,
but nothing you say to them easier to
use a foam on this 12 feet long.
I don't know.
I don't know where it came from that
from probably on a smaller way.
Maybe I should get a foam surfboard,
but I think I think either way though on
the north shore they're going to die,
but to you try to tell that to that
person.
They don't want to hear it.
They're ready and not only that,
they're ready.
I need to go to best buy and get about
four Gopros and then we're going to send
this thing and you're dead and it
presents this and it creates this.
That's what I like.
Uh,
I don't like to talk about the risk
necessarily because there are,
there is,
in my opinion,
a community of people that really
romanticize that risk and they define
themselves by that risk or that's not
for me.
That's not what I'm looking for at all.
But when it comes to skydiving,
it's just fun,
man.
I cannot not smile when I'm flying that
wingsuit.
You're doing 120 miles an hour forward
face first.
They've got a bug in the mug.
Oh yeah.
You'll come down to speckled all sorts.
I've almost hit a bird base jumping in
Switzerland,
like it's just,
Oh yeah,
it's.
But again,
there's a difference between skydiving
and base jumping.
Skydiving is if you have enough
experience and you learned that you can
handle with most likely what's going to
come up,
you can just focus on having fun.
Base jumping is a different activity for
sure.
It looks the same.
It's a different sport,
different act.
I don't even call it a sport.
It's an activity.
How many guys have you seen die base
jumping,
skydiving in a squirrel suit?
Actually,
not that many.
I have seen more people die under the
super small canopies turning to low and
just impacting the ground.
I mean it's,
it's a sight to be seen where the
candidates in such a steep dive,
like as you're the canopies up top,
as your pitch over your body is actually
above the canopy,
so it hits and they them into the
ground.
It's a,
it's like a wet,
wet meat on concrete it,
you know.
Exactly.
And you can hear it coming because the
canopy is whistle.
The lines that suspend you underneath
the canopy that are cutting through the
air and you just hear it.
You look up and then Wham,
uh,
as far as actually physically watching
people go in May too,
I think.
But you know,
my last trip to Switzerland in 2016 last
year,
I was in a,
in the valley with my buddy Alex and we
were there for two weeks and 15 people
when in 15.
Yep.
Now how many people were there that it's
hard to say.
And that's why,
again,
I think you have to be careful talking
about the stats and the risk because I
don't really know how many people
partake in that activity,
but I can tell you this,
of those 15,
zero,
we're gear related,
not a single one was because their gear
failed.
It was in my opinion,
somebody attempting or just living there
or walking on a razor blade and
sometimes when I go over there I'll I
will do that as well.
I'll fly close to the ground or I'll fly
in between.
Trees were all fly through a crack and
mess around with that.
But I,
I try to do it on a very limited time
period.
I try to have outs and I try to work my
way into that position and what I have
seen personally,
which doesn't mean that this.
This is the norm.
What I have personally seen with my own
eyes is people that don't take that
route and they want to go straight to
just,
hey,
hold my beer and there's just no room
for air.
Yeah.
That's a lot of people though.
Like W,
w,
what percentage of the people don't
like,
how many people were there?
I don't know.
Probably a couple hundred as far.
Oh Jesus.
Well that's just 115 people.
Croaked yeah,
that's a lot.
That's a login.
I tried it.
Again,
I try to be honest.
I accept the activity.
Here's my thing.
I don't ever want to gamble but I am
willing to take risk and I know that
that activity has some risk associated
with it but for me personally the
benefit outweighs the risk and I also
spend most of my year trying to put in
place things that can mitigate that
risk.
Like jumping all the time and being
current in my suit and I like I'll walk
away but I've been at plenty of exit
points where the weather wasn't good or
the wind wasn't good or I just wasn't
feeling it.
And I think a lot of other peanut pool
probably had the same feelings and
there's zipping up their suit,
getting ready to go.
And I'm like,
peace out man.
I'll see you later.
I'm going go drink a bottle of red wine
and you know,
have a glass.
Yeah,
I don't,
I would love to be the base jumper that
has walked away from more exits than
anybody else on earth.
More than I would like to be the base
jumper that's done more extreme shit
than anybody else on earth.
Like how many times you think you've
walked away,
how many times have you gotten to a
situation where you're at the starting
line?
You're like,
this doesn't feel right.
15,
20.
Wow.
And some of those things will give you a
two hour hike on the way down,
you know?
And I kinda don't want to hike down.
That's what gets a lot of people too is
they'll get,
they'll,
there's a lot of hiking involved,
like the youtube videos.
That's about five percent of what it
actually takes.
My favorite jump in Switzerland is about
a two and a half to a three hour walk
for a 92nd flight.
So the ratio of busting your ass to
smiling is very askew.
It's like Disneyland pretty much,
except it's actually fun and it's not
full of pedophiles.
So does anyone else feel a pedophile?
Of course really working.
The kids are.
Where would you go if you were a
pedophile?
And think of it that way.
Come on now.
It's like being a freak and go into the
Strip club.
Come on.
There you go.
You know what kills me about Disneyland?
My kids love Disneyland,
so we go there quite often.
There's these gangs,
Disneyland gangs.
Have you ever seen them before?
What are you talking?
They were vests like they're in the
hell's angels and their vests are
covered with a Disneyland buttons and
Patches and Disneyland Employees.
You're talking about?
Oh No.
These are gangs of Disneyland fans and
they used to have entry a admission
things where like to get in there there
see the Disneyland gangs.
Do you remember what I was saying?
His empire a second ago about the
pedophiles?
Yeah.
Hitchhikers.
Disneyland Waltz,
misfits.
So cow.
Yeah,
with a skull with Disneyland hat on.
And these people go in there.
They have a things that would have.
They would have to have like little
things too that they would have to
accomplish to get entry into these
gangs.
And one of the things was they would
have to have one of the rides go down so
they'd have to make a ride go down in
order to get entry into this stupid
fucking gang.
How does one do that?
Throw something into the gears.
That's good.
Thank you for that.
When we were there,
this one dumb lady,
this is how fucking geniuses dummy was.
California screaming is the roller
coaster where you do that loop where you
go upside down.
Okay.
On the top of the loop.
This dummy through her purse and wanted
to catch it on the way down.
Like she had this idea how that work.
It didn't work.
It hit the ground.
The it hit first.
The rollercoaster ran over,
it stopped the rollercoaster and they
got stuck like three quarters of the way
up through loop.
And you know everybody's like yet,
yeah,
they stopped the rollercoaster.
She went to jail.
Another you want to hear something
really gross.
One couple.
They had a two year old kid and they
caught them on security cam after the
fact.
They hung back and they put their kid
near a Disneyland employee and they
went,
uh,
went away and stepped away.
So the kid was like,
confused in what to do.
So this Disneyland employee kept an eye
on the kid and then called security and
the security took care of the kid and
then they went to dinner and they had
drinks and they went out and then they
went and retrieved a kid afterwards.
Security.
Not everybody should have kids,
but just imagine the monster.
Do you have to be to take your two year
old kid?
You're like,
I'm tired of having this kid.
Hey,
I've got a great idea.
Oh,
I'm sure their home life is amazing.
Very nourishing monsters,
man.
And you wonder,
like when you see a school shooting or
something crazy like what happened?
This kind of shit does.
You're raising a potential human being.
This kind of shit happens.
You have some fucking morons.
They're allowed to have kids.
And then basically shit shit on an
innocent victim,
which is my biggest issue with it.
Yeah.
I cannot,
I don't like the victimization of
innocent people.
It drives me nuts.
Yeah,
man,
especially little two year olds,
it's crazy.
It's crazy that someone has that in them
that they could be that fucking stupid
that they have that in them and you
know,
I wish that this was an isolated
instance.
I'm sure there's like quite a few of
those.
I'm sure there probably is.
I can't believe you're drinking that
Kombucha stuff.
That's good.
I love it.
It doesn't.
The Brian Brain do the same thing for
your gut.
No,
no.
That's a nootropic and the right brain
is alcohol.
It's probably bad for your gut.
I'm trying to counteract the effects.
I had a sense of Kimchi either.
Absolutely not from for the mind,
spent some time in Korea and watch this
guys pulling that stuff out of the
ground and they would offer.
It's like,
I'm,
no,
I don't want to Kimchi.
I'm more convinced now than ever that.
Plus having a bunch of really good
podcasts,
guests that explained the benefits of
probiotics and about how probiotics
literally affect your gut ecosystem that
affects your personality and your immune
system and just all sorts of different
aspects of your life.
But I've been eating Kimchi sheet almost
when I'm at home daily.
Pretty much daily food by itself.
One,
pair it with a meal,
a pair it with a meal usually,
but sometimes I'll just open up a jar
and just eat a whole jar of the shit.
That's disgusting.
Don't do books.
Today I had Kimchi with elk and
Jalapenos and uh,
some stuff called no bread.
Knows a company that makes k n,
O,
w.
They make these gluten free breads that
are made with nuts and almonds.
And how's it taste good?
It's actually tastes good.
No,
not totally.
Not like a good piece of San Francisco.
Sour dough bread does not taste like
that,
but that's what it tastes like,
but it tastes good enough.
It's good for me.
And most importantly,
it doesn't Jack up your glycaemic index.
It doesn't,
you know,
you don't have an insulin spike.
You feel good after you eat it,
you still,
uh,
you still reading the Quito train?
Most of the time I will fuck off on
occasion.
I will fuck off.
I fucked off all.
Last week I was in Hawaii and I fucked
off hard.
Thanksgiving was an interesting
adventure diet for me too.
I drank every night a dessert every day
I ate whatever I wanted.
I said,
I'm on vacation.
I'm going to treat this like a vacation.
I'm going to have no restraint and I'm
only gonna gain four pounds.
And I worked out every day.
I worked at every day.
Why does it only take one week to
unravel what seems like a lifetime of
work.
And then you start climbing back into
the saddle,
like,
okay,
cool.
I guess I'll just move an inch at a time
here in the last two miles along the
way.
Well,
the good news is I kept working out so
it wasn't like I came back home like
terribly out of shape,
feeling terrible and having gotten drunk
every night.
I bet if I didn't work every day,
I probably would have gained like seven
or eight pounds.
Oh,
100 percent,
you'd probably at least still kept your
metabolism.
Metabolism of the high.
Yeah,
but I was like,
this is what I'm going do.
I'm gonna treat it like this.
I'm going to work out every day so that
I don't have to think about it,
so I could just go crazy.
You're managing guilt?
Yeah,
I eat.
I ate breakfast one day and uh,
we stayed at this place that had a
buffet and they had chocolate croissants
I had for chocolate croissants and then
I had two pieces of banana bread and I
had to sticky buns,
these sticky buns.
Then.
Then I had all sorts of other food on
top of that.
I just ate like a,
like a glutton.
Isn't that amazing?
I don't usually do that.
So it was nice to do it for a vacation.
Amazing.
For a day or two.
Yeah.
But I felt so weak,
like when I would go to the gym,
I literally felt like it was working out
underwater.
Like my brother just combating all the
booze and all the shitty food.
Would that.
Or I'll find my gas tank is just done.
Like you start,
you normally like,
okay,
I'm going to warm up and you're just
like,
oh yeah,
I think I'm done here,
let's place that a heavy bag.
And I knew they had a heavy bag so I
bought boxing gloves and hand wraps and
everything and I have a timer on my
phone so I set the timer up and I just
wailed away.
It's fucking great because you know
those apple ear pods pod,
probably the best apple not to make an
ad for apple.
Probably the best thing I've ever bought
from apple.
Airpods are great.
And here's the thing,
when you have a um,
this timer,
it would play me music but then the
timer,
like the noise of the time,
but it would also go through the air
pods.
Didn't given both.
Yeah.
So when it was getting like 10 seconds
it would alert me through the.
But I would think like,
oh man,
punching the bag and even kicking the
bag.
Those air pods are gonna fall out.
Nope.
Yeah,
they didn't.
I've actually yet to have them fall out.
Yeah.
Regardless.
The only time I've had them falls when I
was doing chin ups because my shoulders
are so fucking massive.
It touched my ears so it didn't fall
out.
They were ripped out by your massive
shoulders.
They just.
My ears bumped up against my my
shoulders,
but that's it.
That's the only time I've ever ever
accidentally fallen out.
But what's interesting is you take one
out and it knows that you have it out.
So the sound stops like,
how the fuck did they figure that out?
Wizardry out have no problem talking to
you while you have headphones on.
They just start talking like they see
the headphones and they just start
talking to you to pretend like you can't
hear them and you pointed the headphones
and they're like,
no,
no.
You have to talk to me.
They talk louder.
I don't give a fuck if you're on the
phone.
I don't give a fuck if you're in the
middle of the most important audio book
ever getting the secrets of the universe
right now,
people won't talk to you,
man.
I think that might be more of a problem
that you deal with as opposed to others,
but I think girls get it more than me.
I know words.
I know women who have put a headphones
into their ears and not even attached it
to a device.
That's good.
Just so people will leave them alone.
Just stick it right in there posting.
I don't know if you can hear.
Yeah,
I don't.
I don't know if would necessarily
work.
What island did you go to?
Hawaii?
Um,
my favorite is Lanai.
Is that where you guys went for
Thanksgiving?
We went to the big island this time.
Nice split.
I think Linda is the way to go because
they ain't nobody there.
And you gotta take two flights from La.
Hulu?
Yeah.
You got to go to Honolulu and then you
take a little puddle jumper.
A little one of them.
Little buddy holly killing planes.
I guess.
Imagine backpack
you can borrow.
They ask how much your packs.
Oh No,
don't say that.
How much do you weigh,
sir?
Don't lie.
Please don't lie.
Actually padded by about 10 percent.
You're going to be okay.
I wonder if what they do,
if they get like a really overly weight
person who they know might be full of
shit.
Like I don't want to find out what
happens ladies.
I know what happens.
They Jack up a couple of pounds when I
was super young.
Like I just,
I remember that I went on a cruise with
my grandparents to Alaska.
I don't know where we started,
but we went up to Alaska when we were
flying back from Alaska puddle jumper to
probably do now to get on the plane and
they looked at my grandfather like a
little up and down.
Like,
sir,
you're on the next flight.
Really?
Yep.
They bumped him.
GRANDPA had a gut grandpa.
He was,
he was built big boy.
He was.
He was built from the belly button up to
the chest,
like a beach ball.
Hey Man.
Some like I wouldn't want to be in a
puddle jumper with a really big guy that
was full of shit.
No,
you'll kill everybody at some point.
The plans like,
Hey,
I know you're pulling back on the yoke,
but I actually can't take off,
so you're all going to die now,
and that's not the way to go either.
Right?
Because someone has an ego and they
can't tell you.
There are 400 pounds,
not 50.
Yeah.
So they.
I think they actually took his luggage
off and he had to come back like that.
I think it was the next day.
Well,
the real problem is for someone who's
400 pounds,
they have to find a scale that goes up
to 400 pounds or you get a time and as
it goes around.
But Joey Diaz was telling me that when
he was 400 pounds,
like they,
he didn't.
He didn't know how much you weighed
because the scale at his doctor's office
only went to 300 pounds and you have
that.
Imagine that pegged bang,
and then he'd lose 50 pounds and it
would still be pegged.
I think that's not a good sign.
No,
I mean I'm not a doctor obviously,
but I think that all this stuff,
when you see all these people that are
like morbidly obese,
I think this is all a.
there's a lot of things right?
This shitty food.
There's a bad gut flora addict addiction
to like refined carbohydrates and
sugars,
alcohol,
a lot of things that make people that
fat,
but on top of that,
I think a lot of it is that they don't
have like real physical challenges in
their life on a daily basis.
Especially physical challenges that they
enjoy.
That forces them to be disciplined about
their health and to understand that
their body is.
It's not just your body,
okay.
It's like you have this variable vehicle
and the time you put
into it,
the more you pay attention to it and the
more discipline you use to keep this
thing running,
the better it's going to work for you
and if you use it all the time,
you're gonna appreciate it.
But if you just use it to walk over to
the couch and crack a beer and start
fucking filling your face with chips and
cookies,
you don't think about what it is and you
don't have to rely on it to survive.
You don't have to chop wood.
You have to.
You don't have to carry anything.
You gotta go.
You gotta.
Look on your phone for the right APP to
have uber.
Deliver your food so you don't even have
to get off of your ass.
That's a new thing.
It's a new thing,
but I bet she gets pretty popular.
But it doesn't come to your neck of the
woods.
I bet I wouldn't order it.
Even if it did.
I don't have restaurants in your town.
Well,
yes.
We also have electricity and running
water.
No,
we do a lot.
You had a.
well I do at my house we have in the
woods.
Oh,
that's amazing.
Well you should come visit sometime.
Wells.
I liked the idea of water is God damn.
It's good.
Oh yeah.
Unbelievably clear.
Spring water.
It just tastes different.
It tastes different to A.
Yeah,
I it,
I liked the small town we have,
we have everything we need.
Probably a couple things that we
probably still need and not much of what
we don't.
Is there any crime?
I'm sure.
I actually.
Yeah,
I bet you there's some,
a little bit off the rails.
Crime I think any place,
so we don't live in white fish.
White fish is like 15 miles north of us.
I'm pretty sure there's a large like
white nationalists,
white supremacists.
I've read some stuff about it.
I haven't really looked into it too
much,
but I knew that they were getting ready
to do a little bit of a march type
action rally.
You should walk around everywhere in
black face.
I don't think that's the call.
I don't have an Afro.
I was thinking of just driving my truck
through the white nationalist rally is
because my truck is black so.
Right.
Yeah.
That would be the metaphor.
So if one of them Tiki torches and see
if you feel me,
man,
let's fucking dickheads.
Oh,
those dickheads in Charlotte walking on
the street with home depot torches.
I still can't figure out if they're
serious.
Oh,
they're serious.
There've been with Home Depot Tiki torch
in your hand.
You're serious.
Yeah,
they're serious.
They just want a torch and they're so
fucking stupid.
They don't really tell that that's going
to be mocked,
you know?
I don't know if they even care.
I think they're just glad they're either
getting coverage so that they feel that
their message is getting out to
everybody who needs to hear it in their
mind,
but he didn't need to hear it because
most people didn't know that there was a
group that duck fucking stupid that's
willing to go into the streets like that
and do it in this day and age when
you're on the Internet and people are
gonna Realize,
Oh,
you're a Nazi swastika on your chest.
You dumb cunt.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
There you go,
buddy.
I don't know if it's that bad up in
white fish,
but I do know that there is.
I have found is like you eat to the
remote areas.
It seems like a drug related crime might
be a tad higher.
Gets a little messy.
Yeah.
I was gonna say,
but I'm not sure.
I mean
anecdotally I think from my perspective,
that's what it seems to be like,
but I haven't.
I mean I feel super comfortable.
I don't feel.
Yeah,
I mean,
I don't know.
It feels,
it feels smaller is the only way that I
can describe it and that feeling fuels
awesome.
Yeah,
it's peaceful,
right?
Yeah.
So like not a great word for sure.
It's slower to it is.
Like I said,
the only regret is that I wish we had.
I wish we had been able to do it.
Well we would.
We were able to do it.
We just didn't do it.
I wish we had done it a couple of years
ago.
Yeah,
I felt that way about boulder.
Boulder feels like that too.
Vain.
Boulder feels to me like,
you know,
it's only a 100,000
people,
which is way bigger than your town.
Twenty 2000.
That's crazy.
But it just,
everything is like,
oh,
it's just a calmer folders and
interesting town.
It reminded me a lot of where I grew up
in Santa Cruz,
very left like great place.
If you're selling Tofu,
Santa Cruz is a great place to grow up.
The problem is,
is that a lot of people don't leave
Santa Cruz.
It's,
it's so far left that it ends up on the
right somehow there.
Yeah,
it's insane.
And I,
you know,
the guys and girls that I went to high
school with,
a couple of them have never left and not
that I haven't really maintained contact
with them,
but even if I did,
I don't know if I'd have anything to
talk to them about.
It's such an insulated and the like.
So the small town that we live in,
I'm like,
I want my kids when they grow up and
they get to that age,
they get to leave.
They got to go and experience something
else.
I don't want them to think that that
22,000
people is,
this is how the world is.
It's not the best thing I did in Santa
Cruz was leaving at some point.
Um,
friend of mine has been on the podcast
before,
used to be on this podcast called
citizens radio and he was a,
um,
like a real heavy duty lefty social
justice warrior type character.
And somewhere along the line he ran
afoul of them because he dates girls
like girls.
Girls were calling them a Predator or
something like that.
It really didn't do anything wrong.
Like if you look at it on paper,
like,
okay,
what did he do wrong?
There was nothing.
There was no rape,
there was no assault,
there was no harassing.
It was him trying to get laid a which I
thought was normal,
but I guess not in that world it's
problematic.
But in the social justice world,
it's problematic to be an aggressive.
A Sexual Predator she did is actually
had attorney and really not cool at all.
But what he said was that when he was in
that world,
he didn't even,
wasn't even aware of dissenting
viewpoints because he was so insulated
because everybody in that world thought
a certain way.
And so you just get accustomed to these
very rigid sort of channels of thinking
and everybody sort of follows these
channels and he literally wasn't even
aware of the possibility of there being
a dissenting point of view that was
rational.
How do people not realize that that's
inherently dangerous?
They get caught up in it.
People are super tribal,
you know,
I don't have to tell you that I made.
Yeah,
I agree.
But it's at the same point,
like I try to recognize myself,
like if I'm whatever,
consuming anything information.
If I'm like,
okay,
I need to go and figure something else
out or hear another viewpoint or at
least try to balance it to me.
Like the spidey senses started going up.
If too many people are saying the same
thing,
if everybody is all chanted in the sense
like what's going on with you might be
down the rabbit hole here.
We need to take a few steps back.
Yeah,
but that's because you are a winner.
Some people are just not tiger blood,
but I'm trying.
There's some things that people have
that are like unfortunate.
And one of the things that people have
is this deep desire to have other people
like them and to fit in and to cause
zero friction and to,
to be amenable to the group think,
you know,
it's like it's a real.
It's a common issue with folks like you
see them like just slotting into group
think ideology and whether it's group
think on the right side,
a group thing.
I mean there's a lot of fucking really
dumb people that I follow on twitter
that are a make America great again.
People like,
I'll go to Hashtag Maga every now and
then and just start reading tweets and
just just like fucking macaulay culkin
from home alone.
My hand on my head going,
oh my God,
these people are serious.
No,
drain the swamp.
Hashtag drain the swamp.
And I'll go and I'll read these people's
tweets.
I'm like,
these people are just apes that are in a
tribe.
They,
they,
they are really,
really.
Not all of them folks,
don't get me wrong.
There's a lot of people that are making
America great again.
People that really do feel like it's a
good thing to have this guy in office,
stock market's up,
I'm not talking about you,
but I'm talking about people that have
this tiny little brain and this tiny
little brain just needs to slot into a
place and this is where they found this
is their spot and then you go onto their
twitter page and these motherfuckers are
on all day arguing with people about
trump all day accomplishing nothing.
No,
but they feel like they've got a huge
microphone and they're getting
absolutely nowhere.
Yeah.
And they just everyday they just
constantly checking their responses,
checking their tweets,
chicken.
They're thing back and forth,
back and forth.
You know what scares me about that is it
again,
I feel like I'm late to the game to
everything and,
and social media late to the game.
A podcasting late to the game.
Like I was telling you like I'm trying
to play catch up and I used to look at
the news and largely accept,
you know what?
I could corroborate on each side and now
I can't look at any of that.
And so I just have to use my own eyes,
but I see with my own eyes,
people arguing with their head down so
much about what they believe that
they're actually not seeing what's
happening around them and because nobody
trusts anything and they only repeat
what they say,
it provides the seams for people to do
shit that as a country,
I don't think we want to go in that
direction in that distraction moves are
being made that people aren't paying
attention to.
Yeah.
And I feel like with all this thing
about trump and Russia and everybody
thinking that flint is going to turn on
trump and this is it.
We're going to.
Trump's going down,
trump's going down like,
hey guys,
North Korea's got nuclear capability and
they've just launched some new fucking
missile icbm.
Yeah,
high end orbit.
That's cable reaching America.
Do you understand what's happening?
And we're,
we're sending stealth bombers over to
South Korea like we are.
We are literally a few steps away from
the brink of a nuclear war.
We're not there yet,
but we're in the.
We're,
we're where we should.
Everybody should be going,
hey,
what was the fuck is going on over here?
Yeah.
Like what is this?
Why are we even battling them?
What the fuck is the issue?
Other than the fact that.
I mean if you want to talk about going
somewhere where you have a real
communist dictatorship,
that is a ruth ruth iron fist military
dictatorship that has an entire country
of people in slaved North Korea's a
spot.
I mean it really is a video of that
defector whole Lee Shit.
My pulled out a mama hen got Swiss
cheese and just kept the foot on the gas
pedal.
Kept going there.
Not as truck shot him.
Oh,
you have five or six times.
Six times riddled with like parasites.
Yeah.
Big Parasites.
Like two feet long.
My man.
I mean,
there you go.
Well,
what motivates somebody to run that hard
and that fast and he made it and he made
it.
He must be sleeping so good right now.
Yeah.
Was probably getting fed for the head on
the pillow.
I mean,
just imagine how he'll kind of look at
this dude.
Get Out,
get some.
I'll fall down,
buddy.
Nice.
Okay.
I probably played it off though.
He's like,
yeah,
I wouldn't want to shoot syrup.
Is that all they have now?
They have the full thing.
You know,
you get the nightline version of it so
you can get the full actual video of the
full actual video of.
It's pretty interesting.
He was getting shot at in the car.
Yeah.
You can see the trace around and they're
really close to them.
Yeah.
It doesn't necessarily mean anything.
I've missed close shots.
Panicking.
It's welcome.
Here it is.
This guys just hauling ass.
Here's my question.
You think he was playing the radio like
metallica planned?
Kickstart my heart.
Yeah.
Metallica.
I'm going forward North Korea.
Soldiers for sue,
the man while he flees and a military
vehicle.
What kind of cars you got there?
It looked like a jeep.
It looks like a land rover down,
so he stops the car.
He gets out and he's running and they're
shooting at him from six feet away.
Fortunately the guy on the far right's
got a pistol.
He's not hitting shit.
He's tripping over his buddy back.
Ooh,
that guy's got a rifle though.
Oh my God.
The Korean soldier accidentally clock
crosses into South Korea during the
pursuit.
So that's the line right there.
I do not know.
So that's all you have to take.
Turns around.
So there's not a fence.
I don't know.
You just have to get to that spot and I
don't know about the DMZ shot and
injured.
The factor is pulled to safety by the
South Korean military.
Whoa,
that's amazing.
Oh,
these people crawling.
That looks like the South Korean people.
Yeah,
they're dragging him.
Holy Cow.
I didn't know about this.
Oh my God.
See the blood trail.
Oh,
that's what.
That is.
More than likely on a thermal.
Oh,
that's intense.
That's intense.
So you want to talk about an iron fist
dictator that's happening right now and
people,
all they can think of is just looking at
that guard.
Go look at him.
Go.
He's out gear.
Yeah,
I don't.
I don't know the rules on the DMZ or
where the actual line is.
If this video on like South Korea's
side,
is that how they.
Someone saw this taken place.
So it looks like he's driving from north
to south.
Yeah.
Does he just have to get across that
gate?
So this is this like a DMZ.
It's almost like an unedited version.
The second at 10 minute version of it.
Wow.
I guess they just constantly monitor
everything.
How weird must that tension between the
north and south of staring at each other
in the opposite side of the line.
And they both look exactly the same.
They're both Korean,
you know,
it's like the US wall with Mexico.
People go,
oh,
it's racist,
it's racist because one,
people are proud and when people are
white they can't even say it's racist
over there.
They're both the same race just looking
at each other.
And then there were a war.
They hate each other and one's the enemy
and one's not.
One has no money.
One is under the iron rule of a
communist military dictatorship where
they kill everybody.
The other one,
they're making the best cell phones in
the world.
Chicks were all getting plastic surgery,
you know,
the boys are all fucking hip hop break
dancers and shit and like they have mma
over there.
They have everything that South Korea is
that tag windows pretty fucking awesome
souls and awesome town.
Yeah,
I've been there.
I spent my 20th birthday in Seoul,
Korea,
and a bar.
People that think that socialism and
communism is the answer to the woes that
capitalism creates.
Do not understand you.
Just missing the point that is.
It's so contrary to human nature and it
is,
by the way,
never been pulled off successfully in
human history.
Yeah.
I would love an example and that's what
I always ask people.
Just give me the example of what you
want to use as the foundation for those
principals where it's been executed
properly,
where it's thrived,
where it's survived and I'll just sit
here and wait,
and another part of the problem is that
the people that are really like the
people that are in the left that are
really progressive and support Marxism,
the idea of Marxism and socialism,
those people are in general,
very supportive of gay rights,
very supportive of women's rights.
Those are the first things that get
trampled and his communist
dictatorships.
That is the first thing that goes like
every single one of these communists,
Marxists rules,
homosexuality is treated as the devil
like these people.
Did they live in hell that you don't
understand.
It is very for me,
after a long period of time,
the majority of my adult life to pick my
head up and look around
and
and it most of the interaction,
like I said,
as social media,
I sit back and I watch and I see the
things that people say and I see the
complaints that they have and oppressed
this,
that or the other,
and I'll be the first person to say that
there is inequality in the US.
Just like there is an every nation on
the face of the planet.
But to hear how people think,
how bad we have it,
and then to have seen with my own eyes.
Places where people would
claw their way,
cross the border,
to have the opportunities that people in
this country have just waking up.
The Sun rises over the United States and
they wake up and they have so much
opportunity that they don't appreciate.
It's very difficult for me to make sense
of what's going on.
It's a bizarre place to be in because
it's just like who?
Who are you people and where do you get
these ideas there?
Idealistic and they think that we can do
better and I think that we can do better
too,
but I think where people go a foul is
where they start saying that they want
equality of outcome and equality of
outcome is contrary to equality because
when you have a quality,
a quality,
really quality meaning you can do
whatever you want to do.
That breeds inequality.
Yes,
because some people are going to work
harder and competition is what pushes
things and some people think that
competition is bad and the reason why
they think it's bad because it makes
them feel bad.
Like I put something on twitter today
where they were saying that fit bits
that people using fitbit's is fat
shaming and abelist and it's problematic
and it causes all sorts of issues and
these,
these educators,
we're looking at fitbit's as being a
real problem with the emotions of
people.
You know,
they find out like in.
They start comparing and it can cause
all sorts of issues with people,
so they were literally saying that
fitbit's,
they're just devices that give you data
that these things can be a problem.
How about competition's a good thing?
It's a good thing.
Yeah.
How about it's okay to finish last
because it will motivate you to get off
your ass.
You still on the leaderboard?
Exactly.
Yeah.
Go again.
You don't win every time.
Stupid.
It scares me that people are in
positions like I'm looking at.
My oldest son is 14 and
I mean I realized that at some point in
time in the very near future he's going
to go off and you know,
he's gonna want to pursue a higher
education and I almost would rather send
them to a trade school where he learns
something with his hands or I would hope
that he would.
I would never tell him to do that.
I would hope that he would want to go
down that route instead of going into an
environment that is completely
artificial where people portray this
world of no rounded corners in nerfed
everything and you,
your feelings in words hurt and all.
He talks about it all the time.
Actually I don't my son to go into
that environment.
He's already experiencing that a little
bit in the school system that is in like
he uses the word triggered and heal.
His teachers will use that word
triggered and I'm like,
listen,
it's okay to have somebody say something
to you that invokes a reaction or
emotion in you that causes conflict.
That's okay.
Don't run away from that conflict.
Once you go directly,
add that conflict and figure out what
your problem is with it or figure out
why you have an issue with that and then
work through that and you'll be a better
person on the other side of the house.
I feel like these were in a place now
where people are creating.
It's an artificial environment that as
soon as you leave that environment,
you're going to get your teeth kicked in
and I don't.
I see it trending more and more and more
in the u.
s and I almost think we're getting ready
to fall flat on our face and I almost
think we need to to figure out who the
fuck we are and to pick ourselves back
up into,
into realize that those artificial
environments that people are trying to
force onto the world.
It just doesn't work in campus.
Cities and towns that have campuses.
Yeah.
It's just,
it's just really heavy duty leftwing
people that are just committed to this
ideology and they don't have a.
I mean,
it's good to have both sides.
I think it's good to have people that
lean left and people that lean right and
you try to figure out which,
yeah,
balanced way works and by the way it's
gonna work better for some way.
Some people to be left and is going to
work better.
For some people it'll be right,
but this lack of tolerance for other
people's ideas is one of the most
shocking things about the left these
days is this,
this need and desire to shut down
speech.
You know,
um,
there was also the people who are on the
forefront of saying,
you know,
freedom of speech,
but not that,
not anymore,
you know,
they used to be.
The new left is more stifling of free
speech than the right by far the new
left would,
you know,
you'd call neo Marxism or postmoderns.
I guess I look at it differently,
like freedom of speech to me in my mind
is not about what I can say to you.
It's not about me saying I'm going to
say something,
you know,
messed up and try to offend you.
To me,
freedom of speech is how much can I
tolerate from somebody else?
How much am I willing to listen to an
opinion that I absolutely hate,
but I'm going to allow it to exist
because I'm grateful that we have an
environment that that can exist in and
you're not going to get pulled into a
public square and get your head cut off?
Well,
there's certainly that,
but there's also the only way you find
out which idea is correct is you have to
have debate.
You have to have open debate.
You have to have the ability to
communicate your ideas freely,
and if you don't have the ability to
communicate your ideas freely and the
other person just bulldozes you with
their ideas because they think they're
right and I'm going to shut down
everyone else's opinion because I'm
right.
That's not how you handle free speech.
The way you have to tell you that
opinion isn't allowed,
right?
Yup.
You handle bad speech with more better
speech you,
you,
you become.
You have to have your arguments laid out
in a way that's convincing to the people
that are paying attention and you can't
do that if your speech is stifled and
that's what's really a problem with the
left these days and it's just.
And I think a big part of it is these
artificial environments you're talking
about the they,
they,
they live in these insulated things.
Like I was saying,
Jamie Kilstein used to live in.
They live in these insulated
environments where they think they're
right and they think they're doing the
right thing by behaving like this,
but it's so short sighted.
And I,
and again,
I don't,
I don't try to make a character judgment
on them,
but to me in my mind again with,
with my own eyes,
I think the biggest threat to this
country is political correctness and
safe spaces.
Yeah.
I truly think that teaching people in
that manner or getting them,
not getting them,
allowing them to think that that is how
the world outside of that environment
operates is setting you up for a very
longterm failure because you're going to
just get crushed because there are
plenty of other entities throughout the
world that we'll look at what you're
doing and say,
oh,
that's awesome.
You're just teeing it up for me.
That's a complete vulnerability.
They're going to leverage that against
us and manipulate,
not manipulate,
just attack the fact that those people
feel that way.
They'll take it as a weakness and
they'll leverage that for their success
and with them we're fucked.
Yeah.
I don't necessarily think we're fucked
because I think there's enough people
that are paying attention to think it's
terrible and there's a lot of us,
but I think that when something like
nine slash 11 happens,
one of the things that I thought that
was really interesting right after nine
slash 11 was his rallying cry of
patriotism.
Like everybody had an American flag on
their car just like this is.
This is interesting to me.
Did they have them hanging over the
overpasses up here in la?
Oh yeah,
in San Diego that week.
I would say it was about a week after
nine slash 11.
I have never in my life,
felt a level of solidarity of,
of just.
Not only that,
but people were nicer.
They were nicer.
They were more upset.
There wasn't.
They weren't really worried that you cut
them off in traffic.
You know what?
Take the parking spot.
Yeah,
no,
you can put your cart in front of me.
Not Grocery store for us against them.
How fleeting was that freedom hall,
but it was amazing during that time
period to the overpasses and San Diego,
American flags hanging like not just an
American flag covered the entire thing.
It was unbelievable.
I've in longer in New York,
New York,
it lasts for a long time.
They kind of have a daily reminder.
Yeah.
The feeling there was different.
They were just to change the Way New
York City was New York City.
It was almost like a village,
so we have a friendly village that had
been attacked and everybody was like
super thankful that they were alive and
supportive of each other and also the
solidarity.
You know,
Sebastian younger is a war journalist.
You ever heard of him?
I've listened to every podcast you've
done with him.
Restrepo is one of my favorite
documentaries.
He's fucking amazing.
His book tribe changed the way I
understand that.
I'm like,
oh,
this is a natural part of being human,
and like we were talking about these
reward systems that are built into
animals that loud tigers and like they,
they don't get the natural release.
These natural reward systems for good or
for bad human beings are designed to
deal with conflict,
look real conflict,
and when we don't have real conflict,
we make up our own bullshit conflict and
when real conflict shows itself,
then everything sort of normalizes and
that's.
I mean it's for good or for bad.
We haven't evolved past that.
Whatever our DNA is,
whatever our programming is and are very
almost at a cellular level.
We're designed to have a certain amount
of risk and when we don't have that risk
and we don't have that danger,
we don't feel good and you lash out at
people with your egg icon.
These motherfuckers,
I'm going to kill you unless you were
here in my face and then I wouldn't say
that I'm going to kill it.
Yeah,
it was a credit.
I mean,
I remember watching the second airplane
go in live,
standing in an apartment in San Diego
thinking this might change some things.
Yeah.
I remember just waking up.
Someone called me.
Where were you living at the time I was
here,
was getting some phone calls from
friends.
I was like,
what?
Turn on the news.
He turned on the news and you're like,
just having an all sink in.
Like what the fuck?
And then me and man,
I used to have a picture of it.
Me and Eddie Bravo and Joey Diaz went to
get burritos and there wasn't a fucking
plane in the sky and we're hanging out
that day because all air travel had been
suspended and we were just hanging out
thinking how fucking bizarre it as we're
like,
dude,
are we at war?
Like what the hell?
How is this going to change everything?
Did Eddie feel better because there
weren't econ trails up there.
He wasn't the same guy back then.
He wasn't that deep into it.
No,
no.
He liked aliens back then.
He was into like Nibiru.
He as he became older,
he became way more conspiratorial.
I have a hard.
I know I've texted you before like,
hey,
does he actually think those things or
is he.
He loves conspiracies.
I think he thinks of them almost like
some people like paying attention to
sports,
but then there's also like Illuminati
stuff that he legitimately worries that
like Hillary Clinton is going to off him
because he talks to his shed about I
fucking.
I think it's entirely possible the
Clintons are murderers.
I think it's entirely possible
themselves are outsourced.
Outsourced yet.
I don't think they have the stones to do
something,
so I don't think so,
but I think they've definitely made some
calls or at least had some meetings.
I,
uh,
just too many bodies,
many people attached to them that were
in critical positions that either like,
one recent guy vanished.
Does that Seth Rich Guy who is the New
Yorker Dad worked at the DNC that got
shot.
There's,
there's enough of them and then they go
away.
The stories go away.
The one that I pulled up the other day
who was a who's who would,
who would we do in the podcast was the
guy who had dirt on the Clinton
campaign.
It was an academic and he vanished.
The guy vanished and you don't hear
about it.
This guy was about to like give dirt on
the Clinton Foundation and they're like,
whoops.
He's just not around anymore.
Can't find them.
I think their ability to hide and not
just their academic at heart of Clinton
dirt champion vanishes leaving trail of
questions because he's still missing.
Oh,
this is a part of the Russia
investigation.
That's right.
It wasn't the Clinton campaign.
It wasn't the Clinton Foundation.
Yeah,
he's gone,
man.
It's fucking missing.
Poof,
I did.
I just think it's amazing the ability
for people to have the public face and
then who they are.
I have A.
I have not personally had any
interactions with Hillary Clinton,
but I have some firsthand friends that
have had direct interactions with her
from either a security detail
perspective or being on the ground and
securing an area that she was traveling
through and the public face that she
puts on and how she treated those
individuals up to and including people
that were tasked with her personal
security,
upclose detailed the store is that those
people have would melt your hair,
but none of those stories come out.
There's the person that she portrays
herself to be during the election cycle
and this is who I am,
and then he talked to all these people
who live at a day to day level with
these people and the difference between
the two is like sitting there trying to
broad jump the grand canyon.
It absolutely blows my mind.
The is about her in particular and her
hatred or what they had told me her
hatred for basically in essentially
people in military or people who were
there to support her doing her job.
Just the anger and vitriol that she
would attack those people with on a
daily level is unbelievable anger at the
military and angry 100 percent of the.
She was literally campaigning to be the
commander in chief of the military just
because it comes out of how did she
behave to them?
Uh,
one of the best stories that I have was
a,
I won't say the Agency of the person
worked for was basically she was exiting
the White House and he said,
good morning,
Ms Dot Clinton.
And he was in a uniform at the time and
she stopped and turned around and she
said,
hey,
why don't you go fuck yourself?
Don't talk to me when I'm,
you know,
in going in between place a to place b,
wherever she was going,
got back in her car.
Fuck yourself more that I have that
version of the story again,
not personally for me.
I'm basically saying the things that
I've heard other people say to me in
confidence directly,
but their uniform,
these stories correct.
Uniformed,
whether that be.
It could be a military secret service,
fill in the blank.
They wear a uniform also in the way
these stories.
She 100 percent.
It's exactly the same behavior when the
cameras are not rolling and it's fucking
terrifying because yes,
she is.
She is campaigning or was campaigning to
be the commander in chief of,
from what I can tell again,
having no direct relations with this
person,
a person that despises almost I would
describe,
I would describe it at that is what the
organization stands for.
Unbelievable.
I'm not surprised.
Uh,
what stunned me is how the left was
willing to just absolve her of her.
She was against gay marriage until 2013.
Her obvious belief system,
the like,
who she actually is versus like what
she,
you don't know what she's doing is being
a slick politician just like her husband
publicly.
She is the tide.
She may also rise and fall with whatever
the trend is.
The 2013 thing like the fact that like
how could you,
who,
who the fuck who's educated,
who the fuck was a Democrat at 2013,
still thought that a marriage should be
between a man and woman who gives a shit
like she did because that's what she
does.
She licks her fingers,
she finds out whether it was blowing and
she goes that way and when you see the
difference between what call me,
sad about the investigation and what the
investigation and found on her emails
and what the illegal activity that she
had participated in versus what she
said,
you know what the deleted emails at
30,000
deleted emails and all that stuff and
there's a video that shows what he said
versus what she said.
Play them back to back with each other.
It's like how anybody could support her.
The idea that you wanted someone other
than Donald Trump,
I get it.
The idea that you wanted a woman and
historical first for equality of women.
Do I get that too?
But this is not your one.
There's got to be a lot of women out
there.
The two choices we had at of what,
360 plus million people now God do
insane.
It just,
it's proof that the system is broken.
Yeah,
I agree.
It's compromised for sure.
You know,
the only thing good about having a guy
like trump in his,
he's not from the system has that he
used all of his money and kind of jumped
in and the financial system is still
being supported obviously because he's a
big part of it,
but the political system is in chaos.
I mean he's not a part of that at all
and never was so,
so besides donating money to them,
that was the only thing that people
thought was a saving grace about him
being an office.
Like let's see.
But I think he's crazy.
I think he might literally have
dementia.
I just wish that somebody would grab his
film.
Just real.
Do they try?
No,
just like real quick and just modify the
APP.
So,
but before he hits tweet,
it goes to like one or two people who
give it just a quick sanity check,
Da.
And then they're like proof check
twitter chats.
He checks his comments,
he fucking people I know people are
proud about that.
I've heard you talking about now I've
looked at like I'm blocked by presidents
like man,
hilarious.
But again,
I look at that as people have their head
down,
not paying attention to what they should
be paying attention to because in those
seams that people blowing their mind
over a tweet,
what the hell is getting passed through
in regulations and bills and unlike if
that's the shit that scares me,
the EPA shit scares me the most because
you know what they're doing with the
national monuments.
There's people that are.
They had a meeting this morning.
What's up?
Yeah.
What do you do to the different parks
that.
I can't remember him,
but he shrunk by a whole lot to pull it
up.
Yeah.
It's very scary because you're carving
out a land and national monuments for
privatization.
And there was one that um,
they were,
they were talking about in Alaska that's
very close to a gigantic salmon fishery.
Trump's shrinks,
Utah monuments in historic move.
I wonder which one make that bigger
police or to read it.
If only the sandstone stands,
stones could sing.
Imagine the stories they tell of
dinosaurs.
Mammoth hunters and ancient ones known
as the Anasazi.
All Rome southern Utah.
Over the eons longer for the native
Americans struggled to hold their land
against the Mormon settlers.
Modern life.
And now Donald Trump scroll as president
trump arrives in Utah.
Monday afternoon.
It's this rocky corner of the wild west
is a battlefield once again,
but this time the warriors were carried
briefcases and lawsuits.
Trump by signing to presidential
proclamations on Monday,
shrunk the size of bears ears national
monument by more than 80 percent and the
grand staircase Escalante National
Monument by roughly 45 percent.
Fundamentally reshaping the two large
national monuments.
Man.
Fuck that guy.
I mean,
what?
Can you give me a why other than to say
there's got to be an economical
motivation behind it.
Be Resources has got to be national
resources got to be minerals or oil or
something like that.
So.
And that's my thing.
Like why?
So if you go to Fox News,
right?
Every,
every leading above the brake article is
Hillary.
This hillary.
Why?
Why is that not leading really
Americans,
their little puppets.
I mean,
this idea that they're there just for
America.
No,
you're a puppet of the GOP.
That's what they are.
Not Really American.
They're fucking corrupt.
They're corrupt as everybody else's.
They're the worst.
Like that.
The thing that you,
if you're,
you have blind allegiance towards the
president when he does stuff like this.
That's crazy.
You have to call it.
And some people do like that.
Shepherd.
What's his name?
Shepard Shepard Smith.
Yeah,
that guy.
The perfect eyebrows.
He calls the president and I don't know
if I've ever seen as eyebrows,
but I'm going to take.
Seems it seems like he could have been
one of those guys that was upset at
Hillary Clinton up until about 2013.
Yeah.
Um,
I think,
I think I hear what you're putting down
there,
but again,
you know,
so people are,
they're losing their mind about tweets.
And then in the monument got cut by 80
percent and another one by 45 percent.
And I mean,
and that's one example.
I don't know that and I agree with you.
They are corrupt and what I have found
myself in,
again,
what I think is dangerous is that I've
stopped paying attention and as soon as
that happens,
I don't know what the hell is going on.
Yeah.
That's what happens with a lot of people
and a lot of people just want to eat
meat.
You feel like you can't do anything
other than vote right.
Boat and protest and you have a job at a
family.
How do you have time to protest?
And so a lot of people shut out because
they just don't feel like they don't
feel like they can represent their
opinions in a way that's going to be
meaningful and impactful and it's just,
it's a terrible.
The job of having one chief monkey,
the controls,
300 plus million people and your
definition.
Yeah.
And then here's the thing,
if you are the chief monkey,
if they show that you're a liar,
if they can show,
if there's proof that you're a liar,
should be removed from office.
If you get,
if you are,
if you are in court,
right?
And you swear on a Bible and the you
commit perjury you'd go to jail.
Like why is swearing into office for the
United States?
Why is that less of a like a a situation
where you can be charged with perjury
like that seems to me to be far more
significant.
You're,
you're literally in control of the
country.
You can do things like this fucking
thing that he signed that shrinks these
monuments,
these horrible reductions in the power
that the EPA has.
The fucking environmental protection
agency is to protect our very
environment.
He's like,
no,
no.
We don't need that.
We don't even protection.
Trust me,
we got me.
Yeah.
You would think that he would be held
more accountable because the stakes are
so much higher and it affects so many
people.
Yeah,
I mean the amount of lies that he's told
since office or they're stunning and you
can just get away with them.
You shouldn't be able to get away with
lies.
As a president,
I think lies as a president willingly
lie.
There's one thing to be misinformed but
willingly lying as the president,
if they can show that you had
information to the contrary of what
you're saying,
you should be removed from office should
be a disqualifying factor for sure
percent,
100 percent,
but we've never had someone that lives
this much.
We just don't know about it.
Well,
no one has been able to be proven to be
this much of a liar.
We've never had that.
Where someone lies so much.
You're like,
wow.
Like there's a website that was
documenting the number of times trump
lied or it was like they documented all
of the trump lies over the past year and
it's.
It's crazy.
It's just so frustrating.
As of June 23rd,
every day.
Here's a different one.
Yeah,
I mean,
what's that?
What's the website?
Calls from the New York Times flies on
top to scroll up and we could make it
larger so I could read it here.
Yeah.
I don't know,
man.
I don't want to.
I don't even want to read them.
I'll just get super depressed where the
only issue I have with that is that
people are really quick to jump on that
bandwagon and all I would say is you
should be prepared to have that level of
scrutiny thrown back on yourself.
True.
Because my,
I mean how fucking long,
but everybody else's list B,
you know,
I mean that's the one thing that
happened,
like once you get into office,
would that list be the same?
Like if you knew,
like if I say Andy Stump,
do you swear to take the office of the
United States president and then to do
the whole thing hand on the Bible from
there on,
you've got to know that you have to keep
your fucking shit together a hundred
percent.
You can't lie.
Yeah,
I agree.
And like I said,
I'm not,
I'm just,
I wish people would take that level of
accountability on themselves as well
too.
I think the country would be a better
place if people acted as if there was an
organization ready to write down a list
of their deficiencies at any given time.
I think you're totally right.
I think you're totally right,
but I think that what we're seeing is
for the first time,
like a president that is showing why we
have a real flaw with this idea of one
person being chief
dog.
I think he scared the piss out of people
and usually a topic swings back around
to like nuclear weapons or nuclear war
and like,
can this one guy really go and just hit
the button while also the real problem?
Ms Dot Muniz.is
very strategic.
I mean he's thinking.
He thought about reelection.
He filed for reelection almost
immediately or did he really?
Yeah,
there's a strategy for that too.
Meaning that any like,
I forget exactly what the strategy is,
but it's in terms of how people are
addressing him and how people are
talking against him because they'll.
They would be running for president.
They would also be if they're running
for president because he is a
presidential candidate.
There's like certain rules to behavior
and this is a very calculated.
Yeah,
chest movement.
It's a very.
It's a big chess move,
so this is what disturbs me the most
about North Korea because there's one
way to ensure that people want to keep
the same president and that that way is
wore it like once you are in a war,
say if we are three plus years in,
he's campaigning for president again and
it escalates with North Korea.
That propaganda escalates the lies the
bullshit and who knows,
who knows what the fuck happens and then
all of a sudden there's actual military
action that is going to ensure a
reelection,
I think or would I could see that or it
would flip everybody against him.
I could see a swing in both ways.
It could.
It depends on.
It depends on how scared people aren't.
Depends on if we get attacked.
If we get attacked,
I guarantee you he wins again because
nobody's going to want Bernie to in
this.
I'm going to go there and I'm going to
promise them equality.
I think if we got attacked by North
Korea,
yeah,
his escalation might be nucular in and
level and then it's.
We're all.
We're glowing in the dark.
If that shit works,
if this stuff works,
I don't know.
That's I tell you what,
you want to talk about a war that I
would want.
No part of.
North Korea.
Oh,
Daddy.
Yeah.
No,
thank you.
Rugged terrain controlled environments.
No,
thank you very much.
And they got some big old army's just
call on Elon Musk and sending the
drones.
Those Boston dynamic drones that could
do backflips get those fucking new
robots that they have to tell you what.
Right now the drones are carrying the
lion's share.
Are they?
Um,
yeah.
I don't know if people realize how much.
I mean it's,
they are carrying probably the lion
share of the kinetic activity throughout
the globe.
I mean they're,
they're doing as as they can with that
really know like how much drone activity
things going on that we don't know about
that we don't know about.
I have absolutely no idea but about that
would have to imagine that it is.
I would have to imagine that it's
substantial.
It's,
it's less risk from a risk to force
perspective because if you're looking at
it as you're the person who has the
drone,
it's less risk because you're not
putting a physical human being at risk
or launching a forest or an asset or a
helicopter that could fill in the blank
go wrong.
And then on the other side of that risk
though is that how are you really sure
the person that you're going after is
there.
Are you really sure that they're alone?
Are you really sure that you can action
this target in a way that's not going to
have collateral damage?
So there's two different tides of,
uh,
two different sides of the risk and I
think that right now at the American
populace would probably rather not see
flag draped coffins and just assume that
business is being taken care of.
So disturbing the idea of that getting
turned around on us.
And even more disturbing,
I think about it from that perspective
of somebody launched a Tomahawk missile
into downtown or not Tom Hall because
they're not on fire.
How far they go or j dot m or fill in
the blank in an La.
China flies a drone over or whatever.
North Korea flies a drone over and they
just juiced the US bank building in
downtown La.
How would we respond to that?
It's,
I mean,
I sit back and I freaked.
I kick my.
I just do mental judo in my head trying
to figure out what the Hell I did with
almost 20 years of my life and did it
actually do anything important and where
whereas everything going and like,
what the fuck was I doing for so long it
I struggled with it quite often.
How so?
I worry that.
So my biggest fear is that my children
would have to finish something that I
started,
but I also think that the success that
we had as a military drove the creation
of the enemy that we're fighting.
We took an organization that was largely
geographically co located and we were so
effective at finding them when they met
in groups of people that they splintered
and they spread apart,
which is,
you know why now it's more effective to
fly a drone over as an example.
Yemen,
I have no idea if that's happening,
but it's easier to have a drone over
Yemen than an aircraft carrier sitting
off the coast to do something about it.
So now we have a an enemy that was in a
couple of countries that's now in 30,
40,
50,
60,
70 countries and you can't really cut
the head off of that snake anymore.
And I look at did I do anything that
made my kids lives safer to do anything
too major daughter's life safer?
And I would say in the moment I feel I
feel like I had a difference in the
moment,
but I think in the grand scale of thing,
looking for things,
looking back that everything that I was
involved with,
I almost think that the tide is washed
it away and it's very frustrating
because I was.
I was only able to impact the
battlespace that I was physically in.
Right.
But imagine if you weren't there.
Well,
so and so and I imagine for others like
you weren't there.
The role that we played I think is
absolutely essential and looking back on
my career,
I think the role of what I did was to
create space and a barrier and a
boundary so people in this country can
be complete cunts and complain about
their rights and freedoms and oppression
and inequality,
all that stuff.
We have to create an environment where
those things can thrive and flourish and
be in a melting pot and figure out who
we are so we have to have that role,
but I just would frustrates me is seeing
what's going on in the country or in
seeing what's going on in the world and
thinking that I was involved in
something that was important,
but just realizing all I was was a point
in time is sticking my finger in the dam
that had 15 different water spouts
coming out of it.
So you didn't have a total solution,
but you certainly mitigated the problem.
We admitted a good problem,
only been in that moment in time and if
you weren't there to mitigate it in that
moment in time,
who knows how much it could have
escalated,
who knows,
but who knows if the time that I was
there mitigated the problem or the
football down the road and made it worse
and it's a problem that your kids are
mine are going to have to solve in the
future and I don't know those answers.
I don't.
I really.
I was 100 percent and still am 100
percent committed and very proud of the
actions that I took because at the end
of the day I made the decisions of my
actions.
I got to where I'm super lucky and
privileged where the American flag on my
uniform and I got to be the example and
the beacon of what I wanted the US to
be.
Every time that I got.
I mean I've encountered people didn't
know what the US was.
They'd never seen an American before and
how I acted was the u s to them.
So I think it was important and I'm
proud of those things,
but I just hope at the end of the day I
made a difference,
you know,
instead of trying to run up hill on a
soft sand berm and go nowhere.
Isn't that part of the problem with
military action too?
So you don't really know what the result
is ultimately going to be.
I mean,
everybody hopes in urine,
you know,
there's two sides,
right?
Correct.
They both hope that they win.
You don't really know what the fuck the
results can be and it's not a difference
in commitment on either one of those
sides.
People need to understand that as well
too.
It's not that I was more committed than
the people that we were engaging with in
with on a battlefield or anywhere in the
world.
It's a difference of opinion.
They believe what they believe just as
much as you and I believe what we
believe,
whatever the issue may be and who.
I don't know.
I'm not,
I'm not.
I can't say who's right.
You know,
I just did the best that I could do to
try to fight for what it is that I
believed in and I don't know,
it's tough at the end of the day to sit
back and think and be like,
God damn it.
What I do with my time.
Yeah.
It is a,
it's a daunting feeling to think that
there's never going to be a time where
we really are a peace worldwide.
I don't think we ever will be,
but I also don't think we ever have
been.
No,
I don't think we ever have been either.
But do you think we ever would be.
We were to,
were attacked.
You remember that last,
uh,
one of the Reagan's speeches were talked
about,
uh,
how quickly we would put our differences
aside if we were attacked by an alien
force from another world.
I think it would change some things
instead of
being local in San Diego and having or
an la the flags up if the entire world
was challenged with something that we
had to come together with.
I bet you that would be that feeling and
it would cross probably any and all
borders.
The UFO dorks though they grabbed that.
They thought,
oh my God,
this is proof proof.
Reagan knows Reagan knows,
but I,
I do feel like almost like what we were
talking about with nine slash 11,
right?
Like that being attacked made people
more,
more acceptable to each other more.
They felt more connected to each other.
You know,
let people in front of you on the
highway,
that kind of shit.
Hey,
when you have your mortality in your
life thrown in front of you,
I think he creates a pallet that is much
easier to appreciate the little things
and I don't think most people experience
that.
Is it weird for you when you spend so
much time in combat and spend so much
time overseas to come back and see all
these people that really don't know the
darkest side of the world currently mean
people have a view of what the earth is
in 2017 and if you live in San Francisco
and all you do is,
you know,
you work at Silicon Valley and hanging
out in the tech industry,
you think that this is the world in 2017
because this is your world.
This is zero insulated look like we were
talking about.
You don't really know the world until
you go into the forest.
You go into the forest,
you go,
oh,
this is the world to the back.
Country is still.
The world is just,
Oh,
this is what it's really like when we
don't have these artificial structures
and when you spent so much time in
combat and you come over and you see all
these people that are fighting over
these insignificant things and
squabbling about the use of the
preferred gender pronouns and all this
crazy shit that people find significant
today.
It is very challenging for me to listen
to the things that people feel are
important in the lack of.
I would say it's the lack of what I
would consider to be perspective and
it's funny if you do say I did 17 years
in the military.
Let's say a guy does 20 years,
you actually don't spend that much time
in combat.
Let's say you do a six month deployment,
you're working even at every night of
that six month deployment,
which isn't gonna be the case,
so every other night,
so now you're working 90 days of that
time.
You might spend 30 minutes in combat in
those 90 days,
multiply that by five,
six,
seven,
eight,
nine deployments in 20 years.
That's your total time combined in an
actual combat environment.
Not a theater of war,
but a combat environment where you're
directly involved in it,
but that time period for me changes the
way that I view the world.
Not only that time period,
but just the time spent in those
countries in seeing what's the standard
in other countries and what's the
standard here and when I hear,
and again I think we talked about
before,
I,
you know,
people talk about inequality or
oppression here in this country and I'll
be the first to admit that there's
inequality which is fun because there's
inequality everywhere.
But let's take a little bit of
perspective here.
If you are fortunate enough to wake up
in the United States of America,
the water that you sit down on the
toilet over to take a shit is cleaner
than most of the water people on Earth
are going to have access to.
You go to starbucks and you may pay more
per ounce for a cup of coffee,
for the fluid.
Then you do the gas coming out of your
pump going into your car that exceeds
the annual income of most people on the
face of the planet.
Are you living in a first world country
where instead of spending your time
trying to find that water,
you get to spend your time sleeping in
line in front of the apple store,
waiting for the new iphone to come out,
and then you have the balls to bitch
about how bad you have it.
That to me is a super tough pill to
swallow because you want to talk about
oppression and suppression of freedom of
speech.
I've seen street corners.
They're still red from lopping dudes
heads off because they voiced opinion
that was counter to the opinion of the
day.
That will change your perspective on
whether or not words hurt you and you
know,
what rights actually mean.
And you'll be like,
you know what?
What you say is actually really
offended.
You know,
it's offensive to me,
but I'm glad we live in a place where
you can say those things.
Moving on with my day.
How much does that changed your
perspective on human beings when you're
in those environments?
Uh,
what you think a human being actually
is?
I have an inherent distrust of most of
most human beings.
If I'm being totally honest,
I don't want to say that I'm antisocial.
My wife would say that she probably
wishes that I was more social,
but I just kind of just take a step back
and just try to avoid interactions with
just about everybody that I encountered.
While I would imagine that your spectrum
is so much wider than the average person
spectrum in terms of the atrocities that
people are capable of committing,
you've seen mean most of the time,
right?
You're operating in this one small
little sort of village in the spectrum
that most people are that are in
civilization.
You're in this one little tiny area,
but you've seen the full thing.
I mean,
you've seen horrible,
horrible shit.
Yeah.
That's got to mean there's no way that
wouldn't have some sort of no effect on
how you would approach people.
Like I said,
I have to.
It puts me in a position where I almost
have to sit back and I have to bite my
tongue because I don't share the
opinions that most people share because
if the military service that I have gave
me anything,
I think it gave me a different
perspective on the world and it's only
because I traveled to more of it than I
think most people get the chance to do
and I got to see more of it.
Not Through my phone and my instagram
screen,
but through my own eyes and that all it
really did is just changed my value
perspective of life,
of the little things.
Uh,
it,
it just,
it makes it,
it makes it hard sometimes.
It was there like a single or any
significant moments that you can recall
that shifted the way you
think about things.
In what perspective?
Just knowing the people capable of
horrible shit.
I think the times they got me the most
on that is where you would see adults
talking kids into becoming suicide
bombers.
Just the evil,
evil motherfucker who instead of having
the stones to come and face you will go
and try to talk some innocent kid and
strapping on a suicide vest or a suicide
belt and walk into a crowd and clack it
off.
I mean that.
That is,
to me the most insidious type of evil
because
they're not willing to actually engage
in themselves.
They want to prey on victims and I,
that's if I have anything I hate in the
world,
is that it's the victimization of
innocent people watching that and seeing
that that forever throws a different
shade on your glasses for sure.
Just knowing that people are capable of
doing it.
I am.
I am not surprised by any behooven human
behavior that I see,
which doesn't necessarily make me any
more prepared,
but I also probably in the back of my
head have a different thought process
when I enter into situations.
It's not like,
oh,
hey,
everything's going to be great.
Like I get my plan to kill everybody
first and then I relax a little bit.
Yeah.
Who,
who,
uh,
who said that?
Tim Kennedy.
Yeah.
Have have a plan to kill everybody in
the room,
but.
And that's the thing,
and it was it mcmaster's.
It might've been,
yeah,
it would be a be friendly,
be courteous,
but have a plan to kill everybody in the
room and if you're around human behavior
that would put people on their heels
and turn them white in the face long
enough,
that is going to become your default
position.
Whether or not you want it to be or not.
I'm not in a violent person.
I'm probably the last person you could
draw into violence,
but I'm not also surprised by violence
and I'll react to it accordingly if I
encounter it because it doesn't surprise
me.
Right.
So yeah,
I would just think that.
I mean,
I've just got to believe that a person
like you that has experienced that
insane level of cruelty and evil,
that your view of the world,
that you would be really intolerant to
people that do have this sort of narrow
minded view of what the United States is
and our,
our role in the world and how the rest
of the world views us and who the rest
of the world is and I'm incredibly
appreciative that they live in
place that provides an environment for
them that they can have that narrow
minded view.
I'd rather them be that than have that
place not exist.
You can be the biggest asshole you want
to and I'm going to sit back and be
grateful that,
that place on earth
for you to be like that.
You know,
and I understand the idea of the non
interventionist foreign policy that if
you know,
we'd never were in these places,
we would never have issues and I just,
just 100 percent false.
This is just another way to look at
yourself as a victim.
Is it?
I think so.
In my opinion.
Yes you can.
It's easier to blow,
well if we didn't do this
then they wouldn't do that.
No.
How about real evil does exist and there
are always going to be people who want
to do something about that.
Regardless.
If you're a pacifist,
you're a Catholic,
fill in the blank,
you will have your access somewhere on
earth and they're coming for you.
Well,
it's also those parts of the world in
particular are so ancient and people
have been living there for so long.
I believe that they have the echoes of
the past and them so deeply embedded in
their culture and their actions.
I mean you're,
you're talking about parts of the world
that really.
They've had people living there for
five,
6,000
years and the,
the ancient barbaric instincts of those
people just have got to be those.
Those echoes have got to be sort of
reverberating through those cultures.
Some of them are very interesting.
I think one of the biggest difference
differences that I saw between Iraq and
Afghanistan and the United States and
you know a couple actually no def,
definitely those two countries in the
Middle East is that there's just a
different appreciation for life.
They,
there's less of a value of life because
I think they almost find or expect that
it's going to just end sooner.
It's very,
very different culturally and yeah,
I don't know.
I don't know if that oil in water will
mix or if ever can mix or we need to
have a third party that acts as
something in between that allows us to
gel or man,
I don't know,
it's.
I don't have a solution for it,
that's for sure.
And when you look at like how long there
has been conflict in the Middle East,
it almost seems like an insurmountable
issue.
There's been conflict with man since the
history of man,
right?
I mean,
and so I say I think we're in a forever
war right now.
We probably were in a forever war before
it just.
I think the face of warfare has changed
along the way and the access to
information about that has drastically
increased,
was changes people's perception about
it,
right.
Like we're always involved in some sort
of a conflict,
but we think of as a war is when we have
our troops over there are citizens over
there and listed.
Then we said,
okay,
well now we're actually at war.
Yeah.
And this war especially what's going on
in Afghanistan.
It's been going on for so long,
you know,
coming up on 17 years.
That's so crazy.
Yup.
And what's happening over there?
I mean,
what are we accomplishing?
A.
I don't have a complete answer for that
in my opinion.
I would say that they are trying to do
their best to stabilize that region of
the world by supporting the government
would be my best.
Chuck just murderous,
murderous in the sense of not being able
to describe it properly,
explanation of what's going on.
Man and Iraq is the same way.
Don't think for a second that we ever
had boots off of the ground in Iraq.
It's just talked about a lot less.
We still have a presence there that
people don't understand.
We still have a presence in Korea.
We still have a presence in Europe.
That's how long you have to stay if
you're willing to invest the time for
stabilization,
which the US military I would argue is
not very good at those types of
operations.
You can do it,
but you could also probably do open
heart surgery with a shovel to it
doesn't necessarily mean it's going to
be the cleanest.
So you should probably have a military
and then you should probably have some
sort of fix up crew.
Yeah.
Uh,
I mean I think they try to do that with
all the,
uh,
non government organizations or other
government organizations.
I just think it's really difficult.
And in you know,
in the Middle East,
like you said,
you're talking about people who have
been there for five and 6,000
years,
this 17 years that we've had a presence
there and they're like,
talk to me later sun when it's at 1700.
I don't know how the solution for it at
all.
I mean,
it's,
these are the things I think about.
The solution might be moved to a town of
22,000
people here.
God Damn Right.
It is.
It might be just disengage.
I do better somebody enjoy your time.
I do better with it there,
but I mean it's,
I'd spend an inordinate time amount of
time thinking about that stuff,
trying to make sense of that,
that amount of time in my life.
How could you not?
It's 20 years of your existence on
planet earth almost.
Damn,
that's a lot of time.
Nope.
And it probably would have been more if
you didn't get shot.
Well actually nursed it out for eight
more years after I got shot.
I did another deployment after I got
shot,
which was probably not the best call,
uh,
because I had some residual effects from
it and almost gotten to the point where
it's like,
okay,
I need to call a helicopter in and come
pick me up because I'm,
I'm inhibiting the other people that I
was with.
Wow.
I didn't want to be done.
I mean I got shot.
I got shot in 2005,
so I was 27 super,
super young in comparison to where I am
now at a place I wanted to be operating
at a level that I wanted to be operating
at and then,
you know,
I'm in an Indycar,
do an 800 around the track and it's
like,
oops,
just put it in reverse by accident.
There goes the tranny down on the track
and just to try to rebuild that.
And it took awhile.
But yeah,
I ended up strapped it on one more time
and then at the end of that it was like,
okay,
I can't do it.
Why did you want to go back?
Like,
what was what.
I mean this was something that Sebastian
younger talked about a lot in tribe.
I think for me it was more I needed to.
I needed to do it for myself.
Uh,
when I got shot,
it scared the shit out of me.
You know,
there's a lot of,
there's a lot of times in the movies,
there's this just blind heroism and it
doesn't matter what's going on and
you're like,
oh,
I'm just going to run through the hail
of bullets.
Well,
I was flat on my back and but when the
round hit me in my hip and by the time I
had hit the ground,
my first thought in my head was that my
femur had just been shattered and I was
going to bleed to death in the space of
your hamstring and your quality,
you can fit your entire blood volume
there like I'll be dead in about a
minute.
That's what I was thinking in my head
before I hit the ground.
And then what ended up happening that
night happened.
Eight people ended up getting wounded.
I was one of the least wounded people.
So they were flying people out on
helicopters.
I got put into a Bradley fighting
vehicle and taken to the Green Zone in
Iraq.
But it scared the crap out of me.
And not only did it scare the crap out
of me,
it absolutely crushed my confidence in
my ability to do my job,
which up until that point,
I thought that I was at the very least
competent and capable of doing my job
and I had everything was going great up
until that moment and then it and then
it didn't and I had nothing but
questions and avoid that I had to pull
myself out of and it was probably very
selfish in my desire to go back and my
desire to continue doing what I was
doing,
but I had to build myself back up to a
point where I thought I could operate
again.
And I remember very distinctly going
back to Afghanistan in 2010 in standing
outside the door,
getting ready to go into a door on a
house,
thinking in my head,
do you still have it?
And then going into the door and I,
I needed for myself to do that again
too.
I guess regained for me a sense of who I
was and to regain my confidence.
Wow.
What did,
what did you fear would happen?
If you didn't do that,
I feared that I wouldn't know who I was
because when I was younger,
I'll be the first to admit that I
believe I put too much weight into what
I did as opposed to who I was.
I had too much attached to being a seal.
It was,
and I,
I,
and I again,
in my opinion,
the problem that I see with people that
struggle when they get out of the
military is if they attach too much of
their identity to an occupation that
they've walked away from,
they really struggle most times.
Not Always,
but most times,
and those people can end up getting
themselves into some pretty bad
positions.
And when for guys who cut out from that
career,
when they go off the rails,
fuck me Nag,
go off the rails in a big way because we
have two speeds.
We have fifth gear and hold my beer.
That's the only two speeds that we have.
Yeah,
and I thought I had lost that and I,
I was at a point in my life where,
like I said,
I was where I wanted to be doing what I
was wanting to do.
I thought I was doing it right and I
mean it.
I thought I was going to die in 36 hours
after getting shot.
I got off the stairs of an airplane in
Virginia beach and my wife had my son in
a stroller and was pregnant with my
second,
my middle son.
It just was such a bizarre series of
events that happened so quickly and I
went from going so fast to nowhere,
to having nothing to do,
to not understanding why I couldn't
train my body to get back to where I was
because the only job I'd had in my adult
life other than working for my father,
I had too much.
I had too much invested in that
occupational title and I think one of
the best things that I was able to do in
my military career was to survive it and
get out and to move on.
That's one of the hardest things for
fighters as well.
It's a big thing with them and may
fighters boxers too.
They just don't know what to do when
it's over.
They have.
They become these incredible winners in
this one avenue and then once that's
done,
they rarely achieved that same kind of
success in anything else where they're
probably not thinking about anything
else when they're in the middle of
fighting,
which is very common with people in
military too,
right?
Because the job does require a very
focused,
myopic sense of drive.
This is what you need to do,
especially in the seal teams.
It's the team comes first,
team gear,
personal gear.
Then take care of yourself,
worried more about the person to your
left and to the right and then worry
about yourself,
you know,
consider the impacts of your actions and
your words on the people around you and
then on yourself.
So it's very.
It is very driven down into a laser like
focus,
but that's also required to survive and
thrive in those environments.
But if left unchecked,
you'll end up at the end of your career
not prepared for the next phase of your
life and say you do 20 years in the
military,
which is what you need to do to get a
retirement.
You joined when you're 18,
so hey,
you're 38.
Well,
the average lifespan of American is
what?
80,
85.
You got a lot of time left.
What are you going to do?
And if you haven't thought about it,
it's,
it's it.
As see guys who struggle.
I see guys and I struggled myself,
but I,
I think I,
I think I went through that struggle
while I was still in and I think that
struggle allow me to lift my chin up
just a little bit to look around and
start thinking about the future.
You're a bad motherfucker and just dump.
Let's wrap this up.
I don't know about that,
but let's wrap this up right there.
Cool.
Thanks brother.
Appreciate you man.
All Right,
ladies and gentlemen,
we'll be back tomorrow.
See Ya.