The joe rogan experience.
Oh fuck.
That's just gives me such anxiety
watching this.
How big is that wave?
Uh,
I dunno.
Probably 60 feet on the face.
This start damn son.
Oh,
what does that feel like right there
when it's over there's parts.
Cool.
Watch it.
I get air on the way down.
Oh my God.
See my board gets completely in the air
right there.
Oh,
do you are so high.
That is so high.
Wave is so giant.
It's like 40 feet above your head right
now.
Oh my God.
This gives me anxiety.
You know what's cool about surfing is in
those moments,
like there's very few things in the
world other than like,
I dunno,
I dunno how to relate that,
but I'm like that moment right there for
me,
it was like the pinnacle of like who I
am,
what I do best.
That moment,
that wave coming in at that,
at that minute in my life where I was in
a right square foot of the ocean,
when that wave came in,
that was the best.
That was one of the best days in history
at that surf spot.
Wow.
Um,
and I was there,
I was prepared,
I was healthy at the right board,
the right equipment,
the right energy level.
It wasn't sick.
I didn't have any,
you know,
everything was just lined up and the
waves are lined up and the swell was
lined up and the wind was lining up and
the tide is lined up and I was in the
perfect spot when that wave came in.
Do you watch the video all the time?
No,
but every time I do I remember all those
things because it seems so much so,
so much luck had to do with it.
It's just like a line in the stars
aligning and it almost seems like
something I'd want to watch every day.
Like brick get,
get the day going.
You know your first kiss from a girl.
That's what that is.
Wow.
That like mind blown.
Whoa,
this is,
this is like an important moment in my
life.
I need to like have this moment in time
frozen.
That's what that is right there.
And so I think as an adult you very
rarely have those moments left.
I mean I like a really like mind
expanding and exploding moments.
We were like,
Holy Shit,
this is life hundred percent life right
now.
And that's,
that's what I think we're all chasing.
You know what I mean?
Those people sitting in traffic outside
right now driving the freeway,
they're not having those moments.
Not right then.
That's a real problem.
Yeah.
It's a real problem with life is that
people aren't having enough of those
moments and when you're a 75 yards away
from that elc a few weeks ago and you
had an hour to,
to really think about what you're doing
and where you,
where in your life and you know how you
got to 75 yards away from this animal,
the whole year of practicing on the
target and all the millions of arrows
you shot and all the preparation that
is,
and then this thing stands up and time's
ticking and that moment is there for the
taking and it's so easy to fuck up and
it,
it all happens the way that you,
you hope to visualize it though.
Those moments don't happen very often,
man.
Anyway,
I got an email about the 10th,
the 12th of October from some lady at
snap fitness in Shawnee,
Kansas saying,
hey,
just so you know,
you were actually registered for my gym
and we are doing an October challenge.
Yeah.
Um,
so I think I should take
your off.
Currently you're in third place and then
what did you say?
I was at relieves me first place third.
At the time
I was like,
I can take you out,
but I'm in a pot.
I'm going to podcast challenged with my
friends,
Rogan,
sick Thompson,
Gaura and Bert Kreischer and go,
oh,
Bert Kreischer,
he's in sixth place in are legit.
Jim of people trying to work out for a
second.
You were like,
oh,
Bert Kreischer
I was so
excited.
[inaudible] love him.
She just knows yours.
Beak be Christ.
That's my all time
God.
Oh,
Bert Kreischer from that depth.
Like,
oh my God,
no.
The words be Christ on the leaderboard.
Great,
but this guy really needs it and he
really puts it out there.
Try it out and I piss,
I'm going to turn it.
I'm a white trash comes down like whoa
buddy.
Yeah.
Anybody.
Men from jail.
Oh yeah.
And there's an animated version of it.
Yeah.
So it started a flurry of animated try
it out guys.
And then people started to submit their
own takes these,
there's Tommy doing try it.
Yeah.
That's
a stupid,
oh,
I don't care how many,
I can't even fucking free food.
Free Range.
No Man.
Jail Man.
You want to come move in if Franklin
with you too,
man.
Free Reggie.
[inaudible] fuck me.
Piss.
Somebody beat me home.
Ya Know?
You see?
What did he say that or why did just a
little bit Jamie.
He goes,
um,
he goes pissed on me.
Piss.
Somebody beat me a home.
You know what's that?
What's that?
Homey.
I'm now what do you think he's saying?
Good question.
One more time.
Ready to go.
Lisa.
Kay.
Fuck me.
Piss on me.
Beat me home.
You know,
you see me?
My mom.
What does,
we'd have to go through that like the
Zapruder film.
Okay,
well
what do you,
what do you hear?
Like a man out,
it seemed like a word to me home now.
Ho Ho Ho man out.
Fuck me for some,
you'd beat me a home,
Ya know,
right heartland now.
Hello.
Hello Matt Ho a man out is one potential
in here that again,
maybe that's it.
Fuck me.
Piss.
Somebody beat me at home.
You know it could be anything.
Oh Man.
Now,
oh man.
Maybe it's another language.
Whole menu.
We were like working for the government
and we're trying to decipher like a
tape.
Like we have to find out where the
kidnappers being held home and now you
have to like strip the audio.
I hear a train in the distance,
right?
We'd be audio experts in a room
somewhere.
We've got it.
We've got whole man out.
Whole man out whole man.
Oh Man.
Out.
It could be or it could be.
I'm home.
I'm home here now because he gives out
his address.
He goes,
no,
one more time at 2195 and we cut it off.
We cut it out.
Beat me on me.
I know.
These can be anything I'm home,
homey on now.
So you felt calm while it was flipping?
Oh yeah.
I always,
well,
I've seen cars flip,
right?
I've seen it for years,
right.
And so I know it's possible.
So I get in there and I got turned
around at a race in 1998.
I was racing at Daytona and,
uh,
I got turned around and the car,
so I'm flipping for the first time in my
life and this car is like over 3000,
3000 pounds.
So it's,
it's,
but it flies up in the air.
Like it's paper,
man.
It's the craziest thing in the world.
It's so you're weightless,
you know,
and what it felt like to me cause so the
car rolled on its side and uh,
came down kind of on its side.
It felt like somebody rolled a prop wall
of grass up against the car.
You know what I'm saying?
When I was on my side and I could see
the ground,
I felt like I was right side up.
Because as you're flipping,
the force pushes you down in the seat so
you feel it turned ugly.
You feel gravity all the time.
Like you're,
you know,
as a cars flipping,
you're,
you're pushed into the seat so you feel
great,
you feel weight of yourself in the seat.
That never changes.
You never kind of come up out of the
scene like that,
you know?
And so it's like somebody wrote a prop
wall,
the grass up against the side of the car
and then against the roof and then
against that side,
and then this,
you know,
it kept doing that.
And I'm like,
it's just the weirdest feeling and you
feel completely safe.
You know,
you feel like,
you know,
nothing's going to harm me,
but this,
any,
you know,
just,
you,
one of the things we always talk about,
it's like,
get your hands,
uh,
owned to something because the spinning
makes your arms just go like this.
And if you watch a lot of old wrecks
from the sixties and seventies,
you'll see the guy's arms come flying
out the window and they're just kind of
flopping around.
They can't pull it.
Yeah.
It's spinning so fast,
you can't pull it in and,
uh,
your arms would go like that.
So as soon as you know you're going
upside down and he grabbed the bottom of
the steering wheel and Kinda,
you know,
watch.
But um,
I'll flip my pickup truck one time on
Christmas Day and I wasn't holding on
the steering wheel and my arm went out
the window,
you know,
for like a split second.
It banged around in the,
in the,
in the window seal and I was like,
man,
you know,
I got it back in and grabbed a hold of
the steering wheel with both my hands.
And so ever since then I've like,
you know,
now I know like anytime I'm in a crash
you got to have your hands a hold of
something.
Cause that's the one thing that you
can't control your,
you're strapped in with your seatbelt
and everything but your arms are and you
know,
can go anywhere.
And in that moment when the car's
rolling or barrel rolling or flipping
you,
it's so fast.
Like you can't,
your arms just go this way.
The craziest thing in the world.
That's the only fear I guess is that
your arm could get outside the window
and get crushed or something.
Cause you guys have had that happen.
I mean the discourse in this country has
completely collapsed and I love it.
Why do you love it though?
This course is cloud because my rights
are enough for discussion,
let alone a vote.
So whenever people sit down and have a
talk about my life and freedom,
it's going to end badly for me.
So if people can't talk to each other
about this,
maybe we'll go our separate ways and
live peacefully.
So you'd rather not talk about it and
just go peacefully.
Is that what you're saying?
Someone's political opinions and
preferences should have as much impact
in my life as their sexual preferences.
You want to fuck dudes,
you want to have a threesome?
I don't.
I care if you're my friend and that I'm
interested,
but it's not going to impact me and it
shouldn't impact me.
And same thing with,
oh you want more welfare?
Great.
Go live your life that way instead of it
becoming some shouting match on your
front door and exactly.
Yeah.
Instead of you and your buddies coming
up and scare the shit out of my kids.
Yeah.
I mean,
no one,
I mean very few people deserve that.
I was going to say no one,
but very few people deserve that.
Yeah.
So the disengaging from political
discourse as a strategy for just overall
civility,
but also worsening political discourse
on purpose to make it so that people
can't actually form coalitions and get
anything done.
But it is amazing how personal people
take other people's opinions on things.
Crazy.
It's like the people jet it,
you know what it is like when you're
dating and you think,
oh,
this,
this girl likes the same kind of music I
do.
So we're going to get along.
That is a very weak correlation.
And there's lots of people who are right
wing who are good people and there's
lots of people who are left wing,
who are good people and there's lots of
people who are right wing who are bad
people.
There's a very weak correlation between
this.
Uh,
it's a cultural signifier.
You probably came from the same culture
because people just take the culture of
what they grew up with.
But if you're going to just dismiss it,
it's higher schools of thought just
cause they vote differently from you is
as a personal level that's you're
missing out a lot of quality people.
So perhaps Erickson did before him,
I don't know.
Anyway,
you,
you take an automatic process and you
interrupted in the middle.
So like when you're shaking hands with
somebody that's such a familiar process
that when you start,
you're not thinking,
okay,
I'm going to grip this person's hand now
and I'm gonna move my hand up and down
with them a few times,
then I'll take my hand away.
What?
You just kind
of do it automatically and there's
something about interrupting that that
leaves people
really flummoxed and the world it,
cause they're really,
it really caught off guard.
Like if you imagine somebody comes up to
you in the street and says it's not half
past seven,
you know,
your reaction isn't to go,
yeah,
yeah.
I know it's 20 past nine.
Your reaction is to,
is a sort of,
you think like you've missed something,
like you're trying to make sense of it.
It's a strange
kind of,
puts you on the back foot.
And at that point if you to,
if you've got somebody who's fairly
suggestible and people coming up on
stage,
it's such an odd moment for them anyway.
They're naturally very suggestible that
a clear instruction to sleep or whatever
you want to give them tends to be taken
very deeply and very often than you'll
see.
I'll shake hands and I'll break the
pattern to the handshakes.
Well,
I'll often take their hand and lifted up
to their face and say sleep and show
them their hand like that and they just
sleep and well,
it's not sleep that it's a kind of,
um,
it looks like,
I mean,
they,
they'll do anything from eyes closed,
head drops down to just drop like a,
like a dead weight on the floor.
You know,
what I found is most interesting
actually,
it was,
um,
like applying this in slightly more
useful everyday situations was as a sort
of like a self defense technique.
I was walking,
uh,
between,
so I was like,
must have been like 20 or something.
And I was at a magic convention and I
was walking from one hotel to another
and I'm dressing like a three piece
velvet suit as this skinny British law.
I might as well have,
you know,
punched me in the throat,
tattooed across my face.
And this guy comes up and he's like,
uh,
he's drunk.
He's about three in the morning,
drunk,
aggressive is with his girlfriend,
clearly looking for a fight.
And uh,
he sort of,
he comes up to me and he says,
well,
what do you,
what do you fucking looking at when
you're looking at?
And because I had spoken about this,
how to deal with this sort of thing,
but it never found myself in this
situation.
I kind of had it all mentally rehearsed.
So I said to him,
I said,
the wall outside,
my house isn't four foot high.
And I guess there's an equivalent of
this with a sort of adrenaline dump.
I think it's called,
and uh,
in martial arts.
But there's,
uh,
it,
it just like he's got all this
adrenaline and then a thing like that
for me,
which is just out of context.
Like it makes sense.
I'm not like talking gibberish.
It makes sense,
but it's just out of context.
Right.
So now suddenly his thinking that I've
what?
I've missed something.
So now he,
he was hitting,
you went what?
And I said his girlfriend walked off and
I said,
the,
the wall outside,
my house isn't full for high.
I spent some time in Spain,
the walls that were very high,
but if you look at the ones here that
they're tiny,
then nothing.
And then he just sort of broke down.
He sort of went,
wow,
ha and uh,
start crying.
What you eat?
No,
it wasn't quite crying,
but it was just,
it was like all the adrenaline and
everything just,
just flooded out of him.
And he sat down and I ended up sitting
next to him on the,
uh,
like,
you know,
on the road side,
I'm asking him,
you know,
so what I was,
the plan was I was going to try and
stick his feet to the floor and I had
his whole plan.
He just kind of collapsed and sat down.
Yeah.
That was the,
cause I knew it'd be like,
this is highly suggestible state and
like either way,
the moment of aggression in past,
but I ended up,
ended up weirdly sitting with them,
asking him what had happened that
evening and his girlfriend did.
I think she'd bottled somebody or
something horrible had happened.
She said we'd got out with all this
aggression,
but it's a,
it's a good one,
isn't it?
If you just have like,
um,
it could be just a song lyric or just
some,
some weird kind of thing that you can
just go into it in those situations.
I mean,
if someone's running at you with a
knife,
it's a bit difficult,
but you just,
you,
you're kind of strangely taking control
of a situation.
Okay.