Oh,
Janis Joplin's,
when you got to move,
just watch both parts of that fucking
documentary about it.
The new studio,
when I set up the new studio,
I'm going to set up all these fucking
exchange.
One allowed above 19th street and
hoboken's who one go live.
Holla,
Holla.
You bitches every Christmas.
My brother's brother.
Oh Shit.
Merry Christmas.
James Collins one allowed above twelfth
street because the Irish controlled the
Italians in the forties.
That's how it was a pecking order and he
was the first one to make it out and it
just cleared the attack.
You gotTa Watch this document.
It's up to the.
It's on.
He had said I try to hbo all of me or
something like that.
And it's weird because I always grew up
hearing these fucked up stories about
him like that.
He was Kinda a little rough,
but bro,
he fucking love people like us.
Like he lived for that craziness.
He loved it.
Burt Reynolds just put out a book every
reading the excerpts that they had been
released and he went and he goes,
he bumped into Sinatra one night.
It's not just told him to go play cards
over at some bar that playing cards and
the guy dropped the dishes and the owner
was yelling at him and he sinatra call
the Anova and he goes,
how much,
how much you think your glasses because
I don't know,
maybe thirty cents,
and he goes,
give me $3,000,
$3,000
worth of classes.
And he called the bus boy.
He was young and he embarrassed and he
goes,
what's your name?
Hector.
Hector,
I want you to break every fucking class.
And he started breaking glasses.
Nobody knew what was going on.
And he goes,
if I ever come in here and Hector's not
here,
I'm gonna.
Tell all my friends not to come in here
and eat.
And Burt Reynolds got legos.
Where the fuck are you going?
He goes,
I already got my Sinatra Story.
He sit the fuck down like A.
Yeah,
he was supposed to be an incredible guy
like in that sense.
And then after he got down,
like that documentary really breaks it.
He went really down.
They did a world tour out of his pocket,
which is for kids.
He donated everything for kids.
His daughter said he never recovered
from Kennedy screwing them over.
Like he never recovered from that.
He just got to catch it.
It's pretty interesting,
man.
He's from hoboken,
which really,
when I heard that story about how the
Italians,
when you know it was definitely the
Muslims war crime.
Now 100 years ago,
those were the Italians.
One hundred years ago,
there was one of the fucking Chinese
people over cliff.
The fucking for the railroad with
dynamite.
Is that true?
Did you ever hear about that shit when
they built the railroad statement slash
question Chinese people like everybody.
Everybody's suffering this fuck.
The Chinese people who build the
railroads,
the railroads,
they essentially can play the first
finger.
Is it and whoever was it,
strap dynamite around.
They throw them over the phone.
I swear to God,
man.
Somebody your fucking say shit to you.
Like a lot of all these racist suffered.
You know it and walking on the railroad.
Yeah.
Like,
well fuck.
That's why when you go to Wyoming,
there's a Chinese restaurant and all
that shit.
You ever go to Wyoming?
You're like,
wow,
there's no Chinese fucking restaurant in
Cheyenne,
Wyoming,
and they're like,
oh,
because after they built the railroads,
they said,
Fuck Alicia,
stay.
Wow.
That's interesting.
I never really thought about that,
but there was.
Wasn't there.
A place we went to was a vancouver.
Then we went to.
We went to some museum that showed like
how all the Chinese immigrants wound up
in Vancouver.
I don't think it was a railroad or I
forget what it was,
but it's interesting when you have like
these pockets,
there's pockets of like certain parts of
Chinatown where those people just never
assimilated.
Like,
fuck it.
We just stay right here.
Everything's in Chinese.
The signs are all in.
Chinese were good.
They don't learn English.
They just stopped.
They decided we'll just make this China,
China West right here just for a couple
of blocks.
It wasn't there like some mayor or
something or there was some kind of guy
that that,
that.
That was from China that came over
there.
They invited everybody over there.
Everybody were into Vancouver.
Oh,
that's interesting.
I wonder,
I forget,
there was some story about that is I
wish I paid attention to the
capitalistic.
The oldest chinatown was in Cuba up to
sixties,
up to like 61 or [inaudible] 58.
One of the biggest China towns outside
of the China was Nevada Cube and the
fact that Fidel took over,
he never fucked with them.
He left those Chinese people alone,
so there's still a lot of Chinese people
in Cuba and they speak Spanish.
They speak Cuban.
If you go to 79th street and Broadway by
our friends,
we're friends office used to be right
there.
There's a place called la that it's a
Cuban Chinese played.
I said,
are there.
You get pork fried rice with a with a
pork chop and black beans.
It's fucking ridiculous.
Chinese people speaking Spanish.
What?
I was looking for that and they talked
about,
but the Chinese stopped.
Just to hear what that sounds like.
What's that sound?
What does it sound like?
Like really fast.
Let's say I say that will not hold.
Hold it mellowed out a little for
genome.
That's how you would say,
that's how I'd say they'd say that and
they talk really fast track to see a
Chinese person speaks Spanish will blow
your fucking mind,
will blow your mind.
So if you ever have a die even sent,
the opioid opiate ended up going and so
I was on Oprah and athletes talking
about how that.
That's weird restaurant.
If you go in there and high be prepared
to go into shock and when I was younger
they were more.
They were like,
I'm following Cina.
That's the Chinese bell.
That was a couple more like in where I
came from.
Western New York,
that jersey,
that's fucking crazy.
That's like a thing.
Like if you see a Chinese guy with an
English accent,
you'd go,
Whoa,
hey,
what's going on here?
You know like it doesn't.
It doesn't assimilate with that.
That might be the biggest one.
That's the biggest one.
Chinese person with a Cuban accent
speaking Spanish and shit.
Fast,
fast.
They just always like multitech.
They're like,
take that as a way of talking to you and
the rhythm of the Chinese tone,
but they put it into the Spanish.
How crazy is it that there's so many
different sounds that people make to,
to,
to talk,
like you hear those African people to
talking like clicks and they start like,
what?
Like they
just developed,
that's their style.
They figured out their style of making
noise and the each noise means a certain
thing and Cubans figured out this kind
of flight flowing almost dancing style
and Germans have this fucking hard,
which cuts,
you know,
everything's Fuck you touch,
and then the Chinese people that figured
out their own thing,
it's all totally different.
All of them different.
The Japanese have grunts.
Yeah.
They have their own thing.
I liked when I hear Portuguese,
this is what blows my mind when I watch
a fight and uh,
talking to the interpreter,
when I watch Portuguese,
I understand a few words just from being
Spanish.
I don't understand all of them.
I'm not gonna lie to you,
but then it was weird.
Like,
then you have all these countries
together,
but like when Sicilians 12 around me,
I know exactly what they're saying.
They can't pull the wool over that
island is half fucking Spanish.
They don't even know when a Sicilian
stroke.
I picked more words up.
You know what I'm saying?
So important.
You say a five word sentence.
I pick up one word and then I'll take it
from there.
My imagination.
But when Sicilians to or I could take
four to five words,
like I understand that it's closer to
Spanish.
So somewhere along the line I always
figured out we were connected some way.
There's some French words that I
understand that Spanish.
It's kind of weird,
like it's just,
I don't know if I could explain it that
right.
Well there's like the romance languages,
right?
Like Latin Spanish is a franchise,
There's are like what they call the
romance languages,
like old school,
European languages that have that sort
of flair to them.
There's like a beauty to a lot of those
older languages.
You know,
it's,
it's interesting just how different
parts of the country developed different
sounds for talking,
you know,
when you listen to people from the South
Pacific or,
or another.
Another weird one is Filipinos when here
Filipino.
She's like,
wow,
that's kind of a combination of stuff.
Like there's just like a combination of
sort of like an Asian but a Spanish.
There's a flow to it.
It's a weird thing.
Right.
And a lot of like,
a lot of Filipinos have traditionally
Spanish last names as well.
Was conquered by the Spanish.
Right.
It was like Spanish and Chinese right
there.
It's a combination of Spanish and
Chinese and they were all Catholic.
Yeah,
that's true.
Yeah.
Like manny Pacquiao,
super fucking religious time Catholic.
I read something recently about how
emojis are the,
it's the most advanced language that's
been created recently just because you
can pretty much cross,
you know,
I could talk to a Japanese person by
Emoji to some point and you know,
and if you think about it,
that's how cave men started.
So they might've been way more advanced
in their language and we would have been
just shitting on them the whole time.
Well cavemen didn't really do it in
pictures mean they made pictures on the
wall,
but we don't think that they were
communicating,
but they do that a hieroglyphics were
like a super advanced way of
communicating.
We just can't.
We don't quite get it.
You know,
there's no poop
Emoji type thing for that,
that it's more advanced like triangles
and eyeballs and stuff.
Right.
Is that what the languages it looks
like?
Yeah,
it's all different symbols,
you know,
it's different than.
I don't totally understand that,
but there's a lot of uh,
Egyptian language was lost.
A lot of,
a lot of the writing was lost in
something called the fire of Alexandria,
like when they burned Alexandria,
I guess they birth like a lot of,
like really cool shit.
They destroyed all the records.
Like it might've been like explanations
really built all that shit.
All of it got destroyed because it was
all on like I guess a paper or piracy,
which I don't think is really a paper.
I think it's like an animal skin thing,
like paper made with animal skins.
But yeah,
those fucking people,
man,
they drew on their walls.
They had like their history of their
creation and all this different shit and
it was all just written all these
different images.
You know,
they just wrote in images like we think
that you have to write in letters
because that's how we write.
We write in letters,
but if we'd never wrote in letters,
we only wrote an images.
I mean we would just develop a really
advanced system for communicating and
images.
Like when you look at someone's writing
and you don't understand it,
if you look at Portuguese or something
like that,
you don't understand what it means.
You can kind of just look at all the
little letters and everything are all
squished in together to try to make it
strange sound,
you know,
it doesn't really.
It doesn't click and register.
But then when you read something that
you absolutely know what it is,
like the thought and the idea
immediately enters into your head,
well you would weight be way more
universal if it was like images.
So it does make sense.
Yeah.
Like,
I mean if you think about it,
like look at the old Egyptian,
you know,
King type with the hand going up and one
going down and then you look at like our
emoji system where we have like that
one,
like hey felicia chick with their hand
to the sideways and we know exactly what
that means.
When a girl sends,
it's like,
hey,
whatever,
if you see the Egyptian,
that's kind of like the same exact shit.
I don't know what the fuck did that
mean?
Why did the Egyptians hold their hand?
That was it.
Just the walk.
The Egyptian music video that I'm
thinking of.
Maybe they never did.
They didn't.
What they did was pig Latin.
Break that down for me.
It's like you saying nay at the end of
everything and you take the first letter
away and then you like,
you wouldn't say Diaz.
You would say uh,
he as day,
right?
Yes.
His name.
Okay.
Yeah.
When I was a kicker on the ex,
you know,
I've heard that,
I don't even know how to say this.
The Spanish one,
when you're Cuban and they have a peg
leg and my mom used to talk to them in
Spanish.
This form of communication was other
people in the room.
She didn't want people to know what she
was saying to me.
Oh,
it was like she thought she thought she
thought same fucking thing to do
something.
I forgot what fuck fucking was.
Cuban is a very interesting Spanish
cause it's almost like,
like drums are playing,
you know,
when,
when to queue and people start going
back and forth and back and forth.
It's a,
it's like it's got a rhythmic quality to
it out loud to a Cuban food.
It gets,
the conversation gets louder and louder
and louder and you actually think
there's an argument going on,
but there's really not any fun at all.
It's just two people who are so
passionate about this subject.
They're talking about I eat baseball.
Yeah.
You know,
when you get them going,
don't start that fucking argument.
Well,
what was the documentary there?
Saw where they went to Cuba and they
were watching these guys pay to argue.
They would pay to uh,
discuss like sports,
like they'd pay to,
to like to argue.
They would go to this one area and they
would get together with other guys who
want to argue about sports and then
they're actually like,
they had like a ticket and they would go
in there and argue about like soccer,
baseball,
10 years.
Really?
No baseball.
Their arguments are a beautiful
arguments.
That thing I used to do years ago where
I'd yell and then walk away.
Right,
right.
That's cute.
But that means the conversation's over.
Whatever you got to say.
I don't meet the head because you're
wrong.
This,
that's what that means.
That's at Bali.
Let them argue all day about dumb shit.
Music,
you know,
baseball.
It's interesting to them,
but they,
they detail is so much that you'll
actually,
they suck you in with the conversation.
You know,
like that fucking Yoel Romero dude who
more embodies Cuba and Cuban athletics
than that guy him like,
he's like,
when I think of like a Cuban athletes
like Cuban super athletes.
You think Yoel Romero,
right?
Well,
the thing that is the most thing that he
has about being a Cuban is that he's 38
and you don't really know.
Oh,
you can't tell.
Nobody knows.
He's 38.
He could be 22 dogs,
could be sucking you in.
And nobody really knows.
We really have those birth certificates.
They went away.
You just pick the dates.
What do you want to be done?
You know,
he competed as a wrestler for a long
time.
So they know he's a,
at least a certain age.
I'm just teasing,
but I know it's always something with
the Cuban.
I'm going to run.
Mom died.
I told my auntie she was.
How old was your mom?
40 eight flopped.
She's been 48 for 10 fucking years.
You know,
because it's true.
You don't know dog never know.
These motherfuckers ages.
They won't tell you.
You know that last fight.
He fought.
Fucking great man.
You see the one before that where he
told people to not.
He was trying to say,
don't forget Jesus,
but they didn't get it because he's got
a thick,
thick Cuban accent.
The thickest.
So he goes,
don't forget Jesus,
don't forget Jesus.
So people thought he was saying no for
Gay Jesus.
Like there's no gay Jesus,
like Jesus isn't gay.
It could've been way worse though.
But she was saying was,
is
saying don't forget Jesus.
He was just saying,
you know,
I one,
don't forget.
You know,
I didn't go to the why here.
Why?
You know,
why they didn't go that way?
Why it not go that way?
Because I would have gone off on him
that he would have beat up right,
and Luke and how the one that would be
in that room that night.
I know how to motivate Cubans or with
religion,
that radicals,
you would just start talking about God,
I just call him about old goon got
metal,
God of Cuba and he'll wait a minute,
hold on.
This guy,
and he used the one that he used,
the metal worker.
He is the fucking built.
When you go on Youtube,
look for a gun.
He was always a big black guy.
Lives in the jungle and he only comes
out to you.
Only comes out when there's a problem.
So if I would've seen y'all remember
that day,
I would have said the whole Google and I
would have got his blood gone.
Like blood going,
shit dog.
I started doing that to end this civil
when I first met him and I remember one
day in the hallway he couldn't take his
eyes off me.
People talking to them.
They kept looking back,
fuck the sand because it's big in
Brasilia Brasilia.
So I would've started saying,
Oh yeah,
oh yeah,
Augie and I would have started saying
who my mother is,
Eagle Eye,
some DC,
my golden eat that met that your toilet.
Get a guy that's the marrow.
Look it up.
Look like you know all black muscular
Cuban dudes that looked like that.
You fire them up,
tell them their own lunch and they go,
shit,
I'll get you fired up churches before in
Cuba.
It was this guy,
this guy,
right?
So he,
he.
So there's like a series of black porn
film guys,
shirtless six pack covered in oil.
This is the God is Christ.
This is side of the jungle and he like
is in charge of machinery.
When you,
when machinery goes bad and shit like
that,
you have to pray to him.
He has all the weapons of metal.
He just shows up in metal and starts.
He has a metal,
acts metal,
fucking everything that's.
So that's what I would have busted them
with that I would've just,
I would've gotten through his head with
a gun and hate that.
That takes over Jesus and Cuba.
That's what you were brought up on.
You heard that growing up,
so even if you converted to Christianity
later on,
that will still get under your fucking
skin,
like rattle your cage and shit profiled
the study saying that shit.
Everybody out of their rang John
McCarthy.
It would have been an episode of curly
and the little rascals when they fought
that little rascal.
Three students currently to wrestle for
a benefit,
but the problem was when whenever curly
smelled wild license,
she went fucking nuts.
So he's on the bottom of the pile of
guys beating them and all of a sudden
what mo comes over and makes them sniff
the fucking thing.
Curly pushes him off.
And what is it called?
Wild Wild Heisler.
Like some fucking something you know
this is like in the forties it was made
and all of a sudden you flashback and
you just see curly everybody.
People coming out and then he gets a
hold of the belt and he starts clocking
people with the bell from the wild
licensed and they flip over the curly
hitting people with the Bow Boston.
They flip over to the middle of the ring
and they're all piled on top of each
other though not 18 people with that
fucking.
That's what I would have done.
The yellow that day he would have gotten
until the Orleans Bang.
Your head was big.
What's his name?
Goldberg.
I felt bad when that whole forget Jesus
thing went down.
It was so bad.
There was everybody's piling on them.
They all just assumed it was really bad
because you got to know the Cuban accent
to tease become wise.
It just,
that's how they do it in a thick accent
like that.
Like nobody,
nobody figured it out.
It was weird.
It was weird to watch.
There were all like,
he's,
you know,
he's making a statement against gay
people are like,
oh man.
I thought when I heard it,
I was like this mother because Africa,
but it's pro gay.
Right.
And the other fucking half a Cuba.
They'll take the shark content,
but didn't you understand what he was
saying?
Scene as you speak.
Spanish accent.
I didn't get it.
Wow.
I didn't,
you know,
I'm half deaf so I really didn't hear.
Oh,
okay.
What the fuck he was saying and that's
why you're already screaming.
Yeah,
I kind of heard about it after they had
already figured out what it was.
So I didn't.
But when I heard it I was like,
yeah,
that's what he's saying.
He's saying,
don't forget Jesus,
he's fucking Cuban.
It's like,
don't fuck does both for gang.
No far gang.
And you know,
that's him saying,
don't forget Jesus,
he fucking loves you.
Have beaten into the ground.
I love him.
I could tell the way he says you'll make
jokes about,
oh my God,
he loves you.
I can tell how he's excited.
The thing that they should do that the
UFC always.
Mrs.
just tape the best corners in the
business on George a Mazda and Yo Romero
and I hear it because the things they
say are ridiculous.
Ridiculous.
Proceeded in Spanish or Cuban Spanish
where they say,
well,
I was here in Georgia,
the vows trainer.
Same Methadone,
Methadone guy at the hustle,
you know the guy at the top.
So it's an open hand.
The bitch slap can't do that.
And the guys,
oh,
he met guy at docile.
So he's saying he wants to hurt his
hand.
That's Cuba needs most shit.
You can smack somebody.
But in our mind methylome guy,
if that's what fires you up the
hospital.
Oh yeah,
let's listen to what I remember a bit.
Slap is a bitch.
Slap and Cuban.
That's my password.
Oh Man.
He was saying young you don't know.
Have an airplane.
That means hit him
with one of these things that come
across the head like a fucking wild
punch as a phone.
And I will talk to you a Cuban one time
they were interviewing Stevenson in like
the seventies and they go stevens.
And what happened?
Get White.
And the guy's like,
you know,
trying to.
And Stevenson said it and I almost died.
It was a little kid,
man.
I hit them with a plane that's they're
called compile our young.
But a great language.
Know it has so many different meanings.
And the truth of the matter is,
it's such a funny language because they
say shit like one time.
One of the nicest thing you've ever said
to me that you were stuck in an airport
and all of a sudden you heard this party
going on at seven in the morning and
people were delayed and you looked over
when they were Cubans and they were
like,
I got you that day.
That's when I really got you.
I got you.
It's your culture a little,
you know.
Well,
I remember.
I remember that day very well.
It was.
People were,
they were having fun,
man.
They were speaking Spanish with clearly
Cuban accents.
They were dancing.
They were,
they would have.
The little girl was dancing with the
father was dancing and they were playing
music out of their phone.
I was like,
look at these fucking people.
Don't give a fuck who you just,
you're having a good time.
They're just here having a good time.
It's beautiful.
So you know,
the one thing that I don't know too much
about politics and I don't know too much
about like the embargo and how it all
went down.
I know very little of it honestly,
but what I do know is there's something
strange about a culture like Cuba that's
kind of existed outside of the influence
of the United States.
Purely,
you know what I mean?
Obviously we're only 90 miles away,
but since we're.
There was an embargo and there's all
this bullshit that was going on back and
forth between the two countries.
They kind of existed in their own space
and when you see it like in video and
you see like the cars,
all 19 fifties,
cars done up beautifully and people are
driving them around.
They put like diesel engines in some of
them and shit.
They're all like self sustaining and you
look at these people and you see the,
the flowing style of their language and
how they live and it's all right there.
It's fucking 90 miles from from Miami.
He just nothing,
you know,
if you could drive than a car will take
you an hour and a half.
It's closer than San Diego and that's a
totally different world.
Totally different world that essentially
existed with very little us influence
other than the fact that we're close by
and you know,
they have to deal with us,
but other than that,
I mean they're doing their own thing
down there and they athletes,
Jesus fucking Christ.
How many countries that are that small
produce,
the kind of athletes that Cuba has.
Just think about how many baseball
players have defected and become like
major league baseball players.
How many boxers have defected and become
world champions?
Like there's a lot of like super high
level boxers had come over there from
their judo guys.
Guys like Hector Lombard,
you know,
I mean that kind of that caliber of
athlete like Jesus Christ.
A lot of them come from Juba.
He did Hector Lombard and Romero
both what you would call what the fuck
athletes,
you know,
you look at both of them,
you go,
what the fuck?
And I'm thinking,
what did they lift?
And Cuba.
They say two eggs a fucking year in
Cuba.
What?
The protein source.
They got no juice in Cuba.
How do you get that?
Fucking big.
And I've seen,
listen,
when I went home I went to,
I went with my wife and the baby in New
York and one day I said,
listen,
before we go into the city and Shit,
let me take you to my neighbor.
I took him to the actual park.
I used to play,
why you see some crazy shit.
And I sat across the street from
Columbine,
bows and arrows,
has the guy that shot the guy seven
times and self defense and all that shit
and got away with it and they took away
his pension and I'm just staring at the
house or something.
Like I remember being out here when the
FBI had that house surrounded and they
fucking found patty hearst is machines
on in that house,
mine a dog.
And he was like,
that's how deep this guy who was in my
hometown,
and I'm going through like going through
the,
uh,
we were kids,
we had to do the attic and we will find
the money in the attic door.
Hundreds and twenties and 50,
wherever had the house before that had
so much money.
They will use those installation.
Why?
It's like,
this is crazy,
I'm thinking about all these things,
but what all this has gone on.
It's me,
my wife and the baby and a guy and his
little girl and my daughter is kind of
mingled.
A little girl.
It's a beautiful day in.
He just leaves out and everything and
all of a sudden the guy's getting ready
to leave and I just said,
hey man,
how are you?
And I go and I want to say you live
around here just to see kids come to the
park.
You live around here man.
And he was like,
will you live around here?
And he goes,
me know,
and I go,
when he goes,
yeah.
I go,
how long have you been here?
Eight days.
Him and his daughter has been here eight
days.
They had gotten him like the day after
Thanksgiving,
so right away my fucking.
They offered me a Cuban cigarette,
which I smoked.
I smoked a cigarette with the guy just
talking to her just to feel where he was
coming and he was telling me how you're
basically poor unless you tell you have
to affect them to professionalism.
There's a word that you defect in the
country and now you work for yourself,
so he.
This guy was 48 and he was a bicycle guy
that two people sit in the back and
drive you around town.
So when he was making him one day he was
making a month.
That's why they let them effect so
quickly.
They let him out of the country because
you have to claim that first day.
You don't want to be a professional.
He was telling me all this shit.
I told him he had tears in my eyes and
he was telling me what I asked him what
a daily menu was like.
He said,
he came here and saw an Italian
sandwich.
He was coordinator,
so if they're being that Italian
sandwich when you.
I slept for 15 hours,
he goes,
that was tremendous and they've never
seen it.
How can a man be 48 years old?
I've never seen an Italian sandwich.
Are you fucking kidding me?
I went on.
What kind of menu did he say here in
Cuba?
You get I.
you've got a dozen eggs per month.
That's it for a family of five,
you know,
the,
the coffee,
you get like one pouch a month and you
have to read,
keep.
I bought him a cup of coffee.
He's like,
I tasted the coffee for the first time.
I like,
you have to keep going,
running the filter through that coffee
until there's really nothing left.
And then they do things to bring that
coffee back.
You spray windex or something,
something ridiculous like that.
You sit there and go.
Unbelievable what they do for coffee and
the liberties we have.
You know,
unfucking believable was alive.
It was because they,
the US stopped doing trade with them.
Right?
I mean that was a big part of it.
Here's the clinker have pigs.
Uh,
yeah,
they,
they got nothing.
You know,
and I've heard some people that they
went to Cuba,
they seen a Washington apples at the
hotels,
you know,
like the hotels are getting taken care
of for a tourism,
but everybody else lives like savages.
But here's where the compensation gets
past.
The guy's been here eight days.
He already had a fucking job,
already had a fucking job and seacaucus
go,
how's your English?
He goes,
just coming along.
But I worked with a bunch of blocks and
they don't speak English,
so what kind of confused,
but we make it work.
Oh my God.
He was fucking hilarious.
And Joe Rogan,
you know what I mean?
I turned around and went in my pocket
and I had $200 bills,
20 and I said,
do me a favor.
I got a sister in Cuba will mean the
world to me.
We took these two yard sticks and he
goes,
I can't do it.
He wouldn't take my money though.
I got a sister in Cuba.
Just got here.
I go by your daughter.
Something nice out of risk,
you know,
I don't know who you are.
He wouldn't take my house.
Wow.
I sat there.
I go,
wow.
That's pride.
He wouldn't take my money though and I
just,
you know,
people ask you for money all the time.
This guy really fucking needs it.
He wouldn't take it.
He still had Cuban cigarettes.
He had not smoking.
And that's why I said to him,
I go buy yourself a fucking cotton real
fucking cigarette.
How did he get in his sister,
his daughter,
his daughter affected with the mother
when she was three.
You know,
they leave and he stayed and started
another family.
That's it.
And you imagine one damage.
Mrs Rogan.
I got to go back and take care and I'll
get you back guys.
In three years.
Well,
a lot of boxers that happened to a.
What does that trainer a d as The guy
who works with Pedro Diaz was worse and
works with a lot of those other guys.
He,
he left and left the family back home.
They did a,
one of the boxing pieces,
the in depth boxing pieces on them,
you know,
he just realized that he just took to
fulfill his dream of being a
professional.
Boxing trainers.
Got Escape.
That's gotta be so hard,
man,
to leave your loved ones behind.
Just because you know,
like your life is fucked here.
I wonder if they're going to be able to
get back now.
Like what?
How does that happen now?
We opened up Cuba,
so they did the first flight at lax.
You guys saw that and they gave away a
little truck with cigars,
like it's a fucking party for these
people.
So when we like freely allowed to go to
Cuba,
now that's it.
You go with the Mrs.
Wow.
Right.
So dangerous American Airlines.
No,
no,
no.
Listen to what?
None of the time people will tell you
this of 10 people go,
listen bro.
The poverty breaks your heart.
The food kind of sucks,
but the people shit.
That's a different level of heart.
You sit there and go,
wow,
these people have nothing.
Why do they act this way?
I find it.
If I had what these people had,
I would not be a nice person at all.
They say those people.
Some Eric Meyers,
some comment from the store,
pull me aside.
Three weeks ago he goes,
hey man,
I want to give you a present.
I don't even know the comic.
I see them up there because I ain't
never mind.
He goes,
I went to Cuba and somebody robbed my
thing on the plane,
and a Cuban family took me in for four
days and fed me.
He goes to that like two pork chops.
He was telling me,
he goes,
I never felt that way.
He goes,
they're fucking beautiful people.
Everything sucks,
but the people take it to the next step.
Isn't that crazy though?
Because that's what everybody wants.
Everybody wants a community filled with
really nice people like that.
That's what everybody wants.
Everybody wants people to look out for
each other.
Warm,
friendly,
funny people.
Right?
That's it.
So what did.
I mean,
I don't want to say this because I don't
believe it,
but this communism work.
Does it make better people?
I mean if you're in this small
environment like that and you're forced
to work together because the United
States cuts,
cuts your country off and so I mean,
I don't know who they do trade with
mostly,
but that had to hurt them financially.
That hurt their quality of life in a big
way.
Right?
But I don't even think they know what
communism is.
Like the conversations I've had face to
face with my cousins at a where we go
for Pastrami sandwiches and we went to a
Cuban place while they were in la.
Communism didn't come up one time.
I don't have the heart to bring it up at
once.
Like I don't,
I don't want to know.
They know that other people can do
whatever they want and they know and I
went to.
What's the place we go to?
What's the fucking place you go to
drama.
And we were at the store on Qantas.
Qantas,
we went to canter's and they started
singing stairway to heaven.
I almost fucking died.
And they had to sneak the album around.
Like they still had albums.
We're talking about cds here.
They had vinyl,
you know,
and they were like,
you have no idea.
Like if you get caught with that vinyl,
you go to jail,
jail for vinyl,
we're going to jail here for having a
pound of coke.
You know what I'm saying?
I fucking album.
You go to jail,
they write you up,
you got to fucking go through some
process.
You might lose your job,
you know.
And they were singing stand where it
happened.
The way they sang it.
And fucking we hear it.
It's two different worlds,
man.
It was like they sang it with.
This was big too,
that you know,
you don't know the overwhelming feeling
when you come to America.
People don't know the
first time you learned a sentence to a
fucking song,
you know how big that is.
The first time we learned how to say
cool.
Oh cool.
And then just don't fuck it up.
You don't get good on you.
Okay,
cool.
Cool.
If you have no idea what it means to
you,
you know what I'm saying?
Like to really absorb this,
to be a fucking American is huge to an
of people.
We take this for granted every fucking
day.
I see these jerk offs walking around.
They have no fucking idea.
They have no idea until you talk to
somebody Cuban where you talked to
somebody from a country that they'd been
kind of fucked up,
you know.
And listen man,
when I live in boulder,
I got nothing to hide.
One of my best friends was a bad Muslim
dude.
And he wasn't radical and the reason why
I'm here is because he taught me how to
fucking read and write here where my
ged,
his name was.
Mohammed is a b,
but I'll never forget that motherfucker.
And I cracked jokes and all that shit.
But that was my boy when I lived in
boulder.
I used to bring me Hash.
I used to make me smoke reefer.
He's taught me how to smoke a fucking
cigarette with a tobacco,
you know,
these options,
whatever those people,
they fucking get the fuck in tobacco
with the weed.
The Hash.
I almost had a heart attack though.
He's over that blast and this fucking
thing like,
uh,
like it's uh,
and I used to talk to him like how is
it?
And he would tell me,
look at these fucking an appreciative
Americans.
He would say to me all the fucking time.
He came here and he was nine and the
first time he sang a Beatles song,
he almost fucking die.
Like the single whole Beatles Song,
you know,
like,
let it be something like that.
That was fucking amazing to him,
to,
to learn another language.
It was so overwhelming,
you know,
come from someplace where you had
gunfire every night.
Can you imagine living in Israel and
hearing machine gun every night?
That's how you fucking go to bed.
What I'm saying.
You come here and you move to studio
city and you're gluten free and shit.
My name's Shuki and he was from Israel.
He was kickboxing trainer,
Magiro Gym and uh,
he had a place in Tarzana for awhile.
That's where I met him and he's an
Israeli dude and him and his family,
his wife is Israeli as kids.
And uh,
I had dinner over his house once,
after we worked out and they brought out
Bongo drums,
dude.
And they start playing Bongo drums.
He's playing Bongo drums and his wife
starts dancing and his kid gets up and
starts dancing.
And I was like,
wow.
Like they're not even drunk dude.
There's no,
not even any alcohol with drinking
water.
They just start dancing,
like playing the drums and dancing.
And I go,
you guys are so happy,
like your soap.
He goes,
you know why he goes into Israel?
I'm doing a terrible accident and Israel
every day,
it could be death,
could be more war everyday,
so when it's not it's party party,
party and they're like eating this cool.
They had like Israeli food,
you know,
I don't,
I don't want to fuck up the names of the
fruit because there's quite a few years
ago,
but uh,
they were eating their traditional
Israeli food and playing the Bongo and
the,
and the lady was dancing in the,
the little kid,
he has a little son,
his son was dancing.
I was like,
wow.
Like I felt like I felt privileged that
they had showed me that,
you know,
like,
I don't,
I don't know anybody like you,
like here I'm hanging out with you.
Like this is their regular night for
them.
They do this shit all the time.
They come home,
he comes home from training people,
he bust out the Pongo drums,
the wife starts dancing and they started
having a little party.
Like that's just,
they're free.
They're like loose and his,
the way he described it,
he was like,
in Israel,
it's just so dangerous,
you know,
especially this was like a early two
thousands,
you know.
It's always dangerous over there though.
There's always something going on.
There's always,
they're always involved in conflict.
Mandatory military is mandatory.
You have to join the military for a
certain amount of years.
Everybody's military,
everybody's trained so it's a whole
country of like and he's like a deep
comradery because there's not that many
of them and there are a small country
surrounded by a lot of Arab countries
and then you add on top of that the
fucking party and you will have been at
the school of Israeli death squad fans.
Have you seen him at the?
Yes,
they are the people you called me and
said they were waiting for you.
I got stuck at that fucking movie
premiere Israelis.
When Israelis come to the store,
you better be fucking Karma.
Heavy duty to the store.
I've been up there a couple of Tuesdays
and three of them,
my man were from Israel.
The where's the fucking nuts?
You gotTa Love Them.
You gotTa love the comics from listening
to Rogan experience.
They started doing comedy.
I guess Israel's got a big comedy have
seen starting just starting and that
fucking want to be rough comics.
So the one kid's like,
I'm trying to do fucking Hitler jokes
and they throw and they throw me out to
all these places.
What is he talking about?
He's doing these dirty jokes was rarely
people throwing me out of restaurants
and shit.
He goes,
I'm coming to America to do heart.
These motherfuckers sitting there going,
oh no,
where's the flying Jew?
I'm coming to America and you Hitler
show.
He was pissed.
This kid he was doing,
he was serious.
He's like,
dog is a little rough.
He goes,
I'm update the little fucking Nazi
jokes.
Shit.
They throw me.
I actually had him on the Ice House
conduct here on the in town one gray.
What's his name?
Nice kid.
Nice.
There was two guys,
Shiny,
Nice Guy,
and then they came.
They both funds.
Female came on,
Israeli couple came.
They had just gotten married and their
honeymoon.
They came to the comedy store.
That was their honeymoon and they will
not grow.
They had the bucket with the booze.
They were young.
They came out,
pictures
hogs and we love it.
Yeah,
totally.
This kid was really.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that's right.
I'm telling you,
it's that might I left.
I was like,
this is real.
We're get them motherfuckers from Israel
to come over here to meet that squad and
do comedy and he was really funny and he
was really to stand up.
Did he do and killed?
He did kill Tony.
That's how I met him and then I invited
him to the ice house because like if,
if somebody does really good on killed
Tony on vitamin D,
the Friday show and so he.
He was great and he did a podcast and
everything.
What's his name I'm looking at.
There was a war.
You went back to Israel.
He's coming back because he sent me an
email.
I had a blast.
That's awesome.
You know,
we were getting a lot of Australian
people showing up at the store.
Yeah.
Australian people at the store and at
the Ice House too.
And they go on like these comedy tourist
vacations like Australia,
they get like a month off of work,
like they don't like we have,
we get,
if you're lucky,
if you have a really good company,
you get two weeks off,
right?
And they usually encourage you to not
take both those weeks.
Right?
They'll incentivize you.
Isn't that how it works normally?
But in Australia I think they get a
whole month off.
So I think these motherfuckers just go
on vacation.
Just they just go chill places.
You know,
Joe Rogan,
you get into comedy,
Jamie,
you,
you know,
whatever you do.
Well in whatever market you start and
you come to La and New York and you
succeed and they value,
you know,
the,
the whatever success you think it is.
Getting on a TV show or movies,
which is becoming a really funny comic
and working.
I never dreamed of what's going on now.
Every time I wake up my feet hit the
floor.
I thank God for what's going on.
Now.
I don't want to do movies.
I don't want to do TV.
I just want this movement to keep
growing.
This is not what I intended.
This is all new to me,
man.
This is all new to me and nobody asked
for this.
Most comics asked for success to be rich
and famous.
The success.
We're getting something different,
man.
What a fucking reaching the globe,
you know,
and it's fucking hate that.
And I'm not saying that,
you know?
Yeah.
It was big here.
These little podcasts are reaching the
fucking globe.
Joe Rowe,
was that his name?
You know when I'm at the store and
somebody comes up to me with some
additional different from Sweden or
Finland or wherever they're from,
that's not California and they're like,
we came out to the store to see you and
they do.
They do in these comedy fucking
vacations.
This is Ella and that you get in your
car and you drive home and you don't
even know where this is coming from.
Somebody last night some girl came from
like fucking Hong Kong and gave me a
president.
I put the fucking Hong Kong Gardens,
Ventura last night she was here for
Christmas.
She was like,
listen to you and fucking count.
That's you.
Never dreamt of that.
No,
and that's a way different type of
success,
man.
There's definitely something happening
because of these podcasts where you're
getting this connection with people.
Like I did shows in Australia and they
might as well have been in Irvine,
you know,
it's just a bunch of cool people.
They said different accents.
What's his name?
Tom Martin.
Hey.
Hey Jr Morton t a l a n a v e j are on
twitter.
All right.
I'll check that dude out.
Um,
but yeah,
no one would've ever thought this mean.
Brian,
this is like a.
we're almost at our sixth anniversary
right now.
This is our 600 versus actually it.
Or is it somewhere around now?
Somewhere in this area?
I would say I fell on us.
It was the 29th.
I remember it was Christmas Eve because
it was weird being doing it on Christmas
Eve.
I'm pretty sure it was,
it was totally this month whenever it
was.
It was definitely this month,
six years ago.
It's just fucking around on ustream.
Just answering questions,
you know,
Prehab Dashboard Board.
It's just I don't get time last night
and it's weird.
I do this,
that Hong Kong gone.
I'll tell you why I like this place.
I like the comedy scene.
That little ventura comedy scene.
I liked the a comedy scene because it
reminds me of comic,
that black comics.
Who that mean like she's a chick that I
was having two people fucking behind me
and me doing like three minutes.
It's good move and fuck you.
And I was just thinking about building.
This guy does calm me and caused coffee
with cause I'll be drinking coffee.
What if I did stand up in behind me?
There's a bed,
there's a chick getting plowed for three
minutes and I just do a bit and then we
added the bit.
That's it.
Yeah.
He could get them in the right position.
Where your head covers all the naughty
parts.
What do you think?
Yeah,
this is what I'm saying.
Like you just his,
you can see at the top of his ass as he
peaks like right above the back of your
head and that's it.
It's just the top of his ass like
panicky.
You can see that guy fucking a chick you
don't show it was declared as cable.
Hbo Can't you show like a guy's muffler
while you're doing stand up with a suit
and the Tuxedo buttholes on.
But you can show a.
But like he was always you what to the
actual hole.
You could show naked,
but yeah.
Yeah,
definitely naked man or woman's butt.
But you can't,
you can't show the whole during sex.
I mean they were just sitting there with
a button,
the air maybe,
but it was fucking with youtube,
all it takes is a few people complaining
and you can take him down like you can
get taken down for offensive shit or
they make it.
You Click on that thing that says you're
over 18.
You know,
like they could set it up like that.
Except that I saw somebody,
I think Christina [inaudible] Jetski a
post,
a natural childbirth video the other day
that was on youtube and that was one of
the most graphical discussing things.
Beautiful.
But that scene up there,
it's just a bunch of young guys at the
club broke that balls and now they have
open
mic seven nights a week.
So if the club on a broken that ball's
right,
these kids wouldn't have done that.
You know,
you have always been one of those guys
that a lot of clubs in the beginning,
you know,
you were too dirty for a lot of clubs.
That's why you worked with Dick already.
Fucking rumors because.
But it's so weird.
So when you represent them,
I'm one of those guys I didn't know I
had a fucking a seattle.
I'm the ground was the one where I
nurtured with ron reading those days
because that was a club and they
accepted crazy people.
But I,
but I couldn't.
Yeah,
all of us,
we were all down the difference.
When you're young,
you suck,
which I definitely did.
And you're not dirty.
At least you're not hurting anybody's
feelings.
You're not,
you're not offensive.
But if you're young and you suck and
you're dirty,
you're disgusting,
like you're going to just say the most
disgusting.
You're not going to know where the line
is,
so you're gonna fuck up.
Yeah,
but the first 18 months of my comic
career,
I was clean until I saw lenny Clark's
video and then I started going off a
little bit.
Really 18 months.
Yeah,
because everybody put this fear of God
into me,
man,
if I used to wear like a nerdy sued and
go up there and fucking joke about
whatever.
Well,
I've always said that you were the guy
that surprised me the most with how you
figured comedy out.
Like almost you,
you hit this point like when I first met
you and you were first doing the store.
You would be the funniest guy in the
world in that parking lot.
Like we would all hang out in the
parking lot and you would just be
killing everybody in the parking lot.
It was.
But then you get on stage and you would
stiffen up like you didn't.
You didn't have.
They didn't have the same relaxed way
that you know,
I couldn't convert when I was doing my
side of the stage to the stage.
It's funny how I had this conversation
yesterday,
but a guy named Charlie Barnett when I
watched Charlie Barnett,
I really,
really got it because he was the first
guy.
You know how people say,
well,
he's a one trick pony.
Okay,
but at least he brings himself to
Charlie Barnett was a standup comic at
Washington square park with Dave
Chappelle is his fucking apprentice.
I said,
fucking apprentice,
and then he the DC cab and they ended up
a couple of serious seasons of Miami
vice will beat up Don Johnson because he
was just crazy and look man,
whatever his name was,
but he transformed.
We wasn't a stage and person to the to
the screen,
which is I always looked at that's
really fucking hard and that's what I
always wanted to do.
Not The screen,
but just the stage,
how to get Joey Diaz is on the stage.
I didn't really want people to see the
real job ads.
I always was ashamed of jewelry vs so
people really want to see Joey Dsr.
I work clean,
but then I watched that thing again,
Atlantic Clark because I got on stage
because the dice,
but people will call you don't want to
be dirty because people won't give you a
work.
So I actually fell for that shit.
We all did.
And then I wore a suit like running
Clark because I'm.
But I couldn't sell a joke in the suit.
Even if I fucking wanted,
I couldn't sell them a suit.
That's where eventually I lost the suit.
You know,
you just have to lose things and you're
just learning through a process,
you know?
And at the store,
you know where I got it and the belly
room one night,
that's where it came to me.
Wheels was doing a show on a Thursday
night at 11.
There was like 13 people up there and I
was bombing anyway.
And I remember I turned to my side and
for some reason I took myself back to a
corner.
I watched that movie without Pachino and
about football and he has a great speech
for Jamie Foxx.
One time it brings him to the side and
he goes,
listen man,
we got two minutes on the clock.
We're going back to when you were a kid,
your mom just call you in for dental.
You've got one play left.
Remember you used to run to the car and
make a left and do the same fucking
thing and they scored a touchdown and
sometimes we forget about that.
So what I did was I twisted my body
around and I put myself on the corner of
78 and Kennedy Boulevard where I used to
make fun of this guy with the limb.
Look at that janitor with the one eye
and that's when it started.
I stopped looking at them and I
remembered who I was.
I was letting them judge me with their
eyes and I turned that and I never
forgot that.
I remember going home and going,
I'm onto something,
and then little by little I started
being made more up on stage.
It was real quick and I stopped
listening.
The problem is we listen.
Well,
they won't do this unless you're clean.
Oh.
If you go for a showcase at the Improv,
you can't do this.
You have to be yourself.
Unless you got to be yourself,
you'll never move forward.
You'll never move forward and comedy.
You have to tap into this if you don't,
you know,
and everybody did it.
Everybody goes up there doing hokey
jokes in the beginning.
His snow is shame,
snow,
embarrassment.
You do topical material and Shit,
but once you start comparing that
topical material with what's going on in
your life and you open that up,
it becomes a monster.
It takes a long time or it takes some
people longer than others,
but it's the work.
Joe Roman,
it's always been the work man.
You know,
I was watching Chappelle TNM stage Jesus
fucking Christ trail.
I see the 30 years,
I see your 20 years,
but I see is 30 years.
I see that 65 year difference.
He looks at a joke really differently
because he says he was great even when
he was 19.
Yes.
He was always the comedy club in
[inaudible].
Ninety three for men in tights.
I paid it was him.
Nick Depalo.
What an open mic and he always had
something.
Yeah,
she had a way of telling stories.
Two's got a genuinely appealing way.
Delivers his material like it makes you
want to laugh,
but you have a lot of that too,
man.
You have a lot of that too.
You have a lot of genuinely appealing.
You have a different kind of chaos when
you're on stage.
What I was going to say is that it
happened really quick like you,
where you went from being a guy who had
a really hard time on stage most of the
time and then all of a sudden you are
murdering man.
Just murdering.
Just murder in.
I remember one time,
uh,
we,
we were doing gigs together like we were
doing gigs together.
The nineties,
98.
Yeah,
late nineties.
We did some road gigs,
did a bunch of road gigs.
And I remember,
I remember when I knew that you had
caught fire because we were in New
Jersey and I think this might've been
even before fear factor.
We were in New Jersey and you just
caught fire.
We were at that old rascals and I went,
Whoa,
and I remember thinking like,
Joey just fucking hit this totally
different level,
like you just figured out how to be you
and you were on stage and a lot of it is
because you're in jersey,
you know,
and this,
there were animals.
He remembered that club was,
could I call?
It was filled with savages.
Who was so fun?
That rascals club.
Jesus Christ.
That was fun.
Where was that?
In West Orange?
Yes,
west orange.
God,
Dan.
Then there was the other one down the
shore which wasn't.
It was really fun.
Was more like white people who was like
more relaxed.
That one was filled with all sorts of
freaks.
Who was a great club and down so much
fucking strip club from that one,
like a really cold strip club with
Russian chicks.
They had no income then it had no heat
and the other comic took me in there.
I forget who it was.
I was freezing in the breeze and that
was a creepy,
but it was a fun rascals.
Oh,
those was the dude's name that ran it
again.
Kind of the beautiful hair head though.
He'll call me today.
Okay.
He,
I have his number in that.
I forget his name.
He'll call me today to wish me a merry
Christmas after all those years.
That's awesome because somebody will
tell them that we would some last time
or the time before we mentioned him.
He called me that night.
He owns a restaurant now in jersey.
Bailey.
He goes to visit him.
The bus boys went in there going,
oh my God,
Joe Rogan was talking about you.
Some young college kids I like as
waiters or waitresses or whatever the
fuck.
It was a good dude.
He was always a good dude.
It's great to go down to the store now
and just sit in the back and watch calm
and not say a word and slightly and I
watched him.
I watched our sandy hall and I watch her
on why I watched it.
You know,
he's,
you know,
he's talking about he should have taken
the money now.
Dave Chappelle.
I almost fucking died because I should
have taken them up actually.
I put my two feet down and taking the
money.
Uh,
he's an interesting guy,
isn't he?
Because he doesn't really put material
out anymore.
He just killing it,
right.
New Shit.
Killing it everywhere.
But he's not like doing specials.
I wonder if he's thinking about doing a
special.
Oh,
I'm sure they've made them 10 offers
today.
I wonder if he wants to because he's so.
He's so different than any.
But like you can't predict that guy like
his,
what he's done so far.
It's just so unusual.
Like they offer them this big money to
do this thing and he's like,
you know what,
fuck this.
I'm going to Africa.
Like he goes to Africa,
you know?
And then he starts doing shows and parks
like Dave will have like,
people maybe not
never heard these stories,
but he would show up with like a PA
system,
like a little portable PA system in a
park in Seattle and he would put this
little PA system down and just start
doing standup in the park in Germany to
find something on youtube.
Yeah.
Surely.
Shannon,
can you look at Charlie Barnett on
Washington Square Park?
Yeah,
I've seen,
I met Charlie.
No,
I met him.
I've seen just to just to show redman
the gift will tell everybody what you
still do.
Shows outside.
Just like he would just show up in new,
drop his hat in the ground and like do a
standup comedy routine and asked people
to contribute,
throw money in his hat.
Wait,
look at this as what I used to go to
mcsorley's and get eight volumes for $10
and three mugs for a dowel and bring it
back to the beginning,
Jimmy and put the volume of looking at
the red band.
Wow.
The volumes,
not Oregon who had some form of a sound
issue,
ladies and gentlemen.
But what we're seeing for people that
are just listening is this Guy Charlie
Barnett who has since passed away,
uh,
he's wearing like some bread track pants
and a white tee shirt and a white
baseball hat and he's got this huge
group of people circling him and he's in
the middle of a park.
He just set up and he's doing stand up
comedy like he's,
he's doing with no microphone here.
He goes,
water ray gun.
We got a lot of fucking Puerto Reagan's
what?
I'm not gonna fuck with Niggas man.
Cause y'all born with knives.
Y'All got me up and I wouldn't even know
Bob.
And when you finish you're gonna get
passed out Bro.
Because I got into a fight with a Puerto
Rican kid and I was winning.
I was bouncing around like sugar ray
Leonard.
I was Bam,
Bam,
Bam.
It was only about that tall.
Then all of a sudden they went like this
and I was surrounded by small Puerto
Rican family.
I liked everything,
man.
Let me borrow it.
Okay,
so I liked the white white women.
Why would that one has no negros around?
I don't see.
No.
I liked the write.
Different nationalities go to work.
Everybody goes to work different.
For instance,
Caucasian business man,
I need some white people glasses.
It's like walking around,
borrowing from people had been holding
this lady's purse.
What year is this to be this damn.
You can't see shit.
I get why guys gotta work.
They got their briefcase.
I didn't want just like the white man
going to work.
Watch this white guys that when I stood
on a corner and go to work with talking
about get out should get there by payday
just to show people what it was.
I mean this is a guy outside.
Listen,
the reason why you have a microphone
that's control.
Yeah.
He had no microphone.
He's still fucking control me.
You didn't see?
No,
but I mean he got to the point where
people were going down there.
This is by like a college and my friend
was a junky and I was like 16 and he
used to go,
come over to the city with me.
I'll buy you some volumes.
I go into the park or get heroin and
wait for me at the bar.
He would get me served.
He'd get me three mugs,
a budweiser,
and I'd sit there.
He come back when the second mug was
gone,
give me my eight pills.
I take two of them and then he goes,
shoot heroin.
And I'd go,
fuck it.
Let me go walk around the park.
And I saw this one time I saw this and I
was in shock.
I'm like,
didn't like stand up.
I'm having them,
nothing.
I knew Richard Pryor and George Carlin,
David Brenner and I'm watching this guy
going,
what the fuck is this?
And next thing you know,
I sat down,
I started getting high and I watched it
and I asked around and said he's here
every weekend or something and this is
what he does.
Then years later I found that,
but he would do that for four or five
hours,
but he would take breaks and Dave
chappelle coming as a young kid,
they've should,
would take the bus from DC or something
and go up there and do little septum
between.
He died from the banging.
Yeah.
He died from the hip.
He's the real deal that he was an old
New York icon type.
Fucking junkie.
Yeah.
He was a heroin guy.
Right.
I own I,
but it was just weird that he did.
I watched all those.
I didn't know that somebody had taped
them.
That's amazing.
I did a show with Chappelle in Montreal
at the comedy festival in the nineties,
forget what year it was,
but after the show was over,
we did it a club soda.
We go downstairs and Dave just a puts on
a show on the street in Montreal.
People just walking by.
It's like gather around,
gathered around.
They just started doing standup up.
Just stand up for like 20 people on the
street,
you know,
I,
he incorporated like this.
There was a telephone pole incorporated
the pole into his routine.
He had a hat.
He just put the hat down,
ask people to put money in it.
I can these.
He just got off stage so he did a
professional show.
Went downstairs,
was outside and just said,
fuck it.
I'm going to do or do my own impromptu
show out here on the street.
It was fascinating.
I mean,
who,
other than Charlie and him ever.
Have you ever heard of doing that?
I'm sure some people have done it,
but I.
those are the only two guys I've ever
heard was a black guy.
The Venice beach all the time.
I could call you.
Yes.
Yeah.
It's been a bunch of movies and that's
true,
right?
He did a bunch of different stuff you
have to do is show out.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
You did the Milwaukee one for a bunch of
kids and shit on the template.
Did you ever do a little something
summerfest like I had to comment on a
bus one time
so people know,
like a Disney event called me up when I
was in New York,
75 bucks for an hour on the bus and go
from seed to New York and three climbers
got to get up and do commonly what a
fucking bonding experience,
bro.
Jesus Christ,
30 gigs.
I did a spot on New York comedy club one
time and after I get off I probably got
eight minutes dogs and six of it is just
God awful and I get off the stage and
some guy's like,
man,
do you want to do my wife's birthday
party?
I'm like,
sure.
And he's like,
what do you want to know?
What it usually like give you like 1500.
I said one,
he gives me the address.
Alpine,
New Jersey off nine w make the right
bangle with clothes.
I fucking take a cab up there.
I'm about to score 1500 me and you know
me at that time.
I'm looking.
I'm still looking for purchase.
I was still a half a little fucking
collect up.
So you're ready to go?
Yeah.
Where's the microphone?
There's no microphone.
You got to go over by the pool on the
other side of the pool.
There's rocks and staying on top of the
wrap.
Stand up thought they were 80 yards away
from me.
I'm up there telling Godzilla jokes.
Slow death of debt can get off.
I was so embarrassed that the guys like
listening.
I only got like $900 in cash.
You want to check it out?
Just give me a ticket.
I took that my whole house and I walked.
I started walking somewhere.
I hitchhiked and picked me up and made
them drop me at the bridge.
I walked over the bridge and got like an
eight ball of coke.
Had the stone barest.
Could you really have jokes?
Do you remember what year that God will
never attack New York City.
Okay,
because can you imagine Godzilla coming
out?
Hudson and going or something?
All the pollution and shit.
He got like this and go back on the
wall.
That horrible.
That was my big job.
That was it.
I thought that was.
And you know at that time the Puerto
Rican,
something happened with the Puerto Rican
navy.
They bumped into a.
They bumped into a barge,
like some Puerto Rican cruise boat,
bumped into a barge and the New York
side and they broke the buyer,
so everybody on the boat had a job at
the time.
Everybody had to jump into the fucking
water and that was the joke.
I said,
you know,
last Tuesday in New York,
a bus full of a cruise boat,
Puerto Ricans hit the 40 Puerto Ricans
in the Hudson.
That's new.
That was my other big clothes.
That was it.
And that's nothing new.
It's environmental and reset it.
Somebody told me they'd clean it up.
The Hudson.
So true.
He couldn't clear.
They wanted to know how many fucking
sperm loads I shot now.
Often when I was a kid,
I used to go to Binghamton both for
dinner and they had a movie theater in
Edgewater,
New Jersey.
Edgewater is cap land where they shot
capital edge or what it was supposed to
be and my
friend had a restaurant h and b,
Dinah.
I used to go down there.
What exactly were they shot that?
That bar.
I used to go in there and buy the little
bottles of blackberry.
Brandy for us when we were kids.
And uh,
they redid all that shit down.
Have you seen that in New York?
No,
that is beautiful.
Fucking now.
That's where I stay now.
I stayed in edgewater here.
I take the ferry over.
How long does that take?
The ferry?
Ten minutes.
I take the ferry over.
I jumped in my fucking cab.
I go to 20th street.
I do Gotham,
I do the stand.
I take a cab back to the ferry.
How hard would it be to live in New York
and take a boat across from New Jersey?
Every day people do with everyday back.
How many people it matter fact get the
car.
I gave the card to a lot of people,
but I gave the car to Ari.
I would think that that would be like a
smart move.
Yeah.
You get a boat and he could try and then
go do your thing with Louis does.
Isn't he a big guy?
He has his own boat.
He definitely has a boat.
I don't know if that's what he does or
if he.
I think he lives in Manhattan.
No,
but I mean I feel like it wouldn't be
that hard to get across that water,
like just water.
Just get across.
That's way better than a stupid bridges.
Like if you could figure out a way to
like to live like that.
Just take Uber's on one side,
Park your car on the other,
like the way to go.
New York,
but they've taken that city down.
Eventually it don't.
You don't need to be a genius or a
scholar and nostradamus stupid Joey
Diaz.
You pull up the Lincoln tunnel.
Now there's guys in full gear with Nazi
helmets.
Fucking machine guns under their arms
and dogs and they go up to every fucking
car dog and his fucking 50 of them.
The bridges.
You see him everywhere.
And when I went to take my wife to the
tree at the saks fifth avenue,
you could see the motherfuckers snipers
up on the fucking roof.
Stores ain't fucking around.
When you're walking around New York,
you like,
I could see this.
They're really going after the bridge.
Like my friends were oh genome.
They work a hoboken and all those guys.
I'm I,
when I did the whatever factory now I
guess all these cops have to do details
because they want to take that bridge
outdoor and they want to take that
fucking bridge tunnel.
That's going to be a nightmare.
When I was walking around in New York,
had to,
I could see it,
I could see how he could go down.
And that's a big city with a lot of
fucking people.
Joe Rogan.
It's tough to control all those people
in that area.
You know?
It's so much different than any other
city.
To my God,
man,
you get there,
you just see the magnitude of it all.
Just kind of like sets in and you're
like,
no wonder why people can't leave this
place if you get used to this.
There is no place like that place,
so bizarre.
It's 7 million plus people smushed into
the smallest little area.
It's not that big if you,
if you look at all the buildings that
are tucked in.
I remember I had a hotel room once and
it was on a corner and it was in.
It was like,
sometimes it's cool to be on the
outside,
like at a friend lived in Brooklyn and
he had a cool view from the river.
Like you look from his apartment,
you see the whole city skyscraper.
The whole skyline is pretty beautiful.
But there's something cool about being
in the middle of it all.
And this,
uh,
this hotel I stayed at was on a corner
and I'd like to look out the window on
both sides and just fucking,
it's like a science fiction movie.
Just giant constructed buildings to the
left and to the right.
And you're in the middle of all of it.
Hundreds and hundreds of windows.
Everyone looking out at each other.
Everyone's in there watching a little TV
shows,
doing their little thing,
but you're in the middle of all this
crazy Saifai,
beehive type thing.
You know where we live,
we would drive to each other's houses.
There's like a yard.
There's a space.
You're pulling your driveway.
Hey,
come on in.
You know,
park in the driveway.
It's like normal stuff.
You know,
like you get out of the house.
Hey,
this is your house right over there.
That's his house and no it fucking
stacked.
Everybody's
stacked,
stacked on top of,
on top of stack,
smashed together.
Stack,
stack,
stack.
Everybody jammed into these boxes.
Blue Cars,
little fucking yellow cars.
And Uber's everywhere on the ground.
No one gets anywhere.
When gridlock hits crosstown traffic,
there is reason why Hendricks wrote that
fucking song and that was in the
seventies and the sixties.
I guess he wrote it right.
That when you,
when you were in the Manhattan,
grew up gridlock.
Crosstown traffic.
I feel like this is insane.
Like why the fuck would anybody live
here?
You can't go anywhere.
Jam,
jam,
jam.
There was moving anywhere and there's so
many fucking people
and everywhere you look,
there's Delis and restaurants and
storage units and parking lots and
fucking this business and that business
door and that door.
Just just a vortex of energy.
Just luck.
They want for that fucking shit.
Incredibly.
We're at edgewater just driving around
and we saw this thing.
The next day I go ask,
ask around Terry go on the computer like
two days ago.
She's like,
oh my God,
just to move in that half a mil and then
whatever your mortgages,
it's 1700 flat just for maintenance
fees.
Yeah,
a lot of that.
A lot of maintenance fees,
maintenance fees of $1,700
and that's if you don't use the gym or
the pool or the garage if you use all
that stuff,
there's another 890 our fucking fee.
This fee,
you got to buy the water from them.
She goes,
it was fucking crazy.
And at the end of the day you got a
motherfucking apartment.
That's all you got.
Call quality,
Condo,
whatever the fuck you want to call it.
It's a fucking apartment,
my friend.
Then yeah,
you've got the view of uh,
the Manhattan skyline,
that's what you're paying for you to
think about how much of one of those big
apartment buildings must be worth
because every one of those units is a
million bucks,
a million bucks or more.
Milan have a much more.
I saw some that were like $5 million.
So you gotta be kidding.
This is a normal apartment,
silver lake and there's like 5 million
bucks,
but this is crazy.
I couldn't live
like that.
Could you?
I couldn't live like that if I,
if I like,
if I had the experience of living there,
like if it was normal to me,
like I think the people that do live
there,
when you get used to driving around on
the subway,
riding around and calves,
you get used to where all the clubs are.
You do your little routine and getting
the,
getting the airport to take off two
cities and he worked the road.
You get used to it,
you get used to like a tail does it.
A lot of those other guys do it.
But once you get used to space and once
you get used to like being able to go
dip out and dip back in without that
much trouble,
like it's way easier to like live in the
valley and then drive into the store on
a Friday night.
Then it would ever be,
if you live somewhere like that equally
far away from Manhattan and he wanted to
get in to do a spot.
Like that's a to our proposition.
Like you've got to be ready.
You got to be ready to enter that
machine,
you know?
Especially if you're going to do it at
like 7:00
at night.
So what time you leave your house,
you leave your house at 5:30
for a 7:00
show.
Well then you leave your wallet at home,
get your phone and the driveway.
It makes sense to hit and hit.
Let's say if you hit and let's say you
live in Brooklyn,
you got to take the train into
Manhattan,
something like that.
Right?
You get used to that.
I think the town in Brooklyn or
something like that.
Even if he just takes the training,
you do four or five spots.
He does the cell.
Have this?
Yeah.
You do a couple of spots and get back on
your train and go home and 1:30
now with Uber's too,
it's just so easy to do it.
It's so easy to just use your car shows
up in a couple of minutes.
So less so much less hassle,
you know?
Especially because like with cabs,
you don't know if a caps coming.
So what are you going to do in
Manhattan?
You're going to call a cab company.
Say come get me on this.
Nobody ever does that.
You tried to flag one.
So you try to find one.
You go walking around looking for one,
but now you just press a button on your
phone and they like,
we'll be there in three minutes.
All right,
cool.
Because of the calves are getting easier
to get.
I got to count every time I want to do
this time real funky in zero to 100
bitch lift.
Just lax [inaudible].
You ever take Uber?
Yeah,
I take it up one time.
I took a black one time through.
I've taken a few times in New York.
I use it all the time in New York.
I could do.
I think I could do it like he's enjoying
it.
He's enjoying it.
He likes doing it.
It'd be harder for me because I have
kids and I just don't think New York
City,
the best place for kids,
and maybe I'm wrong,
just seems.
First of all,
that brake dust can't be good for you
and there's.
There's break.
If you.
If you feel like I'm finding out what
the fuck you breathe,
go look at your wheels with your cars,
wheels and just stick your finger inside
the rim and get that black shit all over
your finger.
Will.
That just says it doesn't just go on
your wheel and stick their only know as
you like.
See like crazy traffic like on fifth
avenue or something like that.
You'd see Broadway traffic just paint,
Bam,
Bam.
You're breathing in brake dust.
One hundred percent.
That stuff's in the air,
so
it's not just the carbon fuel.
A residue like the exhaust from cars,
whatever.
Fires are being burned,
whatever,
a gas ovens and that.
It's not just that,
but it's brake dust,
brake dust is everywhere and you're
getting that shit in your lungs 100
percent.
It's not good for you.
It's just not.
You know,
and they've shown their studies.
It's that think that living in a high
populated city like New York and take as
much as 10 years off your life,
just living there doing exactly the same
thing,
living exact same choices,
but living in a polluted environment
like downtown La.
It was probably a good example of that.
Right?
Downtown gets Funky,
you know,
it gets fucking polluted,
but it's still more open than say New
York or anything like that.
You could at least see the sky.
Sometimes you can,
sometimes you can't,
but la gets pretty stinky.
Ellie can get pretty bad if we get
stagnant and the winds don't blow,
and then the,
the,
the pollution just sits.
You know how you crest,
like if you come over from Encino and
you see the valley and you see that
fucking horrible brown cloud,
that's real.
Assign an illusion and you don't see
that in the desert.
If you go out where there's no people
that doesn't exist,
that exist because of people burning
things that you're breathing that in.
Everyone's breathing that.
In 93 I lived in New York and I would
get up at seven and go into the city.
I live in cliffside.
I worked in New York and going to New
York and bum around and then sometimes I
take a shower at the gym.
I joined a boxing gym.
I just go there for the locker.
Basically I would if the bag a little.
I didn't know what I was doing and I
would fuck it and just go out at night
and I remember sometimes I wouldn't take
a shower at the gym at six.
I was busy and I get home at 11 and I
take a shower and you'd see what will
come out of my hair and I'd just be
walking around Manhattan guys.
I didn't go anywhere else.
I'd just be walking around Manhattan
given cabs doing this,
dropping off packages.
It was.
You could see I didn't do anything
residue.
It was just this darkness,
like it was like Jesus Christ,
what the fuck have I been used to it
after awhile,
but it really stuck with me like just
walking around Manhattan six or seven
hours with do this to me.
Like it really will get more blackheads
there.
My hair,
like when you wash it,
you would see the fucking dirt bike.
Just not real.
A lot of dirt,
but you see that you have something on
your skin.
Let me ask you this.
Does this make sense to you?
They can make a big giant building like
the empire state building.
They can make a big ass building.
Why can't they make a big ass air
filter?
Well,
if you're going to put up that many
buildings and have that many people,
not many cars.
How about your build a giant air filter?
I mean like they sell air filters for
your house.
Like my daughter's allergic to cats.
We're finding out we have two cats and
so now we have to shave the cats.
So I've been shaving them.
First of all.
It's adorable when you see the line
cuts.
Yeah,
they get the line cuts and the and then
the other thing is when you shave him
it's just almost like skin,
so it's just a little bit of flour and
it must feel so
much better when you pat him because
when I pad,
especially like the little girl with the
big one,
that boy the boy too,
but when I pat them they just start
fucking riving like you're making them
come and they love it.
They love it.
They love it when you're,
uh,
when you're petting them,
when you've shaved them all down.
But we have this air cleaner that we
have to put in her bedroom because she,
she starts sneezing and shit.
We're finding out that she's not
terribly allergic but allergic enough so
we have to figure out what to do.
But they make these air filters.
It makes a big difference.
You put them in your room,
sucks.
All the dander and all this stuff out of
the air cleans it.
It seems like if you can make a giant
ass building,
why can't you make a giant ass air
filter that sucks?
All that dirty brown,
stinky air out and cleans it like that
can't be impossible to do.
Just doesn't seem like it should be.
If you can make a big building and you
can make a big fan,
he can make a big fucking air cleaner,
can't you?
It makes sense.
But then you got to clean it every two
minutes or something from the man who
brought you parachutes on commercial
airplanes that,
that sucks.
A lot of people get use to the cat.
Uh,
our,
Geez.
I know a lot of ex girlfriends that
would first like,
Hey,
I'm allergic to cats.
And then after a few years or whatever,
they would stop being as allergic
though.
A lot of India.
You vaccinated them with your Dick?
Yeah.
Slowly but surely you feel anything,
any non cat allergy DNA into their body
and they assimilate it.
I was at a gas station the other day and
they were selling poppers and I recently
was at a nitrate,
you mean?
Yeah,
yeah,
it's a popper.
It even said like it was like the little
jar and everything and it's like.
And I went to a party and I actually saw
my first person actually using poppers.
What you.
But a guarantee.
That's not the same thing.
I guarantee you the stuff they're
selling it at a gas station is not like
Emile nitrate.
That's highly illegal,
is it?
Yeah.
I think what they're doing is there's
the,
you know,
how those boner pills,
like you buy boner pills,
the gas station and pretend they're
herbs,
but it's really cialis or Viagra or
something like that.
I think with these things are something
similar to that.
Just how like bath salts were never
really bath salts.
They could just call it whatever they
want and call poppers as long as it's
not email nitrate.
But was bachelor that salt was,
they would call it bath salts.
So they could sell it,
it would say not for human consumption,
but it,
when it really is,
was they had done something to meth.
So they say like,
this is an idiot's way of describing
this,
right?
Just let me get that out of the way.
When you describe something like a
molecule like,
um,
uh,
like the,
the chemical that your brain produces,
dimethyltryptamine,
it's an end dimethyltryptamine that's
illegal,
but there's a thing called five meo
dimethyltryptamine that's legal because
they fucked up and they didn't,
they didn't list it so you could get
that stuff and it's like a cousin of
DMT.
It's called five Meo DMT.
Well,
that's a similar to what they did with
this math thing.
They would take meth and then they would
just change a little bit of it,
add an oxygen molecule and a carbon
molecule,
whatever they have they have to do and
that turns it into something
different.
So it's not illegal,
but it's,
it'll fuck you up,
fuck face eating,
fuck you up.
So then they sell it as bath salts
saying,
yeah,
throw this in the bath,
hop in there,
wink,
and everybody knows you're just going to
go smoke it.
And they smoke this stuff and it blows
their fucking brains out because they
don't even know what it is.
But you're selling like high potency
meth at truck stops.
I mean,
that's what they're selling it.
They were selling those little
convenient marks was weird.
Twenty four gas stations,
that's where they were selling it and
you can just go in and buy meth,
but through a loophole and so all these
people were buying this shit.
I am for years.
You go into a place and the east coast
and he always had a rose in the tube.
Yeah,
it's a crack pipe.
I didn't know that.
Yeah,
it's not really a rose.
The rose is throw the fucking blows
away.
Smoke crack out of that thing.
You didn't know that?
Well,
I knew it because my friend Johnny was a
crackhead.
Can you believe that?
They suck,
right?
How many doors did you go from here?
You're like a rose fucking crackhead.
Would they had to figure out a way to
sell those things,
so they sold like a little tiny glass
face with a rosewood.
They should've bought some of these
because it was in west Hollywood and
they were lined up at different logos on
it.
Just like.
Yeah,
I hear that.
The knows.
Come on man.
Those are.
Those are dmt pipes to.
That's what you smoked dmt out or how
crazy is that?
That's the loophole right there.
Yeah,
and then it's just a beauty about paying
a nickel on getting an attorney.
I'd sit with them and going,
how can I sell this butter flour and
it's sunny.
It's beautiful.
Can you believe Brian fucking 40 when I
found that I'm supposed to be the king
of swing,
it's fucking crack.
It is hilarious that keep on finding out
these horrible things that I should have
known a long time ago.
Like,
like on the toaster,
the one through 10.
That's how many minutes.
It's not like hot and cold.
Really?
Yeah.
I wonder why.
I was like,
why does seven take so long?
Such a fucking idiot.
I'm making toast.
Go Jesus Christ.
I need a faster toaster.
Yeah.
Something that gets you a seven quicker.
I had no idea that that little thing
when you zip up your pants,
that little knob thing,
if you put it down that Luxor zipper
down like you know,
like when you're zipping it up,
the handle,
if you put the handle down,
it locks it up.
You just kind of like zip up your pants
and not think about it and they later
you're like,
why is my zipper down?
It's because you didn't just do that
extra little.
You didn't have that one.
I don't understand what you're saying.
This,
this handle thing like this right here.
Yeah.
Thanks.
This.
Put it down,
put it down.
It locks.
It lets the lock the lock and it's the
whole technology unlock until you lift
it up.
Yes.
I didn't know that.
I have like five more.
Just realize what I'm trying to do it,
but it's bent down that I literally
can't
unzip my pants.
Fascinating.
Yes.
I had no idea what makes sense,
right?
Otherwise it just wouldn't work.
Zippers are bullshit.
I'm tired of Zippers.
Man Hates Zipper is always down.
Someone's always like your zipper's
down,
man.
No,
it's not always.
It doesn't.
I don't think it matters where these
goddamn stretchy pants.
All my pants are like fake jeans.
They look like jeans to fake jeans.
I had one that was wearing,
that had fucking,
uh,
it had a tie.
It was a diesel pair of diesel and they
stretch.
And you tie in like sweatpants and P.
I would show people and they would
scream.
No screaming.
No,
no.
You can't wear that.
You wearing stretchy pants that time.
Like why?
Why can't I remember people saying like
these girls at the comedy store,
like you can't wear those.
You can't wear those.
Like I'm wearing them.
Why can't I wear them?
Why can't I wear.
You can't wear pants.
Jeans Look Great.
Fucking fat cheese.
Look,
they look real.
You got me hooked on him.
I don't have to like that.
And you order them online?
Yeah.
These are.
I have no affiliation with this company.
They're called barbell jeans.
Yeah.
Great.
I love them.
They're so stretchy.
They move like sweatpants.
They feel like there's no resistance.
Like,
well we're normal pants.
I feel like I'm wearing a straight
jacket now.
It's like wearing pajamas outside.
I got a new company that I'm.
It's also,
but this is a sponsor of the podcast.
It's called Mizzen and main.
And they make these clothes that are
made out of this really light stretching
material,
like a button up shirt,
button up shirts always.
Like it looks like a normal button up
shirt,
but you don't feel anything.
You move with it.
It's like,
like a,
like a light cotton t shirt.
It's amazing.
It's stretches.
It moves with you everywhere you go.
Like I'm like,
I just want.
Does it have the thickness look of it or
is it like,
you know,
yeah,
let's get buffed body or your nipples
are showing through.
It was probably definitely show through
it because my nipples are ferocious.
But uh,
it looks like a regular shirt.
It doesn't look like anything unusual
about it.
But I'm,
I'm that close to going fucking
sweatpants and fanny pack everywhere.
I'm not close.
I'm not close to just completely thrown
in the towel and picked up school.
Surprise track suit.
A walking stick.
I might even get like some yellow
hunter,
s Thompson glasses,
like just yellow where I'm indoors.
Outdoors.
Fuck it.
Instead.
Hunter s Thompson always had the
cigarette lighter.
That's a vapor pen instead of the
cigarette holder.
It's the same thing as a vapor pen,
just going full yellow glasses,
track suit,
fanny pack.
That's my new look.
Toe Shoes.
I don't give a fuck.
I'm going to wear those to Vibram
fivefingers.
Those already.
Fuck yeah,
and where you were man.
Nowhere to hide those things.
I to really see me and I'll keep them at
the house collapses.
There's something about what you wearing
glasses like that.
You have no business in reality.
You're not.
You're not a.
you're not doing business in reality.
You're here for your own thing.
You're here to party.
That's so crazy.
That was the best.
This guy was fucking.
It was the best,
but he would wear those yellow glasses.
I'll be honest with you guys.
When I saw him,
I didn't know who the fuck he was when
you saw him in real life and Woody
Creek,
right?
Yeah.
I saw him.
I didn't know who the man and then
somebody told me and then I went back
down there and I saw a William Bill
Murray that fucking place.
You know Bill Murray would go visit him.
Oh yeah.
Everybody would go visit him.
People would go visit him.
How crazy
have you ever read fear and loathing in
Las Vegas?
It's been years.
God Damn.
It's good.
It's.
It's good dude.
He's got some great passages in it.
There's some great moments that he
captured on paper.
They just make it yo.
Fuck.
He had this ability to hit these.
These,
these rare patches of insight is rare
areas.
We just break into these rare areas and
make these passages make these
paragraphs that you just go,
whoa.
God Damn.
Like talking with him must have been
fucking fascinating.
I read the biker book.
Yeah.
Hells angels was one of the first books
I read.
That was the first one who the author
was.
I didn't even know what an awful was at
that time.
With that book was though was like a
much more of a regular journalism book
was a book about the hell's angels.
Like they had disputed some of the facts
in it.
You know,
they said that a lot of stuff he made,
it was made up and he tried to make it
all look like a lot different than it
really is in the evidence to.
That was when he started doing his best
work was all that.
His best work was like fear and loathing
and the Kentucky.
The Kentucky Derby is decadent and
depraved.
Fear and loathing and the campaign trail
like that stuff where he combined
fiction and reality like that guy sunk
presidential candidates.
There's this guy named Ed Muskie who was
running for president and monitor is
Thompson.
Started talking about him,
neat bringing in a Brazilian doctor
because he's addicted to Ibogaine,
so he starts spreading these stories
about these rumors that there's a
Brazilian doctor coming to visit.
Ed maschine starts with having fucking
mental breakdowns.
This guy is on the campaign trail and
he's.
He's reading these stories about him
bringing in some Brazilian doctor and
he's fucking falling apart.
100 just making it up.
He's just making up all this shit about
him having an Ibogaine addiction and
that he,
when he was on stage,
you could see him in the full grips of
an Ibogaine addiction.
Nobody even knew what the fuck Ibogaine
was and so he just made up this rumor
and then when they asked him about it,
he goes,
no,
there really was a rumor and I started
the rumor just like you would joke
around about mixing reality and fiction
and he would combine the two of them
together.
Like he was the only guy that ever did
that an openly did it.
Like you would read it and he would call
it Gonzo journalism and you would know
that like as you were reading it,
that this wasn't all real.
Like some of this stuff.
It was just complete total fantasy.
You know,
we were right outside of barstow.
When the bats,
what is it when the drugs were going to
take hold,
like the stories about like all the
different shit that they had in the
truck where they were headed to vegas
from barstow.
The bats in the air,
the fucking acid trip in the,
in the reception area of the Vegas Hotel
when they just like screaming about golf
shoes
and he sees everybody turned into
lizards like this is fucking bizarre,
bizarre shit.
You know.
He was a very,
very unusual guy.
He took a high acid brown.
He did,
but he went a different way with it.
What's really fascinating about him,
he went like guns and fucking living in
the woods and just blowing your brains
out with cocaine every night.
Like he went a totally different way
with it.
He didn't go like the Kumbaya way,
you know,
like all these other dudes.
They got together and they,
they sat Indian style and they,
they played Indian music and chimes and
burned incense and they went the
spiritual route and he just,
he went to.
Otherwise the total other way he went
get acid and then get a gun and then go
outside.
He was shooting golf balls.
Yeah,
like to put them in the hole.
He was playing golf with a gun so he
would shoot the balls to put them in a
hole or something like that.
Just shit that it was a,
you know,
I was living in snowmass village and I
was hearing different rumblings.
I was still 19 or 20,
so I don't know if I was allowed in that
bar that much.
I would just go in there with Keto Keto,
get weed.
That was it.
That was his name was keith corn and he
would take me to keith corn.
His life's mission was to get the best
weed in Colorado.
I told him from now on,
you get bag of weed,
knock on my door,
give me the 40 bucks.
So he would come to me and go,
that's his guy.
And with a click,
he's got this weight.
It's killing people.
We got to go down to the tablet.
It was hunter.
I know that.
It wasn't until I was selling 100 fresh
washer or something that was selling
weed there or something.
How far was that from when you were
living?
Uh,
maybe 10 minutes down.
Snowmass village hill and then go loop
around.
And then go into woody creek.
So you lived in boulder and you lived in
Aspen?
I lived in.
I lived in a town called basalt first
and right around the corner from Goldie
Hawn and motherfucking Kurt Russell
thing,
the river,
whatever river that was the salt is a
golden pond.
No river of the pond.
You fuck this up a little.
This is route 82,
which is one of the most dangerous.
He's trying to map entry.
So it goes north and south.
This is Aspen,
right?
Straight ahead.
You have to go up three miles to go to
snowmass village and then you have to go
over here to go to woody creek.
Okay.
But the salt was down here about 40
minutes from town and you had to go up
and up a hill.
And that hill,
this was,
it was maybe a gun store and a
restaurant,
but there was a place I had never.
I was in New York City fucking kid.
And when I first saw this,
I got addicted to this.
Worse than cocaine.
I would walk from the salt every day and
walked from Holland hills.
That's where where I lived,
in fact,
Dean Cain had home that locked up and
back there.
You go in there and you get to go,
Bro.
The best idea,
I'd smoke homegrown.
The girl maximum me was growing,
grown.
I should cut it with a scissor
and it got me more high than the shit.
I'm paying fucking 54 now.
This shit was fucking deadly.
I was an 18 year old kid and I would
walk.
I'd get this guy $7 and he'd give me a
fishing pole and I throw it into the
roaring creek and after two minutes,
an idiot,
a blind moron to catch a trout and he'd
come over.
You got something and he'd come over and
he'd help you.
Oh Shit.
Little trout.
He'd take it off it,
Cook it and cook it,
and they'll give you a potato salad,
bread and beans,
and you'd have your own fish that he
grill up for it really right there.
Nineteen 83.
I was hooked on that.
I wouldn't even get a job.
I took all my savings and I would go
there.
That was my exercise,
to walk down and get a fish and walk,
walk down and get a fish.
None of the animals that come on when we
squat,
we would squat and do dead lifts and
fucking cleans my roommates.
That's what they're in there shooting
the ball,
shooting back there and eating.
When he vetoed chop up other,
it was amazing.
That's all I had was I never heard of
that and I'm over here is old snowmass
and they used to have a gas station
there and the guys from New York,
so it was always New York time and that
was so bizarre and he sold sap brand hot
dogs there in 1982.
They were that much New Yorkers,
but that's what I saw.
Goldie Hawn and that little girl for the
first time,
that little girl was just a little girl
and I used to see at that gas station
and what is her name?
The trust,
the famous actress and old snowmass had
another road that went this way and this
is a tremendous story.
It was because all of this at the time
in the eighties with kingpins,
lot of kingpins lived there and that's
where they go.
They had this cocaine kingpin,
a white guy lived there,
not the gray bar that we discussed early
on your show.
This other guy and the feds are trying
to get them so they fucking put cameras
on all the,
you know,
all street things to watch him.
They fucked up and they tapped into the
cable tv,
so his house was being shown to
everybody on their tvs.
So Joe Rogan went home,
put on Channel Two and it's me and my
living room smoking a joint.
Watching that fucking guy sued the
government for fucking resilience
because they didn't know how to reverse
that ahead of time on this was an
accident.
I had four channels.
That's hilarious.
One Channel Two and all they played was
Charles Bronson movies.
I was in heaven because at the Holiday
Inn and Aspen right there by the
airport,
Clint Eastwood would go to every night
and get drunk really?
So every bus in night,
but I was a kid.
What year was this?
Is 80 three hand and the rumor was all
you had to do was go to the Holiday Inn
and clinics will be at the bar drinking
and bro,
everybody would say I was too young to
go to the fucking bar.
I was dying to meet Glenys.
What are you fucking kidding me?
But I couldn't go and it was just stuck.
This was just a complete different
fucking city.
This.
Did everybody get attracted to that one
area?
Aspen just had this law let.
Let's,
let's.
Aspens are great
place.
It's a great place.
It's a lot of rich white people though.
Pawns and rich white people might get
bored.
They fucking did you see?
It's different now.
Yesterday they were talking about some.
That check was in Vegas,
a chicken.
We were just talking about.
Goldie Hawn,
her ski instructor.
She gets Hudson.
Kate Hudson?
No,
but the mother.
Goldie Hawn gave her a ski instructor.
Mercedes Benz for Curtis.
Oh Shit.
They give you a cause.
You know what I'm saying?
Like that's how they roll up there,
but it's an evil fucking.
Like Ted Bundy was up there.
Ted Bundy killed people in snowmass
village at that hotel.
Really?
Ted Bundy escape from the Aspen jail.
This place has a really weird Ted Bundy
killed people all the way down in
Florida too,
right?
Florida,
Colorado,
seattle.
Jesus.
This is a really weird part of Colorado.
And I've told you before that I,
80 for asthma was to cocaine capital of
the country.
All that coke was getting shipped up
there for all these hunter Thompson
types.
Nicholson.
All these motherfuckers were up there.
Then how weird that they all decided to
go there.
No TMZ,
no cameras.
And they can get that deck.
So there was a bar called Patty bugattis
that had a swimming pool right in the
middle.
So people be fucking pumping in the
middle of a fucking pumped.
They jumped in the pool with their
clothes on the Aspen club.
Fucking what's his name?
Had a huge club up there.
Uh,
you know,
uh,
the guy.
What's that guy that sings about Tequila
wasted away?
Buffett,
Jimmy Buffett had a club called the
paragon of the biggest bond on the west
coast,
like nine fucking rooms,
bro.
Really huge.
The paragon over the paragon where these
apartments where the employees state and
I became friends with one of the
waitresses and that's why I fainted from
a bong hit.
One time the bong hit,
I fucking fainted.
I would sit on the back like talking
shit,
I'll do it.
And also a Mexico,
they they're waking me up because it's
so filled up there.
That's where the air is really fucking
thing.
We were talking to this guy who lives in
aspen.
He told me he woke up one day and there
was an elk on his back.
Porch was screaming,
fuck you.
You know they scream when they,
when they are Horny,
learn in the Rut.
The big ass elk was sitting on his
porch.
Clop clop,
clop clop
the screaming instead.
It was like 5:00
in the morning or something like that.
They looked through the curtains and
this thousand pound animals like right
there behind the glass screen.
When I was in all,
when I first moved up there,
Colorado one that put me over the top
was cut.
Bloomix.
Bloomix restaurant was a restaurant.
You had a call,
make a reservation and you had to meet
them in a certain location and park your
car and then he got on the sled.
Dogs pulled you to the restaurant.
Oh,
two seatings.
You had a 7:30
seating and the 9:30
seating.
That's how the only way they do it and
then they pull you out of there and
sledge mush.
They take you on a couple of miles,
a couple miles.
What is it?
Daytime.
You go up there and see how they train
the dogs.
Daytime it became a different tourist
attraction.
Really cool.
And then you go over a place called
independence pass independence pastors
when you think you're a bad mother
fuckers.
Independence pass is only open three
months a year.
It's only open from June to two second
week of September and it cuts your time
from Denver to aspen by like an hour,
but it's only open three months because
of the two lane,
two lane road that now a lot of people
can handle.
One time I went down,
I had a big tough friend from Jersey.
He sat in the back and duct and got on
the floor.
He can handle it.
It's that scary Joe Road if you don't
want a lot of my car come over,
but at the end of independence road and
the other side,
they had the black warfare and you went
in there.
He rented a room and the lady had a
wool,
black wolves everywhere and the ones in
the morning.
That's what you at night.
That's all you hear is how.
Who,
who got all the wills eye,
black wolf,
fucking dog.
I know how many times I went in there
because that's a great.
You know,
now it's all changed.
money has really taken video that past
independence,
independence pass.
Is that what they did in the shining?
The shining is the other place where
it's the most.
That's the most visited spot in the
country.
People think it's a grand canyon,
but it's really estes Park Colorado
because you bend over and,
and,
and the,
the doing something with that hotel.
The Stanley hotel,
that's the best brunch on a Sunday in
the country.
Like the brunch there is known to be
like fucking outrageousness where they
shot the shining Stanley hotel.
They doing something that they're really
going to take that part of the hotel and
turning it into a museum for the
shining.
That doing something that they're going
to make a real man's.
You know that the bushes.
Yeah.
They're gonna.
Make a real one just like they did in
the movie.
Yeah.
And take a look at independence pass.
It's a scary fucking road.
Well you,
you ever done the pch all the way up to
San Francisco?
Yes.
Some fucking moment.
That moment when you're looking to the
right of you and you're like,
oh,
okay.
Especially when you're coming back from
San Francisco and you're on the outside.
Sped up right now.
This is a bird.
This is 82 to aspen.
So I guess you're starting.
Wow.
It's changed a lot with those fucking
treats.
So beautiful though,
man.
There's something about mountain views
that to me is the best view.
Like there's a lot of cool views like
the oceans are really cool.
View Meadows,
a really cool view,
but to me mountains and trees,
there's something about that too,
just like I don't even know how to
describe it.
It's so natural and powerful.
The idea of all these plants growing out
of the ground and reaching up to the sky
and they're thick and dense everywhere.
You're just surrounded by plant life and
then you look up in this spectacular
snow cap mountains
and blue sky and floating clouds and
trees and you know,
out there as all just wild life man.
Just fucking girls is where it gets
scary.
This is where it gets good right there
and it gets even fitter at parts.
Yeah.
This is it.
You've got to trust the other people in
their side of the road.
That's the problem.
Same thing with the pch and it was so
wild and here I am.
Then I lived there,
you know,
83 and then I left back to him.
Then I went back in [inaudible] 85 and
that's when I really got into trouble up
there,
but it was so weird amongst all this
beauty that was just fucking cocaine
trade.
Look at the bright side.
Oh yeah.
Oh fuck man.
You think you'll move back there
eventually,
Joe?
I mean,
especially now that you're really big
into hunting and stuff.
It seems like it'd be more.
I love Denver.
I fucking love it.
Love it.
My one might be my favorite spot.
I love it.
Every time I go there and feel like I'm
at home.
Last time I was there,
I had a fucking great time man.
And when I go up to the you could like
live in the mountains near Denver to
like evergreen.
I was like that for.
What is this?
A half hour away,
just independence pass the whole the
whole ride.
But um,
every time I go back there I'm like,
yeah,
this is probably better.
And right now Denver's bowman and it's
on fire.
They can't control it.
Like all the people that didn't want
weed to be legal,
boy,
they got the worst possible result.
Massive economic recovery.
Housing prices are up 19 percent.
Real estate's up 19 percent.
I heard rents crazy,
crazy,
crazy ma.
The money's booming though.
They've made more money in taxes for the
first time ever from marijuana than they
do from alcohol.
No,
there's never been a place ever that's
done that.
They've passed the amount of money.
They're making taxes from alcohol
because they tax it at like 39 percent
is smart.
They tax the shit out of it and no one
gives a fuck.
Good.
Who Cares?
Weed is so economical.
If you think about it,
like,
well,
how about one of those weed pens,
those ones that Gino cells,
how much do they sell for like 100 bucks
or something like that with that much,
you know,
60 slash 40,
whatever it is.
And you have these little cartridges,
the cartridges,
30 bucks or something like that.
Do they will last for weeks.
Those guys for you?
Not really see three days.
That's how I got caught on the plane
though.
Did you set up the alarm?
Right.
So I told him and they came in and
they're like,
why are you smoking?
I'm like,
do I look like I'm fucking smoking?
And she goes,
I wonder what set this up.
So the whole time I'm like,
they gonna throw me in fucking jail when
I get to the EU.
I just told I talked to you about this
because he periscoped and did it and
like he was blowing it up,
blowing it in periscoped
on a plane.
Joey.
That's like a federal listened to me.
He didn't catch me.
I couldn't smoke in those.
Catch you.
You made your own video.
You made your own evidence against
yourself.
The video's gone right?
The ether.
They uh,
I was in my family so I couldn't blow
the smoke because the sides sucks it in
and immerse.
You'll smell it.
Oh,
I just got up.
Mercier was fuck because listen,
let me tell you something.
No one hinchcliffe dope shouldn't tell
you what.
Let me tell you something.
Those five hour flights without edibles,
a brutal.
You need to get a wholesome spray to
everything that I know get angry.
But I got the fucking thing.
I was going to bring you guys and I left
on the counter.
Yeah.
But I got up and went to the.
Got To be careful about telling,
saying what you see,
what they're making the fucking Kinda
keep it on a deal.
I'm just all gone.
The way of Jesus on the way there.
I didn't need no other boots because I
was worried about my kid on the way
back.
I'm like,
fuck it,
six hours with this kid I need to fill
out with the ipod on.
So I really couldn't hear and I'm
hitting this pipe and I'm like,
I just tries this up.
This motherfucker said good fucking
smoke inside bad and all of a sudden I
can't hear it.
I hear,
I see them like going and I'm like,
Oh shit.
So I flush.
I did piss because I was hitting it
while I was busy.
I pissed and I fucking put it in my
pocket and I help and I have a.
What happened?
She goes,
well,
you smoking here?
And they're like,
it doesn't smell like,
oh no,
the fucking.
I don't know what happened.
I banged up against the thing and then
like my farts are so strong you're
setting off smoke detectors and fucking
sat down and like they were gonna throw
me in jail.
I get my wife the car keys.
I said just in case they arrested me,
they even said and thank you for coming
on.
Your daughter was great.
So once they realize it's not smoke
smoke,
I think,
I don't think they're offended as much
as like if you have a cigarette,
like they used to let you smoke those.
Remember people take those blues on
airplanes.
He to smoke them all the time and then
they had to put the just gonna have to
put got.
They had to figure it out.
They had to come up with laws for that.
For e-cigarettes.
They're gonna have to come up with logs
for those fucking hovercrafts because
hoverboards,
they're blowing up now.
Have you seen him on up?
So not a lot on Amazon.
All of them get these fucking morons off
the fucking planes.
They let you just drive around us.
I have with those.
They blow up.
We have a good version of them.
Or you see the problem is,
is straight out of China.
Yeah.
How do you know what's the good version?
A,
the good versions are the ones that I
actually have like a brand name and
stuff where most of these generic ones
or like just,
you know,
they're like just generic batteries.
Generic.
I just bought it from Amazon.
Should I throw them out?
Get new ones to donate them to really
risky kids.
I'll take him.
No,
no kids.
These are fun.
But you're taking a chance.
There's some crazy videos that I've been
seeing lately.
Them blowing up just
because of the generic batteries and um,
yeah,
I'm sure there's probably some of them
that are better than others,
but if you think about how many people
have,
um,
there's probably like a very,
very small percentage of blowing up,
right?
Yeah.
I don't know.
I don't know either.
But anyway,
they're going to have to figure out how
to regulate them at the airport because
people just ride around and I'm in the
airport.
There's one blown up.
All he ever said,
we don't know what happened here.
That guy could have just let that bitch
on fire.
We don't know.
Well,
there's ones that like in malls,
there's.
There's like a blow up of a mall.
That's what I saw.
Yeah.
Know what else I like about them.
Those motherfuckers a strap constantly.
You can't even.
The system knows what the buck lot of
people.
A lot of white people.
A little on the crazy side.
Now they're smoking that TAC.
You don't want to take the chance.
They might shoot you before the grenade
goes off and your world was hurting me.
Fucked up.
They gonna put Cowboy Dick in and take
you up in the mountains and maple syrup
buying and tie it to a tree and fucking
baked yet and then stab you to death.
I'll see how much you fucking love our
after that motherfucker because listen
man,
I have told you a thousand times.
There's some real crazy gun loving
Americans in the mountains of Colorado.
Oh yeah.
I'm talking and then they're not
malicious.
None of those malicious.
I know good white Americans in Colorado
that awaiting at that house right now.
They're building weapons to kill fucking
Talibans and shit like that.
I know them personally.
I know one guy,
I called him from a fucking throwaway
phone because I know they got the taps
on this motherfucker.
This guy 20 years ago showed me grenade
launchers and his fucking garage.
I can't imagine what he's got now.
Every time I called it,
I send them Christmas cards from a
different address.
I like studio city and mail it to them.
I love him.
His first name is Fred.
That's all I can tell you too much.
Or this guy taught me everything about
he was a fucking weapon.
You know?
I was over there when they just talk and
I go,
you ever seen the movie scarface?
That's a great gun.
He had at the end and he just looked at
me when he looked at his wife because do
me a favor and you go in the other room.
She's like,
sure.
She was like a nice white lady.
Is it going to show jewelry?
Something you just let it got out.
He pulled over his couch and what he'd
had under that couch,
the scarface gun was as little as gun.
Do you understand me gun?
That was his fucking appetizers to kill
people.
This guy had so many things and he
started writing themselves out that he
was in Vietnam.
He started showing me the pictures and
the ears and the cards,
a deck of cards they put on people and
all that shit and I was like,
and he was like,
if you want to go shoot some time I'll
take it.
And that was the beginning of a
friendship though.
He taught me so many little things.
He knew how to fucking kill people from.
He could kill somebody in Mars right
now.
He's just.
He just knew he was amazing.
This shit.
This guy knew you want to kill somebody
in months.
I got the angle fucking,
you know,
it was just something from another
planet man.
He would take me on the weekends.
I'd have to buy it for my bullets and
shit
below the other shit we shot.
I can't tell you this shit we shot.
There's a lot of gun enthusiasts out
there,
lot of guns,
but this guy,
my friend Justin,
he doesn't even know how many guns you
as I go.
How many guns you have?
It goes,
I don't know.
I go more than 100 years.
Oh yeah,
more than 100.
What about when I hugged the doctor?
Steve?
Yeah.
I hugged them one time.
I was like,
what the fuck?
He's like,
Oh yeah,
I don't know it without this phone.
He's in the military.
He was a air force flight surgeon.
He doesn't give a fuck.
Steve's uh,
that guy is crazy as fuck.
He's been my friend for 27 years.
Twenty eight years.
More.
Actually more than that.
Shit.
How many years?
Oh my God,
Dude.
Thirty years.
He's been my friend for 30 something
years.
Thirty three years.
Wow.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
That guy,
he's,
he's in his sixties.
He gets his body fixed just so we can go
back to spawn again.
Isn't a 60,
blows his rotator cuff up,
going to have to get that fixed,
gets it all fucking stitched up and blew
my knee out again.
GotTa get that fixed.
He gets,
he's,
he's had more than 20 knee surgeries.
He's uh,
he's crazy guys.
Didn't give a fuck with young kids.
He'll come after you do like a wild dog.
He always been that way.
He's always been that way.
He was an ophthalmologist when I met
him.
He was doing his residency in Boston.
This guy,
I've never met anybody that worked
harder.
There's a few people in my life that
when I was young that let me know what
hard work really was.
I thought I worked hard and then I'd
watch these guys and I just got fuck.
One of 'em was Steve.
Steve was a,
he was an ophthalmologist.
He was doing his residency.
He was sitting on the toilet eating food
out of a tray and he fell asleep as
buzzer went off.
So he's shitting,
eating and sleeping at the same time and
as buzzer goes off to tell them to go
back to work because he had,
when you're in your residency,
you do these insane,
insane hours,
like they're just mindblowing and then
you're studying and you just,
it's chaos.
The amount of sleep that they get versus
the amount of work that they have to do.
It's amazing how nobody just that people
don't constantly accidentally kill
people because they're all so tired.
Like it's the weirdest thing about
doctors and I don't know how they still,
if they still do it this way,
but the way they used to do it,
they.
They would make them work these fucking
ungodly hours and you would.
You would always be exhausted and so you
would think you'd want to be wide awake
and thinking clearly to make medical
decisions,
especially about people's vision,
right?
Nope.
Have these fucking guys.
They make them work insane,
insane hours and the other one was my
friend jumped ship,
junk Chang.
He was a US national taekwondo champion
and he came from my same gym and he was
the guy who won the championships while
he was in medical school.
This fucking guy.
You want to talk about?
A guy who worked hard.
I never met anybody who worked harder,
complained less,
got so little sleep.
If he slept like four hours a night.
It was planning and he's training for
the national taekwondo team.
This fucking guy used to do studying and
in between studying,
he would sprint up the stairs and his
university and come back down and then
sprint and they would do that like image
who we'd like read or do his work for a
couple of hours and then he would sprint
upstairs,
put his backpack through all his books,
his back,
put his backpack on sprint up the
stairs.
It just,
just did every waking moment dedicated
to all the shit that he had to get done
because he came from a Korean background
and Korean parents are super.
Some of them super strict about their,
their children succeeding.
His father just put all this incredible
pressure on them.
So when I would think like people say,
wow,
you work so hard.
I barely,
I sleep eight hours a night.
Like these guys,
Steve and junk to guys incidentally that
were in the medical,
uh,
medical,
um,
education and they both.
I never saw anybody work harder.
I've never seen anything in my life like
that.
There would be exhausted.
Like jumped ship would come in.
Who come in and training and his mouth
would be open like this.
He was.
He goes,
I'm so fucking tired.
I'm so fucking tired within training
with star at this fucking guy.
He would fire up and get crazy.
He's a bad motherfucker.
He would fire up and just start kicking
the shit out of people and he wasn't
even like a talented guy.
He wasn't like physically talented.
He wasn't like some Lebron James,
some unusual freak specimen of
athleticism.
Just working five foot five,
five foot six Korean kid who just didn't
take no for an answer,
just didn't fucking take no for an
answer and figured out how to win the
national title while he was in fucking
medical school.
So whenever I was around people that
were,
you know,
they would say,
yeah,
I work hard.
I work too fucking hard.
I'm like,
Damn,
I'm not saying that you should work the
way those guys did because I don't think
you should.
I think that's too much.
I think there's a point of like,
you can overtrain and fighters
overtraining and workout too hard.
They come into the fight and they're
exhausted.
They just never recovered from the
training,
but they,
it's,
there's something admirable about the
ability to do what they did.
Like I don't think you should do it.
I don't think you should work that hard
because I think you could kill yourself.
I think everybody should get a taste of
it too.
Just know that Bro.
We're fucking soft.
We'll fucking soft.
We'll fucking soft what we do,
what we have to do.
We were talking about this before,
like when I went home with mercy and I
took it to a park when that Taulia and
fucking it was cold out.
My wife's like put the jacket on it.
Fuck no,
like the fucking jacket off and no
gloves either.
Let her climb and shit when I was
saying,
but my hands are freezing.
Look at what she's living out there with
soft.
You know,
we're just talking about that.
When you go on that ferry,
what do you think when that ferry stops
in February when it's 10 below in
Manhattan now.
And you know,
once that sun goes down it's fucking
brutal on that goddamn ferry and you
just make it work,
you know?
But we forget sometimes.
Listen,
man,
how do you fucking work?
Do you work?
When I first met you?
You just work smarter now.
You still put in the hours.
You just worked fucking smarter now.
When I met you used to do news radio and
then go to the fucking store and hang
with to a midnight,
which ain't no fucking joke.
My friend,
a couple Friday nights you would shoot
from 12 or 11 and you wouldn't get out
of news radio 10 and I don't know what
were making our news radio,
but the character was you still came
down and did your $15 spot and you
follow whoever and you were fucking
happy and,
and that's work ethic.
And you know how many times you talked
to a comedian,
they tell you things aren't going their
way and you say,
okay,
what have you been doing lately?
And they tell you and you're like,
are you fucking kidding me?
Are you fucking kidding me?
You know,
hard work goes into being a top notch
fucking comic.
What we just talked about,
Dave Chappelle being at the store.
How old is Ron White?
Did he follow media like the fucking
store?
There's a guy that's a millionaire.
You still fucking out there.
Every fucking nightmare.
It's why he's still good.
I look at these fucking kids and they
tell me,
Oh,
I'm tired.
Fucking tired.
Are you talking about man?
What fucking tyler you talking about the
first time I slept and I got no reason
why he was when I got locked up at 27.
Before that I was asleep.
Sleep three hours here on a couch in
between coke rocks and you know,
whatever,
sleep apnea machine,
there was no sleep apnea machine.
You just roughed it out.
Then you know,
but now people are wanting to do this
shit my life.
You got to put in the fucking hours.
You know,
I read the rolling stone article and
then showed you put in the hours Joe
Rogan and showed a lot.
You know,
I read that article and I'm like,
there's a beautiful article,
but there was many ways.
It didn't show the reasons why I loved
you and that's because of your work
ethic.
What?
I thought that when you moved to this
town,
because when I,
before I got here,
when you moved to this town,
you've got a TV show,
you stopped going to the store.
That's the impression I got.
He started working harder.
He started working on it,
man,
and that's why I got it from.
I finally realized,
you know what?
When you call down to the store,
you got to call him coast to coast.
You got to call him Sunday to Sunday and
you got to see what end.
If it's five nights a week,
I make times we leave the store at three
in the morning.
Man,
a lot.
You know it's
too.
You got to be willing to do those
nonpaid regular spots.
A lot of guys don't want to do is
You got to show up and wait and that's
how I got passed.
It's one of the main reasons why Mitzi
pass me two main reasons.
One,
the todd,
that dude,
the todd to todd,
he was on mtv who was one of Polish
friends.
Fucking great guy.
That guy was the best.
He was so nice and he.
He said,
I'm going to help you.
He goes,
you're really funny.
I'm going to sit next to Mitzi and I'm
going to laugh while you're onstage.
She told me,
and he goes,
and then one day he goes,
you're going to have a friend that you
want to get past.
You'll do the same thing.
Then that dude,
he,
um,
he held up like a serious problem and
had a serious mental problem,
had something wrong like physically with
his brain.
I don't remember what it was,
but it was so depressing to me because,
you know,
he showed me like,
like great comradery,
like,
you know,
the,
there's this comradery that you have
between fellow comics,
you know,
when you meet someone and they're coming
up,
like,
a lot of times you get on killed.
Tony,
get these young guys or young girls that
are coming up and you go,
hey,
you want to look at them like you're
really funny.
Like,
keep this up.
You can do this.
You're really funny.
And when you run into people that,
uh,
that connect,
you like that,
that hook you up like that.
Like he sat down next to Mitzi and it's
like,
Holy Shit just laughed it up.
Hammed it up.
The audience was laughing to submit to
you is like your past Camille year past
your now pay regular.
You can call in on Monday and that was
to me,
that was way bigger a deal than even
getting a TV show.
I was already on a TV show.
The TV show wasn't shit.
I was like,
I'm at the store.
I made it.
I'm a man.
I mean at Mecca.
That was a.
When we were open Mike,
that was the spot.
There was only one spot.
It was Mecca.
There was the catch,
a rising star in New York,
there was,
there was the comic strip in New York,
there was a,
there was all these clubs,
you know,
we all knew about the last stop in
Houston were Kennison came from.
We all knew about all these good spots.
You're supposed to go to xannies.
And Nashville was always a spot that
people would talk about,
but there was one Mecca.
You know,
it's funny because I talked about this
last week and this is something that
again wasn't an interview.
You did,
you know,
I was alright.
So I got funny in 2000 and then I got a
few more years before that and then I
got stuck and then you got stuck and
then I had a talk with somebody.
I had a talk with the black dude who
used to teach me one hop window.
As silly as this watch,
you don't want to knock on doors and
offshoot of Campo.
It's Hawaiian and this was the,
the,
the caskets.
What's his name?
The Costco's.
This is his father's first student.
Two black guys didn't put this in here,
here and here.
And he was saying that,
you know,
he does this thing and he goes,
I really,
I really started getting into martial
arts when I started teaching.
Yeah,
it was a complete different story and he
goes to trigger considered teaching
stands up and I was like fuck will
listen to me.
And I went home.
I thought about what he was saying to me
when we got to the store,
when I got to the store,
you know,
the first week I became a regular,
like the third night I got into a
fucking beef and I can name four times I
got into beef with those older jealousy
type comics.
Oh,
there was a bunch of saying I'm the one
time in the main room.
One time.
Oh Shit.
With the glass and the fucking original
room.
And there was no booze.
That guy broke the bottle.
Okay.
And I remember thinking that.
I remember then you had Charlie Hill who
would fucking pull you aside and go
swimming a man.
Uh,
I had belly laughs when you want to
stage,
hang in with it.
I know you're having a hard time here.
I know it's 1:35
in the morning and you're going up,
but it's gonna pay off for you.
Alan Stevens put me in fucking arliss
opposite James Coburn,
my idol.
We were just talking one day and he
goes,
you really liked James Coburn.
He scheduled to do all this.
I'm going to get you on dog.
You know,
wow,
you know what that does to your insides,
but you had scumbags,
and
I remember again,
I thought to myself,
I'm never going to ever do something
with this,
but if I ever do,
I'm going to be nice to these kids.
When I go to the store.
Now it's hugs with the young kids.
It's only encouragement I get in and out
of that.
I don't want to be that old pervert or
that old guy has given advice.
No,
no,
no.
I look in the.
I put my hand up and I say,
hey man,
no,
seriously.
Court the other day and the fucking.
I got a video,
a short video.
I put it up on Youtube where you're
talking about guns and roses.
Well,
I put it up on instagram.
There's a short video,
but when you were in the back,
but the back door holding court the
other night.
What's this camaraderie there?
Wasn't there when we came,
we came up.
So I made it.
And you don't want me to tear some.
It's made me a hundred percent better
comment.
Oh yeah.
Andre Being Tony,
uh,
those young guys,
you know,
you know how hard it is to be a door guy
and sit there and say hello to people in
your heart.
You want to do the same thing.
Guys,
I don't know how many times I went home
at night,
five years in content.
I cried myself to sleep.
I'd circle just relapsed,
lapsed member,
just last shore newspaper.
Backpage was all the clubs and I would
sit there and circle the clubs that I
was someday perform it to Seattle on the
ground.
Punchline of that land stopped.
Uh,
what was the other one?
What was the one where Ralphie felt
through the stage?
Yeah,
that's a true story that the stage was.
That club was legendary and Houston way
before the laptop.
The other,
whether Houston is another one that was
a fucking great name.
They were just clubs that had names,
like the insignia for Seattle was a
building,
the Seattle thing,
and it was timed and I'm like,
one day I'm gonna fucking play there.
And then after three minutes between the
cocaine and who the fuck I was deep down
inside,
I would just break down into tears and
go,
I'm never going to be good enough to
play those clubs.
Why would I say that to myself?
This is just a fucking pipe dream.
You know,
I'm not doing this shit.
So now to,
to,
to be up there with these guys.
The other night,
Joe Rogan,
I almost went on,
you know that Joey d as the old joke is
when Adam came over and said,
hey man,
you might've Chappelle goes up.
I said,
fuck no before you.
fuck no.
The old Joey deals.
We got fucking assaulted me.
Put Dave Chappelle.
Or like if I was somebody and I get my
car and leave years ago,
I was just like,
fuck you.
I was like,
no man.
Joe Rogan wouldn't leave.
He fucking sent it out and get up there
and chill.
I had such a fucking good time yelling
at Washington Chappelle like I learned
something,
man.
This thing was going through isn't about
podcast.
It isn't about nothing right now.
It's about,
you know,
I did the belly room last night.
Oh,
last one and say,
oh my God,
11 slash 15.
The dollar shop.
Yeah,
the Dallas show.
So that,
that,
that night I told you I couldn't do
yours,
but I can do the late one.
I left there feeling like I won the
academy award because they help these
young kids.
Like I made these young kids,
they hugged me,
they offered me weed,
you know,
that way it just sucks dick either.
I don't know.
It made me feel,
you know,
I didn't get.
I didn't take no money.
I didn't have $15.
It wasn't about that.
It was about doing something with these
young guys,
these young guys looking at you
differently and letting them know that,
hey man,
I ain't no better than you and someday
you're going to be way better than me.
I just watched this.
That you're a writer,
man.
You're a bad motherfucker.
That has made me a way better comic than
doing open mics and throw him because
now I see it from a different angle.
I love comedy.
I love watching it,
but I like watching the young guys at
the store at some fucking goofy fuck.
The whole attitude at that place feels
different.
Fuck yeah.
Way Better.
Right?
I think that's the Internet.
I think that's a big,
like the crop of guys that were coming
in the new crop over the last 10 years.
They're coming in for the right reasons.
I love you with all my heart,
but you're making it sound too good.
They got rid of the shit heads up there.
Okay.
Let's eliminate the internet.
Your sweetness.
That too.
And that's why I love you to death,
but let's be honest.
They got rid of the pure shit up there.
Your shit take came into that store and
then no longer there.
That's such shit.
They wouldn't even show that faces no
more because we called them out on it.
They turned something beautiful into
shit.
That was our fucking home.
That was our camaraderie.
That was my base.
That was everything to me,
man.
That was everything to me and one day
some fucking guy came in and some
fucking dumb comic started putting shit
in his fucking had and that motherfucker
don't go to the academy store no more.
They don't have to get out of the way.
Capullo suck my Dick.
That's what you get for being a control
your fucking life.
That's what you get.
You and Tommy can both suck my dick.
Merry Christmas and don't let me see you
at the more capital you fucking faggot.
Fuck a little punk ass bitch us under
the.
He threw all of us under the bus bro.
I found out about a ton of shit.
Fuck that motherfucker.
That's why I woke up one day and put it
on twitter.
You're a punt and that same matter how
to put them up in the main room and he
froze when he saw me.
Then he had to follow you and he was
calling the fucking club that tell him
not to put you up to wait until he got
there.
So when I found that out,
that was it.
Every time I see him at the store,
I just glare at them.
I'm going to get fucking.
What's his name,
the kid with the diabetes and how do you
know that?
For sure,
because I find that little fucking
things.
I know everything.
Cops soccer.
That's my job.
You don't see him down in Omar.
What's that expression?
You won't be sleeping.
Grow more.
When they go to Michael Corleone,
when he's making the thing.
What happened with Paulie and the fat
guy looks at me.
He goes,
you won't be seeing him normal,
and so he looks at me.
He goes,
okay.
He dips the bread and the sauce.
It was timing.
It was not.
He did a podcast with scheduled.
Did you listen to that psycho?
Fucking more or less the following cycle
deployments.
These fucking psychos have taken over
clubs and they clubs a bad name and then
you know you don't want to play that
club no more.
The comedy store is the Best Club in the
fucking universe.
There's Martians up there and Mars
planning a fucking visit just to go to
the comedy store because there's
something about it.
Even with those old guys,
when we were gone and there was
something about it,
we had each other bro.
We had each other.
We had a little thing.
Advice used to sit on the stairs and
cracked jokes and Barris and all those
guys.
Don Barris,
who does he fucking insult?
Nobody terraces the salt of the comedy
store after midnight.
There's just certain people that made
the comedy store that tells you what
Jamie was saying,
him and sold him.
Oh No,
no.
This is what really happened at the
store.
You put a bunch of shit.
Had fucking comics at a great place and
they poisoned for years and look at the
energy of the store.
Now the proof is in the pudding.
I'm not talking nothing on the line
here.
I'm not saying nothing out of line here.
Tommy's gone.
Cap has gone.
That's it.
The store is fucking beautiful.
You had a couple of guys that would sit
there and night throwing fucking
witchcraft on other good comics.
Fuck you.
I hope you bob.
I hope he doesn't make it so I can get a
stupid fallout set.
Zero fucking guy.
That old woman that was sitting there
and you get in a spot tonight,
man,
I wish Joe Rogan was my friend making
little remarks.
They're all gone.
It's over.
It's a positive comedy.
Fucking a.
even now I only go down three times a
week out of respect because I don't want
to be that old perfect guy sitting
around with the waitresses.
Twelve and a young comics.
I'm a comic.
I go get my work out.
I get my car and I leave.
I love to be able to hang out there for
two hours,
but I can't,
but it's the other night he was there.
We were giggling in the hallways.
Look at what happened here.
What did we start this comment?
That podcast with Chappelle goofing on.
Steve Run is easy and army and they all
had a great fucking time.
I guess everybody did nine slash 11
jokes to Steve runs easy.
Yeah,
it was brutal.
I wish I was there for that.
That is so fun.
It's good that he's taken it on the chin
like that.
He's a great guy and it happens and you
make mistakes and that's it.
But the point is,
we're fucking back.
We're back.
We're just.
We're better.
It's been better than ever that no shit.
Heads go up there.
I think shitheads go to go in and
there's a force now that's an anti
shithead fucking forest and it keeps
them out.
And that's the truth,
man.
That's the fucking truth.
Everybody's super cool up there.
Beyond that,
I was starting to get a mini anxiety
attack.
No edibles,
no nothing.
I was trying to get a mini anxiety
attack and as I was walking to the
stairs with the store,
I had connie and I looked.
I was sat at the Tiana with a hat on his
head.
He went to Hawaii.
It just gave me a different toy.
She's so nice.
She's such a nice person.
Every time you're around her,
she's like,
she's so just so kind to sweetheart,
you know,
don't cut what I set out when I got one
foot in the grave,
one of banana peel.
I don't give a fuck if somebody gets mad
at me
saying I'll call Yo Romero the fuck to
handle things for me now.
At this age.
Yeah,
I don't know,
when I see cap I say hi and I like them.
I get my hug.
I don't know what the fuck happens
behind the scenes,
but he's always nice to me.
Yeah,
same here.
Deep down inside.
He wishes you fucking get hit by a car.
I was watching last night,
last night I was watching Jimmy sugar do
magic tricks by the way.
And amazing magician.
He started as a magician.
Yeah,
he was a magician for years.
But uh,
like I,
he said that he also,
like,
he grew up starting it,
like doing comedy and magic,
like,
um,
like you kinda did also.
Did you know that he,
I only did it for a little while when I
was about eight.
Yeah.
I got a magic to set like a,
like a,
like for Christmas,
you know,
I could take,
teaches you how to do a few stupid
tricks.
And uh,
I did a little show on fisherman's
wharf.
I did it a couple of times.
Yeah,
I would just set up a box and then
people give me money and I'd go buy a
comic books.
But I did it one time and he's fucking
older kids fucked with me.
They of like gave me a hard time and uh,
got scared.
So I stopped doing it.
They just mocked me and were goofing on
me and I was like,
oh,
well I can do here.
That was like,
you know,
eight,
they're probably like young teenagers,
like 13 or something like that.
And they were mean.
So it was like,
all right,
I got scared and stopped doing it.
But it was a,
it was a weird thing too.
If nobody tells you that you can't
perform,
I would go there and I've watched these
people put on shows.
They had all kinds of different shows.
People just like do like street
performance.
So I was like,
I'll try this.
Fuck it.
I got my magic trick thing.
I had a hat,
little magic hat I a cape by myself,
eight.
That's a ridiculous set,
this fucking thing.
So terrible magic tricks,
awful at it.
But just banking on the fact that I was
cute helping people getting to with the
bowl and you put it in a little while
and I got,
I gave up,
couldn't do that shit.
It was tough.
But no,
I appreciate magic if it's his,
his Schubert's magic.
I mean he was bomb ass wasted.
So like I,
you could tell he was a little sloppy
but his magic was legit.
Like it was to the point where he had
four cards down there and we saw just
saw like one second ago what cards they
were and then he would turn them over
like in front of us going,
what the fuck?
It's impossible.
How'd you do that?
Like,
that's magic was legit.
Gabriel's Christmas party yet magician
there.
And the motherfucker came up to me.
I was eating,
by the way,
Lucille's barbecue in Long Beach.
They ain't fucking around though.
Those baby backwards was strongest.
Magician came and he showed me and Steve
Simone on the card.
You got to get up on that microphone.
He showed me and Steve Simone the card
and then he went like this and he did
something.
He told the lady over there,
take out your sleeve,
the car who was in a fucking sleep.
I,
I can't figure out what the fuck.
Fuck this.
She worked for him.
Just know that some fucking manager or
something stupid.
It was fucking crazy.
I don't know how the hell they do.
I don't know how they do it.
There's some craziness going on with
some of these magicians.
The sleight of hand and the way they.
They figured out how to set things up.
It's an art.
They don't tell you either.
They don't want to tell you.
We had a guy out of bed.
He bend a spoon in front of us.
I'm like,
I don't.
How the fuck is this guy doing this?
He's bending a spoon with like,
the air is like moving his finger around
it and the spoon starts to bend and
twist.
So I don't know how the fuck he's doing.
I don't know how he's doing it,
but he's,
he's letting you know,
like there's a trick to it.
I'm not going to tell you how I do it,
but it's just a trick and they've
figured out how to do it in a way that
your eyes don't catch.
Like there's a lot of the movements they
do when they're shuffling the deck and
moving cards around,
like your eyes just are not catching the
fluidity of their movement.
They get so good at it.
They can just hide the cards and you
don't even see it.
You're like,
okay,
wait,
what happened?
And then all of a sudden the cars on top
of his hat and you're like,
where the fuck?
Like you didn't.
You didn't see it.
You ever see a good pick pocket though?
Yeah.
It was only a video.
It's not impersonal.
When you play pool,
you ever see people pick pocket of
people for a living?
They bump into you.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
The whole family,
they do it in teams.
Have you watched that movie focus?
Yeah.
No,
not an academy award winning movie.
Anybody?
Sweet.
What is focused?
Which ones?
This is will smith and some blind shit
and he.
They run a scam of going like New
Orleans with the Super Bowl and how
would it work?
Goes down and they take everything.
They shoplift everything they fucking
thing and it goes around and he bet.
So let's say this fucking brilliant and
this is how it works guys.
They bumped into red band because my
friend's mom used to do it.
They bump into red band.
They take it,
they take just the credit cards,
they put the wallet back.
They have people at restaurants that
when they take your wallet,
when you know when you give your credit
card people,
they take it and they have a thing and
they go like this.
Then they sell it back to will smith.
So at the end of the day will Smith has
all these credit cards.
Now he starts buying stuff online.
Bam,
Bam man.
Then they get it.
Then they put it on Ebay and they
started a third of the cost and that's
how people get all that shit and it just
wasn't.
But forget about all that dog.
Do me a favor.
Watch the motherfucking movie for the
scene.
There's a scene,
they do what he bumped.
You ever seen that little Chinese guy
that plays gay on Svu?
He always comes in and the challenges.
Yeah.
The child suffers from a dementia.
He's spending a lot of show a lot of
movies to watch him in this movie.
One scene,
one scene.
Where do like a a gamble.
He's like the world's biggest gambler.
He bets on anything,
like he'll bet on anything like,
oh,
you got do some them and the whole
hustle,
but when this guy is doing it,
they play sympathy for the devil and you
think the movie's taking you somewhere
else.
You're like,
this motherfucking Chinese guy's the
devil because he's so smooth.
Joe.
He plays the obnoxious Asian that's
filthy.
Rich has a sports box and fucking three
hot young fucking Asians waiting from to
suck his dick.
Everybody's drinking dom or whatever.
Even better than dom and he's brash and
shit.
He's one of the races.
What is this name?
That motherfucker that motherfucker.
God Damn.
He was good in that movie.
What is his name of Jamie fighter's,
his name.
Look it.
Look at the young parts.
Hitler look at the young freak waiting
for him.
He had kind of waiting big old cigar,
bro.
This guy breaks it down so.
And then the movie ends up with after
that you just watched and fucking go
focus.
Huh?
Focus is in theaters now.
I like fucking got hooked on that scene.
I had to take it home and show my wife.
She was like,
Jesus,
he's fucking good.
Bd Wong.
That guy's been in everything.
Where are you from?
San Francisco.
He's 60.
No,
50 55.
He's 55.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
Crazy.
It's got that Asian gene too.
God Damn.
That looks so much better than regular
white people.
Better models at 55.
A 55 year old white guy alive.
It looks like Irish guy.
Jesus Christ.
That's like the polar opposite.
Chinese in Irish,
like who is Chinese?
It's not insult the fucking guy.
Yeah,
he's Chinese.
So he fits the motherfucking built.
Yeah.
Hear that guy is a bad motherfucker.
He's been in a lot of movies.
She's seen Tangerine.
Do you know anything about it?
No.
A Tangerine is a movie that it's all
filmed on iphones and I heard this,
I haven't seen them and I was unsure.
I didn't know what the,
like wish my friend.
This is like let's watch this and I
guess it's,
you know,
it's about a trans transsexuals and out
of nowhere Ian Edwards pops up out of
the movie in the movie and I'm just
like,
what the fuck?
Why is Ian in here?
And it's a really good movie because
what they did is they took real a
transsexual is from la that like hang
out at donut time at three in the
morning,
you know,
like in West Hollywood and then they mix
it with actors and so it's like,
it's got this like documentary type.
Wait,
is this real people?
Kind of.
It's interesting movie though.
So.
But Ian,
Ian Edwards isn't it fucked me up and
show me on of Santa Monica and
motherfucking highland.
I used to get stuck at that time though.
Used to a little weight watcher
meetings.
So you go to like I used to go to the
9:00,
wait watching me.
So I had to be there by 8:40.
I get stuck there.
Sunday mornings I looked at my left bro,
there'll be three hot motherfucking
bitches and that little freak of us like
maybe she's a hooker,
she'll suck my dick for folio,
Laos,
and also they look at you and that's.
You can tell that heavy duty trannies,
bro.
You just step on it.
Fucking gas bill is in the eye contact
the male transgender people make eye
contact with you.
Like to Transy transgender hookers.
They would make the make eye contact.
They look right at you.
Whereas like female hookers,
they'll kind of look in your direction,
but there's a transgender they use so
they don't have to look at it like they
might've had the operation or they might
never get the operation.
They still considered themselves a
woman,
but they have.
They have to out with a Dick.
They have tits with a Dick.
They still consider themselves a woman
and they get hard ons.
So figure that out.
It's like there's pictures of.
A lot of them have ones that are
completely erect.
Fully woman,
like a woman's ass,
woman's legs,
woman's waste,
women's breasts,
woman's face,
Dick hard deck.
So confusing.
It makes no sense.
Like what are you.
I mean you can be whatever you want,
but what are you,
what,
how does that work?
I mean,
I don't,
I'm not.
I'm not sure what's going on here.
You say she,
but yeah,
you have a Dick,
but you're allowed to.
You're just allowed to be whatever you
want.
If you're a girl that Dick,
then that's that.
It's just confusing.
It's crazy for me to even comprehend
like I don't fucking know what they even
fucking whatever what everybody wants to
do yet.
No,
it was very cool.
She was trying.
She did the whole operation.
She was a comic.
I told you.
But the problem was I head was too big.
So that's what you fuck up like that.
That if you make the transgender,
they cut your Dick and they do all the
other things and that your feelings
changed,
but your head remains the same.
So her balance was off.
I'm not kidding you.
I'm not lying to you.
I named was something that was too big
for her.
She was happy.
She was half Japanese.
Have some Rita,
Rita.
Oh Rita.
Oh,
whatever.
She was reading the whole whatever,
and she ended up dying because she would
fall back because the head was too
fucking big.
I remember that story.
The only one I really had,
you know,
remember the one we met in Vegas?
Yeah,
the one we met in Vegas where she kept
showing it to us.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
We didn't even know.
She was so tiny.
You would never suspect that.
She used to be a dude.
I don't know how old women are always at
the.
On the other day,
getting a picture with Santa Claus was
these young girls with tight pants on
and heels and I'm like,
Terry,
why these women taking pictures of Santa
Claus,
tyrese women.
Those are 15 year old fucking girls that
were women and I don't know.
I couldn't fucking tell.
I can't tell man.
Jared said the same thing.
Who Do you think that?
I mean,
do we just not remember it right?
Or do girls look different now when
they're 15 and they didn't?
We're 15.
Are you sure though?
Because they're now showing site boob
and like,
like at young ages they didn't see that
girl.
Some girls had bodies.
Even back then,
like you remember in high school girls
had boobs.
Girl.
I mean there was,
there was girls that were 15 that had
boobs for sure,
but they were also wearing underwear and
using a Hitachi's and looking at porn,
you know,
they were like art.
When we
grew up here,
girls were like,
if they just look different physically.
That's what I'm saying.
Like do the,
are they,
are they more mature early?
Do they look like women earlier?
Is that true?
Or is it just the way they're dressing
confused?
I can't lie to you,
man.
Listen,
when I was 18 I didn't dig 18 year old
women,
so when I was 27 I didn't think young
they just make me nervous.
They make me physically now.
I just started getting comfortable.
The reason why I go on the back of the
ship by the waitresses is because I
always feel embarrassed.
I want everybody's eyes on me.
I don't want no misunderstandings.
That fucking I,
you know what I'm saying?
Right.
I hate when I always listened when I was
20 and I go to a bar and I was slowing
and having a good time.
I'd see a 30 year old want the ball.
I get fucking pissed.
Like little punk ass bitch at a ball.
You're too old guy gone,
you know,
nevermind a 40 or 50 year old.
My blood pressure really goes up.
When I was like fucking 20th.
I saw a 50 year old dancing on a disco.
Oh my fucking.
Why is he here?
Why?
Why I couldn't figure it out.
That stayed with me for the rest of my
life.
So when I got to be 27,
I already felt out of place in most
places.
Like I was like,
these people looking at me like I made
to do something bad.
Nevermind now.
And you've got these young comics like
Joey and they'd come and hug you and I'm
fucking lost.
I'm like,
listen,
I can't do it.
I just feel weird.
I feel too old at the store.
I feel old at the store.
Do you know that?
Like a shame.
So I just go,
that's so weird.
I sit on the freezer.
I don't bother nobody.
Why did you feel like that?
I feel like,
oh my God.
Because I was about to sit that shit
when I was 20.
Yeah,
but it's a different thing now.
Like I feel like when you go there,
it's just a nice group of people that we
all know.
We all love waitstaff.
Fucking the bartenders.
I comics those people at all my home.
Why would you feel like you're too old
to hang around with?
Like sometimes I'm driving.
The waitresses will come out and go,
can you give me a ride up the hill?
Because they make the witches puddle the
way park all the way up and help you
crest hill all the way up.
They're waitresses and I walked down and
they walked down and I'll drive the
waitress up there who were both hands on
the steering wheel.
Like looking straight ahead.
Like when they're like,
good night.
I'm like,
what can you tell a waitress?
I'm not going to give you a ride home,
feel like a fucking idiot,
but sometimes I get leaving.
Joey,
can you give me a ride up the hill?
And you're like,
right.
And the whole that all that stuff broke
bothers me.
Like I can't.
I just can't.
Last night on the way back from fucking
mentor,
I can't lie to you this Christmas.
Right?
I said maybe there's a strip club.
I haven't been to a strip club in 20
fucking years with Eddie.
Last time I went to a strip club was
with Eddie when we went down at his
place.
What was that?
Two?
Oh,
one.
Yeah,
probably the housing.
That's the last I've been in the script,
but I'm a fucking animal of a man.
I don't even go to strip clubs last
night,
so maybe I should goes to the Strip
club,
but it's between the Strip club,
hungry and getting.
I went and got gas
and I went home and had a piece of
fucking cheese and I went to bed.
I am scared of strip clubs that you're
fine,
but I go on the Strip club,
but I don't know what will.
Hold on.
What do you.
What are you scared of?
I don't know Joe.
I'm just scared,
man.
Crazy women that I'm scared of.
Crazy fucking window man.
Are you scared that you would like them?
I like everybody.
I love women.
When you get the,
you know,
when you get to be 50,
you look at like 30 year olds and go,
Jesus Christ,
just a baby.
Yeah.
That's just a fucking baby.
Like she doesn't even know how good the
pussy is right now.
She has no fucking idea.
You know?
It's just so weird.
So I don't know what a 14 year old looks
like.
We're supposed to look like.
I don't remember.
That's the problem.
Don't accurately remember what it looked
like when I was 14 compared to what they
look like today.
I'm pretty sure their bodies were
exactly the same.
We're just seeing more of it because
we're seeing sluts.
They look like porn stars nowadays.
You know,
at 14 where that wasn't the case back
then.
It was,
you know.
Yeah,
it seems like there's definitely an
influence where they're like the pop
culture,
like the Nicki Minaj.
Stick your ass out look and all the
young.
The young one definitely.
It took a dash,
a family for sure.
Candle.
That's what she'd done that every day
she's on my yahoo page.
She said,
why is she on my yahoo page every day
with some young black,
skinny kid kenvil and what's the other?
It's all confusing.
It's all the whole thing.
There's A.
There's a gang of them.
Kylie,
let me tell you something.
I ain't mad at the fucking system no
more.
I ain't mad at that fucking dirty whore.
I ain't mad at that bitch no more.
You know what man?
She picked the loop.
She pitched him.
I read the article by her fucking hot
the other day.
She was making a million dollars an hour
or something like that.
I can't be mad at her man.
She'd made it.
That's the American dream.
How can I be mad at that?
She found her niche.
She showed her pussy one time.
She hasn't showed us anymore.
It's like she shows up once every three
weeks.
She made a tape and she found a window.
A little fucking window though.
I liked it.
Do I want to hang out with her and Kanye
fucking north,
whatever.
No,
I with those people.
Well,
let's give credit where credit is due,
man.
Well,
she's the best ever at reality TV.
That family is the best ever.
At reality TV,
they figured out how to corner the
market to lock it down.
Every scandal makes the show better.
Like just some people that did reality
TV and they got pretty famous like John
and kate plus eight.
Justin,
what about one chick test?
A black boyfriend and he fucked the
transvestite and they got back together.
She's one of the girls or something like
that,
but there's a bunch of them,
but the John and kate plus eight,
they were giant.
There was a giant show.
It was like all over the news.
It was a Christian magazines.
Yeah.
They had artificial intimidation and she
had fucking six babies inside of her.
She was insane.
Well,
they broke up and they.
They didn't survive the scandal,
but these people,
doesn't matter what happens,
it doesn't matter who they married,
it doesn't matter who gets divorced,
it doesn't matter who decides they're a
woman,
doesn't matter who decides there a man
doesn't matter,
just like the show keeps going.
They figured out a way that it's the
right frequency of editing,
of like,
like real relatable drama and people
that are just,
you know,
they look good and they squeeze it all
together in this crazy semi fake show or
it's not really a reality show.
You can call it a reality show,
but they set up every scenario.
It's obvious.
So it's almost like semi scripted.
So this is weird show and these people,
they're just famous for being famous.
She wakes up in the morning and she
looks sort of thing and she'll ask like,
who's trending on what?
Who's trending?
Ronda Rousey watch this,
but within five minutes she's trying to.
Number one,
she goes to trend number one on google.
If you're trending number one on Google,
you're selling shit.
She's selling blouses and had dudes and
I wax remover and fucking,
you know,
whatever the fuck those are.
Many of us have some fucking heavy duty
pussy.
Those Armenio's no least checks.
You got to shave that pussy three times
with a double edged razor and shit.
She got our meeting Stan Hope.
Describe Asian pussy hair.
Something like rat whiskers.
Would it be.
I forget how you described it.
I'm the fucking it up and it's funny.
You don't think there's anything that
could kill that,
that whole thing like.
I mean cause.
But you would never have thought like
something can take down cosby.
You think double cosby could take down.
Occurred dashing is anything that mean
double cosmic?
What are you saying?
Something that is so bad that could
kill.
That's the worst.
It's hard to think.
You'd have to be like w w what he did is
almost like murder.
Yeah.
You know,
I mean you'd have to come in,
right?
No,
not necessarily.
Why they haven't done anything wrong.
Like you think of what they've done.
You can hate this show for sucking.
You could say it's boring and mindless.
But.
So what?
So as most shit that's on tv,
I've never watched it.
I think they set up tomorrow and they
said that they sent the bad plus that he
went in there.
I think he couldn't handle the pressure.
Hola ma?
Yeah,
they freak out.
He's like,
you went after a photographer,
mother-in-law cutting his deal and she
got laker tickets.
Season tickets for the rest of her life.
Jesus Christ.
That's the deal.
She cut though.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
It's like,
it ain't a good show,
you know?
It's not something I want to spend my
time watching.
But why?
Why you so mad?
I liked it 10 times on the road.
It's not entertaining and she doesn't
amuse.
But here's my question.
Why is it like more offensive when
something's not entertaining and it's
quote unquote reality,
like semi.
Why does that bother us?
Whereas a show where you're making shit
up entirely,
it's totally scripted and it sucks.
Doesn't bother you that there's a lot of
shows that suck.
There's a lot of like,
our dramas are fucking terrible.
He tried to watch and be like,
oh my God,
what is this shit?
But he doesn't offend you,
it doesn't get you angry.
Like he will see that show,
like all the reality air quotes about
it,
although the nonsense and you're like,
why isn't anybody watching this?
This is crazy.
So they get mad.
They get mad at that show,
but they don't get mad at scripted
shows.
It's very strange just because those
people are being themselves.
But.
So what?
And said they're real people.
I know Sorta,
but they're not.
You know,
it's all characatures.
It's real people doing fake shit.
Yeah.
But it's like,
who cares?
Like why do we care?
But we do get angry.
You get upset because they're not doing
anything special.
It's not like,
sir,
you should go see Cirque du Soleil and
they're doing handstands with one hand
and there got someone standing on their
feet doing a handstand on this guy and
it was like three people and they're
stacked and they all look shredded.
Like superheroes,
like Holy Shit.
He watched them flip through the air and
catch each other and do all that crazy
shit.
It's undeniable that they put a crazy
amount of work into achieving this.
When you watch these people just be
themselves and make more money than
anybody who's ever lived.
People don't see
seem to care anymore.
Like I mean look at the.
You have all the youtube stars.
They're,
they're just mindless people talking
that half of the time they don't have
any talent.
They're just like pretty much rehab,
hashing people's jokes or ideas and
thoughts and making tons of money and
youtube branding them as their youtube
stars,
but like that's really popular and
that's kind of like a Kurdish
Kardashian.
It's not like it's,
it's,
it's fake shit.
People doing fake shit.
No.
How long has that show been on TV?
Because I'm on going on forever.
It's been around forever.
They're going to go back to the history.
They're going to find out that it was
never not on the air.
That is actually like they used to do it
by fire and what is shadow shows back in
the fucking 16 hundreds to make a year.
Who knows?
Hundreds of millions of dollars
probably.
Jamie knows for sure,
but what my point is like.
I think it's a demonic show and it's
probably been here since the beginning
of time and we just pretend we get
sucked into a trance.
I just started like a few years ago.
Right?
We don't remember.
It's one of those like,
like twilight zone episodes will realize
one day it's always been here.
Boy,
that show's always been here and you
start remembering yourself as a child,
waking up,
looking at your crib and keeping up with
the Kardashians on TV.
It doesn't even make any sense because
from a totally different era,
but you remember it throw your whole
life when no one was around.
Keeping up with the Kardashians was on
some fucking strange phantom channel out
there.
You just had to figure out how to tune
it in.
It's always been there.
Joey always been.
It seems like that,
doesn't it?
No,
no,
I'm high as fuck.
I can't believe that.
Even the guy with the $52 million.
Oh Jesus Christ has a lot of money.
She looks odd.
That is going on.
You look different.
Um,
she still looks beautiful.
Still Beautiful,
gorgeous woman.
No doubt about it.
She's got damn beautiful.
Look at her face,
beautiful classic face structure,
Beautiful Lips,
beautiful eyes,
but she looked odd,
but picks the.
Let's just stop.
We don't need to stare at this poor
girl.
I was telling you about.
Why is,
why is it so offensive?
It is though.
What's to love her,
but she doesn't do anything wrong.
No,
she's not.
She's like,
I say 100 times more stupid shit than
she does.
She's like,
she seems like a nice person.
She.
Kanye is awesome.
I like Kanye.
He says some stupid shit,
but who?
What,
what?
Fucking super talented young uber
celebrity doesn't say stupid shit man.
That guy's driven like he's.
He's like,
there's certain types of driven,
like superstar type driven.
That's what that guy is.
He's got that superstar type drive.
Those guys,
they always have problems with.
People are always mad at someone always
math oppressed,
mad at this guy or that guy.
They're just these bundles of fury and
inspiration and ideas and they just
don't always manage it correctly and
that's why he came out with that song
about assholes and douchebags.
Remember that song that he came out with
after he did the Taylor swift thing?
Let's hear it for the assholes.
Jamie knows he has his phone rang and
talk.
You call them right now.
We'll hear it if I tell you guys.
I don't know.
One Kanye,
so.
Oh yeah,
he's a gold digger.
You know that gold digger.
So that's Jamie Kennedy.
What's his name?
No,
that's a great fucking song.
I know that one,
but nothing else like black Jesus.
Oh,
let me tell you this before I forget.
Jamie Foxx,
you have to listen to Jamie Fox on the
Tim Ferriss podcast.
Holy Shit.
Tim ferriss got together with Jamie Foxx
and did some epic,
crazy long podcast for Jamie Foxx.
Breakdown breaks down is showbiz
experiences.
It's fucking amazing.
Jamie Foxx is one of the baddest
motherfuckers of all time.
When you hear just how he organizes
parties,
he would get the parties goes,
you know what,
how we do it?
We just do it with just everybody's
cool.
That's all I want.
And No,
no,
no assholes.
No one's a dick.
I call people up.
No haters.
Everybody's cool.
You're cool.
He's cool.
Everybody's cool,
we'll get some bomb ass bitches.
We got some girls that are hot,
but they're not stuck up.
They'd friendly,
not too slutty,
just right there,
the perfect mix and get this perfect man
and he's talking about all these artists
that he has come over and he had Kanye
West come over and he asked Kanye West
to freestyle and Kanye West freestyled
in front of everybody and the alleys.
Other guys like,
man,
I've been hearing about you.
He's talking about all these different,
like at the time up and coming.
People like drake who became like these
big,
huge superstars,
some a fucking amazing podcast.
Jane.
I've always thought Jamie Foxx is
insanely talented.
Like if you see the way sings,
I see the way he acts like that red
or the um,
uh,
Ray Charles movie.
God Damn God damn.
He's good.
He's amazing,
right?
But,
and,
and on top of that,
he's stand up comic.
But when you hear him talk,
you realize,
Oh dude,
this guy is as a master life.
He's figured out how to live life.
You want this inside the active
students?
No,
no.
Um,
I want to hear it though.
His Grandmother,
his grandmother raised him,
his grandma used to make them put parent
on everyday.
Wow.
And his grandmother just,
he,
he took every big movie experience that
he had and related to his grandmother,
the football movie.
His grandmother raised him,
right.
And his,
the panel one was the story,
but the music and how he got Ray
Charles,
this is grandma used to make them play
the piano,
just,
you know.
And then this thing at the store,
he changed his name to Jamie Foxx.
So they thought he was like or whatever.
And they sign up at the factory.
He changed his name to Jamie Foxx
because girls get on stage more than
guys did because it wasn't that many of
them,
you know.
So yes.
Smart.
You see these guys that come and go and
I read them,
I can't stand when I see these people
though the Shams and all of a sudden the
part of this social thing and they're
fucking terrible.
But then you get some guy came to put
the work in.
I heard that when he was on in living
color,
he still couldn't get an agent when he
was doing that fucking check,
whatever.
He couldn't get an agent like nobody
would represent them.
Shit like that.
That's crazy.
That's fucking crazy to me.
But you know what man?
Cream always rises to the top.
He would play a drag queen,
right?
Yeah.
He played up whatever it.
Was it a drag queen or is a woman who's
playing to name something like that.
It a drag queen or a woman.
What's that name is Martin Lawrence,
but.
Oh,
okay.
You're right.
She mania.
Fonda was supposed to be a woman.
Just implied he was corrected to
interpretation.
He's great now.
Tom Cruise,
he's great and everything,
but Tom Cruise,
to me it's doing the Mike Tyson movie
right now.
I don't know.
Is He?
Have you ever dressed up as a woman,
Joe?
Oh yeah.
Really?
For sure.
Yeah.
Did it in a public access show on TV in
1988?
We were like open microphone.
I mean this dude,
Todd Parker and a couple other guys is
Larry.
I'm Larry Russ.
Bucci.
We've,
when we first started out doing standup,
we were all open micros together and uh,
there is Wanda,
Wanda,
the massage therapists.
The lips is a lariat.
Jamie Foxx is a bad motherfucker dude.
Anyway,
we did this.
We found out that you could get like
time on cable access shows.
They just like let you use cable access
and you could,
you could make your own television show.
So we put together these horrible
sketches and in one of them I played a
woman.
I had a dress on and a wig and I went to
fucking sketch was,
but I had to come in and sweep the guy
off his feet and run away with them.
So stupid.
Like I don't remember what it was,
but I wore a dress that I find.
I have a picture of you,
joey dressed up as a woman,
dressed me up like a girl before.
I've never done it.
I'm scared.
Don't be scared.
I make my mega hot chick.
You might look at yourself in the mirror
and you just fucking run with this Eddie
izzard.
You don't even have to address it.
Like Eddie Izzard.
He'd go on stage dressed up like a woman
and not say a word too hot.
No,
I can't.
I can't dress up like a woman bothers my
core Spanish.
You had drives me fucking nuts.
I never met this small.
I never got the joke like after I see
you with the dress on.
Okay,
now I've got to stand like this.
Like a fucking asshole.
That's right.
It's like if you go to a football game
with a Jersey on and your team loses,
you got to get back on the train with
that stupid fucking shirt on.
That's a long train ride home.
You're had dumped flopped.
I've always been one of those guys
wearing those jerseys.
You Jack off.
Your team loses.
There you are.
The train like a fucking mobile there.
That's hilarious.
I can't commit.
I ain't got that fucking commitment.
Fuck you.
I can't do it.
That's why.
That's the dress thing like I've been to
shows.
Now we want you to dress up like a doll.
It's not going to work.
Who Was it?
Was it Dave Chappelle that was saying
that there's certain thing that happens
to black actors,
like black Comedians,
black actors,
they get to a certain level of
popularity and then they start putting
them in movies where they make them wear
dresses and it's so true.
Once,
once he said it,
I started looking into it.
Julie Newmar,
right?
Where Wesley snipes shredded is that
chick.
He's fucking yoked and shredded.
He's a chick,
right?
There's a other.
There's a gang of those movies.
The Martin Lawrence movies.
Eddie Murphy played his mom,
right?
He played with.
He's played his grandma who played all
of my head.
All of them,
right?
He's played women.
He's done women before and it just goes
back through like television history.
They would take like famous black
comedians and it would make them play
women.
They would play women in movies there.
There's Wesley Snipes and uh,
what's his face?
The dude on the left.
And Patrick Swayze,
John Leguizamo.
And Patrick swayze.
Patrick swayze movie.
I forgot all about the day by mistake.
I caught it.
How fucking good is that movie?
That movie called revenge with Anthony
Quinn.
And the fucking body.
God,
what's his name?
Kevin Costner.
Oh,
I remember that movie.
And that beautiful woman.
Who is that woman to crazy one.
Crazy one that he cheated on.
Yeah.
Then fucking Quinn put a fucking beat on
him.
But go to revenge.
The beaten that Anthony Quinn puts on.
What's his fucking name?
But that's a good movie.
Then it has a good wave.
Gets out of the hospital or what's his
name?
Gets out of the hospital.
He teams up with Leguizamo and they go.
She makes her a hooker member.
He cuts her face.
He goes,
you want to get fucked?
I'm going to send you to a place where
you get fucked every day.
And he fucking slices of face.
Then they throw it to the hooker house
and they just come in drug or and fuck
her all day long.
And then fucking what's his name has to
come and save.
I forgot all about that fire.
Remember,
look at Anthony Quinn.
How bad ass he was at 70.
He was still spitting out kids in
Mexico.
It's 70.
What's her name?
Uh,
I forget the girl,
but now the dudes beating up.
Kevin Costner Stole Madeline stope.
Oh yeah,
it was madeline stowe.
They beat the shit out of Kevin Costner.
Oh,
so dark movie.
This is a really fucked up.
And Anthony Quinn,
you know his shit.
That motherfucker was a real actor.
I do as a Mexican that played everything
in cowboy.
A gangster.
Yeah.
Good movie though.
Anthony Quinn did a lot of good movies
from Anthony Quinn did 100 times across
110th street.
He did some of our pool.
Didn't he play a pool and somebody he
played somebody or.
No,
no,
no.
Who was the old guy in the hustler?
Jackie gleason?
No,
the other guy.
The guy that was running the game,
like,
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
God Damn bad ass motherfucker.
George,
c Dot Scott.
Scott,
George C dot Scott was Bert.
This fuck.
These guys were sabotaged that watched.
I watched them more with George C dot
Scott was daughters are runaway and she
becomes a strength finder.
Morningstar,
right.
It was a points daunting.
Bing watching some fucked up shit.
Were you on the road and on the road you
bumped into some good fucking mood
hardcore member.
That's what it was called.
The George.
She's Caitlyn hardcore.
That's what does that Anthony Quinn
playing pool.
Oh really?
Huh?
Never heard of it.
Who?
He was a pool hustler.
It comes up on wikipedia.
Oh,
okay.
I was just maybe a scene where he plays
pool pool was just a giant pastime back
then.
You know what the turn of the century
is?
A thousand pool halls in New York City.
The 19th century,
like between like 1900 from the 1800.
Eighteenth Century.
Yeah.
I the fucking pool halls and in New York
City from the 19th to the 20th when it
turned to the 19 hundreds to be the
beginning of the century,
apparently there was a thousand pool
halls.
It was so common,
like everybody played pool.
There was no TV.
Right?
There's no live music and go see live
music.
There's no records or records.
I mean,
I guess they had phonographs maybe a few
people had them,
but bachelor's especially like young men
would go and they would hang out with
these pool halls.
It was like,
um,
that was there,
the lifestyle choice for the men who
didn't go for the married with kids
thing.
He didn't go for the marriage,
but there's like these people that felt
like they were on the outside and they
will all get together in these pool
halls and they would just do what men
wanted to really do.
They want to hang out late and drink and
gamble and do drugs and play cards.
And that's what these places always
worked for.
These guys,
it's like a refuge from the regular
life.
Like you can exist.
It might not be as profitable.
You might,
but at least it will be fun.
So they all just get together.
And then there was like the bachelor
lifestyle of the early 20th century.
Crazy.
I gotta ask you something.
Are you covering next week?
Fight or know which one's next?
Degas.
Yeah.
The one,
the second Robbie lawler versus fuck.
He was getting the show.
And you were like,
no,
I'm not doing a show.
Okay.
Not doing a comedy show.
I T I can't do the caught theater that
much.
It's a giant place.
I just,
we just sold it out like two weeks ago.
I can't to take time off.
Okay.
No I didn't.
That's why I asked you.
I never even mentioned they want to do
it all the time,
but I don't think I need.
A lot of the people are transient,
but a lot of these people are the same
people that keep coming over and over
again.
Like Vegas is a such a hotspot now for
standup and for,
for fights rather,
you know,
people coming from everywhere.
So I feel like I gotta come up with at
least some new material I would even go
because when they asked you to sound too
enthusiastic about something,
like maybe he's not even going into the
fight.
And I'm like,
no,
listen,
if you didn't talk to me about the
fight,
if he didn't think I was a car,
I'll tell you right now.
It's a good card.
But uh,
the big fight of course is Carlos condit
versus Robbie lawler.
And one of the things is,
makes that flight so interesting is that
Robbie lawler is not known to take
people down.
It's like he's taken out so few people
in his life.
I don't think,
I can't think of a single submission
that he's attempted.
I mean,
I'm sure he has attempted to submission.
I just can't recall one because all
Robbie lawler's fight Robbie lawler
trying to knock you into another
dimension until the fights go.
The fights go ding.
Here he comes.
Good luck,
you know.
But the difference between Robbie and
all the guys that Carlos has had
problems with in the past is that those
guys kept taking Carlos down.
Now I don't know if Robbie will
incorporate that kind of strategy just
because he knows it's been effective in
the past.
GSP had good effect with Johny Hendricks
had a good result with it.
And the guys who managed to take Carlos
down and smother him.
Those are guys who have some pretty good
success.
Robbie lawler has good.
Success is just smashing.
He's just a fucking awesome striking
machine.
And such a tough guy.
He just,
his mentality like the bulldog in him as
a 100 percent,
that guy has zero quit,
but neither does conduct.
We conduct,
got a little bit more sneaky ways to
win.
Like he's really good at submission.
It's very good off of his back.
Very good at capitalizing on moments.
And he also,
he can kick box too.
And he's real slick.
He throws all kinds of crazy shit.
Step in elbows.
He does a lot of shit that you don't
predict.
Fucking flying knees last time.
Think about it like he's a bad
motherfucker.
I love.
I'm not saying that college.
And so I went,
but I tell you what I liked the most
about Carlos condit.
This corner,
I don't really know who rob is trained
is our data att,
but they have an excellent game plan
when you fight for winkle,
John,
whatever.
You go in there with such a great.
And I didn't see it till the Holly Holm
fight.
That's what I learned with game is to
uh,
Holly Holm fight.
Then I put together Jim John Jones
fights and I basically thought the most
about him against Diaz,
how he fought the as they always have a
great game plan winkle John Smith,
and it's how good you stick to it and
against Diaz.
This motherfucker stuck through it.
That's why you snuck out that victory.
You know,
if he sticks to the game plan,
whatever.
They always have a great game and they
review it and review it and review it
and review it and review it.
That's why Holly Holm did what she did.
Even when Rhonda went to Shit on her
that she would usually get.
They knew her instincts.
They knew what A.
I forget what that word is.
They knew what she was going to do and
they worked at and drilled and drilled
it.
She kept her hips low.
All those little things.
I really don't know.
I just saw a.
The guy from George St Pierre Camp break
down the video and I thought about it as
a hobby and I go,
you know why she did that?
Because they went over it and they had a
game plan and they knew what her
tendency was going to be and they worked
on the anti tendency and I thought back
to his fight and I thought back to like
maybe three or fucking John,
Jim,
John Jones,
Jim Jones,
John Jones fights and I said that.
That's what I like about that camp.
I've always liked that they really.
And that's why I'm not saying I like
them,
but I'm saying in this particular file,
I'm just saying it's a very competitive
fight.
No,
no,
no.
It's a great competitive fire.
I would think.
The real questions are,
is Robbie gonna follow that game plan or
is he going to try to take Carlos down
if he decides to try to take Carlos down
just to fuck with them,
just to mix it up.
It could be very interesting if they
both just stand up.
It's going to be chaos.
It will be a crazy war I lost.
Give me.
Oh,
check this guy's fucking cry.
Guys have crazy power,
but I'm just.
I'm.
I wonder who's going to try to do
something sneaky because Robbie,
he's like not a sneaky fighter.
He's super skillful,
very tough,
just aggressive,
but you know what's coming.
Whereas guys will mix things up and do
things different and George St Pierre is
a perfect example.
He always had like a game plan.
It was always real sneaky mixing things
up.
It was one of the most effective aspects
of his game.
He didn't know if it's going to take you
down or stand with you so you're always
tense and always worried about what's
coming.
And then he would shoot and be.
You'd be on your back and you've eaten
elbow sandwiches.
So Robert is not like that.
Robbie is like a straightforward come
towards you.
Smart.
Smart with his movement and his angles.
Very hard to take down but determined to
stand and smash it so Carlos won't have
to worry.
Fucking hits hard though.
Fucking truck dogs.
That's a big part.
Well,
he's got so much confidence in his
power.
You know,
if you watched that fight with Melvin
manhoef,
he's getting his ass kicked.
Okay.
Melvin manhoef is kicking the shit out
of his legs,
and Robbie lawler uncorked with all
fucking bomb,
one punch,
one haymaker on the jaw,
and Melvin's whole body stiffens up like
he got tasered.
He falls to the ground and Robbie
smashes him again when he's down and
it's just one of the most brutal one
shot,
knockout power,
not power punches in all of MMA and
he's.
He's always trying to do that.
Every punch is trying to do.
It's just trying to just
knock you in another dimension and he
knows he can do it.
He's just got to hit you.
Just write and conduct can do it too.
Man.
Conduct knocks.
Dude's dead.
He wants to have the Dan Hardee fight.
When he caught damn nasty,
left hook or the stun gun fight that
flying knee to the face or the Tiago
Alvarez fight,
he smashed in with that step in elbow.
He's real tricky.
He's got a bunch of different ways to
win.
He's tall,
he's long and it's real good off of his
back.
Real sneaky off of his back.
Real good at attacking.
When he goes to the ground,
he's caught guys and arm bars and
triangles.
There's no joke,
man.
It's no joke.
It's an interesting fight.
It's real interesting.
If Robbie decides to just only stand
with them because of Cabo,
doesn't have to worry about the take
down as much you get to see a lot more
looseness to is,
uh,
striking game.
It's going to be an easy fight,
man.
I'm going to ask you something.
Are you going to go see this movie?
Concussion?
Fuck you.
You really want to see.
I think I'm going to want to say that.
You know,
where the big fight on that card is.
Here's the fact that no one's talking
about Lorenz Larkin versus Albert to
off.
Dude,
are you fucking kidding me?
That these guys are killers.
This is probably one of the most
underrated fights in the 170 pound
division right now.
This is a fight that everybody should be
talking about and if these guys had had
like more like a on air fights,
like especially Larkin at one 70 and two
minute off,
just fought our bore Allen Joe Ban and
just starched him.
He is nasty.
His fucking striking is so fluid and
loose.
His boxing his hands and Larkin is a
beast to.
That's a sick fight to really good
fight.
That's a fight that people should be
talking about.
Like a lot of people should be talking
about this right now and for whatever
reason it's just flown totally under the
radar.
Like I almost forgot it was even on the
car.
This car is just a good car.
It's a great card,
but nobody's really.
I think the holidays,
they're confused.
I don't know what it is.
Nobody's really saying,
well this is the,
here's another good fight.
Brand down or take a or take us Gracie
Jujitsu,
black belt and uh,
he's coming off a suspension for the
ped.
He to,
for what these usually to juice you had
a little bit of the steroids and the
system.
No,
this gave him a little suspension.
This Donald is Rory Macdonald.
Like,
oh,
Michael Mcdonald returns.
That's exciting.
He's been off for a long time.
A kid's been on for more than a year.
I believe he's fucking good.
That kid's good.
He's got nasty power in his hands too.
And he looks like a small,
slightly built guy.
But Mike,
God,
here.
It's hard.
But that Diego Brandao and um,
uh,
Brian Ortega fight.
That's a good fight.
I split real good fight.
I don't know why Ortega was doing
anything when you might have had an
injury is trying to recover from.
So a lot of these guys,
they get caught with steroids and what
it is is um,
well a lot of these guys are just doing
steroids,
but some of these guys,
they get injured and they try to get
back in there.
So they take a chance to,
just a hope.
I don't get tested.
I'm going to try this for six weeks.
It'll be out of my system in six weeks,
but will ramp up my recovery by 30
percent or more.
And so they take,
they take the chance.
I'm not giving them any excuses.
I don't know if that was the case with
him,
but I just want to say with some people
that is definitely the case.
Steroids.
Steroids are real tricky man because for
the longest time they just been able to
use them whenever anything was injured,
you know,
either you used it all the time,
like some guys certainly did or you used
it when you had injuries,
which is like a very reasonable
approach,
but you know,
we're just fine,
you know,
glace and Tbl just failed to tests.
Yeah.
One for.
I don't know what it was,
but one was for epo and if you look at
gleason bow,
that guy might have the second best body
in the UFC next to fucking next to a
Yoel Romero like glazing is ridiculously
shredded,
you know,
it's just the culture of people using
banned substances.
They've been doing it for a long time.
I think these guys,
the UFC hired,
they're not fucking.
No really.
They're not fucking around.
They're gonna wake you up at 6:30
in the morning,
pee in the cup.
Joey Diaz like,
well at p now.
I can't show.
You can wait.
They don't leave your side.
They stay with you.
They Watch you pee,
they collect your shit and they do it a
couple times.
They do it randomly.
Show up whenever they want.
If they have suspicions like of
Novitsky,
sus suspect.
Something's wrong.
He thinks you're cheating.
They'll just be up your ass with scope.
Are they?
Are they testing you in competition mode
or off season?
They doing everything.
They do everything.
October.
It doesn't matter right now.
It might show up.
Well that's what happened with vandelay.
Vandelay did not have a fight scheduled
and they just showed up to test him and
he was like,
what?
And he just ran out the door,
but come trump vandelay has become
Donald Trump of Brazil.
He just says who's he going to smack in
the face yesterday?
Yeah.
Yes.
It's Kinda sad what Jesus is asked every
fucking month.
He says terrible for vandelay.
I have a very conflicted about this.
I feel terrible for vandelay because I
was a vandelay Silva fan my whole life.
I think if I had to pick one fighter
that I'm like my most favorite guy to
watch fight,
it might be vandelay.
It's he's real close in his pride days,
he was just a fucking awesome spectacle.
He was amazing and when they banned him
for life,
I think that broke his heart and when
the UFC couldn't do anything about it
because it's the Nevada state athletic
commission,
he's going to fight in court so he feels
abandoned.
I don't know what the position is when
everybody's position that I know as far
as like trainers,
commentators,
fighters,
everyone across the board was like,
that's outrageous.
But the guy didn't even fail.
He didn't even fail drug tests.
You get a banned him for life.
That's so crazy.
And by all accounts vandelays one of the
nicest guys ever.
Like every time I met him he was like
super friendly.
Like I don't know if the guy was doing
something,
but I do know is there's a penalty if
you got caught that penalty.
At the time it was only like nine
months.
Like how are you going to take a guy
that if he did get caught,
you get a nine month penalty and you're
just,
you're saying forever.
You can't ever make money.
Like that's cruel,
that's a cruel way of conducting
business.
Like you don't care about this guy,
this guy's a legend,
this sport,
like the reason why people come and pay
all that money and go to see fights and
use them.
Use their credit cards and buy beer and
the whole revenue of the town.
It's because of the product and that
product is fighting and out of those
fighters,
vandelay was one of the most loved and
one of the most respected and revered
fighter.
So people would come to see him like his
very presence with generate income and
for them to just not even take into
account that this guy was a legend and
just never failed before.
Ever.
Never failed a single drug test.
And then all of a sudden they cut his
career out from under him.
He lost his mind,
right?
He made them nervous.
He made people nervous.
You know?
He was just making people nervous,
I think.
And he was,
he didn't do that until after he got
band.
He was a company man.
Nah,
but wasn't the handling vandelay was a
company,
man,
I'll fight anybody.
I know that something happened during
the taping of that show.
I don't know.
It didn't need to do something like the
coach somebody.
Yeah.
That's how it all during that.
He was a little bit about what happened.
So I didn't he do like the ultimate
fighter?
I think so he coached somebody in doing
that.
He was having moments and I'm like him,
I think he's fucking great.
You know,
I watched all of the old footage,
the fight he was involved in with
fucking great.
But you don't.
Now when I read that yesterday,
I'm like,
you know Dana white sit and going.
This guy says something crazy every
month.
If I was dating a white,
I,
I sleep with one eye open to.
Because vandelay Silva,
you never know what the fuck are.
You never know.
Know you didn't want some pink panther.
He told Keto to attack them.
No matter what he used to tell Kayla,
I want you to attack me no matter what,
attacked me.
And he would come home and look around
Keto and he was going to every room.
He was fucking.
He would Keto it for 15 minutes and
shit.
And they go,
Huh?
And then he'd have a bag of groceries.
He put the groceries down.
You get open up the refrigerator,
cato come out of the refrigerator,
grab him and shit.
Same thing with vandelay Silva,
like it looked like there was a report
on the Y.
Vandelay Silva is in Las Vegas and
nobody could find them randomly.
So when all of a sudden they're like
waiting there.
Dana has got his bodyguard and another
guy.
Everybody's got bodyguards and all of a
sudden right there in the fight,
you see a fucking rope come down with
vandelay with Vanda.
Like I've told you,
I you.
That's the shit.
Like he makes people nervous and he's
real.
So he starts swinging somebody's diet
when the hail it.
And that's what it was.
They had a real problem with that.
Oh yeah.
They had.
They had a real problem with that.
Well,
a lot of Brazilians got upset with them
too,
with all the bizarre.
He'll turn on tough offer offers.
Cautionary tale to veteran fighters.
Wow.
Interesting.
He got and I love him.
He's just while retail center and just
wound him up to the point where he was
ready to fight all the time.
Brazilians got upset with them.
You know,
they're like,
you're not representing us.
Right?
Like you're making us look like we're
just thugs ready to fight for no reason.
But like,
for vandelays like this guy is making it
personal.
You're making it real.
I want to fucking kill him.
I want to kick his ass right now.
Fuck this.
You know,
vandelay like wanted to like stand his
ground and established the whole thing
was crazy.
But Charleston was hilarious in that.
Don't touch me.
Don't touch.
No,
don't get gleiss like keeps his hand up
to his head and then eventually just
decided to take him down.
Fuck it happens.
We're out of time.
Joey Diaz.
God dammit.
It's Christmas Eve.
Spend this Christmas Eve.
Merry Christmas brother.
This is nobody.
Nobody,
um,
Wilshire theater is a wiltern isn't sold
out.
Sold out.
Sold.
Yeah.
It's been sold out for awhile.
This was a single or a couple of single
tickets left,
but that's a next week friends.
Very excited.
Ooh,
bowling.
Thursday night.
It's going to be fun week from today.
Yeah,
we're excited too.
So,
uh,
Brian,
you got some shit going on too,
right?
Yeah.
This Saturday,
day after Christmas,
me and Tony Hinchcliffe and Ashley
Barnhill will be in Austin at the spider
house ballroom and then followed by
Dallas.
Uh,
the following day.
Hyenas Comedy Club.
We're doing kill Tony.
Followed by a comedy show in both
cities.
You using like local folks for kill
Tony?
Yeah.
They sign up a half hour before the
show.
You can go to [inaudible] dot TV and get
the tickets.
Click on tour dates.
Nice.
Nice job
going on his name.
They didn't tell us who your show with
you and I'm taking a week off like you
would do just to revitalize myself.
Vitalized get that life in order.
And I spoke with savage dad toward
January 20th motherfucking Charlotte.
And uh,
what is the website website for tickets
you'll,
we'd be as dot.
Oh,
for Charlotte.
For anything.
Job is done that show ideas.net.
Alright,
you fucks.
Thank you everybody.
See you next week.
Stay whatever color you are.
Please.