Okay,
it's on.
I can't hear you.
I can't hear me.
Hear me,
hear me now,
but it's not very loud.
We're using the wrong mic too.
I am sorry I won't use it.
How's that one?
It's not any better.
In fact it's lower.
Hello?
It's actually your headphones.
How am I?
How's mine?
Hello?
It sounds great.
Yeah.
Hello?
Hello.
So should I add snowflakes right now?
Hello?
There it is.
Yeah,
these headphones suck,
but if you turn it all the way up,
it's okay doc.
And can you talk?
Hello?
Beautiful.
We're good.
How do I drop the volume online?
You start sucking his cock.
How do you suck?
It's pushed forward towards me.
Hello?
I thought that's better.
I guess still as wowed.
Don't be gay.
You know you're on right now.
Like 10 minutes ago you were just
telling me when and I'm like,
all right,
ready dude,
you got to do a better job.
Not just preposterous.
Were all smoking.
We will know what the fuck is going on.
How dare you.
So when I say gay,
I spelled a g h e y no take backs.
Broken experience is brought.
We're about to have news,
new sponsors.
You've got some really cool lined up,
very excited in the video game world.
Very excited.
Yeah.
I can't tell you preview,
but uh,
another very cool sponsor and I'm super
excited about it looks.
It's a,
you know,
one of the cool things about having this
podcast is you can kind of pick and
choose who sponsors the show.
You know,
we've had some offers from stuff that we
really weren't Kinda into.
And so like how do we even do this?
This wouldn't even work.
It's not something we give a shit about.
But I'd like video games more than I
want to like video games unfortunately.
Yeah.
We both have problems in my life.
So we're going to come.
We're going to help contribute to a lot
of people's addiction soon.
Really cool.
A lot of it is ipad.
I can't tell you shit.
A lot of them are ipad based though.
It's really cool.
The IPAD.
The cool thing about the IPAD is it's a
gyroscope or whatever the fuck you call
it detects motion euros,
scope,
like it's like a sandwich and you,
um,
you can drive cars and do all kinds of
things just by moving the pattern.
That's fucking incredible device.
Really seen those remote control planes
that you can fly with this.
Yes,
I have quadra copters.
Our original sponsor though is the
flashlight,
the first one,
the,
the one back when we were snowflakes in
the back of a ustream page on,
uh,
on the laptop back in the day as a,
200 episodes ago by the way,
focusing.
That's like 600 hours of listening to
you.
I don't have that much to say.
People say you repeat shit.
I'm like,
dude,
what the fuck do you think,
man?
Come
on dude.
It sounds like we're talking about the
news.
And I were talking about some pretty
preposterous share that I think about
all the time and I repeat things to
myself all the time.
I have a certain amount of memory and
it's all taken up by the fleshlight
ladies.
Gentlemen,
if you go to Joe Rogan.net
and click on a link for the flashlight,
entering the code name,
Rogan,
you will get 15 percent off a very solid
product.
A product that if I left you alone on an
island for a million years,
is all the tools in the world.
You would never be able to figure it
out.
You'd never be able to figure out how to
make a flashlight.
Okay?
You wouldn't.
It'd be like at a salmon over the
average person.
You would never even never figured it.
Yeah.
And then you get those little bones in
your insured to wrap some bamboo like
leaves around a salmon.
You know what?
You would never figured out.
Also,
vitamins,
you would never figure out Alpha brain.
You would never figure out new mood.
He would never figure it out.
True Tech Sport or shroom,
tech,
immune.
All of these are what we call nootropics
except for a shroom tech that's a little
bit of a nootropic,
but also more of a something that,
uh,
is,
aids,
your immune system and your,
um,
your athletic performance.
There's all the explanations for all
these various products.
It's available on [inaudible] dot com.
That's o n n I t checkout Alpha brain.
That is the cognitive enhancing
supplement.
New Mood is the five htp and l trip
defend supplement.
Um,
both of those things are great for
boosting your,
your own body's production of Serotonin,
which actually puts you in a better
mood.
Believe it or not,
a lot of the way you feel is fucking
chemical.
And of course a lot of it is that people
are depressed because their livestocks
let's be.
A lot of us are wage slaves.
Let's be honest.
That's not good.
And I don't think taking pills while
that's going on,
just to try to trick yourself into
thinking that everything's groovy.
I'm not a really big believer in that
either.
I'm much more of a proponent of,
you know,
get your fucking life in order and you'd
be amazed at how much better you feel.
But then again,
I've never had a problem with the
balance of my mind and I know people
have.
So I don't,
I don't ever say that you shouldn't take
this or you should take that.
Everybody's fucking completely different
and it's preposterous to think that you
know,
the inner workings of another man's mind
that said,
go to [inaudible] dot com.
Check out all the shit we have for sale.
Everything is stuff that I have taken,
I believe in.
I take on a regular basis.
It's a normal part of my diet.
I also eat very healthy.
I think you should too.
I eat like a fucking savage sometimes,
you know,
but I earned that for the most part.
I drink Kale shakes every morning with
fresh garlic and ginger and salary.
Like the more you take good things into
your body,
the more you can justify those krispy
Kreme donuts.
I'm like,
fuck it,
I'm just going off right now.
And you always feel like shit
afterwards.
But I think rewards like that,
even your body can process that.
If you do it on occasion.
You know,
if you do it once a week,
once a week day where you just eat ice
cream,
like a fucking slob.
So nothing wrong with that.
As long as the rest of the week,
generally speaking,
treat your body like you fucking love it
and it's precious because it is bitches
on a.com.
All of our products,
especially the first time orders of 30
pills,
if you order 'em all any,
anything,
the first order,
you get 100 percent of your money back
guarantee.
If you don't like it,
and that doesn't mean 100 percent.
If you return the product,
it means 100 percent.
Even if you eat it all and you go,
you know what?
This isn't what I thought I was going to
be.
What is it going to be?
It's going to make your.
Your brain feels sharper.
That's what Alpha brain does.
It's not magic.
It's not nothing new.
What does that movie was that Ashley?
What's his name?
Cooper.
Our limitless.
It's.
It's not.
It's not gonna.
Turn them more on into a brilliant
person,
but it will affect the way your brain
moves.
I like it makes me feel better.
It makes my brain work better.
Go to Joe Rogan.net.
Click on the link for Alpha brain and
use the code named Rogan and you will
get 10 percent any and all orders,
not just your first one.
Ra pitches.
It is podcast number 200.
What a fucking trip
Dunkin.
There's some Russell and trying to find
my alpha.
If you're on a desert island,
you would make Alpha brain adult mermaid
mermaid dried scrapings from the inside
of them were always pushing marriage,
but they say the method,
the mermaid came from horny sailor is
trying to rationalize fucking seals.
Course fucking everything.
Manatees.
Manatees,
yeah.
They'd fuck a manatee because there are
so horny and they then they'd be like,
no,
it was a mermaid.
I swear.
It's kind of a crazy asshole.
Would commit back then getting into the
goddamn boat and going across the ocean
for like four months.
A lot of times,
not even knowing if there was some shit
on the other end thinking it might just
stop like they thought the world just
ended and there a waterfall.
That's how bad Europe sucked in the 14
hundreds that Columbus was like,
yeah,
maybe it does fall off.
Let's go.
Pitches come on forever.
Look what the fuck we're eating at the
streets.
We're living in.
People stink.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That's the.
They were so upset with Europe.
They were like,
fuck this.
We're just going to get in a boat and go
to someplace.
I mean,
we're not even looking at it really,
truly and perspective because here's
something that was really,
really rare back then.
Any one on one accounts of someone who
went there that liked it.
Forget about picture.
They didn't have pictures back then.
Would you see some drawings?
No,
you didn't even talk to one guy probably
that went over there himself and had a
wonderful and prosperous life and was
telling me,
listen,
there's land to be had.
It's a great time.
Come on.
Over.
What a great mass of movement of humans
in such a short period of time.
The population or the population of the
North American continent,
you know,
the fact that there was already a small
group of nomadic people that were living
here and they were just completely
overwhelmed by the volume and the
numbers.
I think there are a lot of them in,
in North America.
I think there was a lot of native
Americans and indigenous people.
When you say a lot,
was there like millions?
Like.
No,
no.
Let me say,
let me say even if there was a lot,
it's nothing in comparison to what it
is.
Like right now like this,
there's never been population numbers
like this anywhere,
right?
Where the,
uh,
what is that?
Has there ever been a place where there
was virtually no one and an immigrants
all came in and then within a few
hundred years there's $300 million over?
Nope.
No.
Right.
I mean we,
unless it was pre flood before the last
media or impact or something like that,
I wonder how many native Americans or
were before they were killed and
pushback back.
And you know what,
that must have been unbelievable for
them.
The people that have lived their lives
like a certain way before the first
white men came.
You know,
it must have been mostly been
preposterous.
Like you know,
they probably generation after
generation,
they had followed the buffalo and they
had lived this,
you know,
very disciplined in spiritual and sort
of in tune with nature and their
environment and they had very clear laws
of morality and how you deal with nature
and how you use up your resources.
Really fascinating.
Like you could tell that they had a deep
reverence and a real understanding for
the resources of the environment and not
taking too much,
not wasting anything because you might
not have it man.
Like they,
they were under a real concern about
starving to death if they didn't get up
in the morning and follow the buffalo
and they lost those motherfuckers.
If they have no food for a few weeks,
like what people use,
your baby can die.
Man.
You might just fuck up and run into a,
you know,
time to seasons wrong and run into
someplace where you're stuck chasing
these buffalo in a place that gets
snowed in and there's no food.
Oh yeah.
Not to mention the fact that bears are
eating you a bear.
That's a real worry for you.
Yeah.
Especially if you're in the woods and
you fuck up and stumble upon its mother.
A mother and the cubs are getting there.
They're fucking monsters.
I mean,
think about how aggressive people are
around their babies.
You know,
you're dealing with a giant thousand
pound fucking dog essentially.
So they go,
I mean dogs a dog with thick skin.
Those things as such.
They did a scan.
They bite themselves.
They don't even hurt themselves.
Never seen them go to war with each
other.
Yeah,
they're taking chunks of hairs are
flying and shit like that and they're
fine.
They're fine.
Just get the fuck out of each other.
Being each other's Claude,
each other's crap.
They literally would have dismembered,
are weak and gelatinous like bodies was
just torn them apart like they're
nothing just crunched through your
skull.
What a shit life it must have been back
then.
I mean the American Indians on one hand
you can say there was a lot of
satisfaction in that life and they
probably were happier than the majority
of people today.
I think that's really arguable,
but that's just the majority of people
there for weak ass bitches.
It's not that today isn't way more
awesome and people get confused in that.
Sometimes people go,
you know what?
People were happier back when they
couldn't read.
Did you know that people are happier?
People
have your back when they just had grunts
and everybody knew what they had to do
to keep saying that doesn't mean back
then doesn't suck,
and today's an awesome.
It just means that today is so uber
complex that a lot of people just don't
even try.
They just go and do it and they just
throw it down on the ground and they run
away because there's no mechanism to
really take care of that back then.
If you throw yourself on the ground,
I'm not doing this so fucking barrack
eats you a bobcat would you?
You have to kill you.
You'd starve to death.
Now you can really get a lot of like
weird,
like weepy.
You can be really weepy and scared with
very little effect,
but the effect is,
like you say,
you still get an effect.
I mean,
the effect is for sure you never
progressed,
but you don't have to worry about
getting eaten outside your house.
You're not going to get eaten.
Yeah.
This,
the,
the reason why people develop character,
the reason why people develop
consequences because there are
consequences for not having those
things.
There's consequences for not having
character.
This confident.
There's consequences for not having
confidence,
for not having control over your
environment,
for not being a fucking man.
There are consequences,
but what are they really?
They're pretty meager.
Some other guy fucks your girlfriend.
She leaves you for someone who's more
powerful.
You lose your,
your metal box and you have to get an
older metal box that someone has already
lived in.
You know what?
What is it?
They take your car away.
You get a new car,
you have to move to a shitty apartment.
What?
What,
what?
What does it really happened?
Cumulative effect of everything that
you're saying means that you're living
in hell when you're a bitch is what?
It's pointing out the garbage.
But my point is,
even with the shittier new car,
you know,
the,
the less cool car,
the older car in this shitty apartment,
you're still living a billion times
lever better than anybody did when they
were,
you know,
Lewis and Clark would hitchhike in their
way across the fucking country,
walking no horses and shit.
They didn't know what the fuck was going
on.
That was a ridiculous thing to do.
You're living pretty,
pretty much everyone is living a life
that's very similar to like Roman
mobility.
You've got running water.
You can just go and turn the water on,
take a hot shower,
heats it up.
That's a brand new thing.
You've got a microwave,
you can cook your food and two minutes.
Have you seen those new?
Or there's new water heaters where it's
a constant flow of hot water.
It heats it instantly and you don't have
to have like giant tanks of water.
The water goes through it and instantly
heats it up.
So you could take a shower for an hour
and a half and it,
you'll never run out of hot water.
Yeah.
So you,
you're living in paradise here.
You're not living back in the day when
you wanted to kill fleas on your
clothes,
you would put it over the toilet.
Did you know about that?
And the castles and the castles.
If you got the.
So everything was flea infested back
then.
Everything was fleeing fast that there's
fleas fucking everywhere because no,
no way to clean,
no way to know poison for this Lisa.
Everything swarming with fleas until
your clothes will get filled with fleas
and to get rid of the fleas and a
castle,
they would put the clothes over the
shaft
where the sewer sewer is because the
ammonia would rise up through the
clothes and kill the fleas and the
clothes.
Oh my God.
That's the world you're living in.
You're washing your clothes and shit
fumes.
So they had to take those clothes and
they had to all walk around smelling
fumes,
but that's better than the fleas,
man.
That's better than the fleas.
I'd rather smell like old first one to
figure that out.
It's like it's gotTa.
Be a way to get these fucking.
Let's try light myself on fire.
No,
that doesn't work.
That just kills me.
Let's try running through the frozen
river.
Nope.
No Hypothermia.
Shit.
Fuck.
What about shit?
Shit.
Nobody likes shit.
I run away from Shit.
Let's see who's.
Let's play chicken with Shit.
Smell.
See who quits first.
Who for
human being?
You could get burned at the stake if you
took a shower more than twice a year.
Like if you were taking like three or
four showers a year,
people might get suspicious.
Like you should take a lot of shower.
Will they also be like,
why is so clean?
Why do you smell that?
Which only witches smell good.
Yeah.
When you like take a warm shower and
then you climb into some like really
soft cotton clothes and you were like,
you are feeling better than most humans
have ever felt in my whole life.
That's like a deeper sense of pleasure.
You plop down on your soft and
comfortable bed and for,
you know,
look for a real reason.
You're not scared of getting eaten by
anything.
Nope.
You're not scared of monsters or tribes
coming into town and rating your village
and.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
You're just chilling.
Maybe sometimes you get colds and then
you know you get a z pack.
Hate your fucking fine.
You know,
you sitting in front of a television
with the avatar playing say,
and you're,
you're sitting propped up on your
pillows and your wearing clean clothes.
You have it better than anyone who's
ever lived ever by a long shot.
Did you imagine Lewis and Clark,
if you could show those motherfuckers
the average 23 year old dude lives in
some shitty apartment is propped up on
his bed watching TV in his bedroom,
eyes,
roommates,
fucking loud and the other room with a
blender like that guy's living in
paradise.
He's like displays,
place.
Show us onto the mouths.
You saw one mouse.
That's it.
Well,
there's not everywhere.
Infesting all your clothes and eating
your food and giving everyone horrible
diseases.
That's killing everyone.
Old.
Everyone with a weak immune system is
just fucking dead.
There's nowhere to put the body.
So they stack them in the streets than
the rats get infested with it and then
the rat starts spreading it all over
town.
And then you have the black plague.
Yeah.
Oh,
you saw a mouse
who poor little booby won't be okay with
sharing the world with a mouse.
Don't.
And also don't forget the fact that like
if you were pregnant,
there's a pretty good chance you're
going to die.
Most likely you're going to die when
that thing comes out of your pussy,
like you're just going to split you in
half and there's no antibiotics in.
The baby's probably going to die too.
During Rome,
the infant mortality rate was 50
percent.
Fifty percent,
half the babies died and you know,
that's one of the things we.
You read about like crazy stories of the
Bible.
We've talked about this before about how
so everything was so violent,
so crazy,
and people say,
well,
this is really a book of God,
the Book of religion.
Why would it have such gratuitous
violence?
Why would violence be condoned?
Oh,
you don't even.
I don't even think we could wrap our
hands around how hard life was back when
they wrote the Bible.
I mean,
and the,
even the New Testament,
even with Constantine and the bishops,
when they reworked the New Testament,
that's still,
you know,
that's still ridiculously hard.
It's a terrible life back then,
you know,
and,
and you,
I think they probably needed religion
back then.
We think about how,
how easy life is today and there's so
many people that need a safety net.
So many people that are terrified so
many people that want one sanity to this
and they,
they seek that Saturday and no really
ridiculous mythology,
but back then it was imperative.
You had to have it.
I think Patton Oswald's got some
brilliant joke about this where he talks
about how religion was invented to trick
dumb people that there's a cake in.
This guy says he stopped,
like attacking everyone.
Essentially.
It's just really smart.
People recognize that there's really
dumb people that have no qualms in
killing and doing ridiculous things is
that they tell them this fib to make
them behave.
I can't remember the jokes.
Awesome.
Look it up.
Sorry.
It could be possible,
but I've always thought that what I
mean,
I always joke around about it being for
dumb people,
but I think there's a pull towards the
idea of something other than us and I
think we always have had that too.
I don't think we're willing to believe
that we're the end of the evolutionary
food chain or the spiritual food chain.
It seems silly.
It seems much more likely.
Like there's something above us.
We just can't even communicate with it.
We're just the same way and can't tell
you stories where we're not able to
communicate with something that's the
next,
the next level of existence.
Well,
yeah,
especially when we're in,
especially when we're so confused by our
environment and we're saddened,
distracted.
I mean,
the thing that you were talking about
initially is,
is something I read this,
ah,
the Dalai Lama was in beverly hills
talking to like some rich people and in
their house doing a home visit and he
said to them,
you know,
here we are years.
You're in Beverly Hills,
you have your mansion and all your
things,
but why are your medicine cabinets
filled with antidepressants and volume
and antianxiety medication?
Even with all this stuff,
you're still experiencing mental
turbulence to the point where you're
depressed.
This is the.
If people are still caught up in that
place,
it's going to be very difficult for them
to to transcend it to a point where you
could communicate with some higher
intelligence.
How are you going to do that when you're
caught up in some ridiculous perception
of the world where you're addicted and
attached to material things where you're
stuck always wanting
some new thing which just makes you
perpetually insane.
You know?
Well,
that's for a lot of people,
that becomes their focus.
You know,
I think the human beings,
you know,
you can look at the shallowness of
materialism and he could say,
God,
it's so shallow.
it's so silly.
Oh yes,
yes and yes,
but what is it really?
What's going on really well?
Well,
human beings are constantly trying to
achieve things.
I mean,
that's the point of staying alive.
The point of staying alive is you have
to achieve success out there while
you're hunting success while you're
fishing.
There's a reason why hunting and fishing
is so satisfying.
I haven't been hunting.
I plan on going very soon,
but I'm going to go with Steve Rinella.
The guy from that.
Uh,
that mediator show.
Working it out.
Yeah.
Name dropper.
Hey,
I need a name.
Drop the fucker.
I didn't even know that is me eating
show.
We're going to eat.
We're going to hunt bears in Alaska.
Wow.
Yeah.
What the fuck?
Anyway.
Um,
uh,
how did I get onto that?
I'm scared.
I just got scared.
What'd you get?
Scared of bears in Alaska.
What we're talking about just before
that.
Oh,
we're talking about materialism.
then I think that it's this.
Oh,
that's right.
Well,
the reason why it's so satisfying.
I did get scared.
Thinking about bears.
Moscow.
You should.
Reason why it's so satisfying.
Hunting and fishing is because those
tasks are.
That's a prerequisite for staying alive
for the longest time.
For the longest time,
the way we stayed alive as we had to go
out and gather our food.
It feels good to pick food,
like if you find some blueberry
somewhere and you pick them,
there's like this weird joy that comes
with your finding and finding a meal
outside that is a natural reward system
that's put in place to ensure our
survival.
Now when there are no hunting and
gathering tasks to get when it's so easy
to just walk to the store and get meat,
the choice is to meet and it takes
literally seconds.
Can I have that big perfectly aged hunk
of flesh that's has no diseases on it,
ready to cook right away and you know,
can I have this milk that's been
homogenized and pasteurized and has no
chance of killing me and I can sit on
the shelf for weeks and can I have this
cheese that's also the same.
It's very resistant to mold and all.
Look at this fresh vegetables that are
genetically modified and then you can
grow tomatoes in the middle of the
fucking winter outside.
You know,
it's all of it is incredible,
but also easy and so accessible that
there's no reward.
You're not getting that reward,
so people will just.
They're.
They're being gluttonous,
unlike the native Americans who the
flesh was so important to them to kill
with so important.
Everything was so sacred that they would
use every single part of the animal to
honor that animal and they wanted to
keep this relationship with the buffalos
and what the,
the deer and all the animals that they
needed to sustain them.
For us,
that system is hijacked,
hijacked by sports cars.
It's hijacked by getting ahead.
Uh,
you know,
getting a house in the hamptons.
It's high,
it's high jacked by having a boat.
It's hijacked by all the things that you
can reward yourself for women.
Maybe it's jewelry or shoes where when
it's shoes,
a lot of women that they become obsessed
with fucking handbags and shit.
I was reading about this woman who was,
um,
some super billionaire's daughter and
uh,
he's,
you know,
I,
I say is like super ridiculously
wealthy.
She has a million dollar bathtub that's
made out of crystal,
like she has a bathtub that is a million
dollars and they imported from Mexico.
It's her bathtub,
a million dollars.
That's like an awesome house.
A million dollars.
She has just incredible supply of
handbags.
It's millions of dollars worth of
handbags,
millions of dollars worth of shoes,
literally millions of dollars worth of
shoes.
You know,
there's people that start,
they get crazy and start buying high end
handmade watches that are a million
dollars and they look like a fucking
timex.
Yeah,
I mean I'm exaggerating,
but they don't look this,
this watch watches.
It's called a tw steel.
It's a,
it's a nice watch.
It's like it's like a 150 bucks on
Amazon.com
or something like that.
For me it's perfect.
It's like cool looking.
I like it.
It's not flashy,
it's not.
I'm trying to stick out in your face,
but I like the way a good machine look
looks,
you know,
something that's designed well and
that's what that looks like.
But some people get crazy and they'll
take it to.
I'd want the finest watched constructed
in the most difficult manner.
Let go in a bottle.
I want them to make the watch in a
bottle with tweezers,
you know,
and I want it to be all magnetized and
all of it's titanium and hand carved and
get the fuck
made in the bottles to the no dust gets
in it.
Is that the reason for that?
Just made the bottle part up.
It's like making a ship in the bottle.
Why the fuck would you make a ship in
the ball?
It's stupid.
Who cares you?
It's harder for you.
Really.
Fucking chip is like whatever.
Like I'm not good.
It's a mystery.
I say make something better.
That's,
that's you know,
right in front of you.
Stupid.
Why are you making things inside
bottles?
It's a challenge.
It's like tetris back in the old days.
It's outrageous.
But Dude,
posture is one thing.
One thing that you're leaving out the
difference between primitive and modern
peoples living situation.
You also have to take into account their
mental state.
People,
uh,
that the native Americans,
they believed in like the great spirit.
They didn't know too much about the
universe and the way that we know it.
They like had this faith in a kind of
ancient religion that,
um,
that gave them a lot of comfort.
The modern guy who's buying all the ham
and the meat and the fucking ship
watches and bottles and the,
and the crazy woman buying the person's,
it gets even more absurd because their
belief in the universe is either,
you know,
a fundamentalist Christian or religious
belief that's always haunted by science.
It all sides.
The whole world is telling them,
you know,
a lot of that stuff isn't true.
A lot of that stuff doesn't,
uh,
didn't really happen.
The people,
the way they're describing that,
nobody flew up into the air.
Now guys flew up into the air,
came,
came back to life after he got nailed to
a cross that's never happened.
Doesn't happen this.
So they're fucking main.
The tenants of their religion are always
getting attacked on all sides by
science.
And if you're not religious then you
exist.
Like if you're an atheist,
then it even more weird.
You're just some like super smart
primate that's been stuck on a ball.
You're December like tiny little tiny
thinking,
little primate bug thing that the force
of gravity is keeping stuck to the
ground on a planet spinning around like
your Joe Spinning around a ball of
fucking fire,
so it's like if you don't really believe
in God when you're in this super absurd
situation,
which is,
it's like now I have infinite amount of
food and whatever I want,
but I'm just some absurd little speck of
something.
You don't have to believe.
I mean,
not all atheists think that by the way,
but it is an absurd place to get to.
I maintained that the reality of living
on a planet in orbit around the Star in
the galaxy,
in a universe is so preposterous and
bizarre and strange that it doesn't
matter if you call it,
you know,
big thunder,
God in the sky,
and it doesn't matter if you're,
you know,
you,
you have some mythology attached to it.
Your reality is your perceptions,
your own perceptions of it are so
abstract.
Yep.
There's so not,
that's not something.
Even if you'd have to have fucking been
to space,
you'd have to have to go to a planet or
at least orbit the moon or something.
Just really wrap your fucking head
around the fact that there's some other
shit out there.
It just seems like you're telling me it,
but it's abstract.
I know the numbers.
Hundreds of billions of galaxies.
Fourteen billion.
I know the numbers.
They're abstracting.
It sounds to me it doesn't sound real.
I think that's religion sounds equally
abstract.
You know,
you,
you can believe in,
and I'm not comparing science,
religion and sciences,
you know,
been measured and it makes sense.
Most of religion is silly,
but I think to us,
I just saying,
I think to us the reality of our
situation is so preposterous that it's
almost like religion had to be put in
place to describe it.
It really makes you wonder like how
quickly people came,
became conscious because like,
all this stuff was shit we had to deal
with like really early on,
you know,
like we,
where are we?
What's going on,
where is this from?
And then,
you know,
Bill weld the thunder.
God came down from the sky and like we
had to like really early on,
had to come up with some fucking
answers.
That's one of the cool things about
Buddhism is that it doesn't have like a
thunder.
It doesn't talk about a thunder God or
something.
It's more like someone recognizing that
is whatever these absurd beings are on
this planet.
We all kind of share the same similar
problems.
There we are all sharing the same
similar problems and then an analysis of
those problems created like the system
of Buddhism,
which is a way to overcome the thing
that's trying to make you buy a shitload
of purses and cars and the thing that's
making you miserable while you're laying
in your fucking nice bed in your
apartment.
It's acknowledging that if you're
fucking hunting,
hunting bears is a native American or if
you're lying in your fucking bed is a
modern pepperoni stuffed rich man.
You both have the same problem,
which is you're going to die.
You're going to get old,
you're going to get disease.
You're going to get old age,
disease and death.
This is an inevitability that we all
share in that all humans have shared
since the beginning of time.
You can't escape it.
So the cool thing about Buddhism is it's
not like if you have prayed to the
mighty loon loon,
you'll get a blessing.
It's like,
alright,
let's sober up.
Can we calm down?
Can we overcome all the fucking
distractions that are surrounding us?
Can we focus our will to a point where
we're no longer being buffeted by
circumstances like all of our ancestors
app?
And that's enlightenment,
man.
When you wake up and you overcome the
fucking
sort of a,
you know,
I mean,
is it real enlightenment?
No,
it's,
you're,
you're sort of managing your situation.
You're sort of reacted dealing
realistically with what does that even
mean?
What inevitable?
What is the inevitable?
What is the death?
You know,
you're just,
all you know is that this ends.
You don't even know what,
what takes place next,
if anything,
you know nothing.
And for a lot of people just that I
think was too much and people also have
that natural primate need to be right.
The need to follow the Alpha need to
have someone who seems to be the leader
of the gang and it's,
it's almost impossible to do that unless
you got a religion rock and it's really
hard.
It's really hard unless you have not
just a guy,
but a guy who appeals to the gods and
you know,
an intermediary.
Someone who's like,
God's manager makes it's way easy to run
shit because you're like way closer to
God.
It's a funny.
I mean,
it's the greatest trick ever.
If you drink a bunch of people to think
that you're the one who can communicate
with God,
like,
yeah,
I wrap it up,
but it does represent God as every cult
not pulled that move.
I mean,
that's like everyone.
People want to believe Shit,
man.
There's a lot of people don't want to
believe shit.
You could start a cult for real.
Yeah,
easily.
Oh No.
I'd never started call.
Of course you would never start a call,
but you could start a call if you want
to do.
If you were a crazy person,
you'd be really good at it.
You think so?
Oh yeah.
That's the nicest thing you've ever said
to me.
You looked like Manson.
You could totally do it.
You're a charismatic guy.
You're very intelligent.
You're right.
You can spin a yarn,
you all their prerequisites for someone
being a cult leader.
Right?
Yeah.
You know,
I think that it would be much more fun
to,
um,
to just be part of what's actually
happening on the planet.
Yeah.
To be part of that,
that's a massive distraction.
To be in a cult of work.
Way more confusing and get the work
running a colt man.
It's like,
that's a lot of fucking organization.
It would be terrible.
I'd have sex.
I bet though you would have,
but it's all tricks.
Sex.
Let me tell you something.
Only sex you want in life period.
Unless you just,
unless you just got to get a hooker and
you just to get your Dick sucked,
period.
You know,
you're just a guy who just never gets
laid and you got to do.
You got to do.
Other than that,
what you really want,
ideally sex with people want to have sex
with you.
You don't want that trick sex,
you know that I'm the Messiah.
Tricks acts.
We're going to get mad at you,
man.
Somewhere along the line someone's going
to get mad at you.
You should only have sex with people
that genuinely want to have sex.
Have you?
Have you ever had payments?
Sex,
like where you did something and they
felt like they had to have sex with,
just as a payment.
That was,
that was,
that was the worst.
Why?
What did you,
what did change the story a little bit.
It's a girl that wanted me to do some
stuff for her and so I did it for just
thinking like I thought she was just
cute,
but then right when it was done,
she's just like,
okay,
and she comes into the next room,
just takes off her clothes and I'm.
And I'm like,
Oh fuck Ya.
And I fucker.
And then then she left and then we later
she wanted to do some more stuff and so
I did it and she goes,
look,
I'm on my period right now after I was
done with it.
She goes,
I'm on my period right now,
but it kind of gets you the next time.
And I'm like,
okay,
she needs to tell her about money.
Yeah.
Can I get so wow.
You know,
we should have had this conversation off
the air.
I want to know who the fuck this is.
Um,
yeah.
You give me a hint now you wouldn't
know.
I would have to explain it or you'd be
like,
Eh,
I eventually you.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Is this a long time ago this happened
or.
Yeah,
it's like seven years ago.
Wow.
That's funny.
I've never,
I've never had that happen before.
I've never had that.
But I have lent money in the past to
people at dated.
Yeah.
But it's never really alone.
They mostly hate doing that though.
I've noticed that people hate that man.
People hate.
They hate when they're stuck.
They hate when they have no one to turn
to.
You know,
all of a sudden like,
your bills are piling up and you fucking
transmission brakes and you literally
can't get to work.
That happens to be super normal.
It happens all the time.
You know,
sucks.
People hate to be in a position.
Most people do.
The people who liked to be in a position
to ask people for money all the time,
those are a pain in the ass,
you know,
and especially,
dudes who just always seem to be in a
spot where you never can get out of
this.
I always in a bind what it was.
What do you,
why are you spending so much for all
your on this house?
Why is this car so much when you're
broken that you're always needing money?
Dude,
you gotta manage your situation.
You know,
if you want better things in life,
you've got to make more money.
Man.
You can't like pretend you had more.
Part of it is credit,
credit,
credit.
No one's forcing you to tell you what,
how you in credit cards so you,
you,
you're a broke person being a waiter and
you're making shit.
No money,
but you want a new TV.
You run it.
You see all your friends have tvs.
What we just talked about,
silly,
but what sucks is that that it should be
fair for credit card companies to charge
like what they're doing now up to 30,
30 percent or something like that.
That's criminal.
I mean that's,
that's,
that should be against the law.
Totally criminal and most people pay the
minimum and you'll pay that off for the
rest of your life and you're just keep
paying them and you'll know you will
have paid so much more money than you
spent.
It's criminal,
but dude,
a lot of people are in a trans man.
A lot of people are in a serious fucking
trans and
like,
Oh
sure,
change the environment of the show.
It's just like that amazing lane that
was.
We did a podcast with Brendan loss and
they do that every episode where they do
that.
They do things like that.
Like they sit there for like five
minutes,
like making crazy noises for no reason
at all.
I didn't know where.
I bet that would be a funny podcast
because Brendan Walsh is a funny
motherfucker.
This one guy,
by the way,
there's a podcast whole network of um,
called death squad that were also
involved in Brian runs all of them and
they're all on itunes and all for free
and they include the ice house
chronicles,
which I think is one of the best
podcasts we do and what the icehouse
chronicles is.
We're actually going to do one after I
do this podcast with Duncan and what is,
is while the show was going on at the
ice house,
we also come over here and we fuck
around and talk shit and have a podcast,
a lot of fun and it's a real green room.
Like it's an actual green room of the
show.
Like you'll see people saying like,
Oh shit,
am I on my own now?
And then they'll run out of the room and
go onstage.
It's,
it's really cool.
I like that,
that Paul Provenza show,
the green room I enjoyed.
I enjoy whenever you can get,
you know,
Stan hope and Dave attell and Janeane
Garofalo in a room together and let them
argue.
Jamie Kilstein,
whoever was in that,
you know,
I,
I enjoy that,
but this is a real green room of a real
show of a bunch of guys who worked
together on a regular basis and you're
not going to get any weird awkwardness
or people you know,
that are attacking people.
Most of it is just a lot of fun with
occasionally Brian,
we'll bring someone in here and fuck.
Are these people Brian Case we've had
only four major instances,
but those have been love those.
They love those moments.
Yeah.
We've got a few incidents where Brian
brought people in and be like,
this person,
she can't talk anymore.
Brian,
like,
Hey,
get out of here.
I can't tell you but this,
you know,
he knows people in that shit.
Some shady businesses keep on running
into shady shit.
Shitty Shit.
Yeah,
that's a lot of it.
I think it might in the future,
like I'm ready to completely do
something.
I thought about this the other day.
I'm ready date somebody that I would
have dated when I was 21,
like like when I was 21,
I was date someone that you should be
dating when you're 37.
The crazier asshole.
Even scarier.
Thirty seven year olds in Los Angeles.
That's the scariest bottom of the weird.
Sometimes for the most part the is
really bad times.
It's like you and sometimes it's like
Duncan.
Sometimes it's a guy or girl for you
who's at a certain point in their life
has actually learned a lot of shit and
it's actually fun to be around.
We all assume chauvinistically as men,
especially that when you meet a girl
that's in their late thirties,
she just going to be a fucking wreck.
She goes to screaming wreck of
desperation and fear and blame my age.
Want to make babies quick so they trick
you.
They try to play exactly who they think
you want you to be interested in me.
Yeah,
I know someone who absolutely
unquestionably was tricked.
The girl he was dating was older and
they like right away,
started dating and she said that she was
on the pill and she got off the pill
immediately.
She immediately knew that she was only
like,
I think she was like 35 or 36,
which is.
Well,
that's where it gets with women.
Not all women,
obviously most of them that aren't
deceptive,
but where it gets with some women it's
like,
listen,
I don't give a fuck what he wants.
I only get one more shot at this.
I'm not going to be in some sort of
relationship with some guy by the way,
who has plenty of money so he can take
care of this thing.
Even if the kid doesn't work out,
this is what I want.
I want a child.
This guy's got money,
he's got genetics,
and they'll just take the loads.
They'll just take the loads and you have
to pretend that you have to somehow or
another,
you know,
you have to.
If you're,
if you're having sexually or when you're
not wearing a condom,
you know,
you have to realize that that's a
possibility that someone could do that
and it's totally illegal by the way she
can do that.
And you know,
even if she was deceptive,
I don't think she could lose in court.
I think she could probably say it's her
business.
You know,
I,
I think you're,
you're,
whether or not you took the pills.
Anybody ever sued someone based on
whether or not they took the pill.
The pill is like they say it's 99
percent effective.
I bet it's 100 percent effective.
Just one people.
Such wretched line cons.
It's unprovable in court.
You know,
it's very possible that the pill is just
straight up affective.
Would you ever get your shit a snipped,
like maybe save some sperm that.
Yeah.
Did he say to you the sperm also a no.
He did not say I save your spring break.
That could be reversed,
but doug's loads at this point or to
fucking completely useless.
His loads will come out like a wet
cardboard.
There's no way they're impregnating
anybody getting reversed.
This has this weird visual that your
penis would be just so broken looking.
No,
it's not.
You're paying this.
It's under something with your balls.
You know,
you wouldn't even see that.
But the innards man,
that's what's really crazy.
Trying to reattach a tube and it might
not work.
It might not take.
Yeah.
This is like the worst felony.
Well,
there's another way of doing it.
That is another way of doing it.
There's a new way.
Um,
I saw online where they're doing it now
with like a clip there actually bending
it
and pinching it and cutting off with a
clip.
And the idea behind the clip is that it
could be reversible,
but I always think that like,
you know,
you're doing Jujitsu and some guy goes
neon belly on you,
hard pops your fucking flip out.
And next thing you know,
well listen man,
that's the reality.
You get a big guy on you.
And so I control neon bellies and
motherfucker.
Dude,
it's,
you got to have tight abs.
I do.
I do my sit ups.
That's what I think.
I don't want to get stuck with some big
fucking guy,
neon belly.
That's what I do.
That's what I think of when I'm doing my
setups.
Ups,
you just gave me an anxiety attack.
I don't get anxiety attacks.
Just do sit ups with 25 pound plates
while you're hanging by your ankles.
This is what you do.
Took a 25 pound plate.
You put it by your chest and you hang by
your ankles and just all the way you're
fucking slow control at Dunkin,
even if you only do one.
How to keep me from having an
illegitimate child choice stomach
muscles.
I'm going to teach you about bald
eagles.
That's the next thing I'm going to teach
you about how to Cagle your boss.
You know women do eagles to keep their.
Their pussy tight.
Apparently you could do that to Kohl's
just from down.
Shut the floors.
It's a really weak muscle.
If you try to squeeze your Dick Muscle
right now as you're sitting here,
just going to try to.
It's so weak.
I have no dick squeezing endurance at
all.
That's why when you,
when you're,
when you have to come,
you don't want to come.
It's so hard,
you know,
when,
when you're like,
don't fucking move,
don't move and just grab her and hold
her in place to move and you're going
crazy and it just forget it.
That's when load sneak out and that's
how people get pregnant.
Do you believe the idea?
Yeah,
that I'm like the galleries in the
tantric sex,
people believe that you actually lose
energy when you come,
like if you come too much,
you're losing some form of energy.
Now.
Like some boxers,
they won't ejaculate like before a
fight,
but they won't have sex before a fight
because they want to.
Well,
they've actually proven physiologically
proven that if you don't have any
release within seven days,
your testosterone goes up significantly.
Significantly.
Like measurably,
I think.
I don't remember the actual number,
but it was enough so that it would.
It would warrant doing that if you were
a fighter,
but for some fighters there,
the difficult thing is relaxing.
The difficult thing is getting in there
and being able to fight up to your
potential.
It's not the amount of testosterone that
you're producing,
it's how well are you in control of your
mind because your mind is what's going
to guide you through this fucking thing.
Your mind is going to have to deal with
the consequences of nipples come and
flying at your face and jumping knees
and dudes try to take you down to try to
throw you literally on your head.
Your mind is dealing with all this and
your mind has gotta be on point and your
mind has got to be relaxed enough to not
freeze up,
relax enough to respond to the pressure
and do the smart thing and not not get
exhausted quickly because of anxiety.
That's a big problem with guys.
They're mine gets them so like this that
their bodies like,
I can't do this anymore because they're
so
inefficient.
They're so completely inefficient in
their use of their body that everything
is a is a strain and everything is a
sprint and they become exhausted like
almost immediately.
Yeah.
Learning to get in that fucking
statement.
By the way,
I was.
What I was saying is in that case,
I would say that you should have sex
because then you're not going to at
least think about the sex because if
you're not having sex,
you're built up with those testosterone
and you're just thinking about pussy and
are so confused.
You might not even be able to be
comfortable in their you.
It might not be able to like get loose
in there,
you know?
Whereas if you're,
if you get it out of your system,
you get the sex that you're still going
to be,
you still feel great.
I mean,
how much of an effect does it have on
you?
It doesn't have an effect on you where
you go to the gym and your week.
Now I'm at sex and go the gym and I feel
great.
It's not that much of a problem.
I think for a lot of guys you'd be
better off just having a sex to calm
down.
Get it out of your system.
Yeah.
I look at it,
I'm like,
don't ask me man.
Like I,
I,
maybe you can go like four days without
jerking off.
I'm not having sex the mud,
so I have no idea the whole here's the
perfect mystery to me,
Taoism and the whole contract thing.
I just don't know if it's something I
wonder about because it's two systems
that both,
you know,
have really developed systems around
this idea of like extending your orgasm.
Like somehow they can like supposedly
make their orgasms lasts much,
much,
much sting.
Isn't that right?
But you would think we would be like
really that in tune with everything is
fucking songs we better lately.
Right.
You know,
like a long time ago,
they were awesome.
You know,
the old sting.
What was the last time sting had a good
new song.
Does he have songs anymore?
Songs I heard that were new that came
out while I was playing a gravy or
whatever.
That's field the gravy.
Well him and his wife,
they have like these 30 minute sessions,
but where's your music bro?
Why?
You know,
I mean it.
Was he putting out music that I'm not
aware of.
Did you say 30 minute?
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It was like crazy tantric orgasms where
they last minute orgasm.
Yeah.
Yeah,
for real or imagined the smell on that.
What do you think?
Hey,
what do you think would happen if you
had a 24 hour orgasm feel great.
I think I would suck.
I take you.
I think.
I don't know,
man.
Do you think it would be wasted?
You'd be exhausted by the time was over,
but yeah,
probably feel great.
Can you mentioned trying to eat while
having an orgasm,
like you're at subway train order.
That'd be embarrassing.
It would be the worst thing would be the
worst drug.
He'd always be around people coming like
wherever,
like you'd go to parties and everyone's
just sat on the couch having orgasms.
That's totally possible.
By the way,
that's not like a really difficult thing
to represent chemical.
I bet.
Yeah.
I don't think it is.
I think they could come up with an
orgasm pill that's around the corner.
No one ever would have thought a hard
dick pill would have been feasible or
achievable so quickly and easily.
No plague of so many fucking think how
hard it would have been to have an
erection.
When you're looking down at your wife's
flea covered pussy that hasn't had a
shower and yeah,
there's no showers.
It could even be if they bathed,
you had to get like buckets of water.
He had to bring them by the river.
By the time you get to go over and over
again to probably take you an hour and a
half each fucking trip back and forth,
back and forth.
I'll get the rest of it tomorrow.
Then what do you do?
You boil the water.
What's going on there?
Or just take an ice cold bath.
Yeah.
Then you draw your dirty ass off on some
fucking skin.
Still Gross.
Dirty again?
Yeah.
What did people smell like back there?
What if it balanced out?
If like all the bacteria in your body
will just fight each other off until it
got to like a balanced warfare state.
You know,
the issue with us is that we clean our
skin so much that we lose a lot of the
healthy bacteria outside of your skin.
That's one of the,
uh,
problems with people that have A.
I'm obsessive compulsive and they have
to clean everything.
What is that?
A phobia?
What is it called when you're afraid of
germs?
Yeah.
Howie Mendell gets warts on his hands
apparently.
Yeah,
because he uses that hand cleaner so
much.
It's heavy.
It's getting worse.
Somebody.
We had a podcast the other day where
somebody knew he won't even touch
knuckles with you anymore.
He used to touch knuckles,
but now he won't even do that.
You know what,
man,
we've already talked about this,
but when you consider how filthy the
assholes and most people in the western
world are,
it kind of makes sense man,
because like we've sort of using toilet
paper to wipe your.
You're using toilet paper.
Yes.
That is gross.
But being such a Germaphobia is
preposterous because we are not one
thing.
We're terrified of these germs,
but we have germs in us.
We are germs.
You know we're not just one thing.
You should clean your hands.
Yes,
for sure.
You should definitely wash your dishes.
You should clean your ass.
You should,
but you also shouldn't be a fucking
freak.
Don't,
don't be crazy about it.
Don't be afraid to touch a table because
somebody might have touched it before.
You just wash your goddamn hands in each
vegetables so they know.
They say,
I think,
I mean I get given Duncan a couple stink
watches before where you don't wash your
finger and then when you shake hands you
just kind of rub it on the inside of
their hand right here and it makes it
smell food.
Ah Jeez man.
You guys were talking about on your
podcast.
It's you asshole Brian.
It just is asking know what I do.
He sits there and watches his asshole
for sure.
And that's completely false.
The you have your asshole and I'm
saying,
I'm saying you.
I'm saying.
I'm saying I know you have itched your
asshole by mistake before or at least at
least once or twice in life.
Right?
Make sure that if I do have to itch my
asshole that I wash my hands afterwards.
I am not convinced that you do the same.
See that.
See,
that's right there is just spreading
false information because.
Do you think I really.
It's my ass and it smells good.
No,
but I do everything that if you were
tired did you didn't feel like getting
up to go wash your hands and your
asshole,
you would hit your
asshole for sure and then go right back
to keyboard.
No,
I would suck it all and wipe it on my
shirt.
Disgusting Man.
Thirty seven year old man whose name is
red band.
We need a commercial.
The adventures of red band.
The avengers or band made up by you
because that was all bullshit.
You.
You know,
you.
You cry sensitive,
but you're the one who wants to
interrupt podcasts with digging your
asshole stories and that's how it got
started in the first place you had a
podcast.
We had a podcast where you jumped in the
middle of it and started talking about
you actually getting shit.
You guys tends because you were talking
about that and that's why you said it.
I don't believe we were,
but the point is you cannot bring to it.
You guys were just talking about is you
cannot bring something like that up.
Yep.
That preposterous.
And then be sensitive about people
talking about you itching your asshole
and having shit.
Although not the only reason I said that
is because I heard you talk about it on
Dunkin's podcast that I did this when in
fact I didn't do this.
So who did it?
Your asshole.
I said I have inched my asshole.
When you judge.
It's not sure asshole.
You cannot be judgmental about guys
talking about you itching your asshole.
Do you not understand that you opened up
a door?
It's like you fit your asshole to.
Yes,
exactly.
Then what's the big deal?
I told you I washed my hands and I did
and I never said I didn't.
You are a guarantee you.
So I didn't say I wash my hands.
I didn't wash my hands.
It's your asshole.
And then typing.
All right.
If you only had like three more words
type,
you would definitely go.
Well,
wash my hands in a little bit and just
I'll remember to wash this keyboard off.
I'll make up some shit about you.
Now listen,
Brian,
want to talk about itching your asshole
and getting shit on it.
You cannot be sensitive about that,
man.
That's silly.
Look,
you live not itched.
Your asshole problems are subject.
It becomes a subject.
Then it becomes fun.
You can't have you guys here if you're
an asshole,
right?
Yes.
How am I any different?
Because I talked about it.
Yes,
because I'm sorry for that.
Just based on your normal behavior that
I.
it's possible.
It's a possible example that you could
invest your asshole and then not gone to
the bathroom and washed it.
It was very possible.
That's very possible.
So that's what we made fun of,
Dude.
So fucking relax.
Now you're saying it as if I did though.
You said on your podcast.
I heard what we said to you.
It's your asshole.
And then didn't wash and then touching
everything.
Yeah,
that's what we said.
That's possible.
That's why it's funny.
Okay.
We don't know.
Obviously we weren't there while you
were itching.
Your asshole and touching things.
It's called goofing on you.
You can't goof on yourself in front of
us like that and then expect us not to
also do the same thing.
If there's anything that we grew fond
about ourselves during the podcast,
feel free to goof on it about us.
We're not here.
I mean if you're doing it yourself,
you can't be upset that other people are
doing it.
You're talking about digging your
asshole,
getting shit all over your hands.
You cannot be upset at other people.
Laughing about that.
If you want to.
Look,
I've talked about the podcast,
about shitting my pants.
I Shit my pants driving home from fear
factor once.
Shit my fucking pants plop filled them
up.
Just just held it in as long as I can,
but I was like,
oh,
just I couldn't.
I couldn't hold it anymore.
I was stuck in traffic.
It was.
It was a horrible diarrhea moment.
Feel free to make fun of that because it
actually did happen.
I actually did have to clean my car.
I actually did have to clean my pants is
that shit.
Didn't get into my car,
but my pants were soaking wet with shit,
so that kind of leaked through some of
the fabric and got all over my seats so
I had to get in there with windex.
I used an old toothbrush and shit's
disgusting.
That's real,
so you can make fun of that and when you
started talking about digging in your
ass and getting shit all over your
hands,
guess what?
Fela,
we're going to joke about it.
You can't be all sensitive about that
silly bitch.
No,
but I've heard you said or did,
and this is just.
I didn't even listen to the podcast.
What I heard you said is you're saying
you're telling that Brian stopped down.
Then stop now.
If you didn't listen to the podcast,
stop now.
Don't ever.
Don't ever comment on something,
especially in an angry way and not even
coming in angry and you're asking why I
brought it up and that.
I'm telling you why I brought it up
because I heard recently he were saying
that I did that.
That's how you asked how I brought up
the situation that I randomly threw in
something about what you were talking
about it.
It was a very similar,
what you guys were trying to settle the
fundus explained to him.
I said,
attack you barely on me,
man.
No,
I'm not crying.
You're being defensive about the fact
that we were joking around about you
itching,
you're being defensive.
You asked me why I randomly brought up
the fact and I was telling you,
we'll certainly are being defensive and
arguing about right now is very child
like that is very defense.
Did you see a dead mouse and Madonna?
Yes,
I did.
That's crazy.
What do you think about this?
Well,
dead mouse is a silly bitch.
He was making fun of Madonna because
Madonna,
like in,
you know,
people at my message board with totally
ragging on her for her attempted being
relevant,
you know,
she gets on stage like who here has
seeing molly?
Molly is a nickname for MDM,
which is her new album,
isn't it or is that a DNA?
Yeah,
but it's written kind of.
So she's just trying to.
She's trying to pump up our album.
Yeah,
I mean that's part of her thing is
connecting ourselves to this very,
very popular rave drug.
So I'm dead mouse gets a mad about it
and he gets pissed at her and saying,
you know,
her daughter,
you know you're connecting drugs.
So the electronic dance music movement,
and you shouldn't do that.
No,
you don't need his ideas.
You don't need drugs to enjoy that move.
The,
the,
uh,
the music that he's making or any of
those artists are making,
which is true.
You do not need drugs to do that.
I mean,
I've listened to stuff and I enjoyed it
and I wasn't.
I wasn't on drugs.
If you took Mtma he's,
he doesn't have any experience in it.
So that's why it's ridiculous.
So for him to say that,
it's like,
man,
you're,
you're talking shit about an experience
that for some people is maybe the most
energetic and positive experience I've
ever had in their life is being high on
ecstasy at a rave.
Listening to dance,
music,
food,
being an excellent mgma and standing in
front of a speaker the size of a house
blasting
out fucking awesome house music.
There's nothing like that.
It's a cool.
That's the best.
That's what most people go to see that
music,
you know,
on.
And Molly,
that's the whole point of listening to
the music.
But what he's saying is it's giving his
electronic music a bad name,
you know,
like you don't have to enjoy listening
to that kind of music on my.
But I think that's ridiculous.
That's like saying reggae music without
marijuana.
That's like saying like rap without
stealing a car.
You're certainly not going to.
That is something I remember that that
was like back in the day when I used to
go to the Raves,
that was like one section of people who
would go to go to the res and a very
small one.
We're a group of like connoisseurs of
the music who didn't think that you
should pollute your mind with the drugs
and just enjoy purely enjoy the music.
Well,
the problem is we had dead mouse on the
podcast.
He was drunk as fuck and he wouldn't
stop smoking cigarettes.
He
chain smoke cigarettes and he was drunk
as fuck.
And I enjoyed hanging out with them.
Don't get me wrong,
I like to do it,
but I think he's,
I think his whole thought processes is
really.
It's uninformed.
And I think if he had experiences with
psychedelic drugs and music,
I mean not that MDM is a psychedelic and
you can be happened once that happened,
I think is what they call it,
but it's impactful.
It is what it is.
It,
it has a Mtma had a very strong
influence on my behavior.
It gave me a very,
very deep insight into behavior patterns
and insecurity.
I said on my message board,
it was like,
I think he could use some Mtma.
I really think it could,
you know,
not that he's a bad guy,
but I think that there's a lot of,
a lot of people,
they have a certain amount of
unnecessary anger inside of them,
a certain amount of unnecessary judgment
and Mtma will knock that shit right out
of you.
It's such a loving feeling and that's
one of the reasons why they're using it
for posttraumatic stress disorder,
for,
for vets coming back from,
from Iraq and Afghanistan.
And that's,
that's a positive thing,
man.
That's a good thing.
Our people abusing it and dancing.
Of course they are.
But that goes back to what I said in
that movie,
the Union people can abuse
cheeseburgers.
Should we make cheeseburgers illegal?
I can take a fork and stick in my eyes.
She would make fortunately.
Do you know how many people a year die
from drinking?
The statistic is 100,000.
Yeah,
between 70 and 100.
And that
doesn't even include drunk driving
deaths.
By the way,
the desk themselves to death.
People die from alcohol poisoning.
People died from overdosing on alcohol.
People die from sclerosis of the liver
directly related to alcoholism.
But MTMA is a small amount.
It's like illegal drugs in this country
is only like 12,000
people die here.
The real problem is prescription drugs
right now,
which you're overcoming drunk driving
accidents.
And as far as fatalities,
oh my God.
Those are the words.
People die from those left and right.
Man.
I have a friend who died,
but I have a friend who died in New
York,
a pool player,
and he was a great guy and a straight
edge.
He was straight edge,
made fun of people smoke cigarettes,
and then all of a sudden he hurt his
back and when he hurt his back,
he had a.
He got on some oxycodones or one of
those and just that was it ya.
Bye Bye.
Trains changes.
Life fell asleep and his mashed
potatoes.
Everyone's hanging out together.
The fucking.
I just falls asleep.
Sitting there eating dinner,
plopped down,
sat like a movie plot,
puts his arm down and falls asleep on a
plate.
So sad dude.
It's the saddest thing ever,
man.
It really is.
It's sad.
It's really sad when you consider that
these drugs,
these synthetic drugs that people are,
that are killing so many people are semi
legal.
Alcohol is killing everybody and it's
totally legal.
Whereas these empath and an empathogen
like Mtma that when you take it,
you can.
If you have some discipline,
you can go dancing.
It's fun to go dancing on it,
but if you have some discipline,
you can shift your life into the
positive forever.
Yes.
If you have some discipline and if
you're working with someone or if
you're.
If you know what you're doing,
well,
if you're honest with your about your
experience of your person who's truly
looking to improve who you are as a
person,
I think NBM Mtma can be very impactful.
I didn't like the way it made me feel.
I wouldn't recommend anybody doing it.
I would say,
man,
you have to weigh your pros and cons.
Even though it impacted me in a very
positive way.
I remember feeling absolutely terrible
the next day.
I don't think it's good for your body.
I don't want to do it again just,
but I learned a lot from doing it and
the fact that oxycontin's,
which are literally synthetic,
Carolyn,
literally this,
that is what it is.
There's no data.
It is a synthetic opiate.
It is incredibly,
incredibly addictive.
People who've done heroin say it's
easier to kick heroin than it is to kick
pills.
The oxycontin pills somehow or another,
and the way they're constructed,
the way it impacts with the human body
makes them even more addictive.
It's just insanity.
Well,
they're fucking fish hooks,
dude.
There fish hooks coming out of the
pharmaceutical companies to get stuck in
people's brains.
You get a fucking fish hook in your
brain attached to a giant corporation.
It's got you fucking wired in whether
you're getting it legally or not.
It's like telephone wires all connecting
back to the telephone company from the
brain's all these pill poppers.
It's just fucking lines going back.
No benefit whatsoever except a little
bit of pain relief.
The benefit social,
the social benefit of MTMA would be
gigantic.
Madison County and maybe Kim legal.
You imagine that it was prescribed,
but the problem is also,
you know,
you got people who would oh,
on and people who drink when they take
the,
there's a,
there's a lot of different
possibilities.
People could fuck it up.
Yeah,
they can fuck it up.
And guess what?
They get to you because their,
it's their life and their.
Yes,
and they can do that with alcohol and
they can do the,
you know,
the fact that there's all these laws
against things like MDM and mushrooms
and things in mushrooms are worth,
really gets crazy because you can't
overdo,
you know,
who the fuck has ever overdosed on
mushrooms.
You have to take,
you have to eat like pounds of it.
The ld 50 rate for for mushrooms is
really high.
Like you,
you got to be really trying to garbage
bag.
I think it's like a garbage,
which by the way is you could eat way
less salt and you'd be dead.
You know,
you get eat like you don't even have to
eat a pound of salt.
You're fucking gone man.
You Ain't coming back.
You know,
you try to have,
you ate a pound of salt and just sat
there with a tablespoon and just started
eating salt.
You had a whole pound bag.
That's it.
That's a wrap kid.
You're dead.
Yeah.
You could die from drinking water.
Remember we were in Sacramento and that
lady died and a contest.
The contest.
It's so sad that happened to a frat kid
too.
They were,
um,
there were a hazing,
a frat kid.
They made him drink water until he
couldn't drink anymore.
He fucking died too.
Die.
Yeah.
It's so fucked up,
man.
It's a terrible way.
Go.
Weird laws that protect people.
Cigarettes being legals,
the most preposterous
but,
and also remember like the impulse for
many people are taking psychedelics is
not to try to wipe out the universe,
but it's to try to go deeper into the
universe.
And so that means that a lot of people
in the jails right now and a lot of
people in the dungeons,
they had the same instincts is like a
lot of the great philosophers.
They just wanted to expand their mind
and understand a little bit about the
universe and they're in prison now.
They're imprisoned and so from the
prohibition,
you're not just getting an inability to
go enjoy a great fucking night at some
underground party or the inability to
like have a great camping trip with your
pals.
It's literally,
I think,
stifling evolution because God knows
what amazing thoughts people could be
coming up with if there was a regulated
psychedelics that and we got to explore
them to understand how to really use
them and how to really fucking a harness
them to make us smarter.
You know,
this is something that's the birthright
of humanity.
All indigenous tribes have some form of
psychedelic that they take.
This is like the ancient people of the
earth knew about this pot Iowasca.
Yet somehow in the modern age,
they're keeping us from this experience
that maybe is the thing that connected
the native Americans to the earth that
you were talking about in the beginning.
Maybe it is the thing that made people
not so fucking fixated on material
possessions,
you know,
but it's white.
We have a prohibition happening now.
It's the dark ages.
It's like,
imagine if there was a book,
just some book and inside of it was
amazing information that will teach you
how to overcome your ego,
that will connect you with your brothers
and sisters around you.
There's this amazing book and it's
surrounded by a fence that the
governments are wrecked and they're
like,
sorry,
I can't read that fucking book.
Can't read it.
It's illegal.
You read that book.
You're going to the dungeon.
If we catch you distributing this book,
copies of this book,
we put you in the dungeon.
Doesn't make any sense,
man.
Why aren't they letting us read that
fucking book?
I don't know anyone who died on
mushrooms.
I don't know anyone where anything bad
happen to them on mushrooms.
Nobody.
I've never heard it.
I'm sure it's out there,
but
I don't.
I've never heard that.
I've heard a lot of things bad on
mushrooms.
All those people were all bitches.
Every person I've ever met that had like
a horrible trip on mushrooms.
They all had like psychological shit.
They were dealing with
five bad problems.
I got sick.
I was shitting myself.
Oh well that's possibly food poisoning.
Most looks.
Bad trips I think are overdosing.
I think that's all it is.
There's an overdose of how much
mushrooms
you should have based on how much you
ate that day.
How much.
I don't know.
All the factors needs to be regulated
because then it can be dispensed like
synthetic I've,
but we're talking about,
um,
the whole idea behind the fact that
these drugs,
like cocaine are illegal,
is what keeps them from being impure.
Know everyone,
cuts them up.
Everyone adds all this stuff to them.
You couldn't do that if it was sold by
Coca Cola.
Coco was selling cocaine.
Sure you know,
you,
you would have to have the ingredients
listed right there on it.
You would know exactly what it was.
You,
they would have to sell your actual
cocaine,
you know,
but when you buying it from some fucking
kid at a rave,
you,
he's calling it Mtma.
Hope he's right.
You don't know.
You're taking a chance.
You want to party,
you want to have a good time.
Who knows what the fuck it is.
It's like what your idea is,
was talking about with the cocaine the
other day.
That's what I just said.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
You don't even listening.
That's what we were actually saying.
That's the subject we were talking,
dude,
if I did,
if I had a time machine,
Rogan and I could go back in time,
one of my stops on the way back to the
crucifixion would be to fucking pick up
a cocaine laden bottle of Coca Cola.
Haven't you always wondered what that
was like to drink at cocaine?
Cocaine,
coke,
do it.
It's got to be.
Well,
when we say cocaine,
this is also.
We talked about this in the podcast or
stayed the coca leaf.
The chewing of the coca leaf has a very
complete.
It's a very different reaction than I'm
eating and by the way,
a coca leaves are still in Coca Cola.
A lot of people don't know,
but yeah,
you,
they still important.
Even though cocoa leaves are illegal,
they still import coca leaves to using
Coca Cola.
I might be talking on my end.
I think they changed the formula for
that for a long time ago.
I don't know.
Is that when they showed it was like the
20th or something like that?
Yeah.
No,
no.
I think it was like a long,
long time ago.
Not sure about that.
Uh,
I'm not sure about that,
but anyway,
the point is the coca leaf,
which,
which they,
they,
you know,
they had,
that was,
that was an ingredient,
right,
but were they using cocaine as an
ingredient or was it just the coca
leaves?
I don't know.
I mean,
it wasn't sherlock holmes addicted to
cocaine and those books.
I think it was a lot of guys.
I thought it was morphine.
It wasn't a morphine.
I can't remember.
Is that,
um,
wider,
wider up used to go to the morphine
probably people.
Well,
yeah,
and they had opium dens and I think
Freud was really into coke.
I think there were like blasting
themselves with coke everywhere and I
was totally illegal,
like no one,
it wasn't regulated back then.
As far as I know.
I,
I think you could at least get
prescriptions for it.
I've seen like cool all bought.
I mean if it's in fucking coke fits in
Coca Cola,
it's illegal.
Yeah,
there is actual legal people.
Must've been a noxious back then.
Everyone's on coke.
It must've been the worst.
Cocacola actually does have a legal
importation of the coca leaf.
I'm still.
Yes,
coca,
Coca Cola.
The coke formula is one of the most
closely guarded corporate secrets in
America.
The company can seeds that using a d,
cocaine,
ised flavor essence in the coca leaves
is one of the few coke ingredients that
company will publicly acknowledged.
So they are using an actual abstract of
the coca leaf that has no cocaine in it.
So I was right.
Yeah,
I know that cocaine going.
They're extracting.
Dude,
who do
I saw goes to Elton John's.
All the cocaine in the world.
You imagine if Coca Cola turned out to
be the number one dealer and on Earth if
they're d extracting cocaine from.
Where's it going?
Done right away.
We don't even need it.
Even though the Chileans forget that
money.
Okay,
we're here to sell kids sugary shit that
makes your teeth rot out.
We're not here to kill anybody and the
guys actually Dr Pepper the whole time.
He's like scarface,
character of the Coca Cola company.
All you need to know about the weather
or not,
they would make money off of things like
that is who's making money off
cigarettes?
Cigarettes are fucking for sure.
Killing,
yeah,
like almost a half a million people a
year in this country alone.
Our ideas about intoxication are so
bizarre and baffling that somehow or
another we think that they are
protecting us from something that
perturbs our state of consciousness that
makes us think about things in a
completely different way and possibly
even hallucinate,
but some weird surge that you get
because of an almost immediate addiction
that you've acquired to some stupid
fucking burning plant that's soaked in
chemicals.
No one even discusses it.
It never comes up.
Not at all.
No campaigns ever bring it up.
No one ever promised.
People are promising bases on the moon.
Newt Gingrich got desperate and plump,
promised a base on the moon.
By the time he had a second term,
he threw a hail Mary.
It's like based on the mood.
No one ever says,
we need to make cigarettes illegal and
save.
Our friends were dying a horrible death,
addicted to a terrible chemical that's
sick company as profiting off,
and we need to really change the way we
look to change the way we look at this
terrible,
terrible scourge in America.
No one,
not,
not a single politician would ever make
that speech and meanwhile they did.
They'd want a dead in the fucking hotel
room somewhere,
but meanwhile,
if any anyone running for president
said,
I think that psilocybin makes you
connect with the universe and it makes
you love the people around you more and
it gives you more of an experience of a
full life and reminds you of how small
you are in relation to everything out so
you can't really God on it.
So I don't think it should be illegal if
somebody said that.
If a president said that right now,
like Santorum said that,
or somebody said that they would never
get elected.
Did you say that?
But I don't.
I don't agree.
Not only will.
The only way they would never get
elected is if they would never get
elected anyway because elections aren't
real.
But could they change the public's
consciousness?
Absolutely depressed.
But if you got an eloquent guy,
well the evidence John Hopkins,
the recent John Hopkins University,
sure it would work a 20 year period of
time.
All these people that took mushrooms
just once at a direct change in their
personality and improvement of their
personality,
illegal.
Of course it shouldn't be illegal,
but I think that if someone was eloquent
and someone made sense in all other
areas,
if someone was a bright person and they
can prove it with data and prove it in
an articulate and eloquent manner,
where it was compelling were what they
were telling you was that,
here's what's going on.
Okay,
I know you're all associating drugs with
being a negative thing and the reason
for that.
It's intelligent to do so.
Most drugs and many,
many drugs can be very negative on your
life.
However,
we've been sold a bill of goods on
certain drugs and certain drugs are
actually good for you.
Not only are they good for you,
they may be the whole reason we evolved
from fucking monkeys in the first place,
but we been lied to and the companies
that keep us in order right now would
like to keep everything the way it is.
The reason being is they're profiting
off things being illegal.
There's a lot of profit on drugs being
illegal that are illegal currently.
It's not as simple as they would just
sell them to and then they would make
the money.
Why wouldn't they make it legal?
There is money to be made that will not
be available once psychedelic drugs or
illegal.
There's a lot of things that are for
sale,
especially pharmaceutical drugs.
A huge amount that just making marijuana
legal would just squash the market for a
good percentage of pain relief and
Glaucoma medication reduces interocular
pressure.
P people on aids who have aids,
who,
uh,
can eat,
people on chemotherapy that have a hard
time eating all of that.
There's so many drugs that are
prescribed for various elements that
literally would be out of business.
So and,
and,
and so consider this,
take it to the human level.
This is where it gets fucked up.
We have access to certain mind states
where you can bring back authentic
information.
They can help your life and the life of
the people around you.
And there's a possibility that if enough
people were having these mind states,
there might be an acceleration in
technology and acceleration and science
and acceleration and philosophy,
but because we can't get these mind
states,
we can't get these mind states.
Things are slow and weird and dumb right
now.
And the reason we can't get it is so
that people can make more money.
Okay.
Well,
let me play devil's advocate please.
First off,
there's a lot of people that think that
a lot of hippies are fucking mooches.
They mooch off the government,
they get welfare,
they get public aid,
they don't want to pull their share.
They don't want to pull their own
weight.
A lot of people think that these,
these experiences that you say that will
benefit people,
they say,
well,
where's the evidence?
Where's the evidence of anybody finding
out anything worthwhile on,
on psychedelics?
Terence Mckenna?
That doesn't mean anything.
Francis Crick.
Okay.
That's a rumor after he died that was
released as that.
He was a deathbed confession.
No,
he was good friends with a brave new
world out as Huxley is friends with
Huxley.
Yeah,
no,
it's true.
It's true if you were friends with not
saying,
but okay,
that's true that he took it,
but it doesn't mean the.
The,
the,
what the statement is,
is that he discovered the double helix
strand.
He figured it out while he was on Lsd.
That's all anecdotal.
That's all deathbed confessions.
He never said that anywhere.
There's no.
It's not written anywhere.
So just in fairness,
I don't think you can directly attribute
that to him.
I've looked at the sources for that.
It's possible that he said that,
but I don't think you can stay.
I can.
I mean,
you're like in a court of law.
I can't prove it,
but being friends with Aldous Huxley,
a manual on his deathbed,
he had himself injected with like 750
micrograms of Lsd.
Being friends with that guy.
That's like being friends with you.
You'll never haven't gotten stumped.
No,
no,
no.
You're not.
You're misunderstanding me.
Yes.
He probably did do LSD.
The question is,
what did he get out of it?
How do you,
how do you know?
He didn't just hallucinate.
You know,
there's no evidence.
There's no evidence that it helped them
in any way.
Do you know what I'm saying?
It's not like they pulled some nothing
on paper.
There's nothing you can be like.
Look here.
There is one guy,
Kerry,
Kary Mullis.
I'm kary Mullis.
He was a Nobel prize winning chemist and
he said that LSD had helped him develop
a polymers chain reaction that helps
amplify,
amplify specific DNA sequences.
And he figured that out while I was on
acid.
Well,
there's one.
So there's one.
Can you.
Can you read that again?
What he did here?
Here's the full thing.
During a symposium held a for Albert
Hoffman,
Hoffman revealed that he was told by
Nobel prize winning chemist,
Kary Mullis that LSD had helped him
develop the Pala polymers.
Pete hope I'm saying this right.
P O l y m e r a s e Dot polyamorous,
polyamorous.
Anyway,
Jamie,
action that helps amplify specific DNA
sequences.
What does that mean?
I don't know.
I'm too stupid for that,
but the,
um,
the guy said,
I'm Kari Moss even admitted a.
What if I had not taken lsd ever?
I would.
I still have invented PCR.
That was the method.
I don't know.
I doubt it.
I seriously doubt that's what I'm
saying,
Bro.
That's what I'm saying.
There's a fucking group of people who've
got their fucking clause dug into the
force of evolution and they're trying to
hold it back.
Okay.
But if all the people that have done
Lsd,
one fucking guy says he figured once
I've done lsd 100 times,
I have not learned any new or not the
best example,
but have you learned,
have you learned something about
yourself personally?
Insight,
personal insight solution.
Personally member.
What I'm doing though,
I am playing devil's advocate.
I'm a republican with shiny shoes on
with black socks and you know,
I'm the guy who was telling you that if
you buy drugs you support terrorism.
Yeah.
No,
no,
no.
You told me one guy,
one guy says he invented a PCR method,
which you don't even understand why I
was on LSD.
Okay.
So we should have lsd legal because guy
in d we should have all psychedelics
mushrooms as well.
Right.
But when you start throwing it around.
What about the arts?
Devil's advocate.
I know.
No,
I don't.
I'm not even seeing you now.
I'm just seeing what about,
uh,
what about the fucking art man?
What a man does that not count?
What,
what good lsd art.
Do you know of?
What's the best to Jimi Hendrix glow.
Okay.
Jimmy Hendrix is more heroin,
wasn't even heroin and cocaine,
wasn't he?
Wasn't he a heroin guy?
Purple Haze.
That's purple haze.
Isn't that pot dude?
Jimi Hendrix was so into fucking LSD or
purple haze.
Is that potter?
Is that it is now purple haze was
asking.
Well,
I'm sure he did ask it.
Don't get me wrong,
but do you think that that's why he was
so good?
I mean,
wasn't he like really good when he was a
bad ass?
Fucking gets helped him.
But again,
I know you're playing devil's advocate,
but I'm being devil's advocate is the
same thing as being friends with a
pedophile.
I mean,
you don't want to be devil's advocate.
It's the worst force in the universe and
always represents everything evil and
bad.
No,
I take the side of an argument that
doesn't currently exist with this table
because I'm sure somebody is screaming
it out on twitter,
right?
Devil's advocate is I,
you know,
I think for sure psychedelics can,
uh,
can help people.
But what I think it is is I think
essentially we have access to super
computers and there's no instruction
manuals laying around and there's no
teachers to teach her how to use these
things.
So a lot of people are getting great
results and they're all scattered and
all over the poor and they're mixed in
with psychosis and bad trips and a lot
of fucking freaky,
freaky things that have happened to
people and they've taken the wrong shit
and they got ahold of a fake computer.
You know,
there's a lot of people that are in that
is because there's lack of regulation
because there's a lack of understanding
because there's a lack of appreciation
for the true effects as human beings.
It is absolutely preposterous.
It's so many people will tell you this,
Carrie,
most guy or whether Francis Crick was
telling you the truth or whether you're
telling me the truth or I'm telling you
the truth or any of us that have had
really positive experiences.
There's there's way too many people that
are saying that folks can benefit from
it,
for it to stay illegal.
The people that are stopping it,
they don't make any more sense than us.
It's not like they're.
They're.
They're really wise and cautious and
noble and loving overlords that want to
protect you from your own folly.
That is not what's going on because they
they're.
They're talking and ignorant statements.
Medically.
It's ignorance.
There's no evidence to back up what
they're saying.
There's no reason that it makes sense
and then when you start throwing numbers
at their face like the,
the amount of nonviolent drug offenders
that are in jail and how preposterous it
is that our society exists where a bunch
of people were doing what they want to
do that doesn't hurt anybody else and
someone decides to lock them in a cage
for it.
Well,
that person is who's doing more harm.
The guy was smoking pot,
or the person who locked him in a
fucking cage destroys their life and
does it because it's written on paper
somewhere that that's okay.
Well,
that guy,
a destructive.
The law
becomes a destructive force in society,
not the drug.
When you say drugs,
kill people and drugs,
drugs are responsible for a million
people in jail right now.
That's why I don't do drugs.
You won't get locked up.
No,
no,
no.
Don't put people in cages because they
don't agree with you because they like
something.
They like it so much.
They're willing to risk freedom because
they found themselves in some sort of a
situation when they're in an environment
that they have no control over
whatsoever.
They were born into this,
they didn't ask to be dropped into this
preposterous,
illogical,
nonsensical,
ridiculously lopsided and corrupt
society,
and you just accept them to comply.
You just expect them to comply with
these stupid fucking things that are
written down on paper that everybody
knows.
Makes no sense.
Well,
that's.
That's the problem.
The laws are the problem.
The laws are destructive.
The laws are anti evolutionary.
The laws are they're anti enlightenment.
That's the problem.
It's not the drug.
It's not pot.
It's not mushrooms.
It's the laws against pot and mushrooms.
Those are a devastating aspect of our
society.
Those are not the fucking drugs you
dummies missed it.
You missed the whole thing.
You're not protecting anybody.
You fucks and anybody that hasn't done
drugs,
if you haven't done mushrooms,
fucking for sure you shouldn't be a cop.
No Way,
man.
You're going to be in position of power
with a gun and making decisions and
you've never done any mushrooms at all.
You've never had any.
Look at yourself through the eyes of
alien intelligence.
You've never had some objective outside
the body experience analyzing all this
shitty aspects of your own life.
How the fuck are you growing?
How are you developing?
Are you crawling along and one little
stumble after another and one little
apology after another and one little
breakup and make up cycle after another.
After another way,
you scream insults at each other and
then so I'm sorry,
baby will never happen again.
Have learned Milosevic.
Is that what you're learning about
yourself from your,
your,
your Shitty,
lonely nights,
eating TV dinners,
hoping that your is going to return your
pager or your text message rather so you
can paint her pastors was go back in
time.
But that's what I'm saying,
you know,
getting someone to respond to you,
getting somebody you know because you,
you,
you realized that being a cunt,
you know,
makes people not like you anymore.
So that's how you grow up,
you know,
instead of like seeing it in one big
burst,
all leaders,
all cops,
all teachers,
all of them should have a psychedelic
experience or they don't know what the
fuck they're talking about as a grown
adult.
If you haven't had a psychedelic
experience,
I look at you like you're some sort of
an infant.
You do.
Y'All look at you like your infant
toddler.
It's like I look at you like form
illiterates.
Yeah,
it is.
It is like a form of like awareness,
illiteracy.
Yeah.
That,
that's a,
that's a great way to put it,
man.
Awareness,
illiteracy.
And it's sad that for some reason
they're keeping as they're keeping so
many people illiterate,
but it's the practice.
They are literate.
That's why they're doing it.
They,
they are suffering under their own
control and their own or most of them
are.
I mean there's a Texas judge who just
got arrested for fucking smoking weed.
Oh really?
Somebody turned them in.
The hotel think it's fucked up.
I think things are gonna Change,
man.
I mean they're lying saying this is the
third year letting the studies happen
again.
And if they're letting the studies
happen again,
there's some reason behind that.
I mean the studies are happening.
They're allowing them to happen for the
first time and I think 30 or 40 years
they're opening them up because
government is dangerously suppressive,
dangerously suppressive.
And not so much with civil liberties,
like a or rather with medical marijuana
and things along those lines.
But that's because it's democratic.
When the ball goes in the opposite
court,
think about how much power has been
given to the government under this,
this democratic regime.
If we got another Bush Cheney,
an office and they started cracking down
like John Ashcroft did on the medical
marijuana places and using losing
blackwater to come in,
mercenaries will fucking machine guns on
their hips and taking all the pot and
money away.
If that shit starts happening again,
think about how much power Obama has
given the government.
Its ridiculous.
It's,
it's,
it's really disgusting and preposterous.
I mean,
if you look at the Huffington,
Huffington Post,
there's an article by this guy named
Jim,
Jim Garrison,
and it's martial law by executive order
not to be confused with Jim Garrison
that thought that Lee Harvey Oswald
didn't kill Kennedy.
You remember that guy?
The prosecutor.
Anyway,
um,
this,
uh,
Obama,
he passed the National Defense
Organization,
uh,
the NDA,
the new executive order called um,
the,
uh,
national defense resources preparedness,
executive order.
And it does the country as a whole,
what the 2012 national defense
authorization act to the constitution in
particular,
completely eviscerate any due process or
judicial oversight for any action by the
government deemed in the interest of
national security.
So they can just say something's
Essentially we're under martial law like
they can just say,
and it's up to the government now,
all the,
the,
the checks and balances that were put in
place by the constitution to ensure that
there would be no corruption.
There would be no ultimate power
corrupting ultimately.
Well,
they,
they've removed all that shit and you
know,
right now everybody's like,
look,
but you're fine.
No one's no one's dying.
No,
nothing's happening.
The people that you say yes to today may
not be the people you say yes to 10
years from now or 20 years from now and
these laws are crazy.
These laws are that we might as well be
living in fucking North Korea and that's
not ridiculous.
That's not an exaggeration.
These are unconstitutional laws and
they're not going to stop.
Now.
They're going to go more and more and
more and more control until ultimately
the government,
which is by the way a approved the idea
of sending drones.
They're going to within the bike,
I think it was 12,
20,
they're going to have a 2020 rather.
They're going to have 30,000
drones in the sky,
but North America.
Awesome.
Come up constantly watching everything
you do.
Well.
Did you.
Have you seen that youtube video of this
swarms of quadcopters?
Have you seen that?
No.
Dude,
look that at Google Quadra.
Pull it up,
right?
Holy Shit Man.
This is it.
So there are these things called quadra
copters that they're working on that are
just like exactly like the toys that you
see,
but much smaller.
These fucking things man,
they can like
they move information.
It says video of them flying
information.
Just this swarm of tiny little nano or a
tiny quadra copters they can like they
give like turned sideways to go through
windows.
They're like,
they can go anywhere man.
So and.
But the scary thing that I never
considered was that they can fucking fly
information.
That's where it gets weird when you
imagine like just seeing like a swarm of
these things descending around your
house or fluids checking you out on the
street.
You're just walking.
We're just walking down the street and
they come and like buzzing.
Do a quick facial scan to get your
fucking face.
Match it up with like whatever
facebook's doing,
Bang,
you know,
like.
So yeah.
So privacy is a,
um,
it's an escaping thing.
It's on its way out.
But the problem is the government,
these consultant running things are
gonna have so much more power than the
average citizen.
We're going to be under the rule of an
oppressive government that has the law
on their side because they changed all
the fuck on paper.
They changed all the stupid shit that's
written down that allows them to do
cunty things.
They changed it all and they put it all
in their defense.
And essentially what they did is the
United States is now under martial law,
but there's no emergency,
no emergency.
It doesn't have to have a national
emergency.
Did just be under martial law.
Now we're just under martial law.
Why?
Why is that?
What the fuck is going on?
Part of it has got to be because they're
losing control.
That's got to be part of it.
They feel like the Internet and all this
anonymous shit and the hackers and
occupied.
It's like,
what is this?
Spell it out for him.
Tell him.
I think it's q u,
a d,
r a copter.
That's what it is.
Quadra Copter,
swarm.
Maybe someone will tweet it.
Someone tweeted it to me.
It freaked me out for a week.
I showed it to.
I showed it to Eddie Bravo at the UFC
and his face went white.
He just was like,
what the fuck?
Swarm of Nana quadros.
That's it.
It's Nano.
Quad raters.
Yeah.
There we go.
Oh Shit.
Look at that.
Just watch it gets better.
That's just one of these fucking things.
Get Ready,
man.
Those things are probably going to eat
your baby one day.
Ooh.
That sound.
When you hear that sound,
you know you're about to get busted.
Whoa.
They just fly around and maneuver.
Okay.
I'm surprised you haven't seen these
vehicles can fly as a formation.
Oh my God.
This is terrifying.
It's gonna sound like Nascar all over
the world.
We're living in the future.
This is really fun.
That's awesome.
This is really nuts.
Yeah.
This is a method to transition between
formations in three d
folks.
You have to see this because what you
will,
what you're not seeing is these guys are
moving in perfect geometrical.
They move in these formations and
they're showing it from overhead and
it's.
It's amazing.
Their precision is incredible.
This is terrifying.
By the way.
This is only like version one.
You know,
this is like the first iphone gets
smaller and smaller.
This is incredible.
I wonder how long they can stay in the
air for.
Oh my God,
look at that.
They're moving in a figure eight,
a perfect figure.
Eight.
Oh my God.
This is spectacular.
This is really scary
stuff.
Scary Shit,
man.
Now look at them building.
Look up quadra copter building a
structure.
Build Shit,
man.
They can actually pick shit up and start
gluing it built.
They can actually build structures.
That's amazing.
That's what Kurzweil was talking about,
man,
because when those things shrink down
enough so that they can like imagine
like just a pile of fucking legos and a
shitload of those fucking things and
they could actually form matter.
That's where it gets really cool.
Think about that forming matter.
That's where it gets weird when you've
got a computer directing swarms of those
things to construct architecture that
humans couldn't even make,
you know,
like weird fucking geometries.
That can only happen when a computers
and control the building process.
If it ever gets to that point,
it might be the just start fucking
killing people.
Well,
that's funny thing man.
People always say that about computers
where they're like,
they're just going to kill us,
but I guess it's.
I don't think it's going to be the
computers.
It would be the things controlling them.
Like people automatically assume when
the machine inevitably wakes up,
it's,
it's gonna want to get,
I want to kill us,
but
plague,
you know,
if it looked at the environment it's
living in and realize that there's
massive overpopulating entity that's
spilling all.
It's bullshit into the sea and eating
all the fucking animals that live in it
and then they will just calculate how
long can this last?
Well,
it can't at this rate,
so they'll just start eating the country
now.
Man.
Fucking work.
It'd be great.
Maybe we would eliminate.
No,
I don't even.
I don't people out of the sky just
conscious gets sucked out of the sky.
I get they're watching and watching
everything.
That's a little bit that machines are
watching everything and when you litter
and when you're a shithead and when you
beat,
your wife just gets sucked out of.
Guy Won't get down voted.
Yeah.
You get a certain number of negatives.
Downvotes like on Reddit,
if you get as a person has certain
number they carry you in this phase,
rub points.
If you get blocked by a certain amount
of people,
just them building this thing.
Oh my God,
crazy fucking thing.
Well,
this,
the thing that they're building is this
enormous like lego building that's
really cool looking.
That was blocks have glue on them or
something,
and by the way,
this is just the beginning of that shit
that's going to be.
That didn't exist 20 years ago.
There was no no hope of that.
Twenty years ago,
20 years from now.
What do check this out?
If you ever seen,
if you've ever seen the video of that,
there a machine that you can take to the
desert that someone made.
It's solar powered because there's so
much energy and it focuses the energy of
the sun and the desert to turn sand into
blocks.
It can burn
sanding blocks,
so now imagine this combined,
those fucking things with solar panels
and a thing that can infinitely can use
an infinite amount of sand in the desert
to make blocks.
Those things could fly out in the
fucking desert and make infinitely
gigantic structures with endless fucking
energy.
Just the combination of those two
technologies at the rudimentary level
that they're at now,
if we can fucking figure out how to make
them solar power.
Solar is really interesting.
It's like it's kind of hit a wall and a
lot of ways.
So what are you,
what are you doing?
I googled a solar power sandbox and it
came up with minecraft.
Solar power is not really strong enough
for a lot of shit right now for most
people.
Can't like have all their electricity
through solar power.
You use like a lot of people use.
Like I have a friend that uses a
combination of solar and wind and he
actually developed enough from the.
He lives in Oregon.
He develops enough from nothing.
He actually sells it back to the grid,
which I don't know.
Strange.
How do you do that?
I don't understand it.
Yeah,
I don't get it.
How do you do what?
Sell Electricity back.
They pay him.
Yeah.
There's a meter on it that regulates it
going in.
But you could also have it fitted so it
regulates how much is going on here.
So he adds.
So the local power plant or whatever is
supplying them power doesn't have to
work as hard.
That's so fucking weird,
man.
Crazy.
You can turn wind into money.
Well,
if you ever been.
There's certain parts of California
where we,
uh,
we have filmed some fear factors where
they have these um,
these huge,
like they look like a farm of these wind
things.
These windmills,
like a windmill farm and there's a
shitload of them just sitting up on a
hill and they power the area.
I don't mind it.
I don't know how much they power,
how many structures,
how many buildings.
But it's enough that the,
a lot of shit is getting powered by the
wind.
It's really a trip.
Well,
it's really windy out there too,
so it's a smart thing to do like even as
you come out here towards Pasadena and
you head up the 2:10
and when you go through that whole
mountain ipass ii area where it's like
you lose your cell phone signal,
fucking beautiful out there.
Windy as fuck.
A lot of people have like real wind
problems.
Even out here,
like remember when they had a problem?
Really recently the wind knocked down a
lot of power cables and Pastina guy
because he got fucked by wind.
I got trapped here.
I couldn't even lead the place.
Fuck why wind from the was too bad.
I like seriously the street out front
here with trees flying down the street,
things off,
flying off the roofs,
like metal things and awnings and stayed
in.
They couldn't get to.
My car was too scary,
man.
It was a death.
It was deadly outside.
It was like being in a tornado.
Wow.
No,
it was no,
seriously.
It was really bad.
It.
There's nothing like NATO.
Next time you go out in his back door
over here,
look at the billboard.
That's billboard wishes ripping apart
and it was like a super old billboard
was shaking like this and things were
just flying off of it.
That's really powerful,
but it's nothing like a fucking tornado.
There's,
uh,
there's been tornadoes that were hit or
hit cities in the middle of the night
and literally made the city disappear.
Especially towns,
small towns in the middle of nowhere.
You know,
what they say that the heat of cities
actually prevents tornadoes since all
the structure and the way it's the way
it's built and the heat coming off of it
apparently doesn't work in cities.
Do you believe any of that weather
control shit they talk about like,
um,
what's the name of like that,
you know,
these Eddie Bravo on here for this
conversation.
Do you believe in that?
Like they've been,
they've been trying to like actually
can.
I know they do it like in China,
don't they?
Like they've been playing around trying
to make it rain and like you can put
certain particles into the air that
actually makes it rain.
Um,
well they're doing.
It sounds like it's some kind of weird.
Yeah,
they will for sure have done that.
In Abu Dhabi.
They did it more than 50 times last
year.
I think they did it once a week.
Last year.
They made it ran.
Yeah.
I don't remember what the exact chemical
they use,
whether there's something with the gum
line,
the crowds with a something silver.
I don't remember what it is,
but um,
they,
they in the clouds with this shit and it
makes a rand.
So it's so odd to think about Nicole.
It's still Nicholson,
I don't know,
but it's really fucking odd to think
about the fact that they're just
starting to learn to control the
weather.
They're just starting to learn to
control the,
whether they're just starting to learn
to have endless amounts of energy.
So if we were to evolve and advance
without blowing each other up,
we would eventually be.
We could eventually be a planet that has
full control of its weather patterns.
Cloud seeding can actually be done by
ground generators,
a plane or it can be done by a rocket.
Weird.
Yeah.
Wow.
Silver iodide,
dry ice solid carbon dioxide.
Wow.
That Pasadena storm was 80 miles per
hour.
A ef one tornado 73 miles per hour.
So it's pretty close.
It's faster than f one.
What?
It's how fast a f one starts at 73 miles
per hour in that Pasadena store ans 80
miles.
Oh,
I thought you had them reversed.
So it's faster than a tornado.
It was like an ef one tornado.
Really?
That doesn't even make sense.
Where there's different levels of
tornadoes.
Oh,
so it was like bitch ass tornadoes don't
to kill anybody.
Well,
not really bitch ass that.
That's a good tornado,
Joe.
Yeah.
It's like the beginning of a hurricane
winds.
They have.
They've even used liquid propane to make
it rain expands into a gas has also been
used.
This can be can ice crystals at higher
temperatures than silver iodide.
The use of high gross scopic materials
such as salt is becoming more popular
after promising research citation needed
seating in cows requires that they
contained super cooled liquid water.
That is that liquid water colder than
zero degrees Celsius.
The introduction of a substance such as
silver iodide,
which has crystalline structure similar
to that of ice,
will induce freezing nucleation,
dry ice or propane expansion cools the
air to such an extent that the ice
crystals can nucleate spontaneously from
the vapor phase.
Wow.
This is crazy.
Kids in the future,
people are terrified.
In the fucking future.
You might be able to send your name,
your personal nanobots swarm out of your
house,
into the clouds above your house and
make a little personal thunder shower
happen above your house.
Yeah.
You probably will be able to.
That's how much it probably pulls water
from farmers.
You know?
It's probably like.
I mean,
yeah.
Where does that,
what we like when you go to a place like
Abu Dhabi,
which is in the desert and they're.
All of a sudden they're making it rain.
Yeah.
What are they doing?
Where's that water coming from?
Somebody else getting fucked over,
but you don't know.
But anyway.
Does that other person deserve that
water?
Who?
Who fucking deserves a lot of the smart
manager figures out how to pull it out
of the sky or some shithead just camps
out next to it and I get lucky with my
water is joining mine.
I found a spot in the dirt and I claim
it.
Yeah.
No,
I think the guy who pulls it out of the
sky shit when for sure.
Fuck that stupid color.
Anyone can make a puddle.
Yeah,
so there is.
There is some cloud seeding.
It's real science.
Whether or not that shit is happening in
Burbank everyday like Eddie Bravo thinks
it is.
All right.
Yeah.
That's where it gets tricky now that.
What do you think it is?
I can error planes.
That's all it is.
It's funny because it's always near an
airport.
Like I live in Burbank.
I see it all the time because I lived by
Burbank because dude,
you don't even understand that's the
government is spraying.
You're spraying the sky pilot.
I just want to know.
The pilots are so there are these pilots
who were flying over the city and
they're like,
let's dump poison for the good of the
country.
That they think they're creating clouds
for us.
I don't think they're doing it as much
as johnny.
They,
it's listens every.
The insurance companies have to pay
money on skin cancer and it's way
cheaper.
If we have a closet door,
we got to cover it up.
I don't want some burns to have.
I think what I've read and whatever,
what's been explained to me by pilots is
that under certain conditions there's a
certain amount of moisture in the air
and it gets turned up in the,
the uh,
turbines have a jet engine and it comes
out looking like clouds and it stays in
this guy for a while.
Turned up water.
Can I tell you what the real fucking
conspiracy.
I figured it out.
Oh my God.
It's the conspiracy of all conspiracies.
It's your inability to stop your hand
from putting shit into your mouth.
That's the conspiracy dude.
It's the fact that people can't control
their fucking hand and are always
shoving poison into their mouth and
eating shitty things and smoking shitty
things and taking bad pictures.
This was going to be profound.
I feel like that is profound,
man.
I can remember talking to a guy believed
in Kim trails some fucking help,
some discipline.
Well,
that's what I'm saying.
I was talking to a guy believed in chem
trails and he was smoking a cigarette
while he was telling me about the
poisons that the government's dumping.
Oh yeah.
Well Michael Rupert.
When Michael Rupert in here,
he's sweating like crazy.
Talking about conspiracy theorist Alex
Jones spoke,
man,
you're killing yourself.
Like maybe there is some kind of like
evil external force that's trying to
destroy you,
but really you're the one shoveling the
poison and your fucking in in your pile,
you know for sure is going to kill you.
You're aiding them by bringing these
troops into your body.
Saying one day I'm going to fight them
off,
but not now.
By now,
I just fucking sick to try to figure it
out.
I'm a pete.
These motherfuckers signed for my fourth
cupcake going to drink because let's
have.
Let's have 17 beers today.
Again,
I think it comes back to what we were
talking about earlier about the native
Americans having a much better sense of
their connection with the food that
they're eating and that for us,
that whole hunter gatherer thing is out
the window.
I go to the vons and I pick up meat and
I go to,
you know,
get up,
get myself a nice salad and that's it.
I didn't have to pick anything.
I don't have to go get my water in
bottles because all the water's poison.
You can't drink it.
People die occasionally.
Yeah,
totally dude.
And it's just so funny though,
that so many people writhing in physical
discomfort because they're too fat or
they don't exercise or they don't eat
right.
Are upset about a conspiracy that the
government is,
is involved in,
is trying to take,
take away their happiness or their
freedom or,
or,
or dumb them down.
It's like,
no,
no.
You don't exercise.
You eat at Mcdonald's,
you smoke cigarettes,
you're house is fucking filthy.
That's the shit you should worry about
first.
Fix that conspiracy,
solve that problem.
Like stop that conspiracy from happening
and then worry about the fucking chem
trails.
I've been obsessed lately with this
finding bigfoot show,
watching the show left and right.
And it leaves me to sometimes,
you know,
stone tweets in the middle of the night
mocking them and everybody and myself
and I'll fucking stupid and for watching
the show.
But uh,
it is a psychological study and one of
psychological studies is who are these
people that are believing in bigfoot?
Who were these people that are leading
these guys?
And this is what we saw and we're
standing here and it comes out and they
never asked these dudes.
They never go,
okay.
What do you think about ghosts?
Right?
Do you believe in Ufos?
What about psychics?
Do you,
how do you feel about.
What do you think is,
do you think chem trails are real?
Like what do you think happened in area
51?
What do you think is in Hungary team get
to the bottom of what the Messenger is?
Because a lot of times the Messenger who
is giving you this really crazy,
preposterous,
outrageous story.
They,
they,
they lean towards that shit.
They want that shit to be real.
They might not even be lying,
but they might.
They might be just seeing shit in the
woods just because they're fucking wired
for that.
They want to see it.
They want to believe they want to
and they can't be fucking trusted.
When they go to these finding big foot,
they go to these local town halls and
shit.
They go,
all right,
who here has seen a sasquatch?
And these motherfuckers raised their
hands and I'm like,
you are.
I'm like,
you assholes are missing the whole real
show.
The whole real show.
It's,
it can't be done by them because they
are the people that the whole real show
is a bunch of fucking people that want
to believe in big foot so bad.
They're out in the woods.
That's a squash.
That was definitely a squash.
The yell out,
the yelling out in the fucking woods
screaming at the top of their lungs and
then they hear something that you're
something knock.
Someone's knocking the Hiller Annie,
who knows what it could be a producer
thrown a rock.
You know,
he's got to squash.
That's definitely a squash,
squash country.
That's a squash.
What else do you believe in?
Dude?
Where do you.
What do you.
What do you do at night when you go to
bed?
What?
What is going on in your mind?
What are you hoping for?
Do you believe in aliens?
Do you?
What do you believe?
Do you believe in ghosts?
You believe in vampires,
vampires,
rail.
How much other crazy shit and you
believe in?
I think that it's more logical to
believe in aliens and that believe in
bigfoot,
not necessarily big foot is a.
first of all.
Jane Goodall was a firm Believer in
bigfoot and actually stated that,
you know,
famous primate expert stated that it
must be real,
that there's too many sightings of the
same animal all over the world and it is
very possible that there is enough area
that hasn't been discovered or it's too
densely wooded that it support a large
primary like that.
If it was intelligent and knew to hide
from people.
There's 250 different names for it in
North America,
in the American Indian language.
That's,
that's big and because there's not a lot
of shit that's not real.
If they don't have names for and it's
based on a real animal,
we're going to get a guy in here that's
a fucking expert on it,
which means nothing.
I'm satisfied.
I'm going to ask her for Shit.
That's probably not right.
This is going to be great because on the
loch ness monster you are foreign.
You have California.
Did you get like a license for that?
And I have photoshop.
I think it comes with a few.
Um,
you know,
if you look at the stories that have
gone back to like,
you know,
long,
long fucking time in history for sure.
Some people saw bears,
they shit their pants.
I as a person and they made up a story
for sure.
Sometimes people remember things in our
own lives.
We know this,
you know,
my,
my mom is terrible at remembering things
that really happened.
I'll tell my mom something,
don't do it.
And I know it happened.
I was there,
I remember it for sure it happened,
but she will swear.
I mean you show her pictures of Angela
whole.
Well,
I don't remember that.
No,
when we did that,
a game show in my head show and I told
you,
we got people to talk about Ufos.
Got them to make up a Ufo story because
we pretended to be a news guy that had
gotten there too late.
Would you mind pretending the use of the
Ufo people just started talking,
man,
just so excited they were going to get
on television and when I'm watching this
stupid bigfoot show and I'm looking at
these people trouncing through the
woods,
I'm looking at a bunch of people that
are lonely.
They don't have any real purpose in
their life.
There's these people that don't have
real good friends is one weird guy with
his poor fucking kid and this kid was
like,
my dad might be crazy sitting here
talking about we saw bigfoot together.
What the fuck did we really see?
My Dad's a liar.
My Dad's claiming you saw big foot and
in the kids sort of along along with it,
you can wash them.
You look at the insincerity and their
words.
They had a guy on the other day just gay
as fuck.
Just beyond gay,
just crazy flock of seagulls haircut
list everything wandering through the
woods,
seeing bigfoot.
I'm sure you did crazy.
You insane asshole.
Believe that show exists,
man.
It sounds hilarious.
Like exactly like ghost hunters in that.
Although shows feature night vision and
nothing.
That's all you need.
Just a house in night vision.
It seems crazy.
Yeah.
I was having a twitter exchange with
this chick the other day and we were
going off about how combined the two
shows and just make it a porno and
that's really what it is.
Split two lonely people who have the
night vision,
unkempt,
pubes,
fatty,
sweaty bodies and night vision loads.
Loneliness,
dude.
They're all pretending to hear thing I
saw or heard something come in here real
quick and then they fuck like getting a
car and the darkness and they just.
I think I heard something.
I think your fingering me,
I think they'll keep the ghosts away or
two.
I think it'll keep.
It goes if you suck my cock.
Yeah.
Scare them.
Scan with your boldness and then they
fucking the darkness.
They fucking the door and then the guy
has to get away with.
Then they,
you know,
after guy comes,
he's like,
I just fucking hurt something for real.
Holy Shit.
I'm not kidding now.
And he runs out of the room.
That's how they get out of it because
after you come,
you know the girl wants a cuddle.
It's like we can't cut over in the
fucking in a haunted house.
Hired something.
Jesus is real and he just runs.
She's like,
you didn't hear shit.
Give it the night vision.
She can't see.
She stuck in the fucking basement in the
corner.
This guy like,
come on,
what?
I'll tell you warmer.
You're getting towards the door warmer.
Give me the night vision.
I can't fucking seat foam.
She hits the wall.
Start screaming no more pussy for him.
That's a weird show,
Joe.
They pretend to hear things.
What was that?
How many of those shows are they said,
what was that?
What was that?
It was you being a crazy asshole alone
either in the woods or in a basement.
Either looking for bigfoot or a ghost.
Fuck all that shit.
Think about the fact that the Catholic
Church still does exorcisms.
Think about that shit,
dude.
Fucking Catholic priests will.
Right now there's probably a priest in
somebodies house getting a demon out of
somebody's body.
Think about that.
Fucking big foot fine.
Aliens.
Fine.
There's guys dressed as God.
Clowns waving around symbols in front of
little kids faces to try to get
imaginary demons to go out to them.
What's really amazing is way more
priests out there.
Fucking kids are doing extra stuff way
more,
way more.
That's fucked up statistic.
We need to figure out if that's true,
man.
So there's more priests molesting kids
and they are getting the demons out of
kids.
Well,
we were talking about on the podcast
with Joey,
we're talking about how people who run
martial arts schools often,
it's very culty and the guy who is at
the head is the master and is almost
beyond reproach and that a lot of times
weird sexual shit happens because of
that,
because it becomes like a cult.
Well,
that is exactly what happens in the
Catholic church and even like in martial
arts schools,
like people try to keep things under
wraps,
like there's always like dark secrets.
So this guy fucking the students and the
fucking one of his students who was
married and the husband finds out about.
There's always those kinds of scandals,
very cult like and with every real
controlling cult,
there's an element of sexuality and it's
usually creepy.
It's not like a peace love,
you know,
everyone polyamorous and whether sexual
or non,
you know,
everything is just about nonjudgmental
affection.
No,
no,
no.
Most of is not.
Most of it's creepy.
It's victim set.
Thanks dude.
And then think about this,
take it back to the story that it comes
from,
whether it's real or not.
The story of the Catholic Church comes
from name one guy dressed like a gnome
in that story.
Name.
One guy wearing a big golden flowing
cape and holding a funny thing and
marching around with fucking that Purple
Velvet on and fucking walking around on
red carpets and giant golden palaces
were.
Find that in the New Testament,
find anything even remotely,
like the rituals outside the law.
Uh,
the holy communion.
Find anything.
It's fucking,
especially,
although the audacious use of,
of gold and money and spending.
Think about all the different gigantic
Roman colosseum there.
The other were the sistine chapel or
think of any of the things of the
construction in Rome.
Any of the stuff that's at the Vatican
that's like a really elaborate,
expensive,
Gadi Non Christian Shit.
Think of what else could have been done
with all that energy,
but they're like,
you know what?
Yet Jesus wanted us to have a beautiful
giant Golden Palace where I could sit
and fuck fucking fuck kids.
Four kids on Red Velvet.
Yeah.
It's just what he wants.
That's this story.
And so like,
so it's very.
Either way,
this attitude is really offending a lot
of people on twitter.
There's a lot of Christians that have
sent me texts saying,
I wish you would remind me or at least
warn us that before you go on these
horrible Antichristian rants,
don't destroy our culture.
Oh No,
no,
no.
See,
I'm not talking about Christianity.
I'm talking about the cult of loon loon,
which is my Christianity.
That's not.
No,
no,
no.
Got To be pushing your loon.
Loon not to sell t shirts.
You Sound Lumina tee shirts and not a
bad idea.
I am selling posts.
There's not a bad idea selling the
fucking tee shirts,
but no man.
It's no my moon brand.
It's the fucking church brand.
I would never take it from that,
but do it.
It's,
it's,
uh,
that's not real.
That's not what I view as real
Christianity because you look at a lot
of the Christianity that some people
follow.
It's based on a lot of the writings of
somebody named Paul who,
uh,
never met Jesus.
He was,
he was persecuted Christians and he was
walking on the road to Damascus.
It's not a vision.
His name was saul of Tarsus and he saw a
vision of Jesus.
Jesus appeared in the sky and said,
Saul,
so why do you persecute me?
And at that moment saw was
filled with the glory of the Lord.
And he was blinded and he wandered and
found some Christians,
Phantom and his name became Paul.
And he was the founder of the modern
Christian church and you wrote all these
letters about what it is to be a in the
spirit of Christ and to be with Christ,
but he never met God outside of,
in that vision.
So essentially he was like Jimmy
swaggered,
but a long time ago,
remember when Swagger,
swagger to Pat Robertson,
southern 90 foot tall Jesus.
I don't know,
but he had a vision.
This part,
the Paul of Tarsus had to add a vision
and I don't know,
I don't know which one,
but yeah,
that's where it came from.
It wasn't from the original teachings.
You know,
the original teachings don't.
I'm sorry if I'm offending pizza.
Really Weird though that.
Um,
uh Oh,
it was oral roberts,
oral roberts,
900 foot tall Jesus in 1977,
which is when he would have been around.
That was one 900 foot tall.
Jesus was touring was part of the
galaxy,
the fucking galaxy coming to oral
roberts in the middle of the desert and
showing show themself.
But it's really interesting to think
about that when you realize that it's
like,
so,
so a lot of people call,
um,
what's after the gospels,
the epistles at which a lot of them,
holly in theology,
it's not Christian Christianity,
it's based on because here's the big
problem that Christians ran into in many
verses in the Bible.
Jesus said,
before some of you die,
I'm going to be back and even come back
in,
some of the disciples started dying and
then it's like,
wait a minute,
he's not coming back,
what are we going to do?
And they had to reorganize shit and turn
it into something that was like,
that made more sense,
which is to deal with this,
uh,
some,
some basic problems.
And what Christ,
if he existed in that story,
he said it was going to happen,
you know?
And now we've got the bank robbers
syndrome,
you know that,
right?
It's the bank robber thing.
What,
when somebody robs a bank,
they say everybody get on the fucking
ground and don't move.
I'm going to walk out of here and I'm
going to come back in two minutes.
And if any of you have moved,
I'm going to blow your fucking brains
out.
This is what a bank robber does when
he's robbing a bank.
This is what Jesus did when he said,
I'm going to be back really soon,
and if anyone's misbehaving,
you're going to hell forever.
And that's been going on for a long
fucking time,
man,
and it's probably going to keep going on
and on and on,
and each it.
Each time it advances down a generation,
it gets weirder and weirder and weirder.
So now we've got a guy dressed like a
fucking gnome feeling.
Totally cool,
sitting in a golden throne when there's
people all over the planet starving.
And somehow that guy is a disciple of a
person who went around saying,
love your neighbor as yourself and love
the Lord your God with all heart,
mind,
and soul.
By the way,
clear evidence that he harbored child
molesters.
Clear evidence that he derailed
investigations and move people around
when he was whatever the fuck he was a
bishop or whatever the fuck he was when
he was doing this.
He was in Phoenix.
Yeah.
Ratzinger.
You can't.
I mean,
imagine the bitch.
Have you ever seen the pictures of him
with the male gymnast?
The acrobatics that.
I honestly still think that that was
the.
I didn't because my brain seems fake.
It's fake right now.
It's totally real.
They the pope.
How did all that?
How does Catholicism become the leading
source of power worldwide of
Christianity?
Because there's red,
there's all the other forms of
Christianity.
They seem to be much more scattered.
Like there's not like one heavy duty
dude.
The head of it,
like Catholicism,
you know,
we were.
Who's the main guy and Episcopalian?
Who's the main guy in the baptist?
There's no one.
There's no main guy like the Catholic
pope that's like there's a.
there's a hierarchy in the episcopal
church,
but nothing like the.
You know what I'm saying?
Worldwide recognized the pope is the top
dog.
How did that get to be the strongest,
most powerful form of Christianity,
which is,
by the way,
also the most nuts,
the most fucking crazy judgmental,
the most guilt ridden in injecting
horrible feelings of sorrow into little
boys' heads because they touch their
penis.
Is there,
Joe?
Is there a,
is there a statistic on the what
percentage of priests and the last kids
is 89 percent,
but we must know a certain number of
them.
I don't think it comes up all the time.
I don't think they can.
I don't think they know.
But is there a number of priests that
have gone,
gotten incarcerated for molesting kids?
What's that number?
How many is it?
Seven 97.
90 seven percent.
Don't listen to him.
Listen,
I know you're talking to 20 percent of
the allegations.
The priests was deceased.
Uh,
let's see.
I'm just curious if they're sending the
campaign,
what percentage of priest abuse.
Okay,
let's see here.
Don't know ma'am.
Well,
there is certainly a certain number of
priests who had been charged.
I mean,
I know that that story has come up,
so there's gotta be some number.
I'm just wondering how many.
Whoa,
what?
Oh,
okay.
It's only for their concluding there.
I thought it's at 40 percent.
Holy Shit.
I my brain blip for a second and
concluded that for about four percent of
the US priests since 1950,
I've been accused of sexual abuse of
children.
Okay.
However,
here's the caveats.
There are probably many victims who
remain silent and not yet come forward
to accuse their abusers.
There are probably some adults who have
come forward to accused priests who have
false recovered memories of abuse that
never happened,
so it could be both ways.
Imagine maybe some adults who knowingly
falsely accused innocent priests who
abuse they do to imagine this.
Imagine if four percent of people who
work at apple stores had been accused of
molesting kids.
Yeah.
I used that onstage before.
You said that Nascar driver,
so saying a massive organization of
Nascar drivers running around in circles
with their cars and then fucking kids,
you know,
we,
we'd say we don't need Nascar.
This is ridiculous.
Yeah.
That four percent of apple employees,
probably molests kids because they're
the computer nerds.
They,
you know,
they don't get paid.
That's not even funny.
I mean,
no,
I'm being serious there.
When you say like,
no,
four percent of apple employees don't
fuck kids do.
It's a tiny,
tiny,
tiny percentage of people in the whole
world who were child molesters.
It's really small.
The problem is when,
when it happens,
it's fucking devastating.
So if it's one in a community of a
million people,
that's a lot.
1,000.
It's a lot.
Have you looked at the APP that shows
you who are near?
There's like 300 in Burbank.
Yeah.
Well,
how many millions of people live in
Burbank?
You know,
how many people you think live in
Burbank?
Let's say population of Burbank.
I'm going to go 500,000
deal with every series.
This is something I've been trying to
figure out for years.
I can't wait to hear the answer.
What is the population at Burbank,
California?
One hundred and 3000.
Three hundred 40.
To answer your question.
Yeah.
I got your bench.
One hundred.
Three thousand.
Three hundred 40 in 2010.
So out of that,
how many,
how many pedals are in Burbank?
MMM.
Isn't that a song?
Should be some hipsters on some ironic,
ironic hipster song about beddoes.
Yeah,
I'd probably say I would probably say it
100.
There's A.
There's a an uncomfortable number of
people that have fuck kids.
That's an question.
Yeah.
It's all pretty disgusting and
terrifying.
Really.
That's one of the first things that we
should eradicate because if that's
something that flux kid up for the rest
of her life and then if they lash out
and start doing on new kids,
then they become.
We talked about this,
that it's like a vampire.
It's real vampires like you actually do
infect someone and make them what you
are.
A monster transmits itself and it's been
transmitted for a fucking long time,
man.
It's been being transmitted for
generations.
It's such a gross thing.
It's such a broken thing and it has
roots in primate behavior.
That's what's really fucked up about it.
Sexuality is so strange and in our world
it's so.
It's so unnatural because we're actually
covering our bodies up.
We hide our genitals.
You know,
we have this weird sort of a common
atory lifestyle of natural animal urges
mixed with his higher self and
consciousness in language and the
awareness of the impact of your words
and deeds and physical acts on other
people and that you're putting out a
negative energy in a negative vibe.
And we encourage that in our communities
and discourage that in our,
in our laws.
But the reality is we have these
fucking,
these urges to fuck and they're not
regulated.
They're not like,
no one's like recognizing that like,
hey,
you know,
we need to like why is,
is prostitution bad?
If someone explained that to me,
if someone needs money and someone has a
mouth,
you know,
and they go,
you know what,
I can make a lot of money with this
mouth and what is worse?
Working at Wendy's for a week and making
$300 or sucking a guy's Dick for 10
minutes and making $500.
And a lot of people will go,
I would rather suck this guy's Dick and
this guy,
he's some poor guy who's Horny,
you know,
and it's like you give him a mouth
massage on his dick and he blows a load
in your mouth and he's so happy.
Oh my God,
he's so released like,
that was so good.
And he gives you $100 tip.
Now you made 600 bucks.
Why is that bad?
I don't.
I'm not sure.
Why is it okay to do that for free?
How come if she meets that guy and she
likes him,
she blows them and it's the greatest
thing that ever happened,
then that's fine.
But if she meets that guy and you know,
he's like,
listen,
I have 500 bucks and I would like to get
my dick sucked and I know your hard
earned money and we want to make a deal.
Why is that bad?
Wow.
I,
yeah,
it's a,
it's a what do you want one?
I just found a website that tells you
how many sex offenders are in each city
and Los Angeles.
And it's pretty shocking at the highest
numbered one.
No.
Right.
So Burbank has 1,875
sex offenders.
That's more than one percent.
Yeah.
Beverly Hills,
wasn't it?
Yeah.
Beverly Hills is the highest railing
with 4,903.
Which is weird because Beverly Hills,
there's more people that live in Burbank
and then beverly hills.
Right.
That's a good question.
Um,
so,
so is it because money.
Yeah.
So money equals,
that's kind of weird.
Pasadena here we got a really hills
pedophiles.
One thousand,
306 here.
Because I mean there's like Beverly
Hills,
the houses are spread apart.
There's not as many people crammed in.
Yeah.
There's only 34,000
people live in Beverly Hills and they
have 4,903.
You guys,
we have figured out to crazy fucking
things in this podcast.
Number one,
Coca Cola is making the majority of
cocaine in the world.
And number two,
beverly hills is filled with.
Holy Shit.
Wow.
That's groundbreaking shit,
man.
That's crazy.
We need to spark up and think about
those two heavy.
Oh,
we might have people coming here for the
next show.
Whatever.
Would those targets?
Did you want to eat?
I'm not supposed to anymore.
I apologize.
We can't say it anymore,
man,
that word,
but it's my friends.
Every now and then I'll slip one out and
plus they're already.
Sounds great.
You know what actually got me saying it
a couple times just to.
My friends got damn stand hopes.
New CD.
Really funny by the way,
before himself it's called.
It's really good.
It's,
I think it stan host best work,
but he says Fagen and a couple of times
with my God I missed that word for word.
It's just the problem is it's associated
as a gay slur and even though I have a
lot of like pro gay stuff in my act
especially now have a lot of still.
You can't say it.
You can't say right now,
man,
I ain't never liked this great word.
I like call me animals didn't like it
because you get called out a few too
many times.
I set you up for that one.
That's now I just fucking such a shitty.
It's like always coming out of the mouth
of fucking dope fucking rednecks and the
backs of school buses and just dip shits
playing.
Fucking true xbox.
They ruined it.
The flux.
Yeah,
they ruined it.
I could have had some years.
Yeah.
My 40th birthday cake,
jody is Ari Shapiro got me a fucking
birthday cake and said happy birthday,
and it was beautiful.
Beautiful.
You know what it seems like back then it
was okay to say that was only like four
years ago when I put my special out.
It changed while I was doing and come in
and out.
They had a real problem using the word
faggot.
Why?
Remember when we were just in Texas
saying retard like that was shocking
that you can't really use retard either
right now.
That's.
That was weird.
I retard became a problem in Austin,
in the vaults.
Austin.
We're in Austin.
I said,
you gotta stop with the retard.
It became a problem.
Yeah.
Political correctness is fucking
completely ridiculous.
Supporting his intent.
Her trainees,
the new word tranny tranny's shut up.
You can't say tranny and people were
telling me that today that trainees the
new.
I don't believe that.
Oh,
I wouldn't know.
It can never take away our trend.
No.
You know what?
I believe it because I've seen someone
say in,
in someone accusing someone of being a
homophobe.
They said something about them upsetting
the lesbian.
Gay.
It was like l,
G,
b,
t,
q.
I go by,
I go queue.
I go,
wait a minute.
I go lesbian,
lesbian,
gay,
transsexual,
transvestite Que [inaudible] Q.
which ones that?
Queer?
Queer.
Queer is a totally obscure one.
They don't want to define it like they
might like guys.
They might like girls.
They might be by.
They might be weird.
They're queer.
Whatever the fuck they are.
What is that?
How can you.
Is that the most ambiguous definition
ever?
Have a sexuality as queer,
queer south,
but that's when people are going real
deep.
Well,
it's because they want people to be able
to define themselves and I agree with
that man.
Of course,
whatever you want,
but when you're getting mad at people
saying gay slurs used,
you know the term queer.
Well,
yeah,
no,
you're right man.
It's all fucking intention to like
what's behind there.
If there's anger behind it,
it's an ugly word.
It's why a black people can call you
niggers.
Hey,
is what it is.
You know,
you know when you hear two bucks site
sitting around shooting the shit with Dr
Dre and they're being funny with each
other.
Yeah.
It's not offensive.
Some old man is yelling at a young kid
because he's walking on his lawn.
Then it becomes offensive and
dehumanizing.
I meant obviously I met a beautiful
black girl the other day about trying.
It was sop.
It's on my list,
but I,
I.
It was my friend's sister,
but she was just so beautiful to get in
shape for that first.
Now you always start off with at your
worst,
start off with your worst presentation
and if they accept you at that,
really you don't ever try to impress a
girl.
Never.
That's bullshit.
When you got dumped the first time,
dude,
you lost like 70 pounds.
That's when you really realize how to
get back in the game.
That was because I was out of,
it was a seven year relationship.
That was internet fame,
Sun.
That's what it was.
That the Internet fame.
You weren't the producer of a very
famous podcast.
Brian,
how many penthouse pat have you dated?
Seven.
That's normal dude.
The guy was like,
you'll usually get a lot of penthouse,
but seriously,
how many?
Uh,
too.
I finally did it to girls in the
industry ever clean industry.
Well,
you know,
since I've been at Hollywood a bit on
the industry part of the industry,
really,
uh,
I do a lot of industry things.
I've been history newsletter that I
subscribed to day.
What's happening with that condom thing?
Man?
Is it fucking up the industry?
Seems to be a lot of talk that they're
going to move to Arizona or something
like that or vegas that it's going to
move to Vegas,
which is a lot of,
well not really because I think a lot of
girls live in vegas anyway because a lot
of them they make money dancing as well
as doing movies.
You know,
they can,
if they like announced like the thing
they announced,
they do feature dancing and people like
dudes are fucking fans.
Have some porn stars.
Me made states may say it's kind of
weird and strange,
but why is it.
I mean,
look,
if you're a fan of an actress,
you know,
you come to see her at a book signing,
you're,
you're a fan of the way of sucks dicks
and she's nice enough to let you watch
her suck a lot of Dick's beautiful women
and then you pretend that it's your and,
and you blast all over yourself.
Dude.
You know what's wrong with that?
Beautiful women is beautiful.
Like the Pamela Anderson right there.
I think she is gorgeous.
You know that.
I think that is A.
I think she is beautiful in that.
Yeah,
that's like art.
So there's a certain art in what she
looks like her body.
It's so.
It's so sexually arousing.
You know,
you look at her perfectly manicured toes
and her toe ring and Oh,
you just want to lick her button.
That's right there.
Right word.
You're obsessed with that button.
Yeah,
it's placed perfectly.
I want to dumb luck.
Look,
see the.
They'd line up on the other side of her
shirt.
I think it's just the way it is.
It's just a hot picture.
The pictures,
by the way,
I didn't create this right here.
You know,
it's unfortunate though,
man.
What's unfortunate is that women like
that man,
especially if they're not like heavy
duty into working out instead of get
older and they lose their body,
they become creepy.
Look,
we tried to kill her ass.
They asked disappears.
That's when it gets really weird when
you see like older women their asses
like sink and turn under,
you know,
and old men to like.
They get that Larry King Body where the.
There's no muscle tone going on and when
a woman becomes.
When a woman goes from Pamela Anderson
and she's still attractive,
she hasn't hit this yet,
but it's coming,
you know,
unless she figures out some way to do a
lot of fucking squats and keep her body.
Like when you become a woman who has
enormous artificial boobs and your
body's kind of falling apart and you
have these big bags sitting in front
pushing out your shirt and you know this
cleavage that you're,
but it's been sun drenched for so long,
it's got this weird sort of leathery
texture,
new trying to tone that down with heavy
doses of moisturizer so your tits are
always greasy and leathery at the same
time and your is of habit rating.
So he tried to stick it out a little.
So you're wearing high heel shoes where
it's really not appropriate and they're
really high and you know,
you're,
you're awkward,
you can barely walk and you really,
your,
your ass has gone.
You become a monster.
You become a stranger on the news.
There's going to be like this wave of
suicides from people as well.
That's a weird thing,
man.
It's a weird look,
you know?
Well,
yeah,
it's weird.
It's,
that's getting attached to your
physical,
to your physical body and using that as
your main tool.
Sure.
I think dangerous proposition,
man.
I think I'm you.
That's a really easy to say though,
when you're a girl and you look like
Pamela Anderson.
Dude,
first of all,
when she was young,
she was so hot.
That's all anyone eat.
Probably comment all the time.
Time when she was young,
all the people that she met,
I guarantee you everyone was just,
holy shit.
You're so pretty.
Yeah.
But that happens.
But it wasn't what,
uh,
when a girl gets addicted and gets
caught up in that,
it's almost like there's nothing that
can match the kind of power and energy
she gets just from her own looks.
So she's almost,
it's almost like,
it's just,
it was too alluring to just run with
that too many people were encouraging
her,
you know,
and essentially she got away with
without doing any porn except for that
one accidental time.
Yeah,
man.
Have a good one too though.
Yeah,
she did like some playboys and stuff,
you know,
where you got to see her naked and that
was satisfying enough.
But I mean she made a living.
She was so hot.
She made a living off being hot and
that's what she did.
What sad is when people.
It does,
I mean it's not her fault that she was
super fucking hot.
It's incredible,
but the sad thing is if she was attached
to that perception of herself,
it's a.
we're just assuming.
We're just assuming now that she's maybe
she's super cool.
She sat her down and had a conversation
whether you would really enjoy it.
I don't know her.
She's all.
I'm.
All I'm saying is positive.
All I'm saying is that she was so
ridiculously hot when she was young that
I think almost anybody would have been
corrupted by that kind of beauty and not
that she even was,
but I mean I don't.
I don't know how you could not be a
professional hot chick if you were that
pretty.
Look at her dude.
Look at her.
That's from whatever that is.
That's her prime.
Just like one of the hottest chicks
that's ever walked the face of the
earth.
I pulled back.
I think that's actually a reasonable
back into see your whole body.
Do you see your whole body?
They're run,
so you get that whole thing there,
man.
It's a recent poster.
Well then she still came to it together.
Good for her.
That chick is hot as fuck.
Great.
That's incredibly hot,
right?
Well,
I think when you're that pretty.
I think you know you have.
We all have to be reasonable.
That girl got some crazy lottery ticket
and she decided to cash it in.
She,
she ran.
She ran the dyson.
She came up double seven in the looks
department.
I don't fault chicks for doing that.
I don't either.
Man.
That's.
I wasn't saying that at all.
Some people do,
right?
Some people like immediately they will
discount somebody if they are a a,
a professional hot check or if they're a
girl who's attractive like immediately
because they know it's so easy to be
that person.
Life is so easy.
What are the odds of you have been
thinking?
What are the.
What are the odds that you've been
contemplating your existence?
Why would you?
Life is so easy.
Everyone is just tripping over
themselves to try to give you things,
but I've met plenty of them that do and
those girls are insane for sure.
It's amazing when you run into someone
who's in his beautiful and intelligent
with great personality,
great sense of humor.
It's amazing.
It's like,
wow,
you're looking at you here because to
get to that point,
you had to have some humility that
didn't come from looking in the mirror.
The reaction that you're getting from
the people around you.
That could be that.
Some of them,
it's just simply that they,
you know,
they got into yoga or that got into some
sort of meditation discipline and they
sort of formed.
I mean,
it could have been the way they were
raised.
They just sort of formed a,
a human personality instead of a hot
chick personality.
That's the best.
It must be hard though,
man.
Being a hot check must be like the
easiest way to get by in life,
skate through a bunch of,
stumbling over that.
Also though,
if there's a lot of sadness to that life
for some.
Sure.
Yeah.
Well,
there's also when,
when,
when someone feels like they're getting
scammed over,
like you don't really like,
um,
you know,
if,
if someone's in a situation where a girl
is using her,
looks to get by in life,
the guy who is taking advantage of that,
the guys who get with those girls,
they know,
they know that this isn't a real,
this isn't a real love,
this is a real love under certain
conditions and that certain conditions
are you're here to provide like finances
or pay for things or something.
There's something that those guys are
going to present that.
So that manipulative relationship is
never the real relationship where you
really both truly love each other and
you can't wait to see that person.
It's always this weird,
creepy deal where you know you're
getting fucked and you want to check her
cell phone because you don't like to
wear a [inaudible] trainer looks at you
when you say hi to her at the gym.
He thinks she might be fucking are
trained.
Man.
It was crazy.
And so imagine if you were like some old
dude,
you're like 80 years old and you get
yourself a 30 year old chippy and she
likes to work out,
you know,
and you,
you're playing golf.
And she walked in and she's like getting
stretched out by this fucking 25 year
old trainer.
She's got her leg on his shoulders.
A lot of dudes who do creepy shit like
that.
All right,
time to stretch out.
So we're going to do here.
I want to pick your leg up.
You gotta put it on my shoulder.
Hey fuck head.
You don't have to do that stupid are
you?
You could stretch all those major muscle
groups on the ground.
You'd dump.
Fuck.
But there's a lot of dudes who like do
creepy shit with girls.
All right,
well it really lean both your arms back
and they'd get a nice firm sexual grip
on their forearms.
So just to let a woman feel the grip
strength,
you know what I'm talking about?
And they just pull you back,
pull you back at some weird,
uncomfortable sort of semi sexual
positions.
Some sorta overinflated doggy style
position.
You know,
and then you let them go and then you're
stretching out their arms and you know,
you're showing your own discipline,
you stretch out with them and then it's
poor fucking guy's 80 years old wasn't
going to do it.
He just has to be happy,
I guess.
Yeah,
he should be happy.
He's just let everybody fuck her and
hope.
Hope nobody poisons them.
Yeah,
that's an inevitability.
But that's the problem is they're all
gonna.
They're all going to poison you,
man.
How many 80 year old guys who you think
are dating third 30 year?
Twenty year olds right now?
That's a really good question.
Uh,
let's think.
Let's,
I wonder if we could find that statistic
online.
That's something you would.
Who knows man up in the hamptons and
like monsters.
But I really love him.
I just think he's wonderful because when
people enter those relationships,
they don't enter them.
They just don't even care about his
lungs.
He's body is an amazing person.
His energy is so loving and you know,
I wouldn't,
I wouldn't want to leave his side.
It sounds amazing.
See,
I hope to grow 81 day the girls got
diamonds on shit and she's just lying
around,
murdered the animal skins and driving
around in a Bentley feels like it's not
even connected to the road.
I feel like you're floating on a carpet
through the air.
She knows he's probably only got two
more years of life and then she gets
millions of dollars because he was in
love with her.
I wonder how many of those there are out
there a lot.
There's a lot and you know,
you could say,
well,
if you want it to be cynical and
pragmatic that you know he's providing
something.
She's getting something out of this.
It's a good relationship.
He wants comfort and sex and she's
willing to sort of give that as long as
he provides a ridiculous income to her.
That's the reason why they have this
unbalanced relationship in the first
place.
He has to be unbalanced financially to
overcompensate for the physical,
unbalanced.
He has to be ridiculous on balance.
He asked to be buying or minks and
diamonds and then you get to stick your
Dick in my mouth.
I like diamonds and that's,
that's the deal.
She has them so they could say,
oh,
he was using her or she was using him
for his money.
Of course.
That's the deal.
Yes.
Using him for his money and he's using
her for her great hot body.
You're not supposed to get this when
you're 80.
It's essentially what you're doing is
taking on an insane prostitution
contract that you almost like,
like almost nobody could keep up with.
That's the only way you can keep a hot
chick if you're 80.
I mean,
it's just incredible to think of that.
Eighty year olds can get that horny man
if they take Viagra.
And I think also if,
um,
it's a lot of them,
it's a psychological thing.
You know,
there's
a lot of 80 year old guys that can't
believe that they can get a 20 year old
hooker.
They probably can't even believe it.
And when they're alone with this,
if they can get it up still,
oh my God,
how good must've feel to bang some
really hard 20 year old Russian hooker.
It's kind of fucked up because he's only
20.
Let's make her 23.
Let's make it 23.
Really hot.
Twenty three year old Russian hooker
who's really good at it.
She's really good at it.
I would just have to like you just.
It's the fact that underneath this
beautiful young thing is a withered
Chris that's about to go feed the worms.
It's like it would be tough for me to
beat that out of my mind as I stared at
her,
at her,
at her hot body.
I would still be like,
man,
you're fucking.
You're wrinkling and you can barely
breathe and your knees or to so good.
God damn this feel so good.
You can come in her mouth.
You can come in around whatever you
want.
She doesn't care.
What do you want to come?
Whether you want to come.
She said he's.
He's healthy.
Oh Man.
More power to him,
but he should give up his whole empire.
He's not gonna live very long anyway.
Just keep it all up.
Yeah,
I think it's.
I mean,
I think that situation,
there certainly is something for.
Dude,
that's priceless.
That's worth a lot of goddamn money.
Yeah.
A girl,
a really hot check to just fuck you
whenever you want and you're an 80 year
old man.
You better be paying that bitch.
That's a ridiculous thing to ask.
You think it's tough to ask them to be a
garbage man.
How about asking a fucking old guy
whenever he wants?
You think there's any like 80 year old.
Do you think there's any 80 year old
guys living in studio apartments that
have 30 year old girlfriends?
No.
No,
there's none of that doesn't exist.
Maybe there might be a few broken chicks
out there that you got roped into some
bad poetry or something like that.
It's possible.
Most guys though,
roped in the back.
Some guy pretends to be good.
You've been lost girl and you know he's
a information he has no.
He takes time with her and something no
one ever did and he has needs and she
takes care of it for them.
That's possible most of the time.
Not Likely.
Most of the time it's a motherfucker
that's living in some shit that nobody
should be living in some crazy fucking
castle.
There's some.
I,
every now and then as a goof,
I like to go on a website and look at
like stupid expensive houses that are
for sale.
Like what is the most expensive house
you could buy,
like $20,
million dollar houses and you can go and
look at the pictures of them.
They show them online and you see the
grounds and everything like holy shit,
like what is this crazy way that one
person gets to live?
This is nuts.
I looked at this one house,
it was a compound.
It was absolutely insane.
It was 600 plus acres and this
incredible fucking house.
And I mean it was one of the most
extravagant things that a person could
ever purchase an urn and own in their
life.
They essentially own a kingdom was
really like a 650 acre
kingdom.
And uh,
you know,
no,
it was a little chippy.
She's 26,
she just came here from Czechoslovakia
and uh,
you know,
we started hanging out man and she likes
to smoke weed.
I still smoke a little weed every now
and then.
Next thing you know,
she's talking to my deck and I don't
know what to do.
I'm a mom.
I'm 86 years old.
I mean,
what kind of relationship we're going to
have.
I mean,
what do you think?
Should I pursue this?
I have a walker,
a walker.
I have a lot of 86 year olds.
Have a lot of them.
If I want to get down the steps,
I've got a ride.
And what would you tell an old man who,
if there was a hunch,
I would say you might want some people
to fucking keep an eye on her,
you know,
but then you gotta make sure that you
have only gay security guards because
uh,
that dirty bitch will suck their dicks.
I mean,
she's really hot.
Well no,
but I'm saying if you're a guy and you
were like the super rich dude who lives
in this giant crazy house and you're 80
years old and this is 23 year old,
really hot eastern bloc chick that may
or may not be an assassin as well.
A hooker and a you gotta have some gay
security guards that are keeping an eye
on her.
You can't have like young stud guys
because she'll just suck their dicks,
you know,
that dirty bitch.
They most guys will not be able to stop
themselves,
you know,
a really,
really fat from Iowa and never met a
girl like that before and all of a
sudden she's like,
listen,
relax baby,
relax.
And she's rubbing your balls.
Like,
Holy Shit,
I can't believe there's going to have a
look.
I get fired for this.
Relax baby with that and we'll work
something out and you know,
she's,
you know,
I can fuck this old man all the time.
You know,
sometimes I want to go out and have fund
and we have a deal.
Yeah.
Next thing you know,
there are plotting his death.
That's what it is.
That's how it goes.
Dunkin.
And that's when he's got to be careful
for.
He's only have gay security guards
should have big bad ass gay dudes that
watch over you.
That's like,
that's the weirdest end of your life.
And find the girl.
Yeah,
you got a big.
And at 30 year old Russian prostitute,
you gotta Gut go get those guys to take
her everywhere.
They never let any guys come near her
because she's mine and you don't let
that bitch fucking poison me.
Just absurd.
It's just absurd,
man.
It's a lot of guys lives,
right?
Yeah.
Its absurdity.
It's so funny the way that you could end
up when you're blinking out of the
universe,
like you can actually blink out of the
universe and a silk robe next to a 30
year old Russian stripper.
I know a man who was a um,
uh,
he was a successful man,
but he was very,
very weak.
He was like very physically weak and he
was much older than her.
He was about 30 years older than her,
you know,
he was maybe.
Yeah,
she was like in her probably in her
forties and he was in his seventies and
there was the anger from her at him and
the way she would yell at him
and treat him this,
this complete total lack of respect
because,
you know,
basically they're the.
They had been married for a long time.
The only reason why they got married in
the first place is because he was rich
and she was hot and she learned along
the way.
This motherfucker's not going to do
nothing,
and the way to get them off you is to
just yell at them and humiliate them in
front of other people.
Will you fucking stop?
Just stop.
She was this Russian lady,
Judy.
She yelled at him in front of me and my
friends and it was this really fucking
super uncomfortable moment,
man.
Just snapped at him in front of
everybody and we're like,
we had a peak at this guy's life.
What,
what,
what did he,
what did he done?
It was so bad.
Do you remember?
I don't know.
Nothing.
At the time.
He was a really nice guy.
He was a doctor and uh,
he made,
made them a lot of money.
Man.
He was rich.
He had a crazy house and crazy cars and
shit and she was like a really hot
Soviet bloc looking chick.
I don't remember what,
what part of what part of the Soviet
Union or Russia or whatever she was
from.
But it was something like that.
I don't remember Ukraine.
She might've.
No,
I don't remember.
I don't remember fucking tragic dude.
It's so tragic and it's tragic when
someone's with someone and that person
doesn't want to be with your man or give
away,
you know,
love and like these little like rations,
they give a sex and affection and little
rations,
you know?
Well No,
it's like that thing they experiment.
They did with the monkey,
you know,
but it's like one of the worst
experiments of all time.
They take a fucking wire monkey and
there's those pictures of the monkeys
leaning to the wire monkey in pretending
it's a real monkey on it.
They put carpet on it and they,
they had this poor monkey that thought
it was a mama.
There was nothing else in there for it.
But some people are in relationships
where there that little fucking monkey
and they're clinging onto nothing.
There's nothing there and they're just
pretending that there's love.
There's something there for them.
And they know in their heart there's
nothing there and they just keep fucking
doing it because they're terrified to
let go of that fucking thing and go out
into the world.
It's super hard to find someone that's
really cool to hang out with.
That doesn't just become a shithead.
Eventually someone just someone who
doesn't fall apart after you get to know
them for awhile.
Because that happens with a lot of
people.
Man,
a lot of people do really good in the
beginning of a relationship because they
can pretend to be someone really cool.
Yeah.
Right.
And then as time goes on you realize
like,
oh,
he's tired and she's a bitch,
man.
Why you negative to,
you know,
you're always negative.
Stop it.
Yeah.
It's really weird.
That thing when you stop acting and you
ended up meeting the real person.
And that can either be.
Hopefully that moment should be
wonderful.
Like when the fucking guard comes down
and you really see the person,
there should be some beautiful thing,
but sometimes it's not.
Sometimes.
Or sometimes one mask comes off and
there's just another one there,
but it's,
it's like all of us are wandering around
right now in that state that we're
putting on his show,
pretending to be as they're pretending
to be hoping to try to fake it till you
make it.
There's some of that going on to you.
I've said
often on this show that my best advice
to someone else.
Pretend to be the guy or be the guy
rather that you pretend to be when
you're trying to get laid.
Just be that guy.
Be that guy,
be that,
ah,
that guy.
When you're trying to impress a chick
with how cool you are,
be that guy for real CFA person know
become the.
Hold yourself to a higher standard.
Hold yourself to a standard.
That's admirable.
A lot of people just act on instinct and
they don't ever look at their life from
like a point of view,
like,
what would I be impressed with if
someone handled this?
Isn't it?
What would be the most moral and the
coolest,
nicest thing to do here?
The most admirable thing to do and when,
when you become capable of doing that,
you become capable of,
of looking at your whole life through
the,
like almost an objective perspective.
Do you,
have you ever heard of something called
transactional analysis or game theory?
Have you ever heard of this sort of game
theory?
I didn't know it was transactional
analysis ideas.
It's like,
so yeah,
it's an analysis of the transactions
that happen between people.
So what they.
Right
something to do with the guy from the,
uh,
a brilliant mind.
I don't know,
isn't it that the Nobel prize I think
was on.
I'm sorry,
I,
I'm reading a book called the Games
people play and it's like an analysis of
like the basic games that we play,
for example,
like shaking hands is a game where the
rules of the game or you're kind of like
transmitting a what I think what they
call a token.
So like if I come up to you and I extend
my hand for you to shake my hand and you
don't shake my hand,
then that creates a weird moment because
you haven't made it a complete
transaction.
You know what I'm saying?
Yes,
yes.
So it's like it's an analysis of
everything at that level and it just
sort of comes back that we're all
engaged in these weird games.
Everyone,
you know,
whether you're acting like you're the
greatest person on a date or whether
you're acting like you're some kind of
weak person who is always broke and it's
always in bad relationships or whether
you're acting like you're a priest or
whether you're acting like you're
whatever the fucking thing is.
You're just playing a game.
You're just playing the game of being
this person,
you know,
that's.
So we're all in the kind of endless,
absurd situation of having to pretend to
be something,
you know,
whatever it is like fucking waiters,
like would it or what anyone you're
buying anything from there having to act
in this weird way called professional,
but they're just acting like who is this
character?
It's a character.
You're playing a weird character of
someone who's like,
thank you.
Yes.
May I get you another drink like tv host
or a strip club dj?
Yeah.
Or,
or just almost anyone.
It's just,
it's just the things that people think
are themselves.
This is who I am.
I love the rolling stones and I really
enjoy fishing.
It's like,
is that really you?
That's who you are.
That's your identity.
Because if you like get far enough back,
you'll realize that that's not you.
That's just a game that you're playing
and you can keep going back and back and
back until you emerge and everything,
but we.
Nobody wants to do that.
Everybody wants to stay as the fucking
thing.
No one wants to.
Everyone wants a little,
certainly comfort in predetermined
patterns.
You know,
the people love to say,
listen man,
I'm a Republican.
I vote.
I'm a Christian,
so I'm voting for George W.
he's my guy.
You know,
people love to be part of teams.
Do that.
It's fun to play.
It's very difficult to back up the way
you're saying.
I mean,
it's like to do it without help.
To do it without either psychedelic help
but to do it without some sort of
intense meditation and Yoga and training
and that's like a huge.
It's a really difficult.
It's a difficult task,
but it's the.
It's,
it's like if you begin to engage in
people are going to get better at that.
Hell yes,
for sure.
Definitely.
People are going to get better because
the information is getting out there.
There's so many information systems out
there that back in the pool of thousands
of years ago,
you couldn't have books.
There weren't even books.
Man,
I was very difficult to get a book.
Books were incredibly valuable.
Now this shit is scattered throughout
the entire fucking planet.
You have instantaneous access to this
stuff.
It's fucking.
Yeah.
I think people are going to learn
profit.
Brendan Walsh just walked in,
which a ends ends his podcast.
We're going to start a new one right
after this.
We're going to start the dusk squad.
Icehouse chronicles,
because the comics are starting to pilot
for the show.
It is already 9:30.
Yeah,
it was John Nash,
the guy from them,
when we have brilliant mind,
he did win a some sort of a Nobel prize
on a game theory,
so I dunno some along those lines.
He went crazy.
He was a guy that went nutty.
I didn't know he went crazy.
That's the movie about what it was the
WHO's the guy who's the guy who played a
beautiful mind?
Gladiator.
Russell Crowe.
Yeah.
Brilliant performance,
and he played that guy and he went
nutty,
like imagined a bunch of shit and shit
to us and man,
you should check it out.
You love it.
It's really brought himself back.
It's a really.
He's a fascinating story.
He actually brought himself back to
reality,
started ignoring the voice.
He still hears voices in the head,
his head,
but he just ignores him now.
He concentrated.
He can differentiate between what's real
and what's not and so he stayed saying,
even in the midst of twirling and Santa,
he managed to figure out how to like how
to maintain it.
That's cool.
Yeah.
That's when everything really fast time
figuring out how to maintain that.
She's a really fascinating case.
Really Interesting Guy,
a brilliant,
brilliant guy.
Who's who,
who,
who went mad and brought himself back
really nuts.
Um,
that's it.
Those are 200 podcasts,
ladies,
gentlemen,
all you freaks people out there at the
gym.
All you people out there driving cross
country and sitting on trains and doing
whatever the fuck you're doing.
A porch swing where we're,
we're so happy that you tuned into the
show.
We'd love doing it.
We're happy.
You guys love it.
And I feel like you guys are some of the
coolest,
most positive people that I've ever come
across on the Internet.
I think it's a,
it's an amazing,
it's an amazing moment when we've
collected so many really cool and
friendly and fun people that follow us.
If you think about the amount of
negative
tweets that you get,
an amount of negative shit that you get,
it's so small in relationship to how
many cool people there are out there.
How many cool stories you get tweeted,
funny things,
you know,
uh,
answers to questions.
I think we're super,
super lucky,
man.
You know,
I think we're putting out a cool vibe
and I think we're putting out an in an
honest way of looking at the world and
people are responding and we're
responding back and it's the most fun
I've ever had to accommodate.
It's the most fun I've ever had doing
anything,
you know,
that you would call like,
like in show business,
this thing is the most fun for sure.
For sure.
And it's the most honest.
It's the most.
I mean it's just,
it is what it is,
man.
There's no preparation,
you know,
and it's,
it's is as open and as honest as we are
capable of.
And I think,
um,
I think that helps us.
I know it helps me.
I know these conversations have been
huge for,
for breaking things down for me and just
kind of reassembling the way I look at
the world,
you know,
and having all these different guests on
and have it,
all these different people and all these
really different intelligent people and
really intense opinions and it's super,
super beneficial man.
And I'm just so happy that we're able to
do this.
I is the fucking coolest thing I've ever
done.
I really,
really enjoy it.
I enjoy it.
It's almost right up there with standup.
Standup will always be like the sacred
top of the food chain,
but it's pretty close to it.
It's really cool.
And the reason why it's cool is how many
cool people it impacts and how many cool
people who had impacts share their love
with us and send that love back at us.
And we appreciate the fuck out of it.
We talk about it all the time and we
just want you to know we love all your
dirty bitches.
Thank you to the flashlight for keeping
it real.
Staying with us since the beginning
where it was ridiculous that anybody
would give us money for this stupid
fucking show.
If you started today,
this is the first episode the ever
downloaded.
Don't download episode one because it's
fucking terrible.
Don't down to,
I think to.
I run out of the room and three or four
times and take a shit.
I got diarrhea.
Um,
but uh,
it didn't get good for awhile.
So,
uh,
it,
you know,
we never publicize this thing and it
sort of just built up on itself
naturally and we love it.
We couldn't be happier.
I just,
I've always wanted to have a radio show
and I never could get anybody to even
think about giving me one,
you know,
and I really want to get up every
morning either.
So this is perfect.
Perfect.
No middleman,
right to the people in Atlanta.
Uh,
tickets are sold out,
I believe for the first show at the
Tabernacle on April 20th.
Um,
but there's still some tickets available
for the second show and that is where
I'm going to be filling my next special.
I'm fucking super pumped about this.
This is for real,
the best shit I've ever done.
I've been doing a lot of standup lately.
I'm in the groove,
like we had a great time this weekend at
the county of Magic Club.
That place is so beautiful.
And then this weekend we're in
Louisville at the Improv all weekend,
Friday,
Saturday and Sunday.
And they're supposedly
some crazy basketball thing.
Like it might be a huge problem with no
one's gonna want to come to the show was
going to be crazy.
It's going to be.
I've been worn 19 times on twitter about
this event.
They said I should put a TV onstage
while the game is on and allow people to
watch it while we talk.
I'm totally cool with that.
Really.
I think it would be fun.
Fucking blast.
I think it'd be fun.
It'd be fun because I don't know what
the fuck is going on and I want them to
stop this nonsense game.
We please do that.
Yeah,
we could totally do that.
Can totally do that.
Yeah,
because I think that'll help people come
to the show too.
If so,
if the Improv can figure that out,
we'll do that poster Joe.
Yeah.
We'll tell people about it too,
because most of the people listening.
Oh yeah,
so I got this.
I've had this poster made,
which is I'm only making 666 of them and
they're these giant posters,
these incredible,
awesome posters that Joe just in
mcalester,
this amazing artists made of me getting
possessed by my satanic puppet.
As you could see,
this is it.
Once we get 666 cities through all the
homes in America,
they will make a chaos vortex and the
senior clarity will happen.
So please purchase one of these posters.
If I need one signed done deal.
I'm tempted to give you six,
six,
six.
I'll take it.
That's a good lucky number for me.
Um,
that's it to,
to the end of listen,
you guys have been cool as fuck.
You've been with us.
Some of you from the very beginning.
And uh,
that's,
that's ridiculous.
I can't believe you stuck out this long.
Crazy.
And we can't believe how many people
enjoy the show.
We love doing it and there's nothing
more I can say.
I know Brian feels the same way.
Yeah.
It's sweet.
Well,
what is it like to you?
I mean,
it was our 200th episode,
Dude,
just tell these people how it feels.
It's a lot of talking about stuff that
happens in your life and now you know us
more than better.
My friend Shane,
a green,
he had it.
He's having a baby today.
He knows.
He's like my best friend.
You guys at home know me way more than
he knows me and he's talking on the
podcast like,
you know more about all of us that and
it's freaky as fuck.
But what's also cool is,
you know,
it feels like you're.
I mean,
you know me better than my best friend.
How fucking crazy is that?
Somebody come up to me on the street and
after a few minutes talking,
they asked me about my friend in college
email and they knew his name.
They were like,
how's it going man?
It's like,
dude,
I don't.
That's something that someone would find
out about me months into a friendship at
barely.
Remember the podcast is a strange thing.
It's the best thing that ever happened
for us for standup.
Now people go,
when you go on stage,
they know what you're going to do.
They know you're a fucking Weirdo.
It look forward to it.
They get excited about it.
Thank God.
You know,
and look,
that's it.
That's all I could say.
We,
we appreciate that.
You guys appreciate it.
And by no means we take it for granted,
it's very,
very important to us and that's exactly
why the podcast is going to remain free.
It's always going to be free.
I'm never going to do this thing for
money.
I'll figure out a way to make money.
Well,
we'll move it around,
but I love the idea of putting something
out there that is absolutely 100 percent
free.
And uh,
you know,
that's what we've managed to do.
I know a lot of people think that our
ads are too long,
but whatever bits off free,
it's not like fast food.
You can fast forward through it.
And by the way,
it's like,
you know,
I mean,
what does that flashlight.
You're doing something with it.
Um,
by the way,
it's not like you have to listen to that
part.
Don't be silly.
So everything else is freaking,
yeah,
don't buy a flashlight if you don't need
one,
but if you want one,
they're awesome.
Go to flashlight.com
and I in the code name Brogan.
Save yourself 15 percent off the number
one sex toy for men's number one bitches
is a bunch of different textures and
shit.
If you want to get crazy,
if you're a con of sewer fee,
what is it they call you a foodie.
If you're a food connoisseur,
what do they call you?
If you're a sex toy person,
are you a sexy?
Do would you call it sexy?
Well,
I'm a sexy.
You know,
I,
I tried toys.
I think two things in my ass.
I'm a big on dildos libraries.
Once I got past that feeling of
something in my ass,
they need that show.
Like the guy who goes around and eat
food,
there's a big guy goes around and talks
everything fucking sexy.
It's totally possible.
You could do a series of that on for
like an Internet porn site.
Brian talked to one of your people in
the industry.
You know,
people that shit would work.
There'll be a good,
uh,
you could have a comic.
Do it,
have a comic.
You know what?
Triple e type character.
AAA,
AAA.
AAA would be perfect.
We should do.
We should start producing our own shows.
We start producing our own shows.
That's what the next move is.
We're going to hire a goddamn camera guy
and start doing anytime we have an idea
for a sketch would just do it that,
that needs to be done.
A guy who just travels around the
country and fucks everything goes in our
outside one of these sticks things in
his ass and tells you what it felt like.
Well,
you know,
I don't like something in my ass,
but it makes you come way harder.
So he's got a fucking vibrator in there.
Will be a great show.
Yeah.
We just wouldn't be able to show it all.
You have to hide.
Hide Shit from people.
Go to a fleshlight,
go buy yourself some,
some goodies.
Okay.
That's the end of that commercial.
Go to [inaudible] dot com.
If you want to.
You don't have to.
O n n I t.
That is where you can buy all the crazy
new tropics and supplements that we
talked about and coming soon,
we're going to have some ridiculous
exercise equipment that'll show you
guys.
It's going to blow your mind.
It's going to freak you out.
Um,
that's it.
That's the end of our 200 podcasts.
We thank you very much.
We appreciate you very much and we'll be
back next week.
You dirty bitches.
God is love
one for all and all for one.