Is you're sick.
It's like those Mri,
two,
one,
Bam.
Yeah.
Dominick Cruz sitting here was looking
at this thing called green belly meal
meal to go.
The guy who created this is like this
long distance hikers,
like he does those,
like do you know that trail?
What is it called?
The Appalachian trail that goes from of
it,
you know of it?
Yeah.
What does it going from Georgia to Maine
or something crazy like that and these
people walk.
It takes like six months.
Yeah,
I'm into stuff like that.
That's like a whole different part of
your life.
I feel like you get to when you do stuff
like that,
well you got to have a real commitment
because you're not doing anything but
that for six months.
Yeah.
It's a different lifestyle changes.
It's like a different time of your life
I feel when you do something like that.
Yeah.
But like being a fighter,
do you feel like,
like you're pretty limited as to what
you can do outside of fighting your.
As far as like you're always recovering
from training,
you're always involved in something
related to either promotion or
preparation.
Yeah,
agreed.
It's,
it's,
um,
I mean I'm not telling you anything you
don't know how many of these things have
you done with Delilah?
Lot done a lot.
You know,
that it's all or nothing because
everybody's so good that if you don't
invest every ounce of yourself into
something,
there's somebody else to is in my
opinion.
So it's like you have to do that or else
you get passed by.
Yeah.
And do you also feel like there's,
you have to be super objective to about
where you stand and where your skills
are at [inaudible] course you're always,
you're either at a point of constant
improvement or you're at some sort of
stagnation or decline.
Yes.
Um,
I think sell.
But then that question always comes to
mind according to win and loss ratio,
which doesn't always tell the truth
because it's not always the fact.
It could just be a bad night and a good
matchup and they had a game plan or you
lost and now you're going to sit and go
to the drawing board and say that
everything was off because of one last
really makes sense to me.
So it's kind of a mixture,
a,
you got to find the happy medium,
it comes down to trust in the people
around you.
I'm not having nothing but yes men
around you and I feel like as long as
you have a good solid base of people
that give the truth to you,
then you don't have to think with your
emotion and you can think with logic and
then I think it's important to have
those people around you so you don't
steer off the course because even if
you.
I mean,
even if you do have a loss,
it's not saying that everything is off,
but certainly something wasn't adequate
in,
in that,
in that particular match.
Right?
So you're just getting off of the second
loss ever of mixed martial arts career.
The first one you got caught by your
ride with a guillotine.
And then the second one,
this,
uh,
cody,
no love fight.
And what,
what are your thoughts on it now having
time to reflect and look back and I'm,
well my thoughts are a,
it,
I pretty much laid it all out
right away because I wanted to just do
that at,
which was at the press conference,
the post fight press conference.
I pretty much just wanted to,
like,
I literally laid every ounce of every
thought I had at that moment out there
for everybody to hear in a point where
on very vulnerable.
And I did that on purpose to show that
we're not all,
you know,
the same.
Some people don't want to show their
vulnerability.
Some people want to just be seen as only
perfect,
only tough,
only strong.
And really the truth of what makes the
strongest people in the world is their
vulnerability early until they learn how
to be tough.
And um,
you know,
losing is part of that lesson
unfortunately for everybody and being
unsuccessful as part of that lesson for,
for people just as much as losing.
So it's like you do what you can with
it.
And that's how I feel now is like I do
what I can with it and they only way to
make the best of it is to accept it,
right?
The second it happens,
understand that,
um,
that's just the way it is.
That's the way that this has been slated
for this portion of my life.
And just move forward.
And as long as you embrace it,
don't make excuses for it.
And,
uh,
then you can actually look at what you
did wrong and take it in the second you
make an excuse.
The second you say,
well,
I was a little off here,
a little out there because of this,
this,
and this is the second you allow your
mind to go into a path of,
um,
well,
it wasn't an,
it wasn't in my control,
which means you're not really dealing
with the problems at hand,
I don't think.
I think you're kind of bypassing the
problems at hand when you do that.
And then you can grow from the
experience.
So what's the point of a loss if you're
not going to grow from it and get the
most out of it?
Now it's just useless if you don't
accept it.
Yeah.
There's a real instinct that many
fighters show like almost immediately
after a loss to go right into what was
wrong with the camp or what was wrong
with an injury,
what they could've done differently,
personal problems and that that really
can wreck havoc with your mind.
Correct.
I agree.
I think,
I think more than wreaking havoc with
your mind.
I think it just shows how long it's
gonna take for them to get over the
loss.
I mean,
that's the thing.
The second you just say it,
lay it all out there and everybody
knows,
including yourself.
The next step is growth.
It's no longer stagnant and sitting in
feeling the loss and trying to accept
it.
I've already accepted it.
I accepted it.
The second I shook his hand in that
octagon and and they,
they raised his hand is the winter like,
am I really going to sit here and make
excuses because let's say on the judges'
scorecard I had some mindset that's
like,
oh,
I shouldn't have lost the decision or
maybe this,
maybe that.
It's like,
what's the point of that?
Because in the end,
it's already been chocked.
It's already there.
It's written down regardless of what
anybody says.
It's not.
That's not leaving that piece of paper.
So what's the point of really saying all
this stuff,
letting people argue that,
well,
you could have one here,
you could have went,
what is where his argument anymore,
where's the logic and then where's the
point and all that and I'm just sick and
tired of excuses.
I.
I've fought so many years winning so
many years hearing so many excuses about
why I beat people and I wanted to set a
perimeter right off the bat that I'm not
that person.
Now you're getting really well known as
an MMA analysts and I think you do an
amazing job on Fox.
I think you're one of the best guys in
the world.
You're really,
really good at it,
but one of the things that people are
getting a chance to see because of that
is how your mind works and how much
thought you put into not just fighting
itself,
but the whole process.
The whole process of preparation and
mindset while the competition is going
on.
And that's also being reflective right
now and the way you express how you get
over a loss.
Like where did,
where did wherever you learned to think
like
this?
Well my mom is a big reason for that.
I would say early on she just always
forced me to deal with the things I
didn't want to deal with and not just
deal with them but look at him in the
eye and talk about it.
Like what kind of stuff?
Anything.
I'm like,
you still a packet of gum from the store
and you walk out with it and you're
seven years old and you get home and
you're eating a piece of gum and your
mom goes,
I didn't buy that.
Where did you get that gum?
And we drive back with the gum in my
mouth,
put it in the wrapper.
So the person at the front.
And that's not enough because I
embarrassed the cash registers.
So I got to apologize to them.
And then I got to go to the owner of
the,
of the other star,
the manager and apologize to them.
And then might have to go paint a wall
forum to make up for the piece of gum
that I,
I mean,
it goes all the way down to that,
like my mom has been that way since I
can remember to where there's just
there.
She would never ever let me make an
excuse for anything I ever did ever.
And I used to get so frustrated with her
because she would also never really get
mad.
She never raised her voice.
She would never really show a whole lot
of emotion.
It was.
She would literally say,
I'm not going to yell.
I'm not going to scream.
I'm not gonna.
Get angry.
I'm not going to give you that power.
But that's one.
And that meant I was getting one
whooping when I got home when I did
something wrong.
And so now I got to sit and think about
that for the next five hours until we
get home.
And then she takes me into a room and
she sits me down with no anger.
Everything's understood.
And she says,
do you know why we're here?
And she explained to me why we're here
and why I'm being,
why I'm in trouble and why I'm getting
smacked on the ass with this breadboard.
And she just,
there was never any escaping anything
ever.
So it's like,
it put me in this weird mindset where I
just,
I don't make excuses and anybody who
makes excuses,
I call them out on it because it's old.
It's annoying.
It's,
it's flawed in my opinion.
It's just weak.
That's a great lesson that that's a
great way to be raised to your mom.
Not Perfect.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm not saying I do this every time.
It's just something that's like made me,
uh,
that you asked.
I got that in my mind and it just,
it wired me a little different.
My grandma's a pretty,
pretty crazy on that too.
So between my grandmother and my mom who
helped raise me because my dad wasn't
around so much,
those two molded me into this weird
being.
Do you think they could have got through
it without beating you without a paddle?
No.
Absolutely.
You think that wasn't part of it was me
and my brother is too much little
mutants in the trailer park.
Like we'd be.
We'd be fighting.
My Mom's at work wearing in the trailer
and my.
We lived in a trailer across the street
from my grandmother and it was like $400
a month,
you know,
to live in this trailer is one bedroom
single wide.
She would come when we would fight,
we'd hear the door open and my grandma
would be at the door,
me and my bro,
because you could hear a slamming into
the floor because it's echoes from the
bottom of the trailer.
Right.
And so she'd run across the street and.
Oh No,
we knew we were in trouble and my
grandma came over.
It was bad news.
So I don't know.
It's just a weird upbringing,
kind of to an extending.
Everybody got raised by their family,
but by my mom and my grandmother,
it just,
it put a different mentality in me and
my grandmother's very tough individual.
She'd been through a lot.
Now when you started fighting,
how did they approach it?
Yeah,
that's another odd thing is um,
my mom was just all support.
She,
even,
I was going to college when I started,
when I start just started,
I was coaching a local high school and
one of the kids that I was coaching
straight up,
I was 19 years old at this point and I
just graduated High School and started
coaching a local high school team
because I wanted to compete wrestling.
Correct.
And I didn't get into college like I
wanted to,
to wrestle and didn't do all these
things,
so I just needed to compete.
So I got in the room and started
coaching these kids.
Well they're my age.
I'm 18,
I'm 19,
I just graduated.
So we become friends.
One of these guys invites me to A.
Jimmy goes to jump in there and start
training.
Right?
So during this time my mom,
I'm going to school,
so I'm working three jobs,
you know,
I'm working at Sherwin Williams,
I am a janitor at the gym and then I'm
coaching this,
this high school wrestling team,
and then I'm going to school at night
and I'm training in between that.
So these are,
this is what I'm doing in Tucson and
during this time,
my,
I told my mom,
you know,
I'm just so tired of school.
I go to night school after my three
jobs,
three jobs,
and then I go to night school at 8:00 PM
and I'm just wore out.
I'm sitting in Spanish class one day
trying to learn like what I've been
learning in high school and in Spanish
class I'm like,
why am I paying for this school when I
just did this class in high school and
now I'm paying for it to get an
associate's degree to go to another four
years in college and I'm going to be in
debt for like,
what am I doing?
I don't want to be here.
I wasn't happy in school after all my
days at work.
Um,
so I said,
you know,
the only time I felt free and happy it
was in the gym.
That's the only time I could talk and
laugh and smile and be myself hurting
other people,
punching things,
kicking things,
yelling at things,
telling people how I felt.
And then if they had a problem,
we could fight about it.
I was at peace there.
Um,
so I,
I just going to school and said,
mom,
I'm going to start.
I'm going to start training to become a
fighter.
I said they got the ultimate fighter
going on.
Um,
it's a big thing.
It's growing.
Now's the time.
If I'm going to do it,
I need to go all in.
She said,
okay,
you don't need to go to school to be
successful.
You don't need to go to college.
Um,
follow your heart and you will be
successful.
It's a guarantee.
And she was right.
Wow,
that's fascinating.
My mom has a weird spiritual,
emotional,
a way of talking,
explaining and getting through to me
that I,
that can't be explained until you meet
somebody like that will also.
It's not.
I mean,
it's,
there's no one that's ever going to be
able to recreate that because she made
you.
Yeah,
that's a good little.
I mean,
I think everybody's mom.
Everybody believes their mom has their.
I mean,
moms are special,
you know,
we all know that,
but every,
every person has their own way that they
were raised and brought up and then
they,
they pass that onto their child.
My mom had a hard life,
you know,
so I think she just so wise that she
passed a lot of,
um,
a lot of wisdom off to me young because
she just growing up and raising us broke
like she did by herself I think just
taught her so much that she didn't want
us to have to live and he kind of
struggled life like that.
So she made us learn the hard way with
her instead of her taking everything and
not teaching us anything we lived at
with her and grew in the experience with
her.
And then that got added to my life and
what I wanted to do moving forward.
Now you developed a really unusual
fighting style.
I mean,
I think I've said about you that one of
the more unusual things about your style
is that I could watch you like as a
silhouette.
Someone could show me a silhouette of
you moving around.
I go,
oh,
that's dominick Cruz.
There's very few people that you would
say that about like where you would
instantaneously recognize their
movements,
like your movements are very unusual,
very difficult to pattern and a,
they're not really indicative of like a
style.
Like you know,
there's the Thai style.
People have that light front leg.
There's a karate style,
like wonder Boy Thompson.
There's a bunch of styles where you go,
oh,
I see what this guy's doing.
Your style is very uniquely yours.
What,
what,
what sort of caused that?
Where'd that come from?
It's a mixture of things as I've been
fighting since,
as long as the Diaz brothers I started
when I was 19 years old,
back in 2005,
and I've been doing it since then.
So that's part of it is that just years
and years of fighting and facing
different people and seeing what the
issues were,
but more than that,
it was built around the fact that I knew
whether I,
whether,
whether I knew I was ahead or not,
my mindset said I have to fight,
do something different because this is a
new sport with new rules and new
different equipment than it's ever been
seen in the history of this world.
So that means there's four ounce gloves
were using kicks,
knees,
elbows and hands,
right?
All I,
uh,
all eight limbs.
So I said I need to make sure that I'm
not taking damage.
Um,
as long as I'm not taking damage I
should.
When I got to be hard to hit on my
defense needs to be flawless with these
size gloves is not going to be the same
as boxing.
I can't just sit here and cover like
this because my gloves or a quarter of
the size things peak in and I learned
that real quick and so I said,
all right,
so I need to move nonstop.
I can't sit still like I do in boxing or
kickboxing because you're going to get
taken down as well,
so that's.
That's where my mind started changing
his with the takedown.
That's where I knew I really had to do
something different is in no striking
sport on earth is their takedown
involved,
so that means that I need to attack on a
different plane and that means I need to
not be down the center line as long as I
fight,
not down the center line.
It takes away a.
As long as I don't fight on the center
line all the time.
It takes away my almost all weapons from
all styles.
Boxing is probably the one style that
flows most off the center line,
but we're talking about Moitai or we're
talking about wrestling or talking about
a judo or we're talking about it almost
every other martial art.
They attack down a straight line and so
I knew I could take away most of their
weapons just by changing the plane that
I fought on.
If I fought on a different plane than
them,
then they would not have answers for the
plane that I'm fighting it because
everything they do is on that line.
So instead of fighting them in their
style,
I fought the lines that they're fighting
on.
And then that kind of changed things
mixed with the defense.
Well,
I've always enjoyed watching you fight
and I've always enjoyed explaining how
you fight the people that have never
seen martial arts.
I don't understand it because for people
on the outside,
maybe someone who's not a fan or never
did any martial arts training,
they,
they look at it like just violence,
you know?
They see guys just beating the shit out
of each other and what I.
The way I tried to describe it to a
friend once I said,
think about it this way,
it's,
it's a lot like a conversation and the
more words you have at your disposal,
the more verbal memory you have,
the more you to stringing together
sentences you are,
the more fluently the conversation is
going to come out of your mouth,
the more it's going to flow and when
you're watching,
and then I'll show someone like you when
you're trying to have call called a
conversation,
you're trying to have a conversation
with Dominic Cruz inside the octagon.
You don't know where the fuck he's going
like you,
you,
you're setting up so many weird angles
and so much weird movements,
so many false entries,
and there's so much going on that you
were in a lot of ways,
you're overloading a person's reactions.
You're overloading their mind.
Well,
that is partially what I'm trying to do.
Yes,
I agree.
Now you're starting to see that over
time there's an answer for every style.
There's an answer for everything.
Yeah,
and that's the fun of this thing is that
it's not stagnant.
It's not always the same.
Um,
and there,
there isn't answered everything that's,
and then you got to adjust.
So I'm,
that's what I'm on his adjustments.
My whole game is built on adjustment so
it can always change and always look
different because every round I come out
with a different adjustment off of what
you did to me.
And now you're fighting a different guy
every round you just don't know it.
Um,
but that comes from fakes and seeing
what they want on you.
And that comes from their game plan.
It's a whole mixture reads in there.
And that's a,
that's something that you either have or
you don't have.
You know,
somebody like Anderson Silva can make
reeds extremely quickly and that's
what's made him so successful.
Demetrius Johnson reads extremely
quickly,
makes them successful.
The best in the world had just,
um,
and the best for me,
the best in the world aren't the ones
who just when it's someone's who win and
stay on top for a long period of time
because now you don't just have a style
to win a fight.
You have a style to stay winning,
which means that your style hits so many
different avenues that you can compete
with all these different styles no
matter what they match you up against
until now,
my style,
I built it so that no matter which style
you try to throw at me,
it was going to give it a problem and
that was the basis that I wanted to
create.
When I fought,
every single time I fought somebody,
it was,
it doesn't matter what your gift is,
the planes that I'm going to fight you
on,
make it impossible for your gifts to be
your gifts anymore.
Now I've seen you practice no senior
footwork drills and I've seen you know a
lot of your steps and the different
various entries.
You have techniques or these moves that
you've learned from somewhere.
Have you acquired them from other
martial arts?
Have you sort of adjusted them and
adapted them or did you figure them out
your own?
It's been a mixture.
Working with Eric Tell Pharaoh was a
huge step because I had a lot of
naturals,
one of the best coaches in the sport and
one of the most underappreciated gods
because he doesn't blow his own horn.
That's why I love them.
I liked the coaches that don't need the
pats on the back for themselves.
They're about the athlete.
Eric is about every athlete he's ever
coached.
He's not about himself.
He's great corner man too.
When he starts talking in the corner,
he knows what he's doing.
He's been in this sport 20 plus years
and I'm the bigger thing that Eric
doesn't get credit for.
It is his understanding of the
psychology that goes into preparing
somebody to win a fight.
You could have all the tools around that
person.
They could be the best human being on
earth,
but if their mind is not pieced together
and the psychological pieces are not
there,
you're not going to be able to trigger
them and get them in the fight when you
need to.
Jeremy Stevens,
a great example of somebody like that.
Sometimes you gotta like get crazy with
that dude in the corner and like even
like slap him around a little bit maybe
and he's just goes and he'll,
he'll kill somebody.
It's like there's a psychological thing
about certain athletes that you have to
be able to touch on.
Same with Greg Jackson is another guy
who can do that and that's what makes a
good coach on that night,
a good corner man on that night.
Not just what you did for eight weeks
holding pads and uh,
you know,
patting the guy in the back and wiping
the sweat off their shoulders and know,
know doing interviews and looking famous
with them.
Like,
what are you doing to make sure this
person wins on that night?
Not what are you doing to make sure you
look good in this person's corner while
he wins.
And that's something that I've run into
a lot with people,
is people a lot want to associate
themselves with you when you're winning
and not actually be there for you but be
there so they look good in your corner
while you win.
And those are the people you got to cut
out.
Those are the yes men.
And those are,
those are the ones that you got to be
careful with.
Eric is the opposite of that.
Um,
and he is somebody that's why I stick
with them.
You someday I can trust.
He understands my psychology,
understands my emotional roller coaster
of outside life,
personal life,
fight life,
everything makes together.
We've gone through this together and
then he's an,
he's a trustworthy person.
They're not a lot of people you can
trust in this industry these days are in
fighting in general boxing or MMA.
So it's hard.
He knows his stuff and he is underrated.
And I think the fact that he doesn't
toot his own horn,
he doesn't get on these interviews.
A does hurt him a little.
Um,
but that was what was hurting me early
in my career to where a lot of light and
I had to,
I had to say,
if I'm going to make a living,
if I'm going to really do this fight
thing,
I better start stepping this media thing
up.
I better start stepping up this portion
that we're doing right here and get
figured out a way to make it because
this is the.
This is part of the sports where you no
longer always fighting who deserves,
who's the best in the world.
You're now fighting in this era,
the best superstar,
not just the best athlete and so you got
to be a happy mixture and when you can
figure that out,
you start piecing your career together.
You look at Eric del Faro hasn't figured
that out.
He doesn't want to.
He doesn't care about it and so you
don't know about them too,
what you showed the best people know
about it,
belt mill,
about him rather now it's.
That's an interesting thing that you put
that up too because it seems like.
I mean,
it doesn't just seem like it.
It is both fighters in general and
trainers almost all at one point in time
we're fighters or at least martial
artists.
The there were a lot of them are broken.
People looking to rebuild and that's
what martial arts Dunn's does for them.
That's what fighting and competing does
for them.
It gives them an identity,
it gives them a sense of purpose and a
sense of a sense of worth and that those
types of people oftentime get very
selfish and it's very difficult to find
someone that you trust enough to let
them all in and then once they do,
they're intensely connected.
Correct.
You know,
I mean the bonds that you have with
people that you train with and people
that you spar with on a regular basis or
people that you've competed with and
gone to places with.
I don't think people that don't expect,
I don't think people that have never
experienced such an intense competition
will ever truly understand that kind of
a bomb that people share.
I agree.
And ironically,
just by chance,
pretty much every one of the closest
friends in my life,
I have fought almost to a bloody death
and that's what's so crazy.
I know that and then you can't lie to
me.
There is nothing you're going to lie to
me because if you lie to me,
I'm going to see you on Monday,
80th and we're going to see what you're
made of.
You'll know anyway.
I mean,
without even knowing what they're made
of,
you'll know their lines,
but it's different when you fight
somebody,
you literally know what they're made of.
When you see the look in their eye and
they say what they say and they do what
they do and then they go and they fight
and they don't say what they say and
they don't do what they do and that's
just fighting and that's what's so
refreshing about it to me.
Yeah.
Well,
the psychological aspect of it.
I mean,
you know who.
Who was it that said this fighting is 90
percent mental and the other 10 percent
in your head.
I forget who said that.
I remember either,
but I heard it.
That's a great quote.
I don't remember who said it,
but I believe it with all my heart.
There's so many people out there.
There's so incredibly physically
talented.
And how many Jim assassins do you know
that for whatever reason they just can't
put it together to care.
When the referee says,
fighter,
are you ready fighter?
Are you ready to go?
They just aren't a fraction of who they
really are.
Just really break down and think about
what happens to the ones that do make it
and then have to deal with the media and
uh,
opinions and I really feel like
athletes,
the biggest hurdle is the fact that
we're willing to actually just get up
there and say we might,
when we might lose and just put that out
there and say,
are you willing to put yourself out
there like that?
Are you willing to embarrass yourself?
If you do lose,
are you willing to deal with the media?
If you win for 10 years straight and
then lose and then now you're the worst
guy that's ever been seen in the sport
or the worst female that's ever been
seen the sport.
You didn't even belong there.
Are you able to deal with that?
That's the question.
That's what being an athlete is not.
Well those would be an fighter.
Yeah.
Big Difference Between basketball game.
What's true.
You lose a basketball game and people
might think you're a fucking loser or a
scrub,
but it's nothing like the shit that I
see fighters face online.
No,
I mean just look at.
I got to bring Ronda Rousey up because
it's heartbreaking for me as an athlete.
I know what she's feeling,
I know what she's going through and um,
as a female it's even on another level.
I can't really imagine that just it's a
different level of scrutiny I would
imagine.
But um,
it's just,
it shows how hard it is to deal with
this man,
the ups and downs because the downs hit
hard just as hard as the upset and you
got to be ready and there can't be any
separation and who you are with a win
and a loss because if there is,
it's going to show and you gotta be who
you are and not be solely connected to
fighting as your whole being.
Otherwise you're over when,
when it,
when it ends,
right.
There was something about the Ronda
Rousey promos that I always felt like I
didn't like hearing it.
Like she was like,
I gotta get back to fighting because
it's the most important thing and it's a
thing that I can be best in the world.
And I was like,
Ooh,
I actually like hearing that studio.
I do.
And the reason is it such a lesson if
you really listening in between the
lines to the issue of the world and
that's just my opinion.
We're all putting so much into this one
thing and we think that that is our
everything when really if she.
It sounds cheesy,
but if you put all that energy towards
loving yourself and not the fight
career,
the fight career will still be there
just as heavy as it is.
Right.
You know,
so what I mean is she's using the
fighting as her identity with that
championship belt.
She is Ronda Rousey the Ronda Rousey
without the championship belt.
We don't know who she is.
She won't come out.
So who are you?
Unless you're winning,
we don't know.
Do you know you're counting on that belt
to know who you are now.
And that's.
That was my biggest point.
That was a hurdle I ran into when I lost
my belt.
I didn't know who I was anymore.
And that's how I knew this.
That's how I figured out what my issues
were is.
All right dom,
you're getting ready to fight brow.
You Ready?
Yes,
I'm ready.
Screw it,
let's do it.
These,
these,
these nice cast.
Tommy's injuries can blow your lawyer
quad out.
Now you're out of that fight.
Now we're taking your belt.
Well,
for people that don't know what we're
going to about to be talking about,
you had one of the most horrific injury
streaks in the sport in your prime.
You know,
you were considered to be one of the top
pound for pound fighters in the world
and then you had a series of
catastrophic injuries and surgeries.
So for this is for a lot of people
listening to podcasts and aren't really
hardcore MMA that makes.
So you like to talk us through it
because you went through like one of the
most difficult trials in terms of
recovery from injury?
Any?
No,
the most difficult I've ever seen
anybody go through and the entire
history of my time of colon fights
hiding.
I definitely agree in the sport of the
score to the nfl because I researched
him.
Oh,
okay.
These guys who went through three acl
reconstructions came back and compete
and one of them was just competing on.
They almost made it to the superbowl and
he had three acl reconstructions in the
game of football and came back,
was still playing and he was like over
there,
over 30.
Wow.
And people like that need to be around
in this world.
Sure.
Just to let you know that it's possible.
You know that it can be done in and now
it's kind of what I what gay.
That mindset right there,
when you make it bigger than yourself is
the only way you get the power to get
through.
Stuff like that,
and that's what got me through is
understanding that I go through this,
these knee surgeries,
I,
I become.
It becomes bigger than me when I come
back and succeed.
It's not just about me coming back and
getting my belt.
I already had belts.
I already knew what it felt like to be a
five time world champion by that point.
At the age of 26,
before I blew my knee out,
I was on top of everything.
I had everything that I thought I needed
in one.
It blew my knee out,
get my belt stripped,
go through three acl reconstructions.
You soon find out that you actually have
no idea who you are.
What?
No.
What was the initial injury?
Uh,
acl,
MCL.
What,
what,
what happened though?
I was a training while I was getting
ready on the ultimate fighter back in
2012 or 11 for Faber fight.
We were getting ready to compete at the
end of the show and I was training with
a guy and it was just a hard week.
I mean we're,
we're,
we were the first show that I ever went
live and was training for the fight at
the same time being tough.
We're the only first and only live show
that they did.
So that meant that while we coached we
were also going to compete at the same
time.
So like I had to do my fight camp while
I trained the ultimate fighter guys
simultaneously.
So I was doing four practices a day,
two at the tough guys in tune with
myself and that work load is just
insane.
That was a hard,
hard training camp and ended up breaking
me down.
I hurt my knee just sparring.
It was aspiring day guy went for
graphing transition in my and a Sagd to
my hip,
weird and just blew my knee out a crappy
takedown,
you know where they sag instead of
actually get the take down and it just
blew my knee out.
When I blew my acl MCL I was.
I was like,
it's all right.
You'll be fine.
I fought it.
I almost literally fought injury.
Like,
you're too tough.
You're too strong.
You're too young.
You can do this.
Let's go for the injury.
Meaning knocked at surgery and try to
rehab it.
You just heard what I just said,
like it didn't mentally.
Right.
Did the surgery?
I did.
That wasn't the problem though.
That's my point.
The problem is if you're doing all the
things right to get better,
it's understanding that it was
understanding that I didn't need to
fight to be better giving up on it was
when I finally got better understanding.
I didn't need fighting to be who I was.
When you say get better,
you mean get better emotionally,
psychologically will physically,
even physically.
So physically I didn't.
I did not get better until I gave up on
fighting the injury and what I mean by
fighting the injuries saying it's,
you'll be fine,
you'll come back,
just keep training,
keep training,
keep training.
And I and I trained but in the law,
in the logic that I was given with my,
uh,
what I'm allowed to do according to my
physical therapist,
Gavin Mcmillan,
he would say,
you can do this,
this and this.
Don't push it.
I wouldn't push it.
I would do the things aloud,
but I'm telling you,
like,
that wasn't the issue.
The issue was surrendering to the issue
is knowing that fighting was the only
way I was going to be happy.
Then it was being able to compete was
the only way I could find peace.
Being able to prove that I was as good
as I always was,
even after the injuries became
everything that I was trying to do it.
It was just a nonstop fight to just get
healthy.
And I get through my second acl
reconstruction on the same knee.
Then I blow my quad out before I was
supposed to fight.
How did you blow out the second one?
You,
you had the injury,
you had it reconstructed.
And then how,
how do you blow out the second one?
It's the same knee and I was training on
Christmas how many months after the
initial surgery?
Six.
So it's real reason.
It's probably not 100 percent healed
yet.
It's not 100 percent healed yet.
Nine months is supposed to be full,
full strength,
but that.
But six month is when you get to start
pushing it to get ready to fall.
So now you're like six months to six
months.
You're not allowed to do any kind of
cutting.
Connie.
Meeting science,
lateral movements just straight down the
line.
No,
nothing risky.
Uh,
keep your brace on.
When you trained at a six month mark,
they're like,
take the brace off.
You've got to start getting the
stabilizers strong.
You can start testing it more.
You can start doing things,
but you still got to wear a brace when
you do live scenarios.
But you can drill without it.
You can,
you see what I'm saying?
So you're actually pretty strong,
but now it's supposed to be strong
enough that it's not going to tear.
But that's when I had a cadaver acl,
so it wasn't as strong as it should have
been at that,
at that six month point,
because it was cadaver tissue.
My Body did not adapt to the tissue as
well as it could have.
So they,
do they do an Mri to see where it's at
or do they just kind of base it on how
it feels?
They base it on the endpoint and the
stability of your knee and then
manipulate it when they manipulate it at
the six month mark,
you're going in every two to three weeks
for six months to double check with the
dogs.
I've had to have a two week while I was
doing that at Kerlan and jobe and they
were good doctors and they tried to stay
on me,
you know?
Um,
so you've had two.
So you know,
and you know,
at the six month mark it's like you can
push it but you don't want to overkill
it,
tear it.
Right.
So the second one,
I wasn't over killing it,
but I was doing what I was allowed in my
brace and I made a,
I made a cut,
like a turn and it just popped it just
like,
it wasn't anything like,
oh I shouldn't have been doing that.
It was Kinda like,
you know,
I was boxing in my brace.
I had it taped,
I warmed up,
I surprised I was uh,
doing drills,
boxing drills,
drills,
yeah,
boxing drills,
but you just pivot wrong then and it
just pops and then,
you know,
like I remember sitting there and I'd
just,
the pain's very specific and then it
goes away too quick.
That's when,
you know,
because it's their real,
real,
real hard pain.
And then it goes away in like two
minutes because the ligaments that now
you don't have pain anymore.
And I'm like,
oh no.
So I sit down and I go,
all right,
my name is torn.
And that was when I hit like a real bad
rock bottom on that one.
That was like that one,
like,
oh my gosh,
when I went to the MRI and got home,
I literally like called my friend and I
told him to come over and I just,
I mean I pretty much just drink as much
of a bottle as I could because I was in
pretty good shape at that point.
So it put me out.
I passed out my head was,
I woke up in my porch with my head on
the grill in the morning,
just a mess.
It was not pretty,
but I didn't even care because I was out
for nine months,
you know,
so everybody hits these lows,
what were you doing financially back
then?
Because that's where it gets rough.
Right.
That's another part of it.
I mean,
US athletes,
we all know or you know,
uh,
we,
we only make money when we,
when we fight for the prize,
you know.
And um,
thank God,
you know,
Lorenzo and in the UFC they gave me a
decent chunk of money for a good part of
time.
While I had the belt and then once they
took the belt,
I stopped getting that chunk of money
even when I was hurt.
So they were paying me a little bit a
stipend while I was hurt and that helped
me.
And then when I left,
when they stripped the belt and gave it
to broad,
they stopped with that because I'm not
the champion anymore.
And then it was kinda like,
that's what,
that's what I mean,
that's when it Kinda went,
got turned reality.
Like you're not the champ on paper
anymore.
He didn't really lose it.
But that's it.
So what are you going to do?
What is this it,
you know,
how you're going to make money,
how are you going to do this?
How are you going to do that?
And I panicked.
Um,
but I knew that I was gonna still come
back and fight because I was still young
and I hadn't given up on fighting yet.
Still only in my second acl surgery.
So I'm still not fully admitting that
I'm not,
that I'm a mess,
right.
I,
I'm kind of not really like admitting it
to myself yet.
And it's,
screw what you're saying,
everybody else's,
what I'm trying to say,
it's what you believe to yourself is all
that matters,
right.
Period.
And I was like,
I'll be fine.
This isn't that bad.
I can do this.
Gone through worse.
So in doing it,
I still hadn't really just given up yet.
And that's.
So I'm still,
I'm still competing in my mind,
which is the problem.
And uh,
that's when you just,
you're overworking and not just doing
things you're not supposed to on your
knee.
But just in general in life on just
overworking.
I'm doing my Fox stuff now to make money
and then I'm trying to do my rehab,
uh,
five days a week because I have to come
back and fight for the belt when I come
back.
And that's another thing people don't
equate as I was the champs.
I got to come back and fight for the
belt.
When I come back after this injury,
I don't just get to come back and fight
somebody three rounds.
I got to come back and fight five
rounds.
Never been done before.
I had nobody to bounce this thought off
of,
um,
I just had to wing it man.
And so I was,
and that caused,
I think,
a lot of problems with me because I
didn't have the mental capacity to deal
with it at that point with all the
things that I was doing.
So I just kept grinding and then I
finally get back to health after the
second acl,
six months,
nine months goes by.
All right,
let's take this brow fight.
So I'm ready.
I'm training in camp.
About a month in m I t I have like a
weird pinch in my groin.
It turns out to be the exact same
injury.
Daniel cormier just pulled out of the
fight for it's the extensor tendon in
your or?
No,
it's the um,
uh,
I forget the name of the.
There's a tendon in your groin area that
pulls and then you got to just rest it.
I tore the mine was a little bit worse.
I tore the muscle,
the quad muscle off the bone,
so it's like separated from the bone,
but it wasn't all the way.
It was just enough that it was,
I could still like think I was okay,
but it would fail on me occasionally so
I could tape it some days and it would
be all right.
Shoot a bunch of Toradol,
which is a,
for anybody who's curious.
It's a natural.
It's,
um,
legal,
anti-inflammatory.
A lot of football players take it.
Um,
Toridol Toridol it's A.
Yeah,
I think that's,
yeah,
I think that's what it's called,
but anyways,
it's,
it's a natural urge to anti-inflammatory
now.
Natural one,
but it's like Ibuprofen but stronger and
I would take that and that helped.
Um,
but it just,
it wasn't right.
I remember I was sparring one day and I
went to throw a right hand and my leg
just gave out and I fell on the floor
and I wasn't kicking,
I wasn't shooting.
I just threw a right hand and the
feeling of falling because I threw right
hand,
made me know,
like something wasn't connected.
Like it just didn't feel right because
they just failed me.
It wasn't,
it wasn't like it hurt and I stopped it
just literally there was no pain and it
just failed.
And I was like,
something's way mechanically wrong with
me.
I can't fight mechanically wrong like
this.
And that was about four weeks out of the
fight,
three,
four weeks out of the fight.
I had already done a month camp with
this injury,
trying to tough it out.
So my camp was rough.
It was a heart camp and I didn't want to
pull out,
obviously naturally.
So I ended up calling Dana and in this
one of the few phone calls I've ever had
with Dana.
Unfortunately in this,
probably one of the times you remember
telling them,
I'm sorry I got to pull out.
But I remember not wanting to have my
manager column this.
This goes back to what my mom,
how my mom put something in my head
where you deal with this face to face or
talking.
Psychologist said,
look,
I don't want to do this,
but I got to pull out of this fight.
I need some doc.
I need.
If you've got any doctors,
you can have an Mri,
me whatever you want,
but I'm telling you something's wrong
with my leg.
So he's like,
okay,
I'll do it.
I got,
I got guys on it.
We can have pulled out now.
I'm sure you're fine.
Check it out.
Get the doctors,
check it.
Yeah.
Your,
your quads torn.
You can't fight.
So the UFC pulls me,
you know,
Dane is naturally pissed,
but then that slide's a favor in their
favor,
gets the shot with,
with brow ends up getting knocked out in
that match up.
But um,
I pull out of that fight and that's when
they stripped my belt.
And then that was the beginning of me
giving up on fighting to an extent.
And what I mean by that is it's
different than you think.
It sounds negative,
right?
When you say that I'm giving up on
fighting,
but it was actually the building point
in my life where I finally let go of
control.
I always had this thing up to that point
where I wanted to control everything.
It's just something that I,
I always had the gift of being able to
do this last one after the two acl
reconstructive surgeries coming back and
then tearing my quad after that.
I said like,
I don't know what else you want me to
do.
I've gotten through two acl
reconstructions.
Uh,
my higher power is God.
So I'm praying at this point saying,
I don't know what you want me to do.
So you're talking to God.
So yeah,
like what are we going to do?
What do I gotta do?
Man,
I'm,
do you want,
I'm in this for,
for reasons bigger than myself.
I want to come back and show people that
this can be done.
I'm not the only one that can do this.
Anybody can do this,
right?
I'm here for you doing bidding your
will.
God,
this is my talking and no answers,
no nothing.
And I said,
maybe that's the answer.
I remember thinking,
maybe that's the answer is just you
might not ever fight again.
Are you okay with that?
And now something that I never allowed
my brain to even go to ever until all
these injuries hit me and I would've
never been able to unless I went through
all that.
That was literally all this stuff
because I'm so stubborn and so just
tough that I had to go through all that
just to mentally say,
okay,
you might never do this again.
It could have been after the first one.
I could've done that,
but I didn't.
When I did that,
my health skyrocketed.
Immediately.
I started.
I just went to therapy everyday knowing
I was trying to get better,
but I didn't care if I fought again or
not.
I focused all my energy and Fox and
coaching the guys at Alliance Training
Center to make them better and uh,
try to make the team better so that when
and,
and feed off the thirst and the hunger
that those guys had to be the champion
that I still wanted to be.
And I and I,
I decided that if I focused on Fox,
focused on the positive energy of these
guys at the gym,
kept training.
I kept my mind in the sport.
I'm,
my body will be there because my age is
compliant with my body still.
I'm still young enough that I'll be
okay.
So I just needed to get my mind wrapped
around the sport,
stay in it mentally,
but understand that if I never have it
again,
that's okay too.
And when I did that,
it took away so much importance off of
needing to fight as have the title as
my,
as the person that I was,
that it allowed me to open up and say,
if you never fight again,
you're still a great person.
You still did great things.
You still a laid the tracks for the
Bantam Weight Division and a lot of
ways,
um,
you did this,
that you had a great career dome.
Like it's okay if this is it.
And I kept that mindset kept focusing on
the things that I could control instead
of the things that I couldn't,
like,
the fact that I wasn't competing yet.
And as I did that I got healthier and
healthier.
Came back,
Ms Dot Docu that set me up to fight Ms
Dot Jackie then destroyed ms dot Dr. One
of your best performances over first
round destruction.
That was the most at peace of felt in a
long time walking in.
I remember interviewing you after the
fight and you were like,
I don't even remember what happened.
She just went like,
you went into a trance.
It was weird.
It was one of the weirdest performances
in my whole career,
easily because the lockout was
different.
Just I was so excited.
I had no,
no connection.
I was.
I had no connection to the win or the
loss.
At that point.
There was nothing.
It was just I was just there to enjoy
being there again.
After three and a half years and all
these injuries like I can't believe I
made it here.
I'm not injured,
and I remember thinking like,
just you're in front of these people.
Enjoy the man.
Enjoy this ride.
Like this is incredible.
There's people that would pay millions
and trillions of dollars to get this
walk you're about to get and go fight
somebody this octagon.
Just enjoy it.
Don't worry,
don't connect and by letting go,
man,
by letting go of the injuries,
by letting go of the wind,
by letting go of the loss,
by letting go of either mattered.
I was in the.
I was in my zone and it allowed me to
just be free and I was.
That was the best performance in my
career,
but more than anything,
it showed me a mental thing that I'd
never opened up before and it was
letting go of the things that you can't
control will give you actually more
peace because it disconnects you from
what happens,
so you feel like that piece was a
significant factor in your body
recovering because the pressure and the
stress and the anxiety,
all that was playing.
It was wrecking not just your mental
state but also your physical state.
One hundred percent every piece of it.
That's really interesting.
Every piece of it,
and that's the biggest thing I learned
is that is like it wasn't my physical
body.
It was my mind doing it to my physical
So it was initially a physical injury
and then it was the cascade of
psychological issues that came with the
physical issue,
some more physical issues.
It was the cascade of trying to figure
out why I was so sad with all these
things that I earned around me that I
already had.
Everything that I thought,
like when you grow up in a trailer like
I did,
and then you go to winning a Gtr,
that car you wanted since you were a kid
in a prize fight and having a home that
you bought with your own money that you
never thought you'd be able to own a
home in California because you live in a
damn trailer park in Tucson,
Arizona.
It kinda like,
um,
makes you feel like,
like that's it,
you know,
like you,
you,
you've done crazy great things and
you've um,
I,
those were all dreams to me and they
happened so quick,
like at 20,
you know,
I mean,
I didn't get my house to later,
but when I got those things it's like,
why are you.
So I was still sad is my point.
Like I was still,
I had my depression that was hitting me.
And,
and that's so many people in this world
are dealing with depression.
Like it's a huge catastrophic problem
across the planet.
And um,
I definitely,
it's in my,
it's in my blood line,
on both sides of my family and it's
something that everybody,
not just myself deals with on a daily
basis,
I think in certain people's lives.
And that hit me very hard and I didn't
understand why it hit me so much harder
now after I stopped competing.
Like why am I,
why is,
why is it so much worse now?
While the reason is my body was used to
the active,
the activity just go,
go,
go.
And I,
what I realized is I turned off all my
emotional,
spiritual and mental issues with
exercise to where I never ever,
ever dealt with them ever.
I only physically worked them out.
So my physical was perfection.
I was a,
I'm a world champion,
monster,
killer,
whatever you want to call me in your own
respective mind,
right?
But emotionally,
physically and spiritually.
I was at cricket and I'd never
understood that until I was hurt,
trapped in my own body.
Like a prison cell,
couldn't train,
couldn't run,
couldn't walk,
couldn't bend my leg,
laying on the couch,
eating pain pills,
realizing,
man,
unless you train,
unless you compete,
you hate yourself,
you're,
you're a piece of shit in your own mind
without those things,
without the beautiful girlfriend,
without the beautiful house,
without the Nice cars,
without them big money to show people
you hate yourself.
So what am I really doing?
Why am I doing this?
I lost sight that the whole reason we're
fighting is,
is it's a spiritual,
emotional,
physical,
mental battle that helps you grow as an
individual and as a human being.
It's not just to have these things that
you think will make you happy.
You have to learn those things through
the process.
And I didn't know that until I was
trapped in my own body and I literally
felt like I was in a prison cell and I
knew that wasn't right.
We shouldn't be in our own body alone
without people around us to keep us
company and a on a couch feeling like
we're in a prison cell,
should we?
No,
definitely not.
we shouldn't,
but I did for three years.
So how did you get yourself out of it by
just accepting it and you must.
There must've been some sort of a
mechanism that caused.
I have people that I talked to,
professionals,
um,
obviously like sports psychologists or
sports psychologist,
and then you got to get a psychologist
in general to deal with the depression,
whatever.
When you hit your lows,
like it's okay to,
to get,
you know,
if you're bench pressing 350 pounds,
it's okay to have a little touch.
It's okay to have a little spot here and
there,
you know,
and then after you get a couple of
spots,
now after awhile you can do it yourself.
You don't need the spot anymore.
That's how I look at psychiatric help to
an extent.
For some people,
especially if they're battling
depression.
Sometimes you just need a floaty and you
did and then you can take the floaties
off after a year.
See what I'm saying?
It's a mental,
it's a mental floaty and it's okay
because we all hit low part low points
in our life where it's unbearable.
And you either allow it to continue to
be unbearable and just deny it,
or you deal with the task at hand and
say,
I'm a little low right now.
I need the floaties.
It's okay,
I'll get through this.
And then when you take the is off,
you realize I only needed them for a
little bit of time and now I'm okay.
I'm here.
And that's Kinda what it felt like.
It's like I just needed a little bit of
a push.
I needed to get through this and learn
some things about my own,
my own mind and understand my own
emotions and understand that I didn't
need all these things that I was
thinking where it real.
It was me not being in control of my own
emotions,
your own emotions or your choice.
And I chose to feel trapped.
I chose to be sad.
I chose to feel like I was Jack Shit.
I chose all these things and it's like
you don't need fighting to be these
things.
You need to.
You need to let go of fighting to learn
that you are something without it.
And that was actually a gift.
It became a gift because I learned so
much in life now bigger than fighting.
I look at the things that I went through
as a gift because I have gotten the gift
of feeling retired during my career.
Who else gets that?
Some people retire for five years,
lose their freaking mind,
end up in the bar and come back and try
to fight again.
Ten years later with a weakened body,
a mess or abuse.
Why?
Though?
Why are they doing that?
They're not doing it because they're
physically capable.
They're doing it because they never
dealt with their life away from
fighting.
Fighting was there like fighting is who
they are.
Fighting is their persona.
So takeaway fighting.
What are they?
They're in the bar drinking away with.
They're not.
Instead of drinking,
putting the booze down and knowing what
you are without fighting,
being happy with that chapter of your
life and being able to live who you are.
I've gotten to feel that and now I can
fight with a peace of mind knowing how
good I am without fighting and how great
I am with it too.
And um,
that's,
that's what this thing's about.
All these fights,
all these me attacking those challenges
coming back and winning and getting my
belt back.
Um,
that could only happen because I let go
of control of the things I couldn't
control.
So you come back,
you fight,
Mitsui,
rocky,
you put on the performance of your
career,
just destroyed him.
It was just a whirlwind,
wild,
crazy first round stoppage.
Then what happens?
Well,
that was,
that was a big deal for me because he'd
never been stopped like that before.
Ms Dot Jackie at this point,
at this point,
he was on a five fight win streak.
He hadn't lost since the whole time I
had been hurt and he was,
he was beating the top guys.
So to beat him was going to tell me
you're good enough,
let's go for the title.
And I beat him.
And I said,
okay,
here I am.
Let's go for that title.
And at this point,
if you remember,
it was Barao was the next coming to
Christ.
And then Tj beat the brakes off of them.
And now Tj is the next company,
crises,
a better version of me.
He's this,
he's that.
And so I said,
yeah,
I can be him.
I knew I could.
I'd been watching him on,
on film and for Fox and breaking down
his fights and I knew I could beat
Barao.
I knew both those guys couldn't beat me
at that point,
but it didn't matter what I thought I
had to prove it and nobody's going to
believe you after for injuries the way I
had them.
So I just had to go do it.
I blew my knee out training one month
after I fought to Chi Mizzou.
Gawky.
Now this is what's interesting about the
story is I did research later.
I'm now basically a doctor to figure all
this stuff because all the injuries I've
been through,
but three weeks before I fought ms dot,
I had a staph infection in my right
thumb that popped up.
So I took a um,
antibiotic called Cipro as I think it's
with the CIP pro.
Now me trusting the doctors and me not,
it's my own fault.
Not the doctor's fault.
I should have read what was the hazards
of the antibiotic,
but you,
you kind of trust the doctors and assume
why would he give me something bad?
Right.
Well,
Cipro has an after effect for six months
after you ingest it that it weakens your
attendance so it makes them soft,
like real puddy.
And so I took it three weeks before the
fight.
That made it.
About two months after I ingested the,
the Cipro,
I was throwing a left high kick.
I'd never had a problem with my right
knee,
my entire life ever,
and it just popped,
throwing a right high kick.
I pivot on my right leg to throw the
left,
went up high and it just popped and I
knew right away obviously because I've
done two,
done it twice,
that I blew it out and I remember
literally blowing it out,
sitting on the floor of the guy that I
was driven with his like,
what's up?
And I was like,
ah,
my knee.
I just blew my knee out.
And he's like,
what?
You just,
you?
Nothing happened.
Like it was crazy.
It was crazy.
It was.
It was a weird feeling and what was even
weirder was the piece I had sitting
there,
not even carry.
I literally was just.
I remember blowing it out and sitting on
the ring.
Like I told her,
I said,
Eric,
come here,
and I told him to come over and I was
like,
you ready for another nine months?
ACL reconstructive surgery.
And he's like,
what?
He's like,
what are you talking about?
Your needs fine,
you need.
I'm like,
no,
it's blew.
I blew it out right now.
He's like,
no,
you didn't.
I said,
yes,
I did.
And that was it.
And so I start again.
Start again.
So I started the Rehab,
same style of a reconstruction this
times better because I had the first two
practice tries and now I had the secret
link.
What's the secret link that I didn't
know for the first three injuries that I
had was letting go of control.
This was the,
this was my diamond,
this was to now I had a way to prove
that I was onto something in my own mind
and I did it and I was onto something
and I know it now and nobody can ever
tell me anything different.
It was.
It was just.
I stopped right then and there.
The day I blew my knee out.
I didn't train again for nine months
other than physical therapy.
I didn't.
I didn't shadow box,
I didn't do a pushup.
I didn't do a setup.
I didn't do a squat.
I didn't.
I went in the gym occasionally,
but because I had learned to let go of
fighting from the first two injuries,
I didn't go in there panicking,
trying to keep training because I needed
it for my health anymore.
I already learned that,
that the way I find health is to not
train.
Let my body completely healed,
don't do anything and focus on my mind.
So I spent another nine months focusing
on nothing but my mind and my tactic
was,
your body's not working right now,
so you've got to switch it over to the
next weapon.
That you have,
which is your mind,
your will,
your mind is the only other weapon you
use besides your body on fight night.
So if your body's not working,
switch it over.
So I just focused on my mind and by
focusing on my mind,
I'm talking.
I started looking up guys like Wayne
Dyer.
Um,
I started talking to a guy named Mike
Michael Jordan,
Michael t larden,
Dr Mark Michael,
t dot larden.
I started putting in place specific,
uh,
go to people for my,
for my,
uh,
to talk to that.
I looked up to a power people,
I guess you'd put them right.
I'm sure you have some too.
And I focused on nothing but my mind,
I didn't train at all.
And um,
I remember I got a call.
I was out at the lake in Arizona.
I literally hit the nine month mark on
this weekend.
I get a call from shelby to nine month
mark.
They knew my knee was going to be old
and he goes,
you're healthy,
right?
And I was like,
well,
I've done nothing but rehab it.
It's been nine months.
So technically I'm cleared by the
doctor,
they know I'm cleared by the doctor
because the UFC talks with the doctors
24 slash seven,
whether they admit it or not.
So it's like even if the doctor
shouldn't tell the UFC there telling
them everything so they know exactly
where I'm at in Rehab exactly where I'm
at in therapy to the tee and that's why
they know when to call me and put the
heat on me.
So I'm out on the boat drinking some
beers,
trying to enjoy my life and I get a call
we can get you.
We want to give you a title fight with
Tj dillashaw in the beginning of the
year,
whatever.
At that point I had 12 weeks when they
called me to get ready for the fight.
So three months but zero training for
nine months.
Correct.
Wow.
After the misery gawky fight,
that's,
that's insane.
Just to be able to get yourself into
five round performance.
Correct?
Correct.
And this is,
I mean,
you're hearing a story right now and I
haven't told anybody because I don't sit
down and talk for two hours to anybody
about this stuff,
so it's like,
who would I,
who am I going to go on an interview
with and talk about this stuff?
Pretty much you're the only guy who gets
into this weird stuff.
So here we are and all it comes down to
that like,
yeah,
I was on zero.
And I said again,
because of what I learned with the MS
dot docket thing,
letting go.
I just kept exercising that because
what's gonna happen is gonna happen.
It's out of my control.
God's God has planned for me.
He took me this far in my mind.
That's my higher power.
And remember,
if you're listening and your higher
power is not God,
it can be whatever you want it to be for
your higher power,
like that matter of just letting a
matter of just letting go and
understanding that there's,
there's something in effect that's
bigger than you hear in the universe and
as soon as you can do that,
you're going to be who you're going to
be.
And then when you,
when you are who you are because you're
not worried about all these other things
connected to it,
you get your,
your fullest self.
And in being that,
it allowed me to get ready for Tj
because I wasn't thinking about.
He's been fighting.
You haven't,
he's been this,
you haven't that I'm,
none of that mattered.
It wasn't relevant because I was
fighting him no matter what.
So I just let go and said getting a tip
top shape you can with the tools you
have and let's go fight him.
You know,
you have the skillset,
you know,
you have the knowledge and the movement
and you're young enough and your body's
working.
You just proved that with ms dot
[inaudible].
So you just got to get in shape and
you're fine.
And that was literally my mindset.
Well,
uh,
at that eight week mark,
so it saw at 12 weeks I start training.
So that's 12 weeks out,
12 weeks out I start,
I stopped just physical therapy,
which I was doing three times a week
only and I go to flight training.
I start my,
my,
just my regimen,
what I do for each camp in doing that,
going from off the couch,
doing nothing straight into a five round
title fight.
Um,
I learned that actually sparked what I
had now have,
which is plantar Fascia tendonitis in
my,
both my feet.
And so it's because going from resting
for a year,
whatever,
three years,
and then going full bore on your feet,
it tore all the Fascia on the bottom of
my feet because they weren't ready for
the brunt of forest that I was putting
on him when my footwork and my movement
and my sparring and my kickboxing and
all that,
it wasn't ready.
So I tore all the Fascia on the bottom
of my feet.
So I started feeling something weird on
the bottom of my left foot in that camp
simultaneously at the,
at the eight week mark,
after I had been training for 12,
what?
Four weeks I've been training for the TJ
dillashaw camp.
I broke my rib so I get kicked in my
rib.
My Body's just soft.
I hadn't been getting kicked or punched
in over for three and a half years now
because if you think about it,
ms dot occupied doesn't even count so
fast and he didn't even hit you.
He didn't hit me.
He hit me one time and it was just under
a minute long fight.
And so the only wear and tear and and
Callus for lack of a better term I have
on my body is from the training camp
before Ms With Aki,
which was only a three round camp.
So I have no wear and tear on my body,
no toughness.
He kicked my rib,
breaks my rib,
I lose right then and there.
I can't wrestle anymore and I can't
speak anymore.
So now I'm at eight weeks out of the
flight and they take away my sparring
and they take away my wrestling because
I can't go live.
So I'm just drilling kickboxing now.
Pad work with coach Eric dolphy around
Miguel Ras and grappling a drills.
So you taping up your rib now?
I get this big a thing that goes over
the top.
It's like this weird protector and I
wear that.
Is it a protector against impact or
protect our.
Does it actually like a cast that holds
your ribs in place or.
No,
it was like I had to look it up online
myself or some makeshift thing that
would work in this thing.
Work the best.
I forget what it's called.
I can text it to you and figure it out.
But it's like a picture,
like what you were,
what the,
what the coaches were when they were
that body plane.
He can punch in the body and it goes all
the way up to here.
Do you know what I'm talking about?
It's like one of those but it's a little
smaller and it just goes here.
And then you,
uh,
you put it on like a shirt and it
crosses and the cables,
crocs crossing the back and then the
whole front is kind like,
squishy,
but protecting you from squeezing and
blunt force.
But I wasn't taking any anyways.
I was just wearing that for when I would
drill.
I wasn't gone live yet.
So then I finally start panicking when I
can't,
I can't spar or wrestle alive after four
weeks with a busted rib,
I was like,
oh,
it'll go away.
It just wasn't going away.
It was just killing me.
I couldn't even breathe,
man.
I couldn't sneeze.
I couldn't cough.
It was horrible.
So I just said I got to shoot a
cortisone and see if that helps.
So I go in,
see the doctor,
they shoot a cortisone.
Thank God it worked and numbed it within
three days a moving again,
I'm good.
So the reason I didn't shoot it right
away is because you want to give it as
much time as you can to heal before you
shoot it,
to see if you can minimize the damage
that you do with the cortisone.
So that makes sense.
That's why I didn't do it right on.
Does damage it.
It breaks down tissue like muscle and
tendon tissue.
If you overdo it,
you can do within three and one injected
area,
but you don't want to do more than three
in one area depending on where you're
at.
Okay.
This is my first one in this particular
rib.
I mean I've had them all over my body,
but this,
in this rip,
when that kicks in,
I'm like,
sweet.
I can spar and I can wrestle now.
I just got to wear that thing.
So the whole camp,
I'm wearing this thing and uh,
I can't do any core workout.
I can't do any strength and conditioning
at all because we had to ditch those two
things in order to focus on cardio and
skill because we had to get my cardio
and skill back in my timing and my reads
back more than I needed strength and
conditioning.
So because I'm coming back from so much,
you actually have to just cut out what's
not needed in the cans that you've had
in the past and take what you can use.
So what are you doing for cardios own
makeshift?
I have a sprint routine that I run that
solely mine that I got from a guy named
drew fickett way back in the day.
I know drew.
Oh yeah,
you did.
As my first MMA coach.
Dude,
he's a nasty,
crazy,
dirty,
filthy son of a gun.
I'll just leave it at that Heaven Don
Frye.
I started out with two of them,
first MMA coach,
just to give you an idea of when I
started and they weren't even my coaches
because if you know them,
they don't coach anybody.
They just yell at you slurs and then
maybe put you to sleep a couple of times
and Don Frye throws head kicks when
you're only supposed to be boxing.
So it's like they're not real coaches,
they're just showing you how to be a
maniac.
But anyways,
he shows me this sprint routine,
which I still use to this day.
So true.
Fake.
It's the man.
I'm so and but you're still dealing with
plantar fasciitis now.
Well then it starts kicking in because
of the sprinting,
sprinting,
footwork,
everything else coming from nothing.
But it's only in my left foot,
so I think I kicked an elbow.
I Dunno a habit yet,
so I don't go get an Mri.
I don't check anything.
I just ignore it because I'm fighting
either way.
I don't want to know.
Sometimes it's just better not knowing,
you know,
especially if you're gonna fight,
whether it's hard or not.
So I just said screw it.
I didn't shoot it up with cortisone or
nothing.
I just ignored it.
Kept running super painful.
If you've ever had it.
Plantar Fasciitis,
it's debilitating to an extent.
But um,
you know,
thank God it was only in one foot and
then I go into that fight with about.
I had about a good solid four week camp
of sparring in wrestling thing,
god of live stuff.
But other than that,
the first 12 weeks was basically just
getting into shape.
So my whole camp was comprised of mostly
sprints,
pad work in about a month of sparring.
And I lost almost all rounds coming back
because I was just so off from the year
and the not doing anything in my body,
not being strong and trying to get back
in shape.
And it was tough.
It was by far that camp was the worst
put together.
Most off in horrible camp.
I've had in my whole 24 fights by far.
You won the title and I.
Yeah,
some thing.
The good Lord above.
I won that title that that's how I,
that's,
that's it didn't really make sense.
But it happened and we didn't know that
you had plantar fasciitis.
So when you kept getting hit by leg
kicks and your leg was giving out,
I was thinking that your leg was giving
out from the impact.
And I,
and I don't take,
you know,
it's hard as a.
especially I do it with you color now.
It's hard,
man.
This thing's hard.
Somebody's going to get mad no matter
what you do,
no matter what you say eventually.
And it's like,
how are you supposed to know?
My Foot's blown out before I get in
there.
Well,
now I saw you in the,
uh,
uriah faber fight,
which happened after that,
and then I noticed your foot was taped
up.
Both.
Yes,
it went into the other foot as well.
And then the cody fight it multiplied by
two in both feet.
So instead of just having it in one for
Tj,
I get through.
Then I have it in both.
It just started my other foot for favor.
And then by the,
by the,
by the cody fight,
it was just,
it's been out of control.
I had done a three camps and I had done
a year,
a year of nonstop work after that,
after that year off.
And what can you.
No excuses.
I want to go ahead and make this this
point right now.
There's no excuses for that.
Um,
I did pretty good at wrapping it.
I shot botox in the bottom of both of my
feet.
Botox,
it was the worst thing I've ever gone
through.
Why does Botox,
what does that do for the,
the idea with botox as it was a,
it was an off the wall method because
there's no cure for plantar fascia
tendons.
You just improvise this?
Yes,
because I was,
well,
I heard it from other doctors.
It's an underground method.
It's like I was just willing to do
anything.
Joe,
like I was in so much pain,
dude.
I couldn't.
I'd wake up in the morning and I'd have
to go on my hands and knees to the
bathtub so I wouldn't put weight on my
feet.
I'm not kidding.
So I wouldn't put up during fight camp.
Oh yeah.
So I wouldn't put weight on my feet
because they're are too cold,
so it's like needles,
you know,
so you have to warm them up first.
So.
So that the fasciitis doesn't get worse.
So I fill up a tub with hot water and
Epson salt and then I,
I filled that out.
I had to fill that out by going on my
hands and knees because you don't want
to put weight on it early.
This is a method I heard from a runner
that he used in order to heal his.
And so I tried it for about a month.
I was going,
I would fill it up and then I soak my
feet every morning.
Then after I sold them,
I have a tape routine that I have on
both my feet at tape,
both my feet,
like you would picture taping your hands
and then I wear my shoes and I warm up
my feet before I get there at the gym
and then I'd go,
um,
but that was for all three of the fights
this last year I've had to deal with
that and I actually did a really good
job minimizing the pain and the botox
first I shot cortisone in them and that
didn't help and numbed it a little bit,
but it didn't help.
I shot it after when I fought Tj and I
was getting kicked in the leg,
like you say,
and I was,
that was my foot being toward like the
Fascia actually completely tore off the
heel in that fight.
That hurt that I felt.
I've never felt anything really in a
fight that I felt when it popped.
And that's how I knew I was,
like I said,
I was like,
I think my foot's tour and a half or
something because it just,
I felt it when it,
when it popped open in that fifth round
and I had about four minutes left
around,
I remember like,
Oh shit,
you better,
you better figure something out.
And then,
you know,
you could tell I was staying a little
bit more stationary I think.
And that's why the kickstart to land.
But um,
so it goes,
man,
we're in the fight business.
All of us go in there with injuries.
I'm not making excuses,
but people want to know,
you know,
injuries.
We all go in there in jail.
I'm not like almost all of us to
something.
And a lot of high level like marathon
runners deal with this foot problem that
I have and they run marathons with this
so it can be done.
But it's just an extra hindrance.
It's very difficult.
And going barefoot with it is,
is the hardest part.
That's true,
right?
Because at least marathon runners,
some wear shoe.
And that helps because I have orthotics
in there.
Supports you can put that,
keep the support,
but I have a high arch and so what that
means is the arch,
there's a Fascia that hold everything in
place and the art starts to fail and
that's what that needle feelings.
It's like it's the Fascia on the bottom
of your foot because I'm always on my
toes.
It just,
it wasn't ready for the brunt from zero
to hero run and it kind of put a bunch
of lesions in it.
And now how do you heal those?
Now?
Can you tape it with an orthotic
underneath?
No,
because I mean then you have orthotics
tucked to the bottom of your feet.
You're hopping around.
You basically just training.
Can I just take my.
Well,
I wear my wrestling shoes and I taped my
feet,
taped my feet and were wrestling shoes
with my,
uh,
supports in there.
And what,
what methods of healing
can they sort of use?
There isn't any.
Now this is why I use both stem cells.
Uh,
I was actually thinking of getting some
stem cells put in my elbows,
my shoulders and my knees coming up.
But for my feet,
prp and stem cell is all just,
it's all just.
Sometimes it works,
sometimes it doesn't.
Anything you look at,
if you google plan to.
They have no cure for it.
It's,
it's a,
it's a worldwide problem that there's no
cure for it.
And where are you going to get the stem
cell stuff done?
Um,
well I've only talked to people about
it,
but I'd be more than happy to care with
you on.
I'm sure he has some hookups because I
need the best in the world out.
There's a guy in Vegas,
Dr Rodney Mcgee.
He's heard of a.
he's worked with a lot.
Daniel.
He's worked with people before Cormier,
Cormier,
this guy does he.
Well,
there's a bunch of different ways to do
it.
[inaudible] guy went into his hip and
they pulled a bone marrow out of his hip
and they,
it's super painful and then they get
your own stem cells from that.
The way the guy in Vegas does it,
they're taking the stem cells.
When a woman has a Cesarean section,
when she gives birth through Sicilian
section,
they take away the placenta.
They usually would just throw it out,
but they can take that placenta and
extract stem cells from it.
I'd rather have that than some of the
dcs,
but you don't want them digging in your
going.
It's super painful on your hip too.
Yeah,
he was talking about how he was limping
for a couple of weeks.
He's big boned though.
Yeah,
he's a big fellow,
but he sees this.
He's.
You know,
it's interesting.
Like somebody said to me once a day,
she should be fight in middleweight and
go stand next to them and say that his.
He's like this.
Yeah,
he's a tank.
He's a big dude.
Yeah.
He might only be five,
10 Chubby,
but he's stronger than anybody can
imagine.
You don't pick up Dan Henderson.
How about Josh Barnett?
Remember when he was fighting a
heavyweight and strikeforce.
He picked up Josh Barnett like it was a
pillow and slammed them on the ground.
I mean like the guy like blows my mind
how good he is.
Phenomenal wrestling enough credit.
I know DC on a training level.
When I watch him train on a personal
level,
I mean,
he's crazy.
He's always talking out of his butt,
you know,
to an extent.
It's hilarious.
But uh,
he's a beast man.
He's got to respect that.
Yeah,
I'd love that guy.
He's a,
he's a great guy.
He's just,
he's in the era of John Jones,
you know,
and he lost to John and his first fight
and he was also dealing with the fact
that John,
although I love John to John's a fuck
up,
you know,
and so he's got to sort of be there
while John keeps fucking up and then a
lot of it comes back to him,
but that's where I look at DC and why I
try to give them all the respect in the
world I can because I don't feel that
people give enough respect to dc for the
fact that he's not fucking know he's a
great outcome.
You.
Right.
How does that get overlooked?
Well,
I think a lot of it has to do with
people can connect fuckups yeah,
too.
There's this,
you know what I mean?
And,
and John Jones is that good?
That's the other thing is literally that
good.
He's that good.
He can beat you after you did coke three
weeks ago.
I don't know what to say,
but the thing about John,
I'm good enough to win after three
surgeries,
so let's see what we can.
We can test the waters on Bob.
Let's see who does what.
I'll do a line of coke next time and to
try to jump in there and see how I do
it.
Let's blow his knees out three times and
they will see his better.
Well,
that's a different animal.
You know?
I mean it's,
it's interesting that sometimes people
are just supreme.
We talented physically and they don't
have to deal with as many trials and
tribulations in that regard.
You know,
he's very gifted like John.
It's,
it's interesting.
I've always said this there,
there's a way that John gets a hold of
people that you know,
you could almost tell when he gets a
hold of them that they've really have
never felt anything like that before.
And you saw it with DC.
You know dc who's a supreme really
talented wrestler.
I mean one of the best wrestlers to ever
compete in MMA.
Jon Jones got ahold of them and you
could see dc was like,
oh shit,
like this guy is no joke.
I agree.
I mean John's stud.
Yeah,
he's that good.
He's not good.
Is that good?
But so was DC.
The DC could still beat him.
I really believe that it's entirely
possible.
There was still a very close fight.
I would probably,
if I had to choose on paper,
you take Jones depending on how healthy
he is.
Well DC was so furious that he didn't
fight it in the oven.
St [inaudible] fight because he was
like,
I would've beat that Jon Jones because I
did commentary with them.
Fine.
I would've beat that Jon Jones and,
and,
and here's another thing on that.
Okay,
because how's that?
That might not be true either because
that Jon Jones would have trained
differently for you than he who knows?
And he was a very late replacement.
Don't forget this though.
I mean how much does he hate dc?
He's not going to.
Oh yeah.
That was a different level of training
you're doing for different people and
where your emotions are with that human
being.
That's a really good point.
It is.
And don't you think that was a big
factor in the first fight as well?
Because DC was very emotionally wrapped
up and finding John.
It was very intense because he had never
had anybody disrespect him like that.
They had that fistfight at the press had
to do with it.
Sure.
Of course.
That has to do with every fight has to
do with my flight.
It has to do with all of them.
You have to calculate it.
I had to do it.
Conor mcgregor,
Rousey's fight.
Anderson Silva's fights when he's
showboating everything.
I mean you can go.
The list goes on to the mental problems
that a lot of these athletes have hadn't
usually at the mental isn't there.
They lose.
It comes down to that and you also got
to go back to the way Daniel cormier
handled rumble.
He's the only guy that's been able to
eat rumble shots,
absorb them and come back and break him.
You know,
that was a.
I mean,
yeah,
he ate that right hand and just hit his
head on the floor,
woke back up and then went after it and
that's,
you know,
that's respectable to that that I don't
think fans or anybody can really
understand what it takes to get slightly
knocked out,
stand back up and want to keep going.
Yeah.
That's a different level of
understanding of the sport,
like as an athlete,
when I watch a fight or go through that
and keep their composure,
move around and deal with that problem
and then even if they lose but stay in
the fight and go the distance and tough
it out.
Like Diego Sanchez,
great example of that.
So like how do you not respect and,
and have a,
a real logical understanding of that
human being is built from something
different.
That's insane.
He just,
there's fighters that come back and his
fighters had almost never come back.
It's really interesting.
Like we were talking about like Bj Penn,
one of the all time greats,
a can't remember a fight where Bj was
losing,
where he came back and won.
Frankie Edgar,
on the other hand,
you can never count that motherfucker
out ever true.
Frankie Edgar in the gray maynard
fights,
there's to those two chaotic fights was
so close to being stopped in the first
round were gray.
Maynard is putting it on him and Frankie
is going down and down again and
stumbling around the octagon and gray
catch keeps catching him and frankie
goes on to stop him.
I mean,
that was insane.
Then those two fights were insane and he
should go down as one of the best ever
for that.
You know what I mean?
It's like stuff like that,
those fights where they want to withdraw
and then the other one when he beat
them,
and it's true.
You gotta it's hard though because
there's so many crazy fights.
He can get credit to everybody.
It's like,
how do you,
how do you really dictate who gets what?
Because they're all.
We're all putting our life out there on
the line too.
So every single one of these,
just as serious as the next and every
single one of us is sacrifice just as
much as the next.
So at what point do you really start
drawing the line as to who is the best
and who was it?
I think it has to come down to who stays
the longest.
Yeah.
No,
I agree with you was really,
that's why I put fate or overcame as the
best heavyweight of all time.
Although I still think I maintain the
cane when he was at his best.
It was far as like what I see him,
what he was able to do two guys and what
I see from his performance inside the
octagon,
especially his cardio as a heavyweight
is clean technique is wrestling the pace
he puts on guys his chin.
I don't think there has been ever
anybody like Cain I think came when he
was at his prime was the best I've ever
seen.
I never got to see fate or fight live,
but I would say if you have to give an
all time great to a heavyweight.
I kind of leaned towards fader because
he stayed on top longer,
beat more guys longer,
obviously be compared to cane Noguera
and his prime cro cop in his prime
fought some freaks,
like semi Schiltz took him down and when
that was in the early days.
Yeah,
when like it was still very limited.
It was wild rules as far as supplements
go.
Take whatever you want,
motherfucker.
Let's get this party going.
Let's see if we can get you bigger than
Joe Rogan.
Everyone's bigger and bigger than me,
man.
I was tiny compared to crow.
Okay.
Lorenzo and to Lorenzo's gorilla.
Yeah.
Cro Cop just won the rise in Grand Prix.
I mean he's a shell of himself in the
UFC under Usada testing.
They send them off to Japan and all of a
sudden he's Super Cro.
Cop again.
Come look sensational.
I didn't see that.
Oh,
he looked fantastic.
That one.
Boxing look fantastic.
Well,
he went and did some kickboxing,
looked really good in kickboxing again,
and then fall and rise and in one wonder
heavyweight Grand Prix.
He mean he looked extraordinary.
He looked like the cro cop of old.
He really did.
He really turned back the clock,
watch it,
and then he decided I'm good.
I'm done.
I ended my career with an amazing high
note to.
Awesome.
Yeah.
And,
and very rarely do people come back and
do that.
Yeah.
You know,
need a little help.
A little help from Dr. Mexican
supplements.
Well,
what it they say what it ricky bobby
said it best.
What is that?
Yeah,
cheating gain trying.
Is that what he said?
I thought was you ain't first.
You're last.
Maybe it's both or maybe I still have
from a different movie sheet and they'd
try it.
That's like real old,
right?
Yeah.
Maybe that was somebody else.
Maybe it was just,
I don't know.
Yeah,
no old guy yelling at me.
I mean there's that,
but that you always have to have that
asterisk next pride that there was no
drug testing and I've had an incident.
You went here on a couple times where
anthony was talking about it.
They're in the contracts.
It said in capital letters,
we will not test you for steroids.
And Ensign was laughing about it.
He's like,
what the fuck?
Like,
is this what I'm fighting?
But they were just selling you like we
want to have some fun.
Yeah.
But I remember even because I was part
of the sport in the air and I'm so glad
I really am.
I'm so glad I was part of the sport
during that time.
And I was just coming up in it.
I was like maybe two,
three and know at this point when I can
specifically remember a time having to
make a decision at 21 years old.
Do I want to be in the IFL?
Do I want to go try out for the ultimate
fighter or do I just keep working with
three jobs,
coaching,
wrestling,
doing what I'm doing here in Tucson as a
janitor,
stay with my money in and just be
patient,
keep winning fights until I get there.
And uh,
I was 20 years old.
They were offering me $2,000 a month to,
to fight in the IFL with the sabers,
which was um,
this was forever ago in $2,000 a month
for me.
Would it changed my life?
I'm 20 years old.
Um,
I'm living paycheck to paycheck and I'm
doing all these jobs.
I can quit all my jobs and focus on
training 24 slash seven.
That's my mindset with $2,000 a month.
Heck yeah,
you can do that.
That's the way to go.
But wait a second,
there is no 135 pound weight class.
There's no 145 pound weight class.
It's only 1:55 and up.
So I'm already eating as much as I can,
trying to put weight on and get into the
weight class to fight at 155 pounds.
What do you walk around?
And then right now,
now I'm walking around 55 60,
but then at 20 years old,
40 to 142 pounds trying to eat
everything I can insight and um,
between that and 50,
you know,
1:50.
So I said you're too small for that.
I felt if they lock you into that
contract for two grand a month,
they're going to throw you out there,
you're going to lose twice.
They're going to cut you and then you
didn't get any money and you lost.
Now you got to losses on your record
because these guys are monsters and how
do you come back from that?
So I said,
alright,
I'm going to say no to that.
I fell.
I'm going to go to trial for the
ultimate fighter,
try it out for the ultimate fighter.
Didn't get in,
lost that opportunity.
So then I just kept training and that's
when I got my first fight at six and now
I was five.
No,
got an offer on two days notice to go
fight and total combat,
which is now my coach,
Eric del Pharaohs a promotion back then
he was a promoter and I took the fight,
fought it,
and then I met Eric and that was the
beginning of that.
Wow.
So you were living in Arizona at the
time and that's how you moved down to
San Diego.
Tucson,
Arizona.
I was raised there from two years old
until I was 21 till I moved to San
Diego.
And for favor,
favor,
fight in 2007 was the first camp I ever
had a coach.
Never had a coach before that point.
Um,
I'd never been to Vegas.
I just legally able to go there.
Uh,
there's a lot of things I'd never gotten
to do with it.
I,
it was incredible to get to do that back
then.
First fight ever on television.
And the WEC was the WC I get to fight in
front of chocolate down and Tito Ortiz
in the,
uh,
audience.
Wow.
Weird things like that that I remember
that was like,
what am I doing here?
What am I doing here?
I made it.
Yeah.
And uh,
the game just to be part of the game at
that point.
Diego Sanchez is the man at 185 pounds,
like a get to training.
That was ultimate fighter season one
when farther.
And that's,
those are the guys I'm watching saying
I'm going to do this.
Wow.
So when you tried out for the ultimate
fighter,
what season was it?
I think it was like two or three times.
So you were trying to 55 then?
I was.
Wow.
And I have three fights at 55.
I have three fights at 45 for I member.
Right.
Also.
Wow.
So at the time when this was going on,
2005 when you started out was right when
Stephan Bonner and forrest griffin had
that epic fight in the finals of the
ultimate fighter season one and it
launched mma and that's what made me
decide and that's when I'm going to
school,
you see?
So I'm like,
all right,
this thing is,
this is the time if you're going to do
it,
get in now and just see what you can do
with it.
Go all in.
And I'm like,
you might make it or keep going to
school,
go get you.
I wanted to be an emt firefighter.
That was the goal.
And it was like,
you know,
what do I do?
Do I,
I have so much stability.
I got three jobs,
I got money coming in,
I'm comfortable.
I'm going to school,
I'm doing the picture.
Perfect.
Twenty,
19,
20 year old vision for a kid who wants
to be something right,
going to school,
working.
I threw it all away and just said screw
it.
And uh,
it was nerve wracking,
but like I said,
I didn't do it until I asked my mom.
My mom didn't even the fact that she
didn't even like
think about it,
like I didn't think about it.
Wow.
I didn't even think about.
I just quit my job,
packed all my shit up in an eclipse.
My car couldn't make it to California,
so I had to have my friend's truck tow
it on a trailer.
Everything I owned in the car.
And then we drove the truck.
Semi truck basically became a shed for
everything.
I have my card in my car,
became a set for everything I owned,
you know.
Wow.
Move out there.
But so many stories like that come on.
I mean,
how many MMA fighters have that story at
ton.
Well,
it's what is interesting to go back to
your style,
you're very unique style is that you
really did come along when the sport was
in its.
I wouldn't say it's infancy,
but it was like a teenager at the time.
The sport,
the sport was really only 12,
13 years old and I'm so glad I got
anything because that exact fact,
what you just mentioned is why I knew I
could do something different.
That's why,
because it was growing and there was so
much room to knew I could do things
nobody had ever seen and it wasn't wrong
anymore because this is new.
Right.
And if you say I'm wrong,
I say fuck you.
I'm going to do it my way because this
is new where there wasn't an established
orthodox like a,
you know,
there was the style.
There was though,
and I got rid of killed my whole career.
Was there,
like in the household,
what were they saying to you?
You're not supposed to do that.
You're boxing.
You're kickbox and you're not supposed
to do that.
You're wrestling,
but I'm not doing any of those things.
I'm doing them all mixed together.
So how are you telling me I'm doing
something wrong right now?
Well,
one of the things that are said about
you,
I said,
if you watch dominick Cruz fight,
I would tell you don't fight like that,
but look how God damn good he is at it,
so you can't say don't fight like that
because he's not just like the way you
throw punches,
the way you move and throw punches and
throw punches from odd angles.
You could tell someone if someone was
like a very traditional technical coach
who would say that is the wrong way to
throw punches,
but I would say no because look,
he's fucking landing them and they're
hurting the guy and he uses them a lot
as very effective with.
That will always be my argument with
every conventional coach and this is why
I break.
What makes them relevant?
Well,
it's not necessarily you break what
makes them relevant.
You figure out a way to make your style
work in a way that confounds the
experts.
Well,
what I mean by that is when they talk to
me maybe not to $20 million other
people,
they are that shit,
but when you try to tell me that,
and I've had.
I can't tell you how many countless
world champion kick boxing coaches go.
Only you can do that.
You're awesome.
Keep doing it.
And I and I couldn't disagree more.
Well,
anybody can do it if they mimic your
movements and your movements aren't like
Cirque de Solei movements that you have
to be like physically gifted in order to
pull off or work towards them for 100
years.
Yeah.
I'm not going to sit here and break it
down,
but there are obviously movements that
I'm doing and they can be read.
It took 30 rounds to figure out what the
same camp for 10 years,
but they figured it out.
Right.
You know they can,
they can imitate.
You ever see Justin Buchholz do.
Yeah.
They're usually pretty well know what
they're doing,
but who
else has fought somebody as much as they
fought me.
I mean think about it.
Benevidez twice.
Favorite twice.
Tj dillashaw,
Charlie Valencia,
his fall with them.
Scott Jorgensen train with them before I
fought him.
I'm Ian Mccall,
train with them for a tiny bit of time
before I fought him.
I'm essentially every single person I've
ever fought for the past 10 years has at
some point been friends with favorite
trained with that camp because they were
the little guy camp while I said why
join them if you can beat them,
and I just did it my own way and let
them all hate me and trained together
and it was okay with me,
you know,
I needed to do things my way in order to
build something different in a,
in a game that hadn't really caught up
to the things that I was thinking about
yet in my opinion.
Um,
it didn't make me.
The only one that was right in these
things is just how I used the things
that I used.
They had theirs too.
But my whole mindset was,
like I said,
if I fight like them,
I'm going to be like them and they're
going to adjust to me.
Like they adjust everybody else.
Now going back to the early days when
you sort of learn the style,
we kind of got off this,
but I really wanted to touch back on it
when you said that your style.
No one had your style before.
No one could tell you that it was the
wrong way to do it because you're being
very effective with it,
but did you take it from anywhere and
did you look at boxing footage?
Did you look at kickboxing or Muay Thai?
Like where did you get all your foot
work from?
Well,
there's a mixture of things.
One,
it all started with me fighting at 155
pounds,
weighing 142 pounds.
That's where this whole mindset started,
so it was there already twice as big as
you and on fight day they're going to be
three times as big as you,
so you better not get touched.
You better not get grabbed and you
better not get hit at all.
Don't let him touch you because they're
too big.
They take you down.
Your energy is going to be zapped by the
time you do get up.
If you get up and if the hit you,
they're big and strong and they're
probably going to put you out.
So you have to use all that strength,
all that size against them and make it
their weakness instead of their
strength.
And that's how I started because I was
so little that I said,
all right,
I need to focus on defense.
Um,
obviously I got to hurt him too.
But after they do what they're trying to
do with their big strength and be
stronger and be more powerful and be
more athletic,
they're going to wear themselves out.
And then now we're even round middle
around to all those things that they had
early where even now and now I can just
sell them and pick them apart and beat
them.
And I always had that mentality rather
than fight fire with fire.
It just didn't make sense to me.
When my body was on the line,
I wanted the path of least resistance.
And so it started with that until I got
to about five and l five in total
combat.
I took that fight on two days notice.
Went out there with no coaches,
no corner men and women myself,
and they just picked corner mit random
corner men and put them in out there
that night was why eric liked me because
he saw,
you know,
I took it at short notice,
won it.
It was a tough fight,
but I had no car man.
I came solo on a flight and just went
and so he's like,
okay,
I can work with this,
you know,
this guy wants to do it.
So he picked me up.
But then that's really when the
progression started meeting Eric like,
and that's because I'd never had.
I mean I had pads held for me here and
there in Tucson,
but only if guys were getting 65 bucks
to do it or something for it because
there's not a lot of money and fight
game.
So they're all as hungry as I am the
trainers and I wasn't really like some
star pupil that everybody wanted to get
on board and make a world champion at
this point I was just a guy,
right?
So I wasn't getting pad work.
I wasn't getting one on one training.
I lined up my own coaching,
I'd have guys that knew what they were
doing,
being pro boxers,
pro high level wrestlers,
high level blue belts at this time and
role and wrestle and make my own team
and my own coaches with the people that
I had available,
but I didn't have a head and when I
found eric at six and I won that fight,
found eric and he said,
I'll coach you,
I'll get you a manager and I'll get all
this figured out for you.
That's what I was really looking for.
That's why I went to California and got
Outta Tucson's because I knew I wasn't
finding that in Tucson when I went there
and got that,
it was like a gift.
I was like,
this is what I'm talking about.
I knew if I went there and one with no
one in my corner,
somebody would want to pick me up.
And they did.
Eric did and we stayed together ever
since.
So was your style something that you
worked on with Eric,
like learning those footwork drills?
Like when,
when you came to him,
you have essentially we're a smaller guy
who were fa,
was fighting bigger guys and had to be a
little trickier in your movement.
Where were you getting that stuff from?
Well now I,
uh,
when I meet Eric,
I'm no longer the smaller guy fighting
bigger guys because,
well,
a little bit,
but 45 and 30,
45 is now allowed.
Now 145 pounds is just getting into
these small shows,
not just the WEC.
So by the time I met Eric at six and no,
I'm,
I take that fight on two days notice at
145 pounds.
But I was getting ready to fight at 1:55
in Colorado for a world title.
But the whole show got canceled.
That's why I was in shape to take the
fight on two days notice.
So when I met Eric,
the 45 pound weight class was there 55?
A was the one that was basking.
So that's,
that was how I got into the UFC.
But your question exactly was what was,
how did you devise your movement?
How did you devise your footwork?
Did you study other stuff?
Did you learn it with Eric?
Did you guys put it together?
Honestly,
like I had a couple things that I did
naturally and then Eric and Eric has a
skillset where he,
if you have a natural movement,
he doesn't tell you to to fix it,
he lets you do it and then turns it in,
has you add a weapon to it?
That's his gift and I had a lot of those
little weird things that I did and those
weird odd things you had just devised to
learn how to bigger people.
Yeah,
and is a mixture of wrestling stance
with punching and kicking.
I kind of have a.
If you watch wrestling that there's no
set stance.
There's no set w,
you know what I mean?
It's constant.
If you watch college,
high school,
like the highest level wrestlers,
it's all fluid motion in both stances.
So I made fighting that because I
started out wrestling and then I added
the punches and the kicks to that move
to that motion instead of trying to
change what I already did with my
wrestling and try to make it this way,
he just let me do what I did up to five
and o with my wrestling and whatever I
taught myself and then he just tightened
it up and made it into a pro level.
Look to an extent,
speed,
timing range,
these type of things.
And now what do you have it now as a
system?
Do you have it organized?
You have a town now?
I have a system but I'm a visual learner
so you could.
You could literally just do a movement
in front of me and I'll learn it really
quick.
But if you write it or I have to read
it,
I'll never get it.
It's all visual.
So I just.
There are certain things that I was
running into when I would spar early on
starting that I came up with habits to
deal with because of my wrestling and my
and and not having a coach that instead
of the coach saying,
no,
do this,
I just adjusted and found my own answers
and do keep a training log of all these
lessons that you learned.
Nod.
I know them.
They're just all in your mind.
Yeah,
I know him.
I know him very well.
Studied it 100 percent confident that
you keep that stuff in your memory.
You don't need to write it down.
No,
I don't need to write it down because I
drill it at once.
I have a memory.
I don't just write it.
I do it.
I drill it,
pad work a show Eric and I'll say,
what do you think about this?
And he'll be like,
okay,
well I do this,
this and this to make it a little better
and keep you dah,
Dah,
Dah.
And then we use it.
But I mean I'm using.
I'm not using the craziest moves in the
world.
You know,
Jon Jones used crazy moves a certain
people like a Stevens,
Steven Thompson throat has crazy moves.
You know what I mean?
I'm actually using crazy movements to
stay defensive and offensive
simultaneously.
That's,
that's the idea to do both at the same
time and to be very hard to read what
you're hard to read if you're being
offensive and defensive at the same
time.
Yeah.
It's,
it's hard to read because you don't know
if I'm being offensive or defensive.
It's one or the other or both.
I can do both because where I put myself
on defensively in a.
generally speaking,
when I,
when I've been doing very well in my
matchups,
I put myself in the,
in the,
in the gray area where even if you do
hit me,
it's limited power and I'm still able to
hit you more and you're able to hit me
basically.
That's the idea.
Now,
generally,
here you are,
you're,
you're coming off of,
uh,
the toughest laws for your career.
You,
you lose to cody.
No love in a very,
very tough fight against a super
talented guy.
Yeah.
How did you,
how do you feel about that fight and how
do you feel right now?
I feel good.
I just want to heal up my,
my body a little bit that that year,
doing the three camps,
coming back after the couch.
It just,
it was,
it was the heart.
It was a hard year.
It was a good year.
It was weren't conditioned when you
first started,
but that also affected my style.
Like if you look at the last three
fights this year and my fights before
the injuries,
I threw a million more kicks.
Well,
you looked out standing against Uriah.
You looked like your body didn't look as
good with Tj.
You looked like I was her.
Right.
That was the one where I was hurt.
You can tell you tell physically by
looking and by the favorite fight I felt
I did strength training camp for that
whole camp.
That's the difference of having a
strength training camp and not having a
structured where the way you looked.
Right,
but my cardio was through the roof
because I implemented sprints instead of
strength and the strength.
Whereas for the favor of fight,
I could do strength training because I
had enough time and my sprints so I
could double up on the workload to make
my body stronger,
more fast,
more efficient,
and more than anything tougher to take,
better to take damage,
better your core tufting of or
everything in kids taking punches feels
night and day different now.
Even for the cody fight,
I felt great.
I do.
I do look at that fight and I think
maybe I could have waited,
but I knew a so I wouldn't overwork
myself in that year with,
uh,
with the training and stuff because it's
one thing to take three fights in a year
and it's another thing to take three
title fights in a year.
Anybody can say whatever they want.
I fought six times this year.
Yeah,
but you didn't fight three.
You didn't go through three title fight
camps and then fight.
These guys were the best in the world.
That's a different thing.
It's so much more work.
It's going to five rounds and it's a lot
of workload,
but the camp is really where the damage
is done.
Not that fight,
the camps are just painful for five
rounds,
just the way it is.
But um,
with,
after getting through that fight with
cody,
I feel like I just want to face the
winter.
Those two,
you know,
I think that he had a good night.
They had a,
like I said,
I've fought that camp.
How many times men,
how legitimately if you had to break
down,
I mean if you went back and looked at
tape,
you could probably break down 30 rounds
with me in that camp.
That means they have all those reads on
me through the years.
And then cody started out watching me in
junior high,
high school and then the way I look at
it is he's the one guy who could
implement it because he looked up to the
guys that wanted to beat me as they are
the shit so at took down the ego from
him and allowed him to learn from the
best guys that I've fought and really
taking that information and use it.
Whereas you give a guy like favor or tj
information and I guarantee you it's in
linear out the other.
They already know everything.
You don't teach teachers learn a lot
from Dwayne.
He is now,
but I'm talking about then in that camp
and I think that cody was just like a
sponge for these guys because he was
young and so he came up in that camp as
a youngster and nothing those guys could
say to them would be wrong and so that
made him very with what he's
doing today and then he's built his
style to be the champion,
which was me.
I think a big factor in cody's ability
is also he came to mma from boxing with
very good hands.
Yes.
His hands are outstanding.
Yeah,
but we expected that.
Right.
I'm sure you did that.
I'm just saying that that's a big factor
in his success in MMA period.
Grief is that his boxing was already a
really high level before you entered
into mma.
I had a lot of,
I think even more than having boxing at
a high level.
It's just a rounds.
Yes,
it's the rounds.
It's the.
It's the experience in the fights more
than even being good or not like.
He was good obviously,
but he hadn't rounds so he wasn't coming
in green.
He was coming in as a tenant,
as an amateur and then having 10 pro
fights and so that's 20 and l basically
we were,
you know what I mean?
Our,
our tendency as a pro,
he lost some fights as an amateur,
but even then he goes through his losses
as an amateur so they don't affect him
on his record and so like he's learning
those things.
Even though your brain is taking the
damage,
he still learning things that are going
to be added to his pro career that gave
them experience in,
in the matter,
and that's what the amateur system,
you know,
the amateur is going to create a,
a different level of up and comers now
because they're not coming in as their
record.
They're coming in as two or three times
that record if you count there.
That's always the thing that drives me
crazy about people that jump right into
the UFC like you.
Not to pick on cm punk,
but the idea that cm punk with no
competition experience whatsoever is
going to fight professionally.
In the biggest organization,
the world,
it's a little offensive.
Really?
Yeah.
Why?
Because here's a guy that has no
competition experience whatsoever and
he's going to fight someone who
legitimately and Micky Gall is a brown
belt in Jujitsu.
Very good on the ground,
good standup,
tough kid,
has fought amateur,
has fought professional,
and has a wealth of martial arts
experience.
It's contrary to everything anyone has
ever learned about learning and teaching
and getting better.
At martial arts,
you don't just jump into the deep end of
the pool when you're not some physical
freak like brock lesnar or something
like that.
You know,
you're talking about a guy was a good
athlete.
I mean cm punk is,
but there's nothing unbelievable about
them.
He's not some freak of nature.
So I would think that if this guy really
did want to do this and do it the right
way,
get them to go through it the right way
like everybody else would.
Get them to start at small
organizations.
Get Him to learn martial arts from
fault.
Yes.
No,
no,
I don't think so.
Who's this?
I don't agree.
Who says,
I think that cm punk is a genius for
saying,
I can make a million dollars on this and
go fight.
Somebody that would've made,
could have,
could have 50,000.
He'd never fought in his life.
I paid $500 to 501st five fights.
Right?
This is my point.
This is exactly the point I'm getting
to.
Right.
He was already famous.
That's what the fight was for him,
but do you think that it should be
approached that way?
No.
No,
but I don't think it's going to keep
happening.
That's what we're.
That's what the UFC to an extent is
promoting.
Right?
Because they're promoting promotion,
not big.
Who deserves and not how good you are.
Right?
If you really look at what sells data,
5,000 and freaking Kimbo slice had
record sales on these weird things and
it's like,
what sense does that make?
Is that fair?
Is that right?
No.
Is it selling?
Yes.
Why aren't people buying it?
Because they understand it,
but wouldn't you think that once you're
already wealthy like cm punk is,
he's already a millionaire?
Wouldn't you want to do it correctly?
Rather than go for the big cash grab
that's going to wind up getting your
face punched in like if he was your
friend.
Let's put it this way,
he raised my friend.
I know exactly what I tell them.
You've got to learn how to fight.
You got to learn how to fight the right
way.
You've got to learn how to fight like
everybody else does.
Slowly and surely you've got to train
with the best people in the world and
learn from your ability up.
Now,
don't pretend you're already there.
Don't jump right into the UFC with a
mean face on that's fucking crazy.
You're going to get smashed and I,
and I respect you because you said that
to Brennan and shop and well Shaw,
who was also an issue of him being a
very good friend of mine and also
knowing that to say to a friend,
you tell the friend the truth.
You don't just.
Yes.
Men and I knew how many times he'd been
knocked out.
I knew how many times he'd been knocked
down a football.
I knew how many times I'd be in,
he had been knocked out in the gym and I
knew he was having issues and I knew he
wasn't able to take a punch like it used
to anymore and I also knew that he also
had a way out with podcasting and he's
being really successful in it.
And I was.
And he had a foot out the door.
He already had a foot out the door.
Yeah.
And that's you being a good friend.
So all I'm saying is it's proof that you
would say that you're following through
with what you know and that that's rare.
And I would never stop cm punk from
competing.
What I would say is,
hey man,
have a fucking Jujitsu match.
Have an amateur submission,
grappling match.
Have an amateur kickboxing.
So why do you think he did?
Because he got a fuck load of money and
because he thought he could do it
because he's a strong man.
He's got a strong mind.
He's like one of those straight edge
guys that thinks he can just get a hard
work,
pays off,
you know,
and just went out there and he's a huge
celebrity and he felt like he was just
going to ride that to a new career in
the UFC and I'm like,
that's like saying you're just going to
jump into Nascar and you've never raised
a car before.
You're just going to wind up dead.
That that being said,
than the logic,
the only logical thing has to be the
money in that district.
One hundred percent money bunny and
delusion,
delusional thinking.
What's the delusion?
Thinking that he's going to beat a guy
like micky gall,
just delusional.
He think he really thought that the more
that you can on it,
100 percent,
100 percent.
I think he thought he could beat him.
I think he thought he could look,
use training,
training.
It wasn't training to lose.
He wasn't trained to be 100 percent
defensive.
He stepped forward and throw a wild
right hand.
He didn't dance around the outside and
try to avoid him.
He tried to,
when he stepped towards him and got
taken down immediately,
then got mauled,
you know,
I mean you've seen him.
It's like,
you know what it's like when a guy has
very little ground experience,
how long it takes before they accident.
I already knew that was going to happen.
Of course knew it was going to happen
here soon.
As soon as you went to the ground you
knew exactly what was going to play out.
Right.
But you said it's almost offensive.
I remember you saying that and it's
like,
how could,
like who's who is who.
Is it more offensive to us as the
fighters or is it a or is it like.
I don't know if I should be more mad at
at Mickey Golfer thinking he can do it
because that's in every single one of us
to not make it go.
Not Me.
Sorry.
Yeah.
Is it up to.
Is it his fault that he believed that he
could do it to an extent.
Does that make them that delusional that
every man on are things that they can go
in there and fight and win?
Or is it the UFC that says,
yeah,
we'll give you this much money and give
you a paper view and puts you at the top
of it and how much money you can
generate?
Well,
it's a great move for the UFC.
The UFC is like,
look,
hey,
we got this huge superstar and we're
going to send them in with this fresh
faced young whipper who was a good
fighter,
who's got a really good mouth,
great at talking and he's gonna fuck him
up for sure.
Like this is great.
And what do they do?
They made a.
They made a hero at a Mickey Golf and
then wants to make he goggles Hazel
Stave Sage Northcutt I think you fucking
corn.
It's another one.
And then takes him out too and chokes
him out and his next fight,
God damn genius.
What he's done is beautiful.
So in a way the UFC has done a beautiful
thing because they go,
oh,
you think you can fight in the UFC?
Come on in.
Have a seat,
can we get you something to drink?
Hey,
come up.
And that being said,
for me,
it's not offensive that cm punk when in
there did it.
It's offensive like I guess how,
depending on who you are,
it's like it's not offensive,
but it's crazy how you start to realize
in those scenarios that it doesn't
matter how much time,
skill,
or purpose you put into this craft,
it matters how famous you are or else
you don't get paid in a way.
Yeah,
you're right,
and this is my issue.
It's not.
It's not who's wrong,
who's right,
it's you don't need to train and be the
best anymore.
In fact,
that has a tiny eensy weensy tiny little
bit of how you make money.
I see.
I don't think that's true.
I think that is a factor and that factor
is compounded.
If you're a great shit talker.
The point being conor Mcgregor,
conor mcgregor is not just a fantastic
shit talker.
He acts a world class fighter fighting.
Yeah,
bad motherfucker and he's capable of
knocking people out with one shot.
I mean,
that is something people,
they are so excited to see him.
They're paying money to see him.
He's different when we're talking about
somebody on a different level than
seeing.
Well Rhonda,
when she was in her prime,
Rhonda,
when she was beating all these women and
when she was just a flip and people in
their head and arm barring them,
you people were paying to see not just
this spectacular figure but also this
person who really knew how to fight.
Right?
And it was,
uh,
it was,
it
was a mixture of that and decent
matchups too.
Oh,
100 percent.
Well,
also when Rhonda with the female MMA
being x,
it's gone through in just a few years,
this fantastic metamorphosis where he's
seeing women like Valentina Shevchenko
that is just an overall well rounded
worldclass mixed martial arts now girls
like,
you know,
rose,
Nama units were coming up.
These,
these MMA fighters that are coming up
that are like super talented now and
everyone's getting better.
The young people coming into the game
that have this really comprehensive mma
game.
Whereas before she was fighting people.
No disrespect to her opponents,
but they were limited.
They were very limited.
They're striking.
Maybe it wasn't so good.
They were awkward.
They weren't that good athletically.
There weren't that strong.
They couldn't last as long.
They couldn't touch her on the ground
and she showed she shined in those
match.
I guess it's just odd how you can look
at somebody like paige vanzant and the
champ,
a young Jay check.
Then the same way,
right?
Yes.
50 slash 50.
Yes,
sorry.
It makes the most times,
uh,
that if you really look at the breakdown
of the,
of the weight class,
paige vanzant and the champ are almost
equal.
Have equal value if you fight them to an
extent because of views and who wants to
see who fight.
One was on dancing with the stars,
became a big household for dancing and
the dancing with the stars because of
before dancing with the stars.
She was already on dancing.
She's like a fucking beautiful
cheerleader.
It's just that is the appeal that's
making money as my point.
Not just,
she can fight.
She absolutely.
She's beating some great girls in the
division,
but if we're talking about young Jay
check who can fight,
fight,
put her blood,
sweat,
tears like you see it in her and
everything about it,
and then paige vanzant who is a a good
athlete and can fight.
It's crazy.
The money levels that come to the same
because one is just that famous and that
a camera perfect compared to the other
one who was just that good at fighting.
Not that she's not,
but she's not as good on the cameras.
The other one,
so it levels everything out and that's
what's blowing my mind is watching that
happen.
Even though the skillset isn't even
close to the same,
they're going to make the same money.
Well,
the really scary thing is when the page
might make more money,
maybe it's crazy.
That's what's trippy.
It is kind of trippy,
but it kind of makes sense because it's
entertainment as well as fighting.
It's not just a sport.
It's not just who's the best sprinter
and that's where I go to.
It doesn't offend you with.
Well,
it doesn't offend me in that sense.
What offended me was that he,
it didn't offend me that he thought it
because I felt like someone should have
told them and it didn't offend me that
his coach has prepared them for it
because his coach is a good friend of
mine,
Duke Roufus and what are you going to
do?
The guy comes through and wants to learn
how to fight.
You got to throw them in there.
Yeah.
It just itch.
It should happen the way it happened
because it's good for everybody to see.
It shouldn't happen the way it happened
because that's all we were going to see.
You know what I'm saying?
It wasn't.
It was a mauling.
You remember?
That was Mike Tyson fights where he
would fight guys and you would just go,
don't blink because this shit is not
going to last.
It's kind of like that.
It's like,
yes,
it's a competition,
but God damn it.
It's not really,
you know,
like paige vanzant.
Let's go back to her again.
Who's a very talented girl.
I've got nothing but respect for her.
I think it was really fun.
It scared the fuck out of me when she
was getting close to your Nana when she
was getting,
like when she was winning fights and
then she fought rose noma,
Eunice and eunice is like right there.
Right.
Rosana,
Eunice lost to Carolina Kovacevich
within a very close fight.
Karolina went on to have a very close
fight with you on a right.
So rose beats paige vanzant decidedly.
Right.
She beat her down.
It was a huge performance for her,
but that meant that page was literally
two steps away from a murderer.
I mean,
you'll wanna look what she did to
Jessica Panay.
Look,
I was just to say that's my home girl.
Like she trades with us at Alliance and
Jessica is no Slouch,
no slouch,
just she's tough.
That's the other thing.
She's not just like.
I mean she took it.
She,
yeah,
she's a tough girl and all these girls
are tough.
But when you.
I don't know,
I was a little off when the girls came
in the gym,
especially in alliance.
We never had women in the gym ever in my
whole career.
It wasn't like,
it was just like,
it was just like no.
Women were fighting,
you know,
for years.
Yeah.
When did the women start coming there?
It's been there.
Had been with us like two,
three years now.
I want to say maybe if that with our
camp,
with Eric,
but when they first came I was a little
off put,
but the longer they are around,
the more they're like,
they just,
they're so in the sport.
They're just,
they're like,
their eyes are just like,
uh,
like sponges.
That's the best way I could put it.
And they're just so hungry to hear and
they're not just listening.
They're hearing you.
That's the biggest difference I noticed
with the women compared to trying to
work with men is men don't they listen,
but they're not hearing you.
They already have their own vision of
um,
cm punk.
I'm going to go out there and hit him
with a right hand and that's going to
be.
He had that vision and no matter what
you told cm punk that it wasn't going to
go that way because you were a 50 time
world champion and you know what's going
to happen.
He,
he had that vision and that was at
women.
You can tell them how it's gonna happen
and they trust and they listen and they
are open and they're willing and when
you have that and you're teaching
somebody something,
that's when you can watch.
Watch this thing grow and that's a huge
thing with the women that I really have
learned being around them is they're
just so humble in knowing where they're
at.
We're in a fight here.
I need to listen and things could go
weird.
Whereas men,
it's like
built to do this.
This is me.
This is how I.
I'm a man.
I'm the man.
I could kill anybody on earth.
We're all wired that way.
Ego is that in some
ways connected to your learning to let
go.
It's 100 percent my biggest battle and I
didn't mention it because I'm still
learning so much about it that I don't
want to sound too off with my
description because I'm not a.
I'm not.
I haven't completely rover it.
Yeah,
and I haven't mastered.
It's such a hard thing to master,
but when you can let go of the ego,
the ego is just such a horrible thing
for us.
I mean it,
it,
it ruined so many things that we could
be free from my ego.
Couldn't allow me to make me think that
I'm above you and that you should have a
two espressos here for me because I'm me
and I should have my water at 80 degrees
and somebody should be giving me a
massage and then we get out of here.
I should have my own car pick me up and
if I have my own car pick picking me up,
then you know some somebody should be.
But that's only because I put myself
above things and the only reason I put
myself about things because my ego.
The only reason I make excuses is
because my ego forces me to hide what I
am rather than what happened.
Ego just demolished is everything,
especially in the sport of fighting.
When you can set your ego aside,
you hear it all the time,
leave your ego at the door and then
come.
That doesn't happen.
Very rare do people leave their ego at
the door.
They're keeping track of every
submission that happens.
Every takedown,
every punch,
they're fixing their shin guards in the
middle of the practice because they're
getting tired and they don't want that
one big kick to land where that one big
take down the line when they're tired
and then it hurts their brain because
their psychology needs to stop.
I'll take downs in order for their ego
not to be hurt if it goes on and on and
on and on.
And Ego is the biggest thing that I
noticed is the difference with men and
women.
Now.
Women have it too,
but it's just a different feel.
What,
uh,
when we got women in the room and men in
the room and how they,
the energies is just interesting.
Do you think that women are better at
taking instruction from men and maybe
not as good as taking it from women?
Do you think that what's going on is
that the women are conceding that these
men are bigger and stronger and more
experience and so it's easier for them
to do a,
but maybe they still have that ego
against other women?
Yes.
I mean you pretty much.
I really believed that that is pretty
much exactly.
I mean there is a now it doesn't always
go this way,
but there is a natural flow in the way
we're built as human beings.
Right?
To where in the past where you know,
the man is the leader of the household
data da Da da.
That was the old way of thinking and now
we're getting contemporary and it's like
everybody is equal and as that's come to
pass,
we've seen women be the biggest hit in
the world for fighting right now.
Like their main carding everything and
they're running stuff and I think that
that has become so many years in the
past where you're like,
all right,
men are the household.
They run everything.
The women had to put their ego aside for
so long that they learn how to do it.
They had no ego walking into things.
They just already assumed the worst,
but then it made them so much more open
that yeah,
they take instruction.
I swear they just,
it's just different with women.
Not all of them,
but it's just odd.
There's,
you have to be in it to really feel it,
that women just take instruction
differently in a fight scenario.
Um,
and that's not what everybody.
I think that if you're dating the
fighter or something and you try to help
them,
it's,
it's actually never happened.
I've seen that.
So it goes both ways.
I've seen it,
but I've rarely do.
I see two lovers coach together and
train together and do fine.
Right.
The only odd one that I,
that I've seen work is smiling.
Misha,
Misha.
Here's another one.
What will you want,
say a smiley?
Who smile he just fought,
got,
always got this smiling on the back of
his head.
A redhead,
smiling Sam.
Hobbies and LV has girls in his corner
was every time you know that.
Yeah.
And Him and his girl,
they got,
he was walking into the last fight with
his kids,
with him and his girl and he's kissing
her while he's laughing at the end.
It just,
it blows my mind because everybody has
their own system,
you know,
and he's a happy guy.
He seems like he's having a grand old
time de who knows,
man,
I don't get it.
But yeah.
Well Tim,
you know,
that's the weird thing about people,
right?
Everyone's got a whole different
formula.
It just the whole thing.
All these topics are interesting.
So we're pretty much running out of time
because you've got to head back to San
Diego,
but I wanted to get back to where you're
at now as far as recovery and what your
thoughts are about resting and getting,
getting back to camp.
And when do you think your feet are
going to be re raring to go again?
And all your injuries.
That's pretty much that year.
Just put a good,
a good a bra on my body.
So I'm just right now I'm just healing.
And then those two are going to fight.
Uh,
I think July.
I don't know,
I think it's still a July fourth card.
Is that what it is?
The July weekend or say I don't really
know,
but I don't know the exact date.
That's the big weekend.
That July fourth weekend is always a
huge weekend for the UFC and I
think,
uh,
those to a fight on that card.
And then I'd like to winter that.
I'd like to come back and fight,
fight for the belt and put on another
good show.
I mean,
regardless,
that show was great and you know,
just to touch on that fight one more
time.
What was going through my head that
changed things?
You know,
I hear a lot about what people,
all he was a,
he didn't look the same.
He,
this,
he that and it's like there's some
things that I want to clarify that
unless you're a professional fighter and
you're in that zone,
you don't really understand.
And that was the,
the,
the way that I approached the fight was
a little different in this one than
you've seen in the past.
For the first two rounds it was,
it was pretty good.
It was back and forth,
me and me and cody was,
it was like,
it was a competitive match up coming
into third.
I get cut.
And when you get what he did,
he hit you with a kick.
It was a kick or a headbutt.
And then,
uh,
I don't know,
but it doesn't matter.
We're going to say it was a kid who
cares about kick got me,
caught me right here in my eyebrow.
And I remember I got cut and I remember
it started bleeding and it wasn't the
blood that bothered me as much as know
as the doctor.
That's when,
if you're me and you're not.
And I think about everything that's
going on and I'm adjusting.
It's like,
all right,
the doctors in here,
this cut is bad.
I mean,
and the way they were talking to me,
are you okay?
How's it look?
And I'm like,
Oh shit,
they're going to stop this fight like
this ever.
And when I heard the cow crowd reaction,
Ooh,
like when they saw,
when they showed it,
I was like,
crap,
they might stop this fight.
So this is the third round,
I got to go after it for the in the
fourth,
like there's no other,
it's not just,
it's no longer fighting smart.
It's no longer fighting smart.
After I got cut,
the third round is lost for me right
when you get cut,
that's it.
Chances of me winning that or I have to
drop them or take them down and hold
them down and then maybe I could win.
But the,
the,
the cut is a deciding factor as an
athlete that you have to make a choice.
Am I all in or am I going to play safe?
And I was all in once I got cut because
I already lost on the score cards in my
mind.
Once you get cut,
you're down on,
on the bleeding and the damage,
they're going to see that.
And that's it.
It's not either cut him or put them out
or keep them down on the mat.
That was the goal.
From then on,
after that cut,
it was no longer stick move,
uh,
go to the weak side.
Go to the strong side time.
This time that it's,
you got to kill this dude or else you're
gonna lose a decision.
That's it and that's why you saw
different me in the fourth and that's
what,
that's where the big mistake wasn't me
getting put down on my butt a couple
times in one round and getting a 10,
eight round and then.
But at that point with the cut,
let's say I take it safe,
let's say I get cut and I play it safe
like I had been doing the chances that
the doctor would stop it were high,
he could go play it safe so it doesn't
cut my eye open worse,
right?
Stick move.
Just stay safe.
No,
it's like to just go for it.
Like I'm all in.
I'm in the fight.
That's what I was feeling at that time
and that's what can't be read on the
outside of a fight is what a fighter's
feeling when I'm feeling is they might
stop this fight because of this cut.
So you either got to take them out,
take them down or cut him back.
And so that was the focus and when that
happened I went all in and then that
created the openings that he needed to
be successful in his game plan.
And that was it.
So fifth round I knew I had to take them
out.
I mean I won the fifth round,
who wins the fifth round after losing
after getting put on there.
But a couple of times,
not very many people.
So it's a matter of that fight can go
different.
I have the tools,
the skillset,
the cardio,
everything.
It takes a little bit of health,
some adjustments and everything's fine.
This is a game of inches.
So that's how I feel about it.
I'm not,
I'm not discouraged by that.
As much as I feel like I'm growing,
I can grow from it.
It's also a massive challenge.
Now that you know that you've faced a
god that can beat you like that.
And now that massive challenge will
certainly burn a fire inside of you.
You don't.
You shouldn't need that to burn a fire
inside of you.
You don't think it gives you more
motivation.
If losing makes you.
For me,
if losing changes to how you approach
something,
then it weighs more than winning.
Does that mean that the.
Well,
okay,
I see what you're saying and I said that
they should.
I don't.
You got to be who you are.
Winning and losing.
You can't let that decide.
Now if I don't have the drive to go win
a world title without winning or losing
and what am I doing?
Right.
So that's not the right way to think and
part of your new mindset.
No,
this is life.
Right?
But this is a part of your new mindset.
New that I've always had this.
I mean it's been,
it's gotten.
I've gotten better at accepting it.
Yes.
With,
with losing control of things that I can
control.
Yes,
but I've always thought that way can't.
How do I make it so winning and losing
are equal because I don't want it to
change me.
Even if I lose,
I need to still be the person that I
tell everybody I am winning and losing.
You have to be what you are.
You can't change because it didn't go
your way,
so I don't think I need that last to be
driven.
I was driven and thought I was going to
win that fight as much as ever before
that fight.
I'm as driven and as good as I always
was.
Now after the loss,
it's just a matter of making
adjustments,
not burning desire,
just another challenge,
not burning desire to burning desire.
If you don't have that in all times and
get out because you're gonna get hurt.
So how much time.
So if we're talking with them fighting
in July,
we're talking right now.
It is now February.
So if they fight in July then you're
likely looking at somewhere around
December,
somewhere like that.
That perhaps depending on if I do one
fight this year,
okay.
And Go back and live my title.
Okay.
And then defended and another three
times in one year.
Okay.
If I,
you know,
I mean these guys are going to fight.
There's going to be a winner.
People want to see me fight them.
I really believe that one of these guys.
So what am I in a rush for other than
getting healthy and healing and putting
on a good show and fight these guys,
they want to fight me.
I'll tell you that.
Both of them.
So what's.
What's the rest other than being
perfectly healthy so I can put that show
on.
I fought three times last year.
Cody sat on the outside,
fought at three round fight,
came in and fought me.
I fought three titles,
thought for three titles against the
best guys in the world.
I would like to see how he can do.
Let's see if he can keep a wind street
going.
Let's see if he can keep the belt at all
against the guy that I already fought.
And let's see if Tj,
what Tj can do with,
with this opportunity.
This is the thing.
I don't mind seeing what these gentlemen
can do with it because I fought them
both and I know what it takes to be the
best for a very long time.
Not just for one fight and I'm not sure
if they have what it takes yet,
but I'm here and I liked the challenge
to find out and I like to challenge them
again to find out.
Donald Cruz has been a pleasure,
man.
I really appreciate you coming down,
That was awesome.
Good time and I'm really looking forward
to seeing you back in there again.
I'm really looking forward to you and me
doing commentary March 4th.
No time soon.
Thanks everybody.
We'll be back tomorrow with a Philip
DEFRANCO.
See you then.