The joe rogan experience.
That's the thing I was reading a lot of
people,
you know,
that we're sort of deriding the idea
that we're calling him crazy and they're
saying,
you know,
basically when,
uh,
when,
a Muslim person blow kills a bunch of
people,
we start talking about uh,
the calling them terrorists.
When,
uh,
when,
you know,
uh,
a black dude kills a bunch of people,
we start calling them thugs.
But when a young white guy starts
killing people,
we call the mentally ill and somehow
bats,
there's some inherent hypocrisy.
And then I kind of just think like,
it's,
I was thinking about this last night,
there's,
there's levels of human evil that are so
intense that will we get,
when we approached them,
we just kind of like shut down.
Like,
you know,
remember the matrix when they would do
like the electronic pulse and all the
machinery would just shut down.
It's like there are levels of human evil
that we get to that are so intense that
when we start approaching them,
a thought just drops out and pee and
it's all emotion that's left.
And so you can look at somebody like
that and say,
you know,
it's a hypocritical to call that guy
mentally ill or you're fighting against
a feminist cause by not recognizing the
inherent misogyny and his attack.
But really what's happening is something
so much sadder and deeper than either of
those things.
It's just like we're living in this
insane fucking world where human beings
have some tick in this country more than
another countries.
No one can figure out why were they
sometimes once in a while we'll go into
a place and shoot a bunch of people and
no one knows why it happens.
And some people say it's because it's
mental illness and some people say it's
because of bad parenting.
And some people say it's because of gun
control.
And some people say it's because of,
you know,
violent video games and violent and MMA
and movies and music and nobody fucking
knows why it's really happening.
And it's so terrifying that we just
start slinging mud at one another.
Trying to,
trying to say,
well it's this,
it's that,
and you're part of the problem by
perpetuating this idea.
And the reality is,
is existence is terrifying and humans
are fucking weird.
And once in a while there's this
evolutionary blip that somebody pops out
of their mother with a,
you know,
sort of genetic code ready to murder
people.
And I don't think it's because of being
spoiled and maybe it is,
and I don't think it's because of,
you know,
chemical imbalances or maybe it is,
it's just the reality is that's what's
happening is jack the ripper exists in
some 0.001% of human beings.
It's terrifying.
I did the audio book and my book and I
wrote an article,
a chapter about Patrice,
and I had to decide in their,
do I do patrice has voice or do I just
do a regular voice?
So in the,
so in when you buy the audio book of my
book,
you hear me,
God damn
good.
And I was like,
do I do that with all black people?
Like when I,
when will smith talks?
Do I make him like I did it,
I did it.
It's done.
Well,
patrice is just so big with it.
He's so is,
uh,
you know,
his voice was so big and he was kind of
almost have to do it because you heard,
I was telling it on opiate anthony,
but the whole thing was that I did a
girl with cerebral palsy,
didn't know she had cerebral palsy,
so I was drinking so much and patrice
thought that was fucking hilarious.
And he kept saying,
you alcoholic,
you can't even say if someone disabled
disabled.
That is the worst version.
But it's like if we did do a Joey Diaz
impression,
you have to do it right.
If you're going to say something that
Joey said,
you kind of have to say it again.
Everybody does.
If they say something as Joey,
you don't just say like,
if Ari has a joke,
you know,
like I might say it like as me,
I might tell you all are,
he's got this great new joke,
you know,
about blah,
blah,
blah.
Except if you're describing already mad,
then you'll do the
mumble.
You can't do that.
What was your will smith voice though?
Um,
same exactly
voice.
Hey,
exactly.
This is coby bryant voice.
I wrote the n word in the book twice and
I was as white people saying it.
I didn't realize it because I didn't
fucking really pay much attention to the
editing of it.
I just wrote them and then if,
if the publisher liked them,
I was in and I was like,
I read it and I was like,
Oh shit,
I've got to say the m word.
It's thinking for history.
I'll go down as saying the word and
despite whether or not I've ever said
it,
no one's got me on record saying it.
So I called my buddy Omar Dorsey,
who's on a,
he's on eastbound and down.
I was like,
Hey,
can you come and read a passage of my
book?
And he's like,
Oh,
I'd be honored.
Oh my God.
So passage,
what's the word?
Oh,
you did.
Am I supposed to do this?
Like a white person?
I go pose how good that way he did it.
He's like,
you know,
I love you.
If I'm getting you out of this one
own up to it.
In the book itself,
an audio book itself,
you would say,
well,
there's a question,
we'll word in this passage.
So I brought in a good friend.
I do.
I'll do
16 hours to read my own audio book.
I was like,
oh my God,
I cannot read out loud to save my life.
Yeah.