We live Jesus Christ.
Jamie,
you're so.
You're so quick on the draw.
You fucking maniac.
Give Jamie a couple of days off and he
started chomping at the bit to hit that
goal button.
Did you hear that?
Microsoft made a fucking ai and they had
a deleted after a day became because it
became a Hitler loving sex robot.
What it.
Somebody found a way to make it do that
though.
Like of course they found a flaw in the
AI that will make it repeat stuff.
And so a team of people on twitter like
purposely tried to make it racist and
all this crap.
That's pretty funny.
Well,
it,
it highlights the problems with an
artificial intelligence though,
like the idea that you've created
something that's some sort of a computer
someone kinda manipulate.
I mean if it's this easy to do something
that fucking Microsoft created,
you would have thought that Microsoft
being a computer manufacturer and the
manufacturer of operating systems would
understand the goddamn internet.
It's kind of weird though.
It's so realistic that that's what kids
actually are.
I have to deal with everyday on twitter,
like a seven year old goes on twitter,
it's going to see racist shit,
just going to see porn,
it's going to see all this crazy stuff.
So it's actually pretty realistic.
Well it isn't a way.
Right.
That means that this is a real problem
with.
That is a real problem with like what
kids are being exposed to like right
away.
If they go online,
like I think they go online as soon as
they get a phone.
Right.
Soon as kids get a phone,
they start talking to each other and
they understand that the foam gets
online,
they're online,
right?
So they're exposed to fucking everything
you get on facebook and if you're doing
that man,
if you're getting on twitter like on a
daily basis,
you're going to be exposed to some
really nutty shit.
And these fucking kids like they did not
being prepared for this.
There's just been thrown into this.
It's,
it's so weird.
Just hearing what my mom's,
she's,
she's been on the Internet recently.
She got the internet like a year ago.
Just her,
her language,
how she talks is different.
Like she's talking about retweeting and
hashtags and it's like my mom never used
that language before.
Somebody made a post on the Rogan for
the other day.
That was so perfect.
They were like,
before the Internet,
I never had any conversations about
feminism.
I never argue with anybody about
transgenders.
There's like all these things that all
of a sudden became an issue because of
the Internet.
Just like we were were transgender
rights.
We're kids.
It wasn't.
There was nothing.
We were led to like run them over with
cars.
I thought I couldn't do that,
but there was that renee richards who
was a high profile case because renee
richards.
Is that the name?
Renee renee the tennis player.
Is that the right name?
Might not be the right name.
The last name might be off,
but there was a tennis player who was a
man who was not a very good tennis
player,
I should say.
Not very good as a professional.
That's it.
That's the right name.
Yeah.
A lot better than me because I don't
play tennis.
Right.
So he became a woman and just started
fucking dominating,
like became like a top flight tennis
player and a lot of people were like,
Whoa,
Shit.
Like what?
How is,
how does that work?
Is that,
is that really a woman like this was
like the precursor to the uh,
the bullshit about the chick who used to
be a dude for 30 years became a check
for two years and they started fighting
female mma with this is a way the female
mma one is a way worse case because
you're talking about someone beating the
shit out of somebody would mail bones
and male mind and mailed tendons and all
that jazz.
But Renee Richards was beaten a lot of
fucking,
like really good test players that were
born women and there was a real
controversy behind it where people like,
man,
I don't fucking know like how,
what is,
how do you,
they should have a transgender league is
what they should have.
They should have transgender men.
And transgender is,
we're like,
well,
we want to be accepted as a regular
person.
Well you are but not in fucking sports.
There's a reason why I can't play like
in the Olympics is like they're,
they're,
they're experiencing social pressure
with this.
This is a big part of it and I think for
some sports that don't have anything to
do with explosiveness and sheer power,
and then you could say like,
well,
Serena Williams is always going to be
stronger and faster than a lot of men.
It's true,
but certainly one of them is Serena or
their sister.
The drug testing people came to their
house.
They locked themselves in a fucking safe
room.
What do you think that is?
Do you think that they just got done
smoking a joint though and they're like,
ah,
no,
I do not.
Brian.
I think his steroids,
I think it's performance enhancing
drugs.
I have friends that are girls that take
testosterone there,
Jujitsu girls and they compete and they
travel all over the place and compete
and they take fucking testosterone.
The testosterone in the Jujitsu world,
this is coming from obviously a person
who takes testosterone.
Me,
Serena Williams locked herself in a
panic room and drug test to mix up.
There was no mixed up.
She knew what the fuck was going on.
Like as a stocker,
someone's trying to kill me.
If that chicken at tennis racket,
she could beat the fuck out of anyone in
the world.
You think she's really worried about
some fucking dork with the pocket
protector comes to our house with a Piss
Cup.
Why can't condition you just not
answered the door.
Oh,
you can't.
They have rules.
The USA Da.
They need to know where you are at all
types to crazy.
Their rules are Donaldson Rooney who
obviously fights for the UFC is one of
the top pros in the world.
Right.
Donald fucking.
So rony gets a call from the US Ada
while he's doing something for the UFC.
He flew to Vegas for the UFC and they
were at your house.
We trying to test you.
He was like,
well,
I'm at the UFC like we have to tell us
exactly where you are.
He like,
well,
the fucking
UFC knows where I am,
man.
I'm here for the UFC.
Like what are you talking about?
Like they,
they literally,
he wasn't there competing was there to
watch,
but they,
they will tell you,
you have to tell them where you are in
any given day all the time.
You're always have to be able to be
reached.
Wow.
Yeah.
So she fucking do.
Yeah,
but you think it instead of a panic
room,
she could just be like,
I'm not going to answer the door.
I'm just going to be asleep.
Like why is she confirmed that she was
scared.
She locked herself in her panic room and
she confirms that she really was scared.
It's a great escape is a great excuse.
Look,
it might be the case,
the guy at the door,
look,
I might be full of Shit.
The guy at the door might have been some
serial killer look and fuck.
Who also works for the USA Da.
He might've been swole.
Who might've been scary looking?
Who the fuck knows?
I don't know,
but if I had a guess,
that chick is so fucking explosive.
She's so fast and it is a ridiculously
competitive sport.
I mean unbelievably competitive and the
money is astronomical.
You're talking about millions of dollars
to be someone like a Serina Williams.
Of course she would take steroids if she
could get away with it.
If she get away with and she doesn't
have a problem with it ethically.
If she was one of those people that grew
up in the world of competitive sports
like she is,
you know,
they realize,
man,
it's a fucking dog eat dog world.
You know what I had Lance Armstrong
onto?
He didn't want to take steroids.
He didn't want to do all that stuff.
He did it because everybody else was
doing it and they realized like,
we gotta do this.
We want to win.
If you want to win,
you've got,
we got to fucking do this.
They all do it,
man.
It works.
And that's why sports suck.
They don't suck.
Yeah,
because you don't know who's on what and
who's doing what time are you just
watching bullshit.
Yeah,
but that's part of the fun is wondering
whether or not a guys on the Jews.
Do you see Rosie Donald's brother caught
way he said about us.
Yeah.
Well he's Roseville.
Donald's brother's gay and this is what
he said.
He said it's like gay porn with a
different ending.
That's hilarious.
That's what gay people would say.
He looks so funny though.
Like when he's saying it,
it's just.
It looks like it's fake.
That's one of those things like this is
not real.
This is part of this simulation that
it's bullshit.
That video is one of the funniest videos
is quite hilarious.
It looks like a Saturday night live
skit.
He can get away with it because he's
gay.
Gay people have so much more leeway to
say gay stuff.
You know?
Let's call everything gay because it's
gay to him,
to him as gay.
To him it is like gay porn.
But do you think,
do you think there's a huge percentage
of people that aren't into the UFC that
go?
I agree man.
A bunch of guys rolling around.
So what?
Who Cares?
I wouldn't be upset at that guy.
I mean I think that guy helped the UFC
here.
Let's play.
Let's do it because it's so fucking.
His name is Daniel Donald Rolling
around on top of one another.
Trying to dominate each other just in
case you don't know that's gay porn with
a different ending
else says,
keep going.
I won't describe the ending for you,
but as I've gotten older,
the endings are less important.
Okay,
so take a delivery.
The timing,
the aggression and the violence of what
that was did not make me necessarily
comfortable but can kind of agnostic.
Then we had a colleague here was brought
before the committee and I've enjoyed
this week discussion about our rules.
God,
he couldn't be gay.
I think John Waters off the bolts.
I enjoyed our conversation.
Sometimes these processes work.
What happened?
We had a colleague here who was deeply
offended by what this was deeply
offended.
It was like the Christians to the Lions
Roman time.
It pauses.
You don't see why people think that
because they get deeply offended by
something.
They should be able to change what other
people enjoy or they should be able to
take freedoms away from people.
Especially when you talk about something
that's been already licensed and
regulated by 49 out of 50 states that
this guy could say,
I'm offended and then I feel like this
is like the Christians in Lyons kiss
what dummy.
First of all,
there's two problems with that.
The Christians didn't have a choice and
the fucking lines didn't have a choice
and it was to the death and they didn't
train for it and it wasn't like a huge
dream of theirs and it couldn't be a
hugely profitable career where you can
make Ronda Rousey conor mcgregor type
money and nate diaz money now to our
friend Nate Diaz is rolling in cash now.
Roland balling out of control.
He might not.
He might not fight again.
He might beat his ass again if they
fight and then like take two years off
and he's making millions of dollars or
not be connor's ass.
Who knows,
right?
I mean connor convenient.
Just slap them the way I just had a
feeling going into that fight.
I was like,
this is a big difference.
There's a big difference too,
and Nate Diaz strikes in anybody else
that connor's fought like natives real
slick with his hands.
He's real good at shoulder roll and he's
got a Nasty Jab.
He drops his hands and sneak stuff in on
you.
He knows how to throw punches too with
like minimal minimal wind up.
He knows how to pop hop you and those.
Dang you man.
They fucking.
He dings guys on the Chin like what he
did with Michael Johnson.
I was like,
Ooh,
this is a tough fight.
And he's a tough out.
The only guys ever stopped him is Josh
Thomson had kicked him and when Josh
Thompson had kicked him,
like he's still didn't go out.
He got rocked,
but he's fucking tough man.
I was like,
Ooh.
And if it goes to the ground,
oh,
that's the wrong guy.
Nate Diaz is the wrong guy to go to the
ground with.
He's a legit black belt,
a really high level black belt.
And I knew connor had gotten submitted
by Joe Duffy when anybody can get
submitted if you get caught,
but he got submitted by that Joe Duffy
Guy.
Just a few years ago and Joe Duffy is a
very talented fighter,
no doubt about it,
but nate wouldn't have got submitted by
that same guy.
I highly,
highly,
highly doubt it.
I mean those San Joe's like that,
that level,
like there's a few guys were like,
Ooh,
if you submit that guy like he's only
been submitted in the USC dosantos wants
and that's because he had a broken jaw
and it's clay.
Guido submitted them because clay was on
top of them,
squeeze in his neck and his jaw was
smashed and he realized he was really
fucked and so he tapped.
But like a guy like conor,
if you've been tapped before by Joe
Duffy just a couple of years ago with an
arm triangle,
you get caught like that.
Like you've got a lot to learn and I
don't know if you've learned and all in
time,
like you got to be obsessed with
Jujitsu.
You gotta be in there every day training
and I didn't think he did.
I didn't think he was that.
I thought it was more of a movement and
it's striking and all that stuff.
And I know he was doing some Jujitsu,
but it's not like the primary focus.
So I felt like,
Ooh,
that's a big deepened fucking Jew.
He might knock them out.
I mean connor can knock out anybody,
but he didn't,
you know.
So now that he didn't.
And now that nate knows he didn't,
and now they're going to go into the
second fight and nate's going to have a
full training camp.
Oh,
good luck.
What's the benefit of this second fight
for conor?
Just to.
That's what I thought.
Money outside of that.
Is there any good?
Well,
he could always go down to 1:45
again.
He's still a champion at 1:45,
but the amount of money and Nate Diaz,
conor mcgregor makes conor mcgregor
rematch makes is going to be off the
fucking charts.
Nate Diaz is a superstar and people
didn't realize it until like the Michael
Johnson fight.
People realized it when he was calling
out connor in the in the octagon and
everybody was cheering and also like the
ratings when Nate Diaz,
he's a fuck,
you know,
there was a big thing we're Dana white
had said that he's not a needle mover is
when they were in the middle of contract
negotiations.
The couldn't be further from the truth.
He's a big needle mover.
I Love Dana,
but that's just contract negotiation.
Talk like Nate Diaz.
Maybe he didn't know.
I mean it's possible he didn't know,
but I know because of the Diaz brothers
as far as like my friends that are like
casual mma fans.
The Diaz brothers are fucking huge.
They're huge.
Those guys are giant stars and after
nick like pretended to sleep with
Anderson Silva and like their big talk
mad shit,
they,
they actually can fight.
They fight very good.
I mean they're excellent world class
fighters and they talk mad shit and they
smoke a lot of weed and they mostly eat
vegan.
Like I think nick might be all Vegan.
I think dick still eats like fish,
but I know nate eats fish and I think
they eat eggs to the tortillas and stuff
that's made with eggs and them,
but they're interesting guys.
Man,
they're there.
They're fucking legit,
fascinating people.
So like there's money.
My point is that guy's out of his mind.
This isn't a Christian versus the lions
is a huge support that these guys are
giant
stars.
They make it fucking boatloads of cash.
Ronda Rousey was on the God cover sports
illustrated with one of those paint
things on paint titties.
How's that?
Okay.
Can I pick.
Paint my cock.
I can.
If I pay my cock and I go out there,
is that all right or is it make it look
like an elephant or chicken or
[inaudible]?
There's a line there,
right?
It's like a woman's nipples.
You cannot show a woman's nipples on the
cover of the magazine,
but.
Well,
how come you can show them painted on
like why do we decided to paint on is
okay.
Like when you're looking at.
Right.
There is a naked Ronda rousey with a
fake swimsuit on.
That's so cool.
So like her vagina.
I'm assuming like most girls,
you could see some of it from the front,
right?
Can we spit?
Can we zoom in on the not do that.
Let's be respectful here for her sake.
And for Travis Browne say,
because if he finds you will fucking
kill you.
Oh,
it's a cool thing though.
That's like a cat.
They had to look a cat design.
I didn't notice that.
That's good because at the bottom could
be a hairy chin.
See there they thought about that in
advance.
She had to probably Tuck in some lip.
I'm guessing.
Maybe not,
man.
Maybe she's one of those tidy girls.
I don't know.
Is that rude?
Is it rude to say?
But my point is I'm.
Rhonda knows I love her.
My point is I can do that with my cock.
Oh my God.
That's so cool.
You know what I'm saying?
Like I could wear like I could get a
full on,
hard on and put Lycra on,
put like spandex on and put it online
and people would say I was offensive.
Right.
But it would be okay.
Like that was what the game did.
Do.
Remember that Jamie or rap fan?
I remember that.
He had an instagram posts.
Yeah,
he put an instagram,
but he's a.
he's got a hog.
Like a fuck up police flashlights took a
picture of him standing there with a
fucking boner.
Oh,
they wouldn't even show it in this.
Some of them.
There was one that chose it got in
trouble.
Jesus stopped doing it,
but he's holding onto it and one he's
warming it up.
And then number two is just showing it
there.
I mean,
to be honest,
even as a guy,
that's scary.
He's a large person too.
He's a large human,
so that's like buddy can't fight it is a
video of him a beaten some guy up and
I'm like,
oh dude,
we need to work on some stuff with you.
We need to work on your technique.
I mean,
he could fight,
but he can't.
He doesn't know like how he doesn't know
actual techniques like Katt Williams
fight.
He's not as good as Kat Williams.
Cat defended the choke.
If you notice that when they went to the
ground,
cat never got strangled.
He held on,
he had two on ones.
What you're supposed to do,
and the way he threw that left hand,
I got to say there was zero power behind
and it probably wouldn't knock out my
seven year old,
but there was no fat in this technique.
Like he didn't wind up.
He just uncorked it from here and it was
a straight punch.
He uncorked a very short straight left
hand with a ring onto which is like a
deadly weapon.
When you see the extended
version of the video,
it definitely seems like he was
threatened.
It seemed like that kid was up in his
face.
He followed him for whatever reason.
That's unfortunate.
The kid apparently said,
Kat Williams is funnier,
you know,
whatever.
Why,
why?
You know,
why do people want to do that?
Like,
why is it you want to do that?
It's Worldstar.
That's what it is.
Yeah.
It's got to do them Worldstar hip hop.
We got to play the full version.
So you're,
here we go.
The kid gets this,
use this version.
It looks like he's just fighting with a
kid.
See,
but how come we miss all the other stuff
up until this got very good control?
Actually.
Nope.
Terrible defense.
I'd take it back.
He was already choked out.
He didn't go to the hands.
Oh,
that's not his hands.
He's got one.
Okay.
It doesn't have to on one.
He's not holding the choking army there.
It's called little boy.
Little boy.
And they were playing soccer on a field
or something like that with a looks like
20 people or something like that.
Shirt on.
It doesn't look like a disc.
Imagine that.
That'd be good.
We should photoshop one and all of the
photos with him and then online.
What?
What,
what,
why was he playing soccer with some
kids?
How about why not?
If he wants to be friendly.
I mean Katt Williams is a gigantic star.
The end.
He's just saying he was hanging out with
people in the hood and this is why most
people,
most celebrities don't come and hang out
in the hood.
So he was just hanging out with this.
That's unfortunate.
It looked like there was definitely some
confrontation going on,
but who knows how the fuck has built up
to that and you've got to expect that,
especially if he's involved in sports
playing sports or people put people play
sports,
they talk shit,
you know,
that choke on the subway here in culver
city was way better GC.
That one was better,
but even then why is that guy grabbing
his forearm like that?
Like,
dude,
don't grab like that.
That's not how you do.
I mean someone like that's like some
wrestling type shit,
like a wrestling sleeper hold.
But he did it right.
I mean he,
he squeezed that guy out and he wasn't
a,
he's just a normal guy.
He wasn't like a Jujitsu guy or a fight
or anything like that.
He was just a normal dude.
Dexter Dexter.
No kidding.
Oh,
it does seem weird that that Jujitsu
moves like choking and stuff like that
seems so common now since the UFC a like
you didn't see this shit 20 years ago.
People doing jokes,
but when high school we had a sleeper
hold like because it was on progress
line,
but we didn't think it was real.
You know,
you'd hear about the sleeper.
He's got that slave buyer,
you know,
guys would get guys in a sleeper hold in
a pro wrestling match and then they
would fight it off and fight it off and
eventually would go to sleep and the
ref,
we'd pick their arm up to make sure
they're awake.
You remember that?
Yeah.
That was.
But we didn't think it was real.
Like no one knew that you could really
choke someone out until the UFC came
around.
You can't do that anymore.
In Highschool,
Kenya,
there's no more sleeper.
No,
that was not in wrestling rest.
It was only in pro wrestling.
Like in wrestling,
wrestling.
You couldn't even do a full Nelson
because it puts too much pressure on the
neck.
You could do like a half Nelson,
so if you're trying to pin someone,
what that means is if you were behind
them,
you get an under hook and you go around
the back of their head and you get now
full Nelson is you have both arms and
it's a bad place to be.
It's.
It hurts.
You could push down your neck and they
made that.
They made that illegal when I was in
high school at least.
And so like if you wanted to pin someone
you had to use a half Nelson so he could
never do a fucking sleeper hold,
but there's like some shit they didn't
know about that you can do.
Like Matt Hughes choked out.
Ricardo Almeda with just a front
headlock.
What he did was he held onto the front
head lock.
He had an Matt Hughes is fucking country
strong.
Like there's some dudes that grow up
working from the time they're young like
lifting bales of Hay and learning how to
use their body.
And also he had excellent genetics too
because his brother was built like that
too.
But there's some strength that those
type of guys have like farm strength,
that Shit's no joke,
man.
Like there's a lot of Kettlebell guys
like Pavle Tot souly,
he,
he's got that kind of bill to where it's
like,
you know that if you try to wrestle with
him,
he even though he looks like a fairly
normal size athletes,
probably just stupid fucking strong.
And so Matt Hughes gets his front head,
ca headlock on Ricardo Medo right.
That,
that is a legal wrestling move that's
fucking legal as far as I know,
unless they've changed shit because all
he's doing is grabbing his neck and he's
using his head and his neck to squeeze
the shoulder and arm of Ricardo Almeida
against his neck on one side.
And then he's using his arm and his
shoulder to squeeze the neck on the
other side.
So it's essentially the same thing as a
head and arm choke.
He's just in a different position.
So like he's in the north south position
from a standup,
which means they,
he grabs his head and he pulls him down.
And Matt's.
Matt's got the upper hand is his arm is
wrapped around Ricardo's neck now they
were reversed on the ground.
That position where Ricardo is being
choked is essentially the same as a head
and arm choke,
which is a super common choke and you
finish it the same way with the hand
grip and the same way you get easily
finish it that way.
Some guys grabbed the Bicep,
but the way matt is doing it,
a lot of guys finish it that way so he
would be different like he would be
mounting them where his body would be on
top of his body instead of like in a
north south position,
but it's essentially the same.
Same way you're applying pressure to
choke someone unconscious.
We had never seen that in the UFC before
nor since no one's been able to do it
since.
My point being like there's some
wrestling shit that they still out there
that you could still do,
but guy like Matt,
he choke you out with Mark Schultz.
Got He got kicked out of the Olympics
because he ripped a guy's fucking
shoulder apart with a a move that was
legal at the time.
It was like a Kimora.
He they call a double wrist lock and
catch wrestling,
but if you pull up Mark Schultz,
I forgot the gentleman's name,
the guy wrestled,
I want to say he was from Iran.
Iran has a very strong wrestling
program,
but Mark Schultz was all fucking go real
law when he was competing as he's the
guy that Fox catcher movies based on,
but meanwhile not really based on him.
I mean it is and it isn't.
They played fast and loose with a lot of
facts,
made it look like he was gay and he's
doing coke and he had frosted tips and
all kinds of weird shit in there.
But that move as far as I knew,
he just took it too far or something I
think,
but I think it was an illegal move.
Here it is.
Watch this,
watch what he does.
He drops,
it,
gets to Kamora.
He Yanks it.
A pulls them down.
Just destroys his arm.
Just destroys them.
Yeah,
and the guy's just screaming in agony on
the ground back in the day.
ABC Wide World of sports I think,
wasn't it?
They don't have that shit anymore.
Remember?
Used to get exposed to weird sports.
Yeah.
They would take you to like a javelin
contest.
Like ABC wide world is ports.
They would show you all kinds of
different shit that you'd never seen
before.
Like they had a Minnesota Plat.
Fats play,
Willie Mosconi in a pool match an ABC
wide world of sports.
Like Whoa,
I'm going to show us some cool shit
today.
I saw vr pool demo the other day.
Like that five thing I showed you a
couple of weeks ago.
Someone was made of a full pool game
where you're walking around a pool hall
and a you can set up,
you can set up a bunch of trick shots
with looks.
It looks a little gaming,
but you can have like beer bottles and
whatnot on the table and shoot your pool
balls right through the bottles and.
Huh?
I saw at best buy there's this new
camera out that's only like $400,
but it's a three 60 camera,
which so you could just put it right
here and it records everything around
it.
Have you seen this,
Jamie?
I don't know if it's good or not,
but uh,
that's kind of interesting.
It is interesting.
I mean it's just a matter of time.
Whoa.
This is bizarre.
Also,
it's showing you the angles and stuff
so you can just walk around if you want
the English you can,
but everything in the whole room is
available at the touch apparently or a
certain extent.
That's cool.
Let's set up ramps.
Well,
what will be really interesting is if
you could somehow set this up with other
people and have virtual balls,
but the problem is you wouldn't feel the
ball,
like the whole idea pool,
like see what they're doing is just
showing the shots,
like landing the shots,
but with pulls really all about is
controlling the rotation of the ball and
cue ball control.
There's a little feedback,
a little bit of touching yet,
but if I don't know if they could make
it feel to say never.
You would
need wait.
Yeah,
like what?
What pool is,
is like a,
there's a big thing about it is the
weight of the queue.
Like um,
guys will change their weight just a
little bit and they feel it in a big
way.
Like they'll go from a 19 point one
ounce q,
two in 19 point three and they're like,
man,
I'm over stroking this ball.
I got to back off.
Like we were talking about like two
tenths of an ounce and it's a big
difference in the way it feels.
Or if you go from like one ounce,
one ounce is giant,
you go from a 19 to a 20,
holy shit.
That's a big difference for people.
You would think like one ounce,
like how,
how would you even notice you hold it in
your hand after a you wouldn't even
notice right
now.
You notice notice in a big way.
So that's.
I don't know if that would work,
but some shit would work on.
I think once they figured out how to do
like some sort of a neurological input
thing,
then you're going to be able to play on
a computer.
You're gonna be able to feel the keys,
you're going to be able to like if you
pull vault,
you'd be able to feel the poll.
It will be able to feel the breeze as
you go launching through the air.
All that stuff's gonna happen.
Video game version of you on UFC two is
so creepy.
Awesome that I love it and it just the
idea of.
Imagine taking that version of you by
mixing the podcasts with it.
You probably could do something like
that.
It'd be so real.
Well,
I know why I did that.
I got out of doing more commentary to do
that.
Commentary is a commentary and a video
game is painstaking and it's one of the
easiest thing.
See,
that's me from my new ketogenic diet.
I'm all shredded now.
I'm the a guy that beat every single
player using you.
That's two hours sitting while talking
like doing like a podcast while he's
playing you.
That's hilarious.
So cool.
And it's real like you hid that from all
of us to like none of us knew about
that.
No,
I didn't tell anybody I was supposed to
be quiet about it.
So I had to take off my clothes and put
shorts on and then they,
um,
they spin it like,
you,
you stand totally still and you have to
go through a series of poses.
And so like,
uh,
like your hold your arms out like that.
You'll hold your arms out like that.
You do certain movements.
I don't think I had a kick.
I don't think I had to throw any kicks.
I'm trying to remember now.
But your kick in the game looks like
you're kicked.
It looks good.
It looks pretty real.
It looks all well they did the
techniques.
They've all analyze the techniques for
like,
like did Jujitsu techniques.
They're all super good.
The wrestling techniques,
boxing and kicking.
It's all like really good fundamentals.
Like everybody,
even guys who have like wonky
fundamentals in this game,
their fundamentals are really good.
They did such a good job also of really
making the experience this time around.
Like just like the ring girls walking in
the background,
just like everything.
It's like creepy.
How good they did a creeping the live
experience.
It's getting better and better.
They're getting so good at this shit,
you know,
they're,
they're getting close to what they call
that uncanny valley.
The crossing that uncanny valley.
That's,
that,
uh,
that's an expression that someone came
up with the difference between
artificial videos and videos of like
this and three d video games and then
real people like when I did that,
a Scifi show,
the questions,
everything show we went to Nvidia and we
saw the latest in their ability to
recreate a person's face and they still
had problems with,
um,
with tongues.
Tongues were a big one and hair and some
hair.
Just an eyes like eyeballs where your
eyeball connects to your eyelashes and
your eyelid.
That looked a little funky.
But everything else,
man,
they'd still,
he did it with a bald guy and a fuck
dude.
It's fucking crazy.
When you look at it,
you're like,
that's not a real guy.
Wow.
Like,
it's so close.
They're so close.
They're like knocking on this door where
they're going to be able to recreate
things and you're not going to be able
to know whether or not you're watching
something that's completely computer
generated or something that's real,
and they did something recently that I
tweeted a couple of days ago or maybe
yesterday where this guy superimposed
his facial expressions on George Bush
and so like he got,
he said things to put words in a George
Bush's mouth at George Bush.
Never said so they show the video.
That's cool.
Yeah.
It's so awesome.
It's creepy,
dude.
We were not going to know.
We're so close.
That's probably already happened.
He 100 percent.
Right?
Like blurry shit.
You're just not going to know.
You're just not going to know what's
real and what's fake.
You just won't know.
Yeah.
There's going to have to be like seals
of approval or something like that.
That's like we're saying that this is
real editor is going to be.
Videos are going to be like stories,
so you're not going to know whether you
told me some crazy story.
I'm not going to know whether or not
it's real.
I'm like,
all right,
you say so that's what a video is going
to be like.
Like you're watching this video of
George Bush.
It's going to be like someone telling
you a story about being abducted by a
Ufo.
Alright,
where's your proof?
Well,
I'll show you the video,
right?
Everyone's going to like,
get out of here.
What your fucking video.
That video can be fake as hell.
You could have made that on your phone
with the face swap APP and shit that's
on the phone that even.
That shit's crazy.
And that's just a little stupid program.
How about the ones when they put tongues
on people like us doing this,
that is so crazy and he's obviously
exaggerating.
He's making like big smiles and weird
side decide motions with his face just
to show that they could do that.
But I guess how it works is they take a.
yeah,
all they're showing it right here.
They take a three dimensional moving
video of this guy's face.
And um,
as he's moving around,
they take a three dimensional image of
the other person's face and they map out
where his mouth is.
And what the shape of his mouth is and
they just have that guy's mouth do the
movements of the other guy is just
crazy.
Cool.
The smiles are off though.
If you see like Putin smile like Donald
Trump's looks fake as fuck because he's
got such a weird mouth.
Like his range of motion in his mouth is
like an old lady trying to do the
splits.
You know what I mean?
In his mouth doesn't move very much.
He's got a small mouth.
Donald trump.
What a crazy technology.
It's nuts.
Well,
they did this with Reagan way back in
the day with audio.
There was a thing where someone had
taken a series of Ronald Reagan's
speeches,
remember that?
And they edited the audio to show the
know for Ronald Reagan to make some
ridiculous statement.
I forgot all about that old school.
It was old school and they played it on
tv and we're like,
whoa.
I remember watching that going well
Nancy remix,
Ronald Reagan's speech went viral years
before Internet memes and that was a
long ass time ago.
You know what else went viral?
Richard Gere in the Journal Story.
That's the real viral treatment.
Taco Bell,
I don't know what that one is that
people come,
they come in,
it's somebody eight come from a Taco
Bell Burrito or something like that.
Did I guarantee that happened?
But the Richard Gere durable thing was a
much better example because it's a story
that Eddie Bravo heard.
He grew up in California.
I grew up.
I heard it in Boston.
We heard on the other side of the
country.
I mean this,
this fucking store.
Everybody knew you heard it right?
I almost think it was a Howard stern
thing,
was the scientology thing.
Supposedly.
That's the rumor.
The rumor was Richard Gere and left
scientology.
Scientology decided to fucking drag them
through the mud.
Wow.
Yeah.
Well,
I think scientology does not like it
when you leave and that's why people
stay like the people that have left.
They fucking go after you,
man.
They go after you hard and the people
that that do leave,
most of the time they just shut the fuck
up,
but the people that have left that have
talked shit about them.
Whoa,
wait outside your house to fucking make
noise.
They'll follow you around like those
videos of um,
these guys getting harassed that were
former scientologist and now the
scientology crew showed up at their
house and they filmed these people.
They don't understand like how creepy
that is to us watching that,
like,
what you win me,
you can't leave,
like you can't quit and if you do quit
you,
you can't talk about what happened.
Like what are you guys doing?
Like,
what are you guys doing that we can't
talk about this?
Like what kind of nuttiness do you
really have kids working for fucking $3
an hour and you make them work 16 hours
a day and you have like,
like that guys was his niece or
something like that.
Uh,
David miscavige guy like one of,
one of his relatives released book and
she's talking about how fucking crazy it
as growing up in this environment.
Like you can't talk about that.
Well,
as soon as you can't talk about
something,
you know you've got a real problem
because you can talk about being a
baptist.
You could,
you could talk all day about growing up
in a Baptist church.
No,
but nobody's going to fucking come after
you because they're not doing anything
crazy.
You know what I mean?
I mean,
even though it's a religion to you,
as soon as you can't talk about what you
guys are doing,
like you can't.
Someone can't complain about what you're
doing.
I mean think about that.
Applied to the Catholic church,
you know,
it's uh,
it seems like that day's coming though
when that shit gets exposed to being
something cosby,
like we're going to find way more about
scientology or Tom Cruise or any of
these,
all these people maybe.
Um,
I mean think,
I think it's definitely gonna be harder
for them to get people to listen.
You know,
it used to be easy.
You just,
before the Internet,
you just had to have like a bunch of
successful people that are part of a
group that were really friendly and you
want it to be a part of it.
You wanted to get in there with them and
the next thing you know,
you have thousands and thousands of
members.
It wasn't,
it wasn't hard to do back then.
But now like you don't have to wait
until you're 10 years in,
find out about the fetus and the fucking
planet,
where the bodies are,
are they fucking drop them into the
volcano and they're frozen or whatever.
Like if you read the actual story that l
Ron Hubbard wrote as detailed in,
um,
in that going clear moving where the guy
first read it and he was like,
what in the fuck is this?
You can get that now.
So it's harder to get people to join now
with something like totally wacky.
But there's some other shit.
Like,
what is landmark?
People keep telling me,
this landmark you've ever heard of
landmark theaters?
No.
Jesus Christ.
Jamie just hanging out with him.
No,
there's some,
there's some fucking,
some sort of a cult.
Is it,
am I saying the name wrong?
Mark?
There's like a,
there's another type of social group
that a bunch of people were tweeting me
St ever seen the Robin Quivers,
isn't it the landmark forum?
Yes,
that's it.
And people are saying that this is some
sort of
cult.
Is that bullshit?
Like what is it?
Some self help thing,
is that what it is?
It's just a message board.
No form is a large group awareness
training program in which a hundred up
to 150 people take a seminar together
aimed at helping them realize their true
potential.
That sounds like something.
Yeah,
sounds like one of those self help
guru things,
which may be okay.
I mean,
are any of those legit.
I mean Anthony Robbins is pretty fucking
legit,
right?
I mean people have used as principals
and they've gotten ahead and that guy
has been around forever.
So if he was a total bullshit act
creeper,
you know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
You would have heard about it by now
maybe.
Wow.
I mean look at Bill Cosby,
like maybe it was like a way less level
creeper,
just like just just gives massages to be
appropriately.
It doesn't take it any further than
that.
But Guy,
he's just a foot back.
He just gives like an unannounced back
rubs.
Just shows up,
starts rubbing your back.
And there was like,
um.
Does he go any further that?
Nope.
He just gives you the weird back rub and
that's it.
You know what's weird is when I.
I got this watch,
I got the Apple Watch and when you're
setting it up it says male,
female or other and I like that.
Welcome to the new world.
That could be another.
I'm a fox kin.
Is it on there?
Because if it's not,
I'm fucking complaining.
I'm going to sue apple and Foxconn.
What's Foxconn?
Spirit animal.
My spirit animal is a Fox.
There was a guy who fucking got his
license at the DMV in Portland and they
let him wear a Fox hat,
like a fake,
like Fox,
like a,
like,
like a furry wood where we had like,
no,
like he had like a Fox eyeballs for
like,
look,
there's a photo.
See if you could find the photo of him
at the DMV getting his fucking
photograph.
And everybody's like,
well that's ridiculous.
Is it?
Is it any more ridiculous than.
What's that thing that Muslim women
wearing head.
Good job.
Yeah.
Look at this guy.
This guy.
Wow.
Fucking Fox at.
Ah,
what's his name?
Edgard Campuzano.
Is that his name?
Down there.
Yup.
No,
that's the guy who wrote the story.
How they was the gentleman's name.
We need to give him props.
What's his name?
Just as Portland,
man.
Come on,
Says Bishop Bishop Bishop,
what's his name to his bishop?
Said his name is bishop.
Oh really?
It goes by bishop.
Oh,
okay.
Well that's good.
Even better.
It's one day.
He's like Oprah.
His name was bishop.
Pull it up so you can see the photo.
Do you think that's just his girlfriend
worked at the DMV?
I bet that's more about.
Well,
it took time to grow that beard.
Look at that beard.
He's got it.
That's a weird,
funny Fu Manchu style.
Long,
long like goat beard.
You know,
he's got one of those like,
uh,
have you ever seen a Turkey beard?
Turkeys have this weird thing.
They grow out of the middle of their
chest is like this long beard.
It looks like some.
And the longer it is,
the older the Turkey is.
So it becomes like a,
I guess a part of the way they struck.
They were that big Turkey things weird.
Um,
so that's like they let the other
Turkey,
no bitch,
I been around,
look at all these fucking metals.
I got Leno,
like as it grows,
that's what that guy has got,
got grown off his chin.
So it's highly possible.
He's out of his fucking mind that,
that dude looks like the Oregon,
Oregon people look like kind of like the
Oregon state bird almost.
Well,
why shouldn't I be able to live a little
able to wear that Fox hat because it was
a girl at south south by southwest who
was a fencer.
She's a competitive fencer and she
wanted to wear a full head garb and the
photos and they were like,
no,
you have to take that off.
And so south by southwest had to
apologize because they asked her to take
her religious clothing off.
Well,
this guy should go to south by southwest
where it's fucking Fox hat.
We should all do that because it's all
ridiculous.
It's all ridiculous.
Like any clothing that you have to wear
and you have to take your photos with
that clothing in order for you to be
free,
like the eastern religions made up.
Okay,
so any clothing that you wear,
any like fanatical garb that you wear
when you go somewhere that's made up?
Shit.
So if that's made up shit,
you should be able to say you're Fox
can.
You should be able to say you should
feel aware octopus on your head.
Everywhere you go.
There are reasons you're not supposed to
have anything on your head because
you're.
You have to see what you look like with
no,
you know what you look like normal,
like base.
So if we're looking for you,
we know your security.
There's a reason why you have an idea in
the first place because there's a lot of
people like if you put on like a face
mask,
like a skier,
where's where it's like it shows you a,
like from the eyebrows up is covered and
from the mouth down is covered.
Fuck man.
You could be a million different people.
It's so hard to tell who you are without
seeing your whole face,
the shape of your head,
the color of your hair,
the whole deal.
There's a lot of people that look
fucking similar as hell and so to have
an id in the law allow someone to wear
some really elaborate costume where your
most of your heads covered and you say
you do it because of your religion.
Like,
no,
like they're apologizing to her because
of the wacky rules that she follows.
Don't allow you to show your head like,
get the fuck Outta here.
It's 2016 folks.
I mean,
come on.
What point in time?
Like the religious tolerance,
it's so important.
Religious tolerance.
It's we have to be tolerant.
Unless they're Christian,
their Christian,
you could shit right in their mouth and
you could make the sign of the cross
with your shit on their forehead and no
one cares.
Like that's the one religion where it's
totally okay to mock openly and make fun
of nobody because you think you're a
goof ball.
But if you wanted to walk into a south
by southwest with a,
uh,
a pope hat on because you said that's
part of your religion.
I'm pope and training and I'm really low
level right now.
But uh,
I'm just going to stick,
you know,
like you are what you believe you are.
So I'm just going to wear this
everywhere.
I'm gonna.
Wear a giant with a fish head one.
The big one where it looks like an open
mouth.
A fish mouth.
No,
we need tolerance.
We need Tawana's appeal though.
He got to keep his head.
Yes,
he should be.
He totally shaved.
He should get to keep it.
And that's why I'm going to.
I'm gonna wear a Bandana.
Like pirate.
I'm going to say I'm a,
I'm a pirate.
Light weight.
I'm tired as fuck.
I'm going to wear.
My pirate is fuck a caveman coffee tea
tee shirt.
Did you see the whole Kogan was the only
guy to win a court case with a do rag on
in court.
Excellent.
You made him a classy.
The Black Bandanna to go with is a black
suit.
I thought it was a classy look.
And I'm a big fan of his.
Now they want $150.
Million plus if you want another 25
million.
See that?
Yeah,
they're on top of the post was at
Gawker.
Was I going out of business now?
How we're cheering,
what I thought would they have unlimited
money?
Just being dicks to guy making videos
has to pay $10 million or something of
his own money.
Yeah,
but he's like super rich.
Apparently it's going to cost them 10
million bucks,
but he's got like $100 million.
The whole thing's hilarious.
His hair cut is so awesome.
Look for him like this is a win win.
I mean this guy's.
He's theater hulk.
Hogan is theater.
Everything is theater.
Did you hear the part?
And as that are in the questioning about
is a 10 inch penis that he said his hogs
not as big as the games.
The game,
the game doesn't even have to go to
court.
It's like look bitch know how big my
dick is.
A fake Dick.
The only thing they could do is they'd
have to have some sort of a deposition
with pulled it out,
shows you.
But he might be a shower and not a grow
or a grower and not a shower.
So like he might have to get worked up
to prove it or you're completely right
or it's just fake.
He just grabbed some girls Dildo,
put it in his shorts,
take a photo just to make everyone go
home and go to the copy.
You have a ticket.
I've done.
Seems connected.
Well that's you though.
You got to understand your unusual and
it's not.
It's connected.
Like is the Dick is connected to them.
Like if you look at it,
it's obviously like it doesn't look like
a.
If it was a Dildo,
there'd be like a dropoff point at the
base and you're like,
wait a minute.
How exactly is this thing attached?
You know what I'm saying?
What they have,
the ones that you stick onto the side of
the wall of the shower maybe just went
like on his.
Should be.
Could be like he talked,
he talked and had that one too.
But even if he stuck it in,
it would be going forward.
It wouldn't be off to the side like
that.
When you have spandex,
he probably just put it to the side.
It's one of those long double ended.
Once you know that the long snake one,
it's not connected though.
I.
Look,
I,
I stared at his dick.
Very careful and from what I'm seeing,
it's a real dick.
And it goes with his body.
You know what I'm saying?
It's not like Tony Hinchcliffe as a
fucking oatmeal box in his pants.
So that's quaker oats box.
Somebody had the expression for it.
Somebody had that description I thought
was the funniest description ever.
Quaker oats box for a dick.
Well,
who is,
he's holding it even looks like him.
This is another one that's even faker.
Um,
no.
That looks like he's fully hard to deck
guys.
Giant.
It's got a giant Dick.
Come on,
sign.
You know that Shit's real.
You want it to be real?
No,
I'd want.
I'm scared.
She,
that could just be.
Oh,
look how he's got marijuana leaf
tattooed right above his dick.
Like,
what's that supposed to mean?
Smoke it,
smoke it.
If he got all the hashtags he has on
there on his body will change your life.
Drops.
Mike.
Restructure your day.
This dick can keep them edges slicked
down.
This dick can file your nails.
This dick.
This tongue will make you late for work.
Wait,
this dick can be your best friend.
This dick console and bundles.
I'm not sure what that means.
If you can.
I'll eat a pussy.
You can take the whole thing.
Can you not?
If you can't,
only Hashtag.
If you can eat your pussy.
I'm till scandal.
Comes back on next week and what the
fuck?
He's funny.
Dick.
Game strong.
I love that.
I love this world.
Somebody
figured out a way to distribute
information through fucking pipes and a
numbers.
It's decoded back into letters,
ones and Zeros and this is what it came
to.
Hashtag Dick.
Game strong.
That's been used for.
It's being used for.
Oh God,
what a beautiful world.
I love how communication has churned
like into animated gifts and hashtags
and it's amazing.
It's so funny.
We live in funny times,
man.
It's funny,
like the amount of funding that we get
in a daily basis is like way higher than
when we were kids.
Like just all these hilarious animated
gifs.
Anytime anything goes wrong or anything
happens in the world,
these fucking things are hilarious and
most of them would be made by regular
folks.
Have a funny idea.
They're not being made by professionals,
which kind of shows you what we have
said all along.
It's just a lot of funny people out
there that don't ever do anything about
it.
You know,
they don't ever become like,
look,
Eddie Bravo is one of the funniest
fucking people I've ever met in my life.
He's hilarious.
But until he started doing our podcast,
most people just knew him as a Jujitsu
instructor.
I'm like,
Eddie Bravo is fucking funny.
Like standup comedian.
Funny.
But he was built.
He was busy with a bunch of other shit
and never pursued it,
but he actually did a couple of times.
I remember he.
I thought I heard he was pretty good.
He did well a few times.
He did like he had nine sets.
He did nine times and I was nine times.
A few of them were like the Hindenburg.
A few of them were like,
he just wanted to just quit life.
They were bad.
A few of them were bad,
it just didn't work,
but a few of them were funny man.
There was a few of them that were really
funny and then there was other ones that
were like a little a mix,
a mix of like really funny and some
stuff that didn't work,
but man,
it's like everything else in this world,
it seems way easier than it is.
It just does.
Like you look at bowling.
Okay.
Just grabbed that stupid ball and roll
it.
How hard could that be?
Obviously it's hard because you know
they have pros like they have
tournaments,
they play on tv,
they roll the ball better than the other
people rolled the ball.
Just like subtle nuances.
They will.
They have special shoes.
They slide when they released the ball,
they have gloves and they spin the ball
as they release it and they wanted to
hit that front pin.
That's perfect way and it seems so
fucking easy if you're outside looking
in the outside in,
at bowling you but shit,
I can fucking do that.
But if you've never bowled in your life
and you go out and try it,
Holy Shit,
are you going to be bad?
Right.
Same thing with everything,
man.
Everything you name it it all things
that look easy.
Like that fucking gay guy talking about
gay porn with a different ending.
Do you think his speeches are.
That's not easy.
Like what that guy's doing the way he's
doing it,
even though it's silly and gay and he's
got jokes thrown in there.
Like it's fucking delivery is pretty
goddamn smooth.
It's pretty funny.
That's funny.
Like,
and he knows what he's doing.
Like he how he's being perceived.
He's adjusting.
He's pausing in the right way.
He's saying it the right way.
You take the average person,
you make him stand up and give a speech
about mma in front of a bunch of other
people in suits in some room like that
and it's going to suck.
He's got a built in joke though.
Everybody knows he's gay.
Like all he has to do is talk about guys
being hot.
Like they'll do that to disarm the
situation.
Like gay guys have that built in thing.
They can always talk about guys being
hot.
Well,
it's very hard for me to concentrate up
here with all these hot guys in the
room.
Like he'd say things like that and then
boom,
they break the ice and people start
laughing.
So there's,
there's that.
But it ain't easy man.
So Eddie tried it and it just was too
much time.
He was busy with his music.
He's busy teaching.
He's busy competing at the time.
He still competing so he quit.
He didn't wanna do it anymore because it
was right around the time when he fought
and fought and Abu Dhabi,
it was right around when I was trying it
out,
but he could do it.
Especially now because he's been
teaching for so long.
He's getting really comfortable with
talking in front of people and in his
classes.
He's really funny.
Like sometimes in his classes he'll say
hilarious shit.
Just not planned out.
Not Jokes he wrote,
he'll just,
something will come up and he'll say
something or you know,
sometimes it's like his classes are
hilarious.
Like one time he came in,
he was talking about some Ufo
documentary that he saw me.
He said,
oh,
Jesus stopped with the chem trails.
It was talking about Kim Charles the
other day.
It still know he's still doing.
They some new documentary documents that
they're approving over La.
They were putting spraying over the last
couple of months told you that they've
never not admitted to to doing it.
But hold on a second.
Here's the difference.
What they have admitted to and what they
do.
We talked about this before.
What they do an Abu Dhabi on a regular
basis is they do cloud seeding.
Yeah.
Cloud seeding is absolutely real.
And what they do is they figure out how
to make it rain and they spray some sort
of silver iodine.
Is that what it is?
Find out what the fuck they spray to
reflect it.
No,
no,
no.
That's the,
I don't know,
hockey shit.
The uh,
the silver stuff somehow or another,
when you spray it in the air,
it coalesces.
That's the wrong word.
It somehow or another attracts these
clouds to form and that you can make it
rain.
And Abi Dhabi,
they've made it rain once a week for a
year.
They make it rain there like once a week
they just fucking spray the Scott and
the desert,
silver iodide potassium iodide.
That's it.
Which by the way is absolutely a
different substance than what these
people are claiming is in these chem
trails.
That was the problem with doing that
show.
Like that Joe Rogan questions.
Everything show like the people have
some shit in their head and they don't,
they,
they just.
This is what they believe.
It's locked in there and they don't want
to accept other information.
Like this one guy that made this
documentary on chem trails,
I mean he had made two documentaries on
chem trails and he said he had evidence.
He had evidence.
We have tested the water and the water
shows high levels of aluminum.
Like why is there aluminum in the Wa?
Well,
it turns out,
first of all,
that dirt all across the world has
aluminum in it.
It's really common.
It's one of the most common things
you'll find like as far as like a
metals,
like it's super common for aluminum to
be in the ground.
That's how they get aluminum.
Okay.
It's in the ground.
It's all over the place.
And when this guy showed me his
paperwork,
he's like,
I'll show you the tests.
He hands me this paper and I.
and it says sludge.
So I said,
well why is this a sludge?
And he goes,
I don't know,
but I gave them water.
I go,
but that's not what it says at the lab.
They tested it and they said it's
sludge.
So what is sludge?
And he goes,
well I don't know what his slides.
Well let's Google it.
Sludge I think is water mixed with shit
and water and dirt.
That's what sledges.
So I go,
okay,
so you admit that dirt has aluminum in
it,
right?
Yes,
I know that.
Okay.
But this water did not have dirty,
but it says sludge,
which means water and dirt.
So your water and dirt tested positive
for water and dirt.
Like that's what happened.
Like your sludge tested positive for
being dirt.
That's it.
Did you.
You didn't prove that they're spraying
shit in the air like this is crazy.
Not only that,
if they sprayed shit in the air,
it would look different than fucking
clouds.
Like what a cloud is is moisture here
moisture and when you have a certain
amount of condensation in the air and
you send those fucking jet engines
through it,
it spirals and it's got all this massive
power and heat and it changes the
temperature of the air in those funnels,
those tubes,
it creates artificial clouds like,
I'm not making this up.
This is all science.
Like the scientists have figured this
out fucking decades and decades ago.
This is like this is a beaten into the
ground subject.
They absolutely know that you can do
that is this is 100 percent proven that
you can send a jet engine to certain
levels of condensation and people are
like,
well,
how come she turns on and turns off?
What?
Look up in the sky.
Do you ever notice that clouds aren't
uniform across the entire sky?
You know why?
Because moisture's not uniform across
the entire sky,
just like you'll be fucking driving and
it'll be raining in one area and he'd
drive to another area and you could pass
through an area where it's not raining
and into a new area.
It's raining again.
You're laughing.
Oh my God.
We drove from the rainy part into the
fucking drug part.
You can do that.
Everybody knows you can do that.
So why would you not assume that the air
in the sky would be very similar?
Sometimes.
Sometimes it's not.
Sometimes it is like this is.
This is a dumb theory,
like there's a lot of fucking conspiracy
theories that everybody should look into
is a lot of them that are legit as fuck.
There's a lot of false flags.
There's a lot of lying to the American
people.
The fucking Gulf of Tonkin that got us
into Vietnam's based on bullshit and
operation northwoods hundred percent
bullshit and lies all the shit that
fucking William Randolph hearst did to
get marijuana illegal in the reefer
madness.
There's a lot of real life conspiracies,
but as soon as you start believe in
something and you're unwilling to accept
evidence that you might be wrong,
it becomes a fucking problem and people
get mad at me on twitter like,
Bro,
look at this youtube documentary.
Look at it,
you do it.
It doesn't mean people haven't sprayed
shit in the sky before folks,
but when you're looking at those goddamn
trails that happened behind jets,
that is normal.
That is just what happens when you fly a
jet through the atmosphere and that's
not.
People should be worried about the
fucking jet fuel.
That's what they should be worried
about.
Everybody that lives around airports,
they all get like high rates of
respiratory illness.
This was just like a real scandal there.
That's the the real scandal.
If you live near an airport,
you're breeding that fucking burning jet
fuel.
If you work at an airport,
if you wanted those baggage handlers,
one of those dudes is on the strip every
day.
Fuck man.
What are you breathing in every day?
Like that's a real.
Like there's real health concerns there.
Do you know what?
How,
how?
what a big deal it would be if we really
found out the government was spraying
stuff and the sky above us and for what
reason?
What are they doing?
Is it mind control?
Because it's not working is to try to
make everybody ill.
That's not working either.
Topics so much doors.
Me and adorable subject.
It's adorable.
You know we're going to find out the
planes that crashed into the World Trade
Center,
work a crop dusting at the timer,
doing chem trails.
There's something that'd be funny if we
combine conspiracy to do this.
People who don't even believe they're
real plain.
Yeah.
I know.
There's people who think that those were
holograms and then they'll show you in
video.
Look,
you can see there's a pixelation on the
left wing people.
Their brains are broken man and it's
because they're not getting any
postings.
That's kind of a good point.
Where you guys are talking about just a
little bit ago,
like video at some point won't be enough
evidence for proof.
Well,
I think it's right now.
I think it's real close.
I think rule right now we're looking at
some normal shit that's showing us and
Youtube ads,
but in the darkest halls of justice,
who knows what foot governments
government back in the Justice League of
America,
fucking Superhero compounds and Xavier
President of Xavier or Professor Xavier,
I think the highest levels of all this
stuff like,
you know,
like that magic leap shit.
Like we're,
we're looking at what they release and
we're watching these little videos
they're putting out and it looks cool
and everything like that.
But we're,
we're just,
we're getting the consumer version of
the report,
like the people that are working on it
at the highest level where you have to
go to their office and sign
nondisclosures and shit like that.
Like,
like I went to um,
the nvidia offices.
And when you go in there and they show
you all your stuff,
you can't,
you're not supposed to.
Like,
you can't like take videos of it other
than the,
they allow you to,
they'll show you some stuff,
but they released their stuff very
carefully.
You can't give out the specifications of
how they make their things.
And because it's all,
there's a big technology,
race is constantly on,
you just get assigned non disclosures
for any of these things.
Now when you do,
um,
motion capture for a video game or any
of those,
those things to people,
they make you sign all this paperwork
and shit.
It ain't that easy.
So the people that are at the highest
level of creating the CGI effects,
we have no idea like how good they are
right now.
They're,
they get better every year.
So like if we go to like one of them,
CGI labs does shit for movies and see
how good that stuff looks better to blow
you away.
Yeah,
I'm sure it's been happening for awhile.
I was,
I'm sure there's shit that we don't know
about.
We'll think about the movies that come
out.
Right.
Those fucking movies like Jurassic Park,
the new Jurassic Park,
which was insane.
It wasn't a good movie.
It was kind of goofy movie,
but it was an insane showcase for like
full state of the art,
Cgi Shit that's available right now.
Like the dinosaurs looked incredible
like that took like how long I think to
make over a year.
I'm sure.
So that's the technology that was
available when they first started doing
that project.
So like what is,
whatever it is,
two years ago,
let's say two years ago,
what can they do now?
What can they do in five years?
I go to this,
we're showing us.
Jamie's popped off.
This is called the climb.
It's a mountain climbing.
Oh,
that thing.
Oh my God.
You no hands your arms.
Yeah,
just have hands it shows you.
But the way that they've,
the scale on what you see when you get
up to like climbing the top of the
mountains and the amount of detail they
put in here so you can like put your
face all the way up to your hand and see
the stitches in the gloves.
They look,
it looks.
I saw a little more of an explanation on
it,
but uh,
it seems like why would I want to do
that for fun?
Well,
I've watched those youtube videos was
crazy Russian dudes that do cartwheels
on rooftops and there's so many of those
guys.
Yeah,
that one guy,
James Kingston.
I think he's scary.
Oh,
he's terrifying.
Been top the top of the tallest building
and was just climbing on a crane and
doing handstands for fun.
Well,
he also does leaps.
He'll lead from the top of one building
to the other,
uh,
key showed one.
He's still in the corner of this
building and leaped across the street
and landed on another building.
Like these guys are serious fucking
athletes because even the ways landing
like he's,
he's like stiff legged it,
like planted himself.
He does not he shit man.
But Hey,
we're talking about how long for that
guy becomes Jello one day.
Right?
So he's looking across here.
He's going to jump all the way there.
He climbed that thing.
Oh Dude,
why?
Oh my God,
I can't do it.
this guy's out of his mind.
So,
uh,
James Kingston.
And what's the name of the video?
People want to watch this.
That's same gap to off 150
meter high south tower.
Christian jumping.
Where's he jumping?
Jumping from here.
Come on.
No,
no,
no.
He's not going to.
Oh my God.
He's going to jump.
What do you going?
What is he going to do here?
I can't watch this.
Theater.
Sweat.
There's some new drones that just came
out recently that you're going to be
able to make some way cooler videos and
he's making now.
Even he's.
He's takes his fucking shirt off while
he's up there folks.
It's going to leave it up there and he
tucked it just so everybody knows.
It's up there forever.
Everybody knows he was really there.
If you want to go up there and retrieve
his shirt,
go get it.
No,
he's not going to jump over to that.
Another thing.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
He's hanging.
Fuck Jesus Christ.
Dude.
Oh my God.
This guy's out of his fucking mind.
This is so hard to watch.
It's so hard.
It's so hard to watch when you're not
there.
Facebook here is this facebook,
James l Kingston.
He's out of his mind.
Man.
That dude's out of his fucking mind,
but that's how we're talking about.
Just like Alex honnold.
What?
What's.
Oh,
it's differ.
Hopefully he's getting paid for it.
It's different.
I guess.
I don't know.
I think what he's both equally crazy.
First of all,
what he's doing is illegal with Alex
honnold does is a sport young Jamie.
I know what Alex does is pretty nice
too,
but you know,
the climbing dudes like the hardcore
climbing guys,
they fall into one or two camps when it
comes to Alex.
either they revere him or they,
uh,
they think he's a real problem and they
think he's going to die.
Like there was this one documentary they
did about a more,
uh,
one of those pieces that he did about
them were,
they talked this one old school climber
who uses ropes and the whole deal and
he's like,
it's not a matter of if he's going to
die,
it's a matter of when.
And the guy was just like being a real
negative about it,
which I don't understand is because when
I watch a guy like Alex Honnold,
I say obviously he knows what the fuck
he's doing.
He's doing it all the time and he
continues to do it all the time.
So why do you assume that one day he's
going to have a mental lapse and not be
able to do it?
Well,
he can do it.
Is he doing it?
He's doing it right.
He's doing it okay.
Well if he's doing it,
he can continue to do it.
The less his handbrakes unless he gets
old,
unless he stops working out.
I mean why,
why is he not going to be able to do it?
Well one day he's going to fall like
what are you hex in him and putting the
fucking the Kibosh on him.
What are you doing?
You know,
you don't know he's going to fall like
what he's doing is very dangerous.
But he might do it forever.
He might be able to do it until he's 80
and then quit.
He might know what he's doing.
You know?
I mean,
he goes over those courses with a rope
first,
he knows he's got a path,
like he doesn't just climb something and
hope he could figure out how to get up.
He goes through these things with ropes
first and then once he goes through the
things with ropes,
he sees his path,
he marks it and it goes even even still,
I guess what?
Why
are they think it's bad that he might
die doing it because it shows other
people that on a bad path to take on
exactly the reason why they think it's
so bad.
Well then we should stop having Nascar.
Yeah,
for sure.
Things you can do that will kill you
that aren't even that dangerous.
Yeah.
I was watching a girl yesterday on the
fucking highway at night wearing
sunglasses,
scrolling through her facebook in the
law in the left lane.
The far left lane,
people were honking.
Is there a passenger?
She didn't give a fuck.
She's fat.
She's probably eating while she was
driving to big fat face.
Looking down at her phone,
scrolling through her pictures,
just careless,
careless American,
just to everything that would be people.
If they're wanting to mock America,
this,
she's probably looking at Kim
Kardashians.
Instagram,
she had sunglasses on.
She's driving,
were their big overfed face and she's
scrolling through putting everyone
around her in danger because she's
barely paying attention and she's doing
the scroll lean.
Here's something that people don't
realize when they're scrolling,
if they have their hand on the steering
wheel and they have their phone,
they do this where they lean over
towards their phone.
So like if you look at her from behind,
uh,
the first thing I saw,
I'm like,
why is this bitch gone 60 miles an hour?
I look it over and because everybody
else was flying by and left and I'm
right and she's in the left lane.
She's,
you see the glow from her phone,
which is a big one.
And then her head is like all the way
over to the right side.
So this picture is like barely paying
attention to what she's doing.
I mean,
she barely paying attention and she had
fucking sunglasses on and it's dark out.
The whole thing was hilariously American
and she probably had a trump bumper
sticker on.
I have a mount,
so I just put my ipad pro right in the
middle of the move to.
She's probably on her way to Ted Cruz's
house.
She's going to go fuck them.
Have you seen that documentary that.
Hold on,
I'm sorry.
Do you believe that?
Do you believe it?
Do you know what we're talking about?
Five women have come out or they said
five women.
Ted Cruz is having an affair with five
different women.
First of all,
Kudos because you know if you're going
to have an affair,
go deep.
Have a gang of them and they said that
one of them even worked for trump now.
Perfect.
That's how you do it.
You get to tell you getting deep into
the enemy lines.
You know,
you gotTa,
you gotta get a spy.
There's some other things.
I was trying.
I was trying to read up on it.
There's been a lot of tweets over the
last six months referring to this thing.
The thing it's in capital letters.
The thing like Hashtag the thing at this
mate might be it,
what they bill been referring to the
last time where there might be something
else.
Secret.
Hidden.
How about of Ted?
Cruz comes out.
Hashtag Dick.
Game strong.
I'm voting for him for him.
Um,
he's in.
If he just owns up to it,
Can you imagine?
Hashtag Dick.
Game strong.
Bam.
Off fucking vote for him.
I'll register.
I'll be a registered public.
I'll go to church.
How about that?
Just to vote for him.
Why?
When you want our great now,
because I think the whole thing's a
joke.
I watched Hillary Clinton yesterday on
Jimmy Kimmel.
You see that video now?
It's hilarious.
Jimmy Kimmel did a really fucking smart
thing.
Very funny.
He set up this thing where he had
hillary come on and he told her about
mansplaining and he asked her if she
knew what mansplaining was and then she
started giving her explanation and he
corrected her course.
And so then he had her go up and give
her speeches and he told her how she
probably should actually dress and how
she should talk.
And he basically mansplained his way
through the whole thing.
Can we play this or will this get us
kicked off of Youtube?
Definitely.
Probably get us kicked off.
Yeah.
You should just watch it on Jimmy's.
Well yeah,
just watch it on his channel.
But if you could find the video.
I uh,
I.
today is the 20.
What is today?
The 24th.
Yeah.
I,
I'm 25th.
I tweeted it today.
So if you get to the 25th and you find
it on,
it's fucking hilarious.
So I'm gonna have to play it.
I want him to get all the hits for it.
Anyway,
he's,
he's great.
He's great.
He's,
I love that guy.
And the way he did it is just so fucking
brilliant.
Nobody else would have the balls to do
that.
Like he did it all,
like fake Dick headedly.
But since,
you know,
he's a nice guy,
nice guy.
He can get away with being a fake Dick
head.
It was great.
It almost made her likable.
Quite.
You're not feeling the Bern.
I feel the burn more than I feel
anything else.
Yeah.
I like burning and I've said this before
because the social stuff,
I think what he represents socially will
be a good like uniting of our country.
I think it'll help us.
I think what trump,
what he represents socialists,
the thing that disturbs me the most,
like when he says things about like
Mexicans and that kind of shit,
that's that.
That to me is.
That's the dumbest part about what it
does and the people that react to it
like the go,
Rah,
that get all fucking Rah Rah about that
kind of shit.
That's the worst aspects of our culture.
We got lucky as fuck.
We got lucky as fuck to be born in
America.
You could say what you want about where
you live and you might love Iceland are
fucking Sweden or wherever you are right
now and you're listening to this and
that's.
I bet you're right.
I bet you're right,
but you're what you.
Where you live has great great
qualities.
I'm not saying there's anything wrong
with where you live,
but what I'm saying is the difference
between being born in America and being
born in Mexico is fucking staggering.
It's a giant fucking difference as far
as the opportunities you have as far as
like the chances of you being able to
get a great job and be able to support
your family,
like people aren't sneaking into America
because it sucks they're sneaking into
America because they got a shitty roll
the dice and they got born into a poor
family in Mexico,
which is connected to the richest nation
in the world today.
It's that simple.
You and I got lucky as fuck we all did,
and so for a guy like Donald Trump,
he doesn't recognize that shit like you
should.
That should be the number one thing that
he says,
if you want to keep America great and
you want to make America great again and
everything like that,
we all,
we're all down with that,
but you can't talk shit about Mexicans.
You can't talk shit about them all being
rapists,
murderers,
than the sheer numbers of people that
come over from Mexico that are great,
that don't do anything,
that they're just trying to work and
trying to feed their families while
they're doing it illegally.
Yeah,
because a lot of other people have done
it illegally to and you know,
and they send back money and they
suddenly realize there's job
opportunities here,
and Donald Trump's fucking home
companies employ illegal aliens.
His wife came from another country.
I mean,
the whole Hillary,
that was Mitt Romney had hilarious joke
here.
What he said.
He said,
uh,
it's a,
it's,
there's some jobs that Americans won't
take trump out of white from and get it,
you know,
that's the product disturbs me about
him.
But,
uh,
the rest of the stuff,
I liked some of the stuff he does think
he's Larry.
I'm pretty sure he's going to win just
because I know for sure in 2020 it's
going to be trump versus Kanye the way
our world is going right now.
It's going to happen.
Just not going to happen.
He's not really going to run for
president.
Oh yes,
yes.
That's a hustle.
That's fake.
That's how you sell cds and what have
you.
But don't you think that's where we're
going?
Especially if trump wins.
Four years later we've bounced back.
I think we bounced back hard the other
way.
I think if trump wins,
what happens is you get someone like a
Gary Johnson,
Gary Johnson who is without a doubt the
best candidate,
but nobody takes him seriously because
he's an independent.
He's.
I mean he's a legit former governor of
New Mexico,
did a fantastic job there.
He's very open minded,
very liberal,
very progressive,
but also very smart.
I'm fiscally aware,
like he's got a lot of super positive
qualities.
He just doesn't want to be a part of
that bullshit two party system and
because of that,
no one's going to take them seriously,
but a guy like Gary Johnson could be a
real leader in a real president,
but to be a president is a fucking
stupid job.
It's to be one person that's in charge
of so many different parts of this
country that it's insane.
I mean,
you have to be in charge of how much
taxes we charge people.
I mean,
that's part of your platform.
What's your foreign policy?
What's the military budget?
What's all these things that are like,
what's.
What are you gonna do about healthcare?
What are you gonna do about education?
We,
all of those things require fucking
years and years and years of extreme
study like you have to like really be
immersed in each individual aspect of
our civilization to even have a thought
of how to fix it and correct it and
change the system whether it's taxes,
whether it's the economy,
it will.
All these different things require
incredible levels of expertise in the
expect that in all these different areas
from one person and then expect them to
have a unique progressive ideas about
society and culture and you know,
and how we move pass over silly
differences about race and gender and
sexual orientation.
This person is,
one person would have to be a master.
They would have to be some guru from
another planet.
I mean they would literally have to be
some non human because a human being
can't have that many levels of expertise
because to be an expert in anything
that's like super complicated like
finance,
like God damn,
those guys are studying it all the time.
I mean,
you might be able to be like a really
good finance guy and also have a mean
racquetball game or something like that.
Say Your Watch freaked me out.
What does it do it my security.
My home security just went off.
So it vibrates.
Broken your house.
Now it's just ups guy.
Oh,
they bang that shit.
I don't know how to turn it off.
Throw it in the water.
It's probably the best move.
Why do you want a computer on your
wrist?
You really liked that,
but it's cool.
I mean they just dropped the price $100.
So it's really cheap.
Wonder why?
Yeah.
Well it wants to fucking computer on the
wrist.
You know what's real?
What's cool?
It's like when you're driving and
somebody texts you,
you just look over and be like,
okay.
Or you can just push a button and just
reply about.
Just drive you.
Fuck.
Exactly.
That's why I listen to books on tape.
Listen to podcast,
don't you like you are a podcast so you
don't even listen to.
I know.
I don't listen to podcasts at all.
That is insane.
Why?
That's your part of your problem.
I,
the only time I ever listened to
podcasts when I'm going on a road trip,
but not like locally.
Every day I listen to podcasts all,
all day long.
I listened to history,
obviously history on fire.
I listened to.
I'm a hardcore history.
Um,
Daniel,
Daniela [inaudible] and I'm Dan.
Patrick's Annette.
Dan Patrick.
Do you listen to guys we fucked?
No.
How was it?
I just hung out with this girls and at
south by southwest or Christian has said
it's pretty funny.
I don't know.
Dan Carlin.
Why am I saying Dan?
Patrick?
Jesus Christ.
Because I was listening to a Dan Patrick
today.
Talk to.
Yeah.
Um,
but,
so I listened to those guys.
I'm Dan Carlin's the best at hardcore
history is insane.
Um,
I listened to some archery podcasts.
I listened to some comedy podcasts,
depending on what I'm into,
you know,
case listen to Joey's.
I'll listen to bill burrs on occasion I
was to rap.
So it's not always a lot elicited.
Dunkin's,
do you watch joey on periscope?
I mean,
do you watch periscopes?
I've watched joey.
That's it.
Sometimes I'll watch brody.
Yeah,
but uh,
I'm in my car,
man.
I don't fuck with the phone now.
Nope.
I don't fuck with it.
I put it down because it's dangerous as
shit.
It's just dangerous and it's addictive.
I know phones are addictive,
so I see people texting.
I think we should all just make an
agreement.
All of us just leave your fucking phone
alone.
When you're in your car.
Don't kill anybody because if you do,
you'll never forgive yourself.
If you wind up texting and you plow into
someone and someone dies,
some fucking kid dies,
some old lady dies or something.
You'll never forgive yourself.
Just stop fucking with your phone.
Stop looking down at it.
Put it down and just drive like the one
time where you can just chill and just
be involved in what you're doing.
Be Present.
Be Mindful what you're doing.
I take this fucking thing and I throw it
in the passenger seat.
I don't even,
I don't want to.
I don't want it in my lap.
I don't want it in the center console.
I don't want it.
I don't want to look at it.
Let's put it over there.
I just think we should all do that.
It's fucking scary,
man.
Watching that dummy yesterday.
Drive in with sunglasses on the right
handed.
Lean.
Scrolling through her instagram and like
looking down,
looking up,
looking up the amount of distance that
you travel.
When you're looking at your phone,
you're going 60 miles an hour and you're
looking at your phone for like two
seconds.
How many fucking feet of you going?
Think about that.
If you're going 60 miles an hour,
think about that one too.
That's a lot of fucking space you're
covering and you're not even looking at
the road.
Yeah,
I mostly bought to.
So for health fitness,
the sensors on it.
Eat vegetables,
fit the fitbit.
I had the fitbit for a while but started
fucking up all the time so I heard this
is a lot better.
So I thought those fit bits or the shit.
That's what I hear.
Well they're not waterproof,
but they're water resistant and I we'd
win.
Wait a minute,
wait a minute.
Really?
Yeah.
So how could you have something to
exercises?
I got some of those beats headphones
that are supposedly really good that
you're supposed to be able to sweat in
these big,
just like those,
but yeah,
just like those exact ones,
wireless ones,
they break after you sweat it.
I'm too much shadow.
Fitbit did awesome on that little button
thing that came apart,
so I have a super glue it back together
and the button stopped working after
awhile and then they started working
again a couple months later I had to buy
another pair just because I needed some.
Yeah,
I just give these a try.
I've been going wired.
I really liked them except they just.
You can't sweat too much in them.
That's ridiculous.
I liked the wired ones,
but when you lift weights and stuff like
specially kettlebell movements and
things along those lines,
you run the possibility of them getting
tangled up or they get bunched up
because that have a microphone on it so
you can use it for fun.
It's great for the fall and I love it.
I love it for everything,
man.
It's great.
It's really easy.
I like it.
I'm a.
I'm a fan.
People told me that it's not loud
enough,
but you know it's,
I don't want to blow my fucking ears.
I listen to music in the gym the other
day and it was fine.
It was good.
Pretty decent headphones,
but this from what they cost,
they shouldn't be.
They should last five to 10 year
standard Rs.
200 bucks.
I think.
Electronics,
man.
I mean you can't get them wet.
It's just they can only protect so much,
which apparently they've done an insane
job with these iphones.
You can dump these in a toilet for half
an hour.
How do I know this?
Someone else did it,
but you can dunk it in the
phone because in the reason why this
should piss everybody off a little bit.
They made these waterproof because now
you can turn them in and you can
exchange them when you want to get a new
one.
So they wanted to make it so they didn't
break.
So why don't you do that already?
You assholes.
Like why didn't you do that a long time
ago?
Because samsungs had waterproof phones
for the new Samsung.
S seven is waterproof.
Yeah.
What do you got there?
You got the note?
Five.
No filter.
Dope man.
They're the difference between an
android phone and an apple phone is
almost indistinguishable now.
As far as like the ability,
the phones ability.
Yeah.
If they could just work on the third
party apps,
like scopes on it.
Well instagram was real bad on the old
version of it.
I only use instagram on a iphone now,
but uh,
on the old version of it,
but I still use a galaxy phone for the
studio.
Alon,
the studio phone for,
for guests and stuff.
That's a,
that's a ting phone and that's a,
that's an android phone.
I like it,
man.
It works great.
It's smooth.
It's easy to use,
you know,
it doesn't,
that doesn't piss me off when I go
online with it or anything when I look
at youtube videos or anything,
but there's some stuff it just doesn't
have.
It's not as.
Which doesn't make any sense because
aren't there as many android phones now
as there are apple phones?
I think there's more apple.
It should be pretty.
Even if it's not one to just slightly
over the other.
Yeah,
I would think by now they would've
caught up like everything would be
caught up still as far as the android
goes,
it's still like as a company will make a
phone for like Samsung or Sony or 10
different companies that can make an
android phone,
then they have to have the most updated
version of the operating system and that
any update that has to go through the
carrier to get through each of those.
So you could have four point one.
Brian could have four point three.
I could have the new four point five or
something.
I don't even know if that's real.
Yeah.
And then there's another problem.
The other problem is a lot of companies
like t mobile or anyone,
they'll add their own bullshit and then
um,
Samsung will add their own bullshit on
top of the original android.
So if you want to buy just android,
like straight android,
you do it through Google and you get
that nexus foam.
The nexus phone is really interesting
because the nexus phone,
you pay google,
you don't pay a carrier,
like you don't pay verizon or t mobile,
you just pay google.
And so your phone works on everything,
it moves around and they just rent time
on everybody's network.
I find that to be fascinating.
So it uses both.
Networks,
uses everything.
He says everything.
So wherever you are apparently make sure
that's true.
Apparently that's how it works though.
Like you,
you just pay google instead of paying
verizon or instead of paying t mobile
and theoretically it uses the best
signal around all the time.
It seems like somebody like t mobile
like,
Nah,
we don't want you to do that.
Why would they do that?
We make more money.
Maybe they wouldn't.
I mean,
I don't think they even.
people even think Google themselves as
being a cell phone provider.
Most people don't think of it.
You think of Android,
but most people don't think about buying
their phone from google and using Google
as their service provider.
Do they?
I mean,
I've never heard that.
Chris Ryan told me about it.
Dr Chris Ryan from sex at dawn and
tangentially speaking,
he uh,
that's what he's got.
He got it that way.
And he got it because he wants it to
work everywhere.
And He,
when he's Roman,
there's no roaming.
His phone works in Indonesia,
works everywhere.
It's just,
it just works.
It's how the team mobile is pretty much.
You can go pretty much anywhere and it
just works.
It's like Canada.
There's no extra cost.
It's just crossing Mexico or nothing.
Now.
That's how it should be.
But didn't they get in trouble for
streaming,
for throttling?
There's nothing.
So they have this plan that's a,
they don't charge you for Netflix for
videos or any music's things like
spotify.
So all that bandwidth is free.
It's all you can eat.
So now it's been exposed or whatever.
They didn't really hide it,
but they said that the videos are down
graded to for ADP,
which is like for your phone 100 percent
fine.
Like you're in the difference between
seven,
20:00
PM for ADP on a whatever,
a four inch screen or five inch screen.
You're not going to notice the
difference.
So.
But Verizon and att and t made a huge
deal about it.
Blah,
blah blah.
What's funny though is yesterday on the
owner's periscope,
the CEO of t a t mobile,
it was shown that this whole time
verizon and att and t had been
downgrading.
There's two,
three,
20 p said they just got caught for like
even having worse signal then a team.
Everybody does it.
Everybody eyes and then the beams
acceptable.
It seems like an intelligent move.
Make sure that your stream doesn't get
interrupted because it's not too much
download.
And netflix is actually the ones behind
it.
Uh,
who was downgrading it from mobile
because if everyone in the road had 10
80 p for no reason,
there's no reason for it.
Well,
it seems like a massive waste of phone.
It is.
I mean,
if you can't meet,
you're looking at a phone,
but I have to tell you one thing I
fucking love about apple is apple tv
because I have apple tv at home and a
buddy of mine.
Yeah,
I got the new one,
but even the album was great.
But a buddy of mine texted me a youtube
video of his show,
so he texted me.
So I click on the link.
It starts playing,
I press down on the button,
it starts showing on my tv I'm talking
about in seconds,
so I got this text,
Bang.
He shows me an episode of his TV show.
I put it on the TV and I sit back on the
couch and I'm watching it in real time
stream on television.
I'm like,
this is fucking crazy.
Like this guy just sent me a show and
it's playing right now from my phone to
the TV and it's perfect.
It's in hd and I'm watching it and my
mouth was why?
I was like I was.
My jaw was open.
I was like,
I couldn't.
I can't believe.
Do you have the new one yet?
But I love it because you're just using
the microphone and being like a broad
city and it shows you where it's on Hulu
or Netflix and you just click on it will
scroll,
Scroll thing to scroll with that top
thing.
It's like a touch pad.
Do except by always having an upside
down or it's embedded and I'd sit on it
and it turns it off.
If there's a lot of problems with that
remote cat paused the walking dead.
They're all over it.
He's,
my cat is such a whore.
Like when,
uh,
when you sit on the couch,
like,
it's like,
oh yeah,
that's right.
It's like if you were a sleazy guy and a
girl said you can stay over at my house
but don't try anything.
And you're like,
yeah,
and we'll try nothing.
Don't worry about it.
And he climbed in bed with her and he
took your pants off and you started like
rubbing your at Dick up against her ass.
That's all my cats like.
You're like,
look dude,
I'm going to sit down here and I'm gonna
just watch TV.
Okay.
And he's like,
yeah,
cool,
cool.
And He plops down next to you and he
forces his head into your armpits and he
walks all over you and climbs on top of
you.
And he's like constantly what?
Jim?
Oh,
sorry.
What is this?
This is that Google a network cellular
network that you're talking about?
Oh,
this is a google fi.
Okay.
And so this is what works with the nexus
phone.
Their phone.
And then you pay them for one plan and
you paid for their data and their $10
per gig for data.
Five basics,
$20 per month.
Fuck off.
See how many gigs I used at month seven
or eight?
Hold on.
It's always $10 per gigabyte.
$10.
$10 per gig per month.
$20 for two gigs.
So if you're only using $30,
it's ridiculous.
How much does a lot though?
How many gigs do you use a month?
I think I used about seven or eight gigs
a month.
I'm around three,
three and a half.
Maybe three now.
I did a lot of periscope and video
stuff.
Oh.
So that counts all of that streaming you
do listening to music unless you're
downloading it from the servers and
whatnot.
That's interesting.
So do you have unlimited downloads,
Brian?
Like how does men live?
I have a family plan,
which is unlimited data unlimited.
Yeah.
That's my t mobile limited.
Unlimited for unused data though.
Huh?
Cool.
Yeah.
You don't pay for unused data.
Everybody's doing that.
That's what tim does.
Everybody does that.
Yeah.
That's so smart.
It's pretty expensive though.
Does it?
Yeah,
it says 32 bucks a month for two gigs
and Jamie just says he only uses three,
so let's make it 42 bucks off without
the $20 you can change your life without
that.
Plus the cost of data.
Yeah.
Okay.
So that would be $20 plus 30.
Well he's come,
he's got three.
That doesn't make any sense because he's
got 20 bucks plus two gigs.
So he's got two gigs.
That's $20 and then it's only 10,
$12.
More than that.
You got eight bucks back because he
didn't use all this data.
See if I used three point five,
you will go to Brian.
What's Brian uses?
Seven cranking up to eight.
Let's go to for fun.
Let's go to eight.
Just to be honest with your Cam girling
100 bucks a month,
which is fine.
It's fine.
That's normal.
What do you pay a month,
Brian?
How about 100 bucks to fuck?
Are you talking about bones?
And I can use an iphone,
but this puts you on technically the
best network possible at any given
moment.
And I'll tell you what though,
do that nexus phone is fucking so wheat.
That is a sweet phone.
Have you seen those?
No.
Iphone.
It's not.
I don't know dude.
They're top of the line.
Can't beat this iphone man.
Really?
This the new camera.
The camera on these phones is just as
good.
See,
receive it.
What is the comparison like nexus
comparisons to sign?
It's hard to argue it.
I'm pretty sure the people like a unbox
therapy or what does that dude's name?
Marcus Mkbhd.
He's really good at that.
Mark has.
He's really good at his breakdown so he
really knows his shit when it comes to a
cellular technology and all the
different components of cell phones.
See what he thinks about them.
I'm interested to try it though.
I mean just to see if it really is
because that's one thing that I just
drove to San Jose and you know when
you're going through the grapevine,
I had zero service for like a good hour
or so.
And everybody though.
No,
well I was in a phone with somebody from
verizon when somebody from 18 and t
verizon was dead and he though it was
okay,
so it would be cool to see if I went
through that with that service.
If it just automatically went to a t and
t or or if it really just chooses like
sprint smartphone cameras shoot out.
Galaxy s seven edge takes on the iphone
six plus.
This is a comparison there.
Just do some side by side photos,
just photos.
Okay,
look at that.
Let's see which one is.
I think the Samsung is the one on the
left.
On the one on.
On top I guess,
and when I scroll over here it shows you
the iphone version.
Okay.
Iphone is better.
Way better away.
It's over conversations.
Dead Front.
Facing camera.
Let's see.
The difference in the front facing
camera.
Which one is which?
Again?
I think it's the samsungs on the left.
Okay.
That's over.
Iphone is better.
Conversations over.
I use both everyday.
They both have low light into this.
We're doing these kinds of comparisons
though.
It's really hard to make these.
Wait a minute.
Who's that?
Who's that low light?
This one should be iphone.
This should be Samsung.
Samsung is way better,
but you know the uh,
the photographer,
how well they do.
But that's the same.
That's the same photo we're supposed to
assume.
Yeah,
I were supposed to,
but wait a minute.
Samsung's bigger aperture really comes
into play when you're taking photos in
low light.
These images were shot in the dark back
corner of a coffee shop and both phones
struggled,
but the iphone fared worse.
That's a big difference man.
And Scroll back again so you can see
the,
that is way better.
Samsung is fucking way better.
Like that is such a vast contrast.
Yeah.
I don't buy this one though because I
use.
I mean the note five is one of the best
cameras.
The no five is one of the best cameras
on a Samsung.
And I use both of these every night and
while the,
this one does have good low light,
it also,
it's very blurry when you move it
around,
it's hard to get a really good shot.
Right?
But that doesn't have as good of
cameras.
Yes.
Seven edge,
seven edges of the newer camera and
newer by four months or so,
but it's newer,
but is it better be get better mom,
man,
you're doing your new iphone cameras.
He's doing chem trails a little bit,
but I'm just trying to add like there's
certain things you can do when you're
taking a phone in a dark situation and
make it look a little bit better and we
don't know if they're doing all that
they can to make the picture.
Look at this.
Let's see.
Um,
this one here.
Speed.
Which is what's the difference?
Shutter speed?
Will they both look good?
Yeah,
it's,
it's very.
Which one's that?
Is that Samsung?
Samsung on top?
That looks better.
I fumble a Samsung one looks better,
but here's the problem.
The angle slightly different.
Do it again.
See that one?
You're going down more than when you're
up more.
So that's what I mean.
The light changes everyone.
We do it more time.
Scroll back pretty fucking close and
it's really such a where they should go
way out of their way to make sure you
have the exact same angle because when
you don't have the same angle,
it's hard to tell like one of them,
like this one is way closer.
Yeah.
Like why would they do that?
It's really one is that this is the
Samsung top was pretty God damn good,
but that looks better.
Boy Genius report,
which is a pretty legit website.
Uh,
they did a whole thing with the
[inaudible] versus the iphone six plus a
and they found that the iphone is still
the best.
It's a says the SR two six plus camera
outperformed the s seven more often than
not.
Yeah,
it seems like it,
it seems like only low light is where it
really has it nailed.
But God damn the differences like here,
these are the differences that the
iphone seems to get things a little
lighter and clear.
It's like,
here's another low light.
This is an s seven and this is the
iphone and this is way better than this
and this is a little light picture.
So again,
it's just the photographer,
you can't really do this shit.
You could just have to have the camera
and go.
Yeah.
Most of the time that this way works.
They should do,
they should have like a double selfie
stick that faces forward and they press
Baltimore the exact same time in the
exact same level.
You would do that?
Yeah,
they usually do that.
Yeah.
That's how they should do it.
They should have everything on a mounted
platform that takes a photo of the exact
same time so that you know.
But even then one of them would be a few
inches over to the side.
So you'd get a little slightly different
angle.
Yeah.
But either way they're both really good.
Fourth,
it just,
it,
it's just what kind of environment you
have.
I use all apple shit so it's easier for
me.
But if I didn't have apolis it,
I probably would use just a Samsung
five.
Well that's like I said,
my friends sending me that video and I
watched it on my TV and seconds.
There's nothing like that that exists in
android yet.
Is there?
Yeah.
You could have a google chromecast.
Oh yeah.
That setup or Amazon fire stick.
I have that too.
Oh,
okay.
So what that means is that like a stick
it into the USB?
Is that how it works?
Or The htmi actual TV.
You download the chrome cast app to your
phone so that anytime you have a video
playing it because it just as good.
No,
no,
I don't have an apple tv so I can't,
I've never used it.
I have chromecast.
Uh,
it works not as good for me.
Like I really stutters a lot when you're
playing stuff back in,
you have to play it through chrome only.
So it's like,
oh,
you have to go through the browser.
And a lot of times like apple is just
way better when it comes to that in my
opinion.
The thing about the apple setup was that
it was instantaneous.
Yeah.
That was what blew me away.
My friend was like,
Hey,
check this episode out.
I click it and then it's plan.
I'm like,
Whoa,
this is nuts.
I mean,
I'm telling you from the moment I
received the text to the moment I was
kicked back on the couch watching it was
more than.
No more than 10 seconds.
Yeah.
This is insane.
And you can stream your,
your,
your whole entire phone to your tv so
you can sit there and just text while
looking at the TV.
One clicking is so big like Amazon one
click.
If you need something.
Oh,
I'm out of printer ink.
Let me just go here.
One Click,
Bam.
And then one clicking on apple store.
That's so big.
Like to be able to just click it and get
it.
Do you want this?
Yeah.
Send me a battery bitch.
Boom.
Yeah.
I get mad now that it's not.
Same Day.
I'm like,
what is it?
That same day,
set a fucking.
Send the Goddamn drone.
Get over here.
Do you have anything that you like?
I have the subscription on certain items
that I know I need every month.
I don't do that.
I do,
but wipes a gummy bear vitamins used to
flush your butt wipes.
Do you flush it line?
It's not my house.
Those things don't work.
Yeah,
I know.
Can't flush them.
They showed a special on it on some
shows are stupid.
They make them so they call them
flushable.
Those fucking people should all go to
jail.
That shit is not flushable.
You are clogging pipes all over the
world that causing millions of dollars
for the plumbing problems all over the
world.
This clogging shit up.
Paint that stuff.
So that's like a thin synthetic paper.
You can't just.
It's not gonna.
It's not gonna dissolve like toilet
paper.
Either way,
all those things are gross.
Those toilets that we had in Japan,
remember,
that's what I have now.
You're so lucky.
Oh,
I'm addicted.
You can get one of those.
You.
You're always there.
They have the shitty ones at Amazon.
Just attached the topic.
Is that kind of you have give given the
Amazon.
You can get it online.
I'll tell you the company that I see own
my place,
so I'm not going to put a nice toilet
removed.
When you leave,
you hire someone to do it.
They come over,
they install it,
and then you hire someone to take it out
when you're gone.
It seems like you just don't want to do
that.
Right.
You get a nice warm jet of water up your
asshole anytime you want.
I have a bit about it now.
Let him do it.
Because it's true.
Like if you read some wacky tweets by
me,
most likely I've got a jet of hot water
shooting up my ass when I'm writing.
I do some ferocious tweeting on the
toilet when the UFC going back to Japan.
Um,
we don't have any plans.
New York coming up first,
right?
Yes.
We got approved in New York.
That was part of Rosie O'Donnell's
brother's gay fantasy.
They don't think they have a car setup
yet.
The next big one is the John Jones
fight,
which is in,
um,
that's in Vegas.
That's a huge card.
Jon Jones.
Daniel cormier.
Rematch.
Dump,
dump,
dump.
That's a big deal.
That's going to be insane.
There's a really cool documentary I
recommend called spy in the pod.
It's a,
I think it's a three part BBC series.
What they did is they made these robot
fish and turtles and dolphins and they
had cameras all over them,
like in their eyes and stuff like that,
and they swam with the dolphins.
So the dolphins thought these fake
robots.
We're like apart,
like,
like friends or like another dolphin.
And it's really cool how they got to go,
like really into like things that no
one's ever seen before because you know,
they,
you know,
it's just a robot.
Uh,
and uh,
it's also really cool to see how other
fish attacked like the turtle and stuff
like that.
And that seemed like that's a camera.
That's a,
this is a fake turtle that's going
around and that's a fake fish.
It's really silly also,
but it got really cool.
Uh,
it was dolphins catching flying fish in
the air and their mouth.
Yeah.
Dolphin life is a ball.
They're just having a great old time out
there in the ocean.
Is He?
Seaworld is say they're not going to
breed orcas anymore.
Yeah.
But that's still,
that's like,
we're not going to breed our slaves
slaves and no longer going to make any
space another way to buy them.
Don't worry,
I'll.
Well,
that's what got exposed by Phil.
Phil Demaris when he was on the podcast
exposed that he's like sea world.
They're liars.
They're getting there.
They're dolphins in their orchestra from
another company which gets them from the
wild.
Like that's how they got them and for
them to say,
we haven't gotten a captive.
See,
I'm an Orca from the wild in 30 years.
He's like,
that's a lie.
That's just not true.
Yeah.
They haven't gotten them from the wild.
You're right,
they haven't done it.
They got somebody else to do it.
Somebody else did it.
They sold it to one organization.
Then they got their dolphins from that
organization.
It's all fucked up,
man.
Those are.
Those are like people.
They're like,
oh,
a water person.
And they're just.
They have a different way of existing
than we do,
but there are smart as shit,
like in some crazy way that we don't
understand the noises they make.
We still can't decipher them.
We don't even know what the hell they're
saying.
We have no idea what they're saying,
but they know what they're saying and
crazy.
That is that like they have a language
that we have been studying.
Uh,
John Lilly was studying that shit in the
19 sixties and when lily was done
studying it,
what they were trying to do is they were
trying to talk dolphins into making
people noises.
There's a radiolab podcast about it,
I think it's called hello.
And they were trying to figure out a way
to get dolphins to make human language
noises so that we could understand them.
They even have the voice box to do that.
No,
no,
that was part of the problem.
But they wanted to imitate it.
But also part of the problem was they
had this lady,
researcher Lilly who was crazy for
people that don't know.
I mean,
brilliant,
crazy but crazy.
Lily invented the semi,
the sensory deprivation tank.
Lily.
I'm also was this pioneer of
interspecies communication.
I mean,
he was really like working on this
dolphin thing long before anybody
thought it was viable.
He was trying to figure out how to
communicate with dolphins and the one of
the methods that he came up with,
he was set up a sensory deprivation tank
next to a dolphin tank and he would take
acid and climbing the sensory
deprivation tank,
jacked up on acid and try to like sense
thoughts through the water and listened
to them talking and see if he could
decipher them.
And apparently he had some anecdotal
success or he kind of understood what
they were,
but who,
I mean it's fucked up on acid.
Who knows what he's actually seeing.
But the woman that he was with,
um,
this was the interesting part about it.
She,
the woman that was part of this
experiment,
she lived in this place that they
created for dolphins and the place that
they created for dolphins was.
They had this,
I'm like living room setup and they had
water in the living room and these
dolphins swam around,
or this dolphin swam around in this
water with her.
And it lived with her,
like her bed was in the water.
So she would like get out of bed and
stepped down.
And she'd be in waist high water and
she'd walk around like that.
Well,
the dolphins in this area that often
gets horny and it's a big distraction.
So what she decides to do is start
jerking the dolphin off.
Just like that guy that got caught last
week that you hear about this.
No.
Yeah.
This happened last week.
And of course every time there's any
kind of news with dolphin sex,
everyone tweets me.
So dolphin sex abuse whistleblower calls
out aquarium for jerking off sea
mammals.
Why is that a bad thing?
Nothing wrong with that.
So this lady,
what was her description of it was,
it was,
it was a physical need that had to be
taken care of before they can go back to
doing the work.
Like this dolphin was so distracted.
What are you doing over there?
I was looking at that story,
still looking it up after you put it on
the screen.
He cut,
he just put it up.
Um,
so she,
you know,
she was like,
this is just a reality of being a living
thing with a sex drive.
Like we have to take care of this.
Otherwise it's going to distract them,
but that shut down all the research and
then they found out about lily doing
acid and he's also being in the
ketamine.
You'd shoot ketamine into Moscow
intramuscularly and get into the sensory
deprivation tank guy was out of his
mind.
Just some of those guys,
especially back then when people didn't
really know what the fuck ketamine was,
you know,
they didn't understand what this guy was
doing and this is the acid days,
like acid wasn't even illegal back then.
This guy was doing all these wacky
experiments and he was so far off the
deep end,
like so far removed from what most
people knew about psychedelic drugs that
he was just,
he was just out there on the furthest
fringes.
And now just to this day,
people are still trying to figure out
what the fuck he was doing.
Still trying to figure out how far we
got and what,
you know,
he was a,
he was a real crazy man.
Like Lily.
Um,
he was the,
the motivation behind that movie altered
states.
That was all about lily because lily was
a scientist and you know,
then he was taken all this crazy shit
and people are like,
Whoa,
what the fuck are you doing,
man?
Like you're taking some crazy
psychedelic drugs and we don't even
really understand.
He's like,
Eh,
whatever,
dude,
leave me alone.
We'll go hang out with dolphins.
It would just take this stuff.
But the,
uh,
the radio lab podcast is really
interesting because it's,
it's weird how hung up people get where
as soon as it becomes about sex.
Like if the dolphin had any other needs
that had to be met,
like maybe dolphins have a,
a certain amount of hugging that they
have to have on a daily basis.
Like maybe their unique requirements are
that they need to be caressed on a daily
basis.
Otherwise they get sick.
If people just climbing in the tank with
them and correct them,
no one ever problem,
but it's caressing his dick.
They were like,
no way.
That's where you draw the line.
We draw the line there because we're
ashamed of sex were shamed or sexuality.
So a scientist who addresses sexuality
the same way we would address food,
shelter,
warmth,
like as a physical need.
She addressed it as a scientist,
not confined by the constraints of our
culture and our ridiculous civilization.
She just thought about,
okay,
we got a problem here,
let's take care of this problem,
and then we can try to get this thing to
say hello.
And everybody's like,
we're shutting it down.
You're jerking off.
Dolphins is John Lilly.
Assistance that are alive are working
and that woman's.
A lot of the women in the Radiolab
podcast.
She's still alive.
Yeah,
there's a few of them that are alive.
I'm todd mccormick,
has John Lilly's sensory deprivation
tank.
He's got one of his.
He was a part of the early Samati
company.
My,
uh,
my first sensory deprivation tank was a
somebody that's the one I wound up
giving away online.
Remember we made that video and we gave
it away was when I found out about the
float lab float labs pot there.
Their pods,
they're a sensory depth.
Tanks are just so much better.
There's two companies that really
fucking kill it right now.
There's a float lab which just kills it.
They make the best shit.
Everything is state of the art,
state of the art,
a decontamination of the water,
ozone,
all that stuff.
By the way,
I've zeroed like connection with them or
any other sensory deprivation tank.
I don't have any business.
I'm not,
I'm not selling them.
Although we have talked to,
um,
there's another company in,
in Austin.
What does the zero gravity.
Is that what's called an Austin?
Make sure it's that they have a dope
tank as well.
And we've thought about,
um,
we've,
we've talked about it,
the onnit company of releasing an audit
tank or being involved in some sort of
high end tank because what this guy's
doing in Austin is A.
Kevin is his name zero gravity.
Uh,
Kevin is doing it with,
um,
he's using like bolt holes like the,
uh,
the same companies that make.
There's Kevin right there with the long
hair.
Look at that fucking God damn hippie.
He's a great guy by the way.
Super Nice Guy.
But his,
his tanks are,
they're right up there with the float
lab tanks and what they're doing is
instead of having a lining,
like the float lab uses this super thick
lining.
That's what it looked like,
similar to what the float labs look like
in a lot of ways.
Like they're just real heavy duty float
lab uses the aligning that they use when
they make Koi ponds that real thick
rubber lining.
So that was a big problem with the
Cemati tanks was that the lining would
burn out because uh,
occasionally you get like a hole in it
and then some water would get through
and it would get on the heating element.
They would short circuit and burned
through and then it would flood.
That happened to me.
My,
my basement got flooded.
Yeah.
So this guy guys figured out a way
around that no lining at all.
And instead they use A.
I'm like the same sort of manufacturing
principles that you would make a boat
out of.
Why is it so tall?
So you stand in it,
why do you want to stand in it?
Because you can lie in it.
And then you have to duck when you get
out or you can just stand up and walk
out.
So they just made them taller.
And also you get more air in there.
The float lab ones have buttons that you
can press that circulate the air.
Like mine has three different speeds.
I can have a little bit of air,
a lot of air or just blows like full
blast or it get shut it off.
So you could circulate some air inside
the chamber while you're in it.
Most of the time I have that off,
but you can turn it on.
It also helps to cool your body off a
little bit because sometimes you can get
a little sweaty.
Like it's hard to get the shut that
fucking phone watch nonsense off.
Take it off man.
He can't.
Dang.
Every hour.
That's just retarded.
Have you haven't done the years is due
every hour.
Like a clock.
That was my alarm system here.
You're exactly at 4:00.
You haven't done the music or isn't it
yet,
have you?
No,
no,
no.
Are you interested in trying that much?
But no.
It's interesting,
I just haven't gotten down to their
place.
I only use the tank that I have,
but if I would definitely try it.
What he's done with the music thing is
figuring out how to wait to have these
floating waterproof speakers that are
right next to your ears and they
literally make the water vibrates so you
feel music in your feet and your skin.
You feel it in your balls,
like you feel the music and the water
and it's supposed to be incredible.
It's supposed to be like some real next
level shit.
If you're cute.
I didn't even really need that.
Those wouldn't.
Binaural beats I would imagine.
You can get some interesting.
Oh yeah,
stuff.
Didn't you just get frozen the other
day?
Jamie did the crypto thing.
How was it?
It was great.
It was cool.
It wasn't genuine.
It was a bit like what I would expect if
a torturous.
Does it feel like torture?
No physical be tortured?
No.
Uh,
I was just playing a mind game with
myself.
I only went for two minutes and they put
music which help go do it.
Man.
I,
I wouldn't mind it.
Let's do it.
Let's do it right after this.
It was just like a little mind game.
They're playing led Zeppelin,
so I'd like,
you know,
there's music and it's only two minutes
so you know,
it's not a full song so you're just
like,
alright,
it sucks for the first 30 seconds I even
know what you're expecting.
And then it's like,
all right,
I'm here,
this is cool.
But like Rhonda,
Patrick Number,
your body gets used to it.
So like when you're doing it,
you did those two minutes,
felt like an eternity.
After awhile.
Three minutes feels pretty easy.
He just sits down there no more than
three.
Right.
That's like the.
I've done three slash 20 simone I've
ever done three minutes.
Twenty seconds.
It gets hairy.
Those last 20 seconds get a little air.
Is there any part of your body that acs
does something that you've noticed?
Like your butthole for free shot or
dizzy or decor?
Like kind of know your legs,
shake your legs,
start shaking.
It wasn't as cold as I thought it would
be honest.
I thought it would be unbearably cold.
I've been in cold situations before and
it's just as cold as you get sick balls.
Like did they get the tight or you know
what I mean?
Like when your,
like when your balls are talking about
your testicles and know that you're
wearing underwear,
but your um,
what happens is your body at first is
like,
Holy Shit and it doesn't feel that cold,
but it feels like,
oh my God,
but you can stand it.
But after a couple minutes it reveals
itself.
You hit three minutes and it reveals
You're like,
oh my God.
Like it reaches a level of cold,
like where your body can't keep itself
warm anymore.
And your body also,
your blood has retreated your buds
retreating to your core to try to
protect your dancing Oregon time,
like just side to side to side step.
And then do you have a sensor on or in
any way they're detecting your heart
rate to make sure you're not,
like you're right there.
They could see you through the glass and
you could always leave anytime you want
and walk out the door.
The door's right next to you.
It's not a hard to open.
Just push it.
You stand out.
The problem with it is if you touch the
walls,
you could definitely get some frost bite
you gotta.
Make sure you don't touch the walls.
You gotta stand in the center.
Don't,
don't touch anything with your skin
because you know it's not a lot of room
to move and it's 270 degrees below zero
shits.
No joke.
It wasn't at.
It could be scary.
You're building yourself up more in like
a haunted house,
like it's not that bad when you should
get some of that scary dude.
It's freaky.
I just don't like being in situations
where what if this door accidentally
it's breaks and they have to open it in
10 minutes or I die.
You could open it.
It's not hard,
man.
Just pushes.
Doesn't have a knob.
It just pushes shot and closes.
Got a little handle on it.
It's not even like being in a cooler at
a restaurant.
It's not.
That's what I'm thinking is super easy
to open.
It opens pretty easy.
It opens easy,
but it's really weird.
But afterwards,
man,
you feel amazing.
Didn't you feel great?
I felt,
I don't know.
I'm not sure if it was.
I drank coffee later that night,
but it kept me up like I had way more
energy than I usually do on a given day.
Yeah.
Well with Dr Patrick said it's
Epinephrin and then your brain produces
it and also cold shock proteins.
They produce all this anti inflammatory
response and the way it makes your brain
feels very interesting the way it makes
your whole body feel like you feel
great.
Like you have to get out of it.
You're like,
Whoa,
God damn.
You feel good.
And you know the physical benefits of it
I think.
I think for anybody who works out and
lift weights and does anything where
you're,
you know,
we have soreness and inflammation and
apparently for people that have
arthritis,
it offers a lot of,
a lot of help,
a lot of assistance for people that have
that.
I just fucking love it.
You have never taken an ice bath though,
so I don't supposed to be just as good
or better jobs.
It's better.
I don't think ice baths or really easy
for a lot of people just to do because
you know,
they'll just have it at the gym list.
They have a hold on their spotlight.
They're starting to have for cryotherapy
for everyone to have an ice bath,
but it's 15 minutes to.
That's what you supposed to do.
Sometimes people do 20 shop says it's
better.
He says the ice bath gives him like more
relief than the tank and also a wim Hoff
said the ice bath has some benefits of
the tank.
Wouldn't have because you learn how to
breathe in those 15 minutes.
It's a long time as opposed to like the
three minutes,
like the,
the,
the cooling tanks,
the crowd,
Janet Chambers.
When you get in them right as they start
to soc,
it's over,
but when you get that ice bath,
I think that sucks from the jump and I
think learning how to calm yourself in
the sock is what's what it's all about.
Like there's a.
You get the same Epinephrin I bet maybe
you get more because you're in that tank
for a long time with that ice water in
there for 20 minutes,
so who knows?
You might get a bigger purse of that
Epinephrin and from people that have
done it,
they say that it's more relief from like
soreness.
Like Brendan swears.
That's more relief and make sense to me.
I haven't done it so I can't comment.
I should probably do it just so I know
the difference.
I'll just probably do it.
I should probably have a good workout,
like lift some weights or something and
then go do it and see if periscope it.
Yeah,
maybe I should.
I probably should because I do the tank
so often.
I should probably know,
but I know that the first time I started
hearing people talk about how you feel
when
you get out though was when people were
doing the sensory deprivation tank.
I never heard about people saying they
felt good when they got out of the ice
bath.
They were like happy it was over,
but I don't remember people saying they
felt good.
I wonder if it requires a certain
temperature.
You experience.
She probably already talked about this
and we forgot it.
Right.
I would imagine she had a temperature in
there.
Yeah.
She fast.
Too much fucking information.
They can't keep up.
She does it with no notes either.
By the way folks,
she'll have like a notebook that she
never looks at and she's rattling off
all that information with no notes.
She said one of the few people that I've
ever met that makes me feel really
fucking stupid,
you know,
I think I asked her three times
separately after that podcast like,
okay,
please explain to me like I'm five,
this sauna thing.
Yeah.
I'm doing it right.
Right,
right.
Ten minutes is good.
Yeah.
Okay.
But there's a few people that have
talked to,
I feel like really fucking stupid while
I'm talking to them where I'm just
trying to like,
like,
uh,
what is it like on your planet?
How do you time travel?
What do you know about us and did you
create us?
Your questions are valid.
I will answer them now.
Um,
who else makes me feel that stupid?
Nailed a cross tastes and he makes me
feel that stupid.
Uh,
Peter Schiff,
he made me feel pretty stupid.
Um,
you know,
who made me feel pretty stupid.
I still don't understand what the fuck
he said.
Was that physicists dude?
I met cost Goswami?
Yes.
Yeah,
Dr.
Goswami man.
To this day I will have,
I'll put on that podcast is try to grab
it.
Try to figure out what he was saying he
was talking about like he was,
he's a quantum physicist.
Is that how you describe them?
Or string of quantum theory and string
theory and whoa man.
That stuff is like,
hold the fuck on.
What are you even saying like that stuff
is so far out the deep band as far as
like how to grasp it.
You hear that guy describing things and
you're like,
what?
Huh?
He's a little too smart.
He's cool and he doesn't give a fuck who
wear a hat with a tie.
It's when it's kangaroo hats,
right?
It's like run DMC.
Shit can go over.
This guy is like giving a speech at a
college and he's got a fucking,
like a sock hat on.
What a weird hat to have as a professor,
but I think those dudes,
they don't give a fuck like their
version of reality is so it's so,
it's,
they're looking at the universe on this
almost impossible to measure level and
there's only a few of them that
understand the mathematics involved when
they started drawing all that
mathematical stuff for quantum theory,
when they started drawing on those
yellow legal pads and they sit in the
park and do it.
If you left that there and you gave the
next 400 people a million dollars,
tell you what it is,
no one's going to know what the fuck
that is.
You could write in Japanese and you
could say,
uh,
if someone can read this,
you get a million dollars.
Someone's going to show up almost
immediately and read that.
There's a lot of people that speak
Japanese.
This very few people understand what the
fuck those guys are writing when they're
writing all those crazy numbers and
letters and squeal lines.
And I watched Brian Cox and um,
I forget who the other scientists was,
but when I did Brian Cox,
his podcast,
he's another one that makes me feel
stupid as fuck.
Maybe this,
these guys were talking,
they were talking about like those
equations and they were talking about
gravity and I was like,
what are you,
why are you even doing up there?
Is that real?
Like,
no,
you have no idea.
They're making these squiggles and all
these lines.
And to them it's like,
of course course,
don't forget the little squiggle with
the a,
like that kind of shit.
I didn't know you had a pod.
It's hilarious because they enjoy doing
it too because it's like a cool little
language that they know.
So few people know,
like the language of that complex,
those equations.
It's like almost,
it's like some crazy foreign
alien language like that.
Only a few people know how to speak.
Like they're doing all these equations
and trying to prove that at its smallest
level the universe is made out of
something that's like strings and they
vibrate at different frequencies and
that's what creates matter.
And what,
what,
what are you guys talking about?
And then they started talking about
subatomic particles and how they react
when being viewed or not viewed.
And what the fuck are you saying?
You know,
I mean that's why that guy doesn't give
a fuck.
You wear a sock hat.
Like who cares?
This is all just strings.
Like you guys don't even know this.
You don't even know what you're involved
in.
You guys are playing this game.
You know you're sitting here wondering
if it's going to be Donald Trump or ted
Cruz to the Republican nomination and
everybody the,
the balance of the country that this guy
is studying strings that we can't see.
Maybe they're the biggest bullshit
artists.
And they were just so confused that we
don't question like they all decided to
keep their mouth shut.
Like it's been going on forever.
Like Einstein with created this like,
hey,
I figured out a way.
We don't really have to have real jobs.
We just talked crazy shit about strings.
It is,
anything's possible.
But I have a feeling that's not what
happened.
I have a feeling because they're
teaching it still.
It's not like,
nope,
no more,
we're just gonna just between you and I
know it's going to die with us.
No,
they teach it,
you know that those high level equations
and that kind of physics and stuff
that's available at universities at the
highest level.
So it's got to be a real thing.
What if they,
just to arguments sake,
what if they found one of those things
to be wrong?
They have to stop teaching it.
It's the right thing with that,
which has happened since we've been in
school.
You know,
they've taught us things that they found
out weren't true.
Okay.
Yeah.
But that's because they get new data and
part of the reason why they get new data
is because they were going over these.
Sure,
man,
there's,
it's part of the whole idea that's so
supposedly so beautiful is that
knowledge is like self correcting and
when more knowledge comes about,
when we learn new things and we have new
discoveries and we have new information
that we add to,
it sort of changes the view of how we're
looking at things like it's self
correcting,
you know,
it's,
it becomes a problem if someone's
resisting it because they don't want to
appear that they were incorrect all
these years,
that that's a giant problem and that's
an ego problem that humans have.
Humans,
they just have that problem.
Even if they were teaching to the best
of their ability and their are doing an
amazing job with what information that
they had.
If something comes out that contradicts
with someone's been teaching,
boy they fucking resist the shit out of
that.
It becomes a problem like archeology a
little bit.
Seen it with some of those,
uh,
Egypt guys like as they try to introduce
the possibilities of civilizations that
were very complex and building giant
stone structures like deep,
deep into our past,
like 14,000
plus years ago when they started,
when the mall of this evidence starts
coming out,
they're still resisting the idea that
Egypt is older than,
than what it is.
And this is kind of John Anthony West.
I know we've had them on that guy.
If you haven't heard this subject before
and you're not interested or you are not
educated about Egypt and its history,
its guys get this insane documentary
series.
It's,
it's.
I mean obviously it's,
it's a DVD and it's only a,
an hour or couple hours long and there's
six of them though and it's a whole
series of them.
I mean the way this guy did it is so
good.
He's so good at explaining it and he's
so passionate about Egypt and he's so
passionate about the architecture and
showing like how much complexity there
is and it's six fucking hours or more
than six hours.
Six Dvds,
right.
Is that what it is?
Each one and our magical Egypt?
Yes,
that's it.
I think he's got an magical Egypt to
that.
He just came out with two,
but this guy is just obsessed with Egypt
and he knows so much about it,
but some of his evidence that they tried
to show to these archeologists to open
up the possibility that we're not just
looking when they're looking at Egypt,
they're not just looking at one
civilization that was advanced that was
making these incredible structures.
You might be looking at like several
generations that are separated by
thousands of years.
Like this might have been an area where
there's been like a one construction
style that went on for thousands of
years and they had another one after
that.
It might have been new people took over.
Like there's a lot of crazy shit
happened in Egypt.
Like the face of the Pharaoh is
apparently an African face and that's
after the new bins.
Conquered that part of Egypt.
So what happens when the New Orleans
came up and conquered Egypt,
they decided to take that Sphinx and
carbon African head into it.
So they made the Pharaoh,
whoever the pharaohs the time,
some bad motherfucker,
dude,
he's the ultimate pimp.
He turned alliance faces like,
yeah,
the line that's been here for about
10,000
years,
dog man,
I think my face look better update and
that line,
he had carved his face into a giant
existing statue and the existing statute
might have been there as long as like
10,000
BC.
Like they think that statute might be
old as fuck and that this guy carved his
head into it like way after it had been
made.
There's all sorts of cool evidence about
that.
Two men that people are reluctant to
consider.
Some of it is these Fisher marks in
these canyon walls.
It's only been created by only could
have been created by thousands of years
of rainfall.
And there's this guy from Boston
University,
Dr Robert Schoch who started proposing
all these ideas.
If you have anybody's ever interested in
this kind of stuff,
magical Egypt is the shit I'm telling
you.
It's amazing.
I watched nothing bet that for months
straight.
I watched it several times.
So good dude.
They were so advanced.
Fuck,
I mean they were making some crazy shit
even if they are right,
even if the egyptologists are 100
percent correct that we're still talking
about 5,000
years ago,
4,500
plus years ago,
we're talking about like 2,500
BC and they were making some insane
shit.
So even if John Anthony West is wrong
and it all comes from the same era,
it still in fucking insane how much
information is available right now.
We could see like how mathematically
complex structures where these people
are doing this and they're making these
immensely complicated structures at the
very earliest or the very most recent
2,500
BC.
Fucking crazy.
I mean that.
It's crazy and they think the African
faces even more recent than that student
came along,
just jack that town and put his fucking
face on the line.
I hope that happens to see the statue of
Liberty.
If what if our statue of Liberty gets
blacked out?
It could if Kanye,
because president,
he'll demand to be the new face on Mount
Rushmore for sure.
Totally.
One hundred percent,
100 percent,
100 percent Tommaso,
she'll,
she'll want to be on that as well,
and that's when we'll know that the
human race is a giant failure.
It just didn't work out.
We got to capable before we got smart
because the really capable people,
the people that have figured out how to
allow us to manipulate matter and
exchange information,
the people that earn that,
they were super,
super intelligent,
but then they took that and they gave
that power to us.
They gave it to the masses.
Hashtag Dick.
Game strong.
Say what they did was they.
They made something that we don't
deserve.
We don't
deserve this.
It's too good.
It's too crazy.
I mean,
it's like we're not ready for this level
of power.
That's what's happening.
Hashtags going to find a way onto our
currency.
At one point,
pretty soon there's going to be like
Hashtag Dick,
game stress Kanye or something like
that.
Hashtag feel the burn that's out there,
right?
Hashtag make America great again.
So trump is,
what is his letters to give up on 1:40,
1:40.
You want to keep America great again or
make America great again.
So many hashtags are too many letters,
right?
Too many characters who you vote for
Brian,
burning man,
burning all the way.
I just think he represents common sense
and that's the one thing that I like
about him.
He just seems like a normal person
talking like you're talking to Ari or
something.
Oh,
exit.
I agree.
And I also think like the fact that he's
not taking money from banks.
Like you know,
when he was asking Hillary to give a
transcript,
the speeches that she gave when she was
getting paid a quarter million bucks to
talk to these bankers.
I mean,
that's a reasonable request.
If you're going to be the president,
And he goes,
you know,
I'll tell you,
I'll give you all the transcripts from
what I spoke in front of those bankers
because there are non.
He's good at it.
Man.
Did you see Larry David Play Him Bernie?
No,
I haven't seen it.
Oh my God.
It's some of the best.
They're identical twins.
It's crazy.
That's funny.
Larry.
David's a genius.
I love to just see the Garry shandling
died,
Huh?
Yeah.
You see the socks?
Fucked up man.
Sixty six years old.
That's all right.
We were talking about before the
podcast.
What were you saying?
That there was a limo that was at his
driveway.
Didn't report on TMZ that said that he
had missed.
He had like was feeling sick the night
before called a doctor friend of his had
totaled my.
Yeah,
he should probably go to the hospital
tomorrow.
He's like,
okay,
I'll go to the hospital tomorrow.
So apparently he had booked a car
service take taken to the hospital,
but before that car had picked them up.
He had already had to call nine one one
because he was distressed and then.
Wow Man.
Yeah.
That came out of nowhere.
You know that that was not.
I hadn't thought about him being sick or
I didn't know him.
I only met him once.
He's very nice.
No,
met him.
I met him at the comedy Magic Club.
I didn't know him,
but damn,
he was funny.
He was funny,
man.
That Larry Sanders show was a hilarious
show and that's the show that got Paul
Sim started,
who was the executive producer of news
radio and the creative news radio.
He got his start in the Larry Sanders
show.
Um,
I mean,
I feel like a feel like it's awful and
everything that he died and especially,
you know,
66.
It's not even that old or 62.
How old was he?
60 six.
Sixty six,
you know?
But I think um,
I would least rather than I think
than the Robin Williams thing,
Robin Williams Swan was such a bummer to
me.
It's weird.
We're living in a weird time where
everyone we know is dying because all
the people that were TV stars and people
that like movie stars,
like of our generations are dying.
Like Robin Williams dead.
Are you kidding me?
Name Nancy Reagan's dead.
What the fuck?
I thought I couldn't believe Nancy
Reagan was alive when she died.
I was like,
yeah,
just tied.
Um,
yeah man.
There's been some weird ones.
The weirdest one is one who had died.
It's a burt reynolds to me because when
I was a kid,
burt reynolds was smokey and the bandit,
like he was so cool.
I remember he would drive that Trans am
and he had that mustache and everybody
wanted to be burt reynolds who's always
laughing and smiling and you're like,
God Damn Burt Reynolds is the shit dude.
Those smokey and the bandit days,
he was like the ultimate having a great
time guy because he was always smiling.
His movies.
It wasn't getting mad at anybody.
He always had that silly mustache.
He's smiling and drive around in his car
and hanging out with sally field back
when she was hot.
That was him all the time.
Just great sense of humor and always
smiling.
He's a bad ass.
They were great movies,
man nights.
Dude.
Burt Reynolds is the shit.
Especially back then.
He looked,
he was the shit.
But um,
there was an episode of that,
um,
garage.
A gas monkeys.
So it is gas monkey garage.
What's that?
Fucking fast and loose fast and fast and
loud.
Fast and loud.
That's it.
Yeah.
The car show fast and loud.
They built one of those Trans Ams,
like they had a one of those smokey and
the bandit trans men.
They were refurbishing it and they met
to meet.
They went to meet Burt Reynolds and man,
he was just struggling even to walk
here.
You can actually find Jamie just pulled
it up and you know this,
these guys,
they showed up at burt's place and when
he comes out,
man,
you see him walk in and like,
look at this.
See he's got a cane and he can.
He's all hunched over like he's
physically pretty fucked up.
Was He also in Cannibal run?
So smokey and the bandit was for some
reason I always thought those were the
same movies dude.
And he was awesome in his first movie or
his first big movie,
which is deliverance.
Do Deliverance was amazing.
We see him here.
Look at him.
He's,
he's hurting man.
He's hurting.
See,
seen walking up.
To me,
that's crazy.
I'm looking at this and I'm like,
how could this be?
It looks like he's got a back injury or
he's such a.
he's starting to hunch,
so hunched over.
He's,
he looks so.
I'm like just wounded and injured,
you know what I mean?
This whole body's just.
I always think of him as being that
fucking lively,
happy guy.
Time you motherfucker time you evil
bitch.
It's
weird to think about like the people
that just kind of fell off and I
completely forget about him.
Like,
like Tim Conway.
Is he alive?
Brendan Frasier.
Yeah.
The guy from the mummy movies.
There's certain guys that are giant
movie stars and then they just say,
ah,
I'm just going to stop doing this.
Or Society says it's going to stop
buying your movies.
One of those happens something.
Rick Maraniss how he just kind of like.
You quit.
Yeah.
He just quit.
He said,
I'm good.
You see David Letterman the other date,
that picture of David Letterman.
Oh my God.
It's like a wild man on top of a
mountain.
It's going to find that sasquatch and I
will bring back his head.
I could totally walk by him and not
think that's David Letterman at all
smart,
but now somebody outed them.
Yeah.
Fuckers shouldn't out at a man.
I guess if he throws his glasses on it
even more so.
Yeah.
If you do,
he's got.
He just kind to have a got to have a new
look to change it to red,
make it all red.
No one will know.
Look at that.
And if he died it all crazy.
You know,
he looks like somebody that would be in
a fishermen or boat.
Well he had some serious heart problem
too,
right?
Didn't you have to have surgery?
Yeah.
So along those lines.
He had some serious heart problems that
gets scary man.
Look at,
I'm out there jogging and shit.
That's why I can't wait to our body can
warn us like we'll have like,
like status lights,
like on my phone.
Like I get this notification like you
might be having a blood clot in your
left leg.
Are you still doing that diet thing?
Yeah,
I had that sickness that everyone has
that I think Jamie has now where it was
like a upper respiratory bronchitis kind
of flu thing that.
But mine lasted like three weeks,
so I had it for a whole week.
I had it for a while.
It might've been more than a week.
It might've been two weeks because I had
it for.
I had it for awhile and then I worked
out too hard and then a god had again.
I was like,
Whoa,
this super strong.
I was like,
this is a deceptive cold.
Like it's taken a long time to kick.
Yeah,
my voice is still kind of fucked up.
I mean I just got done hacking up
goobers for like a week.
It's not a good one.
Yeah,
so for.
For almost a month.
I haven't been to the gym since then
because I still don't like.
Maybe today I feel 100 percent,
but I still haven't been 100 percent for
awhile.
That's the thing,
man.
When you start feeling Shitty,
it's.
It's really important to give your body
a break and let your body rehabilitate
people.
They have this idea of sweating it out
maybe a little bit like a little
exercise.
We'll get your blood pumping and
there'll be.
As long as you're not putting it under
stress and strain,
but when you start thinking you're going
to work your way out of a cold,
you just going to make your body sicker.
Yeah.
I just been sleeping.
Just underestimated it.
Whatever.
I thought it was just a minor cold.
I'm like,
I'm just going to lift a little weights
here.
But uh,
the next day I was like woo.
And it had a little bit of,
almost every symptom like it came back
where I threw up like the flu,
Zika,
the Zika virus.
So don't get pregnant.
My little head baby dude.
Like this poor little head babies are
like,
oh,
the babies that get affected by it.
Oh,
how dare you.
Not all of them that.
Well,
I thought you were saying you were head.
I didn't know what you're talking about
the baby born to the Zika virus,
but are they going to be 100 percent
brain functional?
Like,
I don't know.
It's real dangerous apparently.
But you know,
I,
I don't know enough to really comment on
it.
I don't know how much of it is,
um,
medically proven fact.
But I think when women get pregnant and
they have it,
it's very dangerous.
I think.
Um,
that's what people are scared of.
I've heard people say they won't travel
now because of the Zika virus.
I have some friends that wouldn't go to
Florida.
She's,
they're pregnant.
They didn't move to close and what not.
Hey Man.
I mean if it's true,
I would feel the same way.
Imagine how fucking guilty you would
feel if you're like,
no,
fuck that I'm getting my party on.
No,
I'm going to Miami Bitch.
And you know,
like,
just showing a little bit.
You're like,
I don't give a fuck.
I'm hitting my last night.
Girl.
You'd feel so awful.
What?
A fucked up virus.
A virus.
It ruins the baby.
Now if she fucks a Hawaiian guy,
the head will be fine.
Right?
If she has the Zika virus,
why in guy or,
or somebody gets into the,
into steroids.
Some with a larger head of Polynesia.
Polynesia.
Like some always what you need.
You mean Samoan would've been a good
example.
I don't know what the fuck you're
talking about are normal sized people.
Uh,
I guess you're right there.
I mean there's some big Hawaiians like
the Rock,
you know?
Yeah.
But like,
um,
samoans are giant.
Okay.
So if it's a Mo and fucks,
some,
a woman with is like a virus,
will they have a normal size?
That would be a normal.
I don't think it works that way.
I would like to see.
I think someones just have better brain
structure,
jaw structure and like head structure.
They have a more sound frame to hold the
brain in.
But uh,
I think the fucking brain shrinks.
Dude,
I think it's some real issues.
You just said the rocky made me think of
it.
You know,
he's making the Baywatch movie right
now.
Yeah.
A ZAC Efron's in it with them.
Have you seen the pictures of Zac Efron
going around right now?
We're talking about all of that happened
then.
But what about them?
Is that steroids,
do you think?
Yes.
One hundred percent.
Can you get that?
You can definitely get that big without
steroids.
Do you have a young guy?
But hold on a second.
He's a young guy.
He's been lifting weights for years.
He had a six pack just a couple of years
ago.
Sure.
Um,
he was shredded and if you just steady
straight lifted weights for a long time
without doing anything.
Yes.
Like,
you know,
you've seen that video of me from that,
uh,
NBC from that um,
vh one fashion awards thing.
The,
that was,
yeah,
where I was naked and when I was in that
thing I barely lifted weights.
I mean I,
I did like Chin ups and I did some
weightlifting.
Mostly it was just doing kickboxing and
I had never taken anything.
No testosterone,
no steroids,
no nothing.
And I had quite a bit of muscle,
like there's certain people that are
more prone to being muscular,
especially if you've been doing
gymnastics or something like that,
like really young in life or wrestling.
A lot of wrestlers get it.
But for me it was kickboxing and a lot
of calisthenics and some weightlifting,
but not even that much.
Really.
Not like,
like a serious bodybuilder would be
doing it if I,
if I lifted once a week,
it was very,
it was very rare for me to stay steady.
I would lift like for a few months,
then I would stop and I'd go back to at
some point was I was dedicated way more
to kick boxing that I was to anything
else and I still put on a lot of muscle.
I take that back.
I've seen Zac is always at the comedy
store and when he's wearing normal
clothes he just doesn't look that
muscular,
but I just looked back 2010 and he's
been ripped since then.
So swimmer,
swimmer,
body.
Yeah,
but he's got a trainer.
I'm sure if you've got a trainer,
trainer makes you work hard,
you're going to get more muscle.
It's like you get to a certain level,
like like if you see a guy like me who's
48 and you see that he's.
He still has a good amount of muscle and
it looks thick most of the time.
That guy's taking testosterone,
especially today.
Today's Day.
Like the benefits of it are just so
obvious.
I mean you could not take it and just be
like a regular 60 year old guy and just
feel frail or you see these guys who
aren't taking it.
They're 60 years old that are fucking
shredded,
like you go to the beach,
go to like I'm fucking Maui or something
like that.
Go to the four seasons.
You'll see some businessman.
I was like in his sixties with six pack
and giant traps,
some 60 year old guy with a personal
trainers taking testosterone.
Like,
um,
I think that would be way better than to
be like
burt reynolds character look terrible.
There is 63.
Wow.
That he's using placement of that
floating device.
Hasselhoff was a very nice guy and he
was unfair factor.
So I will cease comment.
However,
there is a gigantic difference between
the left and the man on the right.
The man on the left hand screen is the
fucking rock and Holy Shit.
What a stud.
That guy is like,
look at the size of him and he's a huge
guy on top of that.
So you know,
the rock is like six,
three,
something like that.
Right?
Is He,
he's six three.
That sounds about right.
Probably to 72 gigantic.
I mean just shredded and dedicated.
Gets up every morning
worn out.
But again,
if I had to guess like the rock is a.
not that much younger than me.
I'm 48.
What is that guy?
Is he 44?
How old is he?
How it guest Brian Take.
Yes,
hit the rock.
Yeah,
I would say is if you're age 49,
43.
Here we go.
But point being,
I mean it's,
it's technically possible to be that big
without steroids and he does have an
insane work ethic,
but I would imagine he's taking
testosterone and it has to.
There's no shame in it.
Everybody's people weird about like
hiding that it's these are chemical
components of our body that we can
manipulate.
Not talking about taking massive amounts
of it because that's dangerous.
It's not smart.
It's not good for you.
It'll,
it's gonna fuck you up.
Like when when guys go too deep with it,
it's going to fuck you up.
But that doesn't mean that like low
levels of it aren't possibly helpful.
Take it.
Because the alternative is your body
just stops working.
Good.
I mean that's the alternative.
I mean everybody wants.
It's like there's a pride thing involved
in it.
Like where people don't want to admit
they need it.
It's a real weird.
When do you think is the,
or not the best,
but what's.
What do you think is a good way to
decide when you should take.
Go to a doctor for sure.
One hundred percent.
Yeah,
you should go to a doctor who really
understands what's going on,
where he's on top of the latest as far
as replacing hormones and what are the
benefits of doing it naturally,
where the benefits of augmenting it with
some sort of a synthetic hormone and
have a guy who's kind of a long history
of it,
who does blood work,
extensive blood work and wants to find
out how healthy you are and the first
thing they're going to do if he's good,
first thing they're going to do is
manipulate your diet.
That's the first thing they all do.
They all want to look at your blood work
and go,
look,
you're really low in d,
three this you that you needed to start
taking Niacin,
like what kind of foods are you eating?
Because you're just doing that.
Just lowering your sugar intake and all
your bullshit that you didn't and
alcohol.
Just that alone.
If you can minimize alcohol and lower
your sugar and take like really lower
it,
you'll have a big impact on your
hormones.
Just that it'll have a big impact on all
aspects of your body.
Your body will just work better.
Your insulin won't be so fucking spiked.
It just gets real weird when you start
chugging mountain dew all day and you
get like insane levels of sugar that a
lot of people get and I know people are
going to get all of this focus sugar
joke.
Talk about sugar too much.
I know,
I know you're right,
but.
But that's the part is they'll,
they'll work on your diet first.
So what they would do is they would,
they would check your blood,
they'd find out where your levels are of
everything,
including your thyroid hormones.
A lot of people have thyroid issues.
It might not even know about it.
I put my shit's all fucked up.
I bet all ABC and d probably you should
get it checked out and then you should
totally do that.
You know,
but if you're,
you have to be like willing to listen to
them.
If they say you have to drink water,
you have to take nice and you have to do
this,
you have to do that.
I want you to limit your amount of fried
foods,
trans fats,
which you find a good doctor that does
this.
Besides like maybe just a question
asker.
Backpage.
Good question.
You know,
it's funny because you don't want to
quack.
You know,
you don't want some fucking nutty dude.
He just wants to shoot you up with
steroids.
We want to.
You want to have a doctor that is
intelligent about how they approach it
and hopefully a doctor that's older than
you,
that's on it.
That's like best case scenario.
If your doctor's not taking hormones,
hm,
but you're.
But you're add,
dude,
what are you doing trying to stay alive.
What are you doing?
You know,
be talked to some 80 year old doctor and
he's fucking yoked.
That's the guy you want to listen to.
I'll go,
okay,
what's he doing?
What we doing over there?
Dude,
why so strong?
There's some old dudes that are involved
in power lifting competitions.
It's bananas.
I mean,
I don't know if they're pretending to be
natural.
I don't know how that works.
Are they allowed to do whatever they
want?
But I was watching these,
um,
these guys are,
they're in their sixties and they're
power lifting.
I'm talking like massive amounts of
weight.
Five,
600 pounds.
Watch guys,
peril,
power lift.
And I'm like,
what,
how,
how old are these guys?
And they're dead lifting 500 pounds,
600 pounds.
I'm like,
that's crazy.
Like,
those people didn't exist.
There was no 60 year old dead lifters 20
years ago,
but they didn't even think about doing
it.
Yeah,
there's a lot of those guys at my gym,
a lot of the old guys that you're like,
how is this guy still going to the
academy?
And his body's crazy looking because
when you have an old body mixed with
muscles,
it's really weird.
Well,
there's a big difference between a
person who's not doing well.
How old is that guy?
The Arnold Classic Europe.
Two thousand 12.
Over 60 posedown over 60 guys over 60.
That is.
Oh my God,
that looks like Cgi.
Doesn't that look fake since saying yes
with that guy's old man face.
Look at that.
That looks like it looks like Jay Leno
or something.
Especially as that.
We'll look at him.
He's dancing terribly.
His skin is kind of wrinkly and he's got
a cop mustache.
Got It all going on.
It's got a big enough tub with these
guys.
He's got the John Stossel over 60
shredded fuck.
See,
this is the difference between being a
man and being a woman too,
because I don't think that a woman
couldn't take some shit that will like
give her like a more feminine body as
she gets older.
You know what I mean?
Whereas the guy like these guys were
obviously taken some shit and they're in
their sixties and they have all this
muscle and they look like,
like fucking super athletes.
I mean that's what these guys look like.
It's ridiculous.
Guy Definitely looks.
It definitely looks crazy.
Nah,
didn't look right.
But that guy right there with the red
shorts and the far left like that guy
looks like he will be 30 years old.
That's insane.
The fact that that guy is 60 something
that's the same,
but my point being,
there's not anything like this available
for a woman.
A woman can't take something that like
makes her as she gets older,
look more like a younger woman.
Why do they all have to be that color?
Does that make it look better or
something?
Yeah.
The um,
they use that fake tanning shit because
the darker they are,
the more it highlights their
muscularity.
That old guy has got a flabby ass.
He shouldn't turn his ass to the camera.
Shaved it down to this little cute
Mohawk hipster.
Oh,
that's a.
Oh yeah,
I didn't even notice that.
So you had a 60 year old dude with a
Mohawk?
Maybe at first it could be the original.
Maybe never let it go.
Just get giant ab muscles.
This is getting gay
faces tripping.
Well,
let's wrap this up.
Let's bring it home.
You got anything else you wanted to talk
about?
Can we shut this bitch off?
Could shut this bitch.
Shut this bitch off and move on with our
lives.
Ladies and gentlemen.
It's been beautiful.
Is episode seven,
seven,
seven now,
so I thought it had to be you because of
all the,
your seven references that you threw in
all throughout the years.
That number haunts me.
So bad.
Why?
I don't know.
It just comes up so much now.
Okay.
Are sure I have a seven on my shirt to
you.
Uh,
I dunno,
I might,
I don't give a fuck.
How about that?
You gave a seven on your hat.
Brian?
Death Squad Dot TV?
Yes.
Oh,
I got a new shirt.
That's for a priori.
What is it?
It's the old pill shirt.
The one with the cat looking one bag.
Just have a black and white now.
Like,
like remixed it,
like different colors.
Beautiful.
And uh,
gigs coming up.
Desk squad dot TV.
When you guys got going on.
We're going to be in Nashville soon.
Vancouver next month.
But you do have wiseguys xannies.
Annie's Tony there.
And a Vancouver.
Yeah,
that's,
I'm,
I'm there.
I'm in Nashville too.
I'm at the Wyman w.
Why ryman Ryman?
Ryman Auditorium.
When is that?
What's the date on May 20th and Jamie?
Really Young.
Jamie on the ball?
Yeah.
In the,
in the neighborhood.
All right.
Uh,
anything else?
Oh,
what brian red band do his own podcast
now?
Yes.
Killing it.
Killing.
It hurts.
Dealing really well.
Yeah.
And uh,
this,
this uh,
next episode I'm about to release has
the Seinfeld Shit in it.
Oh,
what's the Seinfeld Shit?
The stupid question I asked them.
Okay.
Maybe you should about I did.
Um,
anything else?
That's it.
Alright.
You fucks.
That's it for this week.
Only one.
Only doing one,
but we'll be back next week.
Strong.
Full force CSUN.
Bye.