Hello,
freaky bitches.
No guy rule.
I can't bring guys over now guys.
I know sometimes it sounds like a sugar
daddy thing.
I had to strip,
right use the day.
She had a sugar daddy and she would just
buy them all a pile of shit,
which is great because I didn't have to
buy it and then I got that appointment.
I go,
you know what?
Maybe he should start getting me some
shit because I'm like,
Nigga out,
he's trying to fuck her.
Obviously.
Sudden I'm like,
well do I remember it was a VCR.
I'm like,
well get me a VCR because I don't want
to put up with their shit.
Meanwhile,
and then she'd come home with a VCR.
It's like I need to feed clr.
I'm like,
beautiful.
I actually went on a date with them in a
limo and pretend that I was the guy
friend and bad mouth myself for an hour
in front of this guy.
You that boyfriend of hers?
Like A.
Yeah,
he's a real dick.
Oh my God.
And we went to a mall and I picked out
like,
like 20 cds he bought me and I think he
bought me like a,
I forget it was like a Walkman at the
time or something like that.
I'm like,
yeah,
I'll take one.
And I'd be like,
sure.
You seem like a good dude.
Just fucking bad.
My Mike and the guys holding her hand in
the limo and I'm just sitting there like
the friend of my.
I don't give a shit.
I'm getting cds,
strong pimp move.
I tried to get a TV but he wasn't going
forward.
I see a lot of these guys,
the rocket like this,
the reason why they have two is because
of prostitution laws.
If prostitution was legal,
there's a lot of these older,
creepy dudes that are just out there
trying to make it happen.
It just tough action,
you know,
unless you're paying for it.
Very tough to get someone love you for
who you are.
Like if you had these really high
standards and your gross,
yeah.
But if you've got a ton of cash and
prostitution's legal,
if they just made prostitution legal in
America,
you'd have exactly the same amount of
hose.
Okay.
Exactly the same.
Listen to me,
they're not gonna know.
More people are not going to be hoes.
Hoes are hoes are ready.
They're just doing it in weird ways.
And maybe it'd be better.
Prostitution was legal.
So you found out exactly who the
tax it will pay.
Exactly.
Amazon one click stuff.
Nothing wrong with it.
It's just sex.
Is it okay to go get a massage?
Yes.
It's okay to pay someone to suck your
Dick.
It just is.
Yes,
it should be.
You know.
And these guys shouldn't have to move
these fucking girls biocar.
That's rude by the guy.
Friends.
Vcrs.
I shouldn't have to do it.
I felt bad just he's trying.
Figured he's trying to bang my check so
at least I should get some gifts out of
it.
Now.
How did you wind up ending this whole
relationship?
You know,
it was a stripper.
So it was just.
I mean with him,
I got
him out of your life.
It seems like he would want some return
for his investments.
He was doing what he was juggling,
like three different ones and he just
never.
I think he was fucking won,
but he wanted the fuck all three of
course.
And my chick had boundaries
while she said,
well,
I wasn't around.
She said she was no way.
I'm not going to sleep with them,
but that's true.
But he bought her tickets to.
She wanted me to buy her textbook for a
brand.
I'm like,
find your tits.
And he bought her tits,
tits.
Holy Shit.
Did you.
Did you guys go to dinner with this guy?
Just.
Yeah,
we went to dinner that just that night.
I only met him that one time I'd be at
the Bardo because you know the sugar
daddy always comes into strip club and
sits there and all the girls come out.
I was right across the bar just sitting
there just watching this guy.
I'm like,
I'm fucking that tonight.
Keep giving her money.
She take a meter to diner.
She's taking me to dinner later with
that money.
Okay.
You're the guy.
When the always people always talk about
Alec Strippers,
crazy boyfriends.
That's you.
Yeah,
the central one,
and I was like cutting lawns at the
time.
I was making like eight bucks an hour
and this guy said this guy is probably
like 300 grand a year.
He just created a.
well,
first of all,
Coen brothers movies are my ultimate
favorite movies of all time.
Like when I saw Donald Trump was running
for president the other day,
I said,
we live in a Cohen brothers movie.
It's official because his fucking Slob,
this goofy Slob is going to run his ego
just pouring out of his ears.
He ever met him.
No.
Weird dude.
And I'm sure we met him.
We did something on top gear where we
were trying to convince him to like pick
one of these cars that we had each pick
for the celebrity and we found out like
halfway through,
it's for Donald Trump.
And he basically was like,
uh,
this guy looks gay.
He's looking at tanner.
He's like,
I think this car,
you look gay.
So the car's probably for a gay person
and whatever tailored.
I don't remember what kind of car he had
picked potatoes.
Like what?
What did y'all tell?
Did you tell Donald Trump to make fun of
me?
That I look like.
I'm mean,
that's just what he does.
I just,
he just went for it and then he was
like,
oh,
I'll take yours.
Was He trying to be funny?
I think he was,
but he's one of those people that I
don't think he can hear other people.
I think maybe he can read lips a tiny
bit,
but like he walks into the room and all
you do is you look at his hair,
man,
you can't.
There is nothing an asteroid hit the
earth next door and you'd still be like,
man,
what's going on up there to that?
Like how do you get up every day?
And you say,
yeah,
this is the look like.
Those are the kinds of people that I see
in like his wife,
a malaria,
malaria,
some of them,
whatever her name is,
Larry Them.
That's one of those girls that I would
look at her and then look at him and
think,
there's no way you guys have ever had a
conversation,
right?
No.
You look at her,
you look at him and you go,
do you know Tom Arnold?
Is He did what you're doing when he did
it with a woman.
Right?
I see what you're doing.
I get ya.
It's all right.
Hey,
look.
It's better that than working at
Wendy's.
If these are your odds.
It's true.
What do you want to do?
Do you get Donald Trump's dick or get a
lot of money?
Do you get the free frosties cheats on
you did well.
I did.
Well,
Donald,
I got to give you that with your wacky
here.
If you're into that.
If you're in a what?
Tens?
Yeah.
Who's into that?
Who's in a hot chicks mouth shut.
I'm always thinking.
I was really thinking for her,
like if you're really into.
Oh,
she's not into that.
I don't know.
She's probably pilled up.
She'd probably just like stays on the
steady oxycontin.
Drip throughout the entire day.
Just stays mellow and weird.
Look at the gelatinous facial thing he's
got going on too,
was thrilled with the chandlers rolls
into his neck.
Colors is really interesting in that
hair too.
I'm telling you,
I hope you meet him.
Just I,
I hope not necessarily that you need
them,
but just that you're in in your life.
You end up in the same room and just
test my theory.
I honestly,
I couldn't look away.
Well the moment if I did meet him,
the moment he gets Dickie,
I go,
I will grab your fucking hair.
I'm just telling you ran down there and
then we'll find out what's going on.
So you might want to shut the fuck up.
What are you gonna do you gonna beat me
up?
Call security.
I Bet I'd get your hair before security
gets here.
I Bet I get to your fucking hair.
Dude.
Don't get picky with me.
Just the lead in this.
I don't touch her hair in the later
stages of my life or whatever where I'm
at.
I don't have any patience for people
like that.
Just don't have any desire.
I get it.
Like,
uh,
you know,
that's the reason why he's so
successful,
but you don't get to be a super fucking
billionaire.
Real estate mogul has his name on every
building dot trump towers.
Right?
You don't get that unless you have that
sort of an attitude.
So I guess I understand.
Stay there history,
put us up there once for the upfronts.
And uh,
I opened the little like mini bar and
his face was on the vodka
for me.
I was like,
this feels like too much bro.
It's just,
I feel like you gotta draw the line
somewhere
or you just go for it.
It would just go for it.
If you just keep going like the further
and deeper you go into the crazy ego,
swimming pool becomes like warmer water
because like it gets better is that he
can be like the Walt Disney of total
douche bag real estate moguls.
Is that
it?
It felt like Disney world.
I couldn't escape his face.
He's kept steaks.
Trump steaks.
Look above that.
JV.
I think those are made from a manatees.
I asked him,
I met Joe.
He's kind of,
I don't know,
I'll be honest with you.
John,
have a chip on his shoulder.
He was angry and stuff,
you know what I mean?
Uh,
he won't mind me telling you this
because they just don't beat meal.
And um,
he,
yeah,
he was an,
it was a bit like that and I seen him at
k one because I did k one in Los Angeles
while ago.
I was talking to him.
I said,
Yo,
miles bad then what you come across on
the Internet,
you're much better person than what you
act.
I can kind of still come with them.
They made me a friend on facebook and
then that concept and said,
do you want me to work with you anyway?
Yeah,
she'll cool.
And then we got on.
He's so smart.
He picks things up so quickly.
He's so open to stuff.
Um,
we've done some really,
really cool stuff.
That's I,
I can experiment on Joe,
if,
if that makes sense.
You know,
some things that I want to try.
I n a dude him and he seems to work
really well in him.
So like,
can you give us an example,
like what do you mean,
like things that you want to explore
that it's really strange but,
but he's like,
I had to think about because uh,
I mean lish have a gala hot date night.
It got to the knights of the roundtable,
king author on Joe didn't want to get
injured because he was going to fly,
I think he,
Robert something or other,
he was on glory and then he was going to
fight on ballots or against Melbourne.
Not have any way to come out on scathed.
So we persuaded his unconscious mind.
So I've armor likes the Gullah hat.
So I talked and Gnosis about the
archetype of Knights,
of the Knights,
of the round table and he will a heart,
not literally obviously,
but you know,
so we had armor so he didn't come.
So we'd come out on injured,
you know,
the words.
I'm not saying it's going to work for
everything,
you know,
I'll get,
so he bullets and stuff like that,
you know what I mean?
But it was just,
it was that,
again,
in mindset into that,
into that sort of the way of thinking.