President United States 20,
24.
Dave Smith is with me.
Is that a real date?
What is that?
A date was 2024.
That wouldn't be it,
right?
16,
20 slash 20 slash eight when I'll be
ready.
Dude.
You could pull it off when entered a
real libertarian candidate that could
fucking hang in there.
Someone who's going to break the mold.
Dave Smith and a stand up comedian as
well.
I didn't want this task,
but now that Joe Rogan's called you
could do it.
You're immune to all the trappings that
hit all those people.
Of course there's dirt on you.
You're a part of skank fest.
You know it's going to be.
There's a lot of grabbing by the
postseason.
You're on a podcast called the legion of
skanks.
It's could be introduced in a
presidential debate and then I have to
go.
Yes,
that was my shower.
but you would do it just like that and
everybody would start laughing.
We're realizing that this just do it
like a politician or I'd be like,
I repudiated that show years ago.
I no longer associate with big joker
seven dude speaking in which they put
wiener in the pokey today.
Twenty one months in jail for sexting.
I believe it was a 15 year old.
Well look,
I.
That guy,
single handedly probably changed
America.
Yeah.
I don't think she really did,
but he changed it through Dick Pics.
Which.
How else were you going to change
America in 2017?
The road edge,
Anthony Windier.
It gets hard time.
Is that the post?
The Post is hilarious.
Whoever writes for the post,
Goddamn they have some fucking great
headlines.
Anthony Wiener gets hard time.
Oh,
you know what's horrible is before all
this happened,
he was fantastic.
That guy could have been the president.
He was.
He had that politiciany thing.
I mean he was he and he was like for a
young politician on the fast track.
Yeah.
But he,
I mean,
I really do think Hilary Clinton.
I just think it was such a close race
that any little thing probably could
have made the difference.
So you could blame any number of
factors,
but I mean the FBI coming out and
reopening and investigation on you like
less than two weeks before an election.
That's pretty tough to get over
politically.
Like in any normal year,
any candidate would be buried by the.
After all that,
lock her up,
lock her up.
There's no way you can survive that.
The FBI is looking into it.
All the people that don't want to look
into it any further than the surface,
they immediately go,
oh,
we fucking got heads over.
And I,
you know,
like I think there's also just in terms
of the politics and the way people work,
there was something about Anthony Wiener
were so it just,
it made the American public think about
him again.
And trump was bringing the women who are
accusing Bill Clinton of rape to the
debates.
And I think the average person just kind
of went like,
wait a minute.
So.
So your husband is a sexual Predator art
and your best friend,
her husband is also a sexual predator.
Like who the fuck are these people?
Who the fuck are you that the story for.
Yeah,
well that's one of the that got me about
Fox News because Fox News has always
been the voice of conservative America
on television,
right.
These staunch verse,
the staunch Voice of conservative
America,
but yet all this sex stuff comes out
like the bill o'reilly tapes where he
was calling up as whoever the girl was
and saying crazy shit with a loofa
sponge.
Remember all that?
The,
I read about it.
It was crazy,
but they had recordings of it and then
it was,
you know,
the,
all the women that accused him of sexual
harassment and sexual harassment with
other people and other people are
sending Dick pics and like,
wow,
you guys are freaks.
And you know,
it was really crazy about it was that so
Roger Ailes,
who is the head of the network,
she went down first for sexual
harassment and then as soon as he was
down like a whole bunch of other people
started going back and then you really
start wondering like,
Oh shit.
Like was it just like a new guy isn't
letting us sexually harass anymore?
What's going on with this?
Well,
I think it was just there was a culture
that they could get away with before the
Internet where they were the bosses and
the women were the underlings and they
all felt.
I'm sure there's probably a lot of
dynamics plan there,
right?
There's a power situation.
The man,
the guy who's the boss is in position
and then there's also women that are
attracted to power figures and then
there's also this conservative like
really repressed environment,
which always leads to freak shit.
It always does.
Yeah.
We have like people buttoned down.
They always lead to frequently.
They have to find a way out that
pressure.
It's got to go.
You're right.
I mean,
I always say to people,
if you're in a.
If you're in New York City,
if you go to a bar in the financial
district,
like right after work,
it's a really crazy scene.
Something interesting like the exact
dynamic you're talking about.
Whereas these people who are all day
working in this crazy like this and then
like the ties are loosen.
Then it's this like drinking and they
take their shoes off at the bar and I'm
like,
whoa.
People are getting slapped on the ass
like crazy shit is going on that you
wouldn't think your banker,
you know the guy,
the guy who runs your retirement
account.
You know why?
Because like we were talking about
before with like before the podcast
started with like these ancient reward
systems,
there's an ancient reward system for
plundering.
I really believed that.
I think these guys feel like their
goddamn pirates,
like they're plundering,
makes sense.
They're part of the financial market and
then they're doing shots.
We're going to fucking check and take
them down.
They grab each other,
we're going to fucking take them down.
We're going to take them down.
And if you think about,
I mean if you think about the
acquisition of property of goods or
anything like that throughout human
history,
I mean the idea of like a,
just a theory of just acquisition of
property is like relatively new and the
way everything was acquired for all of
human history was through conquest.
Just,
you know,
you take it,
you take other people's Shit and you got
to think that like a hostile takeover
must feel incredibly like sacking the
city.
Again,
these guys,
oh,
that's from Wall Street from uh,
what's his name wasn't Wall Street.
What the fuck was it called?
A wolf of Wall Street.
Yeah.
That was a great scene.
But people resonate.
That scene resonated with people.
I'm not fucking going.
And everybody said it's like being above
the system kind of tapping in just same
way football taps in.
It's tapping into this ancient reward
system for plundering when men get
together and they fuck up other men and
take all their shit and then we kick
ass.
It's unbelievable how much.
I thought about this a lot this last
year through the election,
but like it's unbelievable how much like
that football team dynamic is just the
whole thing.
Like it's like human beings love to get
into a stadium to be like red team,
blue team identified with one team and
lose their freaking minds.
Like literally lose their minds and
that's when they know it's meaningless.
It's just about a ball crossing a line.
And this has absolutely no.
We'll still bring God into it with brand
team into all these.
And again,
you see like with this trump thing now
that he just stepped on,
me and Jamie were joking around before
we started like a,
or it's like he,
he liked threatening nuclear war and
insulted Steph curry in,
in one thought I'd ever.
Everyone in America is like,
excuse me,
what was that second?
Excuse me?
What did you say?
And both sides,
like this is just what gets them
interested.
Well,
we are a gossip country now,
like 100 percent officially,
like what we'd like is a squabble
between the leader of the free world who
is a reality star and some of the best
basketball players that have ever lived.
Like,
Oh shit,
it's on football players.
I mean Le Bron James is making videos
about the president being a douchebag.
He's making videos about all these
different people like expressing their
right to free speech.
I saw one of the tweets that he,
uh,
he tweeted out at the president where it
was like,
just kind of like a broken English
tweet.
Like he used the word ain't a lot in it,
just like.
And it's just him verse trump.
And I just had a moment where I was
like,
so this is where the national
conversation is at now,
like,
do you remember,
I just remember watching like a William
f Buckley vs Gore v down to Bates.
And you're like,
how fucking retarded has our country
gotten?
Have you seen the documentary?
Yeah,
it's amazing.
Really interesting.
If you haven't seen it focuses on
Netflix.
What is it called?
Something I don't remember.
Bitter rivals.
Yeah.
No,
that's something that's called bitter
rivals.
That might've been a UFC event back in
the early two.
Thousands.
Sylvia,
best of enemies.
Enemies.
Thank you.
Stupid pattern.
I don't know.
50 four obliteration.
Yeah,
I was saying they're gonna run out of
adjectives and they realized eventually
we are.
This is so stupid.
But you don't ever say.
It's never like a verse.
Sixers slam fest.
Total slam fest.
Yeah.
Like you'd never have a name.
It's just the world series.
It's just the fucking super bowl.
It's never.
It was never a,
you know,
domination event.
Oh,
they figured it out somewhere along
line.
But
what we're talking about.
Oh yeah,
how crazy it is to see that this is all
going on while Puerto Rico has no power
and only five percent of it has cell
phone service.
Holy Shit.
You want to talk about.
There's some.
There's a weird racist thing that we
will like if that was an island filled
with white people,
do you really truly think it was an
island filled with white people that
spoke perfect English and it sounded
just like us.
Do you think we have so little coverage
of Puerto Rico the way we do now?
Oh,
Puerto Rico is technically a part of the
United States.
It's not a state,
but it's technically like we had on
Peter Schiff.
Yes.
We just had a mother who was was
fantastic.
Amazon.
He just moved his whole team down there.
Boy,
Betty's regretting that now for a guy
who's known for predicting the future,
he really,
really missed that one was like that
moment and that that animated Gif with
that black kid has got glasses and a and
everyone around us doesn't.
He just did Peter Schiff.
For guys knowing to predict the future
where he did fucking do,
you don't see the destruction of your
empire by God himself.
Turns out you can only predict the
subprime mortgage crisis,
not acts of God.
Fuck Dude.
And there's another one along the way.
Look at this one,
this one over and over again.
This is great.
That kids faces fucking classic.
Like if he shut you down and gave you
that face,
you'd be like,
fuck.
He got me.
There was no counter argument after this
has happened to you,
but you just accept that you lost.
Yeah,
I mean you might be able to like gain
some ground afterwards with a couple of
good insults,
but fucking contest is over.
If that's like a halfway through a roast
battle,
just call it for the judges to know when
to walk away to with a loss because it's
way worse if you stay there and keep
swinging.
Just keep getting fucked up.
When that guy gives you that face,
you gotta go,
you gotta go get.
I'll come back and fight another blocks.
Pilots about.
Definitely can't believe it.
I mean,
that might be like one of the V perfect
events in human history.
Forget about like,
uh,
you know,
planting the flag and Iud Jima,
this dude,
this dude making that face that will be
used,
who knows how many,
countless hundreds of thousands of
times.
How many times did that thing been used?
It maybe millions,
right?
If,
if a youtube video get millions of hits,
that's probably in the millions.
Millions of times used for sure.
Right.
But yeah,
so it's a weird fucking time with all
this because we're concentrating so much
on weird stuff.
Like whether or not you should stand for
the flag or Neil and first of all,
I think what they're doing,
if correct me if I'm wrong,
they're protesting cops shooting
innocent people.
That's what it's about.
So it's kind of ineffective on their
part,
the message,
because you have to listen to them
afterwards.
Right?
It seems like you don't like America,
right?
That's what people have a problem with
and trump's plan on that,
that they get down on one knee and you
know,
I mean,
it's kind of weird because it's kind of
respectful as all.
Also getting down on one knee for the
flag is actually more respectful than
putting your hand over your heart,
which is really weird.
Right,
so they.
They're supposed to be protesting cops
who have shot innocent unarmed people,
which have been a fuck load of them,
but that's a weird way to do it because
you're doing it during the anthem.
The anthem isn't those cops.
The anthem is all of us,
so it's.
It's a shitty way to divide because it's
not really making a whole lot of sense
because the people who wrote the star
spangled banner who were singing it
right now,
the people who have sung it all
throughout the years and stood there,
they aren't the ones that shot those
unarmed people.
What you have is a cop who was a
probably a nervous wreck,
most likely has been operating with ptsd
for the past five,
six fucking years.
You have friends that are cops.
A few.
Yeah.
They tell you crazy shit,
right?
Yeah.
You know,
I know a bunch of cops,
especially from Jujitsu.
I know a ton of cops and and from the
UFC as well.
They tell you some fucking horror
stores,
things that they have to deal with,
like they stumble upon a crime scene.
Guys got half his fucking head missing
people chopped up,
you know,
all sorts of dark,
dark,
dark shit and it's in their head all the
time.
They've had buddies get shot in the face
at,
you know,
routine traffic stops.
Everybody's freaked out because over the
course of 20 years,
you're a police officer.
You have seen a fucking amazing amount
of shit,
probably unfit for the job.
These guys that are shooting people and
we think about the vast number of people
that are cops that aren't doing this,
the Internet,
all the interactions were concentrating
on these terrible things that obviously
there's no defense for it,
right?
There's no,
no,
no.
Defending someone shooting a 13 year old
boy with a plastic gun.
There's no.
There's no defending any of the crazy
stuff that we saw.
The Guy who shot the guy and he had
planted the Taser.
There's no defending any of this.
Right,
but how many interactions are cops
having with people where this doesn't
happen?
A fuckload man,
like let's keep some perspective because
the other end and if you live in a
country with 320 million people and you
see one incident or a few incidents
there,
there's no perspective there so you can
find it.
Any,
any example to paint whatever narrative
you want to.
If you're just going off random
examples.
God,
I really like it.
It's really frustrating for me because
the whole.
It's like the whole trump thing and the
whole moment we're in now,
it's all about a culture war.
Like that's what it's really about.
It's not about politics or policy or
anything.
It's really a culture war and what you
have here and this is why everyone gets
so into the kneeling for the national
anthem thing because it's symbolic of
two cultures and to me it's like I,
I,
I see the worst in both,
which is really frustrating.
So it's like the left wing thing is just
this bash America with no perspective,
like no fucking perspective at all.
So it's like,
yeah,
I'm right.
So there'll be protesting,
say like cops being shot or something
like that,
which you can say certainly there are
legitimate cases of that and I'm a
person who
believes we have like a real real police
problem in America and,
and we have like just insane amounts of
arrests for nonviolent crimes,
really fucked up,
Shangri mass incarceration,
all these fucked up things.
Um,
uh,
that being said like there's also
justifiable shootings,
shoot cops do,
you know?
Um,
but so,
so you have these people taking a neat.
But it's kind of like symbolic to people
who aren't on the left of this culture
of like everything over the law on the
left is just like anti America,
anti capitalist,
Anti White Man,
anti man in general and anti Western
civilization with no perspective,
like no perspective of like,
you know,
just like Americans is white supremacist
country.
It's like,
well,
what does that mean?
Like compared to what,
you know what I'm saying?
And I'm not saying it doesn't exist,
it's like,
but it's like when they say like we live
in a rape culture,
it's like what does that mean?
If I'm like,
we live in a robbery culture,
there are robberies,
but compared to what?
So if you're going to say we're a white
supremacy culture,
to me it's kind of like saying,
it's like saying America is a poor
country.
I mean,
I,
I suppose compared to some richer
country in the future that's figured
some shit out that we haven't compared
to everything else that's ever existed.
We're a rich country.
So if you're talking about white
supremacy,
it's like,
well no,
by and large were probably the best like
melting pot and most diverse,
most inclusive,
most,
uh,
like we feel more guilty for the sins of
our past than pretty much any other
country commercial.
And I don't know any country that like,
you know,
it's like America was founded by
conquest of the native Americans.
It's like,
right.
And so as every single other country,
and so,
and every country had slavery in every
country had all these things.
It's not no one,
150 years ago,
it wasn't fucked up.
That doesn't exist.
Right?
And so if you have some perspective,
the left wing thing gets pretty
frustrating after awhile.
However,
then on the,
on the trump side,
so I've kind of been more sympathetic to
the right than the left probably over
the last year and a half because I
really do see like the issue of our time
becoming this like are you for free
speech are against free speech that that
to me is like really because we don't
really figure things out unless we get
to debate them.
We can't have been topics and we can
have topics that are supercharged to the
point where they're.
You can't have a position on them.
Yeah.
And you can't explore them.
There is a real powerful.
Yes.
That's it.
That's exactly right.
I mean it's,
it's one reason I think there's many
reasons,
but that's one of the most important.
Like why we need free speech because
unless you fucking.
Unless you come from the position of I
have everything 100 percent correct.
Like then maybe you need to have a
conversation and someone has a
conversation back with you because odds
are you don't have everything 100
percent correct.
It's their correct versus your correct.
Like they're correct.
Is Gender Quality?
They're correct.
Is transgender rights?
Is Socialism there?
Correct.
Is like,
and if you.
Obviously I'm talking about people far
left,
not talking about you.
If you're listening just I'm talking
about the hypothetical extreme far left
person that is protesting Ben Shapiro on
Berkeley campus calling him a Nazi,
but this isn't.
This isn't just,
you know,
a right,
it's not you're making,
you're talking about a hypothetical
person,
but obviously this is happening in
reality.
They exist lots of them and there's
enough to the point where like it's like
this real thing where,
okay,
so the great threat to free speech and
our time isn't coming from the state,
which by the way,
like as a libertarian that would be more
comfortable to my narrative.
Like that's what I've been thinking for
years is the great threat to free
speech.
But no,
it's coming from this left wing culture
that says a right.
Like Ben Shapiro can't speak Milo
Yiannopoulos can't speak Condoleeza Rice
can't speak about it.
Look,
if,
if Ben Shapiro and Jordan Peterson need
to be silenced,
I mean that.
My only problem with those two is that
there to moderate.
Like these are like,
these are not bigots,
these are not these,
these are intellectuals making an
intellectual argument and they can't
even speak.
So it's,
it's very scary.
And then the other thing I would just
say on this left wing culture and is
what cabarnet kind of embodies to meet
is just the,
it's this frustrating ignorance like
this client.
So you'll be protesting police brutality
and mass incarceration and then like
you'll put a Castro image on your
jacket.
Like,
I mean,
come on man.
Come on dude.
You can't,
you can't stand up for something and
swing and miss that big like that.
So like you got to research a little
bit,
I mean do five minutes.
All the information is on your phone.
Like I just don't.
So there's that and I get being against
that and I want to be like on the free
speech side and I see a lot of these
guys like who will bring up like Steven
crowder and Ben Shapiro guys you've had
on your show who I really admire a lot
because they're fighting against that.
And Jordan Peterson fighting against
that anti authoritarian authoritarian pc
antifreeze speech stuff.
So I kind of more sympathetic to the
right,
but then there's this thing with the nfl
where,
and it really just reminds me of all the
cultural aspects of the right that I
hate,
which is when,
first of all,
I'm sorry,
someone who's standing for freedom of
speech.
I'm pretty fucking troubled by the
president of the United States,
the man who's in control of the most
powerful army in the military and the
history of human humanity coming out and
saying,
I think if someone takes a need,
they should be fired.
Now that may not be writing a law
against a speech,
but that's pretty fucking chilling to
have like the government telling you,
hey,
you know,
what would please me is if you started
firing people when they spoke out
against me,
I don't like that.
And this fucking right wing,
like praise the flag.
And if you say anything against it,
you're,
you're in a.
it's like religious,
like it's blast for me.
It is a criticize the troops or
criticized the country.
Like fuck that.
Yeah,
it is a power issue.
When I was going to say earlier is that
when you were talking about the state,
when you were talking about the fear of
the state and the censorship coming from
the state,
it's the same thing because the state is
just power and the far left is power too
and it's power with shame and with blogs
and with protests and it is the power
that they're trying to exercise to get
you to behave the way they want you to
and the right does the same thing.
I think what we should have if we're
gonna,
if we're gonna really keep doing this
whole,
we're a country thing.
We should have like an armistice when
then this is I think reasonable people.
Reasonable people have an issue with
this idea of desecrating the flag
because the flag is just a flag and it's
not important,
but what is important is that we treat
each other like we're a team and we look
out for each other and we're all
together and we're all united together.
We shouldn't be fun.
If we have an issue,
our issue should be with communist
dictatorships across the world that have
nuclear weapons that are holding their
people captive,
like if it was ever a time to look at a
country and go,
wow,
this is a country that is in an unjust
position and it's a really terrifying
dilemma that you have this murderous
dictator who's in control of nuclear
weapons and he has an entire country of
people enslaved,
which is essentially what's going on in
North Korea.
Right.
It's basically like a giant hostage
situation that's,
that's a real giant issue to us.
It's not whether or not transgender
people can use the fucking males,
the men's room or the women's room.
That's not our issue.
That's,
that's,
that's a cultural conversation and that
cultural conversation should become.
And we should be friendly to each other
because we're supposed to be on the same
team though.
I agree with you,
but that stuff with the like the
transgender bathrooms,
I got to say man,
and it's really weird for me sometimes I
just can't.
I can't even believe I hold some of the
positions I do because I grew up like a
kind of left wing kid and uh,
you know,
I was raised by a single mom in New
York.
I kind of like,
that's kind of where I belong
culturally,
but I really can't,
you know,
it's almost like the Kooky conservatives
who,
the religious coogee conservatives who I
just dismissed for years is like,
this is just insane.
Had more of like they had a grain of
truth that I didn't realize they'd be
like,
uh,
you know,
you can't legalize gay marriage or
they'll start coming after the kids and
you're like,
well,
that's just insane.
Anybody like gay marriage gets legalized
it.
Like the next year they're like,
kids should be able to take hormones to
suppress the.
And you're like,
Whoa,
this is kind of weird.
It's very weird to me that the left
didn't take like a minute to celebrate
this victory on gay marriage that they
had been fighting for like my entire
life.
They got a huge victory.
The Supreme Court came in and forced it
on the remaining 20 states or so who
weren't ready.
We weren't going to vote for it.
They forced it on them and there wasn't
a big backlash like that.
One chick went to jail for like three
days.
It's not like the one in Oklahoma with
gay folks,
Wendy Davis Owens,
and then she and then it's not like,
oh,
there was like this wave of Republicans
who rose up like,
we're going to repeal it.
We're going to write a law to reverse
that supreme court decision.
It's like,
no,
actually they elected the first pro gay
marriage president.
It's like you won on this issue and
immediately as soon as they won,
they're like,
now transgender bathrooms.
Now this now.
Well,
I think,
I don't think they're related.
And this is why I think,
um,
first of all,
the gay marriage thing is consenting
adults.
They should be able to do whatever they
want to do.
The difference between gay people and
transgender people is pretty radical.
No great.
If almost the same difference as between
straight people and gay people there.
But they're in the same four letters
according to the left,
but that whole Lbgtq a plus,
whatever the fuck it is now,
there's a bunch of new ones that they've
added on asexual.
No,
I agree with you.
I think it's actually insulting that
they lumped them together as if it's the
same thing.
I mean,
I think it's a weird that when trump
tweeted the thing
about trans people not being able to
serve in the military,
I saw a bunch of people being like,
trump has come out against lgbt rights
and you're like,
what the hell does this have to do with
lg?
Or be like,
what?
Why is that crazy?
They're just a gang.
Lump it all together.
A big progressive gang of acronyms,
but the,
the.
They're always going to say about all
this stuff being lumped in together is
that the left has been the side that has
looked towards the hard science when it
comes to global warming.
Right?
The hard science when it comes to
climate data,
those are the ones that are always
pushing whether they're right or wrong
or getting the right data.
They're the ones that are really harping
on the science and if you looked in
terms of the amount of people that are
working in universities,
there are far more left than there are
far more left.
Professors now are right,
so you would think,
okay,
you have this base of academia and
knowledge on the left,
but yet the left is the side that's
willing to entertain the idea that a
young kid should take hormones to alter
their sex.
When you know for a fucking fact that
when you're a young person,
you're extremely confused,
constantly back and forth,
left and right.
There are hormonal changes.
The cerebral cortex,
the frontal cortex isn't even really
fully develop.
They don't say you're a real fully
developed until you're like 25 if you're
a man,
which explains a lot of the shit that I
did.
Right.
It's a lot of people listening that are
20 and retarded that like,
what the fuck am I doing with my life?
Exactly.
Dude.
You're barely an adult.
Oh,
you're thinking about things you do at
like 22 and you're like,
I can't believe I'm the same human
human,
but so this same party,
the same progressive mindset that is so
incredibly open minded but yet also so
deeply embedded in academia like far
more than the right is this is the side
that is willing to put aside all that
they know about biology and psychology
and physiology and children.
Put aside that a lot of people are not
all in one lump.
Anybody together put aside that for
Progressive Brownie points for saying
that you are so incredibly open.
Like this child obviously knows that he
is a.
She or she is a he and we need to start
addressing them as that and this is just
a fact.
Well,
it's not just a fact.
It's a conversation that we should have
and I think it varies in individuals and
I think there are some people that I
have personally talked to the
transgender people that for sure are
happier being a woman or a man and they
were born in what they feel is the wrong
body.
And I absolutely 100 percent salute
their right to go out and do that,
but we should have a real conversation
as to how many people is that really
happening to me?
How many of these people have a
psychological issue?
How many people.
Is there a physical trait that we're
missing?
Is there a,
some,
some switch that gets flipped when
they're young?
I mean it's a fascinating aspect of
human beings that you are one sex and
wish you were another.
Right.
And it seems strange to me that on the
left the rules always seem to be.
There's this topic like it's like the
left forever.
It's
always like we need to have a national
conversation about race.
But if you say the wrong thing,
I want you ruined.
Yeah.
You know.
And it's the same thing with like the
transgender thing.
It's like they want to like,
it's like we want to have a conversation
about this.
They put this forward as like this is an
issue we need to talk about.
And then also,
by the way,
you're not allowed to say anything.
So if you bring up the 40 percent
suicide rate and say maybe this isn't
due to societal oppression because
there's no real link between societal
oppression and high suicide rates,
now you need to be fired or something,
you know,
say 40 percent of transgender people
commit suicide and the people that want
to support the idea that there's not any
sort of a mental illness in any people
on shore.
It's not in some.
We're not generalizing,
but it must be in some.
Right.
The people that want to deny that side
of the reason why they are suicidal is
because they don't get a chance to
express their genuine,
authentic self,
which is a very good point.
So it's not.
It's not that either or.
No,
I'm.
I'm open to the argument,
the argument that the 40 percent is
possibly.
It's maybe a combination of those two
factors.
Maybe there's some people that are
mentally ill that are suicidal in the
first place and they hope that maybe
becoming a woman would make them feel
better and it didn't work out.
There's a.
there's a whole website where people,
I think it's called transgender regret
or something like that and it's all
people that switched over and we're like
really upset that they did it and then
realized it was like some strange phrase
they were going through or whatever,
and then you know,
there's,
there's people that are sure suicidal
because they want to be one way and
people just constantly shit on them and
bullied him and heckle them and they,
that's what's causing them to be so
deeply.
It's not like one or the other.
No.
And I think in every individual case
there's probably like a complex,
a complex set of different cause causing
factors.
So yeah,
I agree with that.
I just think it's like,
no matter how low,
obviously I'm for,
you know,
like everyone owns their own body and
she's able to do whatever they want to
it.
If you can find a doctor who was willing
to perform a surgery on you,
you know,
whatever surgery you want to have.
And,
and I think transgender people should
have the freedom to do that.
Truthfully speaking though,
I don't really see anyone.
Not that anyone is in saying that,
but I don't really see anyone
disagreeing with that.
You know,
like most people seem to agree are
people that think it's a sickness and
they absolutely shouldn't be allowed to,
but what is it seems like that's pretty
rare.
Like even the people who are getting a
lot of,
a lot of heat for,
for their stance on transgender issues.
Like I've never heard Gavin mcinnes say
it should be illegal.
I've never heard like Ben Shapiro say it
should be illegal.
What they will say is that I'm not going
to pretend that you're a what?
You're a woman.
I'm going to acknowledge that you have a
y chromosome.
Like that to me is like okay,
that has nothing to do with your freedom
to have a surgery.
He,
this guy has a free freedom of thought
to describe what's going on and it is
kind of crazy like you said with the
global warming thing.
Like it's like,
yeah,
the left Prague themselves on being the
science party.
Like we believe in science.
Although the problem is that I try very
hard to like wrap my head around all of
these different issues and I've read a
decent amount on climate change and I'm
pretty tough,
pretty tough stuff.
It's not
easy.
It's not like some of these other issues
that are much easier to understand and I
will say that about 90 percent of the
people on the left who are like have the
science,
they haven't looked into it.
They've just been told this is the
science and they're like,
oh great.
Now I get to bash people by having the
science because if you're going to say
like you're the side that that believes
in science.
I'm sorry to deny that there are
biological effects on biological effects
on gender is,
but that's science as you be such a
small fringe group that do make that
distinction.
They think that there's no biological
difference in the sexes there.
Those people are really just crazy.
The idea of pushed it so far,
they're so far left that there in some
crazy alternative reality.
There are a lot of those.
I look at it like the same way a year.
Like,
um,
scientologists have like their levels I
look at like,
like left wing ideology,
jc or something like the social justice
warrior who's like out in the front
lines protesting Christina Hoff summers.
She's like top level left wing mindset,
but there's a lot.
But no,
the idea that gender is a social
construct is pretty well accepted I
think on the left.
And to me that is insane.
That's true.
I think it's only accepted in a very
fringe group,
especially academics.
Maybe you're right,
and people in school that protest about
it and people that are super active
social justice warriors.
I think if you polled people,
whether or not they think there's a
biological difference and you gave them
three choices.
Yes,
no.
And Dha that most people would say,
Da Da,
here's what,
here's the only thing I'll just,
I,
I think you're 100 percent right.
If they were taking that test
anonymously,
anonymously to put their names behind
it,
I think you'd get a much different
answer.
I talk to college professors,
like my sister's a college professor.
I talked to our friends.
I talked to other people.
A lot of them will come up to me and
it's almost like this thing,
like at a dinner table,
it's like get close and be like,
hey,
just so you know,
I really agree with you on like a lot of
stuff and I'm not,
you know,
like it'll be like the people who for,
for the one Jordan Peterson,
who by the way a guy like Jordan
Peterson really does beg the question,
why aren't there more Jordan Peterson's
like,
why is it just you and five other
people?
Why are there not more professors?
And the reason is because they're all
intimidated.
Look at all the shit he's had to deal
with.
They're all intimidated by that.
Bret Weinstein,
who's a super progressive guy,
I mean he's way left and he got shamed
and he got like literally threatened.
I mean,
and now he just won a lawsuit though.
He just got paid $500,000.
We had him on like right after Evergreen
College had to shut down and kids were
patrolling the fucking parking lot with
baseball bats.
Looking for him.
Like it was really crazy,
man.
It's insane.
Really crazy stuff that the left,
I mean,
imagine if that was coming from the
right,
you would start calling them Nazis.
He started calling them white
supremacists.
You start calling them thugs,
but on the left they conveniently ignore
the same types of pattern.
It's so unbelievable.
Like the double standard of life.
A dude will look.
So you have like the,
the,
the thing that happened in
Charlottesville,
right where you have like,
I mean I'm a few hundred
people marched and,
and I guess there were dozens of them at
least at least who were like wearing
Nazi gear,
which is,
you know,
don't get me wrong.
I mean it's pretty eyeopening and like,
Holy Shit,
I mean,
what?
It's,
it's like disturbing and kind of very.
It very interesting to me that anyone in
2017 in America is putting a swastika
on.
Not only that,
these dumb fucks got together in public
with lit their face with torches so
everybody can take video and photos of
them and March student street together,
yelling like blood and soil and all
sorts of weird fucking shit.
Like what would the quotes that they do
you remember?
What the Jews will not replace us was.
Wow.
What can I tell you is that as a Jewish
person,
I've never felt more empowered in my
life than the Jews will not replace what
an unbelievable.
Like I've never even entertained the
idea of replacing anybody.
And then when they're like,
the Jews will not replace us.
I think we can replace these
motherfuckers got worried about it.
Let's make a move.
Jews,
let's go replace these Charlottesville.
How many people were there?
The protest?
100.
I think between three and $400.
That's it.
That's a good size crowd.
That would be psyched if they came to
see me,
right?
If I,
if I walked into that on the road,
I'd be like,
oh,
that was the line again.
Theater.
You're like,
oh,
we're doing good tonight.
And they'd be like,
it's pretty white supremacy in Italy and
here.
There really,
uh,
I mean,
at first I thought it was well lit.
Can they bring their Tiki torches inside
or a sticker on a dirt outside?
Who's going to funny to watch those
fires and how to get to know which
torches yours has got the.
We got a guy,
we have numbers.
We got it all figured out yet she passed
Walmart Torch when you had a nice home
depot torch.
Good solidly constructed American Home
Depot Choice and some dude stole your
shit and left you with some main Chinese
bullshit.
That would be.
I'll vto bullshit and it's probably just
good enough that you get halfway through
the march before you're like,
wait a minute.
Look up and you see made in China.
Fuck.
I knew this felt light used to have a
little American flag under each.
A little metal bonnet.
Let's get real.
They were all made in China.
Yeah.
Probably.
This is not a big market for Tiki
torches,
but anyway,
I was saying,
but these guys like,
I mean nobody even like people who are
real far ahead on the right wing who are
like pretty,
you know,
considered,
like whoever,
like Ben Shapiro who was being protested
by these guys,
he doesn't associate with any of those
guys.
I disgusted by them.
Gavin McInnes won't associate with any
of these guys.
He's disgusted by them.
These guys can't even speak at their own
rallies.
They don't come to the right wing.
Does a,
I think a fairly decent job at just
being like,
no we're not.
We're not even associated with trump.
Did Not denounce them correctly.
Well,
no,
I don't think so.
I mean,
look,
from what I saw,
I actually thought it was a weird
reaction to what trump said.
It's like,
it's like,
so what I'm saying is I see this going
on here with,
with the one thing that happened in
Charlottesville,
right?
And I haven't seen too much Nazi stuff
outside of that,
right on the Internet.
But I mean like in terms of response.
But this will just make this point
because I to address what you're saying.
But.
So then this happened,
this one limited.
There's one thing with a few hundred
people in Charlottesville happened.
The media goes fucking nuts.
Like,
this is the biggest thing that's ever
happened on the other side,
on the left wing side,
everywhere that someone tries to have a
free speech rally everywhere.
Anyone who's,
who's one step to the right of Bernie
Sanders wants to speak like Condoleezza
Rice can't speak like anyone who's one
step to the right of Bernie Sanders gets
shut down.
And there is this mob,
okay,
called Antifa,
who,
who actively go after assaulting people
and this isn't just Nazis,
they go after trump supporters or
anyone,
anyone who disagrees with them,
they were hammer and sickle flags,
which is,
you know,
represent representing an ideology that
killed more people than the Nazis.
So,
you know,
let's put them both on the level of like
genocidal horrible,
uh,
groups.
However,
this one group on the left is going
everywhere across the country and are
given comfort and aid by college
professors.
So when,
then my ears.
Yes,
yes,
there actually.
And when it's brought up and it's
actually backed up by things like 40
percent of millennials in a Chicago
University,
a study,
a state,
they don't believe in free speech for
hate speech,
which basically means you don't believe
in free speech.
You've got about 40 percent of
millennials who don't believe in free
speech.
You have to define hate speech.
And that's where things get slippery and
what you might call hate speech is so
different from me,
right?
What I might,
what you might call hate speech is me
saying that I don't want to call a
transgender woman,
uh,
her right?
That well,
let's.
And that has been,
that has been labeled hate speech.
That's a microaggression.
These are all.
So it's like,
once you define that,
it's like,
oh,
you can punch a Nazi.
But by the way,
everyone who disagrees with me as a
Nazi,
I am against hate speech.
And by the way,
anything I don't like I'm offended by is
hate speech.
And,
and that's the whole idea of freedom of
speech is to protect unpopular speech.
It's not there.
So we can talk about things that don't
offend you.
Obviously.
No one has a problem with that,
but so you have this on the left,
which this math problem,
and then the media demands that everyone
on the right denounce this non existent
thing,
so when trump can on a nonexistent thing
was disturbing,
was seeing hundreds of people walking
down the street with torches,
yelling out racist things together as a
group,
and the only thing that was
differentiating,
differentiating their idea was so much
more stupid than the free speech idea
because their idea was just to
differentiate people based on how much
melanin in their skin and what part of
the planet their ancestors came from.
That's one of the dumbest fucking ideas
in human history.
So what you have is this river of dumb
dumbs walking down the street and the
president doesn't say that.
The president doesn't say he's the guy
who's running the country,
right?
He doesn't say,
Hey,
this is the lowest form of stupidity
that we know of with humans.
The lowest form of stupidity is to
accept everyone that looks like you.
This is so fucking stupid.
You're pretending that someone has any
power whatsoever over where they were
born,
their national origin,
who their parents were.
You don't,
you don't have any fucking power over
that.
So you're putting all the power and
things that you have zero control with.
That means you're a fucking loser.
Alright,
and that means the only thing that you
got to bank on is this white skin,
the unity of in workforce.
This is the group that you're lumping
everybody together with and you don't
know.
Do you not know any great black people
do not know any great Hispanic or Latino
people you don't know any.
Well then you need to get the fuck out
of your neighborhood,
the ignorance,
but I think that applies to that thing
you're saying about kind of being like a
loser and then grasping to some
collective because you don't have
anything in your own story to really
cling to life.
I agree with you,
but that's.
I mean I think that applies to people
who get into this identity bullshit on
all sides.
I don't disagree.
It's like,
yeah,
I mean for a second about the president,
Short,
short,
but I just think to me what he said,
from what I see,
what like he did call out those guys,
he did say it was like disgusting,
but what people were upset about it that
he said there were bad people on both
sides.
What did you ever see a storm fronts
reaction to trump speech that he never
criticized white supremacy and they were
saying it was very good,
very positive overall,
and he said that there was problems on
both sides and bad people on both sides.
I see videos slide that Antifa was bad
also and they were say,
God bless Donald Trump.
Okay,
so this is what I saw from the videos
that I saw because I have learned and we
could go through this forever,
that I don't trust the mainstream media
at all.
They're completely full of shit.
So whoever rotated by corrupt people,
a reporter.
Sure.
No,
I'm not saying that it's necessarily
corrupt,
but been an embedded reporter that just
wanted to write a story.
Maybe maybe,
but I'm from the videos that I saw like
videos of what was going on there.
It's like,
yeah,
I saw all the stuff you're talking
about,
like the Tiki torches.
The Jews will not replace us,
swastikas,
all that really,
you know,
garbage.
And then I also saw,
um,
like David Duke and Richard Spencer and
all these guys who are kind of like
Richard Spencer,
I think as a white nationalist.
David Duke has been around forever.
You know,
is,
is a bigoted guy who had a almost
successful run for governor I think at
one point in Louisiana.
But you know,
it's been around forever now.
I find a lot of both of their ideas a
fucked up at offensive,
but they got a permit and we're there to
speak and this was the next day.
This has nothing to do the night before
they were out doing all that crazy shit
that we were talking about.
And then I did see this video of groups
of people who were forced out when they
canceled the speech,
a forced out through an Antifa mob at a
bunch of them getting tear gassed and
rocks thrown at them and shit like that.
So I don't know,
I mean as,
as,
as disgusting as like white supremacy
may be,
or national socialism,
particularly to me,
someone whose family was fucking
slaughtered by them.
And I believe in freedom of speech and I
think like the.
So I do think to some degree I get,
I just get where and,
and like I get where trump is being.
I guess what I'm sympathetic to is that
he's being like a raked over the coals
for not for calling out both sides
instead of just calling out one side.
Whereas everyone on the left is silent
about this antifa group.
It just started getting press actually
covered in a fair way in the mainstream
media.
But it's everywhere but blow.
I think the idea of anti for though is
to react to people they disagree with
who are speaking right?
This is,
this is their idea versus the idea of
rights of premesis to walk down the
street and denounce other weaker races
and get together as a big group with
torches and then people protest them and
then there's violence.
I think you got to address the root of
the idea of it as a representative of
all the people in the United States.
The root of the idea of it is that it's
okay to be a white racist and you know,
there's a lot of people that said,
what about Brown pride?
How cain Velasquez is brown product
tattooed on his fucking chest.
If you don't know the difference between
a guy who is born of immigrants that
literally his dad walked from Mexico,
you know,
I mean this is,
he's a first generation.
I mean,
you're second generation.
I guess his dad was first generation.
How does it work?
No,
he's first generation American because
his dad was from Mexico.
I mean this is a,
it's a different.
I mean,
they came here to try to get a better
life because they got a shit roll the
dice.
They were born in Mexico and he wanted
out and he wanted better for his family,
so they took a chance to come here when
he has brown pride tattooed on his.
He's not saying that like,
you know they're going to dominate and
the Jews will not replace us.
He's saying,
I'm proud to be a Mexican.
It sure when you say you're proud to be
a Mexican for whatever reason,
and I don't know why,
it doesn't mean you hate white people.
It doesn't mean you hate black people.
It means you have pride in your heritage
when you have white pride in for
whatever reason.
I don't know why,
but our thought is that you hate other
races.
Like if you are,
if you're a white nationalists like you
love white people,
people look at you like you're a piece
of shit and you are racist and you.
You think black people are inferior and
you think Mexican people and Asian
people and American Indians,
you think they're all inferior.
That's how we look at it.
But if you have black pride,
we look at you as a strong person who's
resisting this really fucked up society
that has brought your ancient ancestors
over from Africa and enslaved people and
literally marginalized everyone who
looks like you and you were there to
fight against that.
But it's kind of strange in a way,
like even as you say it,
it's kind of strange that we think of
one this way and the other that way.
I do think like,
I get that,
I,
I get the certainly get the point that
like came to Alaska,
is tattooing brown pride on his skin,
give him his story is a very different
thing.
Then tattooing white pride on your skin
because you're like a neo Nazi or
something like that.
And it was the UFC heavyweight champion
and it never came up.
Yeah.
He's arguably the greatest UFC
heavyweight in history.
It only,
it only came up in the,
in the fact that like they were like,
oh,
we're gonna sell numbers in Mexico City.
Brown pride.
And they didn't.
He lost the belt.
Well,
he shouldn't have used Brown.
It's a fucking English word.
People to say,
no,
you can't even.
What is the,
what's the word?
Brown and Spanish.
What's the word?
Pride in Spanish.
I get a guarantee you it ain't brown
pride.
If you go over there and you go,
I got brown pride.
They'd go,
what?
What'd you say?
So weirdly symbolizes how American he
is.
Ah,
or our own.
That's how you said that's what it
should say.
That's what she'd say came.
Who?
Fuck cane.
I can't wait to see that guy fighting.
I hope he can heal up.
Yeah.
He's had a lot of injuries or injuries?
Yeah,
just his whole career.
Is that a lot of injuries but he's been
yet,
like you said,
maybe the best heavy weight ever,
but I just wanted to,
to what you were saying like I do,
I get that.
I get the difference and I think that's
a very,
very valid point.
But like there is this thing like the
idea of white people embracing identity
politics.
The way the left has kind of embraced
identity politics.
Oh,
it does in some sick way.
Seemed like the natural logical
progression.
If you want to accept what the left wing
believes and then you're like,
okay,
well you look at the demographics,
white people are becoming a minority in
this country in the future and this is
how you kind of have like I get the
point you're making,
but at the same time it's a bit of a
weird setup that the left has.
We're like,
everyone else is allowed to say these
things except white people ever.
Like political correctness kind of only
applies to this one group and we're
going to put everything you say under a
fine tooth comb,
but somebody else could say whatever
they want.
It gets to a cartoonish point where you
have ice cube lecturing Bill Maher about
making a joke and actually ironically
while he's promoting his gangster rap
album,
sitting there going,
now what made you think it was cool to
say that Bill Maher and it's like
motherfucker,
you made cop killer.
Yeah,
she iced tea.
Oh No,
what?
What was his song now?
I'm sorry.
They both didn't like cops is my point,
but I'm just saying like he makes,
you know.
It's really funny.
It's key calls,
easy e a house Nigga on that album,
right?
He uses the same insults actually toward
another black guy.
Not as a joke,
not as a self deprecating joke the way
Bill Maher used that,
but in the worst way you could insult
another black guy.
He uses it,
so I just think there is this weird
dynamic on the left where it's like the
rhetoric is so anti white and so anti
male that I almost sit there and I go
like,
man,
if you guys think Charlottesville is
ugly,
you're gonna.
You're gonna.
Create a lot more of this.
I was sitting at my sister's place a
couple of weeks ago and talking with a
few of her left wing professors and my
sister's got a.
she's a college professor.
He's got this big bookshelf up behind
the,
you know,
like behind the table,
lots of books and I just looked over and
there was a Michael Moore book from the
nineties called stupid white men and you
just look at it and you're like,
oh yeah,
maybe that's why they're all angry.
People don't like being the bad guy.
Black Guy wrote a book called stupid
black men.
They would come out of him so hard.
Yeah.
It's sounds like something Larry elder
my right,
but with a more eloquent title for it.
Nobody fuck with some stupid black man.
If a black guy wrote a book that was
like,
Ah,
you know,
all white people aren't stupid.
They'd be like uncle Tom,
you know,
like right away it's like,
oh,
you sell out.
Well it's racist.
Yeah.
We just don't like to think it's racist
because it's about
white people and generally white people
don't have to deal with racism nearly as
much as other races.
So we allow it to be okay.
It's also sexist.
There a big thing that's going on now,
especially lately where women think it's
okay to say all white CIS men are trash.
I mean,
it's so fucking common.
It is such a crazy generalization to say
that all men or all white men are
terrible and they're horrible trash
until prove until they prove otherwise.
And it's so fucking killer to say that
it's so contradicts everything they've
supposedly believed in it.
So like,
you know,
if,
if there's,
uh,
if there's like a Muslim terrorist event
and then somebody lumps that into like
radical lumps that into all Muslims,
people on the left will lose their mind.
Like how can you lump every,
the whole group in with what this one
bad guy did and then they turn the land
and lecture white people about the evils
of history.
But forget if we just stopped saying
left and right,
don't you think that what this is is
just human beings doing that team thing,
you know?
And once you start adopting the rules
and the patterns of the team,
whether you're a Wisconsin cheese hat or
you're a Boston red sox fan or whatever
the fuck it is that you're into,
you get into this like you've ever heard
those vikings chant,
whether they get the whole stadium like
a thousand people and they clapped her
hands together.
It's insane.
It's amazing.
It's amazing,
right?
But obviously that is a group think sort
of a situation.
And they all,
they all gear together and they all
support this behavior that makes them
feel good that they're a part of this
group.
And I think people do that when whenever
they support rightwing causes and I
think people do that whenever they
support left wing causes and what the
right and the left arm is essentially
just frameworks that we can fit in our
ideologies and our mind and our needs
and all of our social and emotional
requirements and we can fit them into
these patterns that we follow and when
anybody opposes the structure that we've
adopted as reality,
then we fight with bike locks and
fucking pepper spraying girls with trump
hats on.
And you know,
you find all sorts of insane
justifications for racism,
sexism,
all sorts of crazy shit that you would
if it were happening to anyone else
other than the person that you're
opposing.
You would say,
think of it as being a horrible front to
everything that you stand for.
But as long as it's a white man who
cares?
Hit him in the head with a bike lock.
Imagine if it was a black woman that it
was this professor was disagreeing with
and he stepped up and he hit her in the
head with a bike lock.
It's insane.
Like that's when,
when you see someone who does that from
Antifa,
it is exactly the same as that.
That redneck who pulls out his gun and
shoots at that black guy was holding a
torch.
Yeah.
This is all the same thing.
Well,
I also know,
I mean,
you're right,
and it's,
it's like,
uh,
they're shocking similarities between,
between the extreme and the extreme,
right?
Or,
you know,
whatever.
You know,
these teams,
and I agree with you completely.
I think it's all just this tribal team
group think bullshit kind of that we
have to a large degree outgrown,
but that's still kind of haunts us and
it's still don't think they've outgrown
and universities and that's part of the
issue.
That's why this is all happening at UC
Berkeley.
That's why you're seeing it all
throughout the country in these
universities because in universities,
first of all,
you have a bunch of people.
Let's,
let's try to be as honest and objective
as possible.
First of all,
you have a bunch of people that are
seeking knowledge.
You have young people that are
idealistic,
that want to change the world,
that want to stand out as being better.
They want to virtue signal.
They want to do all the crazy things
that they can to be something great and
there's other ones that want to get laid
and there's other ones that want to
manipulate and they still don't know who
they are.
They still don't know how to behave.
Then you have these professors and a lot
of these professors went through this
process and then after they went through
this process,
they got their phd,
they wrote and then they started
teaching and so they have never been
outside the hallowed halls of academia
since the time they were like 19 years.
They've been going through the whole
system and some of them do it and they
do it with balance and they figure out
who they are and they take great pride
in the fact that they can mold these
young minds and give them information.
And some of them are incredibly broken
people who are never sexually viable
when they were young and now they're in
a position of power and they virtue
signal to a sickening degree and you see
them and you see them standing up for
women above all else,
which is what happened with this whole
betsy devos thing when she's there.
They're trying to push this and say her
name devoss.
I think they're trying to push due
process in the case of these sexual
assault cases on campus and people are
resisting due process.
People are resisting guilty until proven
innocent.
Oh my God,
that's what they want.
And I'm sorry,
like,
and I don't mean to also like uh,
you know,
like keep harping on this kind of left
versus right thing.
But it's hard for me.
I almost want like some term to like
define,
but this left side of a lake on college
campuses.
This grill,
they're position is simultaneously.
I mean,
it's really quite amazing.
Their position is that,
and this is what basically what was just
repealed now,
but this is what the guidelines under
Obama basically did on college campuses.
They said,
okay,
there's no due process for men who are
accused of rape.
Oh,
and by the way,
and this isn't in the legislation,
this is just the cultural punch,
but so there's no due process for men
accused of rape and by the way,
everything is rape.
Everything's right.
Everything.
Every guy you've ever met.
Yeah,
I mean if you had anything to drink,
by the way,
the man is not,
is not responsible or the man is
responsible.
The woman is not so great beers.
I mean you've probably taken 90 percent
at least of the pool of what men and
women in America previously considered.
Good guys.
Forget even like rapists,
good men like just the guys who you
think are good people not like consider
it.
Ninety percent of them are serial
rapists.
Have you heard the story from University
of Amherst?
It's one of the most ridiculous ones or
this guy suing now and he has gone
through hell for the last couple of
years,
but it was a kid who was a student from
Nigeria and some girl who was in his
class and they hooked up and they got
together and they apparently they were
slightly intoxicated,
I think on marijuana.
The girl gave the guy a blow job and
then she wanted to stop and he was
trying to get her to do it again and she
said no.
And so they ended it.
That was it.
Um,
she talked to her friends.
They decided that she had been sexually
assaulted because he was trying to get
her to.
Come on,
please,
you know,
I don't know what he said.
I don't know,
maybe it would be a no,
that wouldn't be enough.
I don't know what the fuck he said.
I don't know what the scenario was,
but I do know that it was essentially an
awkward sexual exchange between young
people,
which is just a part of being a young
person who's having sex.
When you're,
you're a person and you're 18 years old
or whatever they were and you're in
college and you're having sex and you're
in some sort of a sexual scenario with a
new person.
What are they?
How long have you been doing that?
Three years.
How good are you at it or you fight you
probably fucking terrible at it.
You'd probably awkward as Shit.
You probably weird around women.
You can't believe they like you don't
know why they like you.
Maybe you're confused.
Maybe you think you have to act a
certain way.
You know the,
the finding yourself,
you adolescent use it before you
actually do not have a fully developed
brain and it's a different and forget
even insects and stuff like that.
There's just things.
How many things did you do at 20?
We'd look back and go,
oh,
what a douchey thing to do.
Like that's not how you treat someone.
You know,
like,
so this young guy,
I think he was 19 at the time,
somewhere in the college age,
whatever it was,
he's fucked.
They kicked him out of school,
they labeled him some sort of a sexual
Predator and he's in this terrible
position where,
you know,
he's suing the school,
but it's gonna take a long time before
anything gets resolved and you know,
we don't know the whole story of the
case,
but if the case is as he's representing
it and as no one's said,
he held her down,
no one said he tried to rape her and no
one said he threatened violence.
No one said anything like that.
Her version of the story is that they
had some sort of a willing sexual
encounter and she just didn't want to go
any further and he asked her to and she
said no,
and then it ended.
That's it.
That is a normal.
That's just part of being a young person
that's just part of being a young person
having sex,
especially if you're intoxicated.
Is it a good idea to have sex
intoxicated kid?
I don't know.
I mean,
I've done it a bunch and sure you have
to have.
Yes.
Stop pretending you haven't done it.
Stop pretending that a lot.
Look,
there's all sorts of mistakes you make
when you're drunk.
W why?
Why are they so much bigger?
If it's sex and there's something about
just using the word rape,
rape.
I mean it's like look,
rape is a particularly horrific cutting
word because of what a horrific crime it
is and then to try to make everything
else like it's literally,
I mean the extent they go,
it's almost like,
you know,
it's like if you,
if you punch someone in the arm and they
go,
you committed or murder or something
like that,
it's like,
no,
you can't.
You can't just throw that word at
everything.
I mean everybody wants to.
It's worse than that because of race.
That's an assault is an actual egregious
offense.
If you're talking about people
having sex.
No Cross,
right?
You're absolutely calling.
You know,
it'd be like calling a glance murder.
Yeah.
I mean it's really,
it's fucking crazy.
Was the idea of microaggressions and
this is the whole.
This is the whole thing that underpins
the philosophy,
which I find really terrifying is that
the idea of micro aggression or social
justice,
it's like you take these terms like
aggression or justice that meant
something and now you've made the mean
the opposite of what they mean.
But microaggression is not an aggression
inherently.
It's not an aggression.
No,
I know.
It's a normal part of human
communication.
You say something mean and I go like
this and I walk away.
That's what people do is that's a
microaggression and there's this thing,
and this is why I find it to be such
that the issue of our time,
I almost forget like,
you know,
like it's not the issue.
I necessarily wanted to be the issue of
our time.
I was hoping it would be like embracing
libertarianism full on or something,
but it just seems to be like,
are you for free speech or against free
speech and free speech has such a Prereq
for everything.
It's a prerequisite for everything about
the,
uh,
the society we live in and everything
particularly like what you do,
what I do,
everything we do.
Like you can't,
you can't.
What I love in life is like comedy and
truth and you can't have either of those
without that free speech because
possible can have this conversation
about free speech.
I mean,
we couldn't have this conversation if we
were on a state sponsored program.
We couldn't have this.
If we were on a corporate sponsored
program,
we'd likely couldn't have this
conversation without being interrupted
or,
or being lectured to or having some
conversation with someone who says,
Hey,
you can't say the word nigger.
Right?
You're not allowed to say it.
Forget about living in the context.
Yeah,
yeah.
You can say that noise with your mouth.
Right?
Not Calling someone at not saying you
are one,
you know,
and like,
no one can go,
but that's fucking retarded.
It's what's the dumbest thing I've ever
heard,
but that this was the rule and this is
how everybody operates and there's a
thing where it's not.
I mean,
if,
if we're living in a world of I can't
commit a microaggression,
I can't go down a path that might offend
anybody.
You,
you need that freedom in order to find
anything interesting.
There's nothing worth saying if you're
living in this world where you're like,
oh,
I can't get outside of this box.
So I find that to be very,
just very dangerous and I feel like
people in America,
it's almost like we've had it too good
for too long,
that people are removed from the fact
that we can lose all this shit.
It's like there's no,
there's no respect for like,
like what we have,
how much different,
how much higher standard of living we
live than the vast,
you know,
uh,
for,
than most humans that are alive today.
And the vast majority of humans who have
ever existed.
I mean,
it's like what?
I got this from a Jordan Peterson
lecture,
uh,
but he said,
it was an 18,
95.
The average American lived on a dollar a
day adjusted for modern inflation.
So in 18,
95,
you know,
it's like,
like central Asia level poverty in
America and that's just everyone.
Before that living in backbreaking
poverty was like,
just life.
That was just all of life.
And it's like we figured something out
in these last less than 200 years,
you know,
like we figured something or a little
more than 200 years.
We've figured something out.
Wait,
what am I saying?
No,
no,
it's less than 200 years.
We figured something out in this
industrial revolution that like now lets
us live up here on this.
And it's like we can lose that and a lot
of it has to do with freedom.
But the whole thing to me is freedom.
The whole thing is that we embrace.
Look,
if you look in the year,
um,
and uh,
that you had on your show,
Thaddeus Russell,
who's great,
I just did his podcast recently and he
put it this way,
uh,
where he goes,
you know,
in the year 1800 [inaudible] I was
talking about what an incredible thing
the 19th century was and how it
transformed humanity.
And he goes to the year 1800 Americans
are all making their own clothes in the
year.
1,900
Americans are shopping at macy's.
Like we,
we,
if you had said in the,
you know,
in the year 18,
45 and been like,
dude,
in the next 65 years,
slavery is going to be abolished in the
West and we're going to have an
industrial revolution,
you know,
it's like magic happen and that's why we
live the way we live today.
And no one is even interested in that
story.
Like why do we have this much wealth?
And I like what you said.
I think it's,
it's all about freedom.
And when you have a guy like Bernie
Sanders who harps on and on about income
inequality,
I,
I have a real issue with that because
it's one of those blanket statements.
It sounds really good at a campaign
speech,
but freedom itself breeds income
inequality.
Yes.
Because freedom means you can do
whatever you want.
You could do very little or you could
work like a maniac.
Well,
if you're going to work,
like if you're,
if here's the game,
okay,
you do something for that.
Something.
You get currency,
you use that currency to buy things or
to make sure you don't have to work
again by food and goods and take trips
and travel.
The more you work,
the more you decide you want to pursue
something,
the more chances you have to acquire
their currency.
If you do it correctly.
That is income inequality due to
freedom.
I mean take away all the other factors
that might be in play,
whether it's racial discrimination or
sexual discrimination.
I'm not denying that those things exist,
but what I am saying is that the idea
that you are going to have income
equality in a capitalist society where
anybody can do whatever they want.
You know people that is so counter to
what we know about human behavior.
I agree.
This is.
You're talking about a fantasy person
who doesn't exist,
who has motivations outside of wealth.
Outside of that,
most people want some sort of reward for
what they do and if everybody gets the
same amount,
there's no fucking reward for working
extra hard and that's not going to.
We're not going to get Microsoft.
You're not going to get IBM.
It's just,
I mean it's not,
it's not just,
I mean they talk about fairness a lot,
which is a strange concept,
but it's not just that somebody works
twice as hard and doesn't get more.
I mean that's not the right thing to do
anyway.
But like what you were saying,
I just think it's like they,
they use the term so much,
but what's misleading about it?
You're absolutely right that freedom
breeds inequality,
but what's misleading about it is by
that people think like the poor get
poorer and that is objective.
That is a like objectively false,
demonstrably false.
It's not that,
you know,
they make it out like the rich get
richer and the poor get poorer like that
old saying,
but it's like that,
you know,
if you think it through like that can't
really continue like that.
Nobody was going to have rich.
But if the poor work hard and figured
they haven't possibility to escape
whatever economic situation they're in,
it is possible.
But with freedom and homeless people
here live better than,
than rich people in Third World
countries,
or certainly at least better than
average people in third world countries.
Uh,
so it's like,
it's not just that the inequality grows,
it's like everything moves up.
The inequality grows up here.
And this is like what I just,
what I can't understand.
And,
and again,
it's like what I was saying before,
like if you have any concept of the fact
that we're by far the richest freest
human beings who have ever existed in
recorded human history,
at least recorded human history.
Who knows what is going on in ancient
Egypt,
but like a pro before engineered it.
But,
uh,
but if you realize that we have this
incredible amount,
then it's like,
yeah,
it's like just being like,
oh,
we need all of these policies to like
give handouts to poor people.
It's like,
well actually,
let's continue this train of getting
richer and richer and richer,
which is not at all.
You know what people like Bernie
Sanders,
man.
It's like,
well,
it's a hustle.
Bernie's got a hustle going on.
So you find out it's a hustle when you
find out it's got a bunch of houses and
his wife tried to buy up all this
fucking land to expand the university
that she was running and she killed the
whole fucking school.
Like you.
How about the fact that the
motherfucker,
and we haven't seen.
First off he,
he made a million dollars off a book on
how it's wrong to be a millionaire.
I mean it's like how are you not how can
anyone look at you like as a serious
leader when you did that?
So you saying what people want to hear
and there is something,
some truth to some of the things that
he's saying.
I think that the world would be a better
place if we had more social programs in
place.
I think the world be a better place if
college were free.
If we think.
I mean I don't disagree with like the
thought behind that.
I think they're,
all of these things would be better
suited in voluntary arrangements than
some forced government monopoly.
But I do agree with you that like,
sure,
I'd like great schools to be very
affordable or free if possible.
I'd like everyone to be.
And,
and Bernie Sanders certainly addressed
some very real problems.
Like he would point things out that were
very real,
like he would be like,
you know,
they claim it's a great recovery,
but you know,
90 percent of the new wealth has gone to
the top three percent,
you know,
like he either have some Jackie Mason,
I only do one thing,
two and that has to apply to every New
York Jew who's out there.
But like so like there is some,
and I don't care if Bernie Sanders makes
a million dollars,
but there's something like,
number one,
making a million dollars while claiming
it's kind of a moral issue that some
people have so much what others have.
So little endorsing Hillary Clinton.
I mean,
I just don't know how you can have.
You can look at the guy who goes,
the problem is incoming inequality and
these and the banking cartel,
but I'm going to vote for the candidate
of the big banks.
Like to me,
that's,
that's insane.
It would,
to me it would be if Ron Paul endorsed
mccain.
Well,
don't you think the big banks sort
of were on both teams?
Yeah.
Well not.
I don't know if they were on trump's
team,
but there's certainly been on every
other team now.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
No,
certainly.
It's not even like the teams they run
the Treasury Department in the Federal
Reserve.
They run the whole system.
But the fact that Bernie Sanders never
had like a fiery speech about what
happened at the DNC about how they
literally conspired to ruin him and to
take him out of the race with Hillary
because they,
the DNC wanted hillary to be the
candidate.
They literally sabotaged him.
Oh,
they were very open.
I mean,
I shouldn't say they were very open
about that.
Openly.
They lied and said,
we don't have a pick,
but the leaks that were weaponized.
Yeah.
I mean really some of Russia did it.
Russia ruined everything.
I,
I actually remember it was one of the
most surreal and I'm a guy who was
always preaching about how full of shit
the media is,
but even I like this last year that'll
give the trump moment credit even I've
been like,
Holy Shit,
I can't believe it,
but I was watching CNN and they had.
They were playing clips from a Hillary
Clinton interview and talking about it
and Hillary Clinton was claiming that
Vladimir Putin a weaponized information
against Hillary Clinton and they're
discussing this and they never mentioned
that the information is on CNN.
They're breaking down this piece and
they never mentioned that.
The information that was weaponized was
that CNN leaked debate questions to
Hillary Clinton before the debate.
Like you sit here talking about
undermining democracy for a month.
What could be more to under what could
do more to undermine democracy?
The debate,
the things that people actually watch
and vote on in America.
They gave Hillary Clinton the questions
that were asked at the debate.
We know for a fact too,
I'm sure there were more,
but we know two questions were given to
her and that they were both asked and
Hillary Clinton take some doesn't have a
problem,
doesn't have a moral issue with that,
just takes them and pretends she's
hearing the questions for the first time
and the show that I'm watching describe.
Talk about this on CNN that's talking
about the weaponized information and not
mentioning what the information was.
The show is called reliable sources.
It's a show where they break down the
media.
It's like it's surreal to be watching
and then those same guys in CNN go,
we've got an epidemic of fake news on
the Internet and you're like,
man,
I don't know if I'm living through a
fucking simulation or what,
but this is some nutty shit.
Well,
it's so obvious when you watch the
strategies play out.
Like for people who don't remember
Hillary Clinton before she ran against
trump was running against Barack Obama.
Yes.
And when she was running against Barack
Obama,
one of the things she did was she
positioned herself as to be right of
center.
So more right than Obama was.
So one of the things that she did was
she was publicly stating that gay
marriage was wrong.
She was publicly stated that she
believes that marriage is a sacred
institution between a man and a woman.
And that was her way of positioning
herself to the right of Obama.
Like she would appeal to all the
religious nuts.
Obama,
by the way,
I'm okay with going left.
I don't want no more war
in Iraq,
but these fags marrying each other and.
But fucking.
It's just me and Gary Been Married for
25 years.
You think it's right that they get to be
the same thing?
We are under Christ.
She will.
Just to be fair,
that Obama was also against gay marriage
and that election,
but she absolutely,
you're right.
Did he say how he.
He did the same thing.
It was these motherfuckers.
It's like 51 percent approval rating,
right?
Then all of a sudden they come to Jesus
53.
Yeah.
It's like,
well,
it's like right when it went right when
it starts being a wedge issue we can use
right when Obama was going,
oh,
we need reelection and I didn't end in
any of these wars and still open.
It's like if you're a comic,
but the only way you could work is if
somebody gave you an earpiece and they
fed you great lines.
Like you couldn't just ad Lib Yourself.
Like if you were doing this podcast and
why you're doing this podcast,
big Jay's over in the corner feeding you
lines through one of your earpieces
right.
Know there's a team of guys,
you know,
because the other guys in the back,
they're doing like a.
they're like running like research on
it.
The like Jamie's over there constantly
googling and you have like a screen in
front of you.
Like you know Howard stern used to have
that with Jackie.
The joke,
man,
this is way back in the day.
Really?
The jokes?
Yeah.
What he did was he had a thing where you
would write on like an overhead
projector.
This was like a thing.
It was like a camera and he would see
the video of it on his side.
He would see the picture.
So you had a funny line,
you would write down the funny line and
you would put it on the projector and
Howard would get it on his screen and
that's one of the things that Jackie,
the joke man did because he was always.
He was great at like one liners and
things along those lines.
He knew a lot of jokes and so he would
give Howard like really funny things to
say any with juice it up and I did the
Jackie Chair for a couple times when
Jackie,
the joke man quit.
Jackie wanted like a million dollars a
year and they wouldn't give him a
million dollars a year.
They would give them a 900,000.
He was like fuck you.
So he left and so when he left they had
a bunch of guys sit in that chair and
one of them was already and already
wound up taking that job and part of our
job was to feed Howard lines and like
that kid Benji.
He's really funny man.
That guy,
he would write down stuff and feed
Howard funny lines,
so he has a few guys on the side that
would toss some stuff,
which is essentially what a politician
does,
write us a politician like you're not
going to get their full unadulterated
ideas except for trump and that's one of
the things that was so refreshing about,
even though it was a shitty message,
even though there's a poverty of words
and the way he spoke and there was this
clunkiness to it all.
There's certainly as a clunkiness,
there's no question about that.
It's a very,
very simplistic way of,
of speaking compared to what we're used
to.
Politicians.
Yeah,
like all the slogans,
slogans,
work.
I think there is something about it.
The fact that he was as,
as you were saying,
like completely unrestrained,
completely on,
you know,
there's something really interesting
about trump.
I mean the whole thing is really
fascinating,
but it,
it's like the most profoundly hilarious
and interesting moment ever.
And like no one wants to appreciate
it because they're so dug into like one
or the other.
Nuclear War with Korea.
Well,
I get that.
That's kind of scary.
I mean it's more,
more scary for the people in Seoul than
us,
but still like that is scary.
But the thing with trump is that he
speaks and,
you know,
it's like,
okay,
the people who hate trump hate him more
than any.
Anyone.
I mean,
I've never seen a political leader hated
as much as the people who hate trump
hate him right now.
No one in America for sure.
No,
no,
no one in my lifetime has in America has
even come close.
I'm sure there are other countries where
it's like,
you know,
dictator.
Yeah.
Like that I'm sure.
But like there,
um,
but trump has hated and I got to be
honest with if you ask people on the
left why they hate him,
I think they struggled to give you a
really good,
honest answer for it.
I mean they'll say things like,
I think they say things like racism or
bigotry or you know,
I'd say pa people were paying attention
to what he's doing.
Right.
They were worried about that.
Although I gotta say the EPA thing,
I don't think any of this is actually
the source of the trump patriot.
I think this is like we hate trump and
now what's he doing?
That's how we're going to get evidence
against him.
Um,
the truth is what they'll say nine out
of 10 times if I present this to a left
wing person or I'll go like,
oh,
you know,
he's pretty much continuing all the
Obama policies or it's virtually the
same.
Which I think is one of the really big
stories of the trump era so far that how
much is the same since Obama.
No one wants to talk about big changes.
There's been a big change.
I'm not saying there are no changes.
Immigration Policy,
immigration policy.
He wrote one executive order by the
courts,
but it hasn't really gone into effect,
but it's the idea that he's promoting
his rhetoric is very,
very different.
No question about that.
He's promotes different ideas.
His rhetoric is very,
very different.
Um,
but in terms of like monetary policy,
fiscal policy,
foreign policy,
the war on drugs,
see if you're talking about immigration,
I mean,
that's kind of like,
okay,
I would get,
I'm putting that in domestic policy in
my mind,
but yet far enough,
well in foreign policy it speaking
about,
because I was saying nine out of 10
times the answer to me as they go,
well,
that's kind of your white privilege.
And if you were in,
if you were in one of these,
uh,
um,
groups that's worried about being
deported,
you would feel differently.
But the fact is that deportations are
down,
right?
Under trump,
there were more under Obama.
I mean,
they're down now.
There's a few different arguments for
why that reason is,
uh,
there have been a lot of arrests but,
but not deportations,
but it's just like,
even that the narrative isn't fitting
the way.
Like what really,
to me,
what really drove what made people hate
trump was his rhetoric.
It was all rhetoric.
It wasn't.
Obama was deporting lots of people.
Obama was bombing the crap out of him.
Obama was targeting families of,
of and he was torturing like all these
things were happening,
but he didn't talk about it.
He spoke about it in a nice way and
trump was like this unapologetic like
white rich man who didn't play the PC
game and spoke of minorities.
Not In like a glowing.
I'm so sorry,
like minorities are better than me.
I'm the evil white guy.
Was like,
no,
we're
great.
I never say we're great.
He would say,
you know,
some nice things about minorities when
asked,
but his central message was like our
teams great and this to me is I think
the reason why leftwing people's blood
boil was just so many pieces of evidence
that point to corruption with Russia.
So many pieces of evidence that point to
the idea that this guy is operating in
the interest of himself and of big
business and then he's profiting in a
huge way off being the president and one
of the ways they're doing that.
The reason they're not rolling back the
environmental protection agency
standards because they don't believe in
them.
They're rolling a backpack because it's
impeding business.
That's infuriating.
A lot of people on the west scares the
shit out of people when you have some
crazy old man who's just doing
everything for profit.
Some guy who wants to literally start
disc fights with basketball players and
the hosts from.
That was the thing.
We talked about this before,
but the host from espn who had tweeted
some stuff about him being a white
supremacist and then he asked for espn
to apologize.
I'm like,
hey,
how come you didn't talk about her man?
He can't talk about her.
He can't.
They literally can't say her name
because if he goes after a black woman,
then it reinforces all these people's
ideas.
Prejudice might know.
Look,
I,
I get what you're saying and just to the
point about corruption.
I mean like,
of course.
I mean that's the nature of government.
Like whatever decision they're making is
based on what lobbyists is lobbying them
the harder and when it's all corrupt,
but my point is just that,
that is not at all different with trump.
I mean like if you like the corruption
under Obama was.
I mean,
Obama just went and collected $400,000
for a speech to a Wall Street,
so he's in there just a couple of months
ago,
right?
Don't they all do that and once they get
out,
bomb is like you're in there,
you preside over the bailouts of the
banks.
Started under Bush,
but continued under Obama and the big
ones,
the Fed policy,
which really bailed them out.
Like you're in there.
You take all this money for your
campaigns,
you present,
you vote every way that they want you
to.
You preside over the biggest profits for
the big bankers.
You put them all around your
administration and he'd get out and you
collect your check.
It's like time to get rich now.
Now some of them one check,
he's going to get a ton of them.
As you think it's speaking everywhere.
I mean,
maybe I'm wrong,
right?
I'm being too cynical.
Probably all of those bankers just
really loved the way Obama speaks.
He's,
I mean,
he has a great speaker,
but here's my problem.
That's not why they're paying them.
Hillary Clinton is not a great speaker
and they paid her shit tons of money and
that was one of the things that Bernie
said,
we're the transcripts and you know,
what a transcript.
And of course,
uh,
she didn't,
but wikileaks did get their hands on one
of them in which she said something that
kind of indicated why she didn't release
the transcripts because she actually
said I'm lying to the public.
I mean,
not literally,
but she basically said to all these
bankers to not be concerned about
because,
you know,
she hurt public rhetoric at the time was
like,
you know,
no one's too big to fail,
no banker too big to jail.
And then she basically said to them in
this speech that wikileaks leak to the
transcript of where she was like,
you know,
you have to take one public and then
hold
a different position in private.
So she was basically assuring know that
that's an unaltered now.
I mean it's kind of like the same way
that we,
we know that all of the emails are
legit,
like they've been presented.
Even the Clintons aren't arguing that
there are legitimate.
Like nobody's really coming out and
arguing that they're not legitimate and
it,
and it seems too big from a legitimate
site.
Julian assange is sort of shifting over
time,
paying more and more aggressive,
like his,
his position on things.
He's more,
he's more aggressive,
more leaning one way.
I think he's bummed out that he's still
stuck over there.
I mean,
it's rotting him away.
Sure.
But I think he's been kind of
consistent.
It's almost like everybody else,
like changing their of like I feel like
the Democrats to me and the people who
follow them and the trump haters,
it's like insane how much they've
changed their possessions.
Like to me,
Julian assange was exposing all this
bullshit under Bush.
He exposes all the shit about Clinton
and Obama.
And it was like,
yeah,
from my perspective,
they're all part of the same network.
So he's kind of exposing the same
network.
Whereas the Democrats became cold
warriors,
like,
like the Democrats.
As soon as trump got in,
it's like,
well,
everything was CIA is taken without any
evidence being project,
uh,
presented.
And Russia is the evil threat of our
time.
And like when did you go,
you guys became Republicans from the
seventies,
like just that quickly and then every.
I even saw somebody today,
like it's like the trump haters,
like again,
feel however you feel about trump hatim
sure.
Go ahead and be against.
I,
like I said,
I think it's terrible that he's telling
st people should be fired for speaking
up.
Like that's ridiculous.
But I say these guys who are like,
they're like,
oh,
you want,
you know,
you want to talk about patriotism and,
and like bashing trump for being a draft
dodger.
He wants.
He dodged it a ton of.
If you did whatever you did to stay out
of the Vietnam War,
God bless you.
God bless you for staying away from that
fucking nightmare.
That was started on a lie.
That was like the most disgusting mass
slaughter for profit.
I mean like if someone avoided that,
like you're mad at him for avoiding
going and killing some fucking poor
people in Southeast Asia.
But it's just the point that they could
grab him on the hypocrisy of being a
chicken hawk.
Like same as Dick Cheney.
They did it with him as well,
but it's not because he is at,
look,
I'm all for hitting someone for
hypocrisy,
like if you're advocating a war,
hitting them on not wanting to fight a
war,
but you're just mad at him for not being
on the same side of yours about police
brutality.
It's like finding out his character,
pointing out who he is.
Fine,
but don't abandon all of your principle
guy.
He's not like JFK went over and fought
in the war.
I get what you're saying,
but I don't think there's.
I'm just saying if the left is going to
say to me,
it's kind of abandoning your own
principles.
If you're going to bash someone for like
a not fighting in the Vietnam war,
you kind of know what they're doing.
They all do that.
They try to find something that you did
that's kind of questionable that they
can politicize.
Yes.
No,
I get it.
I'm just making the same thing with like
the Democrats becoming the Cold War.
It's just like,
yeah,
so whatever windows,
whatever gets you points.
What really gets me with the Democrats
with the left is how all of a sudden
Julian size is a puppet
of Russia now,
like for the longest time Wiki leaks was
supposed to be the voice of honesty.
This not,
you know,
non bipartisan sorta or bipartisan
openminded group that's just trying to
disseminate information they think is
critical to the American people that
they're being denied.
Like the casual,
would it called casualties?
What was that one video that they had?
There was a v,
one of the first videos was,
I forget what they called it,
but they had a footage from one of those
gunships when those helicopters and they
showed these guys sort of casually
talking about gunning down these
reporters.
They thought these reporters are
carrying guns and so they just opened
fire on them and gunned him down,
including lunch.
I forget what it was called,
I forget,
but that sort of like they.
They felt like they had some information
that people weren't aware of.
They weren't allowed to see photos of
caskets.
They weren't allowed to get the full.
They weren't allowed to have a really
informed opinion and what exactly is
happening there and when they see the
horrors of war in that regard,
like we see people like sort of casually
talking about gunning down some people
and I think there are kids in their car
and well they shouldn't have brought
kids.
You know,
that was one of the things they had
said.
Like that whole thing was like,
Whoa,
we are better off knowing that this is
what can happen if you just allow people
to just go to war.
And especially some really ambiguous war
on terror.
That's what wikileaks did for,
right?
Qliq stood for Chelsea Manning,
AK Bradley Manning,
you know,
releasing this information.
Someone who is under a lot of people's
eyes,
a patriot,
right?
A whistleblower.
See something gets a hold of some stuff
and it's like,
look,
you guys got to see this and gives it
out to wikileaks,
but try to give it out to other people.
Right?
Didn't,
didn't he try or she tried to believe
New York time?
I believe so I got rejected it and then
out into the same thing.
And then uh,
you know,
Chelsea Manning,
Bradley manning at the time,
paid quite a price for it,
I think 200 days in solitary
confinement.
This is a really brutal price.
Um,
and yeah,
and exposed a ton of really interesting
stuff.
I mean,
we,
what we learned from the Bradley Manning
Dump,
what's,
you know,
like all this crazy shit about war
crimes and then like we learned about
how there were like a,
like US officials trying to influence
the British parliament,
trying to influence a reporters and just
all that shady shit that came out.
Um,
and then again it becomes this kind of
like integrity test for the mainstream
media or they just have no interest in
it.
I mean,
if they talk about it,
they'll talk about Chelsea manning.
But that's the story.
The same snowden's the story.
None of it's ever like,
Oh shit,
we learned some crazy shit that's going
on.
Well that's what we are.
We're a nation of gossip,
awesome.
Copper next historic,
not Puerto Rico.
You know,
a guy not standing up with his hand in
the correct position that lets know that
we are
all on one mindset,
that guy is more important and even
within that context and a lot of people
like and this is where there's this
weird disconnect between like there's
like the mainstream media and then all
of the alternative Internet media and
there's certainly a ton of bullshit in
the alternative Internet media world and
a lot of just straight up false stories
short,
but then there are people also talking
about the truth there.
Whereas none of that seems to enter the
mainstream media.
So what doesn't.
What gets brought up online and in the
alternative media,
which should be at the center of this
story,
is that like,
like the the players didn't use to be on
the field for the national anthem.
For the vast majority.
It was 2009 or 2010.
The Defense Department cuts these huge
checks to the nfl and then all of a
sudden they get the players out on the
field so we can do this whole tribute
thing.
And the military industrial complex has
been like working on taking this past
time,
the number one sport in America,
which is already pretty like warring and
making sure we can use this as
propaganda to get Americans,
you know,
into this nationalistic pro military
mindset.
I like no.
Are you a journalist?
Like how are you not interested in that?
How is it,
how can Obama sign into the national
defense authorization act that he has
the right to detain American citizens
with no charges?
And it's like,
okay,
like Alex Jones is over here.
And like,
yeah,
I know he says some wild stuff,
but he is making a big deal about this.
Like this is crazy.
And then the mainstream media just
doesn't think it's a big story.
How is it possible that you're a
journalist in honest journalist with
integrity and you don't think it's a big
store?
You don't look at that and go,
well that's the story of my lifetime.
Obama just repealed habeas corpus.
Don't you think it's the exact same
thing as what we were talking about with
people in academia and on the left,
don't look at things that are in
opposition to the group.
Think of their ideology.
I think it's,
it's a lot of that and it's like this
thing where it's like there's this,
it's almost like unspoken,
unwritten pressure where you just kinda
know.
It's like,
right,
you have this herd mentality and you
know,
if I step out here I get bashed and most
people don't want to get bashed.
Like,
you know,
you were talking about the people who
are professors and and they're certainly
very,
very smart people.
Lots of very,
But it is a certain personality type,
you know?
It's like that,
that,
that person who like that you go to
school your whole life.
Then you go to college,
then you go to Grad school,
then you teach and you basically just
been in college your whole life.
Did you see that video?
That woman at the Berkeley protests
where she's screaming at the cops
fucking yes.
Yes.
Screaming in the.
See if you can find her,
because that is a social retard.
That's what she's asking them to go
arrest people inside.
They're Nazis and these are the types of
people who never got into into like,
look,
there's socially retarded.
I mean,
that's really literally what it is.
They never competed in the real world.
They didn't formulate a normal
psychological outlook.
Yeah,
but there's.
Okay,
so there's that,
that woman who you're talking about and,
and,
and Oh yeah,
she is whatever,
whatever,
the scientology,
whatever the top level is.
I'm saying that it's left wing level
five.
You've achieved the height of those
people are literally mentally disturbed.
People like these
are.
Yeah,
laser.
This is a woman with video's gone.
It impossible.
Well,
this one has to go to four Chan.
So fine.
If I don't believe those geniuses at
four.
Chan haven't kept this job,
but this is,
she's at level five with like trigger
puff and those who like yelled out for
more muscle Missouri state.
These are like the maximum level and
most of those people are made up of like
genuinely disturbed people.
Here she goes,
here,
can we get some volume on this crazy
bitch?
Do you work for Devin?
Wasn't that at Milo's rally?
Which is hilarious.
I think this was Gavin.
Could you say proud boys is getting your
proud boys a boy.
She might work for his marketing.
That's like the best branding.
She's still going.
We shut it off,
but she's still going.
I'm a fucking professor.
How dare you so much make a t shirt.
From my perspective,
I'm a fucking professor.
How dare you.
I've a professor is not what you
expected.
The next line's fucking professor.
How dare you so well,
but also from my perspective,
like as a libertarian,
you just look at that and you're like,
wow,
what a naked like example of you just
calling the state,
calling the authority of the state
because you believe this ridiculous
microaggressive aggression.
Like,
well,
just look at her the way she's behaving
and that's not a balance,
but ilt person.
What I was describing with the college
professor,
I wasn't talking about those people like
that's level five disturbed is that top
people will change you like belt in
Jujitsu.
That's.
That's like,
it's not even like that.
Not even black belt.
That's like next next level.
Like you're tapped out.
Yeah.
You tap out black belts,
coral and then red belt is like Noam
Chomsky,
red belt,
right.
Written Chomsky's,
a red belt.
Noam Chomsky is actually like an
intellectual.
I don't want to lump them in with these
top of right.
He,
but he is talking to the top of the food
chain,
left wing ideologies,
but this is like
some Hixon Gracie Shit,
but these,
these people,
she's more retarded.
She's more of a Kung Fu person.
She's got ineffective martial arts.
She's got some shit,
some shit that doesn't even really work
for work.
She's trying to get people with that
cheat.
Touched was like a guy with like just an
overhand right.
Could probably take you if like you'd
like to see her.
Like in an MMA fight with Cyborg.
She actually would believe that she had
this.
Cheese is still the most amazing.
There's still to me,
nothing better.
I know you've got over a bunch of near
Shell before,
but there's nothing better to me than
someone really believing in a martial
art that doesn't work and finding out in
a fight modular doesn't know.
It was amazing through the early UFC is
when it used to happen.
It'll still,
you'll find internet videos that have
it,
but it's still going on in 2016 and 17
has been some of the best videos ever,
especially at China where they had that.
One guy had to go into hiding.
He brained some fucking poor slob that
thought he knew Kung Fu.
You know some dude really thought he was
going to cheat,
touch this guy,
and he got he this Chinese kid who knows
mma,
fuck this guy up and had to go into
hiding because so many people are mad at
him for using martial arts techniques
that did not originate in China to sort
of denigrate Chinese martial arts,
man.
Yeah.
Myth versus reality.
What's interesting,
they are fighting against the exposing
of their bullshit nonsensical fucking
tiger claws.
Shit like.
And you've got an entire identity
associated with this being real me.
And want the guy who did is also
Chinese,
so China is apparently like Asia in
particular is where a lot of the martial
arts techniques that people use today
originated and they were sort of adapted
and they were changed and they evolved
particularly in Thailand.
They really started understanding how to
kick the legs and they became masters at
using the elbows and the knees more so
than and they did it through
competition,
which is really quite fascinating.
They did it through gambling and by
having these competitions on a regular
basis where people will like nine,
10 years old,
they start fighting and they fight.
They might have hundreds and hundreds of
fights in their career by the time they
retire.
They developed a real acute
understanding of what actually works and
what doesn't work.
Whereas these other worlds,
they didn't do that.
They didn't have.
They weren't like this small island is
filled with hedonists that are gambling,
kicking each other in the legs and
betting on the guy kicking the guy.
That's really what develop that art.
But then there's other ones that sort of
stayed in this non evolved state.
And then as the material sort of got out
to all of the world and people started
to evolve into techniques,
it all coalesced together in the
ultimate fighting championship.
And then we realized,
okay,
it's a combination of these things
doesn't necessarily always work on every
individual and styles sort of straddles
sort of determined interactions and
athletes determined whether or not
something is effective or ineffective as
much as the technique itself,
the athleticism and speed and power of
the practitioner is very important,
but all told these are the things that
we think are pretty effective.
These are the standard techniques.
Yeah,
the new information.
But you figure out pretty quickly like,
okay,
like wrestling and you know,
crane kicks are not the same thing.
One guy used Western boxing techniques
and Moy Tai and wrestling and Jujitsu
and just beat the holy fuck or this
poor.
I mean did it like 10 seconds,
beat the holy fuck out of this poor Kung
Fu guy.
And then he had to go into hiding.
People didn't want to know.
They didn't want to know this is white
power,
white power.
The white power guy goes in there and
gets fucking merch by Anthony.
Joshua Electric Shit.
How is this possible?
Well,
of course it happened.
Did you not know who you were?
Do you not know who he is?
You know you're,
you're in denial of this.
And so if they all came after Anthony
Joshua,
because he beat the shit out of the
white power boxer.
That's exactly what's going on in China.
It's take watch it here.
So get this guy who his poor fucking
dog,
you can just already tell he's got some
crane technique going on and the kid
just fuck and starts beating the shit
out of them.
Boom,
boom,
boom.
Just fucking pummel him.
Unconscious knuckles to the temple.
Literally it happens all the like 10,
15 seconds.
His kid just kicks the shit out of him
and then after this happens and this guy
who doesn't get hit like he's,
he's never been hit before.
You know what I mean?
Like,
yeah,
he didn't get hit at all.
He doesn't listen.
He's not used to even like being in this
situation,
but he must've believed that it was
going to work.
He must've believed that he was capable
of fending off attacks.
I agent and he's doing that crazy shit.
I'm trying to remember in mma,
what was the guy,
I can't remember his name was like some
really,
really Asian name,
but the dude to fought Nick Diaz.
You called the fight.
It was like an old nickname aspect
before he left the website and the guy
tried this crazy technique.
He tried like hands out here.
I'm going to block your punches with
punches.
It was like a short Asian dude.
Me and thinking of Tony Ferguson,
I think.
No,
no,
no.
It's 100 percent a nickname called as
cocoon.
You called it and I remember you being
there.
I remember you saying during the thing
you were like you say before the fight
you go,
this is really weird.
He was doing this stuff before,
like in the octagon warmup and it comes
out like doing it and you're like,
okay,
he's going to try to fight Nick Diaz
with this weird stuff.
Like where he's trying to,
whatever it's doing like this kind of
like,
like style of trying to block by like
hitting their hands with your hands.
Way Out.
Pull up.
Nick Diaz is a record.
I'm,
I'm remembering.
I'm Tony Ferguson fighting this guy
who's a bad motherfucker and pride.
And His name is cocooned.
No.
And he used to fight like that.
Pull up Tony Ferguson's record me.
See if he could find that video.
Tony Ferguson versus cocoon.
Yeah.
It's not.
I don't think it's he though of that
fight.
I don't remember.
Tony Ferguson.
He's been around for awhile.
Yeah,
totally lit him up.
So what it was was that cocoon was a guy
that had this crazy kick that he would
throw to the body and fuck a lot of
people up with it.
And it was kind of a hybrid between a
front kick and a roundhouse kick.
Like some people would call it a 45.
Yeah.
Cotsen,
Nora cocoon.
No.
And He came out him.
Yeah.
I think that's the fight you're thinking
of man.
No,
I'm telling you this guy pull up.
Nick Diaz is one of the ideas.
It's a different guy.
I used to fight like this.
He used to walk forward like this.
The Guy I was like that it was a similar
type of style,
but the guy was saying,
but it was like real short too and I
mean Nick Diaz just,
it was like the worst guy to fight with
that style because he's got like real
Chris boxing so he just came in.
I mean just lit them up like next to his
last fight in his first run in the UFC.
So it's up way before this.
No,
no,
I'm sorry.
Down,
down from.
This is down before it's his first run
in the UFC.
So it's a real maybe before the losses.
Gleason Josh right there.
Right there.
Before Diego Sanchez.
That's it.
Oh,
that Guy Koji.
Click on it.
Cogent.
No,
there's no ass there.
Oh yeah.
Oh he,
she is that he said,
I think you're right.
Koji.
Oishi.
Yeah,
maybe.
Oh,
okay.
Nick Diaz and I remember this kid,
I remember saying this kid looks like
he's on heroin.
Like he walked in like,
like almost like in a Zombie state as he
walked into the octagon.
It was really strange.
Just click on that right there.
That's me.
This is a different.
Is it neat?
Yeah.
And then this was in the UFC,
but it's the vine of it.
Is there?
I don't know.
I guess they both thought,
yeah,
this is the fight I'm talking about.
He's trying to do this openhanded weird
thing and it's just.
Oh Nick,
just by eating them online.
I mean,
uh,
I'm sure it's on the UFC.
See if he could find Tony Ferguson
versus cocoon.
No,
that's a weird one because cocoon.
Oh,
he had this weird style,
like almost like a car,
like you would think of as a guy who
knows karate,
like move forward,
like standing like totally square,
not sideways,
like moving forward in this weird way.
And he would throw this kick and it
wasn't a front kick up the middle.
It was like an angled front kick.
So he hit you with the ball was foot,
but you throw it like a roundhouse kick,
which was one of the ways that they used
to do that in the old taekwondo way too.
They would make impact with the ball of
the foot with a roundhouse kick,
like they would throw a kick.
Like I got a book when I was a kid about
taekwondo techniques and this one old
dude would practice in the park by
kicking trees and the way he would kick
trees with the ball of his foot.
He throw a roundhouse kick and kick the
ball of his foot into the tree.
And it was.
It was really funny,
but because in one,
one of the things where you described
all various self defense techniques,
he described what to do if you ever
threatened by someone and one thing you
should do is kick a tree.
So show them like if you kick a tree,
what you could do to them.
It's probably an actually bad advice.
It's just to break your leg and then
I'll just kick a tree.
You know what I'm saying?
Like if,
if you're not used to getting countries,
see if you can back that up,
CV,
back it up.
But that's,
it's only a ten second view.
Oh,
okay.
Cocoon was a,
hey,
this is also another one of those guys
were go let that play.
Play out.
A little video you were just showing.
He was one of those guys that was in a
shit ton of fights.
So see that was,
that was back when he was competing and
karate.
I think that's Keoki.
Yeah.
Keoki Shin.
And so they fought with yogesh and
outfits on,
but they had an MMA fight and the guy
who was a,
the referee was dressed up in a fucking
weird sort of geisha outfit.
Like what the fuck's that guy wearing?
But cocoon.
Oh,
was a like sort of a classic Japanese
martial arts.
Stryker.
That's,
that's him right there.
Okay.
And you got to think by the time these
guys got to the UFC,
they had been trained so many fucking
times,
especially fighting in pride and k one.
Oh Shit.
Boom.
Front kick to the body.
Right hand.
That's a wrap.
That was due.
Dude is fucked.
Check this out again,
man.
Watch how I do this.
Just steps.
It was a different fight.
Aau Tournament probably,
which is really crazy that these guys
would do this more than one time a day,
but that was what they did in pride a
lot.
Oh,
he just threw them off the top of the
Mat and pride.
They would fight several times a day
early UFC is as well and then it like
eventually I think they started
realizing like a lot of guys get injured
doing this.
The craziest ideas like that stupid
movie warrior when they fought more than
one time in a week,
like they fought once and they fought
again the next day.
That's got to be worse than the same day
probably because you're like all the
soreness that like comes in two days
later.
Your fucking face is all swollen.
You can't say you have to have
sunglasses everywhere.
You definitely can't take a punch.
Like the whole idea is so stupid and
they don't do that.
I mean maybe they've done that a couple
of times throughout history,
but that's not a standard thing in this
movie warrior.
They,
they just added their own Hollywood
judges to the suit,
be like,
let me just change it.
You're going to fight for the flavor,
and then the next day I'll grabbed my
balls.
That's what they did.
They added their own stupidity to it
just didn't even make any sense.
And it was totally unnecessary like
that.
That's you can't,
you're changing what martial arts are
just to fit your narrative because
you're not a good writer.
Like if you,
if you were a good writer,
you would write about how it actually
happens and you'd make a story about how
it actually happens.
You wouldn't create some fake thing that
you can do.
So be several times in a day,
twice,
two days in a row you'd be fucking meat.
Well,
it's just give them super powers at this
point.
Just give him like guns and stuff.
If you're listening to John Claude van
Damme,
you got to decide what you are.
Are you,
uh,
an excellent dramatic movie with Nick
Nolte and Tom,
what the fuck's his name?
Who was another guy?
The fuck's his name?
No,
no,
no.
How dare you?
The young guy who's a Bain,
Tom Hardy,
that motherfucker is amazing,
right?
It's him and Nick Nolte mean they're
amazing,
but yet they put it in this stupid plot
idea where they have to fight in two
days.
Like,
come on,
just come on.
It's like it's,
it's annoying because it's like you're
making this world real and then you're
doing something that's just my little
ridiculous.
Yeah.
World where I work,
so it makes me buy like super offended.
I'm super excited.
It makes it impossible for someone like
you to.
Because it's like if anyone
who knows fighting Canada,
which by the way I will say,
and I do,
even when we talk about old school,
UFC,
there's something like that.
Like I'm nostalgic for it.
I know you can't have it now.
It has to be the sport it is now and
it's evolved way past there,
but there was just something so cool
about the old ufc and there was
something about the conor versus floyd
fight that almost gave you that feeling
again of like these two guys from
different worlds going in there and like
how does this look like?
How does a guy who doing mma striking
and fucking doing like capital Ada stuff
on the side,
how does he go in there and buck and
that it turned out connor actually it
was just like,
oh no,
you got a box,
can't do any of that stuff.
Get destroyed.
So I just went out there and boxed and.
But it was an interesting.
Like I came out of it.
I was arguing with a lot of friends of
mine were like big boxing fans,
nothing against you guys.
God bless boxing.
I'm not like as big a fan as I used to
bake.
I'm a huge MMA fan,
but I just can't.
Like when you look at mma,
the way you look at mma is like the
sport of fighting and,
and the original thing was always
figuring out who's better at fighting
and have these does.
It was just hard for me to not look at
the fight with conor and floyd and go
like,
you know,
it's like when there was the first
Clinton I,
Louis j Gomez said this to me is the
first clinch of the fight.
He goes,
well,
that's where connor would destroy him.
Yeah,
and then you just sit there watching 10
rounds of of a referee,
saving floyd mayweather's life.
Like every few seconds the referee comes
in and goes,
Oh,
let me save your life.
Don't let me save your life.
I know you're the greatest effort this,
but you need even under your rules with
your gloves and your this,
you need a ref to keep coming in and
saving your life every few seconds and
you'd see it like every time they they
clenched.
Like connor would immediately almost
just instinctually just kind of take us
back and like step over here because
right here is where I can hit you and
you can't hit.
It would just cover up and bend over.
Like literally bend over,
guy come saved my life buddy.
And it's just hard to not watch that and
go,
Oh,
if he wanted to,
he would jump on his back and choke them
to death.
And even in Europe,
even in your sport,
like he went 10 rounds and okay,
I know mayweather.
I know what may,
whether did was brilliant and he dragged
him in,
he played it safe and perfectly,
but it wasn't a part of the plan to eat
that upper cut on the chin that
definitely wasn't a part of the planet.
And,
and also I think there's boxers punch a
lot harder than MMA guys do and there's,
there's truth to that too.
So Connor's power didn't translate in
the way that MMA fans thought it would,
but he's just not quite as fluid.
And also I think he was probably very
nervous.
I mean he's fighting literally the
greatest fighter of all time and his
first professional boxing match.
It's so crazy.
And yet he's still got it to the 10th
round it flow.
I mean,
I,
this is why I said I said I gave her a
very small chance of winning a boxing
match,
very small.
So I thought it was like 94 percent that
floyd would beat the shit out of Canada
the way he did.
And the economy would eventually get
tired.
Like the guy who did the best assessment
of it,
uh,
in my opinion was John,
John Donahoe.
John Danaher,
who's a brilliant Jujitsu coach,
is also brilliant mma coach because get
a deep understanding of it.
He basically spelled out exactly what's
going to happen because of all the times
he's seen a boxer's sparring with elite
martial artists that the mixed martial
arts does well for a few rounds because
it takes awhile for the box and to
figure out the timing and then the
efficiency and fluidity of the box.
It starts to take over the ring
generalship the understanding of this
one isolated particular discipline and
then they dominate and that's exactly
what happened to a it.
What I said is I think there's a 94
percent chance that floyd mayweather.
It just boxes the shit out of conor
Mcgregor.
There is a four percent chance that
connor catches him with like an apricot
like it did in the first round and
actually stuns them and hurts them and
then swarms on him and takes him out.
Connor has got ferocious power.
It's whether or not he executed that
power,
like he has an mma,
whether he felt he could drain his gas
tank like that,
especially with two months worth of
training,
not enough,
not enough to get in shape for a 12
round boxing match against the greatest
of all time,
but there was a 100 percent chance that
connor nukes him in a fucking mma fight.
Nukes him like I would be willing to
literally 100 [inaudible] Floyd's not
going to knock them out with one punch
and Conecuh kick his fucking legs out
from under him before we got even close
enough to punch them.
And if they did get to a clinch,
which they absolutely would,
connor would ragdoll him to the ground
and beat his fucking brains in before he
strangled him.
One hundred percent,
100 percent.
Even if you just look,
if you just take out even grappling.
I agree with you that I just thought as
a master of range and he's got excellent
kicks and if he can kick the shit out of
him and stay out of the area where he's
just stay out of his punching range and
kick him in the legs and the body
believed if he can clench,
if you don't break them up.
When he coaches,
he show nice the body,
they're done fucked.
You're fucked in elbows to the head.
He's going to tie you up in the back of
the head and smash you.
Has that ever happened?
No.
He's never.
You don't know what the fuck to do when
a guy's doing that.
You don't know how to deal with those
needs.
The face like when Anderson Silva fucked
up rich Franklin to win the title when
you just plumb the back of his head and
just start smashing these in his face
and he was clear that rich really didn't
know.
He didn't have an answer to that,
which was an amazing thing because that
was one of those moments like everyone
in the mma world thought rich was the
best or not mma world.
Everyone in the UFC world kind of like
what was the,
because you're.
That's why I correct myself because
people who knew the MMA scene better and
pride and that stuff knew what Anderson
Silva was,
but like the average fan of the UFC had
just been.
We hadn't really seen Anderson Silva.
I hadn't seen one or two tapes of pride
and I would say I saw him like maybe
not.
It's on the one where you got ankle,
ankle locked real quick because I didn't
really know how good Anderson Silva was.
I saw I'd seen him beat Carlos Newton
and that was like all I had on them,
so I was like,
I have rich Franklin will probably.
Well the third type is the pride fights.
The thing was when he got out of pride
and then fighting in a cage wars or cage
warrior,
what the fuck was that?
English.
I remember the one you're talking to the
organization.
I know that it's an English
God dammit.
I want to say cage wars,
but it's not that cage warrior the fuck
do they call it?
Anyway,
he went over there and just started
fucking people you can people.
So like I hadn't seen any of that,
any of that,
and I think,
I guess most of UFC fans hadn't seen
that either and they thought rich
Franklin is the champ.
Beat up a bunch of guys.
The odds were actually I'm in innocence
favor though.
Oh,
what are they?
One of the weird ones where the odds
makers,
when he fought Chris Leben,
he was a slight favorite looney his
first UFC fight and I was like,
get ready for some crazy shit because
this motherfucker's on a totally
different level.
I'm like,
I knew him.
I'd seen him fight Jorge Rivera and Lee
Marie.
I saw him hit Tony Ferguson with a step
in upper cut elbow that he had practice
on a pillow at home.
He made his wife hold a pillow and
practice this technique because he
wanted to use it in his fights in as
coaches wouldn't hold the pads for them
because they thought it was ridiculous
and they said,
is this true?
I think I remember hearing this,
but I think it was like in between
rounds.
He said to one of his coaches,
he goes,
I think it's open.
I think it's there.
They were like,
forget about this stupid technique.
Dammit.
Like,
it's not going to be there.
Uh,
I don't know if that's the case.
You were worried about that.
Fucked up Tony Ferguson before that.
The reason why I was able to get that
off,
it's because he wasn't turning 21st.
Excuse me.
I'm 20 Franklin.
Tony fryklund sorry,
my apologies.
Twenty percent.
Um,
he fought Tony Franklin and he hit him
with the standing,
stepping in upper cut with the elbow and
he was just like another level,
maybe three,
four,
five levels above Franklin at the time.
It was just so infrequent,
was a real veteran.
Franklin was in one of the first.
You have c's that I ever worked in.
Nineteen 97.
He was there.
And so that was like his debut in the
UFC.
I was there when he had his debut.
So Anderson was just lightened him on
fire before he decided to step in an
upper cut them.
But I just knew he was on it just such a
different level.
But that was a really important learning
moment for mma because people knew like,
okay,
if you get in a fight and a guy is a
more Thai practitioner on the level of
Anderson Silva,
you better learn how to deal with this
goddamn clinch.
So here's Anderson versus a Tony
Franklin and this is Anderson in,
in my opinion,
maybe his prime ever because he hadn't
taken on all the damage and all the
crazy fights that he had in the UFC.
And by the time he got to Chris Weidman,
I mean he was in his thirties.
He's getting older or his body was
starting to not perform the way it used
to and then obviously he fucked up and
stood in front of Weidmann,
got left hooked in the head while I was
clowning them.
Then it's a lot tougher to come back
when you're 40 now they've taken these
losses,
but it's time back then was so fucking
tight and it was just so levels above
what everyone else was doing.
Oh yeah.
They just did.
Didn't belong in there with them.
Like look how he's moving around.
Just sort of like feeling out.
Tony trying to find out what Tony's
capable of trying to decide when to
move.
I mean he really is like a spider
because he's setting up the web and he's
moving around.
Eventually it's going to sting you and
you know it's come in and you know by
the time you're moving at him,
look at that.
Boom.
One,
two starts kicking you and now he's
coming after you.
Oh Shit Bitch.
Now you know there's a big difference
between the two of you and it just feels
like even if you don't know anything
about fighting,
you just know there's levels here.
Like you can just see it.
Everything he does in this fight,
it's like fucking picture perfect.
He steps in and look at this beautiful
Thai clinch clenched his,
his control of the neck and head was
spectacular.
Look at that.
Boom,
and it's bigger
than all these.
Stronger than them like knees to the
body,
man.
And Franklin is fucking throwing down,
He's,
he's doing his best.
He was a warrior,
but you'd see it when he would be.
When he went up and fought at two.
Oh five.
And he'd be in the clench with honor and
forrest griffin,
like these guys couldn't do anything to
them.
So these guys are like,
just,
he's already fucked here because he's
eating a bunch of really hard shots to
the body and even though he's moving
okay and he's like really compromised.
He'll look at that beautiful right hook
and then left kick,
left low kick.
And Anderson fought a lot from the
southpaw stance.
He could fight from any position he
wanted to,
but he fought a lot from the southpaw
stance,
which is also an advantage to a lot of
people.
It's amazing how much mma guys make it
look like me and Jesus.
His arm's gone limp.
I mean it's this boom,
boom.
Wow Dude.
That is nuts.
It's nuts.
Just the way he moves.
Watch them step in here though,
man.
It's so crazy.
Watch this
step in elbow.
First time ever in MMA.
That was Anderson in his prime and the
cool.
And it was one of those moments where a
particularly you have like,
I've had a lot in watching mma where
when someone comes in and beat someone
else at their strength and then you have
to reorganize your mind where you're
like,
oh,
I thought that guy was like.
Because Franco was like,
this guy's got really great hands,
he's a really good striker.
And then a guy like that lets you know
like,
oh,
there's like another world when,
you know,
it's like levels.
You got these guys like the Chinese Kung
Fu guy and then you have all these
different levels,
these steps along the way in the
spectrum.
And then you've got like Moitai of
Anderson.
But then you got like Moitai of Sand
Chai in Thailand.
It's like several levels,
past Anderson Pool cow and rob deck,
Ramon Ramon dekkers.
And Rob came in and all the greats,
you know,
uh,
Ernesto,
who's these guys are like even further
past that,
you know,
there's all these crazy,
crazy,
crazy levels to this thing.
And you know,
when you see a guy like Anderson you see
just for the first time it was in the
UFC where you have like legitimate world
class,
maybe not the best ever and more Thai,
but legitimate worldclass Moitai skills,
watching them fight.
That's like a professional Moy Thai
fighter.
And it seems to me like,
um,
for whatever reason I think because in
it's on its own,
it works better in a real fight.
So the grappling stuff in mma like
pretty quickly,
we got very high level grapplers pretty
quickly.
Like,
I mean from the first UFC,
you've got the best Jujitsu guys at the
time or were at least one of a
representative of the gracies.
And then uh,
you know,
you got Olympic level wrestlers in there
pretty quickly.
Like,
I mean it was,
it wasn't too long before,
like Dan Severn and Mark Coleman and
guys like that who had like legit
wrestling credits came in.
But it took a long time before you got
like really,
really high level striker.
So he got Maury Smith was the guy,
he was,
he was really the first was the first.
Yeah,
go back to that,
go back to that fight again.
Here's something that's
interesting to point out as Bas rutten
was one of the early guys to strewn was
after Maurice where there weren't too
many besides that,
like it.
Those guys were like a few who actually
because it took so much to learn all the
other shit.
Right.
But the difference between boss and
Maurice was that Maurice was more of a
tactician and boss was a destroyer and
he's like an intelligent animal.
He would just like attack like vicious,
ferocious striking,
you know,
but real aggressive but also very
technical as well.
Whereas Maurice is much more clever like
leg kick dependent,
like Maurice is actually on a higher
level in terms of like professional
kickboxing.
Then boss boss didn't have like a lot of
kickboxing fights.
Maurice was a world champion,
but boss had that Holland style and as
an MMA fighter he was one of the first
guys that we ever saw that kick so
fucking hard.
But if you watch this fight,
what you learn is like what conor
mcgregor figured out.
What conor mcgregor figured out is that
what holds a lot of these guys back his
movement and see if you look at Tony
Franklin as he's moving towards
Anderson,
his movement,
he's very limited like he can't.
He can't cover distance quick enough.
He has to make these little hop steps,
hop steps,
just slide in and blast things.
Connor is fluid with his movement in and
out to the point where he can step
forward and obviously wouldn't be able
to do that with Anderson Silva,
but he can step forward and step in and
step out like when he fought a Joseph,
although one of the most important parts
of that fight was that Aldo was trying
to figure out the movement of Connor,
like go to go to that fight.
Joseph Aldo versus conor mcgregor and
what connor was doing so good was
sliding forward and sliding back.
There's like that one moment because
it's a very short fight,
but there's the one moment where he
faints a thing and jumps back right
here.
See that?
See how sleep pod,
but look how like he.
He's in and out.
He's moving a lot and it's.
It's a different thing,
boom,
slides back and drops the fucking left
hammer on his chin and it's that
movement that's so critical in a really
high level.
If I look,
look how fluid he slides back and
launches that punch at the same time.
It's very interesting to me too because
it was a different intensity in his
movement than like when he fought.
Other guys like Chad Mendez matter
because he respected what Al Alto
throws,
alto throws heat and especially in that
first round when Aldo is furious at you
for disrespecting them.
Like he knows he's coming with like a
bomb,
but yeah,
just but superior movement.
It's also new,
unorthodox movement bloom.
I mean a lot of ways.
They've been doing that shit and karate
tournaments forever.
Right.
But people hadn't figured it out in MMA
yet.
I mean if you look at a lot of what
connor had done with his stance and his
movement,
a lot of it resembles what you see in
the karate point tournaments where they
would leap in and drop a shot on you and
leap out,
but they weren't fighting stationary.
People like.
Although that just charged forward,
but although got used to fighting in
that man fitting more Thai guys and that
kind of mma look,
it's just the wrestling look.
It's been,
you know,
it's really fascinating to me.
Just on this kind of evolution was a um.
Oh God,
what's his name?
A hutto the
guy who fought Demetrius Johnson who
don't,
who just,
I don't know who fights like him now.
He all the sudden he adopted this style
and you're like,
Holy Shit,
this style gives people real problems.
And it's like I get,
I mean maybe I'm wrong about this,
but it reminds me a little bit of almost
like Mochida type thing,
but it's like this,
it's this weird karate kind of thing
that it's like this weird evolution wake
once you have all the other shit.
And what connor does this,
he's also got really good traditional
boxing.
So like,
like not a lot of MMA guys couldn't do
10 rounds with me whether they,
he's also got boxing so he can kind of
mix it up with like traditional boxing
attacks and this crazy other shit.
So what's crazy about him is he'll be
like throwing like,
like these crazy spinning like cartwheel
kicks and then he'll just have like a
one,
two that was like perfect,
which that's new to mma or we haven't
seen a lot of that in the past.
And you know,
it's titles,
those kicks are longer too.
You're dealing with something that
reaches much further than the
traditional Moitai techniques or,
or straight boxing techniques.
He's throwing sidekicks.
He's.
His head is so far away from you when
he's throwing a side kick,
if he lands,
if he's touching you in the chest or the
sidekick,
there's no opportunity for you to
counterpunch he's way over there.
He's bent sideways.
His head is way out of reach.
He might be able to catch them with a
kick if he comes forward after he drops
the sidekick,
if you're in range,
but you might get pushed back.
There's a lot of factors involved.
The fight and the guy who fights like
that.
And so who does figure that out?
And then he just dropped some bombs on
Wilson has that is,
which is,
uh,
you know,
I mean obviously like,
Demetrius Johnson is like head and
shoulders above,
above everybody,
everybody else.
And he made quick work of him.
But that was like,
at least to me,
like a little like glimpse of like,
oh,
well maybe if this guy is this good a
grappler in,
is figuring,
striking out like this.
Maybe he's the guy who could,
you know,
like be a good,
a good contender.
It may may happen very well.
I mean he might challenge them one day,
but what Henry Cejudo represents is like
extreme talent,
a real sponge for knowledge and
information.
And he's got a guy that's in his
division,
that's the king.
That's,
in my opinion,
the greatest martial arts of all time.
I don't think there's anybody that's
been a better representation of what's
possible in modern martial arts better
than mighty mouse because he just
doesn't get hit.
And He fucks everybody up and you can't
hit him,
man.
He's coming at you.
And then all of sudden he's over here.
And then you've got a knee in your body
and then you got punched in the face and
you're trying to figure out what the
fuck's happening.
All the sudden you're on your back and
he's dropping hammer fists on you and
you,
by the time you're reacting to that,
he's gotten in an arm bar.
You're like,
what the fuck just happened to me.
Yeah.
It's hard to argue with the emerald.
He's,
he fights like he's a specialist at
every discipline.
Yeah.
Like he's like,
he's like,
like you feel like he could beat all the
specialists at their discipline.
And it's like what George St Pierre used
to kind of do.
But uh,
yeah,
I do modern,
modern MMA and more dominant.
Not going to decisions destroying
everybody.
He's about to break the record if you
already have about to,
you know,
who knows,
right?
You're right.
I shouldn't grant him.
Weidman knocked out Anderson Silva.
Nobody saw that coming.
This is a crazy sport.
It's not,
it's,
it is a crazy sport.
And it's like,
it seems like nobody can escape it.
Right?
Like it's like it takes the toughest,
most invincible person you can think of
as like Anderson Silva was a Ninja in
untouchable Ninja and then you see him
crying in the center of the ring with
like a shattered,
shattered,
but whatever,
you know,
split up Shinbo.
I mean it's like it's chocolate dal.
Like all these landscapes.
They came,
saw junior dos Santos,
drop a bomb on,
came the Alaska isn't came collapsed.
You're like,
wow.
And then Kane can get Kale and then
junior dos Santos at that point.
Then I was like,
well,
after that you're like,
I guess we're living in junior dos
Santos has world.
I mean those guys destroyed everyone.
And then to watch him get nuked by Cain
and the rematch can you just came back
and beat the fuck out of him,
but can the first fight really probably
should have been fighting.
But it was the first big fight on Fox
and he had a fucked up Neiman and you
couldn't move.
Right.
And the only one out of the way,
his only two losses were when he was
coming off an injury.
I believe he was coming off an injury
against Fabrizio overdo as well.
Uh,
well he was always coming off injuries
by that.
Is that as a problem?
But the real problem with,
for Breo,
for doing fight was that he didn't
prepare in Mexico City.
Mexico City is at 7,000,
500 feet above sea level,
which is where I was in Utah last week.
I couldn't imagine if you didn't train
there that you could be adapted to it.
The way for Breesa was because for he
smart,
he was there for like,
I think a couple months at sea level
training doing his entire camp in Mexico
like way,
even above 7,500.
I think he got up to the eight
thousands.
Yeah,
that's the house seemed in the fight.
Like that made a big difference.
Pretty hard to argue because cane is
known as being the cardio care.
Fabrizio knock on his cardio,
but that's not what he's known for.
He's not known for being like the Cardio
and,
and to see him at last time it was like,
oh yeah,
that's a,
that's almost.
It's almost like cain had so much
confidence in his cardio because this is
what he's been known for since like
before he got into the UFC,
it's like he's,
he's got this unbelievable tank that he
was like,
no,
I'll be fine with that and it.
And it didn't work out.
Okay.
But I'll say,
and I know he's an injury case,
but like the Cain Velasquez that showed
up to ufc 200 that fought a travis
brown.
I don't see any heavyweight beating that
guy.
Well,
I dunno for breach shall beat him.
I mean,
I don't know if he would be able to beat
them again.
But see,
the thing is for eco,
his striking improved radically hand.
He's got long reach.
He's a big tall guy and he's strong as
fuck.
And if you could take him down,
good God damn luck.
Everybody found.
If there's another argument for anybody
being the greatest heavyweight of all
time besides cane,
it's fabrizio.
Fabrizio might have a better argument
because fabricio submitted all the
greats.
He submitted fate or million inco
submitted minotauro.
Nogueira submitted Cain Velasquez.
I mean,
fabrizio submitted fucking everybody.
He's got some amazing ones.
Amazing runs.
Yeah.
If he didn't get killed by Steve Bay and
fighting out of composure,
he was fighting very emotionally.
He's chasing steep a.
I mean,
just got wild.
He was in Brazil.
He wanted to fucking get after it,
you know,
it was pumped up there in Brazil.
He's the heavyweight champ.
He's fired up,
but I think he might've underestimated
what a bad motherfucker steep meo trick
is and how the steep.
They could do the same thing.
Connor did slide away and drop that
right hand,
like pays a fucking elite
athlete.
He's a monster.
I think I slept on him a little bit too
much for a long time.
But no,
you see it in,
you know,
he's,
he's proved it like it was last minute,
but I was blown away by how reckless a
lot about that.
I mean he just charged them like
straight on.
Charge them as a dangerous way to fight
any MMA fighter.
Yeah.
It was like modern day.
He made a mistake and I think he made
that mistake because you got caught
before that.
I think he got clip before that and he
got emotional because he got clipped and
he tried to really ramp it up and
overcompensate.
Like if you watch that fight before
Steve Bay knocks him out.
He catches him a couple times.
Yeah.
Pays a sharp boxer.
Very,
very sharp hands and he catches you on
the chin.
Oh,
we could put people away.
Obviously he's putting everybody away
now.
Put Away Alistair overeem.
Arguably the greatest strike or whoever
fought in mma,
you know,
k one Grand Prix champion.
Strikeforce dropped,
dropped and got right back up.
You know,
that's,
that's pretty impressive.
Fucking animal.
Yeah.
And when I was talking to him after the
fight,
he thought he got kicked.
I,
he didn't even remember he got punched.
It was all.
He was like,
I don't know what the fuck happened.
Usually it wasn't sure if he's like,
oh,
I know that one.
Well,
both of them felt they want.
He's the highest level so far.
You know,
Steve Bay in his athleticism,
his ability to move,
his ability to overcome obstacles like
junior had kicked the shit out of his
leg to the point we had this giant
Hematoma on his shin and he's still
knocked him out.
Yeah,
that was,
that was a very interesting fight.
I mean it was super quick,
but it was like a lot of actions super
quick.
Now I do the more.
I'd love to see a healthy cane come back
and fight.
Yeah.
I don't know what the extent of his
injuries are and why he's been sidelined
so long and you'd have to talk to him
personally,
but what I'm hoping is that I know a lot
of it was back issues and shoulder
issues.
He had shoulder surgery,
knee surgery,
back surgery,
and he had several surgeries,
so it's just that style is so aggressive
and so physically dependent.
I mean he just so fucking overwhelming
that a lot of it is mental toughness,
the mental toughness to push past
everybody.
Sometimes your body just can't keep up.
Right.
And so like,
right in general,
probably every high level MMA,
UFC fighter at this point.
I mean,
what they're doing to their body when
they're putting their body through,
is it a lot for,
you know,
I mean it's like,
it's like really pushing yourself to the
absolute limit constantly.
Then as you mentioned,
his style is particularly,
you know,
like kind of physical,
physical and he comes from a chaos
that's notoriously a very,
very tough case.
Those guys are like known for like
getting in wars and like really,
really training hard.
So I'm sure all of that shit doesn't.
It's bad because if Cain cain had such
amazing cardio and great footwork and
beautiful striking technique as well as
like real elite wrestling technique.
If cain fought more in a mighty mouse
sense.
It's just one of the reasons what made
mighty mouse so good is that like if
cain used his cardio,
not in like a blunt way,
but more in a surgical way.
Right.
You know,
if cane,
like in the junior dos Santos fight in
particular,
he caught them like real early in the
fight and clipped him with a right hand
and heard them rock them and just
decided to mall them.
She has got all over him,
amalgam,
but he took a lot of damage in the
process.
They both did.
They both hit each other and he came
overwhelmingly dominated the fight,
but it wasn't.
It wasn't the way mighty mouse does.
Mighty mouse doesn't get hit.
He's there and then he's here and then
you're getting hit,
you know,
and then he's on your clench and then
boom,
you get a need in the chin and then
you're getting elbowed and then boom,
you're getting tripped and then if he's
just doing things,
he's got this repertoire of
possibilities that no one else has.
Whereas cain just had this ferocious
attitude,
powerful striking and ungodly cardio,
which is common at your bitch.
Here we go.
Yeah.
It's interesting.
One of the things may whether it was
talking about.
I see him like in a few different
interviews leading up to the conor
fight,
but just talking about the fee,
it's a crazy thing that like,
it almost seem like fans like the guy
who takes a lot of head damage more like
they don't like the guy who avoids those
wars and avoid that,
but it's like you sit there and look at
the way Mohammed Ali left and the way
floyd mayweather's leaving.
Oh yeah.
And it's like,
okay,
I get it.
The fans love rope a dope more,
but like,
I dunno,
it's kind of hard to argue with that.
Yeah,
floyd going out,
beating conor is really the perfect way
to do it too because he really didn't
take much damage and that fight took one
good solid upper cut in the first round
and then Kinda like took over.
So He gets his big 50th win and then
really gets to show that it's really
about boxing.
It's not about slugging and standing
there,
but when people talk about him,
they don't talk about them with the same
reverence that they talk about like
Arturo Gotti and micky ward made because
they were more entertaining.
Like the people that get entertained by
the style,
the fighter,
the wild,
crazy slugger.
They love those guys.
I mean,
we all love those guys.
Like,
I mean,
who doesn't love Travis Browne versus
Andrei Arlovski like a fight like that.
I mean it's like the grant and to see
things like,
to see somebody come back after getting
like,
like there's something incredible about
that.
It's like,
it's,
it's an amazing thing that mma,
like when you were talking about a
steeping,
not knowing whether it was a kick or a
punch is this amazing thing that mma
does where you find out someone's true
character when they're in a storm,
you know,
and like how they come and that's
amazing.
But if you are that person,
you know,
it's just a little bit different.
Like there's human elements involved
too.
And like you got a family,
you've got kids.
You want to think for the rest of your
life you want to like,
and how can you argue with floyd?
I mean the guy made the most money and
took the least damage and as the best
record on you argue with that
and figured out a way to neutralize
really dangerous people like Canelo
Alvarez.
I mean,
forget about the conor fight who was
congress,
obviously outmatched,
but if you look at his fights with
really elite knockout artists like manny
Pacquiao neutralized him,
Canelo Alvarez neutralized him.
I mean,
pretty much everybody fought.
He fought a freestyle that was more
entertaining because you wanted him to
lose his,
like his,
his brilliance was that he got you to
hate him so that you would buy a fight
hoping that the guy was going to kick
his ass.
So
I remember doing this thing.
Uh,
I was on,
I was on a radio show,
um,
that,
uh,
Brian Stan called into was like MMA
radio show on Sirius radio that they
used to use me on sometimes.
And Brian Stan called and I remember he
was just talking about like,
I forget what the topic was at first it
was like Joe Silva had just left and he
wasn't matchmaking anymore.
And he started talking about how like,
how,
how tough the job is,
a matchmaking and how much it fucks with
you when someone gets knocked out real
bad.
And then you're like,
and maybe I shouldn't have made that
match.
You know what I mean?
Like you kind of feel like,
oh,
maybe I threw someone in the wrong time.
And I was kind of like,
Oh man,
that's a human element I really never
think about in that job.
And then he was like,
we were talking about GSP coming back.
And he was like,
yeah,
you know,
I just don't think GSP each come back
like,
what's he got to prove and what's it
going to do,
you know,
why risk the brain damage,
you know?
And then it's like this weird thing.
Like you never think about that as a
fan,
but when you start meeting the guys and
they actually become people like I met
Michael bisbing and Lewis does it show
with him?
They do a podcast,
a believer.
You believe you may really great
podcasts.
How do it.
They do it through skype?
Yeah,
skype,
I believe.
Yeah.
So He's in La and Louis is in New York
and they skype it and then like when
they're on the coast,
we'll do it together.
But uh,
but so you know,
like you get to know them like hang a
few times and like your friends and like
I think it kind of like,
oh yeah,
no,
I don't want to see you go fight one of
these killers,
which is fight gsp and then retire after
that.
Dude,
like what,
what are you doing?
Like you've,
you've had a great career,
you're the champ,
you get a huge money fight now you're
great at,
at the commentating thing.
It's like when you know someone
personally,
it's a little bit more like,
ah Nah Dude,
just.
But when you're just a fan,
it's like,
all right,
I want to see you fight Yoel Romero and
then with the car and then this guy and
then.
But like when you know someone,
you're like,
oh,
that guy's a monster.
I don't know.
That's my.
It makes my job way harder for like the
guy I imagine and I know it's going to
be a mismatch.
Like you find out somebody you really
care for.
It was gonna fight.
Somebody that is just going to light
them up and you're like,
oh,
are you going to win this?
You know,
that very public moment with a Brendan
shot.
But it was a very interesting,
compelling moment because it's like a
thing where it's like,
yeah,
you're like,
you're talking to your friend Tommy,
you're also an analyst.
I'm talking to a good friend who I knew
as a good friend was already one foot
out the door and had a bunch of other
things that were going on and was one of
the rare guys that has massive potential
to do things outside the sport.
Yeah,
he's killing it.
He's killing.
It was right.
Look at me and he's smashing it with his
podcast,
smashing it with the fighter and the kid
podcast he does with count to machinate
with his live touring.
It was amazing to see him.
Uh,
he did a fucking great job on all the
stuff leading up to conor conference.
Like he was excellent.
He was like the only mma analysts who
was in there kind of breaking shit down.
It was great.
It's like why?
So all,
all that to just have one or two more
fights and maybe take some real band.
Really see one thing if he really wanted
to do that.
Like if he was obsessed and that's what
he wanted to do,
he wanted to win the heavyweight title
and that was 100 percent of his focus
was.
But he wasn't there.
I mean maybe it was when he first
started his career and often times your
motivation shifts.
You get knocked out a few times and he
had been knocked out several.
By then he got knocked
out by Minotauro.
He got knocked out by big Ben Rothwell.
He got smashed by Travis Brown.
He got knocked out by Roy Nelson.
And these are out cold knockouts,
so like there was so many of them and I
was seeing it so often.
And then towards the end I was noticing
just a lack of enthusiasm.
It wasn't the same as those.
It wasn't the same fire that allowed
them to knock out Mirko Cro,
cop.
It wasn't the same sort of intensity.
You,
you told me last time I was on the show
that you've experienced that a smart
guys have a tougher time.
Yeah.
Coming back from getting knocked out
because I found that really interesting.
Maybe that's part of the case with him.
It was like,
it's hard to avoid knowing the
information.
Yeah,
most certainly.
I mean if you're a person who being you
can be a smart person,
just compartmentalize things and
figuring out how to control the
variables in your mind and just be
refocused on what you're doing.
It's not to say that people come back
aren't smart,
but I think,
uh,
I mean people,
it's not to say also that people who
don't,
who fight aren't smart because a lot of
people think of fighters is not being
smart.
I think that's not true at all.
I think there's a lot of people who
fight who aren't smart,
but I think the people who excel have
exceptional mind power as well as
physical power.
I think some of them are like a,
like a guy like a dominant Cruz.
It's like a very smart guy.
I mean there's guys like that,
right?
Stands by saying I'm very intelligent
guy and then when you go to champions,
like mighty mouse is super smart and
he's a very,
very articulate guy and it doesn't show
any damage at all.
I mean,
I'm sure there are some meat heads also
out there,
but you know,
it's,
it's certainly like a mix.
It's A.
Yeah.
Carlos condit,
he's another one.
There's a lot of guys who fight,
um,
that just aren't like that though.
There's a lot of guys who were just like
super aggressive and they just do well
and they kick ass and you know,
the guys who know that they're
experiencing traumatic brain injury,
they,
they understand the consequences are,
they're unavoidable.
Unless there's some new medical
breakthrough that allows you to heal
cte,
which is super,
super possible.
Yeah,
well absolutely.
I mean if you described the medical
breakthroughs we have now 50 years ago,
you'd be talking about magic.
So yeah,
my buddy Steve Graham was on the US ski
team like in the 19 eighties and he had
scars when I first met him.
He had already had like,
I mean in his life,
I want to say he's had more than 20 knee
surgeries and I think I'm being super
conservative because I think it's way
more than that.
I think he literally had.
He's had 50 surgeries including eye
surgeries.
Um,
he's had shoulder surgery,
everything.
But when I met him,
his knees were so fucked up.
He had these big slices up and down the
side of his knees where they had opened
him up and tried to screw things back
together again from skiing,
just mangling his knees in the old days
of skiing and those same operations.
Today I have one on this knee.
You can't even see the scar.
It's little tiny dots because they did
it arthroscopically and they put it in a
cadaver unit and healed in six months.
I was doing Jujitsu again.
No pain,
no loss of range of motion.
Everything feels
stronger than I felt before.
So like that's just the medical science
that occurred in 20 years,
20 years from his operation to my
operation.
What's it gonna be 20 years from now,
it's totally possible they'll develop
some sort of stem cell technique to
regenerate brain tissue.
Yeah.
Well this is why it's so.
It's so crazy the bulb in human history
where at,
where we're like,
guys,
if we can just not kill each other for
like another couple of years,
we might do some really beautiful,
amazing shit.
Right?
Like we really might.
We might.
Why?
It's crazy that one of our big threats
is North Korea.
Yeah.
Because that represents like one of the
oldest styles of running a country ever.
And it's really,
um,
I do,
I do.
I think trump's been really bad on a,
on that issue.
And like,
that's fucking,
that is terrifying.
I was really happy when you had a
Michael Malice on because I've learned a
lot about North Korea from that.
Yeah.
He knows so much about his book,
dear readers,
excellence.
And yes,
it's an excellent book.
And he's just a fascinating human being.
Yeah,
got it.
But it's,
you know,
it's like you have,
as we were saying before,
like it's like a hostage situation,
but the guy holding the hostages has
nukes,
which makes that like a very different
type of hostage situation.
Any shooting them in the sky but also
duds over Japan.
Yes,
yes.
But there also is like people,
because again,
the media which just absolutely has a
blind spot for the military industrial
complex and the horror of American wars.
So you get,
you don't get the full picture.
I think like to me it's very logical why
he's shooting off rockets left and
right.
Like he,
I mean self preservation is a pretty
obvious motivator and people like
Gaddafi who come out and say,
oh,
okay,
you international community,
you said you don't want us to have
nuclear arms.
So then will disarm.
We'll end our nuclear program where they
do that.
We move in there and throw them out and
get the ends up getting sodomized to
death,
you know.
So that's like if you're this guy you're
like,
well I'm going to not go that route
right.
So now I'm going to show you,
and basically he's showing you I can
fucking nuke South Korea.
I can nuke these fucking places if you
come at me.
Uh,
that being said,
you know,
he's a madman,
he's totally a madman who's holding
people hostage and it's horrific.
But there are like certain,
okay,
if you have a hostage situation,
there are some reasonable ways to handle
that and some ridiculous ways to handle
that.
So like when you have a hostage
situation,
I think it's reasonable to negotiate
with the guy.
I think it's reasonable to take them out
if you have a shot.
You know what I'm saying?
If someone has a shot and like too many,
like,
like people won't be hurt,
we can take them out,
take the shot.
What you don't do is stand outside and
start talking shit.
So the guy who's got the hostages.
Yeah.
Know if trump's not thinking of it as
anything other than like a Rosie
O'donnell.
Yes.
He talks shit about Rosie O'donnell.
Who's calling the sky rocket man?
Where's that?
Kind of like with Rosie O'Donnell.
But you know,
there's the,
there's a thing about trump.
I'm no,
I'm no fan of his,
but there's something,
I kind of get a thrill.
I got a kick out of how he'd Piss off
people who I'm not a huge fan of.
I'll tell you though,
I love Hillary.
When she did the things he,
Bernie Hillary.
I love the nicknames until it was rocket
man.
I was really into the nicky nicknames
and you're like,
whoa.
Hey Buddy,
this isn't funny anymore.
This guy's got nukes.
But there's the um,
well,
look,
when he,
it was a morning Joe,
a cohost,
Mika Brzezinski shape.
So she made a thing and on the show were
they,
there was a picture on Time magazine
with trump with like this,
with his hands under his arms and she
made a joke on the show and she goes,
oh,
how come he doesn't want to show his
hands?
Maybe because they're teeny.
Okay.
That was a joke.
She made the sentinel essentially.
It's a little Dick joke.
I mean,
that's what she was making herself.
So Donald Trump,
like immediately tweets out I think
about her and he goes,
when she was at my,
uh,
when she was at my party,
she had,
she had scars from the facelift.
She's still bleeding,
bleeding from the face looks for that.
They asked me to sit with her,
did not go.
Yes,
yes.
So it's this thing now.
Then of course the media goes right into
the mode of like,
how could you insult a woman's,
you know,
like looks and it's like,
I don't know man,
like if you can't take the heat,
get out of the fucking Dick joke.
And then people were like actual
journalists like grown up people who
consider themselves journalists.
I saw reporting a week later.
It's been confirmed that Mika Brzezinski
wasn't even at that event and didn't
even.
Yeah,
you fucking idiots.
This isn't a real thick.
He's just getting her back.
Like she hit him and he's hitting her
back.
Like,
yes,
if you're,
if you're vain enough to be having
plastic surgery,
probably you're not going out while
you're still bleeding from the plastic
surgery.
But like it's the point is,
and I kind of liked that about trump,
it's like,
oh,
finally someone being unapologetic and
being like,
I disagree with you hardcore because I
think it's stupid and childish and like,
are you fucking dumb?
It's beneath being the president of the
United States and this idea that you're
going to make up a story about a woman
bleeding from plastic surgery to get
over because she said you have little
hands.
That's some weak bitch.
Okay.
As you repeat it back to me,
it does sound like some wheat.
Sweet.
If that was your friend.
Hold on a second.
Okay.
That was your friend and one of your
friends was making fun of the fact that
you,
you had small hands and so you went on a
radio show or podcast and may not the
whole story about him.
Bitch.
Okay.
So far.
So I'll agree with you on that.
You're right,
it is kind of a bitch move 100 percent.
So I'll agree with you.
It doesn't really happen even so I could
get where you could say it's kind of a
bitch move.
Like you should be above this,
but I get what I enjoy about it is if
then everybody else like the like 95
percent of the mainstream media's
reaction is how could you attack a
woman's looks like how you dummies that.
Maybe you'll think next time about.
I just.
I hate the thing that Mika feels
entitled to make a small Dick joke and
then feels entitled the next day to play
though.
Are you insulting a woman's looks like
it's actually worse,
right?
If he was telling the truth because what
she's saying,
he has no control over his.
No control over her head with the of his
hands and he was
born with,
but she does have control over whether
or not she's so vain.
She lets a doctors stick a tube down her
throat and cut her half alive body and
stitch it tighter to give the illusion
of youth.
Now.
I don't think that really happened.
At least that's what a lot of it didn't
really happen,
but if it did happen and he was talking
about that after she was talking shit,
then it makes sense.
What doesn't make sense?
It's not true.
Yeah,
so I get,
I guess what I.
I do agree with you the point you made,
so I will walk back that a little bit.
You're right.
It's kind of a shitty move,
but there's just something I did like
the fact that he's willing to do that.
Someone's like fighting back against the
PC authoritarianism,
which I do see as a really big fucking
problem.
I don't see this as like a little
problem that's annoying.
Like I think it's a really big problem
and I don't care about the dignity of
the president.
I liked that being undermined as much as
possible.
I,
I don't think the whole idea that
there's dignity to this bullshit job
that shouldn't even exist.
I hate.
So I liked that being.
I like that aspect of trump do.
What do you.
What'd you think about when board Dang
got shit?
Because they asked him at the airport.
Just one of them tmz things.
You walk through the airport,
they go,
if you had to cook for Kim Jong Un and
Donald Trump,
what would you serve?
It goes hemlock and they lease.
That's a fucking bordain throw away.
Funny punchline.
That's just good chef humor right there.
God Damn Dude.
I was looking at all the comments and so
many of them were using Hashtag Potus to
talk about potus that way and to talk
mean they were talking about like,
he's the king,
like these sheep.
But they also switched sides.
It's like the Obama people in the trump.
People are so happy to just,
just literally one day.
Oh,
you take that position and I'll take
this position now.
No problem.
No,
no feeling of like,
oh,
this is a little bit weird.
I was literally three days ago lecturing
people about how he's our president and
now I'm like not my president.
Like you don't feel any,
any,
you know.
And,
and there's this thing that I go,
you know,
I remember you said this and I've quoted
this many times on my show.
Part of the problem,
my podcast,
they're a plug in a problem.
I would have a part of the problem,
but no more alliteration.
But I don't know if you were quoting
someone or this was years originally,
but you were describing the,
uh,
the occupy Wall Street movement and you
use the white blood cells as the way to
describe them.
You might,
might've been quoting someone else when
you said it,
but,
or maybe it was years originally,
but I remember hearing you say this,
I think it was mine when I was saying is
it's obviously there's a disease and
they don't know exactly what it is,
but the white blood cells are moving in
and they're surrounding this infection
that's trying to figure out what it is.
I thought it was like such a perfect
analogy and it applies to occupy Wall
Street.
It also applied to like the tea party
movement in some other way.
And you're right,
the point of being like,
look,
a white blood cell does not understand
the complexity of a virus.
It doesn't have the cure for a virus.
It doesn't have like that.
But it knows corruption rush.
Like that's the thing.
It's like corrupt and rush.
And I think that a lot of the trump
thing is that too.
It's like white blood cells and they
know that this pc authoritarian thing
that trump fights,
that they know that's the virus and this
is to them the most anti audit report.
He has half fake people.
You know,
I did that to me today and I posted it
on instagram.
I'm very happy with the results.
You're doing way better than trump's.
Way better than that motherfucker.
I don't have any fake people on twitter
because first of all,
I'm not the president.
I think when you're the president,
you automatically get like a shit ton of
fake people.
Billionaire gop,
patron behind trump's social media bot
army.
Yeah.
Of course he has a media bought.
Of course.
Why would he not use that?
I mean,
it's just like to him that's like a
tool,
like what?
It's like when the Samurai's refuse to
adopt gun pile gunfire,
they refuse to adopt firearms.
That fuck that shit.
We're using bows and arrows and swords
like men and they got gone down.
That was the end of the Japanese empire
as we knew it at the time.
They just aged version of what Kodak
did.
Oh,
right,
right.
Kodak was when digital came out,
they were like,
Eh,
we don't really like digital will be the
film guys.
Fuck you guys go with digital and then
after awhile they tried.
They'll put out to digital cameras,
but then this cameras were on phones.
Bitch,
you missed the whole thing.
You were an industry leader.
Yeah,
you went way behind the curve,
but you're the number one typewriter
distributor now.
That's all it means.
If you are running for President Dave
Smith and you don't use a Bot army,
I'll be very disappointed in you.
I'd be like,
how can I give you my support if you're
not even willing to use a bot army when
we.
We're talking about Smith Twenty four
now,
20,
24.
I think bots are like old technology.
To your point.
You're right.
I'm sorry dude.
I'm not going to get elected with that
crap.
How short sighted of me I go,
dude,
that's totally.
That's 2020 things.
That's bullshit thinking.
Yeah.
The new stuff is all you get to figure
out how to hack into neural implants.
That's right.
I'm also.
A lot of my campaign is going to be
running against the previous four years
of the Kanye West Administration and
everything that they did wrong and be
like,
look,
trump didn't solve the problem.
Kanye didn't solve the problem.
Now let's take a nice libertarian
position.
Will be Kanyi will have established
colony in Africa and uh,
he will have read designed Calabasas in
Africa and they'll all be just driving
around and bentleys and shit and duck in
Lyons.
It's like,
it really is though.
Like it's,
it's almost like seems anything seems
plausible show will live into reality,
but it is a thing that it is like a,
like Andrew Breitbart said,
this is what I've realized over the last
year is that a politics is downstream
from culture.
Yeah.
That was the truth.
I completely missed this.
Uh,
uh,
maybe not completely,
but I definitely underplayed how
important the culture is and how that
really dictates.
It's not,
it's not.
It's not like,
Oh,
if you went to like,
like a,
you know,
central Africa tomorrow and went,
don't worry,
I changed the minimum wage law.
Like,
things will be okay.
It's like,
it's like there,
there's a cultural element that you have
to account for also,
and the Donald trump thing.
It's just kind of like,
in a way,
what's so interesting to me is it's
like,
okay,
so like trump's a buffoon and he's a
cartoon.
I mean literally a cartoon like he's got
is the color of his skin,
the color of his hair.
Like you watch CNN,
the fitting suits,
overweight body like crazy hair.
You're watching the news and then a
cartoon character comes on,
but in this weird way he's had this
ability to like hold up a mirror.
The rest of American society is also a
billionaire,
so he's an undeniably a winner and as
far as we decide,
hard to argue.
Then on top of that,
he's unapologetic and that's something
we all admire because we all wish we
could do that because we can't.
And that's something that pisses off the
left.
Yeah,
I like that.
That I think is right at the heart of
why they hate trump,
which is something I'm fascinated by and
I think it is.
I really think being an unapologetic
white man,
[inaudible] rubs the left wrong.
Like,
look,
you can be a white man and you can be an
ally,
but you gotta be you gotTa.
Be Down here,
you know you can't be like up here.
You can't be like,
Hey,
I have an opinion and this is how I
feel.
You got to be down here.
Like I have an opinion and I know my
opinion's been overrepresented on his
Jamie kill scenes taken enough heat.
You don't have to go after him again on
this podcast like you just did.
I saw what he did.
Will welcome Jamie back.
I will do.
I will come back and he did some silly
things.
Got a little carried away.
Exactly.
People make bad decisions.
He got a.
He got influenced by a silly ideology
and you know,
and it came out.
But then he did some great work for
those people.
Like there was a fucking speech that he
did in front of this giant thing in
Brooklyn.
I forget what it was about,
but he was doing this,
a speech about about Donald Trump and
about black lives matter and it was rick
really well worded stuff,
whether you agree with it or not.
Like he did good work inside that,
that little sort of paradigm.
I met Jamie Kilstein when I was like a
brand new comedian,
like just starting standup comedy and he
was,
you know,
to me like doing things that were really
cool,
like he was on the road with Stan hope
and like to me that was like,
oh,
you're like,
you made it,
like that's amazing.
Like you're doing the thing that we all
want to do.
And he was just super kind and helpful
to me.
I was a young comment and so I always
just have like a,
as a person,
I like Jamie and all the things I don't
like about Jamie where we like seeing
him on your show or seeing something he
tweeted or something like that.
So it's like as a person I always liked
him and then the public persona,
like he knows a few people.
Apologies,
but I'd be happy to.
Yeah,
I mean I think we're all vulnerable to a
certain extent and we're vulnerable to
like if you tap into a vein and you have
success with a certain way of behaving
and thinking and you know,
you put blinders on because this is
benefiting you.
I mean we see that financially with
people were talking about before you see
that culturally,
socially,
and I think Jamie tapped into like the
social vein of success in this very
extreme ideology,
this extreme feminist male feminist ally
ideology,
the denial of the differences between
the men,
the women in.
And it's like he's a cliche and a lot of
ways,
right?
Because he's a small guy and you know,
he's very slight and you always see a
small guy who a Vegan and a feminist.
You're like,
oh,
it's just,
he's one of those guys.
You know what I mean?
It's like you fall into these weird sort
of predetermined patterns of behavior,
these categories and he just was a black
belt at that,
you know,
but also banging chicks.
It turns out you can't,
you can't be in that world.
And also like plus eight.
As it turns out,
so crazy me.
Isn't that the ultimate feminist?
He loves women,
top to bottom.
I don't know what the actual issue that
they had with them.
I don't really know either,
but I will say this,
okay.
That he hangs out in that social justice
warrior crowd that he was hanging out
with.
They will throw out the rape word for
everything.
You can look at someone the wrong way
and they'll call that rape and what they
accused Jamie have was inappropriate and
manipulative behavior toward women.
I mean literally means trying to get
posted.
Like it's not even.
You're not even exaggerating if you go
to them to this in this social justice
warrior world,
if you were to be like,
hey,
why don't we like get outta here and go
back to my place and you're like,
no,
we can't go.
Come on,
let's go.
She said no,
and then you said,
come on.
That is.
That is inappropriate manipulative
behavior.
Skeptics conference and a man in an
elevator asked a woman if she wanted to
come to his room and have some coffee
and she did a whole speech the next day
about how men should not,
if they're with a woman alone and it's
late at night,
do not ask them to coffee because you're
going to imply that this woman is in
danger and make her feel uncomfortable
and all this crazy shit like,
oh,
so a guy was trying to fuck you.
Doesn't that happen all the time like
you're,
you're making a speech about this t
trying to control the behavior of men to
the point where they're not mad anymore,
is shaped them and formed them into some
weird sort of pc version of you would
like this.
No biological difference between the men
and the women.
Men being only allies and like what?
It's so strange.
The whole thing is so weird and like,
you know,
it's always these people who seem to be
so resentful and angry at the male
female relationship and interplay and
like ankle and God wanted to fuck you is
so horrible.
Coincidentally.
Almost always not attractive.
It's you don't see a lot of tens walking
around going like,
oh,
it's so unfair.
There's a few that snuck in there,
but you don't see a ton of them like
publicans.
Well,
here's,
here's the thing is like the sheriffs
Clark's that's right.
And they put them right up front.
We put them right up front,
like see,
look at her tits,
giant tits and a little waist.
She's a fucking feminist.
Well the truth is if you want to get
into a conversation,
a real honest conversation about
privilege,
right?
And who has privileged and who doesn't
have privilege.
I mean hot chick privilege,
it's pretty shit is pretty strong.
I mean,
but you know,
hot chicks walk around in a different
world than regular women and men do.
I mean it's just a different thing and
that's part of the nature of.
But you know,
whatever.
I mean that's like who human beings are,
but it's like I,
you don't hear her complaining about it
as much because she's winning at this,
at this exchange.
You know,
women have to sort of keep their mouth
shut about that shit.
Have to like kind of wanting to get away
with it.
We're working on our end over here.
You know,
I,
I saw this a tweet this woman put out
that said a pro tip if you,
uh,
don't ever date a man who doesn't
identify as a feminist.
And I was like,
that is so crazy.
That's such a crazy thing to say.
Like,
first of all,
pro tip is one of the Douchey is things
you could ever say and not say something
funny.
If you say pro tip,
what you say after that,
better be proposed truss.
He's Jesus Christ.
See pro tip and you're serious.
I just,
you're a fucking condescending,
angry person from the jump.
And it's very rarely a very successful
pro who's giving me this protest.
Second of all,
the idea of every man that you date
should be a feminist.
Well,
every man date shouldn't be a person who
discriminates.
I agree with that.
They should be openminded tissue,
be egalitarian,
but the idea that they have to subscribe
to a feminist ideology that this can't
just be fair and honest and curious and
have real conversations with you.
Open and objective.
That's not good enough.
Now they have to identify with this
ideology that the only way you could
ever have equality,
true equality within the sexes of the
man,
identifies as being a feminist.
Like that's what feminism is.
Feminism is not supportive.
Women know feminism is total uniformity
and there's no discrimination
whatsoever.
And until that happens,
you have to be a feminist.
Yeah.
And feminism to me is like,
like modern day feminism at least.
It's just like a hate group.
I just don't know how else to describe
them.
They're just a hate group.
It's like if you take them at their
word,
you know,
the way you,
you could take any hate group at their
word,
you know,
and they'd be like,
Oh,
you know,
we're not a hate group.
We just care about white people,
white people's rights and the white
children,
Blah Blah.
And then you're Kinda like,
oh,
okay,
well let me come to a meeting and then
by like that meet and you're like,
man,
they sure do seem to hate black people
at this meeting.
We're not hate group.
We just think that all straight white
men are trash until proven otherwise.
Exactly.
And if you want to be there and you're
of that group,
you better first,
uh,
you know,
like confessed to your original sin for
being and be guilty the whole time and
be constantly,
you know,
kind of repenting and then you can be
there.
But even with them,
there's a giant spectrum,
right?
There's a lot of women that are just
what they don't want is some fucking
creepy boss to talk,
you know,
crazy,
creepy sexual shit to them.
And they have to absorb it because they
want to move up the corporate ladder and
they're discriminated sexually in the
office space.
They're discriminated when it comes to,
uh,
you know,
promotions and raises and you know,
the position in the company that's.
Yeah,
sure.
that's fucking gross.
If I don't want that to be a woman
working in an office filled with fucking
men,
think about trying to have sex with you
all the time.
Absolutely,
absolutely.
And there are certain struggles that
like guys are unaware of the or maybe
not unaware completely because you like
you're bringing it up right now,
but we don't experience certainly like
you don't know what it's like to walk
around life as like a tiny hot chick
that men just constantly want to fuck.
I mean that's,
I'm sure that comes from being catcalled
you know when they first came out with
that video that went viral of the chip
being catcalled around New York City.
My first reaction was I thought it was
very interesting and I said,
because you go,
if you're a guy who doesn't cat call
checks,
which is like the category I fall into.
That's just not my style of getting
laid.
I've never thought of just be like,
let me get that ass Motha like as you
walked by me.
But that did roll off the tongue kind of
naturally.
So maybe I should try try that.
Maybe that'll get me a little more and
made me get it nervous.
So it's interesting to see that because
you're like,
oh,
I don't do that.
So as a guy who doesn't do that,
I'm the only category of people who are
unaware of it.
Me Know how they made that video.
I found out later.
Yeah,
I did find out later,
please tell everybody like hours and
hours of footage.
They basically went all day long and
disproportionately took footage of black
neighborhoods.
They went around in circles in this
black neighborhood in Harlem and in
Times Square in these two areas.
And they basically got a lot of black
guys,
uh,
talking,
you know,
uh,
to uh,
a very attractive,
very attractive.
But yes,
the crime of the century,
but at least it's like,
look,
I do think there's something to be said
for like,
oh,
okay,
look,
I don't know what the experience of
getting cat called is.
This might be pissing off some women.
So okay,
like,
let's,
let's look at that.
But then there's also lots of struggles
of men that women don't necessarily know
about.
And the problem with feminists is that
in modern feminist is that they're not
going like,
hey,
we both have struggled here,
let's have a conversation.
We're not like we're humanists were
people lists,
let's have a cup.
They're like,
were feminists were on this team and
we're going to talk about our struggles
and lecture you about it and you can
never discuss the opposite.
The truth and the past gets so perverted
like they,
they'd speak.
The past was all just oppressive gender
roles toward women.
It's like A.
Actually in reality,
there were oppressive gender roles for
everybody in the past.
And it's very debatable who they were
more oppressive for.
Like in my grandmothers and grandfathers
day,
oppressive gender roles landed my
grandfather in combat fighting and war
like it.
It wasn't that,
you know,
it wasn't like,
oh,
the men didn't have any struggles that
the women didn't know about.
Like again,
we technologically advanced,
we don't need those gender roles,
which we did need for lots of years
before technology.
There's no way for humans to survive.
I mean,
go go for a hundred years ago and say
let's abolish gender roles.
It's like,
what's it like?
You're going to have kids until you
know,
three of them died from polio.
I mean that's what that was the point of
the Google memo.
There's still things that people
gravitate towards that or male with more
frequency than they do with are female
and then you have these aberrations,
these women that want to be mma fighters
and these men that want to be florists
and you have all these,
all the different people in between and
to try to get equality and that was like
one of the things that was so
frustrating about people is that we're
not saying that women shouldn't be
equal.
They can't be equal.
We're saying they're not equal.
They're not equally represented in this
particular field.
This particular discipline.
Now let's explore why.
Sure.
Things that I thought was so crazy about
the google memo was that the guy had
like a page and a half of like dedicated
to what would be a way to get women more
interested in tech and he had all these
citations for all these different
studies that he was quoting.
When they reprinted it and several
sources,
they remove the citations and they,
you know,
they would put like these,
they take these quotes out of context
and highlight them and make them larger
and it's like,
which I find strange to be like,
oh yeah,
I read part of that thing and it seems
fairly reasonable to me.
And I saw it very misrepresented in the
way people were talking about it on the
news.
Um,
and like it's just this weird thing
where you're like,
okay,
look,
if you do like,
I like,
equality is what exactly do we even mean
by that?
It's like,
yeah,
the equality under the law or something
like that.
Like,
okay,
sure.
But like,
no,
like men and women are different.
Men are different.
Like you and I are different,
you know,
way more about politics than I do.
And you know way more about hunting elk
and shit like that.
Well that's always going to be the case.
It's not an equal thing because we're
not mathematics.
I've got a huge gap to close on your El
content knowledge.
I got to get at it.
I tried to get out of time.
That's a weird one that I'm probably
shouldn't have done.
Dipped my toes into.
So absorbed.
No,
but you're absolutely right.
In the case with all of it is like
snowflakes I've been working on
completely different and have different
and the idea that equality,
I mean you'll never have that have any
true science and then the thing with
like,
okay,
with women it seems like feminist
basically like they almost well bashing
men and bashing the traditional kind of
masculine gender role.
They also seem to embrace it and want
that for women.
So like if men are,
they really want it for transgender
people,
that's where it gets super slippery
because the left wants really classic
feminine,
like Transgender People.
When Bruce Jenner became Caitlyn Jenner,
he's painting his toes and wearing high
heels and short skirts and it gets a tit
job,
gets his jaw sod down.
Like,
you can't just be a woman.
Got to be looking woman.
You got to be a woman with a fucking
facial surgery.
You've got to be beautiful.
And we go,
yes,
you,
you're amazing.
You go,
that's right.
If a girl embraces those classic gender
roles,
like wearing high heels and short skirts
and her tits are pushed together and
like,
Oh God,
you're falling into this classic gender
trap.
That's right.
Or,
or if a woman said,
oh,
I want to be a housewife and like raise
my kids and live a traditional
lifestyle,
or if I'm going to move for my husband
or something like that,
a married man and you say that,
well for you go girl.
And you see the same thing happen where
they literally the same thing.
They'll hate if a man does the law.
So if you had read,
uh,
you know,
a feminist article about mma seven years
ago,
it would have been all about toxic
masculinity and male aggression and all
this stuff.
But as soon as Ronda Rousey was doing
it,
it's like,
that's our girl,
let's go do it.
If dirty comedy,
offensive comedy,
they're like,
no,
fuck that,
that's your mail.
But,
but as soon as amy Schumer is doing it,
it's like,
let's go.
Like they love for a woman to do all the
things that they always said they hate.
And the crazy thing is like they'll,
they'll say these things where it's
like,
you know,
like women,
um,
whatever it is,
women are uh,
you know,
whatever percentage,
like 51 percent of the population and
they're only like 10 percent of Congress
or something.
I'm just making these numbers up.
Something like in that ballpark.
And there'll be
like,
well this is a problem.
And you're like,
well,
wait a minute.
I mean I'm all for freedom so if there's
any barrier in someone's way,
get that out of there.
But if people are free and like men
choose to go be politicians and women
more choose to go into like,
you know,
like nursing and like these other light
kind of like maternalistic fields that
women go into a lot and you're like,
okay.
So like,
are you sure?
The answer is just that they should be
more like men.
Like maybe this is like saying something
better about women,
like men are going on or like going into
ruling over other people and women are
going into like a nurturing field.
Like maybe the fact that women
prioritize family over money is not a
bad thing that needs to be reorganized.
Great thing.
There's gonna be some women that choose
to pursue a career at the very highest
levels of capitalism and there's gonna
be some that have zero interest in doing
that.
And that's the same with men as well.
It's just we can't deny the patterns
that we see.
Well we should figure out is like are
there barriers if there's bears unjust
barriers to keep women from things.
And I'm sure there are those things we
should concentrate on.
Yes.
But concentrating on leveling the number
of people in Congress and that's
essentially sexual affirmative action.
You want to get more women in those
positions because you think they have.
How many women do you have running?
That's when you get to Hillary Clinton.
I mean like we want a woman to be
president.
Okay.
How about a lying old lady who faints a
lot?
Is that one?
Okay?
You'd be like,
no.
Well that's ridiculous.
Well that's what you got when you wanted
to get only women.
You got that one?
Okay,
so what the fuck do you want to do now?
Because what you're doing is you can't
just decide that you only want,
you know,
you want 50 percent men,
50 percent women in all.
What about coal mining?
You want to have 50 percent of women who
die had fucking coal mining accidents.
You know the disproportionate number of
men who die on the job.
It's,
it's staggering.
But that's my point with the feminist
thing where it's kind of this,
this is why it's,
there'll be like,
well,
we're just for equality.
It's like,
okay,
well if you're just for equality,
how come I never hear about how the
death,
the workplace death rate is like
disproportionately men.
I don't mean disproportionately,
a little bit.
It's like over 90 percent.
Then about prison sentencing differences
though.
These are major,
major things,
but people die or get thrown in a cage,
but we,
you know,
that doesn't come up at all because it's
like if it's black men they look,
well that's right then and only then
okay,
because,
but then of course it's also gotta be
like the white racism white male and
that's linked with the fee.
The woman's struggle.
Like the black struggle,
like they've kind of piggybacked onto
that.
They should take it back on to Lbgtq w.
well they kind of are.
I mean I hear that all the time.
I actually,
I heard one person on Msnbc and they
were like,
we just care about the rights of,
of women and minorities and lgbt people
and immigrants and something else.
And I was like,
just say not white men.
Can I just save you some time?
Say Not Straight CIS white men.
We don't everyone else your name in them
all in groups.
So just say it like,
just cut to the chase just for time.
And they're doing it to align
themselves.
They're doing it to align themselves
with other people that are going to have
their back and agree with them when they
go to war with it that way because the
truth behind them,
like what you said before,
that where you go,
if there's any barriers,
let's remove that.
But then you get to a certain point
where you're just like,
if we're being honest,
there are no real barriers.
There are no real barriers to,
to and,
and,
and if there are,
let's go after them.
But just on the big picture,
like talking about things,
if you're like a woman who really wants
to do something in 2017 in a first world
country like the United States of
America,
I don't see.
I mean there are laws against paying,
uh,
a woman less than a man at the same job.
There are all these rules that are lots
of people who will like,
like actually bend over backwards
[inaudible].
They're really looking to have like a,
a,
you know,
diversity.
Like corporations really love diversity.
Everyone in show business knows that's
true.
So it's like,
okay,
I don't see a real barrier.
But then when you do,
when they can't find one,
they'll,
they'll kind of create this barrier that
you can't say.
So if we give people a bunch of freedom
and then women make certain choices in
men,
make certain choices in this leads to,
on average men making 23 percent more
than women.
Then they go,
well,
and I go,
there's no barrier.
It's just women making choices.
They go,
well,
well there's this,
this barrier called Patriarchy that's
somehow,
you know,
and we've got to like,
it's because these women have been
socialized into thinking that they're.
So then they'll find this thing that you
can't prove or disprove.
You can't test it.
Just kind of like.
But we live in a rape culture,
right?
It's like fighting terrorism,
the war on terror.
It's the same shit.
It's like,
well,
if it's just an idea,
I guess we're always fighting that idea.
And until women assume the power
position and there's a disproportion of
number of women in Congress and this
proportionate number of women who are
police officers and women who are
judges,
women,
her lawyers and when they were in all
positions of power,
if men feel the heavy boot of the
oppressive woman until then until fuck
up.
And it's so.
It's all so ridiculous.
It's just all so silly.
It's like what?
What area of life is there where things
are proportionately representative while
black people in basketball?
No,
not unproportionate.
I'm saying proportionately.
So they don't make up 13 percent of
basketball.
Yeah.
Like they make,
they make up.
I mean it's like where,
where do you find racist?
We need to even that out.
Yes,
absolutely.
More white people and Asians and whites
and down a little bit.
Make it easier to follow.
Yeah.
More black people in hockey.
That's a mess.
But it's all just so it's all so fucking
like we should celebrate the differences
we have and just don't be.
Don't be racist.
That's it.
Now let's say don't be sexist,
don't be racist,
but you don't get Brownie points just
because you're a chick you don't know
and you shouldn't,
you shouldn't get into this thing where
it's like,
and I know it's like I've heard like
people particularly like a left wing
leading feminists or like female comics
who are feminists,
who I know several of them out without
calling out by name,
but uh,
but I've,
I've heard and they'll,
they'll get very.
And one of them said to me once they go,
you know,
Dave,
you're whole thing is just that you hate
women.
Oh,
like,
but it's like hate women.
Like what do you saw women say that to
Brian and you?
Nobody said it was hilarious.
He goes,
you know what?
I've heard that before.
And every woman that said that I hated
it was a great response because it was a
stupid argument.
It is.
She was just like saying like a blanket
statement.
You hate women.
No,
no you.
But I just go.
I challenged a lot of people on,
on the left who,
who talk about race or sexism in these
things.
I just challenge you to to just
entertain the possibility for like one
second,
entertain the possibility that you're
not right about all of this stuff and
that the correct position is to treat
everybody equal.
Now I know that sounds really,
really wild and out there,
and I'm not taking into account my white
privilege and the history,
but just entertain for one second the
possibility that the correct answer is
to treat everybody equal and not judge
them based on their race.
And then you,
if you entertain that for one second,
you'll start realizing like,
oh,
holy shit,
if that's true,
I'm really the one being the biggest
here.
I've seen this.
So like,
uh,
um,
if you know the roast battle shows at
the comedy store here,
it goes up and they started doing them
in New York too.
Now they're really popular.
There are like these group of female
comics that will come out and I don't
even begrudge them for this,
but they'll come out and just hardcore
like root for the female comic like
there they'll post about like just want
to see more women succeed at roast
battle coming out tonight to cheer on my
girl,
Blah Blah,
and there'll be this dynamic where like
their first two jokes,
you know,
they'll just get this like it's just
like,
you know,
female voices from the corner where the
comics hang like super,
super loud for,
for the chick comic and like whatever.
I don't begrudge them anything like,
fine,
come do that.
But it's just like those same people who
will be like,
you're like against women.
Like I would never in a million years go
out to a show and be like,
I'm just rooting for the men today.
Like I don't think this way.
I'm not like on team man,
but you are on team women.
Like it's just,
it just seems to me that there's a lot
of that going on.
You know what I mean?
That shit where it's like you kind of
project this thing that you see racism
everywhere or you see sexism everywhere,
but all I really see is you fucking
lecturing people based on race.
In their mind they're allowed to do it
the same way Cain Velasquez allowed to
have brown pride and his chest.
Yeah.
Kinda the same thing.
Like you're,
you're disenfranchised or marginalized,
so you're allowed to stay.
Even if you're not you playing that
victim card as a woman and you're
allowed to say,
I'm here to support my girl.
Like I was talking about this on stage
of the day.
I saw a bumper sticker on a car and said
girls kick ass.
And I was like,
some of them,
yeah,
some of them are lazy slobs equity.
Going to align yourself with 150 million
women just in this country alone.
That's ridiculous.
He was saying if a guy had a bumper
sticker,
it said boys kick ass.
He'd be like,
follow that guy and find out where he's
been fucking these kids because first of
all,
you'd never say boys,
boys kick ass.
You put that into your bumper.
Sit.
What the fuck are you?
You'd pull them over.
Let me see your license.
Where do you live,
man?
What do you do for a living?
What's that bumper sticker about?
What the fuck do you mean by that?
Yes,
and I don't need like I almost feel like
an asshole sometimes where I preface
everything with a disclaimer like,
and I'm not saying this and I'm not,
but I just want it to be clear
that I'm not saying there aren't
exceptions to the rule,
but it's also kind of strange to me that
like if you want to celebrate women,
why are you celebrating such a masculine
quality?
Like it's kind of like,
it's like,
look,
there are white players who are great
basketball players,
right?
There are the Levitsky was an amazing
basketball player,
but if I just wrote some like white
people kick ass at basketball,
it's like,
well actually that movie tone in
general,
women don't kick ass in general.
Generally speaking,
that's a male thing to do.
So I'm not saying there's not exceptions
to that,
but you're like,
you're writing white people kick ass in
basketball.
It's kind of misleading,
right?
Well,
there's that thing that's coming out,
that movie with Steve Carell where he
plays a,
that man who had a basketball tennis
match against Billie Jean King and he
was like barely ranked,
who's terrible tennis player and he fuck
Billie Jean King up and it was and he
was like,
sort of mocking her the whole way and it
was like a real hallmark,
right?
I don't know about that.
He just played professional tennis
player,
but he wasn't the best and Billie Jean
King was the best woman in the world and
they played and the Steve Carell
character beater is now was not what
happened.
I believe that's what happened.
I'm,
I'm getting them conflated with Renee
Richards,
the guy who used to be a man and then
became a transgender woman and starts
stomping everybody in tennis is a
terrible as a man.
And then it became a woman who was one
of the best of the world,
but there's no biological difference.
Even without a penis,
you still stomping on it again is like
so funny because once you.
It's so funny,
like how much this stuff starts
undermining their own arguments.
Billy Jean King One.
Okay.
I get that wrong.
So I got wrong.
The Renee Richard One.
Yeah,
that's what I could fuse.
So,
um,
what was the.
And he was like particularly Gross,
right?
And Steve Carell plays them really well
and movie same Steve Corral who played
that crazy guy in that wrestling.
He did a really great job with a story.
What a crazy story that espn 30 for 30
on the side too.
Good man.
You know,
not a good in the sense that the stories
are just such a compelling unbelievable
story.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
So when Steve Carell played that
character and then you watch the video
video,
the actual character that like,
whoa,
like he just nailed that guy.
Steve Curls.
Incredible talent.
He's such a good fucking act to be that
funny of a comedian.
And that good of a dramatic actor
spoken.
Pretty incredible.
I guess it's comedy though,
is always kind of his acting,
you know,
is like that's his strength and comedy.
Like he owned that character,
you know.
Well Roger Federer said that recently.
He got in trouble,
right?
That the best women.
No,
it wasn't,
it wasn't the older guy.
Fuck John McEnroe mock McEnroe said
that,
and they let us,
they let him into it.
He said he,
he started by saying Serena was the best
female player and then they go,
why female?
Oh,
well.
And he was like,
well,
what do you mean I,
because I think she's the best female
player goes,
well,
why female?
Why not say male egos?
Because the men are way better.
He was literally just answering the
question,
started off giving this woman in
extraordinary compliment.
That was the story I remember.
Didn't serina play against an unranked
male player?
She did.
They used to play when they were
younger.
I think she,
she played against some guy that was the
story and the guy kicked her ass and
everybody was like,
what?
It just seems to me to be this thing
where I kind of look at,
obviously we're talking in
generalizations here and there are
exceptions like,
you know what I'm saying?
Like there are like,
you know,
uh,
a Rhonda Rousey could beat the shit out
of me as an example,
but it's a bad example,
but I'm not a fighter.
No,
but I'm just making the point that like
if you have this stereotype that men are
stronger than women or something like
that.
There are exceptions to the rule if you
get.
And there are,
there are.
I still use Ronda Rousey even though
she's not championing more,
she's just still got that ring to it.
Um,
but I'm saying there are exceptions to
the rule.
There are exceptions and,
and to treat someone based on a group
dynamic is,
is ignorant like to.
But if you're going to like.
I do think there are differences between
men and women generally speaking and if
you believe that it's like if we're
going to celebrate women,
I just think it's kind of odd that we
have to celebrate the most masculine
achievements of women.
It's like celebrating them kicking ass.
There are these things that I feel like
women are superior to men in that I'm
very impressed by them.
Like I,
I just think women.
Hold on,
let me stop you because you think that
running a corporation is masculine,
like do you think that being involved in
any creative endeavor is masculine?
I think that being involved in anything
in tech is masculine.
Know what they're talking about.
Well,
I was more responding to the women kick
ass.
That's just stupid bumper sticker.
No,
you're right.
It is really a group thing is.
I think my issue with it was if,
if you see things like um,
well I just did,
but the element I'm responding to is
that kick ass to me it just seems to be
kind of like a masculine thing.
I'm describing that as masculine.
Yeah.
It was just one silly stupid bumper.
Like to say those things,
right?
Yes.
But I just think there's something about
it.
It seems to me like the nurturing
element of femininity is almost like
denigrated and the ass kissy asked kicky
element is like his praise where it's
like if I'm talking kicking ass and
nurture and I'm talking men,
verse women in general,
just broad speaking like I tend to think
of one being male and one being a
female,
right?
To wrap this all up and bring it all
day.
I think we'd all be better off male
women,
White,
black,
Asian,
whatever.
If we just reasonable nice people,
you know,
and that's the real problem is that we
lock off as we've been discussing all,
all day into these camps and we are on
camp white male and we are on camp
blackmail or camp gay or transgender or
camp woman and we just locked into these
ideologies and we hate anybody else
different and we have these divisive
things that we say like all white men
are trash unless proven otherwise,
you know,
like that kind of crazy shit.
Like you're,
you're setting it up.
So the guys like,
sorry,
sorry.
Like you come in,
sorry,
do it.
I didn't do it.
Instead of just being a reasonable
normal person,
but there's not enough reasonable,
normal people,
so women are constantly dealing with
assholes,
so they develop these kinds of behavior
patterns of behavior.
They think about men as being these
intrusive,
shitty people just want to get in your
pants and really don't care about you
and they're manipulative and they just
want to fuck you.
Which when do you say it,
I mean that it's somewhat true to
describe and then men think of women as
being manipulative too.
Always looking for the bigger,
better deal.
You know where they're going to fuck
their personal trainer while you're at
work and we think about getting divorced
and losing all your money because you
were too stupid.
You didn't sign a prenuptial agreement.
She has some kick ass attorney and then
you're fucked and we all know guys who
have experienced that before too,
that she lies about you beating the kids
and then she gets full custody.
That's all real,
but then the good stuff is all real.
To know what I mean.
It's real and that does happen,
but then there's also like the chick who
just like gives a guy like,
you know,
like the security and competence.
He never had to go be great.
There's the guy who does support his
chick through like her endeavors and
like,
you know,
it's like,
it's like you got it,
you know,
it's like,
it's like that shouldn't in the
hurricane in Houston.
Kind of put some perspective on that for
me where it's like,
you know,
it's like you see just like all these
people,
it's like Antifa versus Nazis as the
state of the country and then you see
like this,
this horrible hurricane happened and
just the acts of kindness after,
when you see these people,
like,
like young guys,
like these group of like 20 year olds
maybe they were,
I saw took.
They're like,
they're like a motor boats down to
Houston and are pulling old people out
of their homes and you're like,
God damn it,
motherfucker.
Like that's our country too,
you know?
And like,
like it,
it's all like the Nazis are our country
too.
But that guys,
our country,
that is also as people responding to a
very real problem,
we're really unites people.
They feel like they have to help each
other because it's a weird problem.
Most of the time we're separated from
each other by buildings and cars and
there's this weird alienation we have
with one another.
It's one of the reasons why places of
high density you get much more liberal
ideologies or liberal in terms of
accepting,
I should say,
not necessarily conservative,
but there's a lot of that to a
democratic versus conservative or left
wing versus conservative.
But these big population culture is
people interact with each other more.
You know,
you don't get the same kind of racism,
you know,
you get less and it's less accepted I
think in like maybe say New York City
and probably anywhere because in New
York City,
especially in Manhattan,
everybody's got to interact.
Not saying you don't encounter it.
You certainly do sides.
White racism,
black racism.
You're gonna encounter racism,
pizza flaw in human nature.
That's the same thing that we're talking
about with the assholes of the Tiki
torches.
It's a flaw.
Everyone likes to feel like they're the
best and my team is the best at my local
bar is the best and my aunt makes the
best chili towns and it's like,
no,
your aunt does not make the world's Best
Chili.
That's fucking ridiculous.
It's,
it's,
you know,
the odds are very against it.
Let's just say it's a very,
very low chance to prove it,
but people.
Right.
But people want to feel that way and so
there will always be these certain kinds
of in group preference things where
there's.
But like you said,
there are.
I do think like growing up in New York
City,
you also just see,
and this is the beautiful thing that we
fucking lost in America.
That sucks,
but it's like freedom does fucking bring
people together and capitalism,
even though it's become a dirty word,
like all that shit brings people
together,
man.
Like I'm a Jew and I can go in a New
York City Street and put my hand out and
like a Muslim guy comes and picks me up
and drops me off at home and just use
uber.
Do you wasting your time with all that?
I mean,
to be honest,
I really do use Uber,
but Uber,
I uh,
I was doing lyft and now I just switched
over to uber.
Do you feel bad that Uber was getting
locked out of London?
Like I'm going to step up and help out
uber?
I don't know about that.
I knew they're locked out of Austin.
I think Austin,
Austin,
Texas,
they left there.
I think they're locked out of London
now.
I think the marriage you said that the
way they operate socks fuck off.
Well,
I do.
I love anything that undermines
government monopoly.
So I thought that was great that they
undermined that home medallion thing.
I think it's like,
I think technology that undermines the
government is the most beautiful thing
ever.
As you know,
that ways app,
uh,
they,
they have that now in New York City.
They'll tell you if there's a camera on
the next red light,
they'll tell you if there's a cop on the
highway waiting the check,
you know,
like there'll be like police ahead.
So there's literally the system where
the cops,
cops will sit there and wait for someone
to come,
you know,
speeding so they can come,
extort you for some money and understand
how that works.
The waste thing that it's just people
calling in.
So cops calling fake cars.
I did not know that,
but I know that I knew that it was other
people calling in very upset because the
police officers actually call in fake
cop on the side of the road calls.
But.
So what is that doing?
Making people drive the speed limit.
Fucks it up.
It's a car.
It's crying wolf.
So you basically just don't believe it
as much anymore.
It's interesting.
But I thought there was something really
beautiful about that server protect.
I get to know.
I mean that's the third thing.
Protect and rule and take you out.
Yeah.
But I,
I thought when they first did it,
what a beautiful thing that you're
going.
Because look,
if you,
uh,
if you tell them there's a cop ahead,
what you're going to do is make sure
you're not speeding.
I mean that's the only trick.
So essentially it's doing what you would
claim the law wants you to do.
It's just doing it in a way where the
state doesn't fucking extort,
you know,
of course.
So then they'll start going out,
we've got to fuck with that.
I did not let that work.
Yeah.
They'll eventually figure out a way
around that or we're going to get to a
point I think in our lifetimes where
it's impossible to lie.
I think that's where it's headed and I
think that's gonna solve a lot of our
issues socially,
a lot of very.
She's politically,
we're going to understand motivations
behind things in a way like maybe
motivations will seem color coded.
That is when someone's envious,
you literally see green with some new
program.
We're all running.
I think what you're sit like,
we've already started to see it and it's
like it's much,
much harder.
I think that it's much,
much harder for people to pull off
lying.
It was much harder for Hillary Clinton
to pull off then for traditional
politics in the past because they're
leaking everything online now and it's
just harder for the government or the
big corporations have the media to
convince you of this narrative.
It's getting harder and harder,
like we haven't figured out exactly how
to move it in a good direction,
but like it is.
You see the control that they have being
undermined.
The control of the mainstream media is
being undermined.
The control of certain universities.
What's already gone.
The,
the Internet has sort of eroded all the
control of mainstream media.
CNN is now called fake news a million
times a day all throughout the country.
And you look at these people constantly
calling.
The president calls it fake.
That's fucking CNN.
Oh,
that's right.
And then you say like a w when you said
it earlier in the show with Fox News had
had a monopoly on right wing news.
Well that's fucking over.
When you look at the bench,
Shapiro comes and shows.
Look at the numbers.
That thing does.
I mean it's like,
oh yeah.
Fox News as a big competitor on their,
on their hands now and all these other
guys at crowder and all these guys were
like huge and all of the.
If you look at like and Jordan who's
more,
you know,
like he calls himself a classic British
liberal and it looks at it that way,
which is like a sort of a different
definition.
It's more of a pragmatic sort of more
conservative pragmatic,
probably closest to what is called
Libertarian in the American School of
thought.
The classical liberal people in
disingenuously call him outright.
It's just so freaking ridiculous.
But this is the thing where it's like
everyone to the right of Bernie Sanders
is a Nazi.
It's like there's just these words don't
even mean anything and he just installed
so it's like people shouting in your
face and it's like Lion Hillary,
like that kind of thing.
But you take the most fucked up word you
can think of to justify the legal
position.
And then culturally you say,
oh by the way,
that word applies to everything.
It's like women are getting raped on
college campus,
so we get the law passed.
Well,
that's one of the real problems with the
guy like Donald Donald trump said,
when he boils things down to these
slogans,
then they boil things down to slogans in
return and we just have a fucking fight.
Were you throwing rocks at each other?
That was one of the amazing things about
trump and the moment is that trump comes
out,
he's like this simplistic buffoon,
and in every in the normal mind you're
like,
well,
at some point he's going to meet a a
professional who will embarrass him and
then you start to realize after a while
I was like,
oh,
there's just no professional plans.
Neither did Hillary Clinton.
They were all.
They were all completely empty.
The difference between him versus
Hillary versus what we just had with
Mitt Romney versus Obama to really
reasonable well spoken people who are
accomplished and quite intelligent,
and while the one of them believes that
nonsense,
I don't know which one.
They both believe in nonsense.
Right?
But one of them believes in like one of
those magical underwear at a
presidential debate with them.
Yeah,
he has to.
Or it goes straight to like a cabin in
hell.
You have to stay there with no satellite
TV.
I don't know what the rule is.
You only get to have your wives that we
sling back.
I hope we have this blow back this way
and I hope I don't mean I don't know
who's going to emerge between now and 20
slash 20,
but it's gonna have to be someone that's
interesting,
right?
What's going to be have to be someone
that we look at and go,
okay,
this is a viable alternative to what
we're currently dealing with and they
probably shouldn't say shit for a long
time.
They should probably just build up and
prepare and just constantly say I'm not
running.
I'm not running.
I don't know man.
I don't know if there's any bringing
this thing back together.
The United States of America.
I think we might be going our separate
ways in the future.
I just think we might be headed toward
some type of Soviet style breakup.
Like,
like where some of the countries still
exist,
but we're not all a part of the same
thing.
I just,
I look,
I look at these two trends that I see
happening,
right?
And one is that content,
and this to me is the biggest moral
issue of our time,
but the continued growth of the state,
which is just like gets like we live
under choice happens just like a
corporation,
universal growth.
They want to get bigger and stronger
every year pretty much always seems to
happen.
I mean,
and that government,
unlike,
like corporations always want
to grow,
a lot of them go out of business but
they always want to get bigger
governments,
uh,
they can force you to pay them.
So it's a lot easier for them to grow.
And this is our most advanced society.
Start as,
you know,
a constitution with a somewhat limited
government and then it grows.
And that was the big appeal of trump.
The only appeal drain the swamp.
This is what it was then.
And a lot of it was,
you know,
some of it was,
was good.
The idea of draining the swamp is good
and not fighting these wars anymore I
think is really great.
But you know,
you have this thing where we,
we live under the biggest government,
most powerful government in the history
of the world.
I mean,
there's never been a government that
spends $4,000,000,000,000
that can drone bomb anyone on the
planet.
That's,
you know,
we,
we have bases all over the world,
hundreds of different countries or at
least well over 100 and everything is
going up.
I mean every budget,
you know,
Bush spent the most effort then Obama
spent the most ever trump will outspend
Obama,
no question about it.
And all of the major major problems that
I see are our direct result of this.
Like the longest wars in American
history,
the mass incarceration rate spying on
all of our citizens record debt.
You know,
like all of these things are a result of
government being way too big and way too
out of control.
And then at the same time,
while we're like spending ourselves too
far into debt way to extended
militarily,
the culture is also completely decaying.
And we're more at war with each other
than we've ever been.
And like I said before we go from like,
you know,
a Buckley Vidal debate to trump Clinton
like this.
We've had a jerry springer culture and
now we've got a jerry springer president
to go with it and I just see this
culture breaking up.
The government getting too big.
I don't know how this all works out so
that like we're all friends again.
But I'd love for someone to maybe spoken
like a true white man.
Great privilege gave.
We got to wrap this up.
Thank you very much.
So can I plug my on,
just put a new comedy special.
So I just wanted to mention that he just
put out my,
uh,
my debut comedy special.
It's called Libertas and you can get
it@agasdigitalnetwork.com.
The album is a number one on itunes.
So yeah.
So just one of your podcasts,
plug that itunes heart of the problem.
Legion of skanks.
Also both available on itunes.
Both.
All my stuff's at gas digital network to
do this more often.
I can't wait to the other.
Absolutely.
Dave Smith.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we'll see you tomorrow.