Already nailing it,
bitches not even turned on the Joe Rogan
experience podcast,
brought to you by the flashlight.
If you go to Joe Rogan.net
and click on the link to the flashlight.
I'm trying to do this and I'm trying to
tweet at the same time.
This is unprofessional.
If you go to Joe Rogan.net
and click on the link and enter in the
code named Rogan,
you'll get 15 percent off the number one
sex toy for men and Doug Benson.
If you want one.
I have extras.
I have one for you.
It's got your name right.
Did I tell you what my slogan I came up
with for the fleshlight?
No.
Fuck those things.
Oh,
I get,
that's good sample.
It's clean.
I like,
I liked the way you think.
Um,
if you enter in the code name,
Rogan,
you get 15 percent off.
And Brian,
how many of you?
I uh,
I haven't fucked one until recently.
I just went back to fucking one and it
was nice.
It was nice.
I don't know why I took the vacation
because I went for awhile.
I was spitting up my hands,
making myself have yeast infections and
all this shit.
It don't use spit after eating.
Wait a minute.
You've made yourself have a use and I
think I did.
I think I.
I think some mashed potatoes in your
hand are so lazy with my lotion.
So nasty.
You are so nasty.
He spit in your hand.
You gave yourself a yeast infection on
your.
Yeah.
Wow.
From too much breadsticks anyway.
Don't do what he does and clean your
flashlight too.
Don't be disgusting.
No problem.
With like cantaloupes recently where
people were dying from like bad
cantaloupes,
there were fucking bad cantaloupes from
eating them,
but then I was just wondering,
I was going to extrapolate like what
will happen if you fucked up bad
cantaloupe.
No kidding.
Right?
Because Cantaloupe is probably the
nature's backup to the fleshlight,
right?
How many different people do you think?
How many?
What are the numbers of people that are
fucked?
Cantaloupes?
I think there's bit.
When you're young,
you would try anything.
I mean I fucked pillows and then I sleep
on it,
you know,
so it's like hump things.
They'll get elaborate if you want to
carve a correct size hole into a piece
of fruit.
I,
just out of curiosity,
how many people do you think of fucked
cantaloupes?
Cantaloupe?
I would say at least two out of 10
people and I'm like all time numbers as
it a million,
half a million people.
Fifty three,
53.
We've gone through it,
you know,
I mean a lot of people have probably
looked at the cantaloupe and they were
drunk and fuck it,
fuck that.
And maybe look for an apple core.
Couldn't find it or tried to make a
whole circular hole with a knife and it
didn't work out.
And they're like,
ah,
fuck it.
But how many people actually went ahead?
Fucked it and came inside the
cantaloupe.
I want the numbers.
I'm biased because I have.
So I think everyone has,
you know,
you shut a load into account.
I remember I put it in the microwave
and.
Oh,
that's right.
Nice and hot.
I always used heat too.
I always,
when I think about masturbating,
I have to have heat involved,
but I don't like to live in Ohio.
It was freezing all the time.
Have you ever fucked a girl by mistake
by using the back oil you put on back?
That heats up.
You accidentally use it for lube to fuck
a girl in the ass.
Don't do that.
Ruins it,
and they run to the bathroom crying and
my goodness so that,
that hot oil lotions just for your bag.
Don't put it in an asshole.
Don't tell me that.
This is a real story.
It's super real.
I've done it multiple times,
but I say,
you know,
it's supposedly really nasty is a.
If you fill the tub with champagne,
if a lady gets into it,
it would just burn the shit out of her.
A tutor out over stuff.
Wow.
That's.
That supposedly happened in Natalie Wood
one time.
Oh,
that's funny.
I think.
I think Dennis Hopper used to tell this
story.
I bet it's happening.
A lot of hood parties.
You know what I'm saying?
Come on like you don't think Birdman has
parties,
whereas bathtubs full of champagne and
checks and just climbing in and and
booty poppin inside the tub filled the
champion.
Of course they are.
Of course,
we're telling you those girls ladies,
get your kutuchief chucked out,
get some anti yeast infection type
situation going there.
That's dangerous stuff.
Martinelli's,
sparkling apple.
Do you think that that would probably
burn also?
Maybe that would like not burn because
it's not alcoholic,
right?
Maybe picking everything up.
Maybe it would just make everything
smell nice.
Oh,
I like that taste.
Maybe it would be good.
It could be a positive and it's just
apple cider,
right?
Anyway,
that's the fleshlight commercial and go
get yourself a flashlight.
They're awesome.
To beat on a lot of controversy on this
new commercials.
Joe.
Yeah.
They go fuck themselves.
Controversy.
I just.
A lot of people have been tweeting me
and I didn't know what to tell you.
It's like,
you know,
chill the fuck out.
Commercials took so long.
It's not really commercial,
dude.
It's a commercial doing.
Every time.
Every one of them is organic.
Every one of them was just us fucking
around.
We got it out of the way.
It's the best way to do a commercial
folks.
It's really not that big a deal.
I didn't even know we were doing a
commercial pre show chat.
It's fucking entertaining.
Goddammit.
Relax everybody.
It's like what we're trying to do.
Basically just slipping in real quick on
you.
What?
Come on.
Just let me get.
Was it a big deal?
Can I do a five second commercial?
Can you recommend somebody?
Somebody made a funny website search
like Brian Dot com.
It's hilarious.
Use it for your search needs.
It's pretty awesome.
As a butthole to every search.
He adds the word butthole every time he
searched his things,
so it was like,
what do you think it would be like to
live in New Orleans?
Let's see.
It will once,
but whole wells fargo locations,
butthole and it always adds one extra
bottle to all your searches that change
the ultimate.
No,
you still get mixed in for fun.
You just,
if you get to page 1000,
199,
you might see something fucked up.
Old Dude name Wells Fargo who bent over
showing.
You know,
it's funny how that goat see thing.
That guy pulling apart his asshole.
Yeah,
data is the Internet man.
You know,
there's a photo,
um,
I forget somebody,
you know,
was one of those memes and it was a kid
that was a horrified.
It was photoshop obviously and right in
front of this kid's face was the goats.
He asshole.
And it just said,
welcome to the Internet.
I mean,
if you could pick one image that
represents the Internet for me,
it's the goats.
He asshole guy,
the guy pulling apart his asshole that
represents the internet to make is.
Guess what?
There's no way that it should be that
easy to find.
No way you should ever be one click away
from a guy just opening his asshole.
Just pulling it apart like a chew toy,
you know,
there's no fucking way that should be
one click away.
That is the Internet that embodies the
Internet.
That is the potential of the Internet.
It's not the whole Internet,
but it's a good.
It's one particular hole.
It's a good tee shirt for the band.
I mean Fuck Dude,
uh,
we are also sponsored by it on it.com,
o n n I t.
and if you go to a on a.com,
we sell our Alpha brain,
which is a cognitive enhancer and new
mood,
which is a five htp,
a formulation that has five htp and l
trip to fan in it.
And it,
um,
it's,
it really makes you feel awesome.
So if you've been trying.
And I liked it,
I like it a lot.
Five htp is the shit man.
And if you don't want,
don't even forget about what we're
selling.
Go go buy it from some,
you know,
a GNC or local,
local store tryouts and five HDP.
That shit feels good or buying in an
alley.
Try to try to buy from a dealer.
You don't have to buy our stuff.
It just,
you know,
the,
the idea of nootropics,
just because I'm selling nootropics on
the show,
don't you?
Don't buy my shit.
You go buy it from somewhere else.
Go read like what nootropics are all
about online and you know,
and try it.
It might not work for you,
might work for you.
For some people there's,
every body is different biologically I
think.
And I think stuff that might work for
you,
it's not necessarily gonna work for me.
Goodbye.
When time instead.
I mean there's some people that can't
deal with caffeine.
Some people.
I mean I don't,
I don't know if it's gonna work for you,
but for me it wasn't my thing,
but I still try it,
you know,
you never know.
Are you a caffeine guy?
No,
I'm saying it's not at all.
I,
I'm completely off of caffeine,
but I can have it every once in a while
for,
you know,
for.
Do you not go with caffeine because
caffeine kills your boss.
That's a good point.
No,
no.
I'll have like a,
you know,
of like a fancy,
like this time of year I'll like to have
like a Pumpkin latte every once in a
while or something.
But I don't,
I don't really.
I just not a coffee person,
but I'm more specifically not a diet
diet soda person anymore.
I got totally off of that.
Have you ever tried energy drinks or do
you stay away from all that?
Yeah,
I just go with,
you know,
whatever your natural.
When I'm tired,
that's time to go to bed.
It's probably a smart way.
I'm usually not in a position where I
have to force myself to stay up,
you know?
And so he's sort of keeps me,
you know,
if it's a sativa,
it sort of keeps me up anyway.
So you just avoid all stimulants pretty
well.
I drink alcohol,
so.
Yeah.
That's a depressant though,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
But I mean just in terms of.
Have you ever fuck with that are wrong?
No,
no,
no.
I don't.
I haven't really haven't fucked with
much.
I've only done mushrooms a few times and
he a couple of times and that's about
it.
I'm mostly just pot and alcohol.
A lot of people love that.
Adderall man.
A lot of people loved that for getting
shit done.
I think if I could get a supply of it,
I would probably take it away.
Yeah,
but not even going to look.
How damaging do you think it is for you?
I don't think it's bad.
I think I know.
I think if you use it in moderation,
I think it seems like it's one of those
that's kind of hard to use in moderation
leg it a lot.
I think Brian's the kind of guy that
like,
like for me,
if I like masturbate,
it's usually like I can go to sleep
right after that,
but I,
I imagined Brian underwood masturbate
and then want to stay up late enough to
be able to masturbate again.
Probably like you get bummed out that it
makes you sleepy and so you need so you
need some sort of energy thing to power
through to the next one.
Yeah.
I
want you to try something.
Life is short.
I want you to try this Alpha brain shit
right now.
No,
no.
I'll give it to you after the show,
but what?
What's it gonna do to me?
It's,
it just the way it helps me.
It makes me feel like my brain works
better.
It makes me feel cleaner,
like have a little bit more energy,
a little bit more like it feels like
things are firing better,
you know?
It's,
there's a bunch of different interesting
ingredients in it.
All of them have been used by people for
hundreds,
if not thousands of years.
And it's uh,
it's basically vitamins for brain
function,
you know,
I bet it doesn't feel like it'd be
something that you've ever like,
oh,
I need some that now.
Like,
no,
get hooked.
No,
no,
I don't think so.
No,
it doesn't have that profound effect,
you know,
it's quite honestly,
it's like most vitamins,
you know,
I believe in vitamins and I think it's
very important to take care of your body
and give it a lot of nutrients and
stuff.
But most vitamins don't have an
immediate effect.
You know,
he took vitamins.
You just know you have an overall sense
of what I'm doing the right thing and
I'm putting good food in my body.
And maybe you might feel like you have
like a little bit more energy,
but the effects of having a lack of
nutrients there,
you know,
it's slow and long.
It's not like you take vitamins and then
all of a sudden I feel amazing.
No,
it's like if you,
if you do have a good nutritional base,
you will feel better.
You know,
if you are taking nutrients,
your body will be working better and it
will work better and this works along
those.
It's,
these are nutrients that help your brain
function and how they help you think
better.
And uh,
and I'm in.
Let's do it.
I want you to try them anyway.
If you go to Joe Rogan.net
and click on the link for Alpha brain
and enter the code name Rogan,
you will get 10 percent off and then you
can get your freak on.
You'd get rubber pussies.
You get yourself some brain pills.
We're still doing commercials.
I'm going to complain about this.
This is how we do it.
I want to be on the record.
I'm going to tweet you guys and long
fucking commercial,
press the play and let's get the party
rolling.
Super stoner.
Doug Benson is in the house pitches
experience Joe Rogan podcast by night.
Let's be honest,
ladies and gentlemen,
the reason why that commercial went so
long is we're way too high to be talking
publicly.
Okay?
That was ridiculous.
I see what you're saying folks.
I see what you're saying.
I hear you.
I'm on your side now.
I don't know man.
I'm just talking shit.
Five to vaporize.
Let's do some more commercials.
Yeah.
We're not sure if this thing works yet.
We're going to give it another few
minutes because it stills has read about
it though.
Apparently it takes like 10 minutes.
Yeah,
it's like a vaporizer slash pong type
device.
I could barely do a show these days
where somebody doesn't show up with some
new contraption.
Fangled thing.
They want me to try wacky kids these
days.
You gotTa love him.
Hmm.
Months.
I'm sitting saying unable to connect to
the Internet brand.
What does that mean?
Oh,
I just got the son of a bitch.
You son of a bitch.
So people are complaining about these
long form commercials that we're doing
and I don't mean to do that to you
folks,
but that's no other way to do it.
I don't know how to.
I'm not going to say the same thing
every day.
Exactly.
That's too fucking boring.
Well,
you could tell the guest to shut the
fuck up.
You why?
I'm just saying you want it to go
quicker,
but I,
I like it to.
I thought that was fine.
Like that was.
That felt to me like that's part of the
show and people like long podcast.
So you're just giving them.
Just tell them I'm giving you more
fucker.
Shut up.
Yes,
but it's because of money.
That's why.
That's why it freaks them out that
you're doing.
You're making money like you totally.
You motherfucker.
Everyone's saying whatever they want
about the product.
It's not like we're just sitting at
sound like we're the sham wow guy or
something.
Who tries to say funny things and
they're just ridiculous.
Martini Bikini linguine with of.
You're talking about.
Does the shamwow guy,
does he have a podcast?
I don't know.
I would like to.
He was in jail for beating.
It's a girl or something.
Everyone has podcasts now.
It's kind of scary.
Didn't.
Some chick is like a hooker bite his
tongue or something?
Yeah.
That shit.
That's it.
Oh God,
man.
Hooker Bites your tongue.
Dude.
You've hit a wall out.
You have hit a fucking wall in life
when hooker buys your time.
Shit.
Fuck.
That's pretty brutal.
A lot of disaster
now because human bites are like
dangerous.
They're dangerous.
They're like really toxic.
We have nasty mounds were like as
dangerous,
if not more dangerous than most wild
animals.
You have a yeast infection in my mouth.
Why do you keep having used?
When is it going to stop?
Just kidding.
Have you ever gone down on a girl who
has a yeast infection?
I don't know.
I've never.
Probably.
I have no idea of what a lot of girls
right now that are getting angry at this
conversation.
Tastes like bread.
Bread.
Yeah.
Or beers like fish,
fish bread.
This is a subject that makes women
angry.
It makes them really angry.
I'm talking about if you're a fucking a
girl,
what they get like a urinary track
infection where it's like,
you know,
like,
oh,
that's where the legs just juicing
everywhere.
Black blood and smells like,
oh,
vinegar or something.
We'll see why women wouldn't enjoy this
conversation.
Has got to be tough to take care of.
You know?
Oh,
it's so much maintenance.
It's the difference between washing a
car and being a mechanic.
That's what it's like.
It's like men just have to keep their
fucking car washed,
you know,
keep your car washed,
waxed the hood,
boom.
You're done.
Women have a fucking whole internal
thing there.
Now we'll check out,
get in there.
They've got to get under the mechanism
for loads for their fucking Kangaroos,
a human factory inside their box.
They have a human factor in there.
I mean Shit,
crank shaft.
We have balls that make loads.
That's what we have and those loads make
people.
It's really no big deal for us.
They have a human making machine inside
the vagina.
Shit,
what the fuck man?
What's up,
Doug?
Where have you been all over the place?
You've been on the road like Nice.
Remember?
Like every time I'm in la,
he goes,
where were you last weekend?
I don't know.
I went someplace.
You have constant staff and Phoenix last
weekend?
Yeah,
and I,
but I,
I'm really going where I want to go when
I want to go there.
Like for the next couple months,
I've only playing gigs in California and
Florida to avoid winter weather.
To have plants.
No,
no,
no.
But I'm home.
I,
I've only.
I've kind of gotten into a pattern in my
career,
have always trying to be home for a few
days,
then out for a few days.
I never go away for a long time or for
stay home for a long time.
I just sort of does the go away for a
couple days and come back is the best
way.
When people go out for like three months
at a time,
all they do is tour that.
He doesn't like.
You might as well be in a band if you're
going to do that,
you know?
Yeah.
I watched that Dang cooked orgasm,
you know where he and all those guys and
Bobby Kelly.
Three poor guy.
Yeah.
They all went to and toured around.
I call those guys and I felt so bad for
them having like,
because they do stuff like today we're
going to go ride horses to see what
wackiness happens.
And then Robert Kelly falls off the
fucking horse and breaks his arm.
Yeah.
It's just
like,
oh,
you didn't even need to go horse back
riding.
You could have just been hanging out in
a condo like you would if you were out
doing your own gig somewhere.
Yeah.
What was,
um,
what did Robert Kelly break his arm,
twisted it or something?
He had a.
he.
Because during a lot of tour guides him,
he has some sort of cast or sleeping on
his arm I think.
Is that what happened?
I remember there was like an audio that
they were planning on opening.
Anthony was talking about his knee,
right leg hurt his knee.
He broke his leg.
I broke my knee.
Man,
I'd probably need man.
Right?
Yeah.
Yes.
I mean maybe I'm just confusing
everything,
but those guys that had to be really
stressful to go on the road.
I only did it once with that Charlie
Murphy thing,
me and Charlie Murphy and John Drawn and
uh,
it was,
it was not the most fun because we
weren't doing well like ticket sales.
We didn't do well in a lot of places.
Like the promotion wasn't the best,
so a lot of people had no idea we were
even in their towns.
It turned out that we only did well in
the places where I already did well and
Charlie already did well.
It wasn't really like a good,
it wasn't a really well produced,
sort of such a blur too.
Like I don't remember anything.
Do you remember what city was?
What and what club was what it did?
And unfortunately,
you know,
this was before social media.
We didn't have like twitter or anything
like that.
Imagine us having this stream show
during that.
Oh,
had been so fun.
Yeah,
it had been really fun.
It had to be in a different town and we
were literally in a different town.
Every night we would wake up,
stare at the ceiling,
going to fuck.
Where am I chose?
Were asked to blur together for sure.
The hotels,
airlines and the airports and the shows
were awesome,
but it just wasn't,
it wasn't a financial success.
It didn't do well.
The only place it only did well and like
half the places.
Is there a city that you don't like
performing in?
Like you just think,
oh,
the crowd's always suck there because
people always asked me about that.
I,
I always have a great time everywhere I
go.
When you bring your own people now,
you know,
that's true for us as an opening act for
other comics.
I always,
I never was like,
oh,
this city's,
you know,
they don't like me as much as you know,
other cities,
you know,
like sometimes you get a bad crowd,
but yeah,
I find I don't find one city to be like,
oh,
that place,
the crowds are always really stupid.
Or you know,
like some places they skew old,
like I don't do well at Atlantic city
because the crowds are just too old.
Right.
They're just like,
what the hell is he talking about?
Right,
right,
right.
Yeah.
Atlantic city is a tricky place.
That's a tricky place.
I've done that.
What does that big theater there?
We did that at the Borgata did that a
couple times.
It's a tricky place.
There's a lot of old people.
It's a strange thing.
It's like,
it's sort of like trying to be Vegas,
but it's just a,
just a hair seedier.
Just a hair.
Weirder hair,
more possibility of murdering the hair.
Just a hair more,
you know,
it's,
it's caters to adapt to New Jersey and
Philadelphia and you
know,
everything around there.
Like it's,
it's more like a localized,
like people come from all over the world
for Vegas,
but if someone's coming from really far
away,
why are they going to Atlantic city?
That'd be,
that'd be a weird choice.
And Atlantic city's essentially
surrounded by dangerous cities.
You know,
Vegas is essentially in the middle of
nowhere,
you know,
you'd get past bar stone.
What the fuck is it?
It's just a bunch of weird towns that
don't make any sense.
You know,
that drive to Vegas is the real America
though.
You know,
it's,
it's a strange drive.
But that drove to Vegas.
That's the real America Atlantic city.
You have to go through Camden,
you know,
you pass through the outskirts,
south Philly,
you know,
you.
There's like a lot of places around
around Atlantic city that are filled
with
like serious criminals,
man.
I mean they had a fucking big billboard
in Newark when we were there for the UFC
big billboard that said,
stop killing the teachers.
Stop killing the teacher.
Is there a big teacher cleaning going
on?
I don't know,
but the fact that there must be
something,
I mean,
otherwise why would you make a goddamn
billboard about it saying stop killing
the teachers and then,
you know,
my joke of course was the people who are
killing the teachers probably can't
read.
You know,
it's not really helping and by the way
they're going to look at that and go,
no,
mighty had killed the teacher.
Encourage them a little bit like saying
scary,
scary place.
Newark is a spooky place.
I lived in New York for a couple of
years.
I lived there when I was a little kid
and then I lived there again when I was
adult for I think about six months.
I stayed with my grandfather when I
first moved to New York,
I couldn't afford my own place and I got
signed by this management company and so
I had to relocate to New York,
so I just balls up,
pick up my shed,
whatever money I had in the bank and
just went.
I was gone in like two weeks so I had to
stay with my grandfather and he lived on
North Ninth Street in Newark,
New Jersey,
and I'm telling you,
man,
you might as well have been in another
country.
It is a crazy little spot.
There's a lot going on there,
man.
There's a lot going on.
It's like it's a completely different
vibe.
I've only gone through there on a train.
I don't think I.
I don't,
I don't think I ever set foot in there.
They did this thing called block
busting and this is what they used to
do.
This is how real estate guys made money.
It was a really devious practice.
They would go into a neighborhood and
say,
hey,
black people are moving in.
You better sell now because your
property value is going to crash.
By the time they move in,
you know you're,
you're going to be fucked,
you're gonna lose your investment.
So a lot of people bought into it and a
lot of people just took off.
Sure enough,
boom.
It crashed whole neighborhoods.
They did it on purpose.
They did it to try to make money and my
grandfather was like,
fuck you.
I like black people.
Oh,
I'm going to stay right here.
This is my house.
I bought this house and he watched this
neighborhood turned from being an all
Italian neighborhood to being an all
black neighborhood.
And then it became like all Spanish,
you know,
like various different kinds of people
from Puerto Rico,
from all different nationalities,
but a lot of Spanish people now.
So it was really almost like a kid
watched this whole thing where he was in
this old school America,
you know,
19 forties,
and then boom,
all of a sudden he's living in the
modern age where everything has just
gone crazy around them.
I Bet Mitt Romney's done some of that
blockbusting oh yeah.
That seems like that's in his
wheelhouse.
Irritating blockbusting blockbusting for
Jesus or blockbusting for Joseph Smith.
Yeah,
he's A.
He's A.
I'm sure he's a swell guy.
We're just joking around.
Folks.
I'm sure.
Mitt Romney's aces.
I'm sure he's asis.
What he says about a right now he's
saying that they should just.
Everyone should just go ahead and go,
go bankrupt.
Like all on all houses.
Everyone should just lose their house
and let the.
Let the market decide what happens to
everybody.
What the fuck.
That's his strategy is just let
everybody don't loan any money to
anybody.
Is that a real statement?
That's incredible.
Let the foreclosure process happened.
Just sit.
It's like being raped,
like just lay back and let it happen and
don't struggle.
The ultimate acceptance that as a unit,
we're only as strong as our weakest
link.
You know you have to have.
If you're.
If you're working towards things as the
leader,
if you're supposed to be the number one
guide that you're,
you're at the top calling all the shots.
The number one thing you have to take
care of is the weakest of the links.
That's,
that's the people that are fucked up,
the weakest of the links that people
that are down and out,
the people that are homeless,
the people that don't know where their
next meal's coming from,
you've got to take care of them.
You got to figure that out.
Yeah,
and the politics of this country is
those people are not paying for the
politicians.
They're not making the contributions
that racist.
Racist is a lot of poor white people.
Oh yeah.
The poverty level or company level,
ridiculous.
This doesn't matter,
right?
It doesn't matter.
White,
white or black,
doesn't matter.
It's not about that.
It's about people that are in despair,
you know,
and friendly.
One to say that they should just suffer.
That's ridiculous.
You know,
some people can't do it on their own
man.
Some people need a little help.
So when people need to be shown how,
you know,
we need,
we need a nation with someone who's an
actual guide,
someone who can offer real guidance and
now they're not doing that man.
It's just a money grab.
It's a money grab by all these fucking
corporate whores and all these people
who have paid for these politicians to
be in place and paid for these laws to
be in place or just reaping the profits
while the rest of us freak the fuck out
because we can't figure out why the
resources are going the way they're
going.
We were going,
why you there?
Why?
Why do we have 100,000
troops here?
Why do we have troops there?
Why?
Why don't we conserve our fucking
resources?
Why is that the biggest section of our
economy?
Why does it have to be this military
industrial complex?
Why do we have be doing this,
this idea to keep us safe,
to keep the fuck.
Are you talking about man,
keep the troops here.
Let them guard.
Yeah,
exactly.
If you want to keep us safe all over the
country.
I have troops all over the outskirts of
the fucking country.
You know?
That's how you keep safe.
You don't have preemptive shit,
man.
I don't know dude.
I don't know.
The whole thing freaks me out.
It freaks me out because I can't believe
it's this bad in 2011,
I was listening to Robert Anton Wilson
Lecture and he was talking,
it was in 1993 and he was talking about
how war is in the process of being
phased out,
you know,
and he was talking about how in the
future it,
it's obvious obviously being phased out
and I wonder what he would've said now
today,
thinking about that,
like in 1993,
that in 1993 I thought war was going to
be phased out too.
We all thought it was over.
You know,
we got through that whole crazy desert
storm thing under Bush and all of a
sudden here we are and it's 2011 and
it's crazier than ever.
I wonder what he would have said them
get made.
Is it being phased out because it
doesn't seem like it's being phased.
It seems like it
heating up like we may be pulling out of
a couple places,
but going into new ones,
that's like,
what the fuck is going on?
If there's something else going on,
let me know.
All right.
If Indiana Jones is found the fucking
last temple and the Ark of the covenant
is in there and you have to keep the bad
guys from getting to it because if not,
it'll be hell on earth and hopefully
there's some snakes.
Yeah,
fucking please let me know because
otherwise this is crazy.
Otherwise,
this is crazy
and it's so obvious that there's money
behind all this shit.
This.
It's so obvious.
We live in the grossest most corrupt
country ever.
It's so bizarre.
Not ever.
Of course.
I'm just kidding.
I mean,
I'm sure a lot of Middle Eastern
countries and a lot of South American
countries,
they're
pretty corrupt.
Corrupt too,
but the fact that we're,
we're this wonky.
You know,
and then everybody wants to stand up and
say you get,
you should get up if you don't like you,
you should leave Merck.
You know,
there's,
there's so many Rah Rah Rah fans out
there not liking it as what the whole
country has been built up.
Exactly.
That was the idea is that everybody,
everybody gets to contribute.
It's called the democracy and we're all
supposed to participate and help one
another and now it's just like it's
becoming so every man for himself that
the disparity between the richest,
the richest one percent and the poorest
people is,
it's just insane.
The difference.
It's God damn money grab out there.
It's a money grab out there left and
right.
So are all the occupies right now being
shut down like,
oh,
I haven't been.
Each city's kind of treating it
differently.
Like,
um,
there's a few cities that are really
embracing it.
And in La it's not,
it's not really a problem.
The original one I heard got shut down.
Yeah,
I heard some crazy shit that they were
keeping reporters out and they were
forcing reporters out of the area.
They said it was for their own safety.
That's insulting Bloomberg cleared,
but he out at eh,
they're all intense and they went
through and told everybody they had 10
minutes to get out at 1:00
AM on a Tuesday and uh,
and you know,
and then they used,
they used quite a bit of force to get
everybody out of there and now they're
letting people back in,
but they're saying they can't have tents
and sleeping bags like you can go back
in and just stand there.
And the idea is they figure that that's
going to kill the movement a little bit
because it's getting so cold and they
won't be able to lock.
We will be able to last through the
winter.
But Bloomberg keeps saying it's a safety
issue that also that,
you know,
they have the right to peaceably
assemble but they don't have a right to
have a tent or a sleeping bag,
which is this kind of like,
well,
but that's so that they can assemble
peacefully and not,
you know,
not just I'll freeze to death in the
middle of the fucking park in New York.
Like why would they want casualties
there?
Why would,
why would they want people to suffer
that much,
you know,
in order to just express their anger at
Wall Street.
I mean,
I think it's fantastic that it's that,
that,
that it's happening everywhere,
you know,
that there's,
there's occupied dubuque and stuff like
that,
but also this new Bloomberg doing this,
if he just let it,
let it be it,
the movement might have died,
but it brought this whole new media
storm and all these new,
all this new footage of cops just
beating up these,
these people that,
that don't look like hippies.
They're not all in tie dye.
They're just people that are just,
you know,
concerned and showing up to you to make
up
mark.
They're holding hand by hand.
And did you see that video?
My brother wouldn't hit my hand.
That's just insane.
I can't believe that as a,
as a fellow person,
just being able to do that too.
Like that girl little girl.
What what he's saying is they were
jabbing and with Bhutan.
Yeah.
And Bloomberg,
you know,
he makes it all about as horrible.
He makes it all about keeping,
keeping people of New York safe by
kicking everybody out of there and it's
like when they were in their tents,
who was,
who was in danger?
Nobody.
But as soon as they're.
Well maybe he's worried about people
freezing to death.
Don't think he is.
I think ego problem.
I don't think he is either,
but it is sort of a legal concern.
Someone freezes to death on your lawn.
Who's responsible for that?
Yeah,
well it certainly not his lawn.
Like it's,
it's like a public park that's privately
owned.
Is it by some corporation?
Is that public safety though?
Like it's just like our argument is that
it's his argument was that people can
enjoy the park if the park is full of
people that are just point,
but it's like,
you know,
New York City walk two blocks it.
Enjoy that other park.
Yeah,
just one fucking park.
But I think what,
you know,
Eh,
yeah,
it's a,
it's,
there's definitely two sides to it,
but it just feels like,
it feels like,
um,
you know what Bloomberg did sort of.
It sort of energize the movement in a
way that it might not have happened.
If he did,
if he did just let it play out.
How would anybody expect them to behave
though?
They've got to figure out a way to
squash this and they have to take
drastic measures.
There's another go through the middle of
the night.
Everybody's fucking.
There's no MDF sleep and they go in
there and just say,
you got to go now.
Get out with this footage of like cops,
you know,
lifting guys up and throwing them over
the barricade stuff.
It's like,
it's really.
And you know,
in the cops for the most part,
I like to say they're doing what they're
told to do.
I don't.
I don't like to blame the cops.
Yeah.
They're given what they're,
they're,
they're doing what they're told to do,
but when they're doing it,
all the sudden the people that don't
want to listen become the enemy.
They become bad guys.
Yeah.
It's like a bouncer with a drunk person
in a class.
Like when that drunk person then it gets
violent.
People aren't bad guys.
They should like,
like let them still occupy like the
trees,
like they should be allowed to like live
in the trees in the park so that the
park be.
Yeah,
but then what if a hippie falls on you
while you're walking?
You get some real safety issues.
They have to have some safety like chat
people that check it out,
but then they become an [inaudible] and
a couple months and then the idea is the
idea is to cause people.
The idea is to cause some inconvenience
and draw some attention.
You know,
they,
they don't know.
You don't.
You don't like get together and protest
something and imagine that for politely
match.
If that's where swaths came from the
originally people,
they were just so fucking stupid.
They eventually just became these claude
things.
Just degenerated to that point.
Imagine someone proved that slaw is
like,
you know,
that's like a sin.
That's what sends the basics.
Ends,
right?
Yeah.
That's my favorite sloths.
What was that movie with Brad Pitt seven
with a seven slash 10 of a v?
Yeah,
that's a good movie.
It's a good fucking movie.
It's,
it's,
it's a creepy movie.
Went in that one dude that big,
the sloths guy was like sitting over
hunched over the table and it was the
first time where I saw like a body where
they had like makeup where it was like
blue,
like it's been sitting there for awhile,
you know that they did a good job.
Yeah.
Dang it looked at as fuck.
Do you ever do that?
What?
Get makeup like that on you?
Just for fun.
Like it looks like your stomach.
No,
I don't do a lot of things.
Just for fun.
I know Brian Redmond,
bride red band lives just for fun.
I wish you got to dragon's layer shirt
on.
What's that about?
You know what?
I went to a comic book store the other
day because I've been hearing all this
shit about how comic book stores are
just hurting right now.
Like they're,
they're suffering the most with is a
whole economy.
People aren't buying comics anymore.
They don't have any free money where,
you know they're downloading comp.
Kids are downloading comics now,
so I decided there's one in Burbank that
I've always driven bias.
I might check it out,
maybe I can find a cool poster for the
studio or something.
So I went in there and I just.
I was in there for like three hours is
the best story ever and a bunch of
stuff.
Bunch of just like random things.
It was so cheap.
It was like posters were like $7.
I was like,
well,
I never get a chance to brag about this,
but I,
I the very.
I worked at the arcade that had the very
first dragon's layer,
the test one before it went public and I
probably killed the dragon.
I was probably maybe the 30th or 40th
person in the world to get all the way
to the end until the dragon because I
would stay at night when I was off duty
and I had keys to the place and I would
just stay in there and play and play and
play until I finally got to the dragon,
you know,
figured it all out and killed the dragon
and uh,
you know,
and then eventually it went,
went public and that is amazing all over
the place.
Yeah.
Nerd boner.
I worked at an arcade called star port.
It was in a mall,
but when you walked in there was all
this corrugated tin and stuff that
simulate kind of like you're going into
like space mountain or something and
there's stars on the ceiling.
It was,
it was kind of a cool themed arcade
refresh my memory,
because I remember the dragon's lear was
like this really cool animated thing
where,
you know,
you would go,
you would have,
but you would have to move certain ways.
There's a series of scenes that would
happen on the screen,
like an animated movie.
It looked like a dog and you had like a,
you know,
I think you had a regular toggle thing
and then a couple of buttons.
It's a,
yeah,
it's a joystick and uh,
an action button and usually it started
off like you're walking down like a
bridge and then like a snake comes up
and you have to think what would you
want to do?
Like either take the sword to the snake
or left.
But it was more of a guessing game if
you had this more like you have to try
every combination of things to do,
like there's one part where you're like,
you're in a,
like a cave,
roaring down the river in a raft or
something and it's like you have,
you can go to the right of the left.
And so if you toggle to the right,
you know,
you,
you'd go,
you'd go the rest of the way without
encountering anything.
But if you go the other way,
something,
something goes wrong and you lose a life
or something.
And um,
there's just a bunch of options through
the whole thing until finally you get to
and kill the dragon.
But yeah,
it was really,
it was weird because it wasn't,
you know,
it was early enough in video games were,
wasn't like you could really make the
things do that much because also it was,
he was pretty animated,
there weren't a lot of options.
So like as long as you did the right
thing,
you move forward or you or,
or there'd be a scene of you failing.
They have it on the IPAD,
I believe now,
but that's my dream is to get in a
dragon's layer,
original dragon's lair arcade game.
And my friend actually just got one and
I'm so jealous.
That's your dream.
That was one of my like,
you know,
like you have dream things like gold
shorts.
I went the gold short circuit board of
it today,
man.
So yeah,
let me give you also another reason to
be jealous.
Here's the reason to not be jealous is
because when that thing breaks down,
there's nobody that's gonna fix it.
I already have a laser disc player at my
house,
brand new,
just waiting to replace it.
Why?
You're good enough with that kind of
stuff that you can install.
The a couple of my friends,
that's what they do for a living and the
arcade restore restoration.
Does that work on laser disk is.
Oh yeah,
it's a.
it's a laser disc.
So the game is a laser?
Yes.
Essentially.
Yeah,
with just different chat.
You just,
you when you toggle the correct way or
push the button the right way it goes
into a different chapter.
But honestly nowadays you can mod an
arcade games like I could hook up a
computer to it and have every single
arcade game ever,
you know.
So you don't even need the laser disk
player anymore.
Are you using rom?
How many options were there for
movement?
That's what I don't remember.
I just remember being completely
groundbreaking.
Like Whoa,
this is like you're,
it's like an animal.
There was a group,
it's amazing.
It was just joy stick in one button if I
recall.
Yeah,
you just kinda like are always kind of
moving to the left or the right or,
or in the case.
And it was hard case of like throwing
the sword into the Dragon.
I think you had to just press the button
and and and motion in that direction at
the same time.
Laser disc game show.
The eighties were one of my favorite
things ever that he had that mach five
or whatever it was called where it was
like you're a jet plane and it was like
all real film of jets and it was really
cool because it was also using a laser
disc player.
It was like new and the.
They had like a space which was also
done by Don Bluth who did a dragon's
layer and there was one game.
They started taking Japanese cartoon
movies and making them a video games.
A Malibu Grand Prix had a.
It was a race track thing in the midwest
where they had a whole arcade division.
So they took these animated movies and
one was called a space six,
six six or it was like about a train and
it was the coolest video game because
you were on top of a train and it was
like dragon's layer and it was like a
spy movie was so cool,
but that didn't ever really catch on.
Like it didn't really become,
it was big briefly in the eighties,
but it didn't become a lot of them,
you know,
like there's Pac man and then everything
that's sort of vaguely remember that.
I vaguely remember that in an arcade.
What year was this?
This was about 85.
80 six I ever saw that.
I only saw.
I remember space and feeling like it was
already like,
oh well that's not dragon's layer.
That's just an attempt to be like dragon
slayer.
Home Computer Games must have just
crushed video arcades.
Right.
It did.
When the Nintendo finally came out.
I mean not like a big video arcade.
You remember when we used to go to just
video arcades,
you'd open the door and it was just,
it's always,
always with something else or in a weird
place like an airport or a scene.
What are those?
What are those gaven buster type places.
They have a room of games,
but they also have to have food and
drinks and pool tables and you know,
a shuffleboard and like no place is just
video games except for there's one joint
in Portland that's like a whole arcade
that's just all old school shit
Portland.
Right.
Of course.
It's important that.
That's funny.
I told you about my friend that does the
restoration,
spry and Pinzon,
Columbus,
Ohio.
He uh,
he,
his whole basement,
he made a eighties arcade room.
So you walked down.
It's like you walk down into 1980 and so
it's,
it's amazing.
And it's.
So he decorated it like Wayne's world,
everything like those,
like little pink neon that's always at
the top,
you know,
from the eighties.
And as soon as Brian posts saying,
made a nickel in show business,
he bought a.
He and his buddy dave wrath bought a,
um,
a combination.
It was half and half.
Ms Dot Pacman,
Galaga.
Oh,
I would just spend hours over his house.
Gallagher geologists,
the shit.
I love it.
I'm pretty good at Calico.
And then he also got a joust slash
robotron and I'm really good at robotron
was another one that I,
you know,
I just worked in an arcade so I just
played games all day.
Kids would come up to me and they'd be
like,
can I get some tokens that I'd be like,
hang on a second kid,
you know,
and I'd finished the round,
then I'd throw him some tokens and then
I'd go back to playing.
Like it was the craziest job.
Cocktail tables for the studio table.
Pacman,
joust games.
They used to have those like while
you're waiting around like in a pizza
hut or sit down or sit down table
pinball was also kind of cool.
There's a place near me that the movie
theater has an arcade that was a little
entry room.
We can go and play video games while
you're waiting for your movie.
I just liked the look of it.
I liked the style of arcade games.
Like I don't even play it much.
Like I have a pac man at the studio and
I barely ever play.
I just liked the lights of it.
I like just the look it,
it's so Goddamn Lynard skynard poster.
That's right.
It relaxes you and you're masturbating
or get turned on by these video game
commercials.
I get turned on by these video game
commercials,
but not to the point where I'll go out
and get it out.
Really.
I won't,
I won't allow myself.
I just know that I will,
you know,
any new video game,
I sort of kicked it,
you know,
I just stopped doing it altogether.
Uh,
you know,
after uh,
I'd say after Mario Kart.
Yeah.
I used to play that day and night and
then after a while you're just like,
what is getting great at this gonna do
for me.
It's fun,
but it's the truth.
You're getting tricked,
you're getting tricked into doing
something absolutely stupid with your
time.
And it hijacks your,
your whole idea,
your reward system,
you know,
you're succeeding,
you're focused,
you're in on it,
but really you're not even in the real
world.
You're in this getting all these signals
from this fake world.
Yeah.
But it's like watching a movie to me
nowadays,
you know,
it's,
it's like watching a movie to me,
I want to escape reality,
but I want to have more control of the
movie united.
So that's kind of why I do.
I don't watch as many movies anymore.
My time when you have interactive video
games,
there's a lot of thinking involved,
especially if you're playing like if
you're playing counter strike or
something like that or playing quake or,
and any John Madden,
you
got to know about all the players and
stuff.
Oh,
there's a lot of thinking going on.
Like your synapses are firing,
you know whether or not you choose to
think
they're firing on something useful or
not.
That's,
you know,
that's really sort of an arbitrary
decision.
Like you can't say that this person
isn't actually training their mind
through intensive video games
because you're doing intense video
games.
You're multitasking,
you're fucking,
your synapses are firing,
you're moving your fingers.
You have to first person shooters.
You have to be in direct coordination
with your left hand,
which movies your keys and your right
hand,
which controls the mouse.
And you know,
there's a lot of shit going on.
You can't tell me that.
That's not exercise for the mind.
I played a lot of golden eye too,
now that I think,
you know,
they rereleased what's gold?
And it was the first James Bond,
like the pretty cool.
Was it good?
I'll run around different weapons type
thing,
but if they'd have,
you know,
you could play for people at a time.
So me and two other people just sit
there for hours chasing each other
around trying to shoot each other.
So stupid.
Yeah,
man.
The whole staff on Newsradio,
the entire writing staff was addicted to
quake and they had a land set up,
a local area network setup in the office
where they had like six,
seven computers all linked up together
and they would have these mad quake
tournament's and was courageous.
It was really fucking fun.
It was unfortunately though,
highly,
hugely addictive.
And yeah,
I would,
uh,
I would get really stuck playing know
where I was like,
you know,
7:00,
8:00
in the morning,
early,
I got to go home.
Like I make myself drive home because we
were all playing
when I worked at gateway,
all the tech guys with all the gateway
stores in Columbus.
Uh,
we used to have land parties.
Every Friday we'd have just get alcohol
and uh,
we all have like shuttle or like small
little portable computers are
cantaloupes.
And then we would just sit there and
play battlefield 19 or whatever for like
hours till like five in the morning.
No Glare.
Yeah.
No,
it's a fun.
We used to do that in like the quake
claim that I was in.
We would get together in Houston,
Texas.
They would,
most of those guys lived in Houston.
So we would go to Houston,
have these,
a local area network parties set up in
this.
All the computers set up in this room.
Heavy acid.
I've seen places.
That was the thing,
the studio make it like a huge.
Also,
you could sit down and just have like a
land party every time you hang out
there.
Dude,
if we do and do a podcast or email,
I have a real problem.
You can only do it once a month to
podcast play.
If you want to put some quick on there
once a week car open up the door.
I opened up Pandora's box.
Yeah,
that'd be cool.
Land Party podcast.
I got to play guys era.
You did.
Why were.
Why was a good pool player?
That's why you played with him.
Yeah.
He's a buddy.
I didn't know.
I didn't know you knew him or what,
but like it just went to his house.
Are we met?
We met at a pool hall.
Where's the pool hall?
Because that's another thing that seems
to be dying.
It's not hard to find pool halls.
This was the house of billiards in
Sherman Oaks.
Yeah.
It's hard.
Hard to find good places.
Vegas has the most good places.
Vegas still has 24 hour pool halls,
which is an anomaly outside of Vegas.
It used to be in New York you could get
24 hour pool halls a lot.
There was Chelsea,
Chelsea billiards,
and there was a bunch of other smaller
places that were 24 hours.
I don't know how many of them are left,
but Chelsea is gone and a lot of other
big ones are gone.
That's crazy.
At 24 hour place to play a sport.
There's not many of those.
There's not like anything else.
The name pool really is all about
gambling.
It's really pocket billiards.
It's called pool because everybody's
pooling their money together and
bending.
The Fun in pool is all about money.
It's all about gambling and so you would
go to these places and the reason why
they were open 24 hours a day because no
one ever wanted to leave.
They would just play.
You get down and try to get back up.
Guys would sleep under the tables.
It was so common that guys would stay
there for two,
three days.
Yeah.
I would go and do gigs.
I'd come back and the same guys will be
there from the night before and the same
clothes.
Almost like a job for a lot of guys.
Yeah,
and they would.
They would be gambling like crazy,
but it was always fun.
It was always exciting.
You know,
the,
the world of gambling and pool and,
and that like,
you know,
if you're,
if you're in an auction room,
that's fucking fun,
man.
It's,
it's very addictive,
you know,
but it's again,
it's just like the video game thing.
It's like,
what are you doing by getting really
good at putting balls in holes?
What are you doing?
Gambling illegally and getting,
getting in scrapes with guys because you
don't for the most dudes,
for the most part,
if everybody knew everybody.
There was very few problems,
but there was always stories.
If you know,
this guy wanted his money back and he
came at this guy with a fucking golf
club and you know,
there was always those stories.
I saw a few scuffles over the years of
hanging out and pool halls.
But for the most part when people paid,
you know,
they,
if they wanted to keep gambling,
they had to pay when they lost because
everybody had.
There was a gambler's ethic.
If you,
if you cause trouble when you lost and
you're only happy when you won,
nobody would gamble with you.
People didn't want to.
So they were just naturally became guys
who had good reputations and guys who
didn't and if he didn't know the guy
don't play him.
So it sort of Tom Cruise and Paul
Newman's showed up.
That was the big.
That's when people realize how fun it
was.
But it's one of those things.
It's getting,
it's,
it's sort of getting lost in our
culture.
When we were playing last night,
there was a girl a at a table next to us
that was pretty good.
She,
she could play pretty good and she was
with her boyfriend who couldn't fucking
play at all and she was humiliating him
and he was trying getting super upset,
but it's like she didn't even try to
help him.
His technique was fucking horrible.
His elbows up in the air.
He was putting all kinds of extra spin
on the ball.
I couldn't make a ball to save his life.
And the girl was like,
just laughing at him and jumping up and
down.
Every time she won.
And you could see him getting fucking
pissed.
Getting actually pissed off that she was
like bragging because she was winning
this game.
Like you see them,
like almost want to hit her.
I'm like,
wow,
there's some deep seated shit in this
game.
Augie.
All competition between dudes and their
girlfriend.
Any kind.
It brings out some really weird shit,
man.
You got to win against a woman no matter
how nice to women you are and how much
you respect them.
Still this weird thing kicks in.
That's just hardwired.
Yeah.
I was dating.
This is how I got into pool.
I was dating this chick and she was a
little older than.
And she used to like to tell them what
to do and I didn't really like that,
but I like to fuck her.
So I stuck around for a little while.
But uh,
we played.
That was one of the things she tells you
to do.
Yeah,
we played pool once and uh,
she beat me playing pool.
She was not,
I wasn't good.
So I wouldn't say she was pretty good,
but she beat me.
And so I said,
Oh shit,
I found something.
She's good at,
you know,
like she's,
she's,
she's better at meeting this.
Well,
this is terrible.
I have to fix this.
I have to fix this at once,
so I went to the pool hall and learn how
to play pool and we started practicing.
Teacher went and I,
I got a book on it.
I,
I got my own cue.
I figured out how to play pool and then
we played again and I killed her.
Yeah,
we get it.
I totally practice,
totally learn how to pull play pool and
then winter.
I mean I wasn't good by any stretch of
the imagination,
but at least I knew how to play pool
like I was.
I was definitely way better than it was
the first time we played and then I won.
So I like I,
I had a problem that I couldn't let her
have beaten me in something and this is
how I got addicted to playing pool.
I'm imagining you being like the
zookeeper character as you're telling
that story.
I was totally like that guy.
Well that was the dark days.
That was the actual fighting days.
The dark days.
I was,
I was way crazier.
Yeah.
I can't think of an example of something
I taught myself to be better at,
to,
to beat my girlfriend,
but I'm sure it happened.
I could not let her.
She was.
She was older than me and she was smart.
There was no way.
She was a very educated person to,
you know,
she was a musician.
She was in a lot,
a lot,
a lot of shit going on.
She ever wrote a song about you when you
guys were doing.
That'd be cool if there was a song out
there.
I mean,
she's a nice person,
very nice person,
but couldn't sort of.
No,
no,
no.
It's very hard to stay in touch with
people.
You know,
when you used to date them and all down
they date other people.
They don't want some dude fucking
calling and texting and emailing.
It's not great.
It's not right.
You know which from the best and the
don't confuse everybody.
You can confuse the shit out of people.
You know,
don't you think you know,
but you know,
all of a sudden you know you're in a
fight with your husband and you know
you're,
you're having an email talks with your
ex boyfriend.
Then all of a sudden you start thinking,
you know,
maybe this guy and I could give it one
more shot.
Maybe that's why it,
it can conflict,
you know?
I think if it's an
open forum only then that's cool.
Like a facebook wall posts and stuff
like that.
Like,
hey,
how have you been?
And we should hang out sometime or
something like that.
Or maybe you could do some gamesmanship
or somebody wants something and then the
trouble is the other people in your life
start questioning what's going on and it
sucks.
Yeah,
it sucks.
It's annoying.
Really.
We should be able to just fuck
everybody.
That's really ideal,
but no one can handle that.
Red Bands.
The only person that could handle that.
No.
Could you imagine if the ego actually
gets completely cured,
that you can't have art,
then that'd be senior.
You're not going to have artists like
the best jokes were to get paid.
Art is like the struggle,
the best painter artist,
like the struggle between the ego and
like the,
the desire to produce something
fantastic to please others.
You know,
and if you don't control the ego,
you,
you can't really produce aren't.
But the fight with the ego is what fuels
the art sometimes.
So if we had no ego,
we'd have no art,
no art,
but people would just fuck like
randomly.
Everybody would just be able to fuck
everybody.
You wouldn't worry about it.
It takes nerve to be an artist because
you're basically saying,
you know that I can do this thing so
well that people are going to want it.
It's very arrogant.
Yeah,
super arrogant.
But it's also,
you know,
it starts out like you're,
you're just like,
I get people asking me all the time,
how do you become a standup comic?
And I'm just like,
I do it.
That's how you become one.
You just do it.
And then they're always like,
yeah,
but do you have any advice?
And I really like just lots of little
tiny pieces of advice you can give if
you want to sit with a person and talked
to them for two weeks.
But big advice is just do it.
Never underestimate the power of
actually fucking doing something.
And also I'll also not the,
the,
the fact that they're questioning it at
all,
the fact that they're looking to someone
else for help to get started makes you
think that they.
How are they ever going to make it?
Because they don't want it badly enough.
They're not going to just do it.
You know?
I never asked anybody,
oh yeah,
this is what you have to do to go on
stage.
What do you have to do against days?
That was my,
my initial question,
but once I got in and started doing open
mics,
I just,
you know,
you,
you figure it out by doing it and trial
and error.
No one's good.
The no one that you know who thinks
they're funny.
You can go on stage and kill in front of
a room full of strangers.
You might laugh if you think they're
your buddy and they're up there.
Yuck,
Yuck it up,
but guess what?
It's a,
it's a weird fucking way to communicate
with people and it really is not all
that it seems.
It's a very tricky sort of a craft that
you have to learn and develop.
But you can do it.
Anybody can do it,
but nobody's good in the beginning.
Nobody is good in the beginning.
Yeah.
Or you get,
you know,
you get your labs here and there and
that's encouraged.
You get a little chuckle here and there.
You know,
you feel like you're onto something but
you suck.
Dude,
we all sucked.
Everybody does not have your first
time.
Is that usually the best to within the
next 10 times,
but some people get an extra charisma
bump to that.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
Like I bet you the first set of like
Bill Hicks,
Eddie Murphy.
Yes.
Yeah.
Spade started really early.
Rock started really early,
like those guys were probably were,
you know,
very decent their first time out,
just because you know that it's that
charismatic personality.
Well,
I was talking about he has,
who is one of my favorite comedians of
all time.
Joey Joey is in my opinion,
he's at a just sheer laugh out loud,
fall down moments.
He's provided me with the most,
if any human being ever.
And Joey was not that good when I met
him.
He was not that good on stage.
He just couldn't do it.
It was a real weird thing.
I don't know what it was.
He's just a hilarious dude.
I mean he's hilarious talking about
anything but he maybe he couldn't focus
it into setup punchline kind of maybe.
I don't know what it was or bins turned
a fucking corner man and I don't
remember when it was,
but our,
it was,
it was actually,
I don't,
I don't know,
maybe maybe three,
four years in.
I don't know what it was,
three,
four years in o and m,
he turned this fucking corner and just
started destroying.
Wavy just became more himself.
Yeah.
Oh,
he definitely did.
He,
he just learned to be relaxed on stage.
He just eat,
you know,
I asked him what happened and he was
like,
I just stopped giving a fuck.
Yeah,
yeah.
He said,
I stopped giving a fuck.
Yeah.
Not trying too many things,
too many people telling them what to do.
And he was like,
fuck you,
I'm going to do it my way.
And when he did that,
boom,
he was awesome.
But when he was trying to make everybody
happy,
he just couldn't.
He couldn't,
he couldn't really be himself,
you know,
himself as the,
I don't give a fuck guy that tells the
funny stories in the back of the comedy
store and that's the guy that we all
knew and loved.
But then on stage he figured out how to
do it and that was,
you know,
that's,
that's the most dramatic at,
of my life of seeing someone go from not
being good to being really good.
Joe Is the most dramatic.
Oh,
I got it.
I got my most dramatic one.
Who was Doug Stanhope?
Doug Stanhope wasn't good in the
beginning.
Well,
you know,
he was,
I don't know how raw he was when I saw
him.
He was,
what year was this?
Oh man,
a long time ago.
It was like a,
it was back when,
you know,
Steve Sherpa was still physically there
at the Riviera comedy club and it was
maybe even still an Improv at that
point.
And I was one of two.
I always wanted to feature acts with
this other guy named Tom Martin knew now
he writes on simpsons and stuff and the
headliner was hugh fink and Doug
Stanhope was the host,
the Mc for like one of those crazy weeks
where you do two shows a night for seven
nights and uh,
and crowds were starting to get smaller
than,
you know,
like the kind of the vegas comedy boom
was starting to fade a little bit and
Sherpa would just yell at him every
night,
you know,
he was like that weeks punching bag and
what was just yelling at him.
But he was,
it was just Doug Stanhope.
Well,
just,
you know,
being laid,
bringing,
bringing a girl into the showroom
without asking ahead of time and like,
like triple just,
you know,
it happened to me a few times.
He just sort of picks one person to sort
of pick on to kind of establish to the
group that you can't get away with
anything.
But Doug,
like a super,
super good kid,
you know,
nice guy.
I was a few years older than him and
thought I really had it under control
and the three of us,
we just all that we're working with
them,
we just all sort of thought,
oh,
you know,
we'll see what happens with him because
it's,
his act was just like,
he was just like anybody's,
like,
just somebody trying to do is stand back
and not.
I think he,
Stan hope really turned a corner when he
just started talking about his own
experiences instead of trying to say,
do you ever notice that he's not an
observational comic?
I mean,
there's observations within what he's
talking about because these stories are
so interesting and he saw such a funny
guy.
Well,
when you're young it's like,
what do you have to really talk about?
Said that.
Like,
I remember he had this one bit where he
would talk about.
He would talk about,
uh,
he would describe how nasty a egg roll
is and how much he doesn't like egg
rolls and it's like as an audience
member,
you know,
maybe 50,
70 percent of the audience loves
eggrolls.
So then it was just kind of like,
you just kind of sit there going,
well,
this,
you know,
he's got to figure out,
uh,
you know,
he's either got to have more of a
personal take on why they're bad to
convince us or he's got to drop that
because,
you know,
egg rolls are awesome,
they're delicious.
You.
It's just like,
he was like,
they're filled with mulch.
I remember that was one of his punch
punch slides was just the word mulch.
You know,
how like the weirdest thing stick out
when you work with somebody for like a
week.
Like there's some sentence or thing that
they talked about that you remember.
And I always remember that,
but I've always,
you know,
I've known him ever since then.
He never,
you know,
he just kept plowing away and became,
such a powerful,
funny comic like himself found himself
then became himself.
Yeah,
totally.
And you know,
again,
kind of had like sort of a hook of being
like the guy that's going to talk about,
you know,
some pretty horrifying things
with Doug Stanhope business.
The real deal,
he's legit does and hope really is that
guy.
He really does live in a crazy house,
is painted weird colors,
growing crazy house.
She really is on all sorts of fucking
crazy pills.
Joe,
remember,
awesome American flag out there.
Yeah,
dude ass.
I was there when he was still have
homeless people live on his fucking
front lawn like Arizona,
Utah.
He's in business.
Well,
should I even say goes everywhere he
does.
He's lives in Arizona,
but he tours and puts on his own,
like he kinda,
you know.
Yeah,
it does.
It does.
He tours like a Rockstar,
like he goes to town to town.
Doug had a fucking house that was
painted like an American flag in Venice
and we would go party at his house.
When we were doing the man show,
he rented this House that was literally
a fucking American flags and it was
right on the street and he had the
little fenced in area in the front.
He would let homeless people stay there,
so he had this homeless couple that was
staying there and the fucking woman
stabbed the man and they got a video of
her looking at her hands because she had
blood on her hands from the guy she
stabbed and she was.
She had like an accent and she was like,
I'm a company.
Come from my whole,
I'm a,
I'm a whore.
She kept saying something,
something.
I'm a client,
I'm a whore,
and she was looking at.
It was dark dude and this is all on Doug
Stanhope been lost.
He was so crazy.
I was like,
dude,
you're hanging out with people who are
like probably like severely imbalanced.
It's not just a matter of them being
homeless like the.
A lot of the homeless people that you
find on the streets are really people
that were kicked out of mental
institutions,
you know,
or got out of mental institutions that
didn't have anybody to take care of them
and there's a lot of crazy people
or just lost their mind randomly and
didn't,
didn't fit in slowly
but surely eroded until that was their
reality.
Their reality was there.
The rats of society.
You know,
that's funny that I brought,
when I brought dug up,
I totally,
I totally skipped that whole,
that you guys did a show together thing
like I talking,
I knew you knew who he was because he's
so funny.
But I was talking about it like,
you know,
yeah.
You know,
we both know who Doug Stanhope,
but you actually really know the guy.
Like I just run into them here and there
over the years and we've always been
friendly and I just recently just told
them when you're in La,
you know,
let me know because I want him on my
podcast.
He's been on this right?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
He's awesome.
He's a funny.
He's really doing it too.
And his episode of Louis Ck show was
great.
Yeah.
That was weird seeing him like that,
wasn't it?
Yeah.
But also it's interesting,
amalgam of,
you know,
what he's really like.
And then some,
you know,
some things that,
Louis just wrote for him to play that,
you know,
we're,
I guess Louis just sort of,
you know,
rounding out the character in a dramatic
way because I don't know if I don't,
I doubt Doug's ever gone to Louis and
said I'm going to kill myself.
Right.
It's been nice.
It's been nice knowing you
those not going to do that,
unless that was wrong.
And then he would do that.
Who is,
he lived.
Totally.
Hunter s Thompson himself,
a hunter.
S Thompson was done,
man.
He had hip replacement.
Surgery was in constant pain and he
couldn't walk,
couldn't swim.
He was fucked up man.
And he didn't like living life like that
and he was 60 something years old and he
was like,
that's it.
Boom.
Checkout time,
you know?
And he decided to do it that way.
Doug would do that,
you think?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
He would do that.
That's what I take bats.
Yeah.
Make sure he's okay.
You know what?
What's the alternative?
Let it slowly run out of batteries.
Die In the corner.
I don't know,
man.
Exactly the alternative vaporizer
coming.
Um,
it's probably heated up by now.
Well,
it still says read on it.
I think that's a nice special effect to
me.
I mean,
how long do you think we've been talking
for?
Twenty minutes.
An hour and five minutes.
No Way.
That's ridiculous.
This podcast is to easy,
Doug.
You're not.
Casting is so much fun.
It's so much fun.
It's the most fun thing we've ever done,
you know,
as far as like the most honest
connection with people,
you know,
and you just sit there and talk and for
people like that,
they're like working right now.
You know,
I,
I think it's the coolest thing ever.
I'm so happy that we can do something
like this.
You know,
entertainers want to entertain,
you know,
I mean comics want to be funny,
people want to talk.
It's,
we love doing it,
you know?
So the fact that it's such an honest
relationship,
we love doing it.
We put it out there,
it's free,
boom.
People enjoy it.
It's such a great relationship.
You know what I'm saying?
You creating friends all over the place,
that's what you're doing,
you know,
and that's the people that come out to
see you at the,
at the comedy clubs.
They're friends now because I just,
just this last weekend,
funny because I was in Arizona in
flagstaff and then um,
Phoenix and uh,
I didn't know I was going to be doing
the show this week,
you know,
I thought,
oh,
I'll be on again at some point.
You know,
I,
I figured I'd be back here on the show,
but I didn't know you called me like
yesterday or the day before and we set
this up.
So last weekend there's about,
there's about,
over the course of a couple of shows,
there's probably about a good 10,
15 people who said to me,
go on Joe show again or I want to hear
you on Joe show again.
And I was just like,
yeah,
don't worry about it.
It'll happen.
And they're probably right now being
like,
what the fuck he was going to be on the
couple of days later.
We don't really schedule this thing and
advanced folks.
We'd keep this bitches organic as
possible.
But also you're dealing with
the schedules have,
you know,
I mostly have your comedian friends,
they're all in and out of town and have
shit to do.
Well,
this is what the coolest thing about it
is that,
you know,
most of us are around.
If we're around,
we're around like the days we do the
podcast,
like Tuesday,
Thursday,
and now it really has an impact on,
on guys gigs too.
Especially Duncan.
Duncan's getting like some fucking sweet
gigs.
He's getting an pack in places.
Man Dunkin sold out his first show ever
in Seattle and he was tripping out.
It's like
the fuck man.
That's awesome.
He brought back little Hobo puppet thing
that he does the Hobo love.
I love the new dol itself,
you mean?
Yeah,
it's awesome.
It's little Hobo is one of my all time
favorite bits and people either get it
or they don't get it,
but either way it's fun for me.
I love it.
Oh yeah.
When they don't get angry in comedy.
It's so funny.
Well,
if they get uncomfortable,
sometimes it's even more fun.
You know,
just dumped shit.
Fucking send some,
you know,
he says some dark shit in that bit.
I don't want to kill any of his
punchlines.
Yeah,
don't talk about that.
There's a lot of people that hear that
and get what?
He got.
A bunch of people walk out on him and
Atlanta.
Georgia.
Are you serious?
Yeah.
Christian couple got up and left.
He talking,
talking about Jesus onstage.
Hey Man.
People have their beliefs.
They don't want you to fucking with
their beliefs.
They didn't come to a comedy show to get
change.
God dammit.
They came to a comedy show to laugh.
Did you ever can't make everybody laugh?
You're no good.
Mr Comedian she ever had family reunions
growing up like,
like,
no.
You met at a park with other parts of
families that you didn't know you were
connected to at all and like these like,
wait,
that's your second cousin to the left
and you're like,
what the fuck?
I'm related to that person now that you
recall?
Yeah,
New Jersey.
I guess when I was real young we did
have a few of those.
I was really young when I was before I
was sick so I barely remember it like
you said it and it makes me like have
little flashes that might not even be
real know they were put in there,
but I talk about this on stage which is
true.
I remember one vivid moment when I was
young because everybody was mad at me
because I hit my cousin with a bag of
cookies and everybody was mad because
the cookies went flying and I remember
the cookie of looking at the cookies and
the dirt and shit.
I fucked up but I was like four and
people were angry at me and I remember
that.
It's amazing that they.
That there could be even a semi vivid
memory.
I mean,
when you say like I have a vivid memory
of it,
what does really mean?
How much are you extrapolating?
How much are you,
how much are you exaggerating?
How vivid is it real?
It was big enough in the first place to
some form of it his and sometimes like
because that's the thing that's crazy to
me.
It's like whenever somebody remembers a
ton of stuff from when they were little,
I'm always kind of baffled by that.
I think it's almost like they're just
sort of taking what they kind of
remember and then just going ahead and
filling out the story.
Exactly.
I think that is a lot of what happens.
I don't think our memories and I fucking
good and I think they don't understand
really where memory is stored.
You know,
the,
the issue with memory and the brain is
that they believed that every seven
years virtually every cell in the body
has regenerated and reborn in new.
So there's a new version,
like in seven years.
Every cell is different than the seven
years before except the neurons.
And so they don't know if that memory is
stored somehow in the neurons or if it's
just sort of handed down like files.
Like every seven years you got a new
administration comes in and goes,
look,
this is the past,
this is the uncle that fuck them.
This is the thing that happened in
second grade.
This is the car accident.
All this is,
you've got to remember this.
So you got it,
got it.
And then they take it and then seven
years later out,
have pockets of things you don't
remember or the things you remembered at
one point and don't remember anymore.
I,
I hold at episodes of my life.
I don't remember.
I watched like an old fear factory run.
I had no recollection of any of it.
And it was only 10 years ago and I'm
watching.
I don't remember this.
I don't remember this happening.
This is weird.
I have the two earliest memories I have
when is breaking a pickle jar at a
grocery store?
Like one of the huge and it just
remember
it being scary.
I remember like doing it and stuff like
that.
And falling in,
I guess,
I think it was like two or three when it
happened and the other one is getting
attacked by a bunch of chickens at this
farm.
And I got picked.
I think I've said that before where I
got back and I have a scar in between my
nose because I was near a chicken nest.
Eat Chicken every day,
but fried chicken every day with one
hand on my Dick.
Right.
But both of those memories I remember,
like I remember that happening.
I remember the pickle jar.
I remember being attacked by chickens,
but I don't remember it in first person.
I remember kind of being above and
looking down at myself while my.
Well that's the files you've got handed
down the third person view with those
both stories that uh,
the family liked to tell.
Like remember we know that huge pickle
jar.
Not really.
Like every time I bring it up to my mom,
she has no idea.
She has no idea.
I have to like remember.
And then she goes,
that wasn't an important file for her
when she was.
She didn't need to remember that.
Yeah.
That's brutal when your parents don't
remember important shit that happened to
you and that's a big thing like breaking
a pickle jar.
Come on by.
Poor little brian could have been dead
to the fell on the sharpest point of
that.
It could be the over.
Yeah.
He could have died.
Right?
If it cut me night,
I almost fell off a cliff.
I almost fell off a cliff in San
Francisco.
I was like,
yeah,
am I grabbed up?
My father grabbed me at the very last
second.
He's your angel.
Yup.
Yeah,
some cliffs,
San Francisco.
Some little areas we walk like down near
the beach that are really kind of
sketchy.
You know,
there's some areas we could fall down
and really fuck yourself up,
man.
You could die.
Yeah.
The whole.
That whole Pacific coast highway is so
immensely fucking beautiful but so scary
given drive that,
that,
that the pch.
Francisco was that wild?
Doesn't that make your balls just tingle
like their crackling like they have?
What does that say?
Stuff?
The snap pop rocks.
Remember pop rocks that would do to your
mouth.
That's what makes your balls feel like
when you're going around the whole
Pacific coast highway,
looking at that fucking cliff,
that fucking drop that's right there,
right there,
and it's forever and the ground moves
around this bitch all the time.
It's like you're essentially playing a
game of musical chairs.
You're just hoping you can get from this
point to that point where the really
thin fucking outcropping that you're a
little metal boxes driving around with
nothing to stop you from just driving
right the fuck off the thing into the
ground and the rocks in the ocean.
You never drive it in a storm.
Oh my God.
You did iop.
Yeah.
I've had situations where like,
you know,
where it's like a,
the waves are crashing up on it.
I was,
I was stone cold sober.
it was a sunny day.
Um,
I was wide awake and I was still
shitting my pants.
I was like,
this is a crazy drive man.
It's weird to look at.
It's just a mind fuck.
It's a mind fuck that just a little,
you know,
or someone's coming at you,
you're trusting this other asshole that
you don't even know to not be texting
right now to not be fingering himself.
You know your tampons with Paulina
asleep.
All of those at one of those at once.
Everything tsunami of bad luck coming
your way and you're on the left hand
lane.
You get bumped off into the fucking
great blue yonder of the ocean floor.
Fuck man.
That's a crazy way to drive.
You know,
I would like to.
I like to have less worry about death in
my drawer.
Driving is always scary to me.
I mean just today I was driving,
there was fucking like a sandbag truck
overturned or something like that and
they're just sandbags everywhere in the
highway out of nowhere.
Like you're just driving all these sand
bags.
Dude,
I hit a fucking one of those railroad
ties,
those iron things.
What are those?
The tracks.
Not at tire track.
Section of track.
Someone had dropped on the fucking
highway.
I was driving and I saw it last minute.
I saw this thing and I was like,
oh fuck.
Like I remember gripping with both
hands.
There's no way I could turn if I tried
to turn out what I would have flipped
the car,
you know,
it was just too close and I hit it and I
got the car launched into the air,
the carwash and blew the fucking tires
right off the rims.
Like the bolt,
I think at least one of them,
like literally was shredded and I drove
on rims to the next exit and got out and
just called the tow truck and had it
dealt with.
But it was a spooky moment.
Man.
I hit that fucking thing.
I sought last minute.
I'm like,
Oh fuck,
that's metal.
You know,
it's like that thing fucking.
Oh my God.
It's not lucky.
It didn't.
You know,
sometimes when you drive over something
too,
like you can,
you can rip out the bottom of your car,
you know,
it could come up and it can go into the
bottom of your car and can drop a tranny
real easy.
Fuck yeah.
I just wanted to say that in adult life,
a dropped his tranny in highschool guys
are blow their fucking their
transmission apart,
doing donuts.
There was a common thing guys would fuck
up their trainees.
We'd hear him driving the next day here,
the transmission best find clank,
clank,
clank clank because guys were doing
smoke shows.
It's San Diego.
When I was in high school there was
this,
there was this street where it was kind
of like a San Francisco style street
where it went down,
it went pretty steep and then straight
for just a bit and then steep again and
you could fuck in.
You could get air and you know,
if you want it to going down.
And so we would intentionally drive fast
enough to get the car up into the air.
And it was like,
it's the dumbest thing you could do.
Most people don't know,
but we all got away with it because,
you know,
everyone just did it a few times.
The dukes of Hazzard,
I believe you ever fuck your car.
Um,
did you ever break it?
W W one time on another hill driving
with some friends as a joke,
I,
uh,
or as a joke,
I just,
for
whatever reason I was gonna I was trying
to throw the car in neutral and I throw
it into reverse while going know quickly
downhill.
Oh my fucking noise at that made with.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
I immediately had to just pull the car
over and,
you know,
get it,
get it towed and get it fixed and just
exploded your transmission.
I,
yeah,
just really they shouldn't be able to go
there.
It shouldn't be able to go into reverse
that.
You shouldn't be able to do that.
But it was like an old.
It was like an AMC Hornet.
Oh.
And uh,
it was,
it was pretty dumb why you're going in
for direction.
Isn't there a way to engineer some sort
of a way that doesn't just think you
can't anymore?
I don't think you are.
Yeah.
You have to kind of,
you move it to the side,
you know,
it's almost like a stick shift where you
have to kind of a medicine bottle or cut
into each each level or whatever.
But you know,
I was a kid,
teenager,
you a silly,
goofy,
odd,
did so much silly shit when I was a kid.
It's amazing.
The kids should be allowed to drive
cars.
Oh,
it's so now when I'm driving around and
if I get cut off by somebody that looks
like they're 15,
16.
I was just like such assholes.
Like also when I was that age I,
I was an asshole driver,
but I didn't have all I had was maybe an
occasional fast food from the driving.
I didn't have texting,
you know,
I didn't have headphones on or all,
all the,
all the distractions of today and now I
can't believe that there's any,
there's anywhere in a car that has a,
a,
you know,
a TV.
There's not like,
there's not like a limo that's being
driven by a professional.
You know what I mean?
Like,
just even if you have your kids in the
backseat watching some shit on TV,
wouldn't that be an extra distraction
that.
No,
it's the opposite dangerous or you just
like how focused it makes the kids to
kids zone out for kids are done.
But why do you.
But you definitely don't need a TV up,
up above the rear view mirror.
No,
that's stupid.
That's ridiculous.
You can't see that's,
that's how it is.
And I rented a car,
um,
I rented a who was an escalator
navigator,
one of those and that's what the TV was.
The TV would come down in the center and
they would block the view.
You,
you couldn't see,
you look over your rear view or like a,
you know,
to watch it when you're not in motion,
you're supposed to watch an emotion
because the kids,
you know,
that's when,
that's one of the tunes amount,
but the better ones are on the headsets
and now they have them on the headsets
where you can have a.
each one is watching a different thing
so they can watch their headphones.
When you have limited time,
you got a three and a half year old.
That's the perfect shit.
They just zonked out.
No more questions.
It's just a watch.
Dora the explorer and they have a good
old fucking time so they don't even mind
driving.
You know,
they don't mind driving because driving
for them it's like going to the movies
they have like cool little dvds they
watch and they have a good time and the
dvds you can get like little educational
ones.
So it's actually good for them.
I love them.
Watch like,
you know there's like your kid can read
and shit.
Kids are going to be way smarter today
than we were.
We didn't get access to anything until
we were fucking.
It's gonna be cool in the future.
I bet you the babies
are going to be so smart at such a young
age that they're going to be able to
drive cars for you.
So they're going to be like,
as a kid,
being able to see the babies,
then we're going to be able to drive for
you firing of the mine where you didn't
think about that at all.
Babies out of the womb,
we're just going to drive.
You never know they could drive everyone
around.
Driving is gonna be so easy because it's
all going to have magnets around your
whole car that they just have to push
one button for like on or sign.
You're such a silly man.
Such a silly mad,
you know?
Why do,
why do you want more babies?
I need more drivers.
I need more people driving me around
that I don't ever see and knowing no one
wouldn't want to have sex with.
It would just be a matter of,
yeah,
life experience,
but you have full intelligence right
away.
He just needed life experience.
So we make you work as a driver for the
first years.
People are going to be a DM or smarter.
They're going to be in some areas
they're going to be dumber because some
things are going to become obsolete.
Like you're not going to ever need to
know a phone number.
Math maybe,
but hopefully people will adaptation,
right?
I mean that's what's going on.
We're adapting to this new environment.
We're adapting to these new needs.
You know,
it's unquestionably something's
happening and we're getting to a
symbiotic relationship with technology,
but can you imagine how much space in
your brain is available that would 15,
20 years ago be full of phone numbers
that you don't need to remember anymore,
but don't you remember a lot of
different things now?
Don't you think that you have a lot of
information that you get through the
Internet that probably would never get
before?
You know,
a lot of people,
it was difficult for them to be
stimulated in the days before the
Internet,
but today there's not a time in the
world where I'm in an airport that has
wifi.
We're on board yet,
but you know,
I love.
I love the airport wife.
You know what I'm saying?
Will you just sit there and you can
either goof around or get stuff done,
but either way you're killing the time.
You're.
Yeah,
you're,
you know,
you're enjoying yourself.
You're actually having a good time.
You're getting entertained,
but you are also using a different than
some people
use the internet.
A lot of people just go in there and
play cards and talk about video games.
I have
a say if you have a,
an hour to kill and you were at the
airport,
you know,
you log on your favorite video game for
them and you find out what the hell's
going on.
It's entertaining and then listen to
podcasts.
It's um,
it's very,
it's a very interesting,
like a progression to try to like look
ahead too.
It's like what the fuck is this going to
go next?
Like what does the next symbiotic
relationship between human beings and
technology?
Because the cell phone is pretty much a
part of your body.
So what's next phase?
People having sex.
You really think it's actual fake
people.
Flashlights that have emotions.
It's the fucking same emotions.
You can turn it off the emotions that
would get people dick hard.
I do like porn where this seems to be
having fun more than porn.
Whereas people seem to be,
you know,
I just watched the other day that was
just random.
People like watching porn where people
fight and then they fuck.
And then when they fuck the,
like,
you know,
get back at each other and then resolve
their issues through fucking like people
liked those.
They like videos like that when people
were actually angry at each other
because that's when they have their best
sucks.
A lot of people have the best sex they
ever have.
It's makeup sex.
Like this girl that will like.
I firmly believe they have learned to
start fights so that the man will step
in,
are you with them for a little bit?
Then they resolve everything they make
up.
They say they love you and then they
fuck.
And they love it and they have like
super extra charge fucking.
So I think they start problems and men
and women I'm sure because they like a
store.
It's why women can read a pornographic
things and men need to see them.
It's women like the story the women
liked what leads up to having the
foreplay sold.
They like drama crazy for you like it to
have a beginning,
middle and end.
And then the and has to go on for longer
than we want it to.
Have you ever thought what it would be
like to be a woman for a day or every 10
years that microwave with the
cantaloupe?
Dang.
Brian's life would be not much
different.
He would just be a lesbian.
No,
I,
I've said this before where when I was
younger I would like look at my boobs
and act like they were real boobs and
then try to kiss him,
but that's about as close as to.
That's the question though.
If you're.
Are you a girl for a day?
Who wants cock?
Are you a girl for a day and go for the
whole experience?
Oh,
I wish you'd get fucked too.
I wouldn't want the.
I would probably be interesting to feel
what it would feel like to get fucked,
but I couldn't do the memory is a dick
in me.
Yeah.
And in your mouth to stop.
No,
no.
Thanks.
Mentioned period would be like,
I'm a girl for a day.
I'm going to convert to being a.
don't they say Jewish girls don't don't
like to blow.
No.
Jewish girls love to do it.
That's crazy nonsense.
I love it.
Oh wait,
isn't there some sort of girls that
don't don't like to blow dudes or is
that just girls in general?
I don't know.
It's just always going to be dudes
complaining because that's what.
That's what's fun about porn that you
can't often get a girl that you're just
hooking up with or whatever in porn that
they often act like it's the most
delicious thing could have.
So I know most girls are just started
like just doing,
just doing what they gotta do to get it
over with.
Some girls know,
some girls love Derek.
You've got to find them.
You know why it's kind of gross of a
girl sucking your cock and she doesn't
want to.
Doesn't want to like wants to please
you,
but also doesn't think it's the most
delicious thing.
She's like eating pussy.
Don't get any posts.
I do,
I love it.
But how could anybody think I love the
pleasing the person is or maybe a little
sense of control is the most important
part than then
how it tastes and looks and feels.
Those are all good too,
but you know,
I think that it's more like,
it's just fun.
It's just fun to,
you know,
because that's a great way to please a
woman,
Doug Benson and putting it out there,
bitches as,
as you will.
How often do you eat out,
have,
you know,
whenever it's there,
whenever the time is right,
maybe some brunch will be some happy
hour
maybe after dinner as eating.
What does that mean?
Eating ass licking a girl's asshole
don't like that.
I love when people,
when you talk about something and they
go,
yeah,
and then they say,
no,
don't do that.
I did.
It's awesome.
Frenching it.
That's a no,
but that's an immediate reaction.
You know when someone says,
yeah,
I don't think so.
You know,
it's like that's what that same Dusky
guy should have said when they asked him
why you were attracted to young boys.
Yeah,
I don't think so.
No.
Instead he's like,
he repeated like asked me again if I eat
a lot of ass.
Are you,
do you eat a lot of ass too?
I eat a lot of.
No,
I don't eat a lot of.
It was the world's greatest athlete.
That's a world champion.
Well,
the stacks of theater don't eat enough.
This should totally be trophies for the
best
assay eating.
That's a God damn adventure.
You can get trophies for parasailing.
Who should get trophies for ass eating.
Why not asking in contests?
What if the world were free and we
weren't so worried about things.
Pornography could be judged on the
merits of technique.
Zero percent toilet paper in the ass is
always important.
That's very important.
Toilet paper when you,
when you go down on a girl and you find
toilet paper just dangling off her ass
and so disturbing that it's probably one
of the things that keeps me out of that,
out of that region.
It's just could backfire.
I had back in so it's not ruin anything.
I don't want her to be upset.
I get a little stubble.
It's like essentially,
you know,
it's like a little bit of sandpaper.
You rubbed some toilet paper on some
sandpaper.
You're gonna leave some residue.
Do you like stuff in your ass?
No.
You said that.
I'm actually very scared.
I was like,
this is the end of a long conversation
like stuffing your ass.
I'm very scared of my ass.
I don't know if I told her.
It's just,
it's good I guess in my diet.
That's good.
Your meat diet,
how often are you vegetables?
I eat them every day,
but that's just,
I don't know what you should do is what
I do and I just need to get on,
get on the Kale shakes.
I'm telling you.
It's not that delicious,
but I don't mind eating Kale so much.
I kind of picked that up every once in a
while.
Like the whole foods or something like
along with the.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Not Bad,
but a shake of Kevin James turned me
onto this shit and um,
he started doing it in the lost like 80
pounds when he's doing essentially
takes cucumbers,
Kale,
celery,
this,
how I do it,
cucumbers,
Kale,
celery,
and I put a chunk of ginger in there
too.
And a whole pear ginger anymore.
It drives me crazy.
I think.
I hate gender like that.
I like to put some gas in there.
Yeah,
pull the last name.
I like the sting of ginger.
I like that.
Yeah,
it's very spicy,
but I liked that it's good for you and
so anyway,
I blend it all up in this vitamix thing.
You ever see a vitamix?
It's like a mixer designed to to
pulverize it.
It's not really juicing because it's
just chopping the living fuck out of all
these vegetables until it's like a soup
and then you drink this soup and it's
fucking.
It's not bad.
It doesn't taste bad.
It's just sort of a task and you lose
weight because you're losing weight,
vegetables and there's no other feeling
bad.
You feel it's a giant serving of
vegetables,
like much more vegetables probably than
you would ever really eat.
Oh yeah.
You have to force myself to eat.
Most of it can eat like six giant leaves
of Kale,
10 stalks of Celery,
a whole cucumber.
It's rare that you would eat that many
vegetables in one sitting.
You could do it,
but this is even better because it's
completely taken the whole chewing down
process out.
So you're.
You're digesting it,
you're swallowing it,
and it's like just incinerated,
just chopped up into little tiny pieces
and it's like really easily absorbed by
your body and your shit's magnifical.
The shits become easier because.
So lubed up to though do your whole
system is just whenever you have.
If you have a steak later,
it slides out like a Toboggan for your
vitamix Joe.
This is a late night drink,
like with some food vodka,
ice,
a red seedless grapes,
like a lot of red seat lit,
scrapes and a little bit to apples and
it's,
it's a,
it's kind of like grape Fyedka,
but like it's got a little bit of a
texture to it.
It's cool.
Wow,
I love that.
That's a great idea.
So you make like a little smoothing mega
little smitty and if you,
if you have any,
uh,
not,
um,
what's that sweetener that's made out of
a cactus or something like that?
If you have any of that,
put that in there.
Dva?
Yeah.
You can use to Gaba.
Gaba,
I use the Gaba.
Gaba is not so good for you.
It's why not?
I don't know.
I read that somewhere I need to research
that somebody had said that a Gaba is
not good for you.
I think like any artificial sweeteners,
so it's,
it's a,
they make a tequila out of it.
Yeah.
But it's a plant is a plant and it's a
real sweet plant and you know,
that's uh,
somehow or another they make to kill out
of that process.
So that word a lot associated with.
I made lemonade the other day with it,
with the garbage.
It was really delicious,
but I was drinking.
I was like,
it's probably not so good for you.
Why?
No?
Stevia is supposed to be good for you,
but Stevia to me is not like a real
sweet taste.
It's like a trick.
Sweet.
Yeah.
It's like a,
almost like an aspirin.
What was that old shit?
Sweet
and lows.
Sweet and low hip.
Funky fucking.
It was kind of sweet,
but kind of funky.
I kinda like it better than,
than any other.
But the problem I have is they need to
have it at more places.
Like starbucks seems like it should have
starbucks.
I don't think people.
I think it's a taste issue.
I don't prefer the taste of it.
I think it's probably something you can
get used to,
but I don't like and things.
I don't mind.
Things being not sweet,
you know what I mean?
Like coffee.
I don't want coffee,
sweetened,
iced tea,
iced tea.
I just drink it,
you know?
Yeah.
I don't put any extra shit into pretty
much anything really.
You want your health,
do you?
What?
Do you take care of herself?
I go through periods that are,
you know,
can go up and down.
No,
I don't think I've ever eaten.
Kick in bed.
Never.
I don't think so.
What about in the tub?
I don't think I've ever eaten food in
the tub.
That's the cat in the hat.
Comes back.
He kicked in the tub and it becomes a
mess.
That motherfucker to paraphrase it that
way.
When you read that to your children,
this is my kids' favorite stories.
They're fun because I get into them or
get into the cat in the hat once
brilliantly written stuff.
Frog and toad.
You got to get them in the frog and
toad.
Okay.
That's the best.
Remember that frog and toad frog and
attend that live together and they were
sort of vaguely remember that or they
were trying to cross the highway and you
have to.
It was cool.
Get into the lily pads.
That's frogger.
It's weird that a frog would hang with
the toad the other different yet.
So this lucky frogs a little.
Those cons.
You know how he will be.
If they're big,
they'll just be taking kids right out of
your arm and you seen big frog.
They're pretty big.
I mean big like real big like dog size.
The frogs were huge.
They eat babies and was about a frog
recent researching frogs long time ago
because of that,
licking frogs and so I got really into
frogs and they have pac man frog.
He received PAC man frogs or mouth's
open up like PAC man.
Frog is a ruthless motherfuckers.
You know,
they.
They were like my.
Sometimes my might have made that up.
They do those frogs that he dug.
Man.
How about the fact that people take
frogs and they get high with them?
That's why I was researching frogs
because frogs off Ebay a long time.
I got to something like that.
You can buy that.
I don't know if they've made a frog
illegal yet.
What is the frog that does it?
The frog.
It producers five Meo DMT is really
incredibly potent.
Helis engine and will you do is you take
this frog and the skin excretes like
some sort of a white milky substance and
you do it on a window of a car so that
it's in the sun or anything glass that's
outside glass coffee table.
You secrete it and then when it dries
off,
you scrape it with a razor blade and it
becomes a white powder.
You put it in something,
you freebase it and you blast off.
Yeah.
Welcome to the center of the universe
provided by a frog.
Do you think that's why they ended up
what?
I was going to be a bunch of frogs on us
because we're all going to start
tripping off these frogs because it's
going to be frogs everywhere and then
we're going to go into this Dm.
Treaties are likely.
That's tripping off of how justice
hallucinogen Hallucinogen,
hallucinogen hallucinogen.
That's the correct agenda is what I'm
used to it as well.
It's like nuclear or new cuellar.
You're going to have options.
Other options.
If I said nuclear,
would you correct?
It's like authentically often nuclear
coupon and coupon nuclear bombs,
nuclear bombs.
I don't think I are correct.
You out loud.
I would just assume.
I know.
I just assumed you were gonna you know
like you hear in both ways so often.
Like if all the dumb things that George
Bush said and did that one to me it was
like,
well,
but a lot of people say it the wrong
way,
so you just get used to it.
It's just like old expressions that now
people say I'm the wrong the wrong way.
With English.
People write things different.
They right there.
Correct.
Tires is t y r e S.
I kept seeing that written an English
magazine.
I was like,
why is the world world?
It's spelled w r o l d instead of w o r,
l,
D,
real world.
It's pronounced wrong.
Wrong.
Did you just make that up?
I always get,
I say world and everyone gives me shift.
So you make that up.
No,
it's not spelled war.
Made that up.
Yes.
You motherfucker.
Color color.
They have and color.
Yeah.
There's a bunch of different.
It's funny when you reading tweets,
you don't even have to look to see where
the person's from.
When it's got those things in it.
Well they also say cheers mate,
and they always say,
you're a legend isn't legend's mate.
You're a legend.
Right?
I think that's just huge.
Joe Calls Me and says,
you are a legend.
I love that expression.
The love that they love,
they love.
Brilliant.
It's a brilliant,
brilliant,
great.
That's another one.
They retired and con.
They like to say,
I like how you publicly announced that
when you band people on twitter,
like you're like,
you are banned.
No blurry,
blocked,
blocked.
But sometimes I'm just kidding.
Like sometimes I'll just take some dumb
tweet,
the Kim Kardashian road or something and
I'll say blog or irl,
you know,
somebody will write something to me
that's actually kind of Nice and I'll
write block just to be silly and I'll
write to them and say,
I didn't really block you,
I just,
I just wanted to retweet what you said.
But I also,
I don't like just retweet and
compliments and stuff because I just
think that that's true to compliment
than say blocked.
That's funny because then everybody gets
a lot out of it.
Like,
oh,
he's such an asshole.
That guy that said that nice thing,
you know,
but I just think that like there's just
too much,
too many people that just want,
they're all about getting retweets and
like begging for them and it's just
like,
that's kind of whacked.
The whole retweet thing.
I respond to people as much as I can,
but that,
that is kind of whack.
Yeah,
you're good with people though.
You like answer questions and stuff.
I just get the same questions all the
time.
People always ask me because I follow
for under 20 people.
I thought that'd be funny thing on my
side,
on my page and it says I follow under 20
people,
but then also that's like about how many
people I want to follow.
Like if there's somebody that I'm not
interested in anymore and I want to add
somebody,
I'll drop somebody in ad I just keep it
in 20.
Oh.
Then a lot of people get it right away.
They don't ask to be added because
they're like,
I don't want to ruin your for 20 thing
dude,
but I'd love it if you added me or
whatever,
but do.
Does anybody more connected to the pop
movement and you.
I don't know.
I'm not.
I'm not as political as people might
want me to be about it.
Although I've got some news for you
guys.
I'd love to share with your listeners
slash viewers.
Sure.
In Missouri in 2012,
there's a chance of getting outright
legalization on the ballot.
Really skipping over.
They're skipping over the medical thing.
They just need x number of signatures
and it's not that many.
They just need a certain number of
signatures to get it to happen and they
need the signatures by May.
So if you're in Missouri,
get ahold of like your local normal
chapter,
you know,
nor nrml is,
that's how Brian's always spelled
normal.
How many and uh,
and,
and just make sure you find out where
you can go because it's has to be
physical signatures,
which is the most fucked up thing in
this computer age.
People should be able to sign petitions
now on their computer onlines and some
do like the Conservatives get lots of
good petitions going online,
but for to get on the ballot for
legalization in Missouri,
which I would love because there's a lot
of cities in Missouri that I like and if
I got to go there and know that it was
legal,
it was so much fun.
Well,
you know,
marijuana is legal in Denver pretty
much.
Yeah.
They give you some sort of ticket.
They don't,
they don't.
You're like blowing it on A.
I think it's one of those.
I'm sure you're not supposed to be out
there publicly drinking,
just like you're not supposed to be out
there publicly smoking pot,
but then other people are pretty chill.
Yeah.
Then on stopping people at all,
there's a lot of cities and and you
know,
there's 16 states in Washington dc that
are our medical,
but then a lot of cities it's been,
you know,
kind of because I think it's,
it's been kind of quietly decriminalized
and a lot of places,
a lot of those states though,
it's really hard to get a license.
It's not as easy as it is.
Yeah.
And it's really hard to.
The whole dispensary system isn't in
place,
you know,
and that's the problem currently in
California is that the feds are again
threatening to cut two to basically
close down dispensary's and then the
question is,
well where did the patients,
because they've seen me,
there seemed to be okay with patients at
this point.
Like if you're a medical marijuana
patient,
you should be able to get it,
but where the patient's going to get it,
if they close down the dispensary
because they're supposed to grow their
own or have some sort of concern from
the law enforcement is that there's a
lot of profit being made that is not
supposed to be according to the way the
law is structured.
It's there.
You're not supposed to be able to profit
as much as these people are profiting.
But the bottom line is that should be
the very last thing that law enforcement
is devoting its resources to.
You know,
no one's getting hurt there.
Okay,
so you're all,
your attention should be devoted to
crime.
All your attention should be devoted to
reckless drivers.
Drunk drivers,
crime,
assault,
violent crime associated with marijuana
would go away.
It was like,
oh yeah,
just leave it alone and I swear
everything will be better.
It's really simple.
You know,
there's,
there's other shit to concentrate on,
but I think also that in some cases
places need arrests.
They need to make arrests and it's a
fucking easy collar.
It's not hard.
No one's going to shoot you in your
closing down a pot store,
you know,
you go there,
you bring guys who are dressed like
they're ready to go to war in
Afghanistan and they fucking go in there
with machine guns and they clear
everything out and they take everything.
And it's crazy man.
You know,
the,
the ones that,
uh,
they had an la a few years back where
they had the guys who were,
had blackwater uniforms on,
they had,
there were blackwater guys,
they hired mercenaries to go in there
and clean up and close down these pot
shops.
And you're like,
because of the weirdest rates like in.
So you remember that though?
Do you remember that shit in,
in super high.
We show two different rates and uh,
and one of the biggest laughs in the
movies,
the unfortunately not me speaking.
Uh,
so somebody that's just a,
you know,
a protest or advocate that's hanging
outside of place.
It's being rated a yells at the guys as
they're walking downstairs,
have boxes full of marijuana and money
yells at him.
Go bust a meth lab.
You Pussy.
No Shit,
no shit.
It's so easy,
it's an easy color,
it's weak you,
you know,
it's wrong.
And I'm sure a lot of the guys that are
involved in doing those things,
again,
they're just following orders.
They're just like,
you know,
there's absolutely.
That's the.
I get,
I guess people in law enforcement more
and more saying,
hey to me and winking at me and say I
like your work and stuff and kissing on
the lips.
A lot of making out.
I just,
I just will not.
I just draw the line at eating their
ass.
Don't try that line,
bro.
Sacrifice.
I gotta try it.
I just think of assets as being,
you know,
I just said a very juvenile attitude
towards assets.
Make them do a stripper shower before
and I don't want anything in my ass.
He even as Nice,
soft tongue.
I always say the cops don't get nearly
enough credit and there's a,
there's a divide between the citizens
and the police.
It doesn't have to exist.
It's ridiculous.
They should be supported,
you know,
and people support troops.
But very few people support cops.
There's bad cops for sure,
but it's a small percentage.
We get to see how how good cops are
though,
because we're usually in situations
where it's,
it's sort of,
you know,
especially you like wherever you see a
lot of law enforcement,
that's kind of it.
They're sort of protecting you and you
know,
just being out in public and stuff.
Right.
I don't really have protected me when
I'm out in public.
When,
when they see you,
they're like,
you're a celebrity to them.
So you're like,
the last thing there cops are going to
do is hassle you.
That's true.
But you know,
also when I pulled over when I wasn't
a celebrity,
I'm polite.
You,
you,
you asked me a question?
No Sir.
He asked me for my license.
I gave a true.
It's true.
You respectful.
Yeah.
I,
I've gotten out of a few arrests
situations by just being polite.
Cup knows you're legitimately
respectful,
you know,
they appreciate that.
You know,
like man,
that's the fucking job.
The job is.
We agree that guy gets the gun and the
fucking flashing lights and you listen
to him.
Yes sir.
No Sir.
And that means you're a good citizen and
you're not trying to fucking cause any
trouble.
And in turn he doesn't,
you know,
take advantage of this power that's
presented to him by this willingness for
people to obey.
And he doesn't automatically assume that
everybody owes it to them.
And that's the problem with older cops.
That's the problem with these white
shirt concedes.
He punching people in these occupy Wall
Street crowds.
They,
they think they can punch people.
You know,
there,
there's ones and it's not all of them,
it's just a small fraction of it,
but they feel like they're better than
people.
They feel like they've been older and
people around.
People who have been forced to listen to
them so long that they have a complex.
They've been involved in law enforcement
for 30 years and you have to fucking
listen to them,
you know?
Yeah.
They're bullies.
There are bullies.
You know,
you give people ultimate power,
you're going to get ultimate corruption.
We all know that.
And even though you don't think of that
as corruption,
that has absolutely corruption.
When that guy,
that guy white shirt and the video
punches that chicken the face,
that's fucking corruption.
That is a hundred percent corruption.
That's all.
Somebody told me,
that chick,
that's actually a very feminine man.
Either way I say it's a chick,
chick,
chick like dude.
And the guy punches him right in the
face with a very sloppy overhand right
to it's piss poor technique.
I really was very,
very upset with this video tested
correctly.
No,
no.
I mean just take that video and then do
the play by play.
Like you're doing it for a fight.
Who the fuck taught him how to throw
that right hand and for 102 pound check
she takes it.
Well,
she took it wells,
weak ass punch.
But you know,
the fact that he thought that he could
do that.
I don't care what that person said.
Damn.
You know,
if someone's yelling at you and causing
you calling you names and becoming a
problem and you have to arrest him,
then he fucking arrest them.
You don't have to punch people in the
fucking head.
You Dick.
What do you think about the,
um,
the preponderance of a Taser incidents
and uses of tasers everywhere.
Ridiculous.
Not just tasers.
How about the flash bombs they're
throwing on people?
Did you see that shit?
That was a guy was a wounded vet.
The whole thing is disgusting.
It's really disgusting.
It's like these cops are,
you know,
they're forced everyday to go out there
and try to combat this ever growing
thing that has shows no signs of
weakening in fact shows signs of gaining
momentum and strength.
And that's why all these movements are
being taken to try to squash it and try
to suppress it because they go,
well,
we got to stop this now because right
now it's 30,000
people,
but the fuck do we do in it's 300,000
people out there.
Guess what?
They're going to come through those
doors.
Three hundred thousand people are going
to come through those doors and they're
gonna start throwing people out windows,
you know?
And I don't think they will.
I mean it's not violent.
It hasn't been a violent movement so
far,
but that's what they would do if they
have 300,000
people,
so if you,
if you think of,
if you're like mayor Bloomberg or if
you're,
you know,
on these fucking guys that owned some
giant Hedge Fund and you've made
billions of dollars is raping people
your whole life and then all the sudden
you know,
you picture what you would do if you
were all those people,
you would think those people going to
get me,
they're going to come again in a storm.
The gates,
even if they stay nonviolent,
these people are never gonna accept that
because they're always gonna.
Assume that human nature is always
violence,
so they're going to push these people
back before it ever gets to a point
where they can't control it and that's
why they're there.
Clearing these fucking tense out.
That's where they're trying to.
I guess they had an old library full of
books there too,
and they throw the books away.
What the fuck,
man?
You throw on books away.
That should be against the law.
Okay.
Right there.
That should be a crime in this day of
age and age of ultimate retardation that
we find ourselves in when people are so
fucking dope that you're throwing books
away.
God Damn Man.
You talk about someone who's not working
for the greater good of the people cop
that's throwing books away.
Yeah,
for the worst and all in the name of the
supposedly name of public safety.
So gross.
Well,
you know that chase paid the cops four
point $6,000,000,
made a huge donation to the cops.
Of course.
Isn't that ridiculous?
Everything.
Everything behind everything is is is
money now the money that these people
that are going to try to defeat Obama,
the money,
the millions and millions that they're
raising,
that's all it's going to is just trying
to win an election late.
That's a messed up system.
People are starving.
Those millions of dollars could feed
people and instead they're just putting
somebody else in charge who's not who,
you know,
because Obama,
as much as he seems to try is
ineffective.
Everything's gonna be ineffective.
Whoever,
if he loses,
if he wins,
I think is next for years can be kind of
interesting because he'll kind of have
nothing to fucking lose.
Is that true though,
man?
I hope so.
You know,
I don't buy that anymore because I just
haven't seen any evidence whatsoever
that he has any power at all.
I just,
I don't,
I don't necessarily believe it.
I think they,
there's a whole group of people that
have got him into position and once
those people sit down with them,
they explained to him what they would
like to get done and that's what gets
done.
And that's why Guantanamo Bay still
open.
That's why
still slips through the cracks.
Like there's no,
there's no money interests that wanted
to get rid of.
Don't ask,
don't tell.
And he made that happen.
Yeah.
That's a bone that he through people.
That's the bones go.
It's pretty good.
Yeah.
It's good.
That good?
Yeah.
You know what that means.
That means that gay people are to become
hired killers too.
Yay.
The fuck kind of advancement is that.
Well,
they can,
you know,
gay people,
it's not,
it's not that I'm and I'm,
I'm 100 percent not anti soldier
whatsoever.
The show I am for the soldiers would I'm
not for is the people that tell the
soldiers what to do.
Every fucking army needs soldiers.
Every nation needs an army because guess
what?
Human nature is what it is.
There's a lot of bad fucking people in
the world.
What makes me sick is when bad people
take good soldiers and make them do bad
shit,
and they do that for their own good.
So it's not that I'm against soldiers.
I'm 100 percent for soldiers,
soldiers.
Those are people that understand.
What I'm not for is the people that put
soldiers in situations where the
soldiers think they're doing the right
thing because they're following orders.
They think they're doing the right thing
because they're going after guys who
look like bad guys,
but the big question ever gets answered,
what the fuck are you doing there in the
first place?
You think you're doing the right thing.
What the fuck are you doing there in the
first place?
You're going to stop another nine slash
11.
Those guys are dead.
They're all dead.
The guys who did it are dead.
This is how you stop it.
You don't.
Don't let that happen,
but I can get everybody over here.
Fucking more soldiers.
The everybody watches this more
carefully.
Yeah,
keep.
Keep America safe.
Soldiers.
The TSA employee
just keep.
Can't deny the economic reasons for
going over there.
You can't deny it mean in the middle of
this peak oil crisis.
Everybody's freaking out about what
happens when we run out of oil.
Is it possible to run out of oil?
What happens if the prices skyrocket to
the point where we get a massive
recession and so that's the reason why
we go over there.
We go over there to control the oil.
Do we go over there because there's not
much left.
I mean,
what?
What's really going on?
Let me know.
You think that all this is leading up to
the protest.
You know,
getting the troops back here,
like all this is just gonna lead to
something like a new hands across
America and I knew we are the world.
We already have to go through something
like that again.
Get already.
Is there your hands across America?
The only thing I'm worried about is the.
We are the world parodies that stand up
college would close their acts with.
That's what I'm worried about.
11 meaning,
you know the Kevin meaning I remember
hands across America but I don't
remember if I did it or not.
I remember I don't think it worked
right.
It didn't work.
It was fake and they just edited things
together.
It was like,
wow,
look how far it goes.
All the way to the codes were
transferred from person to person.
That one,
I don't know if I stood somewhere and
held hands with two people on the street
somewhere or not.
I think my uncle told me it was if I
didn't.
Well it's what we were talking about
every seven years.
You get some shape files.
The Ellis sort.
That's been a while since that happened.
I think my hands across America
shouldn't have caused you that much
inconvenience,
Brian,
as an individual.
It's not that big a deal,
Brian.
This is the worst fear that you're in.
Fear of another we other world song.
That's so not what's going on here.
What's going on here?
Some overthrow the government type shit.
That's what's going on here.
And what's going on here is people
saying,
Hey,
this system right now,
it doesn't fucking work at all.
The only time in our life that I've ever
seen this,
never seen anything even remotely close
to it.
Know every president,
uh,
in my lifetime has raised taxes at a
point where taxes need to be raised.
It's never been this crazy.
It's never been this.
There's never been this much discontent.
It never been giant protests all over
the world.
They have occupied Toronto.
So
guess what?
Toronto is doing great.
They're doing awesome.
Yeah,
it seems like they have a good economy.
They're,
they're,
you know,
they don't have nearly the problems with
unemployment that we have there.
They're fucking doing pretty good up
there.
A lot better than we're doing,
man,
but people are still like,
fuck it.
It's not good enough.
Was it the 55,000
people at Rogers Center?
Was that the most people at one UFC
event ever?
Yeah.
That was epic.
And those,
those,
those tickets aren't cheap though.
The record is actually being held by.
Um,
I think the,
I think in Japan they've had 90,000
people.
Really?
Yeah.
I think that's what the biggest they've
ever had.
No,
it wasn't the UFC,
it was pride,
pride events.
I'm pretty sure during the peak of mixed
martial arts they had something like
80,000
plus people,
which is really insane when you think
about it because when we did the UFC it
was 55,
but then they released an additional
5,000
seats and they sold them to.
So it turned out to be $60,000.
It was just,
they had to figure out how many seats
they could have and bringing all the
equipment because it was a completely
different show.
It was really stressful for everyone
doing it because they had these giant
fucking tvs everywhere.
So everything is being shown on these 80
foot fucking tvs mean.
It's a huge place,
man.
And you could.
People were watching it from the hotel
that's really wild.
The back of the Roger Center has a
fucking hotel with windows wide open and
you could look.
People had rooms where they could look
out their window and watched the fight.
That's awesome.
Fucking.
I didn't even see that dude.
It's the shit.
That place is huge.
They played baseball in there,
man.
I'm going to wrap your head around that.
Well,
is that the only place where um,
they,
they gave us a earphones.
They gave us these things that we put in
our,
in our ears to listen to you call the,
the matches.
You can get those anywhere.
Everywhere.
Yeah.
They're the only place anybody's ever
walked up to me and said,
here,
do you want this?
You know,
they were just giving them out to people
for some reason in Toronto.
Oh,
that's.
So I listened the whole time.
I think you should get it with your
ticket.
You know,
you're paying a fuck load for a ticket
anyway.
They just hand them bitches out when
they get in the door.
That'd be a nice thing.
It's only 10 bucks and you can reuse it
at every UFC event.
Yeah.
I don't,
I don't know what ended up happening
with the one that I had because you
know,
I smoke a lot of pot.
Smoke a lot of pot,
don't you?
Especially in Toronto.
Toronto's awesome.
Do you ever do that pot club where you.
Yeah,
you told me about it and then I did it
this next time I was there.
We shouldn't say the name because I
don't know how easy it is to get in
trouble for that,
but I don't think it studies either.
I don't know,
but they're all pretty,
pretty fucking chill there.
I'm pretty sure they have a vote really
soon on decriminalization.
You know,
I think there's something going on
there.
I don't know the exact specifics of
their situation with their law,
but it was deemed that the way the law
was written,
the cannabis laws were unconstitutional
and uh,
they only had a certain amount of time
to fight that.
And they're in the midst of it right
now.
I'm pretty sure it's going to be decided
sometime before the end of the year,
before the end of December.
I believe.
That's cool.
Yeah.
Really interpret their,
their attitude towards.
It was amazing up there.
As is NBC.
They just fucking,
you know,
BC has medical now too.
If you have a California license you can
go to basically takes up.
I was just there for just for a night
and I had,
I had a blast.
I love going to Canada.
So greatest city in the country.
Canada,
Canada's greatest city in our country.
Know the,
the,
the greatest city in Canada is.
It is.
You know what,
there's no bad one.
I,
there's a,
it's a tossup between Vancouver,
like the most fun I've ever had between
Vancouver,
Toronto,
and Montreal.
Those are the three big cities that I
performed out.
I would say it's a toss up.
You know,
the only thing in Montreal you get
people,
there's a certain amount of people that
don't necessarily speak English that
well.
It's a little more French.
Most people are bilingual,
but there's a certain percent of the
girls,
but also that could effect a reaction a
little bit,
a little comedy because the language
difference,
we get that a little bit,
but a damn those girls are hot chocolate
with a French accent,
but when they're being horrible brawls
though,
even when they're being mean to you,
what they have horrible bras.
Bras.
I've been with two of those French
Canadian girls and they both had really
creepy.
I think that says more about girls who
want to fuck you.
Love that.
I love that you're sampling to girls.
Is a statement like that.
That's his gallery too.
I was with had terrible bras and did it.
You'd never know.
Duke countries have like,
things like browser more important,
like style wise,
like you know,
like old,
old woman underwear.
Like is there a country want to stay
warm when you were there with chicks?
Wanted to stay warm.
They throw less emphasis on sexy
underwear in Montreal and the winter
man.
Oh son and get cold.
I,
uh,
used to do the old,
I should do Jimbo comedy works in
Montreal.
I still do that.
Did it last time I was there was a great
little small club.
It only seats like 100 people.
I should do it like way,
way back in the day when I do the
Montreal comedy festival.
But uh,
I walked from my hotel to a,
the club because it was only a few
blocks.
That's all I got there every day is,
you know,
long time ago and it was minus 15,
minus 16,
I think it was something like that.
And I walked to the club and it was
ruthlessly painful dude.
It was ruthlessly painful.
Like my ears felt like they're going to
fall off my head.
You had to have a wool hat,
like you had to have ear covers.
It's not like a looks thing like you
have to have,
should wear a ski mask,
ski masks,
you should wear a ski mask because your
face gets ripped apart by the cold air.
Fuck that noise.
I'm not a fan of that.
So I guess we just officially decided
Vancouver's because in the wintertime
it's just got like Portland weather or
Seattle.
Vancouver is pretty fucking bad ass.
That's the cool people are as cool as
fuck.
That is one of the most marijuana
influence cities in the world.
Oh yeah.
One of the most.
The movie that I was in the union,
the business of getting high.
Have you ever watched that?
So,
uh,
my friend Adam scored,
he did it and it's all about the,
the economy in Vancouver and how much of
it is based around marijuana and how
insane it is,
you know,
the American laws and the horseshoe that
goes on with legalization.
But it's a great documentary on how
ridiculous the whole scenario is.
The fact that it's illegal in the first
place we should vaporize when we talk
about this,
you think that things are ready to roll?
How long could it possibly take?
But it's flashing red light flashing the
whole time.
I'm not supposed to be solid when it's
right.
I don't want to say the name of this
product because I don't want to give
this guy a bad review because he seems
like a real nice guy.
Isn't the red light you talking about?
Hold on,
let's try and see if it works.
Give it a shot
tomorrow.
Yeah.
Tomorrow we have a death squad comedy
show at the Pasadena Ice House.
The dog will be there,
won't be doing a podcast beforehand.
So the podcast starts eight PM Pacific.
So it's going to be the same deal where
people can watch it live.
They can watch it live and we're going
to have a John Reap a little esther.
I'm Yoshi.
Wait,
is this a comedy show or a video game
company?
So I like that video game with little
estrogen Yossi.
Try to get,
get into the castle.
A asshole Joe is trying to.
Allegedly.
You think it works?
Yeah,
it works.
I'm just,
you know,
I'd like to try it.
You do it looks Kinda like sucking a
cock though.
And you know,
I'm against that.
Do you,
do you usually use vaporizers or what's
your huh?
Like way better for.
I don't have any usual.
I have a myriad of ways to uh,
to get thc into my system.
I had a lollipop in the car on the way
over here.
You animal fucking savage.
Those are good.
And then,
you know,
and then people always have joints
around that you smoke and I'm not a
joint roller myself.
I'm not a,
I don't have those skills.
I make apps so easy to make apples into
pipes whenever I'm in hotels because
they always have them in the lobby and.
But don't you feel like you're getting a
lot of the butane from the lighter in
your mouth?
Don't you taste that shit when you
inhale it through an apple?
Anytime you use anything?
We have to highlight the weed.
We liked the weed over and over again.
You know that the joints is your light
at once and you could light it with a
match.
Yeah,
that's a good.
That's a good point.
But I just like with joints it's almost
become more like a social thing for me.
Like I never just sit and smoke a joint
by myself and,
and,
and you don't get,
you don't get big hits off of it.
I like,
you know,
that's why like you don't get big hits,
you're such a fucking still.
And we'll give you a little pin joint or
something.
I'm like,
oh,
that's fun to pretend we're smoking
polo.
Little tiny joint.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But you know,
I'd rather have a blunt that adjoin and
pipe over go do,
you know?
And then Bong bongs really like I hit
them so rarely now that they really
knocked me on my ass,
you know,
and like,
especially like somebody put some like
fucking hash oil in there or something
because I'm really getting used to just
smoke and vaporizer in my apartment and
you know,
and,
and doing a lot of edibles.
So my smoking game is coming,
coming down,
you know,
like smoking game bonds will show you,
glitches in the Matrix.
Bongs,
you'll,
you'll have moments with the same exact
thing.
Is repeated a second later.
What,
what?
There is this house that I lived in
where I,
in college I lived with seven girls and
it was a two story house.
It was like,
just like the railroad and we made a
bong out of PCP that went from the first
story.
See PCP bro,
bro.
Crazy man.
We made fucking pipes out of agile dosh
and it went to the second floor.
It was like so huge and there was one
guy that could clear the whole thing,
just hit it,
just hit it.
Just said it like it's a like,
it's a son,
doesn't feel like it's doing anything.
Does it?
Was it clouding up?
It doesn't.
Sam,
he sounds like a.
A teapot.
Yeah.
The little tea pot.
Short and stout here.
Really powerful professional stoner
professional stoner.
Doug Benson approves of this device.
Yeah.
My seemed like a pretty good,
pretty good hit.
W,
what do you know about this nonsense
that the ATF was going to stop people
from getting new firearms if you were a
medical marijuana patient now you heard
this.
I've heard stuff to that effect in that.
Sounds.
Sounds pretty.
It sounds nutty,
but it's also.
It doesn't hit me at home because I
don't,
you know,
I'm not a firearms guy.
Well,
I understand that.
For me,
I wish everybody.
I wish everybody had guns was high
fight.
You think more about your fellow man
before you pull the trigger.
It's disgusting.
Like he don't like.
I,
I hate that when people kind of paint
this idea that you could just that poc
and somehow,
I mean,
I guess there's some people that can
make kind of crazy,
but for the most part it doesn't,
it doesn't make you have visions or do
things that you like,
like with alcohol where you do things
that you wouldn't do if you weren't
drunk.
There's weed doesn't really have that.
I mean not full or something,
you know what I mean?
Like behind the wheel of a car,
how many people do you know or like when
they're high and driving,
they're maniacs in there and dangerous
and you know,
more of a threat than the old chart.
The cop pulls you over,
do you know why I pulled you over?
You're going three miles an hour.
You're not parked.
But even then,
you know,
like every once in a while,
like I,
I've been trying to write down lately,
every time I do something stupid and
when I'm not high,
I'm not,
I'm,
I'm not high like maybe an hour out of
every day.
So it's a small window because whether
you do your taxes.
Yeah,
I could do my taxes high too.
I mean I used to,
I now I have an account.
Doesn't freak you out though.
It does,
but you double check it,
you know,
like text to the,
when you're high and you're leaving a
hotel room,
you,
you pace around the room three or four
times to make sure you got all of items.
And then one time out of five you left
something behind and you're just going
to have to buy it.
Check your pocket for $20 to buy a new
iphone adapter at the airport power
adapter.
And I lose it every time I leave the
house more than $20.
Those things.
Yeah,
they're pricey.
They're like 100 bucks or they really.
Yeah.
But what I did was I bought phone power
adapters.
A 100 bucks or no,
uh,
you know,
for the laptop,
for laptop,
you know,
those ones with the big white square.
Okay.
And uh,
but those things I know last a couple
over the years and then I just finally
got wise and bought two and I travel
with one and have one at home.
Yeah,
I do the same thing.
I have a laptop at least.
At least when I get back home,
it's there and I'm ready to go.
I was so confused.
I thought you were just talking about
iphone adapters.
I'm like,
how the fuck are they charge 100 bucks.
30 bucks though.
Apple just released a recall on power
adapters and it's funny.
It's about time they did something about
this because I've seen this on both my
power adapters for laptops and I phones
where the cord kind of comes out of the
plug.
Have you seen that?
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
And so finally the recalling it right
now,
the new ones are much more sturdy
new ones though.
They're like waste 30.
Yeah.
Technology man.
It's adapting.
That seems to be the fucking bottleneck
though,
is battery life,
the real battle battery life.
You have to be connected to power.
You know,
real battery life was just not
substantial interest for power
everywhere now.
Yeah.
But the real question is,
will there ever be some sort of an
infinite battery source or some sort of
an amazing battery source where shit
last forever,
but the print power,
how can you do that though?
How is something storing power?
You know,
it would have to be like or something.
Yeah,
something like that.
But I'm,
I'm pretty cool with how it is.
I don't,
I don't get caught off guard by my
computer,
you know,
running out.
Look,
I'm,
I'm amazed that it works at all.
You know,
the whole device is incredible.
Especially I know a lot of people I had
a conversation with is very,
very intelligent lady,
but she was talking to me about a
windows and she only uses windows and
the reason why she only uses windows is
because she doesn't like being told what
forum she buys her computers in.
She wants to be able to pick her own
parts and different,
different things and I understand that.
But the rational part of me goes,
yeah,
but macs don't have viruses and they
work better.
Done.
That conversation's over like.
Yeah,
I,
yeah.
I would rather you know anybody,
but the reason why they work so good is
because there's not a billion different
douche bags making these computers with
all these different parts and you know,
the,
the operating system has to figure out
how the drivers to each individual
device work.
I just think this is a shitty operating
system.
It used to be good and then they went to
like,
you know,
xp was,
what is it that now windows eight is it
seven,
77 and I just think it's the Shitty,
like I don't like it.
I like Osx and then when it comes to
most things you buy for your computer
nowadays,
everything's USB.
If it doesn't,
you don't have to have like what are you
really doing it?
If you didn't have a computer,
windows would be awesome.
If somebody gave you a windows seven
computer in 1995,
you would have,
you would shoot a load all over your
keyboard.
You would be so excited,
but things have changed drastically at
one point.
Totally.
I remember I couldn't believe you
actually controlling that white line,
which I'm moving on screen and it's fun
to get good at it.
That was another one.
I was good at.
Pong.
Yeah.
Real good at the one where you play,
where you play against the machine or
whatever.
Yeah,
that was great.
That really freestone or days to.
Right.
That was the one I was really good at is
my parents used to go to a lay
priesthood days.
My parents used to go to a bar at a,
at a golf course.
There was also a restaurant,
so they'd hang out there and you know,
they just bring me along or whatever.
And they had like that.
It was almost like my babysitter was
playing with the fucking pong machine
while my parents had some cocktails and
uh,
I got so good at that.
And also you used to be able to get free
games on pong by the metal thing in the
front that you,
that you put the quarters into the slot
if you rubbed your feet on the ground
and carpeting and built up static
electricity and then had like a piece of
metal in your hand like a quarter.
You could tap it just right and it would
throw a credits onto the.
Onto the machine.
Yeah,
I did it all the time or that I've,
I've like,
that is crazy.
My life.
I've always found all these weird scams
that eventually like not only do they
not save you a whole lot in the first
place is twenty five cents,
but they also over time become,
you know,
become worthless.
But it's weird little skills you pick up
just to just to cheat the,
like the ski bus over and put it in the
50 and you just keep on getting those
tickets and put it into throwing it in
their tickets to animal that bad.
So many tickets that we hadn't.
Anything of value.
There was always like one,
like,
like a beat box,
like a,
you know,
you can't help that.
We'd call the day and yeah.
And you can't save up to get that many
tickets.
A million tickets for this one.
You thinking about how much money you
spent,
how much time of your life has gone
rolling a stupid ball.
Oh,
all the things I've done that take time.
Like the amount of time I've spent
playing poker,
the amount of time I spend watching dumb
movies.
How you a road poker player.
Do you go to casinos when you do the
road?
That's what I'm in a gambling town or
like I don't,
I don't seek out casinos everywhere I go
because a lot of places have them now
because if Indian grounds or because
you're on a boat on the river.
But uh,
I only,
I only go if I'm playing the casino or
you know,
or I live across the street from it.
That's part of what I love about going
to see UFC in vegas is it gets me away
from the tables for like five hours
because.
Yeah,
because I'll just sit and play and play
and play,
you know,
I love it,
but it's such a waste of time.
But also,
and it also at this point in my life,
the thrill of winning a hand isn't
really the same because I don't,
I don't need the money as bad.
You know,
back when I was playing when I was like,
you know,
I,
I could pay for rent next month in his
hand.
That was,
it was a lot more exciting.
Well,
Ari should fear would one point in time
was winning more money playing poker
than he was making it,
doing comedy for?
He's a good player.
I only played like we were the same
table in one tournament once I think,
but I,
I,
I got to vibe off of him like he really
knows what he's doing because I still.
There's still things that professional
poker players could,
could teach me that I could,
I could stand to learn,
but I'm just too lazy to learn.
Like you know,
all the kinds of calculations you should
be making during each hand.
Like how exactly how much to bet and all
that stuff.
I'm just more like,
you know,
just goofing around.
He was just having fun.
You're not trying to be the best poker
player in the world.
No,
but I'm trying.
I'm trying to win through.
Just playing like an asshole.
You can play chess.
I did.
You know,
when I was younger.
I haven't haven't in a long time.
That's a great obsession game.
That game could drive people.
Deepened the whole.
Yeah.
You could spend a lot of time on that.
You can go crazy.
You can really go mad and playing chess
because for certain people it absorbs
there everyday.
Like there'll be walking down the street
and there'll be thinking about moves.
Like it starts.
It starts getting to a point where you
know,
you,
you see a direct result between the more
concentrated you are,
the more you concentrate on it,
more that you focus on it,
the more you start winning and the
better you get at playing chess and then
you just go.
You get lost,
then you're crazy.
Yeah.
See,
that's what I suggest doing poker is I
don't like sit there and evaluate how
everyone else is playing and what their
personalities are and like,
oh,
what he did on that hand and then what
he did on the next hand.
Like I'm just like more,
I'm just playing in the moment and I
know when,
you know,
I know good cards when I see him or when
I have a good chance of,
you know,
drawing a winning hand and I just sort
of,
you know,
play like that.
I did a movie once and the guy who was
renting out the house,
they rent out,
you know,
you want to shoot a movie in the house,
you can rent someone's house like people
offer them for rent and this guy was a
professional chess player and um,
so you know,
a lot of downtime during movie.
So I'd go hang out with this guy and
talk to them,
try to figure out what he was doing.
And he was playing chess online,
you know,
with all these different people.
And he was like some super fucking
master chess player.
So it was a,
it was fascinating that he's got this
giant community of apparently you could
just get chess games like anytime of the
day,
anytime of the night online,
whatever level you're at,
you know,
and there's people from all over the
world that would play chess with,
you know,
same thing with scrabble really.
People are fucking nuts with the
scrabble,
scrabble computer downwards with like
where they're playing against people all
over the place.
But you can see you can do it anytime
you want.
That's part of what I love about twitter
is if I am like up in the middle of the
night and not asleep for some reason
because I got to go to the airport or
whatever.
Can't sleep that.
So great that like the,
it's the,
that it's international.
Once you get a certain number of
followers you can like,
you know,
I'm sure some people go on twitter and
they're pissed because they,
you know,
they can't,
nobody that they follow saying anything
or write back to them.
But it just.
So it's such,
such a 24 hour chat room source of.
Yeah.
Well,
you don't have to chat with people,
you can just read what people are saying
and really choose what you want to
respond to.
The 24 hour aspect is really interesting
when you're flying,
when you're in like in England or Europe
or something like that and times are all
screwed up and weird,
but you can constantly be tweeting and
you know,
and you can kind of like,
it kind of replaces texting all your
friends about what you're doing.
You just send a tweet that's not going
to wake somebody up like you didn't want
to text.
So I'm at Buckingham Palace and you
know,
they're trying to sleep and the phone's
going on,
you know,
it's a good way to like I use it as like
a texting device when I think somebody
might not be awake,
I just write to them a direct message on
twitter instead of texting them.
Oh do you really?
I don't check those enough.
Yeah,
I know you're really slow to get back on
those sometimes for weeks and some
people,
it's funny,
when you write direct messages to
people,
sometimes they just don't even know that
that's a thing that I did that with
voicemail.
Now I don't ever listen to my voicemails
and it's probably the dumbest thing
ever,
but I just,
that's,
to me,
it's just annoying.
I went to one guys,
one guy tweeted me,
it was like,
it's a shame who's fucking phone is on?
That was me.
That would wake a person up.
Yeah,
that's brutal.
How hard.
Why don't you have that bitch on
vibrate?
He's not used to doing podcasts.
One Guy tweeted,
one guy tweeted me,
um,
something that was on vibrate.
It wasn't me.
It was a fibrate.
Shit's broken sun.
Yeah,
it's,
it's got a weird quirk to it because you
don't have a case on you drop that
bitch.
Tell the truth.
No,
I,
it's,
I've done pretty good at not dropping
it.
It's my baby,
you know,
I don't.
Uh,
I don't drop it.
This guy tweeted me.
Um,
you know,
it's a shame that you can't reply and
say something to,
for help the troops.
It was like really weird,
like phonetically all fucked up and it
was all caps to see,
to support the troops,
the explanation point,
exclamation point one,
one,
one.
And it was like it was.
And then I go,
wow,
what the fuck did I like?
This guy expects me to reply is I have a
half a million twitter followers.
Dude.
Sometimes I don't look at it all day.
I don't.
There's no way I could respond to
everybody.
It's impossible.
I do.
So then I thought you're awesome.
Every single person.
Absolutely awesome.
Right?
So then I go to every single person,
but quite a few,
I go to his twitter page and that's the
same message he sent to literally
thousands of evil.
He just like,
Oh yeah,
you go look at any time somebody writes,
in case you're wondering about their
personality or whatever,
you can go and see everything else
they've written.
I love robot.
Probably hate it when it's like if it's
at Benson,
at Joe Rogan,
at red band,
some some shit.
And it's like,
well,
no,
that's what happened.
That's what happens is it's fine when
it's,
my actual friends are
thrown in there like we all have common
interests,
but when somebody just throws in random,
you know,
like,
princess.
So it's as well that's just,
that's just his ass will now be tweeting
you tonight.
I guarantee you people are right.
Snoop Dogg and Doug Benson,
you guys something about pot that they
think we both need to know.
But when they just throw in,
like when it's just to me and Kim
Kardashians and Brian Williams from NBC
news or whatever,
like some weird combination of,
you know,
on the,
on the fringe celebrity,
uh,
it's,
it's such a turnout.
It makes you want to just not respond to
them.
And then you go look at their page and
they're just randomly picking names and
that's how they do a lot of,
uh,
there's a lot of spam now on,
on twitter.
If you,
you know,
as soon as you get a message us that
seems like an ad and then you,
then you check their page and they're
just,
it's just sending that same thing.
I'm talking to my podcast.
So in the interest of brevity,
I got hacked like I,
I signed up for,
yeah,
I must have clicked on some link to get
some twitter picture or something like
that.
And somehow or another they tweeted from
my account about some contests for an
ipad two and I was following them.
All of the sudden I was like,
wow,
this is amazing.
Like they hacked into by twitter
account.
You apparently it was probably some red
tape or some,
you know,
find print rather.
And you know,
when you agreed to,
uh,
accept some,
you know,
some twitter application.
It happens everyday.
Not Everyday,
but pretty frequently I'll see one of my
more famous friends or people had
followed just because I'm curious about
them,
that we still treat something odd or
something that sends,
seems like an ad.
And then the next tweet is like,
Oh shit,
I got hacked.
Do you know,
did you see when Ashton Kutcher was
tweeting?
Oh my gosh,
that was particularly about paternal
being fired.
Yeah,
because he did all.
He knew all he,
all he reacted to,
and I'm sure that's what a lot of people
reacted to,
was just hearing that this amazing coach
got fired just very suddenly and he
didn't stop to think,
wow,
that big of a move.
Like why would penn state following a
fire a guy?
So suddenly if something really terrible
didn't happen,
but he still went on and tweeted,
oh man,
that's a bummer.
Or something like that.
Or I love you,
Joe Pa.
Yeah.
And then the other guy,
but then he did Qa,
I guess kind of a good thing to spin it.
He respond.
He retweeted every person that wrote to
them,
you're an asshole urine idiot and you
just write in each one something like,
yeah,
I'm sorry I did.
I just didn't know all the facts.
He sort of responded to a lot of people
in show them,
showed a lot of the vitriol that was
happening.
You made a staff at Foxconn responded
to.
It seemed like something he really did.
It was kind of the whole factory of
people responding to twitter.
Imagine he is always Chinese workers,
like the ones they use in world of
warcraft
to build up your energy,
you know,
they send your account overseas and some
Chinese guy plays with it until he
fucking starves to death.
Just copying machines,
body aside and throw some new student
onto the block too.
I'm not cynical enough to think that
Ashton didn't do it himself because it.
Because it all happened in such real
time.
Right.
You just had so many people.
Seems to me that when you're a celebrity
that's involved in a public scandal,
he has this most latest one.
It seems interesting that he's tweeting
people at all.
You know,
it's like you wouldn't.
You would think if you're gonna,
you're gonna read any of the replies.
You know you're going to get a lot of
people that are going to ask you a bunch
of questions and you don't want to
answer like,
do you really want to just go out there
and,
and interconnect with people,
but I guess he does it.
Spill.
That's the amazing thing is it's like,
you know,
how important is it to get,
to try to feel like you're getting your
side of it out when,
when you think you're misunderstood,
you know,
and,
and at a certain point in time,
a lot of the people's twitters become a
very impersonal,
you know,
when the numbers get too big,
it seems like people take less chances.
The they say less than a million people
writing back to you that you shouldn't
have used a certain slur.
Something when you were trying to.
The joke was how inappropriate what you
were.
Right.
Like I'll sometimes,
if I think it's something really dark,
I'll just,
I'll just drop it in the middle of the
night because a lot of stuff just gets
sort of lost in the twitter verse,
you know,
like nobody's sitting.
Most people don't sit and read every
single thing written by every single
person.
They follow that because a lot of people
follow a thousand people.
So you're just in this kind of rushing
stream of comments and sometimes they'll
land on you because they know they like
you more than other people they follow
or whatever.
But sometimes they'll also like anything
that looks like you're just promoting a
Gig,
they might just breeze past it.
I get every time I play a town,
like the day after on twitter,
someone will write me,
when are you coming to?
And it's that town I was just in and it
just been tweeting about.
But it's just,
you can't expect everybody to see
everything.
It's hard to.
I mean,
think that you're going to communicate.
I mean you,
you got to hope that your twitter is
interesting enough that people are going
to lock onto it,
you know,
and you're going to hope that you build
some sort of a community there and then
they're going to be able to follow you
on your website or follow you at your
shows or look through your tweets to
find out where you're at or you know,
do you have a little schedule on your
twitter page?
So if you go to your twitter page,
you can see what the upcoming dates are.
They have a link to a site where I've
got all my dates,
but that,
what do you guys think about this new
business they have on there with all
the,
um,
you know,
activity following activity following.
Oh,
clicked on that.
Yet there's a word activity now in the
top of your page and if you click on it,
you see just a list of everything that
everybody,
you follow what they're up to,
like,
who they've retreated,
who they're following,
much information tells you,
it tells you.
You get to find out now as soon as
somebody follows you,
do you do that?
Because that's kind of interesting
because then because then you can,
if you're just sitting there looking at
it and it comes up that somebody just
started following you,
it's kind of cool to just immediately
send them some sort of,
hey,
welcome,
hope you hope you like it.
Kind of message from my peer specialists
got big tits.
Dude,
tell me what you do,
how do you work and how do you work with
Doug Benson?
It's 2:00
in the morning,
11 in the morning.
Okay,
here's the scenario.
You're alone stone to the gills.
Okay.
And you just like checking out twitter
and some really ridiculously hot suicide
girl with tattoos just starts following
you.
I,
you know,
I might write back and say,
hey,
what's up?
Or what's up?
Hello?
Or whatever.
Just what you do,
just reach,
reach,
reach out,
somebody to see what happens to a little
high,
just little,
hey,
what's up?
Nothing incriminating button creeping.
And then often what we'll come back is I
can't direct message you because you
don't follow me.
And my next direct message says the
system works and then you know,
and then you,
you see how different people handle it.
Different ways.
Some people will get pissed off right
away and don't want to,
you know,
don't want to deal with somebody where
they're half of the conversation is
public,
but your half is,
is private.
But you know,
what else am I going to do?
You know,
I,
I'm not on twitter to have conversations
with other people in front of all,
all of my followers because.
So why don't you just fucking with them,
it's not interesting to read.
Just follow them for a little while and
then unfold.
You can do that for 20 number,
but no.
Then I really will play a game where if
there's somebody that I want to follow,
I will add them and then go through the
list and see who's going to go.
It's usually somebody that I followed
that just ultimately is their tweets.
Haven't been that interesting because
they're like,
you know,
I,
I followed some crazy super famous
people just because I,
I think it could be interesting and some
I cling to like I,
I love following Alec Baldwin.
I think he's really entertaining and
yeah,
and I don't follow them out.
But I gave up my,
her,
I followed her for a while and then
stop.
I stopped a long time ago.
Why?
Because he just tweets a lot and for
awhile there it was just a lot of back
and forth with Demi Moore and that was
just kinda like they were being way too
cute.
Like the whole time you're like,
this relationship is not going to last.
They're putting way too much effort into
pretending,
not pretending,
maybe actually being in love with each
other,
but they just won't shut up about it.
How can you maintain that is a couple
PDA on twitter's growth.
What if she's a lesbian and he's like
her beard?
Ooh,
no,
I think they probably fucked.
They had turned sex where?
Like the creepy weird.
Sorry.
I came in and looked ashen,
his asshole and stuff like that.
Brian,
you just ruined everything.
It ruined everything.
I know he's mad at Ashton now.
Ashton supposedly having affairs.
Oh,
so now they don't talk.
Uncle Bruce is going to kick them out.
But that's the funny thing that he's,
you know,
for TV viewers instantly forgive the
whole thing about him having affairs,
but you know,
that show the ratings might have come
down a little bit from the jumping out
in favor of Joe Papa.
Really at the wrong moment,
you know,
because you know,
that's what's amazing to me about the
whole Penn state story is just that.
That is,
that is,
you know,
only one notch above the worst thing.
The worst thing a person could do
probably right there,
you know,
and I don't even want to think about
what's below it and,
and you know,
and so everyone's disgusted by it,
but some are still managed to be some
people that,
that are just,
you know,
defending in some weird way,
the people that were involved in the
story.
Yeah.
You can't,
you know,
I was saying how weird it is.
The guy's name was officer or Macquarie,
the guy who,
uh,
found them in,
in the hotel room together,
which did,
that whole thing now is just falling
apart.
His story's not matching what,
what supposedly happened at the time.
And which guy?
Macquarie.
Yeah.
He's saying now that he went,
he did go to police officers and then
they and they proceeded to,
you know,
not follow through because initially
he's just sick of getting all this shit
about people saying that he just went to
Joe Pa and he didn't go to the cops.
So he now he's saying he did,
but he testified,
you know,
because this guy has gone through,
people had to testify for and against
San Dusky before on it earlier charges,
this is crazy.
And so at that time it supposedly the
report was that he didn't speak to any
cops and now he's saying he did.
So it's,
it's,
it's one of those complicated,
horrifying stories that we may never end
in our lifetimes.
It may just go on and on and on,
just because getting to the bottom of
everything that happened.
Like I heard someone tell someone else
the theory that then I heard that is
just absolutely mortifying that,
you know,
this guy saying Dusky worked with the
children's charity and those were the
kids he was bringing to the Games and
that they show pictures of him like
leaning on these kids and they got
little foothill football helmets on and,
and you know,
it's crazy that he was showering with
them at all,
like the kids and the end him.
Neither one of them are playing in a
game.
So why do they even need.
Why?
What's the pretense for being in the
showers?
Yeah,
like right there,
the guy's guilty.
Could he be,
you know,
like I don't care if you put.
If he actually had sex with him,
he's just setting up that scenario,
makes them a creep that shouldn't be
allowed to do that.
And with kids with these disinfect,
these kids that are poor and you know,
and from foster homes or whatever the,
you know,
this,
this charity,
he's,
he's got these extra vulnerable kids and
he's doing these things too and it's
probably being taken to a football game.
It's the most amazing thing that's ever
happened to them.
And they also don't necessarily
understand the implications of what he's
doing to them when he physically attacks
them or those photos real of his house.
Like being in the same like,
like the backyard of an elementary
school.
Just seen
that I bought surprise.
I mean it just like an elementary school
and a little bit of woods and then a
house and then supposedly,
I don't know if it was just a joke,
but supposedly that's his house.
Like on the other side of this little
woods,
I'm thinking like that woods is probably
like that scene in like human centipede
word.
Like they go and find this house in the
middle of the other side of the woods
and there's like a creepy guy that lives
in there and molests kids I come to,
you know,
you probably like sneaks through the
forest and spies on kids at the
elementary school and it's just like
this creepy rape force.
We all just start talking and just go.
It's hilarious when you're fucking high
and just start talking about something
because I never even got to my point
which was,
which was that,
you know,
there's a lot of rich people that also
pumped money into this charity because
this guy told them to.
And so this one law enforcement officer
who I think probably has a good idea
about these things,
suggested the notion that this guy was
grooming kids for boosters to fool
around with.
Oh my God.
Like there was a whole ring.
He had a whole.
Yeah.
Like he had like,
he had a whole system like that.
That's a,
that's a possibility.
Oh my God,
like this thing is going to get so
twisted and deep as used.
Horrifying.
It's amazing that he got away with it as
long as he did and the only way he got
away with it for 19 years,
20 years,
whatever the fuck it was,
is if people knew and didn't say
anything,
period.
It was the institution.
It was the everyone afraid of losing
their jobs,
losing the game,
losing their,
you know,
their,
everything is so important to them.
I mean they rioted when he got fired,
you saw the riots,
right?
What I'm saying,
they were Ashton Kutcher,
Ashton Kutcher would've flipped a car
over if he was there because the story
just got quickly,
more and more horrifying,
but they just reacted immediately that
he was fired.
Yeah.
Well,
as soon as he was like,
well also how horrible for him to come
out and say,
this is horrible.
I'm going to finish out the season and
then retire.
Like his first move should have been.
I'm Outta here.
Like I went to retire and I fucked up,
but saying I'm going to finish out the
season.
That gave everyone like this hope that
like they were going to have a great
championship season and then worry about
this later,
and so then when they turned around and
really,
you know,
he ended up being fired or resigned or
whatever,
however went down,
that's when they started flipping shit
over.
This story was in a book.
It would be two.
Fantastic.
It'd be like,
this is too crazy.
This is not like a Stephen King Book.
Yeah,
you wouldn't.
it is.
Really.
It really is.
Really is.
You would think there's no way that can
happen for this long.
There's no way I could go on for 20
years and he could just keep getting
away with it and keep mining these
children to have such shame and
confusion by the incident that they
never tell anyone.
How many guys,
how many kids?
Always kids.
It's also kids like most of this stuff
happens with kids that are familiar
with.
They're the person that attacks them.
It's never.
It's rarely an abject stranger who gets
in their life and quickly done something
horrible.
We actually spent a good deal of time
talking about this in the podcast last
night.
About how,
or last time about how um,
there were some emails back and forth
from some priests were they actually
talked about getting boys from troubled
homes,
getting boys who don't have good
connections to their family.
They don't have anyone to count on.
Get them.
They go after them and grown them.
Some dark shit,
man.
Yeah.
So this is Sanduski guy's just,
it's just not a very,
like we were making fun of earlier his,
his side of the story,
talking to Bob Costas,
particularly scary.
Bob Cast is so good at those interviews
too.
And I said,
why were you in this?
Why did you need to shower at all?
Yeah,
that's a good question.
Asking that.
That's a good question.
Well,
I think everybody,
but he did press him pretty hard.
You did.
I think everybody assumes that guy fucks
kids.
I think everybody's assuming that,
but they have to be careful in how they
proceed with questioning him,
I think.
But the thing that he did that he did
this tea,
this radio interview to spin the court
of public opinion,
that's ridiculous,
you know,
but I think it just made it worse.
I'll way,
way,
way worse,
way worse because he was.
Because he went into it with the Hubris
in the confidence of thinking that as
long as I just go in there and denied,
at least some people might believe me.
Yes.
But then saying just being such a creep
and saying like being around children
now the answer is no.
I would never do that to a child.
That's the answer.
It's in their parents that are going to
try to murder him.
Now I'm.
Oh yeah,
no,
that's the thing that I think not only
is the media outside his house now,
I think that like that's another crazy
thing letting him go on bales.
Ridiculous.
Like,
I mean certainly in jail,
I don't think they cheat child predators
very well.
They to isolate doctors,
isolate them in a jail,
like letting him go on bail.
I don't,
I don't get that at all.
I think that guy's going to ice himself.
He might ice himself or get out of the
access to kids in showers have to be
limited at least to a couple of hours a
week or something like that says you
can't do it daily because that's what
happened to him the first time where I
was.
They took away as key to the showers.
What they took away.
It's got such a school did because the
first time it happened,
they believed him.
When he said he was,
it was just horseplay.
There was no,
so it was hot and he had to only do hot
dog hot tubs after that.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
Where's it defined?
A new venue.
It takes them to hotel rooms.
That's what it does.
Who brought kids with them on the road
there were staying with them.
That's.
It's such an amazing.
Such an amazing cover.
Like I always.
I always joke around on stage about how
wouldn't it be funny if I did all I've
done to create this idea that I'm a pod
comic and it turns out I am a cop and
that all my shows,
everybody gets arrested like a giant
sting operation.
Other people in the pot movement it
probably undercover cops you think?
Yeah,
there was one that died in a motorcycle
accident and he would uh,
meet at this.
It was like a normal chapter.
One of those groups,
you know,
and uh,
he was uh,
a local guy and he was in this,
this group and I died in a motorcycle
accident.
It turned out he was a cop and he was
undercover the entire time or maybe just
enjoying himself.
I don't think so.
I think that was his job.
I think that's what it came to.
Kids that don't smoke course,
which is an interesting.
Like those people are like saints to me.
Like why go to all this trouble or
something that you're not doing,
but they see the big picture.
Yeah.
It's a freedom issue.
The main issue is why would anybody be
able to tell you what you can't do and
someone telling you that you can't get
high is absolutely nuts.
It's crazy.
It's like if you were.
I always say if you're on an island with
two people and one person said,
listen man,
I don't want you getting high.
You get high,
I'm going to put you in a cage.
He'd be like,
I'm going to have to kill this guy going
to lock me in a fucking cage if I get
high.
That's ridiculous.
Tell that I want to do.
Like if they said you can't,
you know you can't have sex with a
cantaloupe,
and if there was four people,
and I mean it's just as ridiculous.
If there's a 4 million people,
it's just as ridiculous.
It's ridiculous for one person to tell
you what you can and can't do with your
bond and it's not gonna affect other
people.
It's not an issue where you're ruining
the fucking environment.
It's not an issue with her.
You're damaging the civilization.
You're not doing anything while you're
doing it wrong,
then you're doing it wrong.
For sure.
Where?
Where are you at this weekend and you're
going to do the Sunday show at the
center of your shows are sold out
already,
right?
Yeah,
they're sold out.
I got one.
I got one show at four,
20 in the afternoon on Sunday.
San Jose is ridiculous.
You are sticking to a meme.
You to that motherfucker.
Do you like it so much?
Well,
you know,
you gotta play clubs where they don't
have a lot of windows,
you know,
so it still looks like a nightclub or
whatever.
You've still got the same vibe,
but I've had really good time because,
you know,
I'm,
I'm done for the night,
I'm off for the rest of the night at
6:00
PM when I do that is cool and I get to
actually go out and enjoy these cities
that I visit all the time and never see
because I'm in the stupid comedy club
all night.
Not to say that that's not also a great
way to just do my living days.
But uh,
Saturdays and Sundays I'll and some
cities I'll come in and they'll do both
days.
You know,
like I got coming up at the Sacramento
punchline,
Martin Luther King weekend.
I'm going to do a show on four slash
Saturday slash Sunday for 20 Monday and
just hang out there all weekend,
have my nights free.
There's a lot of likeminded people in
Sacramento.
She says I am.
Yeah,
I see what you're saying.
It's a fun place.
So that's a really smart thing to do,
man.
So you,
you sort of reorganized the weekend,
you'd take a spot where it wasn't
ordinarily open,
you open it for you and you can do it in
comedy clubs.
They see people that show up are the
ones that I told about the show through
my podcast or through twitter.
And so the crowds are great.
We play a game,
we play that game that I play on the
podcast.
I'll let her Balton game.
We played that with audience members in
my opening act and it's a,
it's a blast.
Oh really?
That's how people from the audience come
up and,
and,
and you know,
challenge to whoever I brought with me
on the road for that particular and it's
super fun and they're awake for four,
20 in the afternoon except in Denver.
Both Times I did it in Denver.
Somebody managed to get drunk,
but everywhere else they're sober.
They're not,
you know,
they may be a few beers in or whatever,
but like they're not that,
that kind of trash that you see when you
do shows at night,
especially in a town where there was
some sports thing in the afternoon and
they'd been drinking since then.
They come to your show and there were,
you know,
they're pre drunk before they even start
drinking their two drink minimum.
So is that how you're doing all your
shows now?
You're doing all?
Not all of them.
I also do like,
I'll go into a club and just be there on
a night.
They're normally closed Sunday,
Monday or Tuesday,
like I'm doing the,
um,
Fort Lauderdale Improv on Monday,
December 11th,
and the West Palm Improv on Tuesday,
December twelfth.
And they're both huge clubs.
They're really nice,
but they're huge.
So every time I play there,
you know,
normally if I have to do two or three
shows,
I'm just not gonna to every show is
going to have a lot of empty seats.
But if I just go in and do one on a
night when they're not even normally
open and hopefully everybody that's,
you know,
into me and has the night available.
Come check it out.
Yeah.
That improv is gigantic.
I think it's 600 plus seats,
right?
Isn't it?
It's a palace.
You know?
That's a big goddamn place.
Now when you think about how many shows
you're doing two shows on a Friday night
and 600 seats.
Holy Shit Man.
That's a.
that's a good day here.
Show.
That's a theater show.
It's hard to get that many people to
come to her and it's like,
oh,
you're dying.
What?
Your Voice.
Because that's the new impression.
This is a,
this is mafia Doug Benson data.
Come on the watering a podcast pretty
much over.
What do you think?
You know,
since I can't talk anymore,
is that really your voice now?
For like a minute or two?
I just like know you're serious.
Wow.
Yeah.
Because I was on one of those tirades
where we want something to drink and
take a breath.
Do you want a water or something?
I got a water.
Okay.
You're okay.
Damn.
I never seen anybody before fall apart.
I mean you're okay.
I not read about it.
I'm falling apart.
Just vocally fall apart.
I'm trying to pull it back faster than I
normally would.
But.
So when did you start doing this?
You don't do any weekends anymore.
You don't do like a regular weekend and
the club?
Uh,
some every once in a while,
but for the most part the smaller club
that I,
you don't do that.
I really like.
You don't do midnight Saturday shows do
you,
do you ever do.
That's ridiculous.
Three shows in one night.
That's the other thing I like about
doing the four slash 20 shows or,
or even 8:00,
but it's the only show I love doing one
show.
Like comics would like to go from club
to club to club,
you know,
like to do that.
Will you have a,
you,
you like to like you have a big chunk.
You do what will you do?
Like an hour or so what do you do?
Like I do 45 a standup and then an extra
15 or 20 of,
you know,
playing the game and fucking around with
the crowd and that's pretty much all
people want to see.
And then you're done.
You feel like you did it.
You don't want to Redo it.
Yeah.
It's weird.
It's weird,
you know,
it's not a movie where they just started
up again and it's the same thing again.
Well,
the real problem with second shows that
sometimes I'll be in the middle of the
second show when I'll go,
did I do this?
But yet,
because I can't remember because I've
gone through a whole show and now I'm in
the second show.
Again,
when you're on stage,
you're pretty much in this zone and I'm
in the zone and I'm like,
I'm in the zone.
I've been his own for a long time,
but did I know I did that?
Did I do that earlier?
I don't.
I don't know if I did that joke.
Holy Shit.
And then you panic.
You're like,
was that the first show or is it the
second show?
Should I try this?
And then you go into it and you're like,
oh my God.
And you kind of have your bits tend to
be,
you know,
on the,
on the longer end,
like they don't really,
you don't really bring up things that
are super brief.
So much of a case if it's a really short
joke,
right.
Gets a big laugh when I say it again,
because it was like,
yeah,
he's,
he said it again.
You don't ever play up the fact that
you're,
hi.
I heard about people doing like fake
shots.
I'm like,
man,
I can't be fake shots.
That's terrible.
No,
but yeah,
if the intention is to like,
hey everybody,
I'm doing a shot.
But if I tell the staff,
send me up fake shots.
If people offer to buy me one really
because I don't.
I hate it.
You can't say no when a shot comes up to
you,
unless you're like a.
If you go,
I'm an alcoholic or something.
I'm,
I'm six years sober.
I'm not going to do it.
But with my act and the fact that I've
already got a cocktail up there,
they'll send me up shots and you know,
sometimes I'll do them and I'm fine with
it.
But a lot of reserves the right to drink
fake shots.
Yeah.
Well,
and you know,
it's just,
it just gets it over with.
If you just drank a fake show telling
everybody.
Yeah,
I'll never do it again.
Yeah.
People are going to know now now the
secrets on your game son.
But once you know what I mean,
you,
if you do the shot quickly,
it's over with.
But if you stand there and act like
you're not going to do it,
then people started chanting worse
wouldn't be out of it.
Now.
All the people that went to shows before
going to think back at the times,
you threw a shot back and screamed
yeehaw and jumped up and they don't act
like God damn.
I don't act it too,
too big.
I just,
I just pretend to drink it because even
when I normally drink Assad,
I usually don't make a lot of noise on
top of the glass and it's just a glass
of water and I do a whole song and dance
numbers.
The glass against the wall fucking guts
or is it on his tip?
All that and we find out you were just
stone cold,
sober drinking water,
putting on a show.
Fuck.
I'd have to say that I,
it's probably happened maybe four times
in entire career.
I've never dressed.
The combination of me saying to the
staff send me up a fake shot combined
with somebody wanting to send me up a
shot because it doesn't happen every
show because I'm not.
So what happens to the money laundering
going on here where it was a fake shot
is not worth anything.
They're charging someone for a shy.
Well,
regular shots barely worth the price of
a.
It doesn't seem like there's money
that's unaccounted for there.
Yeah.
Money Laundering,
I think that Shit's illegal.
Well,
let me tell you how I balanced it out in
my,
uh,
the rest of my years as a comic is when
people,
when I'm at the bar and a comedy club
and somebody offers to buy me a drink,
I always turn it down and say I get the
club gives me free drinks and I don't
want you to buy one.
And then a lot of times they go,
I want to buy you one anyway.
Like it becomes important to do
something for you,
which I appreciate the bat,
but it's frustrating to have,
you know,
that kind of argument with somebody,
like,
don't spend your money,
you don't spend your money.
So people that have,
you know,
I don't know,
they have a chance to meet you for the
first time.
It's important to them.
I understood I was still standing right
there and talk to them.
I don't say I don't want you to drink
and run away if they want to give you
something,
you know,
it's a gesture that's why never turned
down.
We'd.
When people give me,
we'd really,
you trust it all.
You don't ever think,
man,
I could be smart to have this
conversation before you're.
You're on the more paranoid interest the
whole week thing that I am.
I've never looked at him like,
oh my God,
I'm not taking that.
That looks like.
Yeah,
I just think it's such a.
it's such a crap shoot.
I mean,
let's say I probably smoked from
strangers,
either a bud they gave me or some sort
of joint.
It must be in the thousands at this
point.
Wow.
So nothing's happened yet.
So the odds seem incredibly good that
I'll get through a few more years of it
do.
I'm so happy for you.
I'm glad.
I'm glad you pulled through it.
Mti.
It's dangerous.
That's great.
Do you ever worry about what's dangerous
provocateurs?
Perhaps comps posing as donors want to
get high with you,
go to their current of trouble because
the voice of the movement people
craziest when Willie Nelson's tour bus,
that seems like it's really.
And get them for pot.
Come on,
come on,
find something else or just leave him
alone,
but he's in trouble for that.
You know,
they were letting him off the hook,
but then,
uh,
they,
you know,
someone get offended that the fact that
he,
uh,
is above the law,
above the wall.
Yeah.
So some idiot kind of fed into the whole
thing.
This Texas man,
you don't understand texts as well.
A lot of places.
I don't understand that.
Texas is a real tricky one.
There's some big cities and then there's
some fucking people that live in a time
warp.
You know,
there's,
you've got Dallas,
you got Houston,
you've got Austin,
you've got San Jose,
San Antonio,
you know,
you got,
you got some cool cities and then on top
of that you've got these weird spots in
between the cities that go on forever
and ever.
And they're massive.
There's so much room in Texas,
man.
It's a country,
you know,
it really is,
is a giant ass fucking state.
But boy do I love that Austin though.
Oh,
that's the best that,
that's one of my favorite cities of all
time.
Anywhere full time.
And that's where I'm going to cap city
club.
You played there.
Oh yeah.
I love that.
I'm going to do,
I'm not only might doing for 20 shows,
I'm combining my other thing that I love
to do now,
which is podcasts and I add 4:20
on thanksgiving weekend on Saturday and
Sunday I'm doing a two different tapings
of my podcast that I'll then be able to
cap city got will.
Then be able to turn around and put out
on the Internet because that's the only
thing I don't.
I don't like about stand.
I love about stand up comedy.
The fact that it's just you and the
audience and no one else hears it,
but thanks to podcasting,
I'm feeling I want to get more stuff out
to people right now.
So this is a great opportunity for me to
show up in a town and instead of doing
standup,
I do the podcast.
So you're saying that you can't put your
standing up on the Internet?
Well you can't.
You know how I am going to do a thing
coming up soon.
I think my next album is going to be two
discs.
One is me,
like I'll wake up the day of the shows
and I won't smoke pot all day,
maybe even stopped the day before or
something and just be crazy,
super sober for the first recording and
then between the first show,
the second show,
smoke as much weed and do as much as I
can and then try to do the exact same
set again,
try to do the album again and then
people can listen to both and see the
good and the bad news.
Your conclusion one into.
Yeah,
and was like Doug Benson banked and
unbanked or stoned and unstained or
something like that.
But the illusion was it 2002.
Two versions of it are two different
Algos.
Two completely different animals.
So Brian was just having fun.
He's a silly boy.
Yeah,
he just says things this motherfucker.
So you'll sell a one or the other?
Is that we won both.
You're buying double album.
You bought them both.
Okay.
And I also dream of a day where I can do
a tour where like,
you know,
how a pearl jam sold like every night of
the tour on,
on the CD that one time and,
and bootlegs obviously happened to
everybody all the time and I'd like to
make my own bootleg and just make like
do a tour of 10 cities and the same act
essentially that whatever I'm doing at
that time and then a recorded in each
place and you can buy,
you can buy more than one if you want to
see the differences or you can just buy
the one from the city or from,
from a city you think will be funny to
hear me interacting with people of that
city.
That's a funny idea.
And have a bunch of different recordings
to choose from.
Um,
some comics used to sell recordings of
the show that you just went to.
Yeah.
So like cds at a club or two has tried
to kind of toy with that sort of idea.
A lot of Goddamn cds.
But it also doesn't,
it only appeals to the drunkest audience
members yelled out the dumbest Shit,
you know,
it's kind of a weird thing to say here
by what you just what just happened.
But that's what I'm doing with podcasts.
Like I do podcasts where people were
there live and then they listen to it
later.
It's like their email address and you go
here,
I'm going to send you a link to where
you can buy this for five bucks.
You have your podcast setup where some
of them are free,
some of them aren't weekly free one of
one week.
There's bonus free ones that I do like
where I record,
like if I'm in a rental car with another
comic,
I'll just record an episode of the show
while we're driving.
And so I put those up pretty frequently
and then like once or twice a month,
usually once a month I'll have a episode
that's $2 in the comedy album section of
Itunes,
which is a fun place to be and to be
that cheap because like right now one of
mine is like number one because it's
only $2.
And then all the album or the album is
behind it costs like eight bucks.
So you get a nice,
cool,
nice placement for a little while and
then it falls pretty fast because,
you know,
people will buy it later,
but most people buy it right away or you
know,
shortly after it goes,
becomes available and it's,
you know,
the money.
So you off air,
how much the money as well,
you know,
it's,
I don't know if it's,
it's just a different route.
Gang signs at me,
it's a different route that I've gone
instead of,
uh,
instead of having actual advertisers not
against having advertisers,
I just have already gathered,
found the right match.
Yeah.
People just kept the ones that every
other podcast has.
And I did those for awhile and I just
felt like if I listen to a bunch of
podcasts,
if I had to always hear about audible
books,
every podcast I listened to about one
800 flowers.
Doug,
I never did that one.
But yeah,
I are Adam and eve or whatever.
I wouldn't want to hear about the same
thing all over the place.
I think each show should have its own
thing.
Unfortunately for me,
movie studios can't really support me
because I trashed movies and I can't get
like a movie theater chain to support me
because people go see movies at the
theater near their house.
Do you ever feel like confined by the
theme of your podcast?
The movie thing?
Yeah.
Well I would,
if I were you and you know,
like your,
your interest in and the amount of
movies you see is so far fewer than than
what I do,
so like I could see where that could be
limiting.
If you just feel like a movie,
why would you choose that?
You know what I mean?
Just you.
If you weren't a comic and you were in,
you were in,
you worked in UFC like you do,
would you,
would you think you'd be able to find
ongoing satisfaction just talking about
UFC as a podcast?
Sure,
definitely.
Yeah,
so that's,
that's how much I love movies.
It's just that I could just,
I could talk on and on and on,
but if I just said,
dude,
just a UFC podcast every week,
I'd feel a little defined by it or you
would because you've got so many other
areas that you're interested in,
but I'm saying like somebody who's just
really,
that's their main focus,
like because for me,
growing up,
my main focus was just movies.
Like I wanted to watch them and be in
them and that's all I cared about.
Do you do,
do you write scripts for the two?
Of course.
Uh,
yeah,
a little bit,
but I've,
you know,
I've grown really,
I,
that's the good and bad of podcasting is
it's allowed to talk about and
participate in what I want to do without
ever having to sit by myself and write,
you know,
like the process of just sitting and
writing something while the outcome is
very satisfying.
Like right now I'm working on a book and
it's,
you know,
it's torture for me to sit down and
write a chapter of my book.
Why?
Because they're just sitting there by
myself.
Writing is just not,
it's no fun to me.
I want to always have,
you know,
a TV on or listening to something or
watching something going,
you know,
going out and doing something.
Go to starbucks.
What is that exactly?
Is that.
Those guys are,
that's what they are.
It's like I do enjoy sometimes sitting
in a whole foods or something and
getting work done on my computer because
it's fun to have all that weird stimuli
around you,
but you can still just kinda look at
your,
what you're doing.
Well,
just look up whenever.
Anything interesting because your ideas
too when you're looking around.
Like if you have your twitter handy,
it's like you know,
you see something stupid ass.
Especially when you're paying bills.
Yeah.
We gotta wrap this picture but that's
the thing I do like thank God I do have
the marijuana,
not God,
but you know what I mean.
Jesus.
Yes.
Thank Jesus.
I have to have marijuana because that
does help to make writing less boring
and frustrated.
Doug Benson,
things writing is boring.
Thank you doug.
Thanks for being on the podcast.
Doug Benson and follow him on twitter.
At [inaudible],
G,
b e n s o n son Benson,
pitches respect and follow the desk
squad on itunes a thank you to the flush
loads.
If you go to Joe Rogan.net
and click on the link for the flashlight
and enter in the code name Rogan,
you get 15 percent off your new
girlfriend.
And don't forget,
fuck those things.
Use it,
abuse it,
and follow what Doug's instructions.
Our thank you to [inaudible] dot com o n
n I t,
makers of Alpha brain,
the cognitive enhancement,
substance and supplement.
And um,
thank you to uh,
also a new mood.
The other new thing that they got and
shroom tech,
which is the,
um,
the athletic performance enhancing
supplement.
That's legal.
It's the Chinese,
uh,
Olympic team used it.
It's a quarter seps mushroom supplement
that's a really good for it.
Gives you like a little boost of extra
endurance when you're in heavy duty
hardcore training and you're working out
hard.
Um,
so that's on it.
Dot Com,
O n n I t.
and if you go to [inaudible] dot net and
click on the link for the flashlight and
entering the code name or no,
not the fleshlight.
Click on a link for O,
n n I t on it.com.
The Alpha brain link.
You know what I'm talking about?
Bitches.
Click on that shit.
Put in my name and save some money or
don't do whatever you want,
man.
I'm not fucking telling you what to do.
Doug Benson a telling anybody what to
do.
No,
no sir.
No Sir.
We might have smoked too much pot before
this podcast.
Just a little bit more,
but a little bit in the middle of it
too.
In the middle of it.
Maybe in Doug will be joining us
tomorrow in that corner.
Yeah.
Dugald be joining tomorrow.
Tomorrow.
We're going to
be doing the Ice House tomorrow with the
Ice House in Pasadena.
The second stage,
you want to go to stage two?
It's a small place to only 85 seats.
It's probably going to sound really high
end.
Tweeted it yet,
but we're going to tweet it right after
we get off this podcast,
but they're awesome.
Shows we do them there as much as
possible.
Last time we did it,
it was a packed house,
and this time we got John Reed,
we got Benson,
Yoshi,
and a secret surprise.
And no secret surprise.
It's going to be a big fat fucking
chilled out party.
So enjoy.
So,
uh,
thank you to everybody and we'll see you
dirty bitches tomorrow.