Fight it.
We'll do it live well to alive.
Fuck it.
We'll do it live.
Dad will go down in history as one of
the all time,
like hissy fit remixes too.
Did you ever see the bill o'reilly Remix
a dance remix?
I was.
I was amazed by that.
With bill o'reilly were he was going.
No,
don't.
They're gone.
Yeah,
we're gonna.
That's what we're going to do.
I don't know what that means to play us
out.
I'm like,
how do you know what it means to play a
so angry?
So angry?
Yeah.
He's an angry man.
What?
What we were talking before the podcast
started about some the.
No,
no,
no.
I'm talking about.
That's insider information.
Being at Fox for years.
I can't,
but I'll let her go,
but can you can talk about moby though
right here we can talk about Mobi.
Mobi says he has like inside information
about Donald Trump that he knows that
Donald Trump talked to the Russians.
First of all,
when you look at Mobi with his fucking
Hashtag Vegan tee shirt on,
do you really think anybody in the
Russian fucking intelligence communities
talking to moby?
Actually,
it would be a brilliant ploy from the
Russians.
They just give a little info to moby
like you go.
You tell them and he's going to do it,
you know,
you definitely leaked decent formation.
Wouldn't be the downfall.
Then they found out he wasn't Enya and
they'd made a mistake.
He,
um,
he,
my mom was a wardrobe style,
so costume designer for a show called
[inaudible].
It's like the French Canadian sort of
Letterman,
like Kinda like Graham Norton in
England,
so they'd have stars coming all the
time.
And moby was there.
He was just a headcase.
The guy was just absolutely out of his
mind.
Nothing was good enough and you would
want something and then say he wanted to
change it.
Like what kind of things did he want to
change?
I don't know.
I can tell you this.
There were only two people who made my
mom like,
come home crying.
One was Brett Butler and uh,
she just thought live from grace under
fire was all pilled out of her head in
the nineties when she was crying to my
mom.
She was the wardrobe person you might
have,
even if you did one of the gallows and
never did the gallows because I wanted
me to work clean.
Did they put you in the nasty shell?
So it was always on the advertising and
I was on my own shows.
After awhile I would do my own shows.
But the,
uh,
the Gallo,
they were always like,
you have to be cleaned.
I'm like,
not interested.
Yeah,
I understand being cleaned for Canadian
TV for no money.
Thanks though with that flip side is the
nasty show.
Like just don't market it that way.
Just make,
make the show and everyone coming like
I'm going into the nasty shit.
Yeah.
But they liked it.
That was,
they would go to see it and it would be
like the way that the festival would
sort of differentiate.
I Dunno,
I dunno not the worst name for a show.
I guess.
It just seems like it just seems like,
like they're little kids in the school
year,
like he said,
a bad word.
Like we know Comedians,
you know it's going to be a ra show,
dirty,
nasty.
Speaking to nasty.
We are gentlemen today and we have
pipes.
Oh yeah,
because crowder had a crowder by the
way,
I don't think.
No,
I don't ever do that.
We just started talking.
Steven crowder,
who's from louder with crowder is
Internet show and he has a thing on his
internet show where you have like a
little pipe.
What would you it like a trolley would
you call the trials to pipe crack pipe
rack.
Okay.
I wanted to come up with a better name
than the name.
So you went to Mr Rogers' neighborhood
right away.
I saw it.
I said I always wanted to smoke a pipe
man.
I just think they smell good to know
that that's actually for my,
my brother out there.
That's called a seer sucker.
You.
So your brother is a serious pike?
He knows more than I do.
So this isn't like a seersucker the type
of suit.
I know that's what they call it.
Let's say they called this all kinds of
weird names like lane one.
Q is really common is actually really.
It smells really nice and interesting
English blends,
which he smokes.
That's we don't want to do.
Then I was super heavy nicotine,
but a lot of Kia.
You get some perico.
Very smoky,
like instancy barbecue.
We have some done killed dunhill night
camp,
which it'll.
It'll put you to sleep.
So how much do you put in?
So sorry I.
People Are Thinking yes,
no,
here.
Here's the rule.
So we're gotta do is put it up to the
brim,
up to the brand.
Just kind of the brand.
Pack it in there.
No,
no,
don't pack it in yet.
The general rule is the first one.
You Tamp it down with your finger.
The strength of a child.
Then you fill it again,
the strength of a woman and you fill it
a third time with the strength of a man.
Okay,
so fill it just barely now.
Then more strength of a woman.
Well,
what kind of a woman man?
Like a Chris Cyborg?
No,
not like a cyber.
Let's not talk about that because that
can go sideways and this show.
Okay,
well it's already gone sideways.
The fact that I said her name,
she's like,
candy man,
I'm going to have a job than a man.
Kind of a man.
Like a Mobi.
Men are like me.
I'm,
I'm saying,
well not get jared.
Just his arm wrestling.
Courtney,
who's like super crossfit extraordinary
this week.
She's really strong.
She likes go onto 65.
Whoa,
that's a lot.
But I think he's gonna smoke on the
armrest thing.
So this is the think that.
Well,
people can tune in and watch.
I think he's a man.
So he texted me right away.
Well she thinks he's going to win too.
Wow,
I bet the bet is like 74.
Yeah.
So you tamp that down.
Tamp it.
Like what?
You want us to be a little springy.
Okay,
I got a little spring you there?
Yeah.
Little springy running on moss perhaps.
Yes.
Exactly.
Okay.
And then,
uh,
I didn't.
You got to file.
I do too.
So when you do is you light it once and
that's what we call the charring light.
So we're going to do is you're gonna see
that already turned me off by the way.
Only tobacco in that pipe or it'll ruin
the briar.
Let's meet me if I closed.
We eat in there.
It'll fuck it up.
Will you won't be able to taste the
tobacco from there forward.
Yeah.
Because it'll taste like something so
around in a circle.
And I do not want you to do it.
Gosh.
And then,
uh,
you're gonna see that tobacco kind of
raise up.
So puff it.
Keep puffing on it.
Yeah.
And then you tamp it down one more time.
Once it goes out and then you light it
again.
Okay.
So super involved.
I know it is.
It's,
it's not one thing.
It's not something you just kind of
lightened go and it won't last long.
Hold on.
Immediate head rush by the way.
Really?
Oh by the way,
don't inhale it.
Just puff it too late.
Well,
about bots.
Bowker broke.
Well you don't want hail that.
There's no filter on that.
What are your busby?
What I'm saying,
that's like you'll get actual chunks of
tobacco in your lungs.
There's no,
that's a big,
big.
Maybe you will.
Not me,
bro.
Probably.
You touched some matches over.
Hear you bro.
But smell that smell nice.
I got an a on it now.
Um,
do I use a lighter?
Can I use the lighter?
As long as it's not a jet lighter
because that'll damage the briar.
So like I said,
it's not A.
I like it.
I feel like a,
a distinguished gentlemen,
like who's at a Nigel Farrage.
No,
no.
He's not distinguished.
He's an asshole,
but he's a lot of fun.
It was fun to listen to them talk to
people.
I love when you guys had that thing,
when he a thug life,
the thug life thing.
It was hilarious on your own.
Not Gay.
Jarrod came over and gave you a lap
dance and getting silly.
Yeah.
We got word that night or liked that
show.
I don't know how true it is,
but.
Well,
you guys are one of the very few.
I mean you're a conservative guy,
but I would say you get a bad rap dude.
You really do.
That's one of the reasons why I like you
is because you are.
You're a pretty much fact oriented guy
when it comes to a lot of issues,
political issues,
social issues.
You don't bullshit and you don't.
You don't like try to sway things toward
one side or the other when it's not
accurate.
Well,
I appreciate that and by the way these,
you know,
these probably will go out.
You have to relight it because it's just
kind of an art.
So I've had people talk to me about you
and they give me this bullshit take on
you and I know he's a smart guy.
I go,
he's just.
Yeah,
he's conservative.
So yeah,
I know a lot of people that are liberal
to a lot of people that are in the
middle.
What you can't talk to someone because
they appreciate that and that's to,
not to kiss him,
but people out there that need to know
that Joe has been incredibly fair and
very kind behind the scenes you have
like because there do,
you have every reason not to and I think
a big reason of it honestly.
Yeah.
Here's a good example,
the young Turks,
and we've seen this transition with
trump or people who were really afraid
to speak out.
Now you're seeing that change online
because the establishment has been
Barack Obama,
so kids who were raised for eight years
under Bushmen,
eight Bush,
you know,
listen to no effects,
go to the vans warped tour,
whatever it is,
and now they've been raised under Obama
for eight years and all this political
correctness run amok and they're
rejecting that.
So for the longest time I had this small
youtube channel and I was on Fox so it
was kind of muddled a little bit because
I was there and there were certain
things that I could say or couldn't say
online because it was a liability young
issue at the time as well as to take you
seriously.
That's 21 years old.
Yeah.
He a little fresh faced little lad now.
You're not even that old now holding
that 29.
You're a young fellow.
Well,
um,
and so what happened is they kind of had
their interpretation from whenever the
young Turks said about me because when I
had 50,000
subscribers it was like their day job to
go after me and now when I've had Alex
Jones and we'd been doing proactive
parodies of the young Turks,
call them out asthma debate,
they will trash talk every conservative,
not named Steven crowder.
It's like I'm Voldemort,
my name won't be spoken when at 50,000
subscribers they would talk about me all
the time and they had,
you know,
a million or 2 million.
Now that's changed and people were able
to come here directly and only that you
will give me your lighter.
The matches are getting annoying.
Yeah.
Thank you.
So,
um,
I,
you know,
I like to think,
but you know,
there's also the real possibility that
people just don't like me because I'm
kind of a Dick.
Well,
you can be a dick sometimes,
but you're a funny Dick.
Like you do some funny shit.
Like one of the things that you did that
was really funny was a will.
What was that feminist rally thing that
you went to?
The recent one where?
The tranny.
Yeah,
and I actually interviewed Wendy Davis.
I don't think you're supposed to as a
trainee,
Bro.
Yeah,
I don't really.
Well,
so that's why people don't like me
sometimes,
but I think now you're seeing more
people say that they don't care.
I think it's funny when they start
making words taboo,
I really do like people said tranny
forever and then all of a sudden it's
like disparaging like,
okay,
I haven't noticed in the new build burst
special.
He said like,
Oh,
what are you going to deal?
You'll fucking Mary.
And I said,
I was like,
he would've said fag four years ago
because he did in his special and used
the word Mary talking about like a sissy
hasn't.
Like that's not a.
that's not a word we ever heard him use
before.
Oh,
Bill uses that word.
Duh.
Yeah,
that's a Boston word.
Yeah.
You fucking marry people called guys
Mary's.
Well,
he's probably.
Maybe he's trying to be a little bit
more politically correct.
You know what I do?
I use the word,
but I do it in character.
Yeah,
because if I say like Faggot,
like,
well,
I didn't say it.
Nigel said it.
That was not me.
I had this joke about tigers in Texas
because I don't know if you know my,
my,
uh,
this is a true story from my last,
a Netflix special.
There are more tigers in captivity in
Texas than there are in all of the wild,
the world in private collections,
in people's backyards.
There are more tigers in Texas than the
rest of the fucking planet earth.
That is a fact.
That is a real step because they can
have them.
Just a bunch of dentists who carried him
back just because I know people that
know people that have tigers.
I know people in Texas who's friends
have tigers.
It just,
you can have a title.
Are you aware?
By the way,
what's the biggest category?
You probably know this,
but the biggest,
a predatory cat.
Do you know what it ligers,
but it's not.
They're not viable.
They can't breathe.
Well,
I thought the lion at first tiger with
so much bigger back in the Roman Roman
times and the coliseum.
This is what,
and I can't entirely corroborate this,
I will say this,
corroborate it.
When you do the lions,
the lions have to be on three points and
can Paul,
where's the Siberian tigers would
leverage back in pounds.
Yeah.
Said it wasn't even close.
Not to mention that the tigers are way
bigger,
but they were able to just go back on
their two legs,
whereas the lion has to have three
points of contact,
which is like a dog given the POC.
Yeah.
So when I saw him I was like,
well that's,
that's something that's pretty
incredible because you see a lion.
I mean,
you know,
you're,
I saw the ghost in the darkness and
that's pretty,
pretty scary.
Well,
it's not even close to mountain lion
will fuck you up dude.
Like just a small mountain line.
That 80 pound mountain lion fuck you up.
But a Siberian tiger will fuck you up in
ways you couldn't possibly imagine.
Well,
I have a dog hopper,
Dogo Argentino.
Oh,
those are big dogs.
Well you can google it too.
They're not.
They are not trained them good.
But their sketch.
Well he is.
He ran for president with Dean Cain and
he had like a few hundred votes,
which I felt bad about cause it was a
gag.
So who knows if that changed the state
of Michigan.
But by the way,
if it starts going out,
you put two fingers over,
kind of create a slipstream and suck it
in and I'll give you.
Probably not now.
You probably need to relate it.
It's not like a cigar.
It's not good to talk and smoke a pipe.
It's meant to be more contemplated.
But Bertrand Russell used to smoke a
pipe.
Trinity,
I don't know if you did it.
Are you doing the voice,
the voice to speak and it was a one.
It was one of the things like he wanted
to fly and he would only fly if he could
smoke on the plane because he was so
addicted to tobacco that he had to
constantly smoke.
There he is.
Look at him,
look at him smoking a pipe or a pipe.
That's how he would speak,
but it is,
um,
it is very relaxing because it's kind of
like Jujitsu.
You said you've used the term moving
meditation when you're sitting down
there outside.
At the end of the day,
if you don't focus on it,
it's going to go out.
It's not like a cigar.
It's not like a cigarette.
So you have to sit there and focus on
the draw,
focus on the exhale.
And all you're thinking about is,
is the pipe.
So it really is kind of a contemplate of
art.
No,
you're getting fucked up on tobacco.
Why you lying?
You're lying to people.
Um,
what were we talking about before?
That was tigers in Texas.
There's more time to bring her in May.
Dude.
You're going all over the place.
Run a youtube search on Doug Argentino
mountain lions.
You will see doug.
Argentina was messing up actual mountain
lions.
Yeah.
You know why?
Because the mountain lion wants to get
away.
It's probably true.
The amount of mine doesn't want to fight
to the death.
The mountain lion is a predatory animal.
Predatory animals don't necessarily
fight to the death.
It's one of the reasons why dogs are so
fucking dangerous because dogs are bred
to not feel pain,
not recognize me.
That's one of the things about pit
bulls.
They're not the biggest,
strongest dogs,
but they're bred to ignore pain and
that,
that drive to attack and ignore pain
makes some very problematic.
Just you just used the word problematic.
Let's,
let's span that word a little bit and
use an anecdote.
Smoking a pipe.
But uh,
yeah,
they are,
that's what they're bred for.
They're actually really people oriented
because they're bred to be protective of
people in hunt with people,
so they're not bred to fight dogs.
So a lot of actually people there was,
that's where we got robberies or rescue
out in,
in Michigan.
Um,
a lot of guys in the inner cities bought
them thinking this is like a bigger pit
bull.
They're going to be great dog fighters.
They were horrible and they just got
abandoned.
So there's all kinds of dog out there in
western Michigan.
I Dunno if there still are.
I'm wild dogs will just,
our dog howl.
I look cute.
That looks very much like guard dog or a
cute photo.
They're so big.
Such a big dog.
Ours,
a little bit of a runt.
He's about 90 pounds because he,
um,
we found him with a broken leg roaming
the streets.
Alopecia,
lyme disease.
So you rescue them right off the street?
Well,
no,
he was rescued into a lady who
specialized in Dagos and then we took
them from her and uh,
he's the most people oriented dog we've
ever seen.
I mean,
to the point where he'll actually,
the biggest problem you have is if you
stop petting him and you don't know him,
he'll growl free to keep petting him.
So kids and they're terrified her.
Well that seems like a Dickie dog.
Yeah,
a little bit.
I have a dog called a regency massive.
Oh yeah.
Those are no joke.
It's a neapolitan is bread with a pit
bull.
So there are about 140 pounds to get
with the athletes is great.
My kids ride him,
like literally ride them,
they get on top of him and he'll just
watch it again.
Pita on you for that.
Now these shouldn't be writing because
he's older now.
Poor,
poor fella.
He's like 11.
He's got some hip problems.
Susan walks with a limp.
Well,
thank you for having me back.
Even though part of your audience
doesn't like it,
but don't be defensive.
Don't say that.
Have you noticed a change,
a kind of a new sort of trump?
Well,
culturally I think there's.
I know this is sound sounds like a
broken record,
but counterculture why's he have a lot
of people who were afraid to even speak
up.
Even from the last time I was on the
show where they've been called racist,
sexist,
homophobic,
transphobic is a new thing we're in.
Was going.
You know what,
alright,
fine.
Let's go with that.
I think if you were to hold the election
today,
Donald trump would win in a landslide.
Wouldn't even be close.
Just because.
Yeah.
That's because of how bad the behavior
has been from the left.
All the rest of America.
I had my uber driver coming here and she
believed every lie.
Her name.
She was a Latino.
Why ever talked to Uber Drivers about
politics?
It always seems to end in a TMZ value.
Explain why I have a four point two
rating.
So I'm right at the threshold of losing
my uber privileges.
Are you serious?
So like you get a rating as a customer.
Yeah.
You get to rating as a customer.
What's a good rating?
A 10.
You have a four point two?
No,
no,
it's fine.
It's at a five.
Oh,
that's not that bad.
No,
it's not that bad.
But if you go,
you're out.
You're out.
So you go like someone could find you
right now.
Uber drivers could be like unite and
blackball you.
They could.
Well my friend,
uh,
I can't say his name because it's
illegal.
Actually had his concealed carry with
them in an Uber and he forgot his
magazine and that person rated him like
a one.
So it took one bad rating,
a drop his score because he had to call
them,
say,
hey,
um,
I think I forgot something in the back
of your car.
I'm like,
what is it?
Like a magazine?
It was like,
Oh,
like a people magazine.
And she's like,
no,
just look.
And the guy was just on the phone with
them saying,
what did you do in my car?
And he just said I was going to the
range.
He wasn't,
he carries a gun and I'm everywhere.
It's everywhere he goes.
But,
um,
this lady,
Uber La,
she decided to start talking about it,
talking about the women's March and
stuff.
So I just,
it's hard for me to say nothing,
but we ended up on very good terms,
but there's a different story.
This is not the message,
not the magazine story.
And she on drugs right now and the speed
or anything on new drugs.
It's very quick.
Everything's going quick.
Well,
I settled into the show.
I'm not.
Well,
I had that nitro coffee and I came from
coffee bean and tea leaf right already.
That is 270 milligrams caffeine.
So I've probably got about five,
600 milligrams.
So that's two grand day starbucks
coffees.
Seriously,
I think there's kind of the middle of
that 200.
Yeah.
It's closing,
closing in on two Grande's.
Um,
but she said,
she's like,
well,
Donald Trump called all Mexicans.
Rapists said,
no,
she was Donald Trump is gonna ruin gay
rights.
People want what?
Because it's because it's just in my
nature,
and I said,
well,
why?
She goes,
because Donald trump removed the gay
rights thing on the website as well.
What about the fact that all presidents,
they remove everything from the previous
administration and they put up new,
a whole new whitehouse.gov
website and these people,
they buy it in La.
They're in such an insular bubble.
I don't think they realize that there's
a whole bunch of people who voted for
Donald trump and I wasn't a fan of him
in the primaries,
but they didn't vote for him because
they're racist.
They didn't vote for him because I don't
want Caitlyn Jenner to take a dump at
trump towers.
They didn't vote for him because they
hate brown people.
They voted for him because they're tired
of being called all those things and
that's why I think you see a lot of
these young people who just kind of want
to be instigators and provoca tours,
but at the same time they're
appreciating more traditionalism and
some of the values that our parents
tried to instill in them because that's
kind of more rebellious and going along
with the entertainment industry.
Well,
there's always this sort of longing for
nostalgia that people exhibit.
There's always like back in the good old
days,
like back in the good old days is
bullshit because the good old days you
died of syphilis and the good old days
people got fucking plague from rats.
There was no good old days.
This is the good old days right now.
So there's always that.
There's always this longing for
nostalgia,
but I think.
I think you're right with some people,
but for sure there's some people that
are racist.
There voted for Donald trump just
because some people are racist.
Sure,
yeah,
of course.
But to try and paint,
I mean if you look at the numbers,
a huge percentage of people who voted
for Barack Obama had to have voted for
Donald Trump,
particularly in Michigan and
Pennsylvania.
There just aren't the numbers there
with,
don't you think that they probably voted
for him?
A lot of it is for economic reasons
because they thought that he's going to
loosen up some regulations,
encourage industry.
I think it's the opposite.
I think a lot of the Union voters,
they thought Hillary Clinton was in the
pocket of Goldman Sachs and they thought
Donald trump was his sort of economic
protectionism is going to bring jobs
back to the Midwest.
Um,
which encourage industry.
But that's one of the things I disagree
with the idea of.
For example,
I've been in Michigan,
the unions have a stranglehold.
I would rather be able to move to Texas
or anywhere they want to be competitive
in the car market,
but I can't even get to that because as
soon as I'm going,
we don't.
Hold on.
Donald trump made a mistake here.
I disagree with them because then
there's a women's march where their
lighting hair on fire and calling him
literally Hitler and sliding hair on
fire.
What do you mean?
At the woman's March girl got her hair
lit on fire.
A girl?
Yeah.
By someone with one of those pussy hat
and say,
you know what,
man?
The thing about that stuff is it's
always one fucking person or a couple
people out of hundreds of thousands that
are acting in that mob mentality and
interrupt violence.
Shit.
Incorrect.
Oh,
come on,
man.
There's not that many people that do
violence shit.
At those women's marches,
there was no arrests?
No.
Every.
Well there are no rest of the lansing
protest either where they cut down a
tent with box cutters.
There were,
there were the lansing protests when it
went right to work.
That was a big thing where I was there,
but even the inauguration protest.
That's the one you got punched?
Yeah,
I did get punched,
so that wasn't fun.
It's hilarious.
They couldn't punch.
Well.
I know,
but when you're not expecting,
why throw a punch when you don't know
how to punch.
Like,
come on.
Think about everywhere.
Leftists gather though,
whether it's woodstock back then.
Woodstock,
[inaudible],
99 Woodstock High Wall Street.
Violent.
Yes.
There are so many rapes.
How do you know you there?
There are reports of rape that's rapes
that occurred where they rape rapes or
were they like.
I think back then they were back then
Lena Dunham wasn't,
you know,
shoving fast food napkins.
And her sister's cooch claiming she was
raped because she saw the condom in a
potted plant.
So what?
Lena Dunham,
she claimed she was raped because she
saw the condom on a plant after she was
drunk and muscle relaxers.
I feel like we always go back to Lena
Dunham.
Yeah.
Um,
I didn't know about that story.
I knew that there was some sort of a
gross interaction with her younger
sister.
She was reaching inner inner,
inner,
Inner Vagina.
But the point is anywhere leftists
gather,
there's always violence and
exaggeration.
I mean,
when the women's March,
no violence,
there was no arrest.
There was no nothing else that can you
say there was no violence,
but people said there was no violence at
all of these other marches.
Right.
Girls I can.
It's like isolated incidents,
but when you have to look at a trend,
right?
I'm not saying everyone got a million
people in la.
A million people march,
right?
It's 970,000
people.
Okay,
but you have way more than that with the
tea party,
which was accused of being racist.
Not One minute.
There are way more than that.
No,
no,
no.
You never had a march in la that had
more people than 970 across the country
with the first year.
Yeah.
More people across the country with the
tea party.
There's no way.
Hold on a second.
Not a model.
The day of the women's March when there
were hundreds of thousands of people all
over the country marching together in
one day.
There was never a movement like that for
the tea party.
Yes.
There was a day with the tea party.
Had One day,
the one day Glen Beck,
100,000
in Washington DC.
Okay.
That's less than was in la for the
women's,
but across the country because there
were so many.
Like in Dallas,
there were four or five different ones.
I crossed out the same day.
Come on in the same day.
Now,
not how many different city here's had a
march like that for the tea party.
They were in hundreds of cities,
hundreds of cities simultaneously in one
day,
and it was bigger than the women's
march.
Certainly comparable with a comparable,
comparable and not a single incident,
and they left.
The place is cleaner than they found
them.
You look at occupy Wall Street,
suite 500 crimes including felonies.
You look at the women's March,
let's disregard the crime people up
there with pussy hats,
bringing their two year old with the
most profane,
disgusting signs you can imagine when
leftist congregate.
It's generally not a peaceful assembly,
not in the same way as when people who
are right wing congregate.
Look at Berkeley,
Jake shields of Vegan from Berkeley is
becoming a vegetarian from Berkeley is
becoming conservative because if he just
said this was,
this was the rule,
not the exception in Berkeley.
Well I know Jake,
he's a buddy of mine and essentially he
was saying that these people that were
doing what they're claiming they're
fighting fascist.
He's like,
you're being a fascist.
Do you understand what a fascist means
using violence to enforce your ideology
and your tolerating no deviations from
that ideology that is being a fascist.
Yeah.
Pipe smoker blows,
bro to the on your own.
It takes too much effort.
But um,
but we had them on the show and he was
saying like,
you know,
I just,
it's changed where the left.
We need to call this out and we need to,
we need to take ownership over this and
when you need to squash it because it's
becoming a real problem.
It's also a problem when you say the
left,
the left or the right,
because it's not necessarily just the
left.
It's these fucking idiots.
They go to these things and put masks on
and want to beat people up and mace
women.
I saw that girl with a make make bitcoin
great again hat.
She had a joke hat and someone hit her
over the head with a stick.
Yeah,
that was holding up a sign and then
another guy master face.
I mean,
and they think that they can spend it on
people getting pulled out of cars,
getting punched,
you know,
occupy Wall Street.
You had people putting bloody rags on
tents that they claimed had aids.
I mean anywhere.
Again,
just go back through history in the last
decade,
it's very different and not saying all
left,
right?
We're speaking.
You have to speak in generalities to
save time.
But as a general rule,
if you look at the right,
if you look at,
for example,
the tea party,
you look at the movement,
people who were complaining about the
stimulus package,
you look at people at economic problems
with Barack Obama.
They didn't riot.
They didn't beat people up in record
numbers.
There was not a single trash can lid on
fire thrown through a window.
That seems to be a common occurrence at
these leftist protests.
Well,
it is now.
It is now.
It certainly isn't now power.
Well,
it's also these people feel like what
Donald Trump represents is the worst
possible scenario for the right.
They feel like he represents this,
like really arrogant businessman who
promotes rape culture and grabbing
pussies and you know,
that's how,
that's how they're looking at it.
So they're like,
it's time to act like there was some
woman who was on Fox News,
the other.
Who's the one that Dude Tucker.
Tucker Carlson.
Yeah.
Is he a Fox News Guy?
He's.
He used to be CNN on crossfire and he
had some woman on and she was talking a
little Asian.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
She's a fucking school teacher.
She's talking about Bob Blop and I was
like,
this is crazy.
Like she's talking about.
She called Milo Yiannopoulos,
who's a gay Jew by the way.
She called them homophobic and prefers
prefers black men.
Yeah,
I mean,
but how do you call it gang guy?
Homophobic.
Just what?
Everyone's a Nazi now.
I mean,
I was not for trump in the primary so I
could call the Kuk right.
And I was like,
well listen,
he's,
he's the most liberal Republican ever.
People don't want to talk.
He's the only one,
a Democrat,
most of his last president to ever take
office being pro gay marriage when he
was sworn in.
Barack Obama can't even claim that.
That's true.
It was the first person.
That's something that people need to
recognize about Hillary Clinton.
She was anti gay marriage is recently as
2013.
She was,
she was speaking in 2013.
And she said,
I believe that marriage is a bond
between a man and a woman in 2013.
And she was making arguments to.
It wasn't like she was put on the spot
and well,
I think she was out there arguing
against same sex marriage.
So,
um,
you know,
my point here is they're out of power
and so they declare everyone a Nazi,
you know,
they declared me a Nazi,
they'll declare Milo Nazi.
And so if you say,
hey,
there,
it's okay to punch Nazis in the face.
If Hitler walked in here,
you'd probably have a tussle with Adolf
Hitler,
but it's acceptable if you
make me or even you or milo equivalent
to Hitler.
And that's what they're doing now.
And that's the point that I'm making is
I think because they behaved so poorly,
more Americans would,
would vote,
screw you with a lever and vote for
Donald trump now than they did under
member eighth.
I believe that's highly speculative.
It is highly strict crowder,
hence the pipe.
We can speculate and highly speculative.
Not sure if I buy it might maybe let me
present.
People are also freaking out.
They're freaking out about his
appointment of a Golden Sachs executive.
They're freaking out over what's
happening with that Flynn fellow who was
forced to resign because he was
coordinating with Russia and you know,
talking about removing sanctions before
they got into office and all that stuff.
Well,
that was a screw up.
But,
um,
you know,
and I'm not here to defend Donald Trump.
Screw up,
we call it trees.
It is by making them a five.
He's a whole new man.
Um,
it is delicious though,
isn't it?
It's good.
It really is good.
High as fuck right now.
Oh really?
Yeah.
He hits some marijuana after this.
Probably like takes it to the next
level.
Gets you high as fuck man.
That's pretty low in nicotine and
aromantic like that.
Yeah.
But I'm a rookie or you don't?
I don't smoke any weed.
Smoke a cigar.
Yeah.
That's pretty occasional.
Like maybe once a month I'll puff a
cigar.
Yeah.
Well,
yeah,
there you go.
You can keep that one.
That one's already broken in.
Can keep this pipe yet because there's a
real process with a pipe.
It's actually,
you know,
you have to smoke it really slow when
you first get it because the briar
expands.
So I know pure faggotry sending a
different voice.
Fuel faggotry and to them.
Um,
I don't know if that's a word.
Train them.
Let me present this.
Okay.
You take someone like Bernie Sanders,
son of a bitch,
he explained to relax.
Drink.
Do you drink?
I can't drink.
You drink some whiskey.
Let's get some whiskey up in here and we
need to make a beer if you have to.
Very.
We need drink,
drink real booze.
What do you want to talk about?
I just want to relax a little.
Okay.
I want you to be a human.
I don't want all these talking points.
These aren't talking fired up to fucking
defend the write and promote your
agenda.
I'll just.
Because I know you said people like to
think you're an asshole because you're
right wing.
I don't care what they think.
People think I'm a fucking meathead.
Well,
I'm right.
There are.
I am in a way,
very meat,
heavy,
strong,
not well.
I'm fucking.
I eat meat a,
I'm a cage fighting commentator.
I look like a meathead.
There's a lot of meathead qualities that
I possess.
Although I'm a kind person,
very openminded and more probably more
left than I am.
Right?
If you looked at a giant spectrum,
don't think so.
No.
No,
not anymore.
I just think it's such a narrow path on
the left.
There's so unaccepting of people.
That's why you've seen all this very
accepting in that way.
I mean,
I'm very accepting,
even have ridiculous ideas.
I want you to talk about them.
You know why?
I just think one of the real problems
that I have right now with all these
protestors and all these people that are
going crazy and calling everybody Nazis
is you're stifling communication and
you're stifling the marketplace of
Freddy's.
I want real booze broke.
Get up,
get out some whiskey straight.
What's good?
Even better.
Make it hurt.
Bring out some whiskey.
Trying to bring out that Alex Jones
whiskey the stuff that makes you talk
about interdimensional child molesters
actually stopped talking about pizza
gate.
Remember?
That was a big contract.
So you didn't want to have them on here.
Oh really?
Oh yeah.
Eddie was probably instigating.
Eddie was out of his fucking mind drunk.
He doesn't know what he did.
I remember you asked me the one thing
about this pizza.
Good thing.
And again,
I don't think it's going to go.
Um,
it may not be true,
but what do you think about what a
Bright Bart was saying?
Like way back in 2011 about pedesta that
pedesta like shields files.
Come on.
Don't be a pussy with a beer.
I'm going with a beer.
I have to go to the airport.
You and Jack gets marketing.
I think he gave it to me for free.
Fuck off.
Gentleman.
Gentleman,
Jack.
Jack Daniels did.
No,
no.
I like.
I enjoy Jack Town.
Actually never had gentleman.
Jack.
Yeah.
Now I'm well [inaudible] you asked me
about it in the first thing where my
antenna went up with pizza gate.
As I said,
Jane James Alefantis means I love kids
in French and I.
I know where they're trying to get it
from.
It's a Jim Lee's on fa.
That's not James Alefantis.
So right away when it's the PR,
the first premise that I read is a lie.
I'm going,
all right,
well there was a bunch of weird ones,
but there was some stuff that was like
really odd,
like the pizza place that had that
symbol.
That is the international fucking symbol
for pedophilia and trauma lasting and
beyond says in the Illuminati and.
But no,
this as a symbol that the FBI admits
that they use in these secret
organizations that when they capture
pedophiles,
which they do all the time.
Yeah,
they use that symbol.
I mean they agree upon that symbol that
says there's a lot of weirdness to it.
And here's the thing.
It could be,
this is my take on it and I'm not.
I don't have a side and I'm not,
I'm not claiming that I have any
knowledge,
but there absolutely are pedophile
rings.
They exist.
They have caught them before they busted
them before.
Like Jerry Sandusky kid just got busted.
I know yesterday.
That was the beauty of Michael Jackson.
The guy was so clever about it.
Think about it.
He screwed every kid in Hollywood except
Macaulay Culkin.
So he's at Canary in the coal mine.
Macola caulkins and no,
no,
I go to Neverland ranch.
He never touched me here.
That's what I would say to other kids
are coming back.
They still swear up and that's what I
would say.
It's like if you went,
if you went to a bachelor party and
everybody got their Dick sucked and your
wife said,
Hey,
what the fuck?
Bobby says he got his dick suck.
Not Me.
I don't know what I mean.
Maybe she just didn't like me.
You get up.
Macaulay Culkin has no reason to say
that now.
Yes,
he does.
Really?
Yeah.
Nobody wants to know that you got
molested by Michael Jackson.
You'll never get a girlfriend again.
Should we get one hell of a book deal?
Come on.
You shouldn't be about to go down on
you.
And she'll think,
oh my God,
Michael Jackson's right.
Don't you think you'll get one hell of a
book deal?
Well,
you know,
Andrew Breitbart actually not Breitbart
the trademark.
Andrew Breitbart,
the name is.
I mean,
he was actually,
I
got my start and um,
he wrote about that,
you know,
Neverland ranch.
His photographer was a pornographer who
specialized in European actors who
looked under age.
And so once he talked about this,
the guy was fired from Neverland ranch,
I think it was six months later he was
back.
So my point was like,
the pizza good stuff is there are things
that are provable like that,
which people can go search Andrew
Breitbart and find that story and
because people are cocked and loaded to
hate someone from the right online
cocked what you really do go into a
different voice was with nasty words.
That was my beavis and butthead voice.
Because of that,
I'd rather dwell on stories that we know
we can prove or commentary because it's
really easy to go,
oh,
crowder was wrong with pizza gate or
whatever it is.
So we just,
there's so much there that's real.
That's where I focus.
That's my issue with Alex Jones.
Alex Jones go super deep and I did not
know him before I had him,
that he was a sandy hook denier and I
saw that and it's pretty rough.
It hurt my soul.
It really did.
Yeah.
He's um,
he's been.
His son is a fan.
He's been really,
really good to me and coming on the
show.
He's done the young Turks sketches with
us.
I think he's doing less of the
conspiracy stuff now.
It seems like less now.
Get them,
get them drunk,
get them drunk and watch it come out.
Well,
it doesn't surprise me.
Alex has been my friend for a long time.
He's 84 percent crazy,
but uh,
he's,
he's like,
it's one of those things where if you
chase,
there's enough corruption and enough
crazy shit in the world that if you
chase it down,
you're going to find it right?
It's there.
But you got to be careful what you call
it,
corruption and what you call
conspiracies,
right?
Because there are a fuck ton of them
that he's missing the mark.
Like the sandy hook thing.
I mean that,
that,
that the sandy hook thing is so fucked.
There was a great article that was
written about a guy who was a conspiracy
theorist until his kid was killed at
Sandy Hook.
Right?
And then realized like,
Holy Shit,
like these people are telling me that my
kid didn't die when I realized how
dangerous this whole thinking that the
government spraying shit in the sky from
mind control mind control organization.
I've been told that I'm in the fucking
CIA.
Oh yeah,
there are people think I'm in the
Illuminati.
How do we get in?
I think they'd be Tuesdays.
Do you think you could get in or we.
Are you young to old?
Are you too young rather?
I have no idea.
I think you just need to have the all
seeing eye and one of your music videos
and you're in like flint.
That is it.
Do you just got to go like this?
I think they're doing diamonds.
He's saying I like diamonds.
Or is he like do it a little bit about.
Well,
I didn't realize diamond is also like a
black term for a lady's Nether regions.
Really?
I found that in a risque song.
Smell.
Yo Dick.
You hear that song on Youtube?
Yeah,
I like that.
I was wild and I wasn't clown like that.
He says diamond like that.
No,
it wasn't this feeling or die length
that like that.
I've heard of white people who are out
of touch with black culture.
That's.
That was ridiculous.
Welcome.
Welcome to me.
I didn't know I have to tune to jamie
because Jamie's on black twitter
everyday.
Jamie keeps.
He's done a vine must have been rough
for you.
Jamie's got tweet deck and he sets up
one hashtag black twitter and it's just
all black,
but it's all just black twitter
references and he tells me that people
steal from black twitter and they make
jokes on late night tv because yeah,
it's a subculture.
Yeah.
Black twitter.
They say funny shit and then people
steal it.
Is that true,
Jamie?
Is that what you just said?
What I heard,
that's the rumor.
That is what he heard.
I've heard that too.
Um,
when did women.
But speaking of which like black is a
subculture,
right?
We talked about minority groups.
I think you need another drink.
Women more whiskey.
I'll take to finish that.
No,
I didn't finish them on posts.
Come on.
That doesn't work on me yet.
So you weren't an Illuminati.
You're feeling men like that?
See diamonds a stripper.
Oh,
I was wrong all this time.
This whole thing up dude.
See you're spreading disinformation.
How much time and Dick,
wait a minute.
Hold on.
See that's not how a bitch get her ass.
Woke up.
That's just lazy.
How long reach get her.
I swab.
Yes,
please.
Promoting violence against women because
she wants to smell his dick.
She beats the hell out of her,
but that's lazy.
So to her,
that's not my fault song.
Right?
They didn't even introduce the character
diamond beforehand.
How am I supposed to know what we can't
know?
That's not a racism thing.
That's a bad song.
Okay.
If he said,
I ain't even feel in Mercedes like that,
would you assume?
Okay.
Mercedes is probably a stripper lapses
to the main stage probably,
but I don't.
I didn't read the lyrics so I didn't see
a capital and diamond.
I can't know this [inaudible] I was
trying to be understanding of another
culture and it backfired.
I'm gonna give you that.
Yeah.
Why isn't he just washed his dick?
Like when you go to the crab shack,
we have that automatic hand cleaner,
doesn't have hand sanitizer and keeps in
his fucking.
Ben's just spray thieves.
Essential oil.
Like my wife's not sure.
Dick Brown,
dirty bitch coming home with a dirty
dick.
Jesus.
That's worse than adultery start.
That's not his wife for sure.
First of all,
they're not married.
This is not a marriage we're talking
about.
This is not saying,
oh,
look at this.
More booze.
Bring it out.
Both bring them both out.
This guy needs to get drunk talks.
Too much shit.
Want we want to talk about everything?
Life Generale.
Okay.
Let's say this generally a,
I've never been as mad as I was watching
that Holly Holm fight.
Why?
Because of the uh,
here's what I think.
I think if you hit someone after the
bell and it's really clear,
it should be an immediate point
deduction and they should be given time
to recover more than a minute.
That's just an opinion you twice.
But I agree with you.
But here's why I disagree with you.
I,
I'm even more extreme.
I think that hitting someone after the
bell is grounds for disqualification
because you know,
you know,
fam,
you know down your whole mindset
changes.
You're not expecting it.
She definitely heard the bell.
The guy was stepping in,
she threw
the shots.
It's grounds for disqualification.
I fought,
you know,
it's been a long time,
but I did and I heard bells and I didn't
hit anybody afterwards.
You know what the fuck it is,
you know what it is.
Well,
if you do the point deduction,
holly wins that fight or a draw for
sure.
Germain de Randamie is fucking awesome.
She's an awesome fighter.
I mean she is a 46 and o 10 time world
champion and for that to happen with her
it,
it upsets me in,
in two ways.
One,
it upsets me because holly got fouled.
Intuit upsets me because she's a great
fighter.
For her to do something like that was
like,
why did you do that?
Don't do that.
Yeah.
And she rocked holly.
The problem is when you rock someone who
knows how much that affects them for the
rest of the fight,
holly is so bad ass.
She not only came back from that,
she came back from that wound up head
kicking Jermaine,
dropping her and then rocking her little
hook that you threw that we've looked at
in that first.
Yeah.
With just straight left.
I thought I was like a hook.
All he rocked her straight legs are
straight left that she was coming in,
so it's just really short.
Then perfect shot.
Yeah,
she's incredible.
She's so bad ass.
In that question.
Mark kick that she hit her with over the
top of the shoulder,
drops down and hits her in the head.
Isn't it funny though that she doesn't.
She doesn't fight like a boxer in the
octagon at all.
She.
It's much more like an American
kickboxer well,
because she was also an American
kickboxer and she's also trained by Mike
Winkeljohn who was one of the best
American kickboxing from his era.
He was world class in his time.
He's really good.
When he fought,
he fought Rick Rufus.
He fought some really good guys.
He said great striking coach man.
Very similar to him.
You know when I'm in Dallas,
Guy Metzger,
very similar style to that kind of stand
up.
Not as much head movement.
That Guy Metzger is a good friend of
mine.
I love that guy.
He's really just an awesome guy.
I won't get into personal stories,
but he's been.
He's done some really nice things for
people and he's a really.
He's the exact example of when people
say fighters are our meatheads,
you just really kindhearted guy.
Well,
he's definitely not immediate.
I'm more of a meathead than him for
sure.
He's a,
he's not just a kindhearted guy.
He's very intelligent,
soft spoken.
You never hear Guy Metzger yelling at
people and he's,
he's also,
you know,
he's worked really hard to mitigate some
of his,
uh,
brain trauma and been really open about
it,
which I think is very,
very,
very important because it's like this
silent thing that guys don't want to
talk about the issues that they're
dealing with from fighting.
Yeah.
Well he also.
Did you hear the story about when he got
into the fight in a parking lot?
It was like a bunch of guys who jumped
him you about,
well,
how long this one?
That long ago.
We were probably thinking the one where
the guy had a knife and stabbed him in
the face because he got in between an
altercation between a minute and you
just don't do that.
And when it was done,
go out fighting,
stay home.
No,
this was something maybe he may not want
me to tell the story,
but it was in a parking lot.
Something happened.
I don't know how it started,
but what happened was there were three
or four guys and all he did was he
grabbed one guy just got him to the
ground somehow and put him in a choke
hold.
And he told his friend,
he said,
if you come forward,
I'm going to choke your friend out.
And they just got back into their rav
four,
close the doors.
He let the guy go.
They were gone.
That's a really nice person.
Most people chose that guy as well.
He also,
he's a striker.
He could have really hurt him.
Yeah.
That's kind of the beauty of grappling.
You can hurt them or not as much as you
want to.
Master is a very high level striker.
I mean,
he's not known as a grappler,
so that's why he's a grappler to.
He choked out.
Tito Ortiz was one of his first UFC.
He just won worlds at Brown in the
senior division.
Did it really?
Yeah,
that's amazing.
he's still competing and doing that
stuff.
That's pretty awesome.
That's a nice thing for people that
don't want to strike anymore.
I know Baba loose abroad,
he's been doing a lot of grappling
competitions,
staff,
you know,
guys that just have taken a lot of head
trauma,
a lot of crazy fights,
long careers.
They still like to compete.
They can do that.
And you know,
and Bob Ballou has,
um,
I think it's Bob Lose Iron Jim,
I think that is what he calls it and
he's got a really nice high level jim
down in Orange County and you know,
that's an explanation every time parents
taking their kids for lessons,
they walk in and see Bob Ballou great.
But they have to do that.
That kind of.
Right.
Let me,
let you see the tattoos up his neck.
Yeah.
Parents are going to be a little
apprehensive.
Great Guy.
He's a great guy and he's a real pioneer
in Bob Ballou was in the early,
early days of fighting.
You say there's a fight with him and
Brad Kohler.
It's one of the fucking scariest
knockouts ever because it was back when
you could soccer kick on the ground and
uh,
he dropped Brad Colt because Bob Ballou
was one of the first Brazilian
wrestlers,
which a lot of people don't know.
I mean he was a black belt in Brazilian
Jujitsu and very good striker and all
those things.
But he also was on the Brazilian
national wrestling team back in the day.
And so Brad Kohler,
who was like this really beefed up
fucking just jacked dude could,
couldn't touch them on the feet and Bob
will eventually got them tired out.
And when he dropped him,
got him down to the ground,
he fucking soccer kicked him into
oblivion.
It was just those days when you can,
when you could soccer kick someone who
was already tired and down.
Those are,
those are dark.
But to put it into context of Brazilian
national wrestling team,
they'd be like ventures to Oklahoma
state wrestlers.
It's just not even the same level maybe,
but a high level wrestlers.
A high level roadside is,
but it's like Sarah Mcmahon,
you know,
she was silver at the Olympics number
when people said she was going to beat
Rhonda with the wrestling.
I'm like,
well,
hold on a second.
The talent pool in women's wrestling is
nowhere near where it is judo at that
point.
I mean,
you just have women in Japan in judo who
are criminals.
Um,
Kayla Harrison to following her.
She was actually one of the first guests
on our show.
She just a monster,
you know,
there's no one in female wrestling.
No one who will even come close to her
level of experience with them in the
same can be said about Brazilian
Jujitsu,
you know,
Brazilian Jujitsu,
which isn't in the Olympics yet,
but really should be,
is there's some phenomenal.
You've seen Mackenzie dern.
I've seen her compete in MMA.
Uh,
I haven't seen it.
Well,
yeah,
I was the most bad ass choke outs that
I've ever seen in my life.
She started with an Omoplata,
worked away.
This girl's back.
She's got this move that she does where
she gets a in on the plot that and she
rolls over onto her back and chokes this
chick out.
Apparently she hits this move all the
time.
Will they teach something similar to
that at Marcello Garcia School in New
York,
where if ever someone turtling you
said your knee into their ribs and their
hip crease and you kind of get around
not quite an Omoplata,
but you're bringing your other leg
around their front and you're wrapping
and you're blocking.
If let's save coming in from your right
side,
you blocked her left arm,
which is something we actually would,
would learn in judo quite a bit.
A really basic back.
So you black,
you broke blocking by taking an
underdog.
So you're in your admin console and
you're having risk control around so
you're not putting a hook in.
And when you control this,
the way they taught it to me,
like if you watch Marcella Garcia,
they'll just go for the choke straight
from there.
They don't even need to get their hooks
in.
Right.
And uh,
you know,
then you have Clark race.
Who does the Omoplata role to the lapel
choke?
I mean,
it really is.
The plan is.
I don't think there's been a submission
from that in a long time,
but there's only ever in the UFC history
was Ben Saunders.
This is Mackenzie dern.
Well,
that's how she does this for me is also
is that she's hot as fuck.
And so she,
she gets,
she gets the Omoplata to the girl,
tries to roll.
Now watch how she handles this.
When she gets her from disposition.
No,
no,
no.
You've got to go back.
Got to go back.
See,
I shouldn't even have her hooks.
Oh,
it's just a highlight video.
So she doesn't,
she doesn't need the hook.
What she does is she rolls and you don't
see it from that position.
Well that's a lot like a Nogi version of
clerk.
Racies.
Omoplata Lapel.
Show me.
See if they show it here.
But she does is she gets up and when she
gets up on her hip,
she the girl roles and then watch how
she scrambles.
Now she takes her,
right?
They don't show it.
She takes her right arm and she rolls
underneath the girl.
Anyway,
you know,
her dad is Megaton Diaz who's world
famous.
Yeah,
no,
very,
very respected.
Presented Jujitsu,
black belt.
But um,
there's the,
one of the coolest things about Jujitsu
is it's like almost like sentences and
languages.
There's so many different ways you can
go with things.
There's so many different possibilities.
It's just,
it's almost never ending.
Well,
there's a guy like my dad,
you know,
he's in his fifties and he hasn't lost a
point,
let alone around competing up to purple
belt and he competes against guys who
were 40 and open way because there's no
one is age and uh,
you know,
you played hockey,
you have m high,
high level athlete and he's not super
flexible.
He's not going to do a guard game.
He got really good at takedowns,
really good at trips,
really good at guard passing and side
control of jokes,
you know,
paper cutter and things like that.
And he's,
he's diverse enough where he can protect
himself in areas.
But that's one thing too,
you know,
when I was helping coach him for his
first tournament,
I'm like,
listen,
in training,
you want to work these positions,
you know,
you want to work your guard,
you want to work,
we have guard,
but there's nothing that says in the
competition,
you can't stuff the head get up and just
come up on top.
And when he realized that when he
competes,
it's just getting out and getting on
top.
And if he gets on top,
he's going to pass.
You know what his level at a purple belt
level,
the problem with that strategies that
only works with someone who's weaker
than you.
Like as soon as you find someone who's
better at that game than you,
you have to have other options.
So if he's not good off of his back,
someone's eventually going to put them
on his.
But he's pretty good in his back.
Well that's good.
But in a,
in a tournament,
the point is there's no unwritten
agreement where we're working,
passing.
Know what I mean?
So he can try his scissor sweep,
which is a big thing for him as a strong
guy and if it doesn't work,
he can do a technical standout and come
up.
Well Helson Gracie has the best
description of Jujitsu.
He said,
you do this than I do that.
Then you do this than I do that forever.
I love that because it's like once you
tried Jujitsu,
you go,
yeah,
that is what it is.
Until someone taps like you,
like Hixon Gracie has always been famous
for saying about other other athletes,
other competitors that if they can't
keep the rhythm there will lose some
amazing meaning.
Not like George St Pierre,
but like meaning that he keeps,
keeps attacking and you keep defending
and counterattacking eventually you're
going to slip up.
He's going to get a dominant position.
Sure.
And then once from there,
I'm not saying he's world class,
I'm just saying he's able to learn a
game.
I know you want to Brag about your
dad's.
Thank you gentleman.
Jack,
I guess on.
Oh no,
that's normal.
Jack.
This is a regular jet.
MMM.
Um,
yeah.
What does this stuff called?
This a Sinatra Shit.
They're just.
That's how you sell it.
If they were a sponsor sponsor,
you're getting phone calls yesterday it
was a Sinatra Shit and RPR
representatives have a problem with
that.
Well then they wouldn't be a sponsor
anymore.
Nobody cares anymore,
man.
This people who have to realize this is
the age of Shit.
You can say it.
You know?
It's actually a great whiskey that has
wild Turkey one-on-one.
That stuff's disgusting.
No,
no,
no.
We have some.
You want some?
No,
I'm good.
Pussy,
but wild Turkey.
One hundred one is a fantastic drink.
It really is.
It's like Jim beam advertises aged four
years.
What about Turkey?
One on one is eight years off the bat.
Why is it better to be old?
Why is it better for whiskey to be aged
or we would save in this tastes like
shit.
Just be honest.
It all tastes like shit.
No.
Well,
if the raw you want at younger with a
bourbon,
you want that.
You want more of that chart kind of
flavor in there anyway.
It's a good.
It's a good whiskey.
The best whiskey can't fuck with
Koolaid.
Tastes better than the best whiskey.
Cool.
What are you doing with Sinatra?
She had.
I liked the pain.
I like feeling.
I like the suffering.
I like the suffering that comes with
Jack Daniels.
That's what I like.
Really.
Like when you shoot that shot down and
go,
you know exactly what you just did.
You're not playing any stupid,
you know it's poison.
I come here to enlighten myself.
I'm here to spread love and Karma.
Is that what people do?
What with Horchata?
What's that?
With her child has a Mexican drink.
Rum Shot,
shot,
shot at some shit we get.
Whether you get tacos and inauthentic.
Joint was thinking rum,
Chata I missed.
What's rum shot?
I don't even know what that is.
They sell it.
It's like Horchata but alcoholic and
they saw a white bottle and it's already
premade and it's just got the spices and
whatever.
The dairy filler is a good thing to
make.
Terrible decisions will not get.
Jared loves it,
so it fits in perfectly.
Oh,
he loves rum.
Chose not to do so.
Fuck is not gay.
Jared,
he's my producer and my show interest
during WWII.
So you after this election and where,
where,
where do you line up now?
Where are you?
Because beforehand you were kind of,
I mean you saw the black lives matter
thing and you talked about the issue of
libertarian than anything.
So did you bet Gary Johnson?
I did,
but only because he did my podcast.
Oh really?
Yeah.
I'm like,
you do my podcast.
I'll vote for you for president.
It's deal's a deal.
Did he smoke pot and doing your podcast?
She should've.
Should've got them high right now.
We talked pretty sensibly.
I like Gary as a human and I think he's
a good guy and I think that um,
the Aleppo things suck that fucking
boat,
like a goddamn torpedo when he didn't
know what Aleppo is with like,
okay,
here's the thing.
Plays Good Pool.
Most people don't know about Aleppo.
When that happened,
every,
there was a spike in Google searches for
Aleppo and he doesn't know what Aleppo
isn't.
I didn't know.
I didn't know about Aleppo.
I knew that Syria was in a terrible,
terrible situation.
I knew the Syrian refugees that are
fleeing,
I knew the bombings and who I didn't
know the name of the city.
The problem is,
you know,
he got caught not knowing the name of
the city and he should have known the
name of the city.
Like if you asked me,
you know,
uh,
how do you think matt hume handles a
mighty mouse is career?
I'd be like,
who the fuck's mad at him if I said that
I shouldn't be doing mma commentator
ever again,
but I'm a man.
I'm a mixed martial arts commentator.
That is part of my job.
If you're running for president,
it's part of your job.
Know the name of the city where you
know,
the worst part was when you tried to
cover it up like African.
What is Aleppo?
Syria?
Yes.
Got It,
got it.
You said it twice.
Buying some time.
She's like,
you just said,
you know what?
I don't really know,
but I'm a libertarian so it wouldn't
even be in Aleppo.
So what does it matter?
Yeah,
but see,
I don't buy that either,
man.
Once you've entangled yourself in the
world of politics,
foreign politics and international
politics,
the idea that you're not going to be
there anymore.
Well,
we found out what happens with that in
Iraq.
We have found out what happens with
that.
In Libya you create a vacuum and that
vacuum is filled by terrible,
terrible people.
Well,
particularly when you give them a
timetable of when you're going to pull
out.
Yeah.
You know,
and everyone in the right was saying,
well listen,
that's,
that's a mistake.
No,
no,
this is gonna work.
Well,
trust me,
but in his defense,
what the fuck else do you do?
I mean,
do you stay there,
stay there and you keep putting it in
there.
It's not going to light,
bitch.
I know how to do this.
Pay For at least an hour afterward.
I'll show you how to get it.
I'm already doing it like,
man,
we're going to suffocate the flame
lighters,
bro.
Yeah,
modern technology.
Um,
well here's something that I,
that I do think we've seen afterwards.
I guess I wasn't a big trump supporter
with that.
Or you want to go down and you did say
we can,
but let's talk.
Let's talk politics.
Let's Talk Jack Daniels with Bernie
Sanders or whoever it is.
You can't line up with the black lives
matter you all the time.
You can line up with the pussy hat,
economics,
the women's March all the time.
You can't line up with the antifreeze.
Speech protesters on campus all the
time.
He can't line up with the people online
who want a band.
Voices of dissent all the time.
You can't line up with,
we want to tax the wealthy.
Can you line up?
Well,
the point is people like Bernie or
Hillary when they do that,
until you realize,
hold on a second,
there's a line and I've lined up with
everyone except for the rest
of America.
And you see that in Los Angeles.
It's an insulated bubble of.
People don't realize.
You know what?
There are a lot of people saying that,
or New York,
whatever.
Cities want you to relax it didn't you?
Didn't you go to Colorado one point
because he hated it.
No,
I wanted to live.
I do not like the population.
I do love the mountains,
right bro?
I got a straight off the mountain tee
shirt on hoyt archery.com.
That could be in Washington.
No fucking bowhunter on that thing.
Um,
I think that chickens.
Yeah,
right.
Yeah.
I don't live in Los Angeles.
I live outside of Los Angeles.
Yeah.
I have several locations.
And which to sleep.
I think,
uh,
I think that there's,
there's a real problem with high
population areas and that problem is,
there is two things.
One,
there's a diffusion of responsibility.
There's too many people.
You just feel like you don't,
they don't value,
you don't value each other because
there's too many,
there's everyone's there.
If you see an accident you don't pull
over to try to help because there's
100,000
people on the highway.
You just keep going.
Yeah.
If you saw that same accident on a
single lane road in the country and you
know,
some cops you might pull over and help,
you know,
you might add about New York,
New Yorkers care about each other.
I got you walk past the Hobo on the
street in New York for a lot of people
they just ignore it because they're so
used to it.
They did after nine slash 11.
They love it.
You know,
I went to New York after nine slash 11.
We filmed a fear factor there and I'll
tell you man,
it was a beautiful thing because there
was,
there was a real palpable,
like a tangible feeling of community
there that doesn't exist there anymore.
No,
it's gone.
Also the New York that existed in 2001
is not the New York that he is here in
2016.
No,
you know,
um,
I've had some like Judah freelander is a
friend of mine is a stand up comic and
he,
he was telling me,
he's like,
dude,
it's all bankers now.
He's like,
there's no artist in New York anymore.
They can't afford it.
He's like,
if you go to Brooklyn maybe,
but in New York City the rents are so
fucking expensive and there's so much
international money in New York.
It's like I can tell you that's flipped
a little bit having when I lived there.
Um,
the lower east side in New York City.
I lived there when I was with Fox for,
well,
well there are two different stints,
one time sleeping on couches and a one
time this would've been 2011,
maybe 2011,
2012.
And the rent was cheaper in old money,
upper east side than an east village or
lower east side because that's where all
the hipsters and the artists were.
So they don't want it to be there now in
the upper east side was seen as not
cool.
So I got a place that was so inexpensive
compared to if I wanted to live down
downtown.
So that's Kinda switched.
But no one,
none of the artists want to live with
all the wasp.
So this is always a problem when too
many people have too much money and
they're all congregated in one area
because then they're just annoying.
It's annoying.
They're all trying to buy the same
fucking cars on your voice.
And Bertrand Russell short pipes and
stomp on the little mat.
And I,
um,
yeah,
I think you're right.
And I think,
uh,
I think it also,
I mean there's obviously this is where
leftest tend to congregate leftist
ideology in big cities.
They want you on public transportation.
They want you to do that.
Then they don't want you riding,
Bro.
No,
they won't get well.
Bikes,
public,
trans,
public transport,
but certainly they want to limit what
kind of cars you can drive,
how far you can drive them.
You look in any big city,
they definitely wanna reduce
independence and um,
there's a real art.
Do you think that's what it really is?
No.
They want to reduce carbon emissions.
They don't want to reduce independence.
No,
I think.
I think it's both.
It's both and less consistent than
pieces.
Stop.
If kids say that people want you on
buses and dependent on government,
just like they want you on welfare,
they,
the transit people don't.
Maybe some percentage of the people do.
But if Tesla came out with some car that
you could drive across the country on
one charge,
you think people would be suppressing
that?
They would welcome it.
Zero emissions car that give you total
freedom.
No one's going to try to suppress that.
The issue is,
is the only one?
I don't think so.
How and why they would do is remove all
the government subsidies that make tesla
even remotely competitive as they this.
They should have started them a crazy.
I'm talking about the United States
government and the subsidies that go
into a tesla,
right?
Prius could still be losing Toyota on
everyone sold.
But you look at the government
subsidies,
the government incentives for people
don't want to buy these cars.
Oh,
that's Tesla.
Yeah,
but not a prius.
That's not true either.
I know a bunch of people bought Prius is
Prius a Brendan Schaub as a Prius.
My buddies have drives a prius.
He's got off fucking Prius.
Has even fit in a prius and a Bentley.
Well there you can.
Barely fucking.
Big Gorilla.
He barely fits in.
I would say those things handled like
trash.
There's shit cars.
Bill Burr has a prius.
How about that?
And the Jaguar?
Exactly it.
That's exactly what it is.
It's the white,
the white guilt symbol in Los Angeles,
or you can say,
I got to say that,
but it's people that don't want to spend
a lot of money on gas.
They bought a lot of them,
bought them in 2000.
Now here's the thing.
If you don't want to spend a lot of
money on gas,
you would do the cost savings
estimation.
You would see buying a used car,
any used car,
especially a Ford Fiesta,
which would get more mileage and a prius
anyway.
So White,
guilty.
Um,
no.
It doesn't get done.
Fiesta gets more money or American small
cars will get over 40 miles per gallon.
Yeah,
but a praise gets over 50.
No,
pull it up.
Jamie.
Motherfucker.
Let's ride.
Let's say it's an eight mileage
difference.
Yeah,
but that's not what you want.
You don't want an old car's gonna break
down.
You want a new car that's reliable.
That gets really,
really shouldn't be enhanced with a
Prius.
That's fucking pussy.
No,
seriously.
You don't want.
That's going to be tar straight into
your lungs.
If you inhale that and switched into
weed,
you're driving me crazy.
I'm,
oh this is so much better.
Well,
back to the.
Oh,
there you go.
Alright,
so what's that?
A Prius is Ford Fiesta.
Alright,
so 40 highway,
29 city sun,
40 highway.
Now pull up,
pull up a preschool.
I have way more in the city because
there was a battery work here because
it's better.
Son of a bitch point sucks.
No,
no,
that wasn't the point though.
That was a,
that was a side trying to say that if
you really wanted to save money on gas,
you would get a fucking shitty old Ford
Fiesta.
And that's absolutely.
Absolutely.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Son,
are you it more in the city but all you
want.
But here's the truth.
Many tens of miles per gallon.
You are incorrect.
If you look at the actual price of a
Prius versus the best thing you can do
for the environment is by an old beater
car by an old Camaro.
This poorly understood that it's
$24,000.
It's cheap as fuck for a car.
No,
you'd be better off buying an old beater
car recycle than buying a prius.
Dig Your heels in a.
You don't see the other side,
you buy a Prius,
two giant non recyclable batteries.
Dig Your heels,
your giant non-recyclable non recyclable
for now,
but much like nuclear waste.
It's making a comeback.
You know,
that they can make diamonds batteries on
a diamonds with nuclear waste now that
last thousands of years.
Give what do we want?
Diamonds.
Oh,
they make batteries that have diamonds,
the nuclear waste,
nuclear diamond waste batteries.
Thousands of years.
Nuclear energy that we could be using,
but we can't be using because people
thought it was worse for the environment
we're using it.
Whether people thought it was worse or
not.
The real issue is like the old plants
like Fukushima,
that they have huge difficulties with
shutting down.
Someone told me that is not,
you know,
we're talking about the other day that
someone had said that the radiation
levels are growing.
This business not growing,
that the real issue is a aerosol or
something.
The old global warming.
Cfcs sort of noticed but not aerosols.
What was the airborne airborne?
Uh,
radiation is an issue with Fukushima
that they're monitoring it.
Yeah.
It doesn't surprise me,
but my.
My point on that one is why?
Why are leftist,
for example,
against the sharing economy?
Why would Bernie Sanders,
Bernie Sanders,
they're plastic forks just abandoned,
left versus right,
and tries to tell people what are the
innovations or the Bernie social
ascenders against the sharing economy.
You can you give them a nickname?
Yeah,
you son of a socialist.
He's a self about European socialists.
Why would they be against the sharing
hundred thousand dollars a year?
Let's,
let's,
let's stay on the ground.
What are you telling me?
This bouncing all over it.
You bring up your fucking dog again.
What about your dad is Jitsu guy not
talk about politics,
so it's hard to say.
I don't want to talk to them.
I says,
this is the point,
the sharing economy,
Uber,
and Airbnb.
Shouldn't everyone be on board with
that?
What do you have?
People like Bernie Sanders or Nancy
Pelosi banning them or poor Austin
politicians and constituents banning
them from their city.
If we're talking about sharing
socialism,
yeah,
you can't do uber and Austin.
Bernie Sanders doesn't want to uber.
AIRBNB.
Why do you think they're doing that?
Do you think they're doing that because
they want taxis to survive?
I think they're doing it because just
like people like to throw out this big
conspiracy about big bankers and their
own self interest,
which is true.
I think that people don't want to
acknowledge that the left is beholden to
giant cabby unions who are punching
people in the face in New York because
Uber removes their surcharge and decides
to ignore the trump travel ban.
I think they're against airbnb because
they're beholden to,
for example,
the culinary union who might sneak in
the side about the trump travel ban.
We talked about that was that people
weren't even road testing and Uber in
New York City.
They went in and they were still going
to the airport.
The cabbies unions in New York said,
we're not going to go,
and so people were punching over
drivers.
People getting furious about it.
Saying,
you're you're scams.
You're coming in.
Uber actually removed their surcharge.
[inaudible] remember all the airport
protests,
right?
It was a quagmire.
No,
I don't.
Oh yeah.
Join the airplane mode of the trump's
travel ban.
There were protests at all these
different airports about that.
Yeah.
Well,
what does that have to do with Uber?
The point is in New York,
the cabbies unions went on strike
against the travel ban,
right?
Uber's going in weren't clear,
and they're moving their surcharge.
Well,
if we're talking about the sharing
economy,
if we're talking about bringing in
refugees and resettling them against
people's will,
right?
Because we want to be compassionate.
We'll just take that and say,
okay,
instead of resettling refugees against
somebody's will,
because you want to share what about
somebody deciding to share their car at
an agreed upon service or share their
house and the the left,
the political left has fought against
that vehemently.
It is inconsistent.
They were band.
Who is this day?
Okay.
So the board or he polosi.
Elizabeth Warren.
What they want to do is either get uber
banned in cities,
as you see in cities like Austin or in
cities in Europe or they want to make
sure that unions,
that caveat is either get first,
right?
Or that Uber Hires these union workers.
Okay.
Well,
I have,
I definitely have an issue with that,
so let's pull up that.
Pull up that story that Bernie Sanders
is in favor of banning uber,
Bernie Sanders,
Uber,
and let's,
let's break that down and unpack it
because I think when something comes
along that's better and it fucks with a
business that is worse,
the better things should win because
that's progress.
Sure.
I think uber is progress.
I think lyft is progress.
I think what lyft is doing and what
these these programs are doing where you
have an application on your phone,
you can turn it on and off anytime you
want.
You can work anytime you want,
as long as they certify and test you and
run it.
Make sure you're not a crazy person as
long as they know where you are at every
time.
They can actually monitor your location
through gps,
which they can and everybody saves money
and the people who drive the car make
money.
Like you can make like 35 bucks an hour
doing that.
Why wouldn't you rather do that?
If you have a car like a prius that gets
50 fucking eight miles to the gallon,
wouldn't you rather do that?
So I'm in favor of 100 percent in
progress and I think that anybody that
opposes that because somehow or another
it's going to challenge other people's
jobs.
Right?
When it comes to something like uber
versus cab,
in my opinion,
this is pretty black and white.
This is a new technology,
a disruptive technology that benefits a
lot of individual users.
Hence it's good.
Well also benefits the middle class more
than anybody and there's no union for
Uber drivers.
That's a big problem.
No lobbying and there's no money that
goes to politician.
Well that's a big problem.
So I'm not aware of this.
You're more balls deep in politics than
I am.
So let's.
Jamie's going to pull up a story and
we're going to figure out what
the fuck is wrong with Bernie Sanders.
Take on it from an individual point of
view.
Yeah,
or you can look up.
I mean,
you can even look up European cities
that have banded are awesome and I know
it was a huge issue in London.
I remember watching those cab drivers
that had decided to block streets.
They decided to shut their cars off in
the middle of the street and literally
stop cars from passing.
People had to go way around them and it
was a huge issue.
The reason the term political left and
right and matters right now to me anyway
and matter to some people,
but the reason it matters to me is
because you do look at one side of the
political spectrum right now and I think
the line's been pretty clear in this
last election where there's an
ideological divide and where one is
deliberately looking at marginalizing
and targeting and dividing victimized
groups and they do so and ignore other
groups of people who are victimized as a
result of them complaining about
victimization.
Okay?
Like what this is.
That's very vague.
So let going to give you want a concrete
example.
Let's find this with Bernie Sanders may
go into this thought as Janice guidance
on what he was trying to find a quote
about what he had,
so here's about what I guess he has some
serious problems with serious problems
with popular mobile ride hailing
services.
Uber speaking with Bloomberg,
the Democratic presidential candidate
contender rather called the service
unregulated,
waiting into one of the most closely
watched economic debates of the 2016
race workers on demand at on demand
economy.
Companies like Uber,
Airbnb,
or Lyft,
are considered independent contractors
and therefore I do not receive the
benefits and protections afforded to
fulltime employees.
Okay.
So I could see that,
but they do make more money,
right?
Isn't that correct?
Yeah.
Well they don't.
They don't have to pay a huge commission
to the cabbies union and they're totally
independent and they have their own car
and they make more money.
Don't mean is that true?
Maybe.
Let's make sure that that is true.
It doesn't matter if it's true,
but let's just have the choice to just
google uber drivers make more than car
companies versus how much uber makes
from their drivers because that's the
real issue.
Like say Uber as a company and they're
pumping out all these drivers and then
making shit tons of money and then
they're not given the drivers enough.
Then given the uncertainty,
I think they take a much smaller
commission and then the cab driver's
license.
I don't have enough in front of me,
reiterate.
I'm pro uber 100 percent.
I have a friend of mine is actually a
big wig at Uber.
I think it's great.
I think even if I wasn't what's matter
this how uber fails to prove its drivers
make more than tax post that's happened
in post those sons of bitches.
That's the blade.
You know,
they feel the need to be defensive or
they failed to prove how they failed to
prove.
What does that mean?
I don't know.
Claim and Huffington post can't disprove
it,
but they're saying uber is failed to
prove it,
so this isn't going to help that crowd.
Or read the fucking quotes going crazy
and defend your right wing,
right wing,
God,
Time Dot Com.
Then instead having that beer bearson
time.com.
Oh,
Uber reveals how much is drivers really
earned?
Sort of.
Uber has long said the drivers get paid
more than traditional cabbies,
but do they driver surveys,
strikes and class action lawsuit
suggests otherwise.
Most recently.
Buzzfeed.
Is that okay?
Is it okay if it's bud?
Is that too left wing you?
Fuck yeah.
Buzz feed is fake news.
I mean your fat.
Those estimates,
buzzfeed,
you fake estimate that terrible trauma
impression that drivers in Denver,
Detroit,
and Houston make less than 13 point two,
five cents an hour.
$13,
twenty five cents an hour after expenses
using calculations based on the more
than a million trips.
Well,
that's not good.
This spring,
uber was hit with two class action
lawsuits from drivers in Florida and
Illinois who seek to recover unpaid
overtime wages and other expenses.
This is after the company.
This is our shitty.
Now we have one Shitty TV that can't
handle an htmi cable and it cuts out
every minute and a half.
We have one of those when Blah,
blah,
blah who seek to recover unpaid
overtime.
Jesus Christ,
unpaid overtime wages and other
expenses.
This is after the company paid
$100,000,000
to settle similar lawsuits in California
and Massachusetts.
Okay.
Yeah.
So Massachusetts big union strong if
they have lawsuits and if there is a law
suit that does make sense enough where a
judge decides that they're going to rule
against Uber.
Okay.
But that's,
I mean,
I don't know the law.
Do you,
do,
you know,
it depends on a right to work state,
but wouldn't you assume that the lawyers
and the judges in Massachusetts would
make a strong enough case where they
would show the legality of it to the
point where it wouldn't lose $100 or
$100,000,000
lawsuit?
No,
I wouldn't assume.
Do you know anything about the lawsuit?
Well,
I.
here's what I would know,
whether it's a right to work state or
not and that will determine the lawsuit
and that's why people like Bernie
Sanders and that's why people.
Oh Geez,
what happened there?
You opened that too fast.
Just go do it like you did the pilot
scared good enough.
And Bro,
I'm so.
It depends if it's a right to work state
or not.
I don't care.
Right.
They make less than cab drivers.
I don't care.
Well,
let's eliminate people.
What is the difference between a right
to work state effectively means you
don't have to join a union means you can
work without being a part of the labor
union and determine the case.
Just for example.
That's what when we do hidden camera
videos,
we have to make sure that it's a two,
a one party consent state as opposed to
a two party consent state.
Right.
Like Nevada,
when they used to do this prank call
shows,
they would do like.
You remember crank anchors?
Yeah.
They would do it in Nevada,
right?
Because he calls.
Lorna is a one party consent state.
No,
it's too well in Nevada and California
is one.
What do you mean California?
When,
again,
the definition wrong,
but I'm thinking is we both have to
agree.
Is that true?
Yeah.
They will do it in Nevada instead of
California.
Right.
That's what I'm saying.
Right in Nevada,
you only like,
you can call me up a prank.
Me and not doing it.
I wouldn't have to agree.
Right.
That might've changed.
It might change.
For example,
in Michigan it was really controversial.
It was a one party consent state that
depending on the judge read as a two
party consent state.
So that's really scary because you can
be in the clear,
right,
we recorded a prank call or we found
some kind of corruption and it should be
legal.
There's a little wiggle room where they
can say,
actually this isn't legal and you
committed a felony.
So that's a problem with that.
Um,
so in these right to work states,
um,
when you have this uber situation,
is the issue that it's taking cabs out
of business or is the issue that they
are not paying people enough and they're
taking cabs out of business so that
people like the or cab drivers,
if they switched over to becoming uber
drivers,
they would actually lose money because
these companies aren't regulated so they
don't have to pay insurance,
health insurance.
I mean,
that seems like what the issue is,
right?
That's what they would say the issues
are.
So it's not true.
Well,
no,
it's not necessarily true.
And again,
that depends on the state.
So first off,
I would want to clarify just people
listening.
It would not be the right to work
states.
The right to work states would be fine,
right?
I'm a right to work state means I have
the right to say,
Hey,
do you want to work for this amount?
And you have the right to say yes or non
right to work above minimum wage.
Everybody's cool.
Yeah.
As long as they're as cool as you can
be,
right?
Yep.
And report is a non right.
Towards stage is when,
depending on the profession,
if there is an established union in that
profession,
you can't work outside of that union.
Right?
How's that?
Is that the case with trades like
plumbing being a carpenter?
Generally repair.
Yeah.
Generally speaking,
it's auto repair that they have a union.
Uh,
it depends on the state,
depends on the state,
but she'll son and actually would have
some stories about his dad being in the,
uh,
the plumber's union.
He had some stories about that.
Vince Vaughn and some funny stories
about that,
he's told actually when he worked at his
dad's like papermill,
um,
but,
but to go back to it again,
first off,
I don't care if someone agrees to this
price and the service,
I believe that's a marketplace of ideas
and services and you have the right to
do it and I have the right to provide
those services.
Now if Uber is doing a poor job,
thank God there's lift,
right?
Because there's some competition there,
but if the government steps in and says,
no,
you have to use the cabbies,
unions will even then you can
artificially increased wages at the
expense of the taxpayer who now has to
pay more for a taxi ride.
So I don't care.
I think that people should be able to
make their own decisions if they want to
do uber,
if they want to rent out their house.
And airbnb.
And I don't think that Nancy Pelosi in
the bay area representing our district
should have any say in whether I can
read.
Well,
I agree with you 100 percent on that.
And I think there's also a real problem
with people resisting change because
technologically influenced changes
coming at such a high rate.
There's no way you can put a finger in
all the holes in the dam.
It's just you can't do it.
There's too many things that are
happening.
They're going to change the way we
communicate,
change the way we do business,
change everything from top to bottom.
You're not going to be able to stop it.
So anytime we try to stop something like
an Uber,
the only thing that I think is that who
you got to figure out where's the,
how's the money being distributed,
is that fair?
And if it's not fair,
what's the,
what's the solution?
Because it's a solution alert people to
what the actual numbers are and let it
all sorted itself out.
Or is it passing regulation?
I'm a firm believer that the less
regulation you have,
the better.
Right?
And that's what songs,
it's not like environmental pollution
type shit,
the invisible hand write,
the more that moves the market.
Um,
I certainly believe that the market is
more efficient at regulating itself.
Then the government creating a monopoly
will also because unions can be
influenced and when you get large groups
of people together,
I think it's good because like what a
union can do is they can say,
you know,
hey,
we're going to stand strong when I got
to let these people take advantage of us
like some sort of slave labor factory in
the Middle East or wherever the fuck it
is.
We're gonna,
we're gonna.
Figure out a way to.
You can,
if you work here,
you're going to get an honest wage and
I'm 100 percent with that.
The problem is that you get giant groups
of people that you can't go against.
Someone's going to be in control of
those giant notion that that's no
different than being the mayor of a city
or the leader of a country.
No different than being beholden to
Goldman Sachs or JP Morgan.
And if you look at the top political
donors,
you can bring it up from open secrets.
If you look at the top 20,
it's like 16 out of the top 20 are big
unions.
So that's this idea that it's big banks
and the Koch brothers and energy
companies,
no one wields more influence in American
politics today than big unions
particularly come into the party because
it's power because they can influence
the people that are,
can also take cues from you give 100
percent of Democrats and you have no
say,
well,
it's one of the big contributors to the
war against drugs.
One of the big things that's happening
in this country is the prison guard
unions have spent money to ensure that
innocuous things like marijuana or they
stay illegal because if they stay
illegal then they keep their jobs like
they've literally fought for that.
Like fought to keep more people in cages
because that would earn them more money.
I mean that's really what it is.
We break it down to black and white and
it's.
Did you just make a joke about the
discriminatory prison system in the
United States?
That was cold.
I didn't say black and white because I'm
at black and white people I met.
It could have been black and white
matters.
The reality of the situation is that
prison guard unions are spending money
and using their influence to ensure it
didn't work.
Influential,
influential.
I'm like from south off that edge to
ensure that marijuana stays illegal and
the reason why they're doing that
because they profit off of it,
so that's not an altruistic ideal.
That's not someone who cares about the
people that they represent.
That's not someone who cares about their
community as a whole,
that someone is looking out for their
best interests in a way that is negative
towards the general population.
With you and I,
I think that's where the wool was pulled
over people's eyes with people like
Bernie will.
He's from the people.
He's never gotten big donors.
That's actually not true.
If you look at the collective donations
from union members and from union
organizations and when you look at that,
and what bothers me is when people
follow the money trail and only one side
and act as though the political left is
on beholden to people.
That's the big point,
what you just said on one side,
because I think you can see the benefits
in unions as well.
You could see the benefits and
protecting wages and making sure that
people get insurance and making sure
that people live a good life.
That like if you're going to work for
this company,
you're going to be well compensated and
you're going to.
There's going to be an agreement between
the workers and the people that run the
company.
There's a problem with that and the
problem with that is,
but there's not always a problem with
that.
There is occasionally sometimes.
No,
there's the,
that's the rule rather than the
exception.
And I talked about this,
the,
the Walmart CEO for example,
makes $19 million,
right?
People are curious about that.
Well,
Walmart employs two point 5 million
people.
One point 5 million people a full time.
So he had that.
He's getting less than than uh,
well,
if you add up all the workers,
not the full time workers will be less
than $10 per person he's employing and
providing an active living.
So when you have workers who say,
well,
he is 19 million,
that's more than I have,
I have no million,
19 is 19 more millions.
These people,
they pick an arbitrary number.
That's what Bernie Sanders we're doing
with the debate with Ted Cruz,
whether you like them or not,
it was such a floor mopping because
Bernie Sanders dealt with these phantom
fears and again tried to victimize
groups and marginalized groups.
In my point that I was talking about
there is,
for example,
we talked about the victimized groups
and marginalized groups who don't have
insurance in the country,
right?
It was 40 something thousand.
Most of them were young people who chose
not to buy insurance.
So now you can stay on your parent's
insurance till 26.
There you go.
We bought some votes because you talk
about them and they're getting more
affordable insurance now.
And now the play is we're going to take
all these people off of insurance.
Okay?
So we're talking about that victimized
group.
People who didn't buy insurance.
But what about the people who have seen
their premiums go up?
Hardworking Americans?
Forty something percent,
24 percent on average in certain states.
Forty six percent,
sometimes 60 something percent of the
premiums have gone up.
Why don't we talk about the
ramifications of the everyday Americans
who now can no longer afford healthcare
insurance and don't qualify for a
government subsidy.
And if you look at the trend,
I will argue this and I'll dig my heels
and if I feel I have to,
the political left seeks to divide and
conquer and find for sure the most
victimized group of that day.
W W how so?
Like what do you mean the most most
victimized group of that day to do what?
Well,
I think,
well,
like right now for example,
I'm just using that as an example
because you said a concrete example with
obamacare.
So right now it's these people aren't
gonna be able to afford insurance?
Well,
there are times people cycle too far
away from unions because you were way
out into the obamacare pool.
Well,
no,
because we were talking about that deep
and long.
No,
no it's not.
It's really not obamacare's subsidized,
technically healthcare sub costs of
other taxpayers who couldn't afford it
and now they can't afford to live.
Let's start from the beginning because
you went way out there and you started
out with the CEO.
I went out there and have Alex Jones and
I went out there.
When you went out there in terms of you
covered so many different things before
anybody could address either one of
them.
You have to like slow down and like take
it point by point.
You said that this guy makes so much
money that if everybody gave him 10
bucks,
like why should they give him 10 bucks?
Here's the thing,
like what is this guy doing?
Single biggest employer of people in
what?
He's just a guy who works for them.
He doesn't even own it.
Why is this guy makes so much money?
I'm not saying you should.
I'm not saying he shouldn't.
He should make that much money,
but why defend that?
Why defend that?
Why not?
Why not have.
See that's like,
can I get a raise?
And they say no.
And he'd go away.
That guy makes $15,000,000
a year and it doesn't
even work.
What does he do?
He sits behind there.
A lot of punches.
What you just said,
there were a lot of assumptions.
He doesn't work.
Why does that guy make that much money?
How much?
Obviously,
who sees this factory?
This gutters need to have a real job
that's much driven around a fucking
limousine.
He gets $50 million.
We can't get a raise.
That's my point.
Well,
you can just tell them this is too much,
but don't you think,
and this is what I think.
If that guy really does make that amount
of money,
he's probably like how the fuck am I
pulling and extracting numbers from some
system by his choice thing.
So at all ones and Zeros and moving
things around and making sure that
profit margin trees and he gets a piece
of that and he just live in like a
fucking baller on a yacht,
a golden bikini with a bottle of Dom
Perignon,
a cross dresser now,
and seven fun is fucking gold.
Made $15,000,000
this year.
You can do whatever the fuck he wants,
but there's there's room for debate as
to what a job is worth and good job on
my show of having people on or disagree
in engaging in those debates.
We don't just say here,
just about this subject right here.
I think there's.
How do I make an assumption there's room
to soon how much a job is worth.
Yes,
there is room to debate,
so if determined by the value of the
company and the services rendered not
some arbitrary number because Bernie
sanders throws out a percentage point,
so I'm not saying that he's right.
I'm just saying,
well,
I think it's totally within the interest
of all the people that work for a
company that are critical to this
company actually working to figure out
like,
hey,
how much should we get for this?
How much do they get?
Well,
one guy's getting $15,
million bucks and the other guys getting
$15 an hour and you got to like this
guy.
If this guy doesn't work,
this guy doesn't get any money.
These people have to work.
If they didn't work,
the CEO would make $0 because there
would be no profit.
So someone has to work.
So I don't think it's outside the realm
of rational discourse to discuss how
much a person should make to be a CEO.
No,
I don't think it's outside the realm of
rational discourse.
Um,
I do think people are wrong when they
say,
for example,
to to take your argument how much a CEO
should make.
I think that's silly.
You shouldn't be to determine that.
Just.
I don't think you should either.
Just like,
I don't think you'd be able to say $15
an hour.
Look,
I think if somebody is,
if some super baller,
you know,
fucking steve jobs type character comes
in and starts running a company and all
of a sudden it goes blockbuster through
the roof and becomes apple.
I don't think you should be able to say
that guy doesn't deserve way more money
than the average person goes fucking.
Of course he does.
Yeah.
That guy is an obsessed genius who's
making this.
Okay.
Exactly.
Who does determine?
I think the market does,
but it's an interrelationship between
the people who are.
This is Bernie Sanders point of view.
I would imagine the people that don't
have a say that people that are making
the least amount of money,
they're the easiest to replace and
they're the ones that are worried about
being treated fairly well.
First off,
I would say,
you know,
heart exactly what little I do and
that's where they get mad.
They say you're a conservative,
therefore you don't care about poor
people.
I'm not talking about poor people.
I was sleeping out of an 82 dots and
when I first lived in Los Angeles,
so I'm,
I cared about myself,
let's put it that way.
I used to be in high school,
but I want to talk to those folks.
But that's,
that's the thing that they'll say is
right.
Attributed motive.
And I think,
and I think we both met.
I think you don't do it.
I don't do it.
Um,
I don't attribute node of.
I don't say will you do this because you
hate poor people when you do this
because.
But you do have to look at the numbers
and you look at a certain point when
people say they're underrepresented,
they have no voice.
Well,
that's not true with union workers.
They have a huge voice if huge political
influence.
These people don't not have a voice.
Especially they have the payment
industry.
They have a,
you know,
the entire music industry has been so
far left for so long,
pushing for these same ideas that
country.
A lot of those people are actually
pretty fuck.
Kid Rock was just talking about how most
of them are pretty far left.
Country Music is not far left,
so you're taking an extremely poor
country the fuck out of dodge to stop
you remove country.
It's one of the biggest genres of music
in this country.
Not only that,
I bet they sell more fucking albums than
anybody.
His country going out there and making
redacted and lions for lambs and
rendition and Avatar and all these.
These Suzanne Thai corporate screeds.
The point is,
I know what you're talking about.
You his country.
He's not going to the movie.
Is that what you're saying?
Yeah.
Fucking movie about aliens,
Bro.
Avatar.
The movie is possibly the biggest piece
of Neil environmentalist propaganda.
You talking about Pizza Gate,
you son of a bitch is a fucking amazing
guy.
Blue Aliens.
Now,
just out of boredom.
That guy fell in love with that blue
alien.
He became one of them,
Bro.
He was paralyzed.
They put them inside the blue alien
mind.
James Cameron could buy an island in
paint people blue and have them run
around for the rest of his life if he
wanted.
Instead he decides to print them out on
blu rays using petroleum products.
It was a dope movie and you're a fucking
communist.
Communist to fucking great movie.
You didn't enjoy it?
No,
I hated it.
I thought it was a terrible dude.
Is Great.
Really fucking flying dragons.
Bad Ass marines.
What else do you want?
What kind of a pussy am I talking to?
What happened to you?
You've been up in Michigan too long.
It's too cold in the winter.
Therefore I need to like Avatar for your
brain.
You don't think straight.
You just want to stay home.
You like it.
How do you actually like avatars that
can't wait for Avatar to really hurt?
It's underwater.
That even better.
They just stole that idea from Mario.
Level two.
Let's make it.
Cameron is a bad motherfucker.
He's one of the best directors of all
time.
He's a classic.
He's a great director.
He's also political moron.
I don't care about his politics.
He makes great.
No.
The point I was making,
I was talking about the media and
entertainment industry.
The backlash for someone who.
I'm not even a huge supporter of Donald
trump.
Neither one of us are,
so I think we can be relatively
objective,
so let's remove country,
but if you look at the end,
have you turned on CNN or something?
Drink slow down.
Have you turned it on?
CNN,
reese.
Cheers.
Well,
a good drink.
It good to the.
This is literally like one guy in high
school.
Relax.
If you want me to drink it.
That was a dope movie.
It was horrible.
The guy in high school,
if you love me,
you'll drink it.
Who the fuck were you partying with guys
like you?
Apparently kid rock being considered as
potential sentence.
Could you see that today?
Hold the fuck on.
Is that true?
Is a bowhunter I'm voting for him.
Actually just saw his interview with Dan
Rather last night was pretty
interesting.
He's a lot smarter than I think you.
I'd give him credit for it.
He's not a dumb guy.
Have you ever seen him alive?
No,
I have not,
but I like what he does.
You know what he does?
He puts a lot of effort.
Extremely low ticket prices,
like 20 bucks for a guy like him that's
huge.
Sales out these places and he gets a
piece of the booze.
He's smart.
He's a smart guy.
Given he's given his audience like a
good deal.
Yeah.
It makes a good deal with the venues
like,
look,
if kid rock showing up this fucking
place of selling out,
so let's just make a deal.
Let's make a deal in his deal is is
really smart.
I like what he's doing.
Well,
that's a good example of a guy not being
forced to do it.
Right.
He's just doing it because he wants to
do something that helps people.
Plus you've got a dope Cadillac.
You ever seen his Cadillac?
He had one of them.
West coast customs custom made Cadillac
as the shit man.
Where he got damn impressive is that
they remember that.
So if you got to touch it.
He started a beer company.
It was called like bad ass American bad
ass or something.
Beer.
I like kid rock there.
I said it.
Do you like his music?
He just like wants to do.
No,
I like some of his music is not bad.
I agree with you.
Some of his music is really not bad and
it's become popular to crap on them.
I liked them for that.
Cadillac is unabashedly friends with Ted
nugent.
Now you're still really into cars.
I love cars because I remember I was
listen to your podcast when wants and
you said it's only to the point when you
make so much money that you no longer
care about money and you use your car as
an example.
You said,
you know,
for example,
like I cry,
I got a dent or something in my car at
one point would have lost my mind
because that car man so much and now
it's just like,
okay,
it's only a car.
So that was a good point though that you
made that when you have enough money,
it's kind like it's what I call gorilla
Buddhism.
Okay.
Like the idea of this is part of
Buddhism that you should not be attached
to items.
You should not be attached to objects
and you,
you know,
I have a friend of mine who became a
Buddhist monk and he wouldn't even have
sex anymore.
I gave up on sex all carnal pleasure.
All pleasure.
All attachment to women,
attachment to relationships and the
ideas that you don't want to be
connected to that because you are
connected to owns you.
And my take on that was okay,
but does it have to own you?
Like,
can you just enjoy automobiles?
Can't you enjoy engineering?
He said that you can't have a,
you know,
you can't own a thing.
Can possess a thing.
I feel like that is so ignorant of the
world that we live and it's so
ridiculous.
You pretend you're choosing to act in a
way that you're ignoring this amazing
technological revolution that is going
on right before your eyes and it is
going to fucking happen with you ride a
bike to work or not.
It's gonna happen.
It's what people do.
We are a part of this cascade of
electronic progress,
of innovation and is never going to stop
and that's.
And that's tillie killer,
so I want to go back to that point in
the car,
but you know,
that would be a good analogy out of
business because of iphone or we put
political arm that I want to talk cars.
You're about that.
There's nothing wrong with appreciating
things that people make,
whether it's an automobile,
whether it's a painting,
a sculpture.
I feel like cars are like.
People look at them as just
transportation and I totally appreciate
that because they have worked so far.
If you get a prius,
it's just transportation.
I said they're works of art,
so if you get in 1969 Mustang,
that is a goddamn marvel of time.
It is a moment where people decided to
just create something that just looks
inherently like,
like collectively bad ass.
There's no.
No one looks at a 69 mach one.
He goes,
that's fucking gross.
If you do fuck you with that is if you
do fuck you right.
If you look at a 69 Mustang,
you don't.
You don't say,
wow,
that's crazy.
Look,
and that's amazing.
Isn't that a big irony that you're able
to appreciate it and not be attached to
it because you've been more financially
successful?
Well,
that's what I say.
You know,
that's the whole point of this whole
thing.
It's not a rational,
normal position take because most people
are behind the eight ball all the time
and it always need to pay their bills.
Look at that car.
Look behind you,
sir.
Look at that.
Yeah,
the low cuts it in and now we talked
about that earlier before you were
drunk.
It looks nice.
That's a fucking amazing car man.
That 1969 Mustang is a marvel.
It all came together.
It's just they figured it out.
They just figured out some way to make
something that just is incredibly
pleasing to your eyes and doubles as
transportation.
No.
Should get one right?
You can.
There's a company that takes them and
this is what I like.
They take the,
the inside of it and the engine,
all that stuff out and they put a 2000,
12 shelby gt,
500 inside of it.
So you get like antilock brakes,
you get airbags,
you get everything.
Yeah.
And then they,
you know,
they put it together and so that's the
way to go.
It's,
it's,
this was actually my experience with
very nice cars.
I want to buy a car and I had very
little money.
So I went and I looked,
there was a 2003 Ford Taurus with like
60,000
miles on it and old guy had cataracts.
So they took away his license.
I can drive and like no,
they took away his license.
So I went in to buy this tourist.
The guy took like four grand for it.
Not a great car,
it's getting you from point a to point
b,
but I had to walk through cars.
One from George W dot Bush won.
I can't remember the singer,
and there was one that was the exact
same model of car that James Dean.
He died and apparently they're only like
13 porsche spyder.
You had a poor spot.
I don't know.
I didn't have it.
I walked through it.
Here's the crazy thing was this guy.
Well let me,
let me finish with this guy who was
selling this whole 2003 tourists.
What are you a ghost?
This is what he drove,
right?
But you know what his business was?
His business was customizing cars like
that poor spider and doing high end
cars.
People like George W dot Bush,
the nicest cars in the country and he
drove it 2003 Ford Taurus that I bought
from him.
It was the most.
It was just this surreal experience
walking through these cars that.
I mean you don't even want to touch,
right?
You want to put a fingerprint on it.
And this guy I found out later was a
multimillionaire.
He could afford any car that he wanted.
He had 2003 tourists.
Well,
some people do that because they want to
stay low key and they just want to just
kind of chill man.
You know,
there's,
there's that,
there's definitely that.
Like Henry rollins drives a Mazda six.
He drives like a regular car and the
reason why he does it is because he's
just like,
he's not,
he doesn't give a fuck.
Henry wants to like sit in front of his
gigantic $200,000
speakers and listen to records.
Like he doesn't care about his car.
So like for him it's like he doesn't
want a ball,
he doesn't want to floss.
He wears the same t shirt.
He has like 100 gray tee shirts.
He wears the same thing every day.
He said,
well,
he's a fascinating character in that
regard because he's a guy who has
financial means.
Like he has a very wealthy guy,
but he chooses not spending on things
like that.
Yeah.
Well it's like my dad gave me this
analogy one time.
We're talking about cars or the ability
to appreciate it,
but you don't need it.
It's like air,
right?
If you all of a sudden you stopped
breathing,
you don't have air.
All you can think about is breathing,
right?
That's the first thing that do just.
I can do Jitsu for being suffocated by
300 pound guy inside control.
Um,
what's the same thing with money?
If you take away the money,
all you can think about is money because
you need money.
And my point was like we were talking
about earlier,
is we don't want people in those
positions determining exactly what I
have to do with my money personally.
As soon as you get money,
you get this stress alleviation that's
palpable.
I mean,
I'm sure it's happened to you because
you've been really successful over the
last few years when you all of a sudden
don't worry about whether or not you
could pay a gas bill this month.
Right?
It's a different feeling.
But until I was 25 years old,
every day of my life was checked.
Check everyday am I was barely mean
fucking barely,
you know,
lying to the landlord.
I sent it.
What happened?
You know,
I mean everybody's,
everybody's who's been in that situation
where you're like literally wondering
how much can I spend today to eat,
you know,
and I've been,
I've been there and we all been there
the moment I got a development deal way
back in the day with Disney of all
people,
of all peoples on the Disney show.
Like either you're just there,
like he's a young good looking guy.
Let's put them into little stud muffin
when I was young and they saw your set.
And I'm like,
Oh,
I was boy,
pretty you wanting to be on TV.
Uh,
well it was,
you know,
1993 or something like that.
So I got a development deal because it
did an mtv half hour comedy hour.
I remember those shows do.
I did one episode of the MTV half hour
comedy hour and I got a development deal
from Disney because of it.
I got like this little thing and they
sent me some money and uh,
as soon as they sent me some money it
was like literally like someone just
took a weight,
lifted it,
like I was carrying around a weighted
backpack right my whole life and they
took it off and it wasn't enough money
where I was wealthy,
where I could say I don't have to work
again,
but it was enough money where I didn't
have to think about money for a year.
Right.
And so all of a sudden I was like,
wow,
this is what it feels like to not worry
about bills.
I have never felt this before.
And then I became obsessed with
maintaining that position.
Once you realize that,
I was like,
oh my God,
I'm a bulldog.
I'm going to work constantly.
I'm going to,
I'm going to do stand up.
I'm now.
I'm not quitting anything will.
Now.
Why was that?
Because I realized how important it is
to not be dependent on anyone,
to not to not change.
Like here's the thing about looking at.
You're talking about Hollywood and the
way people would behave in Hollywood.
It's in many ways,
it's a self in forcing ideology in that
you know that someone like Meryl Streep
who gets up in front of the Golden
Globes or whatever the fuck it was and
says crazy shit,
real art,
but when she's saying that what she's
doing is she's like,
it's a war cry for,
for the likeminded.
Yeah.
You know,
there's no reason to say that and for
any other reason she's,
she wants to rally the troops.
She wants to enforce her ideas and she
wants to make sure that everyone is on
board and the reason she said something,
she hollywood royalty because and
because of that she would say something
that stupid that was received the way it
was because she probably ran it by a
bunch of people beforehand.
Not,
not that the point is not a single
person there.
They all roared and cheered them on a
single person.
There it goes.
What?
Of course you're surrounded by people,
but.
But what I'm saying is that those people
that are reacting to that,
they may agree with it or they may feel
like they have to agree with it.
Yeah.
I don't ever want to be the guy who
feels like he has to agree with
something.
I grew up in a weird way where like my
parents got.
They broke up when I was really young
and we moved around a lot and I didn't
have roots like I didn't live in one
place until Massachusetts when I was 13.
I lived there for a long time.
That was the first place I lived for a
long time and I got a chance to see the
way people cling to ideas versus
actually believe things and I think it's
very important to find out what you
actually believe and it's almost
impossible in Hollywood.
Yeah,
because in Hollywood people have to
audition for things.
Right,
and I've been there,
man,
it's gross.
You go in this room and some person
looks at you and they have a clipboard
and they're judging you and they have
power and the same with and unions can
control groups of people.
The same thing can happen for really
self-righteous ideologues who happen to
be holding that clipboard.
Well then there's also the throwing out
the baby with the bathwater.
We're calling anybody who has a
worldview and idealog and I do think
that you're susceptible if you don't
have a framework from which you look
through the world.
If you have a prison where you go,
okay,
hold on a second.
If you're a hardcore Democrat,
do or die without any exceptions
whatsoever.
You're an ideologue.
If you start going,
US versus them.
I kind of had conversations with people
in Hollywood where they've talked to me
about the Democratic Party.
They'll go,
we have to win the house when the house.
Then we get this like,
well,
what is this we man,
yeah,
you make a fucking cartoon,
but then you have people who just go,
man,
it's left and right.
It's all same.
No,
it's not.
You do need to determine a prism through
which you see the world.
For example,
there's a very clear decision you make.
Do I believe in choice?
Do I believe in freedom and personal
liberty or do I believe in equal
outcomes and that doesn't mean that you
line up with either party the same on
every single issue,
but it is a filter through which you
will be able to see it.
She explained those options.
Again,
a good example right now you have to
make it so someone has to make a
decision right now to one of the three
options that you said.
No,
I put two options and what do I value?
Virginal liberty,
personal liberty and choice,
right?
And choice.
Freedom of choice,
or do I value the idea of equal
outcomes?
Oh,
well,
equal outcomes is ridiculous because I
can't play basketball,
but you can't understand that unless you
have some kind of of people don't like
to.
There's an ism there,
don't you think?
The law that is in things,
people need to play dodge ball.
The need to bring back dodge ball.
You gotta realize stay away from that
big fucker.
That guy throws that dodge ball.
It's going to hurt when the little kid
gets hit,
rush them through the Asian kid with the
glasses that's reading them as soon as
the lesson.
But that kid's a bad motherfucker.
Maybe he's from Thailand.
Maybe people didn't fuck with them since
it was little.
Pretty rare.
Catch them outside of kick you in the
Dick.
How about that guy?
That's possible.
That's entirely possible.
But the point is there,
there is an ism and people don't need to
shy away from saying,
you know what,
I do have some.
There is an ism.
What do you mean by an ism?
Ism where people,
whether we're conservatism left ism,
uh,
liberalism.
I don't think anybody's ever said to act
as though well,
because liberalism is the first person
to say leftism.
No,
I don't think so at all.
Been alive for 49 years.
Never heard a single motherfucker say
left is well because today's left is not
the same as classical liberals.
The word leftism don't skirt the issue.
That might be the first time anybody's
ever said,
have you ever heard of leftism?
Fuck,
I'll stick with it.
I don't care.
I don't think liberalism describes the
current,
the current progressive movement,
um,
but people want people to say,
well,
I,
I'm not a navy log.
Well actually a lot of people,
they don't realize they are to some
degree and you just had to determine to
which degree that is and recognize that
about yourself.
Everyone has a leaning.
Well,
everyone has.
It makes it easier.
It makes it easier to get along if you
subscribe to a predetermined set.
I'm not talking about this and I'm not
talking about that.
There's no predetermined set of values
or ideas.
If someone says,
okay,
I'm looking at the world through this
Lens,
do I look through it where we need to
ensure fairness and equal outcomes?
Or do I look through it?
And the idea that people should be free
to make their own decisions.
That doesn't mean you're subscribing to
the Republican Party when you're talking
about your first initial.
See what I'm talking about,
what we were talking about really
recently,
but I agree with you.
Yeah.
I mean,
I think what we should do see,
I think a big part of the problem with
human beings today is that the,
it's not a fair hand of cards that were
dealt and some want to pretend that it
is.
It's not,
it's just not and you know it and I know
it and we say,
well,
you know what,
you've got to do the best with what
you've got.
And I agree with that.
Yeah.
The real problem with that as the people
that got to fucking ones those people
more than a prone.
Well,
because for them,
the guy with four aces just got Donald
Trump jr.
He was lucky motherfucker by the way.
Donald trump jr is a very nice guy.
He's a sportsman and a hunter and now
that he's.
No,
I like him.
He's my friend.
I mean hunting advocate.
He is.
I mean I only text him,
but he's good buddies with and now
you're going to.
The forms are going to go nuts.
Joe rogan illuminati.
Donald trump said it before.
I've said it before.
They're very friendly guy.
I've every single person that I know
that it's come in contact with Donald
Trump.
Jr said he's a lovely man.
Nothing but good things about him.
One hundred percent.
He became more wealthy.
When you become more successful,
do you find yourself being more
generous?
I've always been a generous person,
but whenever I could be,
because I realized the importance of
comradery.
I realized that because I didn't have a
lot of friends because it was constantly
moving around,
so when I had friends,
I've valued them greatly there.
They were not disposable.
Like my friends to me,
like they are as important as my family
is.
A bunch of my friends have lived with
me,
you know,
like when they'd been broke.
I like when I was single,
especially like tate live with me,
duck and live with me.
They were like,
I got nowhere to go.
I'm like,
fuck you Dude.
Come on man.
So money just amplify your character.
didn'T change it.
Well,
it,
it helped me help people right when I
had the opportunity to do something.
Like if you see someone and they were a
good friend and your,
your.
You have a bounty of wealth,
like could say a good friend is hungry,
you have all this food.
You would have to be some kind of piece
of shit to say,
don't eat my food that I can never
possibly all eat myself.
Right?
You would want them to eat so you feel
better,
but my point is that's who you are.
Right,
and I will say gi Joe has been generous
with what you've been generous with me
in the sense of actually allowing me on
the show content,
whether people get mad about it or not,
and I appreciate that,
but the point is the money didn't
change.
You would amplify.
It's like alcohol.
It amplifies your character.
You're not a racist and you.
Well,
I'm not an alcoholic,
so it amplifies my character.
Amplified your character.
Right?
And so that's important people to know
because you have.
If you,
if you take that and you believe that
again,
as a worldview that money doesn't
necessarily.
It can.
It doesn't inherently change who you
are.
you'll find that you'll see just as many
greedy poor people as you will wealthy
people,
and that's important because when we're
deciding on some arbitrary number and we
just tossed it to democracy,
you can have just as many greedy
portions of the masses as you would big
bankers and they can just vote in their
own self interest and that's not right
either.
WHat do you mean by an arbitrary number?
Liquid?
Well,
I'm saying what should a ceo make?
Right?
What's the fair minimum wage,
and if you understand that there can be
people making less than minimum wage.
Who if they got the joe rogan,
they made their break,
you worked really hard,
but all of a sudden they have millions
of dollars.
They're just as greedy as they are
making $13 an hour.
Again,
it's no at the human condition question
leah,
correct.
That there are people that don't care
about other people's feelings,
don't matter what they make,
but I say to you,
do you have kids?
not yet.
No.
I would say to you as a parent that a
big part of that was how they were
treated while they were developing
trend.
There's genetic variables,
there's people that have illnesses,
mental illnesses.
There's is,
there's all sorts of.
There's all sorts of variables wheN it
comes to who is steven crowder at 29
years of age now?
Who are you?
How'd you get to this point?
Or who am I at 49 years of age?
How did I get to this point?
40 nine,
40 nIne.
Moisturize.
Right.
I was watching the day where you lifted
a kettlebell.
he said,
I'm a strong motherfucker,
although I probably didn't say that.
You did say tHat.
You said those exact words.
Oh yeah,
that's right.
He was talking to me about like really
talking about 450 pounds,
like dead lifts.
I'm like,
dude,
that's not that much yet because you
think you do.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I,
um,
I had knee surgery recently and so for
me,
I know you went through the jujitsu
drawbacks and then got back in and blew
your acl out.
Well,
actually I tore my lcl and the acl was
slightly torn,
but they were like,
actually the guy who does the surgery
and the redwings,
he came out.
He goes,
do you wrestle?
I said,
yeah.
He goes,
okay.
We rarely ever see an lcl that torn
without a blown acl.
He's like,
did you do anything with your ankle?
Was going towards your face guard pass?
But the problem is they went in and they
fix that,
but that wasn't the real raw real
problem.
THe real problem is my kneecap,
I guess whatever it is,
the tissue that holds that in place,
it's gone and they said it would be
easier if you had a torn acl to fix
because we know what it is like with the
kneecap,
take it out,
do a replacement.
There's really a vacatIon.
Kneecap.
I mean they saId.
He basically said there's no reason to
do anything with a kneecap because we
don't know what to say.
If they replace it,
replace it with an iron one.
Just start still rich franklin versus
anderson silva just rearrange this face.
That was so heartbreaking to watch.
A lot of dudes were steel cups to tie
cups necessarily.
think there's a law against it in the
ufc.
They started making laws against it in
brazilian jujitsu.
Jujitsu.
Because you're talking to.
I can't talk.
No,
no.
Here's the deal.
I had a buddy of mine did it to me once.
My friend amir ren have already.
He got on top.
No,
he got on top of me,
mounted me and he had a steel cup on and
he was essentially fucking my solar
plexus.
It was totally uncomfortable because I'm
asking,
well,
it's metal.
I mean you have a metal piece and it
really affects armbars in particular it.
It creates an unnatural fulcrum.
Well,
a back take two is really uncomfortable.
Exactly.
It's going into your lower spine.
Regular cup.
Like I use a diamond mma cup,
you know those aren't.
Those are their compression shorts.
Yeah,
they're,
they're in compression shorts and the
outside of them is like this rubberized
thing.
Yep.
And the outside in the front is all like
a really hard plastic.
Like they.
There's videos of them showing people
taking like full groin shots on purpose
when that was or advertisements.
I can kick the ball.
It really does protect you in an amazing
way,
but it doesn't hurt like a,
like one of those steel tie cups.
So these dudes are fucking real status.
They get these steel tie cup.
It's definitely an advantage.
And you think,
oh yeah.
well I think kenny,
kenny florian fought with it.
I'm pretty sure if I'm a pretty closely.
If you fucking mess up and you kicked
kenny florian and she couldn't break
your foot kid that bar fight.
Hey,
why are you walking with a limp?
I kicked kenny florian.
I'm sure he doesn't wear it to the bar.
I'm talking about it in a cage.
You don't know.
That's a judgment.
I thinking.
Judge kenny.
Yeah.
He wears tight pants.
There's no way.
He's got a fucking compress it.
The local dive.
Just no one that he's looking to impress
a married man.
You son of a bitch.
I thought you were conservative and
Florida and dare you go there.
I'm going to take more tobacco.
Packard.
Turn manson.
I don't ask that tip to kiss ass and
say,
look,
joe rogan so generous,
but I do believe in again,
and go with the of isms.
Generally.
This is a message to people that like
wonder whether they should be generous
or not.
Generosity makes you feel better.
It does.
It Just does.
Like,
it's not a selfish thing to like this
idea that um,
oR not,
not necessarily not a selfish thing.
This idea that to keep your money
yourself,
you protectIng yourself,
you're looking out for number one,
it's not true,
right?
It's,
it's the wrong way to think because when
you're generous,
especially when you're generous to
friends,
it's super important that people who
actually love that,
you expressed that to those people.
When you Do do that,
it's good for you too.
It just doesn't seem like it's good for
you because people are so survival.
Oregon.
There's a great book called who really
cares abouT famine mentality or brooks
or David Brooks,
but he went out kind of seeing who,
who actually donate and who's generous
and kind of going by political
persuasion,
by geographical,
you know,
by just let me guess.
Conservatives are number one.
Yes.
So,
um,
but,
but especially litigious ones.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That is actually true.
Fucking Michigan.
First off,
a minister I mentioned in my home state,
especially with jihadists out there,
you know,
you've seen the muslim videos.
Um,
but uh,
there is the,
the ism and this is one thing that I do
that I do sincerely believe,
and this is why I don't shy away from
saying,
listen,
I'm a conservative.
You saId some that was pretty telling
you said because I really wanted to work
hard.
I never wanted to be beholden to someone
again.
Right?
So you made that decision.
Well,
you knew that if you did that and you
worked hard,
then you wouldn't be holding someone
else.
That was,
that was the assumption you made.
Okay.
But there's a lot of.
Let me just go with this real quick.
The assumption that that is free
enterprise,
free enterprise or capitalism to use the
term,
right?
It can only work under the,
under an optimistic society under people
believing they can retire and do better.
socialism,
collectivism can only operate by
appealing to people's most selfish
nature by appealing to people saying,
listen,
the cards or the deck is stacked against
you.
You can't do this.
There's someone else out there.
It was an ace in the hole.
You've been born without the leg up that
they have.
Therefore,
I need to help you.
That is the big difference.
Capitalism can only survive and
optimism.
Where's collectivism requires the worst
of human nature to sustain itself.
Maybe I believe that,
but what wouldn't it be nicer if people
just.
If someone figured out a way to say,
hey,
how much do you really need?
Instead of saying you have to do this
and put on their deals,
it sounds like a nightmare.
No,
that's not what I'm saying.
What I'm saying is can you contribute a
small amount that's not even going to
affect you,
but it's going to help other people and
do you do that and if you do do that,
how do you do it?
Do you do it in the form of generosity?
like do tip waitresses more than you
should do you do it in the form of
giving out to charities that you feel
are very worthy and you know you've
researched them and you know the people
that are behind them.
Do you do It in terms of,
you know,
a social work you do?
Do you do it in terms of putting out
informational videos that help people
figure out how they can advance their
own lives?
We all do in certain one.
I know you do too.
Certain charitable things amongst people
we care about.
When you address causes that you care
about,
you go out of your way in a non selfish
way.
Try to eliminate certain things or or
add to the coffers of certain
organizations that are doing.
Where do you think are good,
good things.
I agree,
but that should be enforced more than
the idea that some people are fucking
you.
Right?
Right.
Well,
I,
I agree with you and that's again that
idea like you're talking about why are
you giving to this cause why are you,
why are you donating your time?
Right.
You're either,
it comes down to either donating money
or time.
Really the end of the day,
it's some sort of material goods or time
because you're doing it with the belief
that you'll help people.
It doesn't work if you're being forced
to because you know,
there's some people that do it for a tax
break now that's silly.
No one gives away 100,000
dollars to get a kidney.
Got $40,000
tax break.
The math doesn't.
it might have to.
If you run some fucking llc,
you might have some weird shit llc.
Aren't you an llc?
Of course I'm talking about the other
llc.
Some pipes.
Let's smoke a pipe.
It smells amazing though,
doesn't it?
It's good.
It really does smell good.
That's um,
it's definitely way better than
cigarettes.
WhIch shows you how much the fda has
been fucking you.
well actually they've now pipes or a
controlled tobacco product,
which they didn't use to be,
but it's all the chemicals that are
actually added two cigarettes.
What does that mean?
is it hard to get?
I have to show my id to get piped into
the underground.
There's,
there's,
because with pipe tobaccos,
a lot of these local,
like a local tobacco shop,
they'll do their own blends so they'll
buy pipe tobacco in bulk,
like that sear sucker from someplace in
one of the carolinas and I think that's
changing,
so it actually removes the artistry
where a lot of people like this is,
this is the blend I can get in.
I don't know.
You know,
holland,
Michigan,
you can't get anywhere else.
It's amazing.
That's going away.
And what that does fda steps in is what
are the,
do it favors the big boys who send out
their tendons from one centralized
company.
The smaller tobacconist can compete.
That's the worry about mariJuana.
Well,
right,
it'll,
it'll go legal.
You don't need these dispensary's
anymore,
right?
Isn't that kind of what will happen?
They'll be out of business.
Exactly.
It's problem.
Well,
what it also people,
it's okay to possess it and it's okay to
sell it or your friends can give you
some on satisfying we'd ever got.
My yoga teacher gave it to me.
That sounds about right.
How about that?
Every time my wife goes in there tryna
give her some kind of weird incense or
newest,
every time she goes,
she goes into the pot store.
Yoga,
yoga.
There's always something they're selling
essential oils and pot.
No,
not pot,
but they're always got something you
really want to put on incentives or
something.
There's this my point.
My point is you're beholden to the yoga
instructors,
so they use it sometimes.
The sales pitch,
my yoga instructor pure and she's my
friend.
What's,
what's the posing with the pipe?
Fuck.
You can't see when god said,
fuck you.
It actually blew out his own lighter.
Fuck you right wing.
Listen,
I mean,
I sit firmly in the flip flopping
position of the middle.
You don't though.
You're pretty,
you're pretty fair.
Um,
and I do like to think that,
I mean,
it's really hard to get leftists guests
on our show.
That's just a reality.
We try and book them.
And then after a couple of times,
well,
you know,
it's the most leftist guests you've ever
had.
Well,
we had [inaudible] chowdhry who actually
said I should die on hair.
Whoa.
Yeah.
He's the guy who now he's in jail for,
for giving to isis or something from the
uk.
SO we had to.
We had to create a whole new set.
You should die on air.
Why?
Why do you say you should die?
Oh,
because I did a three stooges routine.
dressing up as mahogany on the shabbas.
Three old wife?
Yeah.
Isn't that amazing?
You should die for that.
Die for dressing up as a guy.
Outside of that,
you know sally cone is pretty far left.
Christopher titus.
Oh,
that's what I wanted to talk about.
OH,
they want to talk about Michael Woods
junior because we tried to hit them on.
We wouldn't come on.
The christopher titus debate was one of
the most painful ones I've ever watched.
Was it painful for you?
It,
it.
It Was because I felt as though I
usually do try and get into an
engagement of ideas and he was just
screaming so much.
It was more painful for me because I'm a
dad.
yeah.
And dead kids something,
know something went wrong somewhere
along the line to get him to that place
where he's arguing about something.
We really doesn't know the facts.
Yeah.
It wasn't,
it wasn't just that.
It was when you were throwing out laws,
regulations and he just didn't know
enough.
I kept arguing about it.
You know,
when someone's arguing about something
and they don't know exactly what they're
talking about.
Yeah.
And they've gone down a dark road and
instead saying,
okay,
I can't really talk about this because I
don't,
I don't have any facts at my disposal.
Instead of doing that,
he kept arguing it.
Yeah.
And I was like,
oh jesus.
And I contacted you afterwards.
Jesus bro.
This is rough.
Well,
he is also were very nice about that.
You were very nice to him while I was
going on because it was fucking ugly and
you were very nice afterwards.
You didn't gloat.
We
had him back.
We had him back one time.
Some common ground.
And you just get so mad.
Yes.
Sally cone will you saying you don't
care about dead kid it got.
That's the motive thing that I'm talking
about.
I don't shy away from an emotive thing.
It was,
it was,
it was a conversational debate ploy is
like he.
It was a crude debate,
but he's trying to box you into a
corner.
I want to say this because I appreciate
christopher titus and we've talked off
air a nice guy.
Whereas someone like a Michael Woods
junior who refused to come on the show,
try to leverage coming on this show to
debate me is dishonest.
And someone who's afraid or michael,
ian black,
uh,
who recently got into it with hopefully
he'll come on the show.
A lot of get there with him.
Literally I was on air and all he did
was.
We talked about this last time,
my video on rape culture.
You saw it with the lena dunham thing
where it's one in four women are raped.
And in the video I literally say,
I'm not saying rape is a horrible crime
and those people should be buried
beneath the train tracks.
Okay.
I'm also not apologizing for.
I literally say that in the video.
Okay,
great.
Okay.
And then I get into the stats as to why
rape culture doesn't exist in United
States and it doesn't the middle east.
So all michael ian black tweets out is a
portion of that video,
a snippet that is not the statistics
that I present a snippet that's a sketch
cutaway.
Just tweets out,
holy shit.
And this is the thing that a lot,
if someone sent that to him,
if he got a clip clear,
it goes further.
It's just tweets out,
holy shit.
And this is a constant thing,
right?
That often people who dIsagree with me
politically who identify as a left go
creditor doesn't think there's a great
culture.
And so if they say it as though it's
absurd enough,
people go,
yeah,
that's silly.
But I say,
well hold on,
tell me why I'm wrong.
And so I said,
well,
come on the show,
tell me why I'm wrong.
And he said,
well,
I wouldn't want to straight white guys
debating rape culture.
I'd rather you talk with someone who's a
victim of rape or a woman would have a
better handle on it.
So I said,
okay,
how about you talk with one of my two
head writers,
casey or courtney?
They disagree with you.
They'll be glad to debate it.
no,
I don't think there's going to go.
and then I had to call them out on air
to the point where he's agreed to come
on next thursday.
But again,
the point is,
holy shit,
this is absurd.
Why is it absurd?
Tell me why it's I don't want to show
up.
If you have to ask,
then you don't know and that's the
position today that we see on cable news
that we see from in this election,
but you particularly see from people
trying to silence dissent.
I love the idea of as a white man,
you shouldn't be able to talk about the
certain thing.
You should be able to talk about bugs on
jupiter.
Okay.
It doesn't fucking matter what your
sexual orientation is,
what your gender is,
what your race is.
You should be able to talk about things.
Just because you talk to somebody about
something doesn't mean you the premier
expert of it to the premier,
your the premier expert of it.
No,
you should be able to talk about things.
I think you're right and that's a silly.
That's a silly way whether do you plead
to the left?
Yeah,
it that that really is.
That's what that is,
is you're saying things that you think
people could possibly criticize you
about and you're cutting it off at the
pass before they're preposterous ideas
get to you and your twitter feed.
Well,
to me,
I mean,
like you said,
you disagree with people on certain
things,
but you're not a coward ideologically.
I'm not about physically,
but you'll allow people on who you
disagree with and you'll change your
mind and I definitely changed my mind.
I'm not married to my ideas as much as I
get criticized for that.
No,
I think you're.
I think you're pretty consistent in that
and I think on the flip side,
what we try and do that I say,
listen,
this is my bias.
This is what I believe.
What's your bIas on my body?
And you said,
I'm right wing.
What do you sort of.
If you had to,
like,
if you go god damn minute,
maybe I went too far down this road.
If I could just relax one aspect of my,
my dialogue,
what would it be?
Me.
It will be my pipe smoking your pipe
smoking.
Um,
I probably,
you know,
I probably wouldn't talk about the
marijuana issue that I wouldn't care
because here's the thIng,
I don't care about it one way or the
other,
but my issue with it is when he saw some
montreal,
I talked about it.
When people lie about it and they're
dishonest with their voting
constituency.
Like how so?
Well saying you know,
it's medicine for abc or d and maybe
medicine for a but not for b,
c or d.
Well,
what are the bs,
cs and ds.
One of the things that's not medicine
example.
Well you're asking me what I wouldn't
talk about and asking me to defend it.
The point is I don't really care about
it,
but what are the bcs and d,
what you,
you said the answer is has been shown.
It helps with cancer,
about as much as tumeric and ginger.
Those things helps anti inflammatories,
but it's not a prescriptive.
Cbd has been shown to see tremendous,
tremendous benefits for cancer and non
psychoactive.
Yeah,
and certainly with seizures,
I have zero problem with cbd cannabis,
but much of those little cannabis to.
Yeah,
I feel the need to call people out and
bullshit when they say,
well,
the reason it's not because of big
pharmaceutical companies.
Go,
hold on a second.
There's seven patents on chemical
compounds from marijuana right now.
The people who stand to make the most
out of marijuana legalization or
pharmaceutical companies,
that's why they make not true.
Well,
it is.
If you look at the biggest supplement
now,
but at the same pharmaceutical companies
can't pan the one.
Yes you can.
They've patented seven,
seven.
You leave terrains that gmos.
No,
no.
Seven active chemical compounds and pot
that have been patented as drugs.
They've gone through the process.
Here's one that's really effIcient.
The point where you can't grow pot.
How would you stop someone if it's
legal,
if pot's legal,
how would anyone and if they.
If that's the truth,
that's a real problem.
Pot is recognized as a medicine,
right?
If potus recognize there's no one who
would stand to gain more than
pharmaceutical companies by providing it
as not necessarily true.
If people allowed to fail.
It's not necessarIly true.
I'll give you that,
but I also think it's not necessarily
true that the reason people can't smoke
up is because big pharma is sitting
somewhere,
you know,
martin correctly going,
oh,
let's make potty illegal.
Well,
not that's my only point,
but there are absolutely people who have
lobbied as we talked about how the
prison guard union has lobbied to keep
marijuana illegal.
There's absolutely.
Pharmaceutical companies have done the
same thing.
It was revealed in the wiki leaks.
Memo's.
See,
this is what I was saying was told her,
I'm done interrupting you.
fuck where hillary clinton said that
she's against marijuana in every sense
of the word.
Right.
You remember those.
Those were pretty against it.
That came out.
Yeah.
Is he?
He said he would leave it up to the
states.
Yeah.
That's actually a constitutional
approach,
but he's pretty.
He wants to beef up the war
on drugs.
You know why?
I bet someone slipped him a pot cookie
wants and he looked at his hair in the
mirror and know he's a teetotaler.
He didn't even drink vodka.
Doesn't drink Donald Trump ever.
Now he says he,
Colorado topped 1 billion in legal
marijuana sales in 2016.
Good holla.
Holla.
Colorado.
Yeah,
but another thing that we just wrote
about,
and again,
people get mad with the weed issue.
Well no,
no.
A traffic fatalities regarding marijuana
have skyrocketed.
Google that because that's nonsense.
No drunk driving arrest have dropped.
What do you mean you've what?
First of all,
I read about what the sources are
original.
Just because someone gets in an accident
and they're high.
See,
hold on.
Stop.
No,
no way too much.
And you stopped.
No,
no,
no.
I don't talk about the graphs.
I make full points.
If people are high a lot,
then the same amount of fatalities
exist,
but the people that get checked once
they get into these accidents happened
to be high.
It does not necessarily mean that
marijuana causes fatalities.
It could be that you have an increased
incidence of people doing marijuana and
altercations that could not have been
avoided.
It could be,
it could be the statistical changes,
measurable will what you're talking
about In Colorado,
uh,
in states where it's been
decriminalized.
Go.
It's Colorado.
Pull up jamie and all the sudden you
just said,
let me make my point again.
My point is I don't care about it.
Yeah,
you do.
No,
I really don't.
You don't care about you sign up.
You get so touchy about it because
someone says,
you know what,
if people want to smoke,
fine.
I just don't really buy the arguments
that everyone is in some big conspiracy
to try and sniff it out.
No,
there aren't.
And the Idea that the drug war will end
and the idea that it's,
it's,
it's cures cancer.
I just don't buy that and done so upset.
Well,
we'll listen.
Silence.
Wouldn't studies have proven that it
shrinks tumors that it helps people with
cancer,
much like tumeric law,
much like any things that reduce
inflammation and community tart cherry.
Right?
But it's not necessarily a shit.
They're all legal and there's no issue
because they're not psychoactive,
right?
But there are beneficial,
so all these things are good.
marijuana is one of the things that are
good and don't sure,
man,
just like you don't sure to merrick,
you don't sure.
Ginger,
you don't sure a reduced sugar diet,
all those things that reduce
inflammation or I don't buy that smoking
marijuana would be as beneficial as the
reduced sugar diet and my point is that
people might so offended that and sing,
but if you want to smoke,
go head,
you might be correct and be offended.
IT doesn't matter because it's not a
fucking contest to see what's the most
beneficial it.
The question is,
is it beneficial and is it damaging?
It is.
It does matter.
The fact that.
No,
let me,
let me finish my point.
It does matter.
You said,
what would you not talk about?
I said probably pot because I don't
care.
Well,
what do you think?
You would definitely think about it and
your eyes light up and all of a sudden
krg and worldviews shouldn't be
discussed.
You're going like a tractor beam on the
most important issue of the day that I
said I don't care.
You're the guy that thinks people should
be able to do whatever your
market guy.
So if you're a free market guy,
why wouLdn't you be in support of some
thing,
whether it's the most beneficial or
equally beneficial,
but you're not necessarily because
you're denying chemical compound.
Fuck.
Face your friends.
I'm just joking.
Since marijuana legalization highway
fatalities in Colorado or at rehab and
bringing up the source that you want to
bring up the study right there.
Yeah,
Washington post's.
Bring up the study that we wrote.
We wrote about it on our website.
Look,
I don't care about your website.
You fuck.
Since marijuana legalization.
Highway fatalities in Colorado since you
called me a fucking pussy and you do
this with the crazy lady to comedy club.
You think if you scream enough that it
makes it,
but my point is I don't care about that.
And you just said it was interrupting.
You're interrupting screaming because
don't care about to put up a post,
but I don't buy that.
It's as valuable as a low sugar diet and
the fact that doesn't have to as value
can't have a conversation about this as
civilly as he did.
Every other issue tells me that there's
a problem.
This is tnt powder.
Can I get very defensive when people
start talking over me and you started at
first,
but the reality is that it's a low sugar
diet is fine.
It's good too,
but why is there a competition between a
low sugar diet and tumeric and marijuana
and cbd oil?
Why?
Why does making the claim regarding
legality that it cures cancer.
My only.
My only point is the other ones are
already legally don't have to fight for
the ones prescribing.
No ones dishing out a dispensary for
tumeric.
Ginger.
They certainly are.
If you go to these local juice shop,
you go to these jews shops.
People are promoted with ginger tumeric
like crazy people couldn't care less.
People want to smoke joints.
You're An ideologue buddy.
Really?
That's an ideologue position by saying,
leave it to the states.
Yeah,
you,
you're,
you're locked in man.
Really?
You locked deep into this fucking thing.
Man.
I was raised in a socialist province
with bread is buttered buddy,
a socialist province hand mirror over
here in America.
Just as much of an immigrant is some
dude who sneaks over the wall.
Trump just built a porn in detroit,
so that remains to be seen.
It could be annexed,
so horrible.
Detroit.
Have you seen that thing where there is
a guy who is making a an urban farm in
detroit?
Oh,
that's very common in detroit now.
Well,
he's kind of the largest urban farm.
Yeah.
He's bought up all this land and as he's
bought up all this land,
he's taking these dilapidated houses.
They tear them down,
is building this farm really cheap land
and people are getting pissed off at
them.
They're getting pissed off because this
one guy now buys all this land.
They're like,
well,
what about us and this?
This is weird thing that's going on
where people somehow or another mad at
this guy who was trying to do something
positive,
if I'm not mistaken on that story,
I could be wrong,
but urban farming was a real.
We wrote about that when we did this
report in detroit.
I was telling jamie about it beforehand.
We did a realtime right along because
people said we selectively edited the
worst parts of detroit,
so went back with my producer,
not gay yard.
We said,
okay,
we're going to start dead center
downtown detroit where all the hipsters
drink their coffee and talk about how
it's being revived.
We will drive out in three different
directions.
We put a gopro on top of the car,
go pro in the car,
a mileage tab and a timer clock,
and it never took more than about,
I think,
point nine miles out of the city to
certain death and unbelievable urban
plight.
The crazy thing about detroit is you'll
see downtown detroit and then you look
to the left and it looks like the upper
peninsula.
There's nothing there.
It's so desolate and if I'm not mistaken
with that story,
everyone was doing urban farming,
but there were some problems with the
soil and so it was a guy who probably
found out he could make money if he
improved the soil and he got it down to
a system that was more efficient and
people didn't like that aspect of it
because now it's the big urban farmer,
right?
They're always so wealthy guy who bought
up a lot of land.
Right.
And he's a white guy and he bought it up
in this,
you know,
really urban area and you know,
the buildings were all fucked up and
somehow or another people felt like
somebody was encroaching in their
neighborhood that they had watched
deteriorate.
I know in there there's no one there and
those names.
Some people were there,
but the point is they felt like that
should have been somehow or another part
of their world,
which is weird.
It's weird to think that you deserve
somethIng because that's where you live.
I think like we were talking earlier
about uber and all these things,
change is a real part of being an
organism that lives on a planet.
Right?
And whether it's changed because of
nature,
like the fucking,
the shoreline changes,
the ocean rises,
tsunamis hit the coast,
earthquakes changed the landscape.
What volcanoes,
whether it's that kind of change or
whether it's economic change or whether
it's technological change,
there's going to be changed and if you
try to stop change,
you're on the wrong side of history.
It's not gonna work.
You gotta you gotta try it.
It's eventually gonna overcome you.
Yeah.
I think,
uh,
you know,
my,
my view is you should allow people to be
the change they seek as barack obama put
it and it shouldn't try to force change.
We,
if you live in a shitty neighborhood,
some dude wants a break down the,
the terrible houses and build a farm.
that's not necessarily a bad idea.
No,
it's not at all.
Yeah.
I mean they have,
when we did our video in detroit,
packs of wild dogs roaming the streets
and it's real.
Yeah.
That's real.
And we've got fact checked on it because
we did a video on this where we said,
you know,
packs of.
And then I made a joke where I said
apparently there've been grizzly bear
sightings,
so hopefully this will be our next
national geographic specials.
So That doesn't bear sightings.
Right.
But I got fact checked.
I don't know if it was back then.
It,
I don't remember if it was snopes or
something.
Someone's saying.
Steven crowder made the claim that
grizzly bears were in detroit.
Facts check reveals that only black
bears have been sitting there like,
well,
you should fact check them because blue
black bears are more lIkely to be
predatory on human beings.
Then grizzly bears.
This is because of more common
interactions though.
Statistically,
you're very smart.
You're right.
That's right.
Kinda like sharks that occurs in three
to four feet of water.
That's where people are swimming.
Exactly.
Um,
but that is the case with grizzly.
Grizzly bears are way more aggressive,
but they don't necessarily associate
human beings with food.
Are you supposed to play dead?
Are run wIth a grizzly bear?
You wouldn't know that.
Probably.
It depends entirely on why the grizzly
bears attacking you.
The reality is,
if a grizzly bear is attacking you
because she's with her cubs,
you're better off playing dead.
You're better off covering up,
texting your vitals,
getting the turtle position,
and taking your beatings and she's your
ass.
Goodbye.
She's gonna fuck you up,
but she might leave you alone if you
just lay still and then she feels like
she can run away.
She's gonna.
Fuck you up.
No matter what,
she's going to incapacitate you,
but if an old male or a predatory male
that has killed another human being and
recognize as human beings is food that
has happened before where hikers have
disappeared and hikers disappear all the
time to the tune of hundreds of people
every year just vanish.
I read that actually polar bears will
stalk people.
Well,
that's a different animal.
Polar bears or completely predatory,
which means they don't eat any
vegetation.
You can get lucky with grizzly bears.
What?
Grizzly bears can have a fucking field
of blueberries and they don't want to
have anything to do with you because
blueberries are delicious.
They don't run and they Could just sit
there and eat and they don't have any
hunger pangs.
Really?
Yeah.
How many blueberries would it take?
The feet of grizzlies?
Well,
does she know you're talking about
Alaska,
like a mountain side,
like in the spring or in the fall,
rather like before they go into
hibernation.
That'S what they primarily eat because
all that sugar just gets like straight
into the fat.
Their bodies and they store it up big,
thick,
fat layers,
but an animal that has already killed a
person is where it becomes a real
problem.
It's not that animals are evil or
animals like target people.
It's they recognize food sources that
they've already eaten.
Did you see those people who were
protesting?
They were really mad.
The rangers that yellowstone park,
so they're very strict that you cannot
feed the bears.
You can then interact with them and what
they do is they had a bear that wasn't
necessarily aggressive,
but they do this all the time,
but there was some specific instance
that piss people off.
Wasn't necessarily being aggressive,
but learn that people would throw food
at it,
and so we're going,
well not only can we not have that bear
doing it,
but we can't have other bears seeing
that bear as an example.
So what they do,
their first ep has taken the bear far
away.
You know,
somehow transporting them,
a sedating them,
and if it comes back either a second or
third time they euthanized.
They have to.
And all of these people were furious.
No,
no,
no.
We're doing this that the bears don't
become dependent on humans for food.
If euthanize one barrier that prevents
the rest of them,
the they no longer can forage,
can hunt for themselves because they
realize these people are gonna throw us
a sandwich.
And that's a great example of just
people not knowing,
not being informed enough on an on an
issue and instead deciding to be
outraged.
Like,
I don't know about grizzly bears.
They assume the yellowstone rangers kind
of have their crap together on it.
Well,
that's also like peta,
people that don't want to admit that
peta kills thousands of cats and dogs
every year and their heads a diabetic
who uses insulin,
which came to courtesy of animal
testing,
but she feels like that's okay because
she's a vegan,
she's skinny fat,
but there's a great podcast that's
available right now,
the most recent meat eater podcast with
steve rinella,
where he talks to a bear biologist who
discusses the history of yellowstone at
one point in time,
the dumps where people in restaurants
used to dump all their food was places
where people would go to watch to watch
bear.
We Did it at a campground.
There was like,
well,
what year was this?
Gosh,
nineties.
Where were you not in yellowstone?
No,
this wasn't Canada.
Okay.
They'd already made it illegal in
yellowstone I barriers when we went.
We just drove by.
There was no one,
but it's like,
yeah,
if you go down under this area,
it's really cool.
You get to see the bears foraging thing.
In yelloWstone it was one of the main,
like mortality,
like if you look at mortality events,
it was a huge mortality event because
they went cold Turkey,
they stopped dumping all the trash there
and these bands had become acclimated so
much so that they had stopped learning
how to forage for food and bears died.
Like unmask.
Yeah,
it's really kind of crazy.
That's also the flip side with a rescue
dog where I tell people like we have a
rescue dog and people get so offended
really say,
but if you have kids,
probably better to go from a breeder,
you know,
because for example,
hopper on the road,
we don't know,
you know,
we don't know what happened to me.
Happens to me the most affectIonate,
loving dog that we've known,
but a dog like that,
that starving can learn to become much
more of a wild dog,
you know,
that can be trained in them because
they're scared.
They're scared and you bring them in.
For example,
he gets recall any gun ever since we've
had him any handgun,
rifle,
pull it out,
goes nuts.
So he's seen guns.
He seen something in a negative
connotation with guns.
You can't know that,
so if you have some kid and he pulls out
a squirt gun,
now he's not aggressive.
He's just a bark.
If he doesn't like something and people
have.
I don't know if it was to some animal
person got really mad.
Well,
well there are so many dogs that need
homes going.
Listen,
I've rescued a dog.
I think if you know what you're
handling,
you should if you're able,
but if you have kids who don't have a
lot of dog training and you don't know
where this dogs come from,
I placed kids higher on the totem pole
than dog.
How dare you?
A species.
A species is.
That's a new thing.
It isn't there.
Speciesism,
when we were kids,
jamie,
you're younger.
There was a fiLm species where that
blonde chick that's different.
Which he go,
she quit.
I don't know.
She's probably doing softcore
pornography.
How dare you.
Maybe she's writing books.
Well,
the the grid,
so I didn't know that.
I've never thought of black bears as
being aggressive toward people.
Yeah,
man,
I rinella.
The same guy who has the podcast I was
talking about told me a story of a guy
who went on his very first hunt and
while he was in his tent,
a 500 pound predatory grizzly bear
attacked him.
His friend shot the bear and hit him in
the wrist.
The bear takes off,
out of the tent,
goes to another dude's 10 and they shoot
it in that tent to kill it.
So everyone's covered in blood and hair
and it didn't kill it.
Yeah,
they killed it,
but I mean the guy had a bullet wound in
his wrist.
He had been mauled by this bear.
I mean this is first hunting trip ever.
Could you see the reverend?
Yes.
Remember that there was a rumor before
that film came out that leonardo
dicaprio gets raped by the bear.
Did you read that?
That was front page and are on the wrong
website.
It was frontpage at exactly the wrong
side and I remember thinking about that
number,
watching it going.
This is an example of fake news,
whether it's the right or the left is
going.
This is clearly not a bear rape scene,
but it was a huge rumor that was going
around because it don't.
Don't go see.
The rep was in huge enough to reach mY
twitter page.
You have a big twitter page just to into
it,
man.
You too deep into the news of the world.
I told this story to chris leaving at
the reverend reverend revenue revenue,
revenue revenue.
So we're there.
This is,
I swear this is true.
And crystal even thought it was fake and
fake it.
So we're watching the revenant and it's
right at that scene where he cauterizes
as wound and with the gunpowder on his
neck.
So we're sitting there and we're
watching it and,
and he's screaming and so for a second
we didn't realize it.
A few rows down.
A guys all of a sudden starts projectile
vomiting wildly and I was on three
months and we're looking and we're
going,
oh my god,
we think you starts shaking.
We think he's having a seizure.
My wife being a sweeter goes,
okay,
everybody move away.
Someone called nine slash 11 and his,
his wife or his girlfriend.
I was like,
sweetie,
are you,
and it's going down to rose.
We,
I go,
I wait for the ambulance that they come
in.
The guy has vomit all over him.
I think someone who's sitting in front
of the bottom on the back of his head,
they thought for sure he had a seizure.
Turns out he'd fallen asleep and inhaled
a popcorn kernel [inaudible],
and he was just choking and then free
time and then aspirating on his own
vomit.
So we're watching this film,
the revenue,
one of the most graphic scenes in
cinematic modern history,
facts and evidence.
What the hell is going on?
Wow.
And a coincidence.
Yeah,
and it was.
I mean the guy was embarrassed.
He just fell asleep.
It's not a cool story.
I've amassed.
It was a scene like a.
You remember that movie?
What was that movie with matt?
damon?
Matt dillon.
What was the movie where the two girls
were making out by the pool?
Stranger?
No.
Oh.
Oh,
wild things with things.
yeah.
What if he watched that movie and one of
that scene was going down and that
popcorn kernel got stuck in his mouth.
They started projectile vomiting.
Why would that be worse?
It'd be way worse.
Just be making sense.
I like the guy has scared the berries
killing leonardo dicaprio.
No,
don't kill leo.
don't do it to him.
He's the king of the world.
He's in the front of the fucking
titanic.
Don't,
don't do it.
you know,
people freak out and like a bear attack.
But if you're freaking out like a
lesbian event,
it turns out just coincidentally,
just the story people are going to tell
about you for the rest of your life.
Now,
bobby saw these two broads making out
there will hopped on his loan.
He's alarms by himself.
We just started hurling changes.
Lifepro city chosen popcorn.
But we know that.
Oh my gosh,
I've never,
I've never seen it.
Like,
I mean from here to that buddha statue
taken the kid in the pie eating contest
and that Stephen King boomi stand by me.
Remember that?
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Very pie contest.
I went to this this worse because it
wasn't like a flow.
It was pressurized.
It's funny because he was also holding
his mouth.
So it's coming on,
you know,
like this where it's going to squirt and
so was it when he fell asleep with a
popcorn kernel,
his mouth at the revenue in the middle
of that fucking really exciting movie in
the middle of that scene.
Right where he's cauterizes the wound in
his neck.
Fuck.
I felt bad for them and I imagine that
if that,
if that wasn't his wife that was,
wasn't as fiance,
there's a good chance theY're not
together.
Did you think that movie was based on
real life events?
Have no idea.
Was it supposedly but incorrectly?
Oh really?
Yeah.
It's not so much a sound check.
I think they already have.
Oh really didn't happen in an
environment.
Anything like the environment.
They filmed it in and they filmed it in
this like tropical rain forest in
british columbia.
The guy never had a son.
When leonardo dicaprio son is killed in
front of them.
The only thing that was true it was the
guy got mauled by a bear,
made it back to camp.
They left him for dead.
He actually survived.
You made it back to camp.
That's.
And he's like,
what the fuck,
bro?
The guy was like,
sorry,
I thought you were dead.
That's it.
That's the movie.
But in the entire cast,
caesar was the lead up to the bear
attack and it was him going back and
killing the guy left him behind.
You also killed his son.
No son,
nobody killed anybody.
He got fucked up by a bear and they left
him alone.
That's interesting.
When you think about that,
you know,
you go back and I'm like,
weston price,
not western price foundation for they do
like the fermented cod liver oil and
stuff and they,
they're a big catalyst for like eating
real fats and stuff.
And the guy claimed were this,
what does the weston a price foundation
and we're advert advocates,
traditional order along around for a
long time.
yeah.
Guy.
I think his name is weston price and
that,
because I always watched those movies
like the revenant and I go,
could you imagine how much it smelled or
imagine what their teeth were like.
But this guy claimed he went down to,
uh,
like,
you know,
third world sort of african nations
where they didn't brush their teeth,
but they had perfect smiles.
Any claims it was because I don't know
how,
I don't know if it's true at all,
but he says it was because they ate a
lot of organ meats that are gettIng a
lot of vitamin k natural vitamin d as
opposed to kind of the sugary lifestyle
with refined carbohydrates in the new
world.
Um,
and that's a big part of this whole kind
of high saturated fat.
Oregon's a bone broths.
It's called the weston price foundation.
But I remember there were these pictures
side by side of people in the new world.
We're in largely grain fed diets and
these people who were basically third
world sort of tribesmen,
but that these beautiful white teeth.
No,
make sense in some ways that people that
live natural lives with natural foods
without anything
processed would be healthier.
Yeah.
but the teeth and they were a nice white
teeth look better for sure,
is definitely deteriorates your teeth.
We know that.
We know that should keep kids.
We had a lot of sugar and don't brush
their teeth,
and I think a lot of that is also that
stuff getting caught in your gums and
your teeth and just not good causes
causes tooth decay.
We know that.
Yep,
and the worst thing is a sugar free
gummy bears.
You read those reviews and amazon god,
what do they do to your asshole?
That's exactly what the reviews on
amazon.
I swear to you,
if you just google sugar free gummy
bears,
just like my asshole has never been the
same size since.
It's just a bunch of people who tRolled
the amazon review section for if you're
ever looking for a laugh on a sunday
afternoon,
read the amazon reviews for sugar free,
haribo gummy.
Remember olestra,
there was an additive to like potato
chips,
a less traditional banks,
people just rocket shit.
Other asshole.
They allow it.
No.
Well,
trans fats are now they're illegal,
but you have they ever.
There's a grace period until 2018,
I believe,
or maybe 19 where companies are allowed
to still use that stuff and their potato
chips or wherever the fuck they sell.
Up until then,
like that's it,
like you can poison people for two more
years.
That's it.
Well,
you know why we use terrible for you
because of the same environmental
vegetarian lobby.
Who back then mcdonald's used beef
tallow fries.
It was,
no,
you need to be using vegetable oil,
hydrogenated vegetable oils.
So that was a bunch of lobbyists.
You know,
that's why we started eating trans fats
and now they're going,
actually margarine is not as good for
you as butter and they've changed,
but that was a huge powerful lobbying
group for the vegetarians.
You know,
the san francisco kind of hippie era.
That's why trans fats became ubiquitous.
Well,
it was also a byproduct of the sugar
industry driving scientists to lie about
the beneficial qualities of their sugar
and they just pretended that sugar's
fine when you born with it saturated
fat,
that's the issue and everybody wants
shit.
We got to get some margarine.
Yeah.
These people went out and bought margin
because it terrified of saturated fat
because the sugar companies had bribed.
Some scientists were that when we were
kids,
country crock margarine and we didn't
feel so bad for you.
It's interesting now that that's been
revealed and you find out that those
people didn't even get that much money.
They got like the equivalent of $50,000
today,
right?
To literallY lie to everybody about the.
They just made up a bunch of shit about
saturated fat and they,
they just diminished all the negative
effects of sugar and people just started
drinking that.
That milk from a captain crunch.
Remember that milk when you get that
fucking sugary captain crunch milk or
delicious,
it's absolutely delicious.
You get the chocolate milk at a coco
pops.
Oh my god,
count chocula.
Oh my jesus.
we grew up on sugar.
I know in Canada we,
uh,
we had a whole different.
I didn't realize till I moved to the
states.
Corn pops in Canada
are actually like spherical captain
crunch.
They're not at all like corn pops in the
states.
Is there a lot of little differences
because it's such a silly country where
you'll be raised there and you'll come
here and like,
wait,
aren't the same super sugar crisp had
sugar in the title.
That's right.
That was the sugar bear,
right?
Yeah.
It wasn't bad enough of that sugar.
That's right.
Super sugar crisp.
You imagine you have a god damned drug
in the name of your look at.
There you go.
That is crazy exist.
It's not even good.
It's illegal.
you go to jail if you even sell that.
Does the sugar bear?
I'm here.
I'm in sugar.
the sugar chris.
Chris.
Some differences in sugar.
I'm of strange mongoose.
I'm a mongoose with a tee shirt off.
Then there was cookie crisp cookies in
milk,
but then it was reese's puffs cereal.
Look at that one smacks.
They have an indian cultural
appropriation that today.
Look at that.
What does that have to do with a native
american?
What smacks?
It's kinda like latino selling cars.
They just put tits on it because it
sells in their culture.
Inside is a free indian car.
That's a special indian it.
She doesn't make an acceptable.
They created the indian cards.
It's just as bad.
No,
it's fine.
There's a giveaway of the cultural
frosted flakes.
Go down a frosted flakes over there.
yeah.
Nineteen 50 years of vitamin d.
Vitamin d?
Yeah.
Throw it in there.
There's no natural losses.
Millionaire.
He's got milk.
Posey.
Kid's going to get sick fRom sugar.
What kind of fucking shitty kids are you
raising?
Reese's puffs cereal.
That was a big one.
Everyone else.
Reese's puffs.
Reese's pieces.
Peanut butter cups of cereal.
You know?
That's it.
You never had that?
No.
That was a little later than you.
I guess you might have been illegal in
my country.
They find been looking out for our best
interest by the.
I remember it because there was.
There was like a fat black kid from
hanging with Mr.
Cooper who did the commercials and
Canada for reasons I love that.
Reese's puffs cereal who were sitting
there as this kid who was in hanging
with Mr.
Cooper and so as a kid you're like,
well,
we watched that show on t gif.
We have to get reese's peanut butter
cups.
Siri gif up there.
That was what?
That was the same thing.
Abc,
you know,
it's a fucking place itself was bad
wIngs too.
They're not that bad.
They're pretty bad in Kansas.
You're on the road.
It's true.
Tgi friday's,
what's the big deal?
Bennigan's is coming back to bennigan's
is back.
Don't remember that.
They were gone away because there was
like,
well,
okay,
bennigan's we can do without.
Didn't notice.
I mean they went under and then they
came back.
They were gone.
Now they're back.
I don't know why.
Huh?
Whole new brand.
Probably investment bankers.
Probably some dudes from marin county.
It's the globalists wire.
Wire frame.
Glasses was fucks.
Skinny Jeans will return to do is bring
back a really recognizable brand.
It's really important to America.
have you ever had people do that on this
show feel and we understand you.
People try to in and be like,
listen,
we can take your show even bigger.
We just think there are a few tweaks
here.
We got those people who approach,
you know,
which is interesting.
Now everybody's like,
no,
no.
Adam curl.
they got him though.
They did.
I don't know,
I did,
I did his show once and it was a,
it was the most awkward thing I'd ever
done in my life.
Why was it so awkward?
What?
Cause the booker,
so was doing prager university.
He's like,
oh hey,
I know I'll hook you up.
And um,
first off he's like,
adam carolla,
he's not like you,
like,
like come in and you talk off air.
You kind of like doesn't,
it doesn't really talk to you until
you're on air,
which I can respect.
It's professional,
but it wasn't on the adam carolla
podcast.
It was adam carolla and dr drew had
reunited to do,
like,
it wasn't a love line,
but it's effectively the same thing.
Right.
And so they still do that or they
brought it back and it was there for
like the first week I was there for like
the first week they brought it back and
so it's him and dr drew sitting there
doing their stick at a table and then
I'm literally at the end of the table
with nothing to say like,
oh yeah,
that sounds about right.
They're taking calls from people didn't
even bring you in a little bit,
but it just,
you know,
adam carolla does his podcasts,
like this was an interview and that was
just,
it was really weird and I think what
happened was they didn't realize he
wasn't doing the show that day and they
brought me.
They were very nice.
Dr drew and adam was gracious afterward,
but it was,
it was clear like it's a two guy show
taking phone calls and you were just
there.
Yeah,
it was pretty much just.
They say your name.
No,
no,
they did.
They did,
but it was like,
we want to take phone calls.
Well,
adam does essentially doesn't internet
radio show.
That's what his show is,
you know?
I mean he was,
he had his radio show that was a big hit
radio show and then the station went
under an la and I think he just decided
to do the same format and just do that
same format online.
Yeah.
That makes it.
Well,
when we started our show it was
syndicated and so we had radio and so we
had all these commercial breaks.
When you do at 6:00
AM on friday mornings out of detroit and
what we do well,
no one really cares about these
commercial breaks nationally,
so we just did a bunch of sketches and
fake commercials and that's what created
all these characters that people have
treated these twitter profiles for
because we just said,
well,
you know,
so we're not going to run an ad for a
local car dealership.
Right.
We'll do a fake news break and we would
do like fake tornado warnings and stuff
like that,
which is highly illegal by the way.
We learned that one later on,
uh,
because we had to kind of work with the
format online and now we just took it
off,
took it off radio.
Fuck radio.
It was too much dying market.
That thing is not going to last.
It's stupid.
It was the last time you turned on your
radio.
I haven't ever.
Yeah.
Remember as another person,
I think like all the cells in your body
except your neuron switch every seven
years.
That means every cell in my body has
never listened to the radio.
That's real.
That's fucking real man.
It's like if someone said to me when was
the last time you watched a vhs
cassette?
As it was another person?
I wasn't even me.
I don't take responsibility for me of 14
years ago because if I did I would still
be pissed at shit in my pants when I was
a baby.
Okay.
Because that would take it back to when
I was three and I even bit my sister or
something.
I don't know what the fuck I did,
but you know what I mean.
I met,
I might've,
I don't know.
I don't remember.
Three is my point.
It's like if you go back to the things
you did when you were developing
individual.
Yeah.
So I feel like every seven years I
don't,
I don't even want.
I don't even want to know what I did.
Fourteen years at three.
It's pretty rough years.
I called my dad's pastor a little
bastard.
Three.
You should probably write well because
my grandfather called me a little
bastard and I thought it was a term of
endearment and somebody has like this
test or kevin butcher.
I said,
hey,
how you doing?
Little bastard weld that pastors should
have known,
oh,
this kid is getting fucked over at home.
No,
you know what happened?
Actually,
he got outed.
Uh,
and this is actually a point where,
no,
he got it from the church because there
was his pregnant,
I think his pregnant wife bomb,
which wasn't a detroit lions game.
And there was a guy with a bull horn
behind her,
right up against her ear.
Right?
This guy was a pat,
but a really good guy,
uh,
regardless of someone's,
you know,
religious affiliation,
but a good guy.
And he's like,
hey man,
can you stop my wife's here?
You know,
whatever.
She was pregnant or something and I to
look at it and kept doing it right next
to his wife's here,
like,
got right up on her ear.
And he,
he,
he ended up kicking the guY's ass,
uh,
getting into a fight with him because
the guy was getting up on their space
and it didn't exactly turn the other
cheek.
He did not.
He did when he asked them to.
And so there was a whole vote.
And uh,
I remember that was,
that was when I was pretty young.
I thought,
well,
so they outed him.
They got rid of them,
meaning I could be wrong.
There was a hole up,
there was a whole controversy over it.
And I remember learning about it as a
kid thing.
Well that's,
that seems pretty reasonable.
The guy getting up and his wife's grill
and bothering a pregnant woman.
It's like,
what do you do?
Because human nature is definitely the
hit the person.
But do you just leave,
you know,
because you're,
you're,
your nIght is ruined.
Yeah.
Period.
Well,
I say kick his ass.
I mean,
I think what happened was.
No,
no,
I don't think he kicked his ass,
I'm saying,
but you got physical and he got physical
with a guy and got the better of them.
So it could have been a shoving match.
Could have been a punch.
He didn't beat him.
It wasn't american history.
X,
curb stomp.
I'm just saying no one expected a pastor
to do anything to protect his wife
again.
Yeah.
And uh,
that was a big deal.
I called him little bastard.
That's the end of that rabbit trail.
While you were right,
once you got kicked out that crowd or
kid,
he's got vision.
He sees the future.
This kid's going places.
He knew that guy was a brawler.
He's in fucking bleachers.
Brawler tag.
It's look it up.
Fucks his wife,
gets her pregnant texture to the game.
That crowd has gone places.
He calls It.
He's going to go to fox news for four
years.
He knows four years of his life.
I saw him on this show once with amy
schumer.
He acted with a.
Oh,
I took his side.
He good with it.
What is this?
What did she do?
She,
you guys were on some show and she was
trying to like diminish you as a
comedian.
Yeah,
it was.
She,
she was trying to say you weren't a
comedian.
Yeah.
And then the interesting thing,
this is like a thing that people do in
the world of standup comedy with it.
Just say,
oh,
he's an opener.
Like he's a middle act.
Right.
you know,
like the,
there's like there's this weird sort of
a thing and someone like if they're
looking like shit on you.
Oh,
you do ta,
you do comedy,
you do comedy.
Yeah.
What he'd done,
he'd do a few open mics.
You think you're a fucking comedian?
Yeah,
I really.
It's very,
very,
really disliked that.
Yeah,
she did that right off and I knew it
because she was asking me questions in
the green room.
Like,
where do you,
where do you do comedy?
What do you do?
Do you.
And she was like,
she asked me one point,
did you perform at churches?
I said,
no.
no,
I never have.
And she.
But she was so inflexible and argument.
She was an old maybe 22,
23.
I would have shit on you too dude.
Probably what?
I would have been right next to it that
changed.
If you look at the rehab,
amy would have fucking dog tag deal.
No,
I don't.
I don't think so.
It changed drowsing sound.
What do you think would have happened?
You would have won that.
Been there and done really well?
Yeah.
Yeah,
I think,
I think if you watched that thing,
her argument was you're not a real
comedian.
I think I would have never accessed
information and shimmers of 30 something
year old girl who bitches and people on
twitter now and is unmarried and
miserable and I'm married to a woman.
Uh,
I'm pretty happy With.
Are you comparing lives?
Um,
I am and I think I was right.
Well I think that whenever someone and
also that she's funny by the way.
Okay,
good for you.
I think whenever someone says that
you're not a comedian thing,
that's,
that's an issue.
I have an issue with that because we all
started out as an open micros and when
you're talking to someone who's 22 years
old when I was 22 hours and open miker I
was doing open mic nights just for
laughs at that point.
So it wasn't an open mic or.
Yeah,
I mean,
and you know,
I'd will,
you be clunky.
Well,
you're getting paid professional
comedian.
You're making your living off of standup
comedy or reading only made my living
ever off of acting standup comedy or
writing since 18 years old.
Wow.
So when you were 22 years old,
all your bills when you lived with your
mom or what's going on now?
How are you paying your bills?
A standup comedy?
We're 22 years,
so I was,
I was uh,
I would do stand up and they had some
pretty relatively successful acting
gigs.
Did some films,
commercials on tv.
I'm at that point.
I was a fox news contributor which paid
me retainer.
Um,
I did freelance writing where they would
pay by the word.
So those you were doing standup on a
regular basis.
See where a standup guy.
I don't do it much anymore.
I would readily admit now I don't
because the show and everything is a 14
hour day and I would never claim to be
as good of a standup as,
as you are nick depaulo or a builder by
the way.
But nick depAulo asked me to plug.
He's doing a standup special in boston.
Yeah.
His standup specials going on seeso this
thursday.
So please go.
He's tomorrow the best for my money,
one of the best living comedians.
Uh,
he's certainly one of my favorite.
Nick depaulo was goddamn hilarious and
he was here yesterday and you fucking
killed me.
he's,
he's a very fun and a very,
very,
very good dude.
And another weirdo,
right wing.
Fuck yeah,
he is.
But um,
you know,
it's pretty common.
I mean,
christopher titus at the same thing.
That was the same thing.
We staRted losing the gun issue.
He goes,
well on stand up.
I get paid for standing.
Well,
you know,
that's he when he was doing was trying
to save whatever was going on in his
mind when there's a conversation,
whether it was a competition,
whatever,
the little battle ground and his mind
was going on.
He was trying to save his,
his patch of land.
Well,
I think,
and I think it would work with most
people,
I think you would probably go with,
there's a lot of standup comedians.
They,
they have a void and they're filling it.
This becomes their identity.
And so for me it was never my whole
identity wrapped up in standup.
I mean,
I had been doing acting since I was 12
years old and I was tutored on set with
a lot of things.
Uh,
you know,
I did kid's cartoons that show arthur's
how I started out,
so I did stand up and I'll be the first
minute I did it as a means to getting to
other avenues and then it turned out I
fell in love with it,
but I never planned on doing stand up my
whole life.
So if I were,
I'm a standup comedian,
I'm a road comic.
I love being,
you know,
waking up for leftover drugs and being
unhappy and bitching about my manager
leftover drugs.
Have you ever heard of such thing?
YeAh,
yeah.
I'm,
I've got leftover Turkey.
Oh,
drugs,
drugs.
This will have them write the pride in
standup of barely getting by,
kind of like New York.
Right?
You're in a shitty city in a two bedroom
apartment with five roommates and you're
proud of it because you can tell
everyone how miserable you are.
So it just didn't work out real.
Oh yeah,
no,
no.
It's real.
Once you become successful,
it's never real.
While it's struggling,
people try to act like it is right,
like all man,
I couldn't do anywhere else.
It's the energy of this city.
It's like you literally see you shit in
a drain in the kitchen,
you know,
and those in the lower east side,
you're the lower east side.
It's so saturated.
I have not right wing.
people are always exaggerating.
I looked at it in the east village
because he'd have like 19 polish family
members per apartment and the toilet was
right in the middle of the kitchen
because they weren't designed.
Sometimes you have to dig a shit bacon.
Same tIme.
It's an extra toilet.
There's one for mom.
While she's making spaghetti,
they're multitasking.
She could squat,
squat,
one of those little squatty potty
things.
He ever seen that one sign.
Like if you go to some places frequented
by too many people from asia,
you'll see signs that show like a person
standing on the shitter squatting down.
It's got a red line through it.
don't shit.
yes.
Pull.
Has it become that popular?
The squatty potty.
but I've seen it.
I've seen here's the squatty potty.
Yes I do.
And home I would assume.
So it helps the caveman thing,
the bowel movement.
Well if I prefer to shit in a hole in
the ground.
So the kitchen has the time to dig.
Like look at the guy.
No,
no,
no it right.
That would just one.
This is a joke one,
but I have literally seen that that's
real.
That is an actual real for people in
asia.
Arusha fear went to China and he has
this fucking hilarious bit about it and
I don't want to.
I don't want to do his bit.
That's,
that's real.
But in China he went into a restroom and
there was literally a hole in the ground
and you were supposed to squat over the
hole and they had no toilet paper.
Yeah.
That is real.
And he told me that when people from
asia who are used to that environment as
the norm come over to the United States,
sometimes they actually stand on the
toilet seat and,
and shit that way.
So the toilet seat is not designed for
the ame to be accurate.
If you're.
If you're sitting on the toilet seat,
you'd be crapping on the water tank.
They don't know any better either from
another country without trump,
without trump leading them.
They don't even know anything man.
What happens?
Tossing,
defending trump,
I think,
uh,
you know,
do,
do you think he's a good leader?
Are you happy that he's an office?
Are you,
is it good because it's a shakeup.
I will say this.
Um,
I,
I think that again,
the left has behaved so poorly.
Yeah.
I think that trump,
Donald Trump has been a lightning rod.
I would disagree with him on some policy
issues for sure,
but I think that because everyone has
called him a nazi and a racist and
sexist and a transfer job that it's
removed those arguments from the table
for,
for at least several decades because
people are going.
Yeah,
but you saId it about john mccain and
mitt romney.
Everyone you disagree with is a racist.
I think that card has been played too
much and because of Donald Trump has
been overplayed and I think now we see
with our channel,
um,
granted it's not as big as,
you know,
the outreach you guys have,
but it's grown pretty substantially and
a lot of our audience are self
professed.
Liberals going,
you know what?
I used to hate you.
I used to,
I used to watch the young turks and that
we used to watch some crap on you,
but actually some of these points make
sense.
And I used to think everyone will
disagree with me with racist.
And I think because it's so overplaYed,
it's left such a bad taste in people's
mouth.
I do think that Donald Trump has served
a real purpose to shine a light on that.
And you know,
that may be the most important point of
all at this point in our culture.
What's political correctness?
I think when things go too far,
one way people get upset with that and
when people get too bias,
whether it's towards the left or towards
the right,
it tends to balance things out in the
other direction.
Like robert anton wilson called lyndon
johnson,
the pacifist president,
you know why he called them the pacifist
president because he was such a cunt
that he created so many pacifists
because if his atrocities that he
ordered in the Vietnam war,
people were so upset that more people
became pacifist during the lincoln,
or excuse me,
they're in during the lyndon johnson
administration than than ever before.
By the same token,
he called reagan,
the intellectual president because more
people just went,
oh my god,
you gotta.
Fuck god dammit.
It's important to know things.
yeah,
god damn it.
It's important to be smart.
Like just say,
no bitch.
What are you talking about?
Just saying no,
you're.
You're bringing heroin and from just say
no.
You're selling coke in south central to
pay for the fucking consciously.
This is reagan was selling coke.
All of you don't know the oliver north
story.
Oh,
oliver north ross.
You know the whole story from real rick
ross.
Dude,
the real rick ross.
Not the wrapper,
but the real rick ross has been on my
podcast twice,
was a drug dealer in south central who
they put away for life due to the three
strikes rule,
but became,
didn't know how to read.
Okay.
Went to jail,
was a drug dealer,
made millions of dollars selling coke.
Okay.
Did not have any idea who was bringing
him to coach kelly was getting at where
it was coming from.
The profits that they were making was
literally paying north oliver north to
arm the conscious versus the
sandinistas.
I mean,
it was literally,
it was all proven in court.
I mean,
this is what my current are contracted
in front of.
What was the,
uh,
I forget what the gathering was,
but on television,
on cspan,
michael rupert,
who was a narcotics officer for the los
angeles police department who has also
been on my podcast for committed
suicide.
He was the guy that was the focus,
that movie collapse.
Remember that movie collapsed where he's
talking about.
I'm trying to remember that he,
it was just him smoking cigarettes.
Sitting there talking about what he knew
about the economy,
what he knew about all these different
things that were problematic in our
society and how there's only a certain
amount of time for it,
it's going to collapse.
It was kind of crazy doom and gloom
documentary,
but the point is he had caught cia
agents,
rogue cowboy cia agents in the,
in the middle of selling drugs in south
central los angeles reported it and was
in trouble because of that and decided
to go public with it and they were
selling these drugs.
They were making shitloads of money and
they were transferring the money to arm
these rebels.
Well,
rick ross was in the middle of that and
didn't know he was in the middle of
that.
He was literally selling drugs and
funneling this whole thing.
Went to,
went to jail as an illiterate person who
couldn't literally couldn't read,
learn how to read in jail.
Became a lawyer,
a jail like,
like learned.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
I figured out that you can't charge him
for the three strikes rule.
If it's one thing,
if it's.
If you're charging him with a bunch of
counts under one incident,
it's the three strikes.
Law doesn't apply and that's how they
got him in jail.
So now he's out like all of this came
because of that.
Well,
I knew about all of the north and in the
contra thing I didn't know about rick
ross specifically.
Well,
this has been proved.
Some elements of our government have
sold drugs to improv which neighborhoods
in order to fund black ops,
like this is a fact,
and this is one of the things that
robert anton wilson was talking about
when he was talking about the reagan
administration.
It was like it became the intellectual
president because people were so
frustrated by how fucking crazy and
chaotic and movie like,
you know,
things can become that they had decided
to arm themselves with information.
I wonder if a big part of it too is the
backlash with ronald reagan because
everyone said again,
he had no chance.
He was a moron and he won in a landslide
or people go,
all right,
screw you.
We're going to consider them an
intellectual.
Like with Donald Trump.
Listen,
I don't think donald trump's
intellectual and no one was entering in
an intellectual.
They were considering him a great
american.
Right?
He had slicked back hair and his wife
stood still and everybody was happy in
between seances at the white house
called her astrologer,
making sure,
but I think people might've just been
like,
you know what?
You called him a moron for so long and
everyone voted him a moron that.
Well,
they didn't really call reagan a moron.
Yeah,
they did.
They called George Bush.
Yeah,
they did.
Yes,
I did.
Here's the playbook with,
with anyone who's conservative,
republican is if they can make you a
more than they will.
If not,
you're evil,
right?
dick cheney can't be a moron.
He's evil.
I think you're confusing the narrative a
little bit because reagan might have
been simplistic,
but he was a wonderful speaker like he.
He gave really articulate well thought
out speeches that spoke to americans.
Again,
longing for this nostalgia of a time
where the norman rockwell painting made
sense and that's what ronald reagan
represents it to.
A lot of people.
yeah.
A lot of people,
they were,
you know,
they were coming out of the chaos of the
carter administration and the fucking
Vietnam and lines,
the gas lines and the iranians taking
the american hostages and all that crazy
shit.
And ronald reagan came along.
He was like,
I'm going to fix it.
I'm your dad.
Never was like,
we're in.
But the media treated him like a real
moron.
If you go back and watch that,
and then right before his landslide
election,
when they may,
if you look at the,
uh,
the electoral map,
sort of the poles and the predictive
predictions,
they,
they gave him no chance of winning and
that's full of shit about Colorado and
traffic deaths.
Should we go and fuck you up with this
too?
Yeah.
The Colorado thing at all.
What?
I never said Colorado.
I said states that legalized.
What other ones are there?
Well,
you didn't bring up the source that I
wrote about.
I can,
but the fact that you're still hung up
on police.
Hopeless.
Oh,
you got the article.
I've been looking at it for like last
few minutes on your website.
There's a couple of statements that are
really bad just off to just off the
gate.
Like this right here.
If you want to get high,
you're a moron.
Hmm.
Well it's getting high.
That's not a news article.
Hold on please.
That's commentary.
Hold on,
but fine.
After all things like coachella wouldn't
exist.
Is this your article?
It's an article on my site.
Oh,
wait a minute.
If you could want to get high,
you will.
You're a moron.
Moron.
I think.
Courtney,
who is courtney,
she's working on one of the best writers
I've ever encountered.
Dare you not read them,
but.
So then the article links.
So a couple like this for instance,
is when it says it has deadliest year of
traffic fatalities since 2008.
Yeah.
This article doesn't say anything about
marijuana.
Not one.
One thing doesn't mention me weed at
once.
It does say that it could be attributed
to crisis,
people driving more people in the state.
Sure,
etc.
Etc.
Well,
but that's the only thing I'm going to
defend myself here because you have
someone here at the ready and what you
do is instead of bringing up
information,
this is what happens with christopher
titus,
right?
You don't have information that you
bring up.
You have another guy.
I look up a source that you specifically
want him to find.
I didn't ask him to bring that up.
I brought up Washington post and goes,
this is what's wrong with your article
taking the job.
You didn't have a joke.
The joke in there about things like
coachella wouldn't exist if there
weren't even that article.
That's a joke,
right,
but the triangle.
Do you think people who smoke pot or
morton's?
No.
It's a joke.
Okay,
let's not do that.
Let's not do that.
And know pot's not comparable to
alcohol.
There are tests that how much alcohol
content is in your bloodstream.
We can't yet do that with weed.
So it's impossible to handle these
incidents in the same way.
That's what they're happy.
Okay,
but there have been tasks where they
showed people,
but that will go back to what he said
and what you said have been tasked with
they've shown people drunk versus on
marijuana and the people on marijuana
drove far better.
Okay,
that's true.
So this is also anecdotal.
No,
it goes back to your point,
right?
Let's say someone has alcohol tests the.
Well I don't,
I haven't read your test.
Okay.
So what are you arguing against them?
I'm saying I agree with your point
earlier.
So why are you saying that the.
Well it is anecdotal.
If you're saying some people drive
better on marijuana.
I'm not saying that.
I've said there have been tests.
Would they have shown that people drive
better on marijuana than alcohol?
If you want anecdotal.
My point is if we're going to be really
good at this argument and just settle
down,
you said you wouldn't pile on and you
got two people talking to talk and when
someone brought on the show,
when someone comes on the show,
jared cannot enter.
Congratulations,
you're not on the show,
and all he did was pull up bringing up
information.
Me without a laptop.
No,
he brought it up about it.
You said what would be the one thing
that you've changed your mind on?
A similar problem with two people are
correct and you're incorrect.
Does that bother you?
I don't agree that you're correct.
What are you talking about?
You just pulled up some statistics that
show the Colorado has less traffic
fatalities in statistics.
He did.
you just kill you.
I will give you the laptop.
I'll turn my laptop and you can.
You can pull up the shows contract.
What is the issue that you would care
about the least that you've changed your
mind?
I said probably wouldn't even talk
about.
That's.
That's a long version of what you said.
Well,
was there have been more fatalities
since marijuana has been legal in those
days?
The things we've discussed,
not true.
Why are you so obsessed with the body?
Because you're not right and it doesn't
matter if we've talked about it for four
hours in this instance,
you are incorrect.
You know,
you're correct in that instance that
traffic fatalities have increased in
areas where pod of increased.
We did the same study in Michigan where
pot was legalized and people were
actually selling more marijuana to
underage kids.
I don't care if that doesn't have
anything to do with traffic to get
tapped to do with it.
It doesn't have anything to do with
traffic fatalities unless you can prove
there's more traffic fatalities and
underage kids.
Since marijuana has been legal.
Yeah.
There've been several articles that have
made that claim,
made that assertion.
What's been written about it?
Let's find them.
They all come from one article mostly,
and it's from the aaa stats and the
stats that they said it was almost all
the articles you're talking about coming
from this one article.
Okay,
so this is the percentage of drivers
involved in fatal crashes who recently
used marijuana more than doubled from
eight to 17 percent from 2014 or 2013
and 2014.
One in six drivers involved in fatal
crashes from 2014 had recently used
marijuana,
which is the most recent data available
now.
Do you understand the consequences?
Middles crashes involving marijuana is a
charming says who opinion.
That's an opinion.
President and ceo of aaa foundation
alarming.
Well is that,
is that a batter of more people smoking
marijuana because it's legal or it's a.
Is it a matter of the marijuana causing
these accidents?
Is this no one article put out but no
one else is true?
Do you knoW what else is true that all
these people also had alcohol in their
system?
Do you know that?
Well,
no.
We don't know that all of the tech gIant
percentage of something that's you know
this to be true because I've read these.
He had alcohol in their system.
Can you prove that?
You just said a lot of them rewind the
tape to say all a lot of them.
Well,
you made a lot of.
Let's find out.
It doesn't say anything in the article
about alcohol though and for sure they
should have tested that shoes for sure.
They can't test for a cup of joy and
just google made him do it.
Anything.
It's a point that you're going to have
an obvious position that would disagree
with this one single article,
so if I can finish a point,
you've talked about interruption.
Let me finish the one point that I'm
making.
Well,
you marijuana,
you've already test for marijuana
roadside,
right?
Can wE agree On that?
You absolutely.
Can you just do tests because there's
new tests.
Test.
Let's find out.
Before you do that,
what you said,
how many of the hour,
how many of the marijuana related
fatalities also involved alcohol because
it's a massively significant percentage.
Yeah,
so you can't necessarily say that just
because they have these new tests for
marijuana,
especially roadsides barrel problem is
he can't.
Okay.
I'll tell you what.
I'll give you that.
What do you give them?
Let's say you'Re correct,
but here's the thing,
so let's test indirect.
Physiologically,
it doesn't have an effect on motor
skills the way alcohol does or it
doesn't slow down your response time.
Well,
I know that we've had several doctors in
the show with two of whom had differing
opinions on that.
They don't have to be right.
The iranians have it.
Do they smoke marijuana themselves?
Do they knoW what it's like to get into
this?
This whole study studies on cbs news
caught blatantly distorting cannabis
study says this doubles fatal because
comes from mini press news,
minipress news.
So again,
we can go into questioning sources all
day long.
If you have someone else bringing up
something just as a good source.
You think maybe,
maybe it is.
Let's say you're right crowder,
but let's say what letter can we sourced
out to something else?
I know you guys went on one issue and
you said,
hold on.
What's the issue?
You don't care about your sources right
here.
I've looked them up.
There's people online also sourcing
them.
They are skewed.
You're skewing them to make ends.
George Washington post study that you
skewed,
but you're not the Washington post.
You're supposed to be the answer to the
Washington post.
The Washington post.
Don't say that someone's evil,
so I'm evil to what you just said.
Is that what you're saying?
That's the argument that you just know I
didn't make that better.
Just said,
come on man.
It's made that argument and all of a
sudden when someone mentions pot,
you put on the along your worldview with
the lens of we know you get upset with
holy shit has nothing to do with eat,
but you haven't made an argument.
I haven't made an argument.
You said,
we showed you what he wrote about this
app.
What have you shown me?
We showed you the statistics show that
marijuana and traffic violations,
they may not be causal accident.
right?
Okay,
so what else is causing the drop number
and why keep increasing number?
What increased?
This fake increase from failure?
Bringing fake news.
It's not real.
It's real cowboy shows.
Is it real?
What was this?
It comes from is aaa study.
That was trip lands council.
Aaa is owned by the bilderberg group.
You don't even know this and now we're
going to go to cures cancer and people
having meetings and rams has got one.
One article that says one thing and one
article from Colorado that says there's
been a decrease in traffic fatalities.
Right?
You're not willing to recognize that.
I just said,
let's give that to you because this
entire conversation started with you
saying what issue would you change your
mind on a pot?
Because this argument started with you
saying that it causes more fatalities,
traffic violations.
That's not true.
You said,
which is you do not care about.
I say hot trend.
Why?
What's your opinion on pot?
And I said,
I really don't care if people want to
smoke pot.
I think it's a state issue.
I honestly don't care.
I've changed my mind.
Where as a kid I thought it was harmful.
I don't think it's harmful.
And you say that it causes more traffic
fatality.
Then you said,
well let's expand on this.
What issue do you have with pot?
I said,
I don't like the dishonesty where people
just say it cures cancer.
It'll end the war on drugs.
It's,
it's completely harmless and I have some
arguments that are entirely.
No,
it's not entirely harmless.
Well,
it's not without consequences.
Consequences are so much leeway there.
How have you have you?
Bay,
big consequences based started from me
saying I probably couldn't care less
about this out of all the other issues
that we discussed and you lasered in on
that and go,
where do we disagree on this?
No,
because it's a huge blind spot.
it's not huge blind spots out there that
if you say that marijuana is in some Way
or another a dangerous thing.
Yeah.
I can tell you that it's not.
No,
I didn't say in a dangerous thing.
What are the consequences?
Okay.
What is.
What do you believe marijuana does,
for example?
Well,
no,
I'm not going to get baited into this
because you're gonna.
You're gonna.
You're trying to force me to say that I
don't think pot cures cancer and there's
a big farm now listen,
smoke pot.
Now.
That's not what I will ask this.
I was saying,
what are the consequences of you come on
my show.
I'd love to have a discussion about it.
I think so.
Unless you're in front of me.
Why now?
Why don't you and I right now you're
having a conversation with,
oh,
that's not good to read.
Smart says it's not fair to have two
people,
it's Just like before he take a Room
with no internet.
Think of amy and I ganged up on.
You think you would have done well in
that argument.
Come on man,
because I want to find out how you feel.
Think and want to see if you get
defensive for some reason.
You said you think of her and I worked
together.
You think you would have done well on
that because I want to see if you get
defensive,
but when someone's coming into
conversation with someone that you do
that,
right?
No,
no,
but you've made it the hall about the
pod issue.
No,
that had nothing to do with pod.
The amy shouldn't have gotten into this
pot issue because of the issue was
brought up and it's the one area that
you're super,
super adorable.
You're adorable,
and there's the same thing.
If you're not a real comedian.
No,
you're adorable.
You're going to date someone on an open
territory without someone else to back
up your argument.
It's never happened.
If it looks back up when someone pulls
up information,
let me check.
Really does is he pulls up evidence to
the contrary.
If I was wrong,
he would stick it right in my face and
we would laugh about it and that's what
he does.
That's why he pulled up a trip,
the country,
and I've given it to you.
What tense do you haven't given me?
Shit.
I know I've given you the argument.
What are your command?
I'm fine.
Let's say there's no.
There's no causation.
let's say that wasn't backed up well
enough.
Let's give you the argument.
Okay.
What's this?
Jamie was also some evidence that
medical marijuana laws to decrease in
traffic.
What of me doing this though?
If we don't do that,
this is what we always do.
It's just talking about facts.
listen,
hold please.
There are some.
There are also some evidence that
medical that doesn't make any sense.
there's also.
I'm wrong,
that medical marijuana laws may
contribute to decreasing traffic
fatalities.
One study published in the journal of
law and economics in 2013,
reviewed traffic fatalities in the 19
states that have passed medical
marijuana laws by 2010 and found that
legalization is associated with an eight
to 11 percent decrease in traffic
fatalities for the year after the laws
took effect.
The researchers from the university of
Colorado,
denver and elsewhere also found the
decrease is more significant for alcohol
related fatalities.
At 13 point two percent ask a question.
Interesting.
Can I ask a question?
Please do.
Why is that study from 2010 considered
completely valid to you in the study
from aaa in 2014 considered completely
triple a's.
GoT a fucking biased in ago because
there you go.
The gas company and have different
opinions.
Charge.
Well,
what are they basing it on?
What your argument is?
This is.
This is the only valid study because aaa
is,
but this is a study.
You ignore it.
Do you think that's right?
I think they're lying to me,
right?
I think it could be right.
So if they're right,
if that studies right then you were
wrong,
right?
If that.
What if that study's right?
They knew right?
I could be wrong.
You were wrong,
right when you were just shouting it
out.
So we proved that in Colorado.
You were wrong.
You didn't.
If that study is true,
well you didn't prep.
You said if that's what you do,
what can to ask one question and then
you get a paragraph.
You're doing this,
don't you,
joe,
you give it to you win the argument and
you bring up another thing about pot.
Well,
it's because you don't.
You don't really give up.
You reluctantly give up.
Give it to your right.
Let's assume you're definitely wrong.
Let's assume I'm wrong.
Okay?
So what else would be the problem with
marijuana if it wasn't?
Traffic fatalities?
Zero,
right?
No,
not zero,
zero,
but I don't want to spend the entire day
talking about.
Well,
let's come on man.
We're talking about real issues.
What would it be?
The other problems it wasn't for
different before you go,
oh man,
just loosen up.
Let's talk about life in jujitsu.
Then you get into one thing.
So I said,
let's talk.
I just want to get you away from your
left versus right talking points because
I'm lucky because people with
convictions paradigm,
bertrand russell for central.
I kinda am joe.
Joe.
here's the thing,
and I started off very and I still mean
the complementary things I said,
but you can't bring people on and called
them pussy and dumped box.
I cAn then continue going back to an
issue and with with someone who agrees
with you entirely and act as though,
well,
someone will now you're defensive.
Well,
of course I'm defensive.
I think that you were spewing a little
bit of anti marijuana propaganda about
traffic fatalities that I had an address
on a pair of propaganda.
That's right.
Unpaid bond payments paid by anybody,
but I just think you had a point of view
that pushed the propaganda,
but propaganda by definition means I
have to be pushing for someone
necessarily that someone is telling you
to do it.
it's just that you had a point.
It's propaganda you had dug your heels
in and it's not propaganda.
It's wrong.
It's wrong if you have read it and you
are spouting it out,
but that statistics prove different.
Okay,
and then I would say it's propaganda or
someone takes yours cancer.
I'm not saying you're promoting pump
again to like someone.
Okay,
pull that up.
Then we can find out what not saying
cures.
Does that matter why it has my
unofficial effect?
No,
no,
no.
That wasn't my claim.
Yours cancer.
Nothing.
Treat cancer and that was what I was
talking about.
I literally will get nothing.
Cures anything mean things.
Truth of your listeners will tweet me
saying that cures anything.
Things treat things.
Your immune system kicks in.
System fails of drugs like heroin.
Okay?
What?
What trulio cures things.
Polio.
Vaccine.
Polio vaccine doesn't cure things you
fuck.
It prevents you from getting polio.
Disease is you understand what you just
said.
You just yourself.
No,
I didn't know what the disease is not
effectively cured in the person who has
polio.
We're talking about marijuana curing
cancer on people that don't have cancer
yet.
That's not what.
It's not a vaccine for cancer.
What you're saying is marijuana cures
cancer with people that have cancer.
There's not a fucking drug.
You proved yourself not only agree
medicine that proves that you can't
fucking cure polio with a medicine.
You get so aggressive on your example
right now.
You have a blind spot.
I'm pretty sure there's drugs out there
that cure some diseases.
I'm sure there are.
I've never heard of them.
Well,
they.
You know their name one not off hand.
If I had someone who could bring it up,
no,
you don't have to bring it up,
man.
You're going to argue for it.
Shouldn't argue for it.
I don't think.
I think that's incorrect.
You're in.
Your immune system has to be in place.
If you are a fuck,
if you're dying and someone gives you
some sort of a drug,
how many drugs are there that cure a
nasty disease that's killing you and how
many of them have to be also
compensated?
Your immune system has to kick in as
well.
There's a bunch of factors.
It's not like how many.
I mean there's penicillin that kills
some.
Some like venereal diseases and all
sorts of different.
Fucking horrible infections.
There's not a lot,
but it takes your immune system has to
be an effect too.
There's,
there's a lot of factors.
Now we're going to the definition of
cure and saying,
man,
because you're talking about fucking
polio.
Nothing curious.
Polio,
bitch and marijuana.
No one's saying marijuana all the time.
All the time.
It's just you're assholes.
Does people that say you're a nazi,
those the same people that say you're a
nazi?
No,
it's pretty common.
It's pretty funky.
Nazi punching.
For example,
we had a woman on the show at a woman on
the show psychiatrist who basically said
she said,
uh,
people who are adult healthy smoke pot
and probably not a problem.
So it is a problem for [inaudible] for
the developing brain.
People who are under the age of 25.
She explained as to what the correct.
Then she explained as to why it's.
I don't think they,
they think that the human brain is even
fully developed.
You're not text.
And she talked about specifically also
people who might have mental illnesses,
whether it's schizophrenia,
bipolar.
Most people don't realize that or
depression.
It goes unrecognized and she talked
about how for those people,
marijuana can act as a trigger
mechanism,
so she said,
healthy people,
none of these conditions,
marijuana is probably relatively benign,
but for some of these people and most
people who might have these conditions
are afflicted by them.
It could be a real problem.
She's got some very good points,
but dna are,
we'd cures cancer.
This dumb bitch should get off the show,
do this.
Cannabis has been shown to kill cancer
cells in laboratory testing.
question six,
you know that doesn't cure cancer
though.
KiLl cancer cells.
No one's saying cure cancer.
It's beneficial effects.
I'm telling you exactly what people say,
that you compared it to tumeric.
You compare these things,
but look,
the the point being,
I think you agree and I agree that as
long as it doesn't hurt other people any
more than anything else like sugar
hurts,
other people.
Look,
if you want to make an argument for a
high insurance rates and you want to
look at the overall causes of disease in
this country and why insurance and
health insurance costs so much,
you would almost immediately go towards
simple sugar.
Simple sugar is a huge problem wiTh
people who are obese.
Obesity is a huge issue in this country
and it's a major factor when it comes to
healthcare costs.
Right?
I think it's adorable that you're
telling me how to craft arguments and I
know that you're not saying that it's.
It's an easier argument to say that ice
cream should be illegal and is that
marijuana should be illegal.
No,
I don't.
And I think.
Tell me why now I'm to.
I'm going to say what I was about to
say.
please stop beforehand because he keep
redirecting the conversation and your
turn and for some reason you're turning
it into something hostile that it really
doesn't need to be hostile.
Might be to you.
Yeah.
It didn't feel weird about it.
I feel great.
It is.
When someone comes in and somebody where
they know they disagree and someone out
to other people have the same opinion,
are gonna do a team up?
He doesn't even have to think that what
you're doing right now,
joe,
is like you talk about what people in
jujitsu is what I think there are now
100 scientific studies that say that I
think that you think these arguments
where cannabis cures cancer.
I think that you think he's arguments
work and I think it's like someone going
to jujitsu for the first time.
You've never done it.
I don't think you've ever actually
gotten to a place without someone who
can bring up sources for you.
I don't think you've gotten into an
argument or done anything with a debate
team where people would actually hold
you accountable to the argument that you
make.
I think we're redirecting.
You don't think that I have.
If you don't know what conversations
that have never seen,
so what do you.
Somebody with me 24 slash seven slash
nine point is this.
I think you'll be very surprised right
now.
You're the kung fu guy hitting the kung
fu,
dealt with the spikes,
and you've convinced yourself that this
is an argument that would work if you
had other people more
qualified than myself to discuss it and
you decided to zone in on an artist that
have you diffusing all these stats that
jamie keeps bringing up.
There's more than 100.
Studies exactly proves that cannabis
cures cancer.
Exactly.
Do deny the studies.
You don't need a jamie,
jamie.
Jamie's pulling shit off the internet.
You hiding civically about something
where I changed my mind so clearly we're
ready or upset about the pot though.
It wasn't a nice thing about that
anymore because I don't really care
about it and I think states should be
able to legalize it or if she don't care
about it,
she fucking touch three followup
questions.
It'd be like me asking you why you
endorsed bernie sanders on thIs show.
Definitely send you info.
Tom,
in the green room with the man.
He's insane with the socialist stuff.
I don't think it's very genuine.
What you're doing.
What?
This is something that appeals to.
you know,
it's not.
You started on with traffic fatalities
and start on I guess on with kevin
tells,
you said,
what is she up and not talk about and
this is exactly why,
right?
Because we always occur.
That was one of the things he used was
wasn't it?
And there's no active conversation that
comes from it.
Oh sure.
There is no.
For people who are listening to this,
this is extremely productive because
they understand how someone with
blinders could ignore the evidence.
Sure.
And figure out some way where they're
being wronged intellectually.
Someone like someone will say that,
oh,
you should be in some sort of a debate.
You've never been in a debate.
You don't know what fucking debates I've
been in.
You know what?
No televised.
Right?
you know you don't know what I'm calling
you on your bullshit.
You're saying,
I've never had a conversation with you
and steven were having fun.
Why is this bullyiNg?
It's because there are two people who
hold one opinion,
asked me on something that I don't care
about.
Followup three,
four questIons to go into an area where
you two are so very specifically
passionate and I said,
I don't want to talk about it.
you don't want to talk about it because
you're wrong.
No,
I don't want to tell because I don't
care because he keeps showing stage.
Want to legalize it.
That's fine,
but it is a valid issue.
When people of Colorado are looking at
this now and there are people in
Colorado who might vote differently on
the marijuana issue because of how it's
perceived or because of the information
at hand,
and I believe that people in Colorado
she be able to vote.
They voted for pot,
but if they want to vote the other way
in states they have the right to do
that.
Who's arguing against that?
Well,
that was my point when we're talking
about marijuana.
My point was when I worked at fox,
we were thrust under panels where you
had to talk about this because it was
going on in Colorado.
I can't believe you called me a bully.
That's such a left wing arc.
How dare you.
You are.
How dare is how early you are,
but you fax.
No,
you use this.
I'll use these absolutes and call on it
and then say,
well no,
I'm just joking.
I'm joking.
What?
Absolutely.
Well,
okay.
Let me give you one that I can pull from
my memory to.
All of them are on alcohol.
that did.
Fuck that up.
Yeah,
and you've done it several times,
but we were supposed to be a productive
discussion.
Wouldn't be doing that.
I wouldn't.
I know there's a large number.
there's a large number of narcan on or
one of those company.
One of those.
There was one that was unlikely source.
Yeah.
Well you don't tell me you have to leave
now.
My flight.
Turn this around more.
You're going to miss your flight no
matter what.
Now if you're fucked,
we're going to be fine,
dude.
Now I'm not going to be fun.
I'm not gonna.
Make my flight back.
Yeah,
you're going to be fine.
You're living in America.
Could be in Ethiopia right now.
Huddling in a fucking hut.
You know,
trying to protect yourself from a,
some rabid animal.
You know,
don't be scared.
We're going To be fun.
You got a little defensive.
I thought were friends did listen.
I thought we were going to have some
fun.
We were having fun and then toward the
end of the conversation you asked me
what does she do not care about.
I don't really care about the pod issue,
which I thought I cared about when I was
21.
You said you wouldn't defend issues when
you were from when you were seven,
seven years ago,
right?
All of your cells?
Every was 21.
I was probably a lot harsher on pot than
I am today.
I thought it was worse.
I grew up around it.
I had negative experiences and I didn't
realize that was anecdotal.
I don't really care much anymore,
but I think state should be able to do
what they want to do.
Then three,
four,
five follow up questions so we could get
to a point into this debate where the
show is now going on two,
three hours long and I've missed my
flight.
Well,
you were trying to say was that people
that are pro marijuana ignore the
negative consequences of marijuana,
and I asked you what those were and you
said traffic fatalities,
one of them,
and then we tried to find out if that's
true and we found out it's not going to
find out that it's not true.
You made an argument that it's not true,
but we didn't.
We didn't definitively find out that
it's not true statistics.
Well,
you just.
It's very easy to do that.
When you ignore opposing statistics.
Let's find the claims about them.
What's.
Let's have jamie miss my flight.
I'll have another hour to get plenty of
time.
Man,
you're not going to get your flight.
You got a lot of time.
This is.
This is an interesting argument,
right?
It's an interesting argument because it
shows what happens when people not
necessarily disagree,
but getting new position where one
person wants to have the upper hand and
you keep jockeying back and forth.
We're trying to figure out who's going
to wind up on the top of the heap.
No,
there's no jockeying back and forth.
Now you're the one jockeying back and
fall,
sweetie.
Come on honey.
Come on with the bullying.
If that's a bully thing that we have a
real problem in this country.
Pussy,
come on.
Fuck that money.
That might be dumb.
Fuck might be bullying.
Yeah,
sweetie is what you've done.
I did it as a joke because I thought
were friends.
Oh,
you don't think where we talk every now
and then I like,
I like you too,
but I immediately think we're friends.
You probably a pipe.
He gave me a pipe.
I think if you apply been on my podcast
twice.
I know.
How dare pro.
Probably not invite her back.
You're a goddamn building.
Invite you back.
Listen,
here's the truth.
Are you upset more than me?
When you say you're defensive and you
have somebody else to bring up sources,
that's let's be at really anything you
want to.
No,
I don'T want you to look up and you want
me to.
Jamie will be.
Let me tell you something.
If jamie found something that shows me
I'm wrong and he does all the time,
he pulls it up.
Well,
not gay.
Jarrod note that as a standing on our
show,
we do it differently and that's why I
invited you on the show.
How do you do it differently?
Titus comes in the show.
If sally cohen comes on the show,
if you come on the show and you say,
I want to talk about pot in the show.
If you say that and you say,
I disagree with you,
I said,
okay,
not [inaudible] not a word,
and you don't bring up any sources.
This is going to be.
Well this is the difference between you
and me.
I'd let them talk about like you think I
would out jerry talks all the time,
but I don't think it's fair.
Why not?
I would talk to him to two on one and an
argument is fair on.
One is,
you know it's not and if he disagrees
with me and you disagree with me
together,
we can go back and forth all together.
I don'T care.
I don't mind if there's three people.
Get another friend that hates pot it.
I don't hate pot.
Well,
I mean just what absolutes.
Another hates pot.
I said,
ms dot characterizations and absolutes
there.
I don't hate pot.
I'm not saying you do.
I'm saying get a friend who hates pot.
Bring get another friend who hates
pocket another friend.
What is it?
Get another friend who also picked up
another.
Jamie looked.
I should have used the word also.
No,
because the implication there is another
meaning.
You hate pot.
No,
I don't.
I said,
joe,
get another person.
You don't endorse bernie sanders and
then had a thing on his face.
I think it would imply that the
documents,
I think he losing argue the argument and
you continued for another hour.
Joe.
He didn't really.
He gave it to me with a caveat and the
caveat is that I'm a bully and the jamie
pulls up statistics that only benefit on
that.
On that argument,
you are,
you are.
You are.
How my.
How is it a bully when two people are
talking,
how's it builds?
Not two people talking.
No,
you don't have a conversation with two
people talking.
You have a fail safe.
You have other people who agree with
you.
You have an audience who agreeS with
I'm on your program talking to homies,
man.
Just two people talking.
Let me be clear.
I don't hate ponte.
Okay?
I couldn't care less if you want to
smoke pot.
If states want to legalize pot.
Okay.
I couldn't care less about that now.
Pod is not a substance without
consequence.
That's all.
And some of those consequences can be
damaged to developing brain when they're
25.
We have a psychiatrist on talk about it
and people called her a dumb bitch who
doesn't weed cures cancer.
Um,
there have been statistics and reports
on fatalities increasing regarding
marijuana.
You may not accept them and maybe you're
reading those sources.
Maybe your sources are more valid.
My sources.
I'll grant you that.
So my issue is when people are dishonest
and only present one side of the issue,
I just presented several sides and on my
show in a regular basis that,
listen,
if you want to smoke pot,
I couldn't care less.
Go ahead and smoke pot.
And I think that the people who have
tried to make you think reefer madness
and wild and wacky tobacky,
I think that's overblown.
But I also think there are some issues
that people who simply want to justify
it.
Sometimes a habit which could be
negative to some people,
not all.
I'm overlooked completely one side of
the issue and there is an entire side of
the medical community who disagrees with
you and I don't know that I agree with
them or disagree with them.
Yet when I'm in the medical community,
there is entire side to the medical
community who would disagree with your
position and a position to know that I
that that you think marijuana is a
benign substance?
I don't think it's benign to developing
brains.
We already discussed that.
okay.
Good example.
Developing brains.
Why don't.
I don't think alcohol is a lot.
I think a lot of.
I would agree.
I think a lot of kids listen to you.
I know you're not responsible.
It's like you should be 18 years old,
18 and candidates should be 16 years old
to drive a car.
You're not telling kids to go and smoke
up,
but I think a lot of people who are
listening,
you have many young listeners who are in
that developmental stage.
Certainly under the age of 25 who only
hear the positive virtues,
extolled the marijuana.
Sometimes they're not entirely honest.
Sometimes are not entirely accurate,
I should say.
I don't think that's necessarily a good
thing necessarily.
Accurate.
How so a positive thing.
You talked about how harmful marijuana
could be to the developing brain under
two weeks.
So we have many times.
Have you in a way that you've conceded
that's valid?
No,
we've said I don't tHink you should do
anything when I don't think like any 15
year old to do anything to their brand
because we don't know what the fuck
happens to your brain when you give a
kid alcohol.
I did it.
I'm sure you probably did it too.
When was the.
When did you drink first?
How old were you?
probably like 51st beer.
I think I was 14 the first time I got
drunk with my friends.
I mean it's terrible.
It's not good for you.
It's not smart.
It's definitely not smart and I know and
you know,
and I'm sure we all know someone who did
get completely overindulgent and
marijuana and became one of those wake
and bake people that ruined their lives
and I think people can do that with
almost any substance.
Anything that's psychoactive,
at least I think people do that with
cigarettes where they.
They need that fucking cigarette more
than they need anything.
I think a lot of aa people do that with
cigarettes and alcohol.
They replaced their weird addiction to
alcohol to something that's not as bad
for them.
I think there's a lot of things for the
developing mind,
particularly for the developing mind
that we have available to us all the
time that are really dangerous.
You know,
and Henry Rollins on here and was
talking about when he was a little kid,
he was like five year olds.
They put him on ritalin at the time it
was five.
I think that's fucking horrible.
I think psych meds for little kids that
don't necessarily need them,
but maybe they're just a little too
energetic.
I think all that shit's horrible.
So whether it's marijuana or alcohol or
quaaludes or whatever you want to give a
15 year old kid that's got a developing
mind,
I think there's massive consequences and
I don't think you can really calculate
those consequences.
That's my position.
I think you can calculate those
consequences and when I think you can,
but I mean you would have to fuck up a
lot of kids in order to really prove the
viability of what damage is being done
to kids.
And how much would cause the damage
about ritalin.
Talking about quaaludes alcohol,
marijuana,
heroin,
preludes in 2017.
Wow.
Quail eludes oxies go.
Let's go with oxycontin's.
I'm just talking about downer.
So I'm talking about anything where it's
a depressant or stimulant.
There's significant amount of effects
across the board.
Bitch quit by the way.
I think it's just classified as a
narcotic.
It's not like a downer,
like a,
like a benzodiazepine or something.
Aren't opiates considered a downer?
COnsidered barbiturates?
whether there.
I think there's it a depressant.
Alcohol is a depressant,
right?
Because the central nervous system
depressant.
But I know something like
food or I'm actually knew a power lifter
were the only drug he could.
It was a prescriptive.
I don't remember this to date rape drug.
Was it prescribed drug?
A guy named Chad,
one of the date rape drugs.
Well,
whatever the most common date,
rape drug,
I don't know if it's,
I don't know if it's actually rueful in
or whatever it's called.
Um,
but most commonly used or the most
effective date rape drug.
I know what you're thinking about.
Um,
but I can't.
It's not coming to me.
I know the drug,
but it's,
it's a weird one where it helps
bodybuilders sleep.
Power lifter and power lifters do it too
because it actually infers more
developed growth hormone growth.
Well,
not just growth hormone,
but a recovery time because they have
like deep sleep.
Fuck.
What is it called?
But you know wHat I'm talking about.
Is it used as a date rape?
Drug hypnosis is not ready to.
No,
not,
not.
That's released.
That's roofie.
So there's another thing.
I know what you're talking about.
It's usually the date rape drug.
Yes.
And there was a guy thing he could sleep
on and then It became so they don't
prescribe it anymore.
He had insomnia.
He had like a kid,
like an 1100 squat was not quite world
record but close to it and lived out in
reno,
Nevada.
And uh,
that was the only way he could sleep
when he wasn't able to get it anymore.
His lifts,
you find it fell or just tricks?
No,
no,
god,
it,
it's kinda like a real common name.
I'll text my buddy because he had an
overdose of it,
but he was like 18.
Oh god.
Hold on a second.
Can you talk please for a moment while I
pull this?
That's it.
I'm a shoulder due tomorrow.
And where are you going to go back?
I'm a show tomorrow.
A tv show or radio show to do.
So there's no way we're going to get it
done.
Us making up is gonna be so good For
your show and my show to know it's not
the entire commentary from this is going
to be,
oh my god.
What a moron.
Anything so we doesn't cute man.
We're going guarantee it.
I guarantee it,
don't be,
don't worry about it.
We're going to be,
we're gonna get through this and get
through it in a way that makes sense.
I definitely get weird with these
conversations and I assume everybody can
get,
you know,
fake hostile with me.
So if I call it,
come on bitch,
I talked to you like that.
I don't Mean it in a negative.
I do it like I would do it if you were
brian cowen and he would start laughing
along.
Yeah,
but you live in Michigan,
you get a little sensitive when you go.
That's adorable.
Let's listen on a second when you said
that's not meant to and we were joking
about their topics,
but on that you lasered in.
Got serious.
You're wrong.
Let's stay on this pounded in.
That's,
that's just,
it's,
it's just I don't understand the purpose
to.
It can have some fun.
So you're.
So that's fun.
Do you like doing that?
You like having,
you like having someone in disagreeing
with him?
What happened?
Going into town?
Get a little silly like I think you
might've got a little silly.
I like to have a little fun guy.
Little silly did I.
Did I bring up the punish you?
I said it's the issue.
I care about the least come home and I.
Let's get away from that.
We were were free.
Were out of the woods.
We're back on the road.
We're doing good.
You just want to grab the wheel back.
Turned towards the trees.
Don't do it.
Resist nitrile.
Hibiscus cold brew tea.
It's tea.
Yeah.
I had a hibiscus,
a beer recently.
Most disgusting they've ever had in my
life and I love hibiscus tea.
Just does not work for beer.
I bet.
If you were in birkenstocks and you,
what if you had white dreadlocks,
you would have thought this is amazing.
Have you seen that kombucha beer,
beer?
You've actually had kombucha?
No.
Kombucha beeR.
So that's like a kombucha that's like
super strong or interesting.
I don't know how they do it because the
alcohol with the active culture and
kombucha should figuratively,
right?
There shouldn't be.
Alcohol.
Shouldn't have fIgured it.
They eat it as sugar because of the way
kombucha ferments.
No,
not necessarily because gts can boot you
that you buy at whole foods.
You have to actually have an id to buy
it because it's more than one half of
one percent alcohol by volume,
so you have to show your id and be over
21 in order to buy kombucha right.
Now that you say that,
I think I might have tried kombucha beer
once called.
Can I say the name or is it on good
vibrations and there's one that's okay
in one that literally tastes like vomit.
There's like a ginger one and there's
like a bit and one of them I don't.
The problem is I don't remember which
one.
So it's rolling the dice every time you
have it.
See some people I just tell them about
kombucha,
about the positive benefits of
probiotics and like you should try it
and you should eat Kimchi and you should
eat kraut.
Kiefer's great.
I had a my own culture.
Did you,
have you ever had a.
Have you ever done key for yourself,
but I did make kombucha myself.
I've done that before.
Kiefer's easier.
Relatable?
Yeah.
It looks like it looks like a slimy,
kind of like a c brain or cauliflower.
It's not like a grain originally.
TecHnically it's a grain,
but it's really just an active culture
of bacteria and yeast,
so lIterally as opposed to yogurt with a
straining or kombucha,
which you literally just put it in a
jar,
put it in on a countertop for a day and
strain it and after I think about four
or five batches,
it's doubled and then it quadruples it's
like an investment account and my wife
killed it when I was on the road
actually doing standup I was.
I had a few shows and I came back and
you have to replace it every day.
Otherwise there's no sugar to feed it
and came back and it looked like a snot
rag and it was something that was the
end of it and I just buy it at the
store.
Kombucha has not really a fungus,
but it's somehow or another like a
cousin of a fungus and people think it's
a fungus but it's a life form and when
you get it,
like I had it at one point in time,
it was like the size of a laptop and I
had this like big salad bowl and I was
growing kombucha in my refrigerator and
a salad bowl and the tea,
the whole top of the salad bowl was thIs
rubbery sort of life form if that disc
pancake but it would get big.
It would get really big and then what I
would do is I would drain it into a
pitcher and I would put the picture into
the fridgerator and then I would put
more of the sugar water and I forget
what all the ingredients were,
but I know sugar was a part of it
because the culture had to eat sugar in
order to stay alive and then it would
ferment and the fermentation was a part
of it and then you would get like some
sort of probiotic benefit from it.
That's a lot harder than keefer keefer
you just pour the milk in,
the lactose is the sugar and that's it.
And it's done.
What's actually good about it too?
Um,
if you read the studies on it,
like two tablespoons of keifer,
like actual homemade kiefer is tens of
billions of microorganisms as opposed to
yogurt.
Super good for You.
And it's higher in protein because if
you do the math,
so you can still basically at that point
you're left without the lactose.
So You're left with really just the fat
and the protein and all the b vitamins.
So it's like,
it's like they,
I read an article once could not
corroborate this,
but they said that goat's milk,
whole goat's milk keifer.
If you could only have one,
food would be the most complete food you
could have.
Wow.
But what about all your vitamins that
you would get like fido nutrients?
Ideal.
It's not ideal to see if you'd only do
one because you get the b vitamins,
you get vitamin d,
vitamin k,
um,
and that's whatever they said.
If you could only have one.
And then there was an article that if
you could only have two,
you'd be like that.
And egg yolks.
Have you ever fucked with like some of
those pharmaceutical grade probiotics?
Like what was rhonda?
Patrick was talking about?
Those ones on the podcast.
She was talking about some stuff.
You have to refrigerate it,
you buy it as like super.
Oh yeah,
I have.
Yeah,
I have,
have you.
Well,
you know,
my,
my producer not get shared had
ulcerative colitis,
so he has no.
Oh jesus christ.
So he's going to our office bathroom
four or five times a day.
Oh,
the poor guy.
And I had a problem one time where I
just,
I was so stressed and know,
have all these nerve endings where my
stomach just,
I felt like I thought oh no,
all sort of colitis was getting tested
for it and just turned out it was
stress.
And uh,
they put me on these probiotics and it,
it didn't really work.
And then when I did the kiefer at that
actually helped a lot more.
Wouldn't it be ironic if marijuana was
really the cure,
the unity of the entire time that you
probably would have helped because it
would have eased the anxiety?
I bet you it would have been.
Might have played.
It also might've made you more anxious
because it makes people.
That's one thing you want to talk about
the.
Here's the negative.
I'll give you one side of the negative
that people ignore is the paranoia that
marijuana can do it 100 percent.
Gives yOu paranoid.
I have had some friends that were deep,
deep potheads that one fucking cold
Turkey and don't want to go back.
It's like a monster that's in their
closet,
has written a waiting to get them.
When they go to pick out their socks,
there's.
There's no doubt about it.
It has this one effect on some people,
particularly if you take too much of it
or if your life is getting away from
you,
you know,
if it's like slipping away from you and
then you start wake and bacon and then
you just don't ever deal with all your
issues,
so they compound and fucking whirlwind.
I was told daniel of bullshit by my
shrink.
SHe say,
you probably have you done this gene
site testing now.
What's that?
Really haven't done it.
No surprise.
So,
um,
it's mainly used in psychiatry now,
but they're saying it's gonna have all
kinds of future with determining cancer
and things like that.
And they actually use it to look for
depression,
bipolar,
adhd,
and they can look at your genes.
Now,
I'm not a doctor,
I'm going to butcher this.
But basically for me,
um,
they can look at your dopamine and say,
this is,
this is how your genetics work.
And basically if you go,
I don't know if they can tell if you're
gay,
but they already have accepted it.
I actually have a video called you
choose to be gay.
And my answer is definitively know what
if it was you?
Well,
again,
because I don't choose a pretty much
knew when I tuned into the,
when I was a kid and I was looking at me
shit and rachel bilson and the people
who wanted to screw adam brody,
I think that's when you realize you're
gay.
If it were me than it'd be gay.
Okay.
What does that matter?
Just question.
Would you be uncomfortable if I know
I've had myeloma in the show because
I've talked quite a bit.
Thank you.
That you could look and say,
well,
maybe he's gay.
Maybe an ulterior motives.
I don't think I would think,
but with dopamine for,
with me,
like we have a relative in the family
who actually um,
well I should say who has an issue?
And so they looked at genes that create
serotonin and then okay,
you have a long.
Most people have a long a short gene and
you have to short jeans.
And with me,
that's the case with dopamine.
So like a lot of people who would maybe
typically be addicts or people with adhd
are people who,
um,
for me,
I didn't realize this until it was a lot
older.
Look,
this is,
I'm going to totally exposed myself as
vulnerable to all the angry potheads
after the argument.
I didn't realize until I was older,
I didn't actually feel the same feelings
of joy for like pleasure that other
people don't.
So delving right.
You know how that works,
it's your reward center,
like you do something good bang.
And uh,
I was a b student in high school.
I never opened a textbook a because if I
completed something,
I did a project that was it bumpy.
LIke I did a project spectrum.
Okay.
I did a product.
What's the next thing?
I never really felt that reward center
in the brain.
And they did this gene site testing and
they found that basically have the worst
genetic pattern.
It's not entirely accurate,
but it's actually increased the efficacy
of antidepressants from like a one in a,
one in two to like a two and three,
something like that.
um,
because they can look in and look at
your genetics more effectively.
And so,
no,
I'm sorry to interrupt,
but are you,
have you taken anti depressants?
Uh,
I've taken adhd medication that's on
antidepressants,
but it's easy to.
Activity disorder is a completely
different situation,
but it's also basically a dopamine
shortage in adhd is.
And wow,
that's why stimulants on people who
actually have adhd don't rev them up.
Actually the zone I'm in,
you know,
some studying and they feel like wired
and uh,
before there's nick testing,
that's how they often tested for it as
well.
How do you react to this drug and if you
feel wired,
like,
you know,
meet with all this.
I had 600 milligrams of caffeine.
Um,
then you probably don't have adhd.
What kind of shit that they put you on
when they put you on adhd medication and
the base of like,
adderall,
stuff like that.
Oh,
so theY put you on adderall?
I've,
yeah,
I've taken it and I don't,
I don't take it every day because I
never want to be dependent on how often
you take it.
Uh,
I don't know.
Couple of times a week.
yeah,
probably.
Yeah.
You just hIt it when you feel down like
I take it is amazing.
I will tell you this,
I never realized until I took it,
and this is not an advocate because I
think it's way over prescribed.
I think you're right.
I think most kids who are,
I don't think you should put kids on it.
I think you're right.
and I think that most kids or most
people who take it don't need it,
but I also think that there are people
with real conditions out there like you
that can benefit from it.
Well,
you have a genetic.
Well we can prove it well because for
the longest time my wife will hear this
and she'll,
I,
I'm denied it through and through.
I thought,
no,
you know,
there's,
this is just,
this is bullshit.
The adhd is just to get kids whacked out
on ritalin.
And uh,
I,
you know,
I had people that I would deal with like
counseling or stuff.
Here's the kicker that would get
stressed.
I had stress management issues and a
thought about adhd.
I'm like,
no,
I don't believe it.
And then,
um,
I was given a book on adhd and I never,
I've never finished reading.
It was like three pages and moved onto
something else.
And they said,
okay,
um,
let's do this test,
this whole kind of questionnaire deal.
And it was pretty extensive,
you know,
short of actually doing a cat scan.
So,
okay,
you test like in the top 99th
percentile.
And we did the gene site testing,
I think it's called gene site,
and um,
it was pretty remarkable and I will say
that,
uh,
I won't get into exactly what it is that
I've done or what medications I've
taken,
but it was certainly life changing as
far as I didn't know what normal people
felt like,
wow,
that's really fast.
And adhd is a fascinating form of a sort
of a mild mental disorder that's
extremely frequent.
I don't think it's as frequent as a lot
of people think that I would give you.
I think it's overprescribed.
I really do.
I really do because whenever I say it,
you know,
people go,
oh,
I to,
I made your add.
I go,
no,
it's not the same thing.
Right.
That's the thing that people like to say
to,
does compensate for them being a
douchebag.
Asperger's.
Um,
so I'm on the spectrum spectrum,
so,
but it is,
I came into it kicking and screaming and
uh,
I mean I never did any in school.
I Just did the bare minimum was so
boring,
so boring.
And then when they sort of do an actual
test iq testing and stuff,
and we found it like,
well listen,
medication doesn't make you smarter.
Right?
I have my own
theories about this whole thing that
they do when they take kids and they
make them all sit in the same school,
in the same class and listen to the same
subject.
Right?
I don't think there's anything in life
that mirrors that and I think
experiences in life very radically and I
think that if you looked at nature and
the great spectrum of survivors and
winners and losers and how genes get
expressed and how evolution takes place
in nature.
Yeah,
there's all sorts of different kinds of
animals.
Why wouldn't we assume there's all sorts
of different kinds of people.
Whenever you force all people to sit
down and do the same thing,
you're going to have aberrations.
You gonna have people that don't like.
Obviously you've found something with
your show and with public speaking that
you excel at,
like you've found this thing like this
renting thing that you could do.
We could just go on 100 words a second
about all these different things,
like you've found this thing where
whatever way your brain works,
it works perfectly for that.
It's the same thing with a standup
comedian and same thing with a musician,
an author.
There's a lot of people that daydream
all the time like,
oh,
you're a fucking loser.
No,
this guy's writing books and his fucking
head.
Just give me a god damn laptop,
but he's going to make a million bucks.
You know what I mean?
It's like,
well,
I mean,
and the truth is people they want to
know.
You probably talked about this with
christina hoff summers actually.
There are people who have a lot of those
kinds of interactions that you talked
about in the classroom on a daily basis.
They're called Women.
They sit down and talk.
Think about women.
They get together with a book group,
whatever it is.
They literally sit down and listen and
to listen to someone and that's it,
and they'll sit because they're very
auditory.
That's the way they learned the public
education system In the United States
was designed for girls from the ground
up and you put boys into a world where
they don't do well.
They do not thrive in that atmosphere of
what girls do and that's why girls have
much higher grades in high school going
into college.
and then when boys can study at their
own pace,
they do better on the sats.
There's actually a great book called out
wild at heart,
I think by john eldridge that talks
about that.
And this was a long time ago talking
about then rather we know boys learn
better with their hands.
Think about it,
right?
It's considered a masculine jim shop or
not just masculine things,
but physical science where you're
working in a laboratory.
Those are subjects where boys actually
tend to do better than girls often in
high school or they rated as something
they like.
Instead of changing the way we do male
education,
we try and change little boys and that's
a real,
that's a real problem.
And uh,
I think that's a big reason,
not because someone was bullied because
someone used the word fag.
I think you probably have a lot of
incidents of depression in young boys in
particular because you're putting them
in an atmosphere where they can't
possibly succeed.
Yeah.
Well I think both are problematic,
but I think the square peg round hole
issue has been there for the beginning
of school in the first place.
I mean,
I don't mean to be like a proponent of
homeschooling,
but really every.
I mean,
once you have kids,
I think you kind of realized that god
damn every kid out of the box is a
totally different thing.
They're just different,
you know,
we're gonna homeschool because my wife,
she went to montessori school and she
went to a public high school or a
private high school.
Um,
but she's,
she's,
she basically,
she's a genius.
She's very,
very smart.
But she did not do well in a normal
school at all,
at all.
Do you think you could find a school
that maybe is more flexible or because
of the montessori school?
Socializing is critical for kids and
socializing during the day where they
learn about each other,
you know,
they learned about interactions and you
can talk to them too.
They come home,
you know,
uh,
debbie said something mean to me,
what did she say?
And I think that's important.
I can tell you kind of a tale of two
homeschooled kids.
I've,
I won't give any names here because
they'll know who they are.
Family,
they have a homeschool kids.
Very weird.
I'm just stare at their screen all day.
I have another family,
friends who were homeschooled.
Their kids,
they're the best kids you could possibly
have in an adult dinner table because
they put the kids in jujitsu.
I tHink one of them does tennis.
They put kids in all kinds of social
activities.
They travel with the kids,
they take them to europe and then
whenever they have adult get togethers
where it's appropriate for kids to be,
they still have adult night and date
night.
Kids can be there and they'll speak when
asked to speak.
They don't interrupt.
They're able to interact with adults.
They're probably the most well adjusted
kids I've ever seen and then I have seen
the weird,
creepy,
homeschooled kids where you do your
class on your ipad and then afterwards
you get to watch pewdie pie,
you know,
play video or whatever it is.
Um,
so it really does come down to the
parents,
but I do think that a parent who knows
how to homeschool kid,
I think that's going to be a,
especially if the mom is at home with
the kids,
you know,
um,
I think it's a huge leg up for this.
Obviously so many variables as far as
the intellect of the parents and what
their thought processes behind
homeschooling their kid and what their
experience level is and how much thought
they put into it and where they're
coming from emotionally,
psychologically,
intellectually.
Yeah.
There's a lot of variables.
I mean,
the idea of homeschooling is bad or
homeschooling is good.
I have a friends that have hold
homeschooled,
three of their kids.
They have four kids.
They homeschool three of them.
The kids are fine,
they're fine.
They put a lot of work into it.
They spend a lot of time with their
kids.
They took their kids all over the world.
They took their kids traveling all
through europe,
you know,
they just decided at some point in time
and it wasn't always homeschool.
They had done some public school,
they had done some private school and
then they got to a point they were like,
look like what are we,
what are we doing here?
We're tryIng to teach.
The kids got older into their like
preteens and then their teens and then
they came to this conclusion like what?
What they are coming back from high
school with and from middle school with
is not what I want them to be exposed
to.
Rather I want to be exposed to the
classics.
I want them to be exposed to life and
let just looking at human beings in a
way that's like open minded and
traveling and seeing things and so
instead of like necessarily just having
them take spanish.
They lived in Spain for a little while.
They went to Spain and lived there.
So they think of interesting,
crazy age.
and you were talking about tucker
carlson.
She's a middle school teacher.
THink of the enclaves of crazy places
for these social justice warriors go and
often they go into teaching because it's
their way to get power of these little
kids.
And here's the thing that was really.
We wrote about that on the website and
what I wrote about that.
Does that interview?
Yeah,
whatever it about that was.
This is a horrible interview because
she's okay with violence in berkeley,
but what really disturbs me is every
other professor out there who isn't a
national story,
let's say she didn't get caught on
camera hitting a guy with a stick,
right?
But some kid stands up who's a
conservative in middle school,
I was that way where I would argue with
the teacher,
um,
and just as well,
I think you're wrong.
And she kicks that kid out of class and
just says that kid's being disruptive
and,
or a fat.
Let's say that teacher is the principal,
gets the kid expelled from school.
These people have these little enclaves
of poWer,
these positions of authority and parents
kind of have to trust the teacher.
So you see that it's a national story.
She's exposed,
but what about all the teachers who
aren't?
I had a teacher complained to my parents
and talk about how disrespectful I was
and what a horrible person it was
because I think in the ninth grade I
actually argued,
I was like,
I actually don't think we should give
the land back to the native americans
when she was teaching with the teacher.
Fuck you.
But I made an argument and she argument.
What did you say?
Um,
well I was,
I was a smart ass.
So this was me as you know,
as a 14 year old.
But I said,
the fact that I remember the shoe,
I won't use her name.
I was say the fact that you're wearing
levi's and because you have a sore
throat,
you're speaking to an electronic speaker
when you dress,
drove here in a toyota yarus and you're
going to like electric electrically
powered school.
uh,
in a union tells me you're glad that we
settled here.
And she just,
she didn't answer.
She didn't argue.
She just sent me out of class and I
remember the next morning I thought it
was.
I didn't really think my dad was furious
because he got a call from someone
saying I was disrupting class,
or she asked students was you dealt with
that?
And the teacher know he's mad at me.
Why was he mad at you?
Because he didn't get the full story.
He just,
he just hears steven's being immensely
disrespectful.
Talking back in class,
she didn't hear the.
She asked for an opinion.
This was mrt.
Moral religious education was a class we
had to take in my religious education.
Yep.
So there's guilt for the first nation
people up in Canada.
Is that what it is?
This just specific professor.
And a matter of fact,
I learned what right wing was because I
remember at one point,
so that,
so right wing.
That's so right.
And I didn't know what it was.
I was 14.
I had said something and I said,
dad,
what does right wing says?
Well,
and it kind of explain to me the
political spectrum.
I said,
okay,
I guess I am right wing in.
I was in alberta and I was with some
friends who live up there and uh,
we were fishing and uh,
we were fishing right next to these,
a first nation people,
which is their native americans,
right.
And uh,
they have a limit of walleye that you
can take.
You can only take one walleye per day,
right?
If you're a regular person.
But if you're a first nations person,
you could just,
yeah,
pull in as many as you want.
And uh,
and,
and I was like,
how does that work?
And they go,
oh,
it's way crazier than that.
They can go out at night with spotlights
and shine them on moose and gunned them
down from trucks.
Right.
Because then it frees them the
spotlight.
Yeah.
They don't know what it is.
Stand still and they try to figure out
what the,
what's going.
Moose don't see spotlights ever in the
real world.
So yeah.
So when they see,
when they freeze and they shoot them
with guns from trucks and I was like,
what?
So they're alloWed to poach.
Well,
it's not poaching.
They can do whatever they want.
I go,
well,
how many are they allowed to kill as
many as they want so they can kill all
the moose.
They can kill all the most.
Whoa.
I was like,
that is,
that seems.
That seems odd.
What makes a great argument in the
native american case is actually,
have you read [inaudible] book?
No,
it's very interesting.
And he talks about this,
like michael medved and dennis prager
have talked about this,
but I was surprised as to how cogent
arguments where he's a very smart guy.
He's a very smart guy.
Um,
and then he always kind of play.
He plays it down or plays it up when
it's convenient.
But if you read his book he talks about,
he says it's just a numbers game.
The reason that we were able to colonize
here is entirely because of native
americans.
They were being [inaudible].
He wrote about it in a way I'm
butchering it,
but he said like when we came,
for example,
like let's talk about the mayans.
He goes,
they had literally a pyramids are as
tech,
whatever.
They had buildings entirely full of
cold.
He goes,
now,
how do you think they procured said
gold?
Do you think that they mayBe went to
other tribes or other members and said
you are going to bring us this coal gold
or be die,
and so what happened was thousands upon
thousands,
tens of thousands,
maybe hundreds,
thousands said one of the keys to doors
came who would never have had enough to
take over that area of the world said,
we're going to take our chances with the
red guys with the beards and the metal
helmets because they'd been treated so
poorly for so long and the same thing.
If you look at the algonquins in the
iroquois and come back,
those were the tribes that we had and
the kind of the packs that they would
have,
and listen,
they screwed them.
Don't get me wrong.
They really screwed them with the
firewater thing and they pulled the rug
out from under them.
I'm not defending it,
but the idea that we came in and just
conquered these people know there were a
lot of people who were mistreated
because it's horse culture that they
did.
First off,
they hadn't domesticated horses.
They didn't even use the wheel and uh,
so a lot of the things that we're taught
are not true and we're taught that they
were peaceful.
No,
they weren't peaceful.
That's why all of a sudden these new
people who came in with sticks that go
boom,
had thousands of native americans at
their disposal who were willing to die
with them because they were tired of
being treated that way,
and I made some arguments.
Maybe that affect,
got in trouble,
got sent home.
Well,
it's a complicated issue that spans
hundreds of years,
but there was certainly inter tribal
warfare and the word that the use,
they don't use the word sue,
they use the word lakota.
They call themselves the lakota people.
Sue's award for enemy.
That's what it means.
So like that's what other native
american cultures would call them.
They call them the enemy because they're
killing each other.
The nez perce and the apaches,
they would go to war with each other.
Neighboring tribes.
It was constant.
It's just when the europeans came,
they were so overwhelming that we feel
bad for what they did.
But you know,
what?
Killed more native americans than
anything.
Our diseases are dirty,
dirty bugs.
Yeah.
We came over here and coughed on them
and they all fucking died.
Well,
that's another thing too,
right?
That we killed them deliberately with
smallpox blankets.
That's true.
That's not true.
We didn't.
We didn't even understand.
We didn't have germ theory.
They didn't understand.
They didn't.
They didn't understand that scabs.
If you'd like to leave.
The idea was you take scabs from people
with fucking diseases and you put them
on blankets and he gave them native
americans out rubbing your hands.
No,
that's a big thing with horses.
They hadn't domesticated horses and a
lot of animals.
So think about that.
You've never come in contact with these
animals there in the wild and all of a
sudden these people are coming off
effectively with a boat that's a giant
farm and they're bringing these animals
and that you've never had contact with
before.
all kinds of disease.
Oh sure.
Well that's the thing that people.
A lot of people who don't understand
where diseases come from,
a giant percentage of them come from our
livestock,
right?
That's why you have swine flu and avian
viruses and all those different things.
Sars in the toronto airport,
only Canada.
It was brought back.
Sars.
You were the only ones who had sars.
What was that?
What was what it stands for?
I don't remember.
I jusT knew.
I knew all the asians were wearing those
masks at the toronto airport.
I remember that one.
Well,
how about a bowl?
It was just a year ago,
but it's fucking.
We're going to die a bola.
That fucking chick from New Jersey.
That bitch.
She's.
She left the hospital.
right.
There is a big deal.
So much flack from conservatives to
[inaudible].
I was like,
listen,
I don't like barack obama as a
president,
but you can't blame a bowl on the guy
and we're like,
oh fuck you.
African africa from Kenya.
I know.
You know,
and that's one of those things where I
know I'm seen as an ideologue,
but sending.
We get so much flack for criticizing
Donald Trump,
for example,
on,
on some trade policies.
Really.
I just think this is bad.
That's the big thing that you've been
criticized about trump for that.
I've been criticized for theater show
just for criticizing him at all.
Anything and toe the line.
Yeah.
People get real versus them bro.
Well,
because you know they're used to lIke
you.
You've had people on the show.
You've even mentioned in this program,
people who are.
They're only,
they're only his on data,
right?
Is being a concern is being a
provocateur to offender and there's,
there's a purpose to that.
But if just offending people as the end
goal.
And I really don't think that's what we
do.
If people actually watched the show,
I mean people actually watch the show
every day,
an hour of content.
Most of it is really pretty reasonable.
They see the highlight reel of me
dressing as a trainee interviewing wendy
davis,
right?
That's from thousands and thousands of
hours of the program.
So we criticize them all the time,
but you know,
less and less because every time he does
something stupid,
the left as something so bad.
So where it's like calling them
literally hitler.
Like that woman who was a school teacher
was talking about the origin.
Jeffrey's really bothered with the woman
who was a school teacher was.
She was talking about that,
just just labeling.
They're all fascists and you have to
stop fascist and then when he described,
when he asked her what is a fascist,
she gave like this shitbag definition of
what a fascist is and only suited her
knee.
Let's pull up the actual literal
definition of fascist young jamie.
What is the literal definition of
fascist?
As I interpreted it is I did a video on
this and here's what's so funny.
If I'm not mistaken,
google's definition brings up fascism
and mentions right wing,
but if you bring up communism or
socialism,
maybe it's authoritarianism.
Something that's very clearly left wing.
They don't actually mention the left
wing.
Okay,
and advocate or follower of the
political philosophy or system of
fascism.
He went to Spain to fight against the
fascist to extreme right wingers,
extreme right winger,
rightest,
or a military coup throughout the old
fascist regime,
synonymous authoritarian,
totalitarian,
dictatorial.
See,
this is where it gets weird because
undemocratic illiberal now type and
communism,
but authority,
but hold on a second.
The authoritarian and totalitarian like
this.
When you talk about extreme left wing
ideologues,
you are talking about authoritarians and
you're talking about totalitarian.
Yeah,
and you're also talking about people
that would advocate violence against
anyone who does not fit their mold of
how a person think or behave and what
they do is they call them a fascist or
they called him a nazi and that lets
them alleviate themselves,
have any guilt of being a violent person
against these people and that's what
happened at berkeley and that's why this
woman felt no irony about being on
television saying that milo is a
homophobe when he's a gay guy.
Once she was also talking about
justifying beating up people who weren't
milo.
Jimmy,
could you hit authoritarian real?
Yeah.
Okay.
Favoring or enforcing strict obedience
or authority,
especially especially that of the
government of the expensive personal.
Now do me a favor type in communism and
I want you to see the google,
so it just said right wing extremism
right with fascism,
which is not a right wing ideology and
own communism.
Do we all agree is an inherently left
wing ideology?
Yeah.
Well,
a political theory derived from karl
marx,
well,
there's a lot of,
like I had Jordan Peterson on the
podcast,
we talked about how was like
progressives who are sensitive and kind
people gradually gravitate towards
marxism and a lot of ways because the
initial draw seems appealing,
advocating class,
war and leading to a society in which
all property is publicly owned and each
person works and is paid for according
to their abilities and needs.
So here's the point,
and I wrote about this.
I think we did a video on this fascism,
which is not inherently right wing at
all.
No,
it's not.
They,
right,
right wing,
extreme right wing,
illiberal communism,
which inherently has to be left wing.
It is the definition of the political
spectrum of left wing would be communism
and capitalism,
and then in between can be
authoritarianism.
Fascism,
depending on the regime,
no mention of left wing with communism
because I know there's google,
they know there's a negative
connotation.
It's the first one that comes up,
but fascism,
authoritarianism,
they immediately try to attribute to the
right.
That's what people are fighting back
again when they.
When they talk about media and fake news
and the constant bias,
you see it,
there was google.
That's not fair.
Right.
Do you think there's a problem with also
defining things in terms of a word like
marxism or like communism,
like let's just talk about like what are
you trying to do?
Like what are.
What are you actually trying to appeal
to when you're saying that you can have
someone speak at your university if they
say things that you don't agree with?
Like do you remember the story about the
university of toronto?
Really famous story guy who is an
author.
They completely misrepresented what his
book was about.
They were saying he's pro rape culture
and these feminist shut it down.
They pulled fire alarms.
The famous red haired lady who's fucking
screaming at people.
I remember her name,
melissa click click.
No,
no,
no.
That's the one from the university of
Missouri.
Oh,
that's.
I'm talking about the one from toronto
who is like this.
Like she's kind of funny in a way
because she was like,
shut up fuck face.
I'm talking.
She's the rambler.
That red hair glasses.
I mean,
that was the,
that was this crazy moment in time where
this guy had scheduled an appearance to
speak about his book and someone had
misrepresented his book.
He decided what his book was actually
all about and decided that they were
going to have a campaign to make sure
that this guy couldn't talk so people
would show up and they would try to just
go to listen to this guy talk and women
were screaming in their face,
you fucking rapist you piece of shit.
And The guy's like,
I want to hear the guy talk.
Can I hear the guy talk?
No,
they wouldn't let people.
I mean,
that is fascism,
isn't it?
Well,
it happened to with ann coulter in
toronto.
I remember.
and whether you agree with her and he
deserves it.
I disagree with on the line,
but she was a.
She was asking me like,
what?
And I said,
well,
you understand,
freedom of speech doesn't really exist
in Canada.
As a matter of fact,
it doesn't exist outside of the United
States.
It really doesn't exist in Canada.
They have some weird rule,
doesn't exist in europe and when I told
her that she couldn't and then actually
someone went on news on the news and
said,
well,
what ann coulter needs to understand is
that America has this idea of free
speech and rugged individualism and all
speech is protected,
but that's not the case in Canada and
this was the representative.
They trotted out where she basically
said freedom of speech does not exist in
Canada,
and so you can read the youtube comments
where every time I say freedom of speech
doesn't exist in Canada.
Thousands of people.
That's bullshit because they thinK they
get to type in an internet message
board,
but you can be jailed in Canada for st
louis where you can lose your business.
This is a human rights council.
We talked about it.
Actually my story.
Did you have him that you know,
but we talked about.
Well,
he's got a different case that's from
montreal.
We talked about the comedian from
vancouver that had the altercation with
the lesbians and the crowd.
They were heckling him and the comedians
before and he called them some fucking
you pussy dykes or whatever.
He saId something crazy and they sent
him and won.
They won.
Yeah.
He like,
he had pe.
I don't know if He's paid,
but hit.
It was tens of thousands of dollars.
I think it was something like $15,000
this fucking guy had to pay to.
These people were hecklers.
yeah.
I know that people.
I get more people to the left versus.
Right.
This is why it does matter because I
lived through it in quebec.
In quebec,
we only have the left.
We have liberals and then liberal
separatists.
That's it.
There's no.
There's liberals and those liberals who
want to only speak french and separate
from the rest of Canada.
yeah,
exactly.
That's a weird place,
right?
It's a very weird place.
It's not like the rest of Canada.
It's multiculturalism gone awry.
The french were a conquered people.
it should have been shut up.
You're speaking english instead.
They said it's cute.
Let's let them have the little enclave
and now it's just a nightmare for the
rest of the.
That's where white golfers are afraid
about with California.
Is that what you're just going to
dominate and turn this whole thing into
a mexican speaking joint?
I don't remember what we were talking
about.
Oh yeah,
the left,
because I do think you do one at a
certain point.
I think a lot of people are readily
acknowledging now that those stories
that you're talking about,
the red haired girl,
the melissa click is asian lady.
You really can't find that today on the
right.
Right.
It just doesn't exist today and the
right and that exist like that.
What doesn't exist period.
On the right,
you know,
people try to point to like add parental
advisory lyrics and stuff and he
probably has to pee as badly as I do in
my gut.
That was tip or go away.
Yeah.
Know the parental advisory thing from
the eighties when they were trying.
She was trying to ban rap music.
People forget about that.
Al gore's wIfe was trying to ban rap
music and christians never wanted to
band south park thing where they talked
about.
They said,
no,
we don't.
We just don't want it on it.
Not we wanted on late at night,
we don't want our kids watching it.
Never my tray,
parker and matt stone does it,
matte stone,
ems stone and trey parker.
I saw matt speak at ut and he just a guy
stood up and he was like asking this
question,
like,
how do you fight back against these
christians?
And he actually said,
he said,
well,
you know what?
He said,
we've actually never had an issue
really.
He said they don't want it on a prime
time.
We don't want it on in prime time.
We've seen them as an ally is and you
said,
contrast
that to the comedy central reaction
where they decided to cut an episode
because we put muhammad in it and that
tells you who's really empowered
something to that effect.
But the kid who was at ut in austin,
my brother went to ut so he would get
access to all of these speeches or
presentations.
The kid was dumbfounded.
He thought,
well,
matt stones,
not one of me,
and matt stone is not a conservative,
not a republican.
He's not a trump supporter,
but he Just recognizes the intolerance.
Today of the progressive left,
well there's definitely an issue when
you have that woman,
melissa glick lady who was yelling at
that kid who was just a for tog grapher.
He was a journalist.
Yeah,
and I think he was hired to be there in
a public space who was asian and he's
taking pictures and she said,
can I,
can we get some muscle here because
we've created a saFe space.
You tank can't take photos of our
protests and our sit in,
in our safe space about racism,
so we're going to get this asian guy
because you don't understand black
America.
like what the fuck.
How long do you think she was waiting to
say,
I just want to use the term muscle.
Oh man.
She was just gonna say get some here.
She was intolerant in that.
She was very adamant about getting her
way and she did not consider whether or
not they were in a public place and this
kid hAd the right to take those
photographs.
And again,
like you said,
this an asian kid.
I mean this is not like some fucking
white jock with a crew cut.
Like from back to the future,
we didn't say,
oh,
it's fucking biff.
Fuck him.
You know,
it waSn't that.
it was,
it was like,
it was really hard to label him as an
oppressor,
but she still found a way and it was
such an asian response to where he was
just like,
I just want to do my job.
I don't want to be the center of this
story at his camera,
up above his head,
you know,
I don't want to start a march.
This isn't like you have to get out of
here.
He's like,
no,
I don't know.
This is my job.
I'm paid to be here.
I have to be.
You have a public thing going on here.
There's a protest after urinate.
So bad.
Don't do it,
dude.
Go do it.
You're gonna.
Keep doing the show now.
We'll wrap up.
Let's wrap up.
Alright,
so as crowder on onto.
I'm glad we got through this dude.
No,
it was just a generous dude.
I really do like you fucked with you a
little bit.
I treated you like a standup comedian.
I figured you'd fuck wiTh me back and
you got a little four,
five.
we got through that.
Was that we got back.
We got through it.
Yeah.
We got listen seriously,
and for those listening,
honestly I won't say I don't because I
don't want you to get in trouble if I
say behind the scenes joe has done some
things.
He's said something.
They've been very nice,
so he's a nice he,
you know.
Anyway,
I don't know if that hurts your street
credit,
like,
no,
I don't have any bad credit.
I've zeros tree credit.
Well I like,
I have cats.
You have cats.
Have no street cred.
Dude.
I take yoga.
He's a good dude to folks.
we're all fine.
We're going to be fun.
We're going to find a way.
All these ideas to come together and
this is part of it is part of it,
so thank you very much.
ThAnks for tuning in.
Thank you.
Steven crowder.
Thank you everybody.
See fuckers.