Where's the real captain?
Live would live.
Who is the real captain?
Man?
I'm.
We're talking about the new star trek
versus the oldest.
This is shade grown men do in their
spare time.
Testing flat cap.
Is that Echo in New Mexico?
Yes.
My,
uh,
shirt.
A new Eva Cerveza.
You don't that New Mexico might be the
only shape of a state that sort of makes
sense.
It's fucking square.
Basically Square.
It's square,
but like it looks like on the bottom.
Some dudes just had some
miscommunication.
Like fucking do that.
You're supposed to be over here.
That's Mexico miscommunication.
Oh,
the lives that Mexico wanted,
like there must have been like a cool
elk hunting spot probably.
And a New Mexico is like,
oh,
we gotta have a story about a need.
This little area,
this little block off in that corner.
Mexico know New Mexico is like the one
of the premier elk hunting spots in the
country.
Different.
Like when I was a kid in Michigan we
went whoa.
And maybe but not at all when I was like
12 or something,
stuff changed.
And because elk used to be not hunted
and then they opened up a season,
I'm so fucking elk,
you could like walk up to a herd of 100
deep and there would be.
I remember there'd be centuries they
would post like young bull elks all
around the perimeter.
And it was fucking wild dude.
They were almost tame.
And then the year after they opened up
permits is skiddish as white tail deer.
Really crazy.
One of the best hunting experiences I
had there.
Uh,
I was in like a pit blind with a bowl
and there were a bunch of dough at the
feed pile.
And then as in this big field and I hear
like come through the woods.
And then another group and these elk met
two bowls and they started smashing
horns and I was fucking blown away.
The deer didn't give a shit.
They're like,
just eating whatever.
Not even our species.
We're good.
And um,
it was awesome,
man.
It was,
it was.
I loved growing up in the woods or Rad
man.
It's so cool that you got into hunting
in your deep,
deep,
deep in it.
Like there's nothing better than
obsessed,
but it's the elk thing is so strange.
The noises they make,
like when we were a hunting Colorado,
when the female see they bark.
That's awesome.
Like everybody know,
let everybody know so open.
There's all that huge tracking.
Like you got to be an athlete,
New Mexico and Colorado.
It's a different kind of.
Well Colorado where we were was in the
mountain,
so it's all trees and stuff and it was
all about hiding behind trees and
bringing them to you and being on a,
on a,
on a run or something.
Yeah.
Trying to be near where they are and
since it's the raw you tryna make
noises,
you know,
like cow calls or you're trying to bring
them in while you're trying to sneak
off.
Don't piss all over you.
Is that the new shit?
Okay.
I was listening to this podcast.
Uh,
it's a Ted Ted talk podcast and I don't
know if you've ever seen
that video,
but there's a video that got around
about when they reintroduced wolves to
yellowstone park.
Yep.
But do you,
you can't hunt in yellowstone park.
So the animals in yellowstone park or
the same way that you were talking about
those elk,
the elk are the same way.
Like they somehow or another know that
people are not gonna hunt them.
That's the weird thing about it and how
it changed in one season.
I'm like,
how are they all symbiotic in this way
where they all communicate because none
of them had been hunted.
And it's like all of a sudden all the
fucking elk new though.
Yeah,
it's wild.
They,
uh,
I mean,
you know what it's like,
I think,
you know how uh,
is there something wrong?
You know what it's like a,
you know,
how you see birds when they fly and
those big or schools of fish,
schools of fish,
when they'll turn on a dime,
the flocks just know where everybody's
going.
It's weird.
There's some sort of strange
communication telepathy.
And I think that you read that book,
the rise of Superman.
No,
I haven't heard.
It's awesome though.
Awesome.
And they talk about,
I think the movie was transformers that
all these dudes in wing suits went off
the.
Is it the sears tower in Chicago?
And make an almost 90 degree banks and
stuff and then if and there are four of
them and they're following each other
and if one guy goes after I see you
move,
I'm too late,
I have to move as you're moving around
inside ruined the air flow and all that.
And then I hit the building.
These guys practicing the Alps and they
talked about that,
that you need to be in that flow state
and that you can start to work with each
other in a way that is a supernatural,
which is crazy because I felt that flow
state as a singular person in different
events in my life,
but like that kind of thing where
they're working in tandem with each
other and they're all talking to each
other and I think like that's the way
that that fish move or that's the way
like,
you know,
what is it that gives a frog the fence
to jump off the lily pad right as the
Hawk is diving before the Hawks moved or
whatever.
Like what?
Like all those fish,
it's not like one turns in the rest
follow up.
They all move uniformly,
the schools of fish efficient.
The flocks of birds are so magical when
you watch them dance in the sky.
That was giant flocks of birds like how
are,
how are they not just slamming heads,
how,
what is going on there,
and then the hawks that birds of prey
are so different than that,
you know?
No,
no flocks of that meat is a different
kind of thing.
It does people.
Yeah.
Those are those seed eating birds are
the ones that can do that.
They're like,
we really need each other.
The ones that are mediators are like,
I'm good.
This the same tent talk.
This guy was talking about how a humans,
it was a different guy was st podcast
though,
was talking about how humans interrupt
the natural symphony of nature and that
this symphony,
there's like there's a frequency that
all these different animals operate at.
There's like a frog has a niche in this
frequency and a bird has a niche in this
frequency and they were talking about
one frogs.
When you have like a whole like swamp
filled with Brady predators would also
does.
It makes it impossible to locate them
because there's so much sound coming
from so many different places.
It's you can't find them,
but they have these low flying jets in
this area because this is a place where
they practice or pilots practice fighter
fighter pilots and so they fly these
jets like 600 meters above the ground.
It's pretty low and they age,
they fucking supersonic speeds.
They're fucking just going crazy over
the swamp and the disruption of sound is
so intense that everything stops for a
while and then slowly these frogs start
to resynchronize,
so like one one,
one will read it and then they'll try to
find each other and get into that rhythm
again.
But when that happens,
when they're trying to find that rhythm,
that's when all the hawks,
all the owls and all the coyotes know
exactly when to move in.
So they move in then and they start
picking apart all these frogs.
They find the frogs and they eat them.
It's really interesting,
like they know that there's like a
disruption in the frequency.
Wonder how the like.
So are those predation animals working
on a different frequency than the frogs
then are like,
they're,
they're opportunists in this way where
they're like,
this is a tie,
you know?
Yeah.
That must be opportunist I think.
I mean,
I think the whole idea of what he.
The way he was describing it though,
the way the frogs do it where you know,
like you're in the swamp or something
like that and you hear frogs,
you didn't know where the fuck there are
so many of them sometimes what it is
like,
they sound fucking crazy.
Yeah.
There's so many of them.
And so when they have to kind of find
each other and because the sound is so
intense,
when the jet flies over,
everybody stops what they're doing.
And so they're like,
we doing this,
we're doing this,
we did,
let's do it,
let's do it.
And how long does it take them to
recalibrate?
It wasn't,
it wasn't long.
It was only a few minutes.
It was like,
I think I want to say 15 minutes where I
might be.
I might be mistaken,
but it was less than an hour and in that
time these trying to get their shit back
together again and they just get jacked.
That's the thing about us humans being
the disruption is that even though like
what we think of our.
I read something somewhere,
I heard a podcast where they're like,
there's a kid or somebody that developed
a bacteria or a some kind of biome that
that will eat plastic and maybe take
care of the big island of plastic or
whatever.
And I started thinking about that.
I'm like,
we're fucking idiots.
Like we created plastic.
Like that was our solution then to,
you know what I mean?
It's like we,
we put nuclear reactors on the biggest,
a fault line in the world where it's the
most active.
Like that's how smart we are.
And like,
what do you do when you create a
bacteria or something that will eat?
What happens when all the plastics gone?
Like is like,
was that like
the introducing,
oh we've got a rabbit problem in
Australia,
let's get a Fox and then we've got a Fox
problem.
You know,
it's like fun.
It's Australia.
Australia is crazy.
Yeah.
My Buddy Adam will learn from anything.
No.
What are the most adaptable creature and
we're like,
let's go ahead and get some.
We got a desert.
Get the golf courses out here.
Let's go ahead and do that.
Well,
that was what was interesting about this
Ted podcast is this same guy who was
talking about the wolves.
Who's done that video but the wolves in
yellowstone.
It's really interesting because he's
got.
He's got an English accent.
He asked about the wolves in yellowstone
and amazing things have happened.
This.
This guy's crazy though because he
didn't just want to bring wolves back to
yellowstone.
Now he's talking about bringing mega
fauna to England.
See they did these studies where they
dug deep into the ground and they found
fossilized remains from 10,000
plus years ago of lions and elephants.
This crazy fucker is talking about
reintroducing lions to England.
We need that.
But what was interesting about this cat
is that he admitted that this all this
fascination with wolves and everything
came out of a midlife crisis.
He's like,
he went into a midlife crisis and then
uh,
his,
his solution was to get a pussy and now
my spirit animals will.
Exactly,
exactly.
So this dude got like really super and
the wolves and super into the idea of
what he calls rewilding,
but the thing is like he was talking
about how megafauna used to live in
England and that human predation and all
that stuff wiped them out,
but that hasn't been proven that they
don't know that for a fact that it is
entirely possible that the climate was
just not the best climate for them.
And then also natural disasters.
And then also the absolute fact that 90
plus percent of everything that has ever
lived ever is extinct.
Right?
So this guy's idea of reducing don't
want to kill nothing,
don't want to let nothing die.
We are the ultimate pussy arrogant
fuckers that are building golf courses
and deserts.
It's crazy.
Well,
the wolf thing is so fast.
So there's both sides of that.
I've heard both,
like it's awesome that we have wolves
again there.
And then I've heard people are like,
this is really the decimation of an
environment like this change the
environment and the topographical,
a makeup of yellowstone so much that we
were retarding growth and a lot of ways
are all like.
I mean,
anytime you ready to do something,
there's an alteration,
but like is it for the good or the bad?
Well,
it's good for some species.
It's really good.
For some birds it's really good for
some,
a lot of different kinds of plants and
trees.
It's really good for trees because
yellowstone had such a huge population
of deer and elk and bison and all these
different animals.
They were just eating the shit out of
all the grass and the trees got thicker
and they're,
they grew taller,
like within six years they grew much,
much taller.
It's part of the,
uh,
the Ted talk.
This guy gave and the root system got
stronger because the root system got
stronger.
The path of the rivers was,
was,
yeah,
it changed and it was really,
really intense.
So it is good for some animal.
It's not good for the deer,
but,
but do they take those anyway?
Would Rangers go out and be like,
we need to take 50 zero this year?
Or like there was no hunting.
I don't think there was any hunting,
but they do in certain circumstances in
places where there's no hunting,
they will bring in people to kill the
population if it gets too high and pick
what?
Yeah,
but the solution to that is allow
hunters to go into yellowstone,
but the problem with that of course,
is it yellowstone national park people
were out there hiking and shit.
You don't want Yahoos out there shooting
a gun.
Just have rangers and he'd be like,
the session is closed and make sure
there's no campers.
Go through it.
All that.
Yeah.
It's hard though.
I mean how many animals and animal can
give birth to and if there's no wolves
like.
And it's like,
that's the other thing about hunting.
One of the things you realize is how
much woods there really are,
how deep the everyone's talking about
the human beings have absolutely taken
over big parts of this country.
Right?
Southern California.
I mean,
you go around Los Angeles area,
like the wildlife that used to be here,
it's all been pushed out,
but there's still areas that are
insanely wild and yellowstone is one of
them.
I mean there's a lot of wilderness
when I fly from here to New Mexico,
it's like fly over New Mexico and
telling me like there's just no land
anymore.
It's like there's fucking no people
living anywhere and most of that state,
like it's just that something happened
and there's a fucking mountain lion that
stocked and hunted.
One of my friends,
I'm in Hollywood in the Hollywood hills.
She was at a party like fourth of July
or something,
parked your car on a little cul de sac
house.
The people are gone on vacation.
Some really rich folks up in the hills.
She walks down and she and two friends
and fucking car and there's a fucking
mountain lion that's there that they are
in the Culdesac,
the mountain lions here and it's.
There's nowhere to go.
There's a fence into the fucking crazy
story.
So anyway,
she ends up yelling at it,
scaring and jumping on top of this audio
or some car that was there that was
parked there screaming at it.
And um,
and then that stopped at,
stopped it from advancing,
but still the extra,
I was like,
what sounds did it make?
And she was like,
oh,
it was like,
it was like a beast from a move.
It was crazy just talking to her and um,
but you would think
if that was the case,
it might've been cornered and it wasn't,
it was cornering them.
Yeah.
But why would it cornered them and just
growl at them?
Delphy
no idea,
but made itself known.
She jumped the fence,
tried to break the windows of the house,
got a nine one one call out was sketchy
service.
Thanks a lot.
And t
and uh,
so I switched to verizon at and t
they're just not reliable mountain lions
hunting friends were one.
I want
to switch it to.
They go,
they go,
well,
were you using your phone in a high a,
in a high traffic zone?
Like I'm like a high traffic.
So I'm like,
are you just telling me you oversold
your system and that like,
I can only call it certain times because
you charged me every minute of the
fucking day.
Anyway,
I digress.
Um,
and then the phone call dropped.
It was awesome.
I was in the verizon store.
I was like,
this is a phone call dropped to the t
guy while you were in the verizon store
and the AP and t guy goes,
no,
my battery went dead.
I'm like,
motherfucker,
you're in,
you're the,
you're a tech Geek.
Like,
you know,
your shit is bunk,
on the street,
your friends laugh.
They're like,
oh,
you're slang that att and t shirts,
you know that fuck off.
Come on.
Just tell me.
It's funny,
you know it's funny.
He's like,
no,
I don't understand what you mean.
So I'm like,
I can't even talk.
That's baby powder cocaine.
Stop all that.
Stop Light Shit.
Anyway,
the line was tagged.
Oh yeah.
That's why she didn't get charged with
like an attempted breaking and entering
and all this shit from security cameras
on them because they knew where the line
is like yeah,
the line fucking was done and I'm like,
so you got taglines that are in high
density population,
but like right in downtown Hollywood.
Yeah.
We're super awesome.
Super Arrogant about mountain lions in
California.
You can't hunt mammoth mountain lions.
They're not hunted.
Right.
So because of that,
their population has skyrocketed in this
place that I'm going to to hone ranch.
There's one waterhole that they have
where they took pictures of 16 different
mountain lions.
I mean they have a massive population of
animals up there because it's 270,000
acres.
Whose ranch is it?
Privately owned?
Privately owned,
giant ranch and they,
it's just huge and there's nothing going
on up there other than hunting and some.
I think they have a water pipeline goes
through it and a bunch of other ways
they make money off the ranch,
but it's not like there's a lot of
people there.
There's,
it's very,
very few people go in and out of the
ranch.
So these fucking cats have the run of
the land and there's elk up there and
there's deer up there and there's a lot
of pigs up there and they just party.
I want to put Gopros on him.
All came back like a fucking stock.
It like be bad ass.
Why do I think someone did something
like that recently?
They put a Gopro on something.
Those aren't those park rangers.
They're not fulfilling their fucking
need.
If they're not dark,
those things put Gopros on them and
let's walk.
Well,
how long will the battery last?
I don't know man.
They need to get in there.
Figure it out.
Let's go do something for this world.
You've got a battery that'll never
fucking disintegrate and that we're
going to keep around forever.
That's polluting the environment for
sure.
But you can't get that on a mountain
lion.
Come on entertainment.
At least I think that there's going to
be in the future there's going to be
batteries.
It just don't run out of juice.
Like we're going to look back 100 years
from now.
They're going to laugh at us like piles
and batteries and landfills and
hopefully we get to the place where we
can be laughed at hopefully if we make
it right.
And that's the thing is I think we get
just smart enough.
I mean he say it all the time,
just smart enough to where we can.
We can go ahead and have our own
destruction because of our progress
because we won't stop progress.
It's like,
is that weird thing?
It's like that thing.
I think Duncan was talking about the
Elon Musk put $10,000,000
towards like this is going to guard us
in the future against the rise of the
machines type shit.
He wanted to stop artificial until,
well,
he wants to protect us or at least
analyze artificial intelligence.
That's the thing is like any pro,
show me where progress got halted.
It's like progress.
It just spurts.
It's like a weed,
you know,
my boss,
my hope about progress is they figured
out a way to make no residue like that.
No footprint.
Well,
not like there's no waste,
like the idea of like,
like right now we create pollution.
Right?
But we had that,
how did we have that?
Did you ever read,
uh,
that Goddamn book about food anyway?
And,
and it,
it,
it surveyed three different meals and
one was like a fast food meal and other
was like a all organic home cooked meal
and another was a meal that you made
everything,
like you made the flower,
you harvested the yeast,
you did all that kind of stuff.
And uh,
it was the Omnivore's dilemma was the
name of it.
And,
and like farms used to be like that,
like you'd have some sheep and some pigs
and some chickens and they would shit
all over here and you'd be growing wheat
or corn or whatever over here.
Then they'd move over here and then you
move your crops over here.
And so you had a continual fertilization
and um,
and self utilized farm.
And then we moved all the animals off
the farm and put them in feed lots.
And then now we just grow one crop over
and over again.
So we need to have.
Yeah.
But even if they're doing that,
they're,
you're still using farm equipment.
The farm equipment had to be built
somewhere.
The construction materials,
there's residue,
there's,
there's waste,
there's all sorts of pollution that
comes out of the machines themselves.
There's some people that are trying to
figure out a way how to take carbon
dioxide out of the atmosphere and
utilize it.
How to take waste,
like what are all the different waste
products that people create with all the
different things that we do,
whether it's making computers or whether
it's driving buses are and figuring out
a way to turn that waste into something
profitable or into something useful.
Had to be Hella profitable.
Well,
I'd have to be held you useful too,
right?
Like that's the idea behind this.
The plastic island in the ocean,
how to utilize that.
It's not really an island.
People who get mad if you call it an
island because you can't build a house
on it.
Exactly.
We can't sell real estate on that,
so fuck you.
It's not that.
That figure is on environment though.
Like what do we call it?
It's a floating,
floating,
like the size of Texas.
They don't even know how big it is
really.
It's just like how all the plastic finds
each other.
Everybody wants even plastic.
That's beautiful.
Love Story.
Plastic plastic should be one of those
little 15 minute shorts before you watch
a kids meal.
You know what dude,
that's what I need to do.
All this other shit.
I need to get a job with like Chevron or
something or the plastic companies and
I'll be the guy that goes out there.
I remember when we were filming two guns
and I was like in Louisiana and,
and that fucking,
they just fucked up the whole golf.
So way to go.
You were there when that happened?
It was right after that.
And so there's just no,
I didn't go down.
That wasn't like that right there.
I wasn't on the shores.
But like how far away were you were in
New Orleans and how far away is that
from them?
One and I don't know,
not to bad river runs out into it.
And you didn't smell anything crazier,
but I mean no more.
I mean you want to smell is fucking
weird.
You know,
there's a lot of new smells to me like I
go to.
I went to Bourbon Street and I was like,
this is just like,
and they got everybody at Walmart
hammered and brought a party bus and
drop them off.
And that's what Bourbon streets like.
It's a trip permit.
Awesome.
It's fucking crazy.
And then it feels like you walk back all
through that quarter and you're like,
it's all misty and shit and you're like,
this is where Jack the ripper lips,
like it's fucking hot as fuck back
there.
And there's tranny,
hookers and fucking all kinds of
darkness all through there.
It's a trip.
There's,
bp is doing all this shit and they're
going look at what we've done to help.
Like I could be one of those spin
doctors for the,
for the,
uh,
plastic.
Gosh,
look at the love and plastic help is.
It was awesome.
I was like,
I really believed these guys.
These are great commercials.
I look up even though we've dumped
millions of gallons,
like Halliburton,
they can be like,
look at all these dead Iraqis and look
at what we've done to help them.
And they could show them Baghdad like
five years ago in Baghdad now.
And it's a little different just to be
like New York City now.
It's caves.
Well,
we're trying to do is we start from
scratch and then do it right and do it
right.
You know,
that is one of the arguments that
historians use,
like it's in the beginning of a Dan
Carlin's hardcore history series on the
Mongols.
Did you listen to that?
You know what he's talking about?
Hitler and the beginning of the thing.
He was talking about how the way people
talk about gang is calm today.
They say that he opened up the trade
routes with China and all the things
they tried to put a positive spin on
what he did.
But the reason why they could do that is
because it was a thousand years ago.
Right?
But if they try to do that about Hitler,
it's too soon.
He's like,
it's an interesting thing that people do
when it comes to history.
Hashtag.
Hashtag too soon.
Hashtag blessed.
Yeah.
Every revolution starts with the fight.
I learned that today on the UFC,
a promo for Rhonda and Holly.
You know,
if you've seen the thing that they've
done.
Well actually I can't talk about it.
I don't think I cried.
I cried when I saw it was so good.
It was great fucking promo work for
that.
For Holly and Ronda fight.
Oh,
the one with the.
It shows him as little girls coming up
and you cry.
Oh Dude.
What is,
you know what broad Yvonne is when holly
as a little girl is sitting in church
and all the people that are looking at
her,
cause she's got bought fucking and it
looks up and she's got a black eye.
She kind of gives that smile
and I'm like.
And what made me cry as like the pride
of a black eye like that people don't
have,
you know,
like there's,
there's,
there's not a lot of people that will
know what that is like to be proud.
Like she worked for that black guy.
You know what I mean?
It's like I would look at a girl with a
black guy and think that she got beat by
her man and that's what a lot of people
don't think that way.
I don't see color Joe,
that's not a colored,
but I think that's a male female.
It's a gender.
Be that aggressive.
It isn't funny thing left Jamie.
It is a funny thing,
man.
If you,
if you train a lot of you have a black
guy.
It's kind of a badge of courage.
Oh,
was like cauliflower ear.
Somebody asked me what the fuck was
wrong with my hair.
I'm like,
what's wrong with yours?
It's a mansion.
When I uh,
when I,
one time I had a,
like a serious black.
I actually had two black eyes and I was
uh,
on fear factor and I was like,
look,
just just let me do the show with black
guys who gives a shit.
Right?
They brought it in because I didn't wear
makeup on fear factor,
but during that I did.
They brought in a makeup artist.
I spray person.
How people don't want to be authentic.
They were like,
we can't have this be real.
We need to have it look a certain way.
The way we think of him to look.
It's like,
how about you?
I look like me.
It's great.
It's like all that shit about the camera
puts on 10 pounds or whatever
motherfuckers.
It makes you look exactly like you are.
You're not happy with that.
Don't be so fat.
I don't have to tell her.
Understood.
That camera puts rounds thing.
I look in the mirror,
I look at myself on camera.
Right.
It's exactly the same.
Similar care we put on 10 pounds.
What it.
Where's that coming from?
Oh good.
Is that like the old cameras?
Maybe so maybe like them old with some
kind of flux lens.
Maybe like a circus lens.
Maybe.
It was like before the head Hd.
You can.
Funny Man,
you know when I was on news radio just
people are pussies and they'll make any
excuse to not have it be real.
Like it's not my fault.
I don't.
I don't need to be accountable for that
camera.
Really good shape.
It's just this one time in my gut when I
was on news radio,
it was right when they were introducing
hd cameras and I'll tell you,
man,
actresses were shitting their pants.
Really?
It was crazy.
Yeah.
They were like,
they'd have conversations in the makeup
room,
like when need a lot more of this was
the hd cameras come holy.
They were all scared because you could
have a girl.
Does makeup people like to be scared
anymore?
Like created.
There wasn't a makeup people.
It was the actresses actresses,
but they were almost signed.
Mom sound mind stable.
They knew that they look better on tv
than they did in real life.
Look at David Caruso and Oh Geez.
In real life.
It's like,
holy fuck.
Real life.
He looks like a Zombie Dude and 106.
Yeah.
At least 100,
606 with some real diet.
Real crypt keeper shit.
Yeah.
He swings kettlebells.
Does he know that guy?
He's like,
is he a smoker?
Is that what it looks like?
You must be,
but he's also redheaded.
He's got that bill bird shit,
but bill per looks great.
Looks really good.
He looks healthy as fuck.
He's got the thing too about facelifts,
like he's like,
yeah.
He's like,
I'd rather look like is.
It was like I'd rather look like a 40
year old guy that a 29 year old lizard
or they don't have that shit worked out.
What are you doing pulling your face
straight like that?
It is awesome.
There's this lady at my daughter's
gymnastics class who's got monster face.
I call it monster face.
When those poor ladies,
they do their lips.
They shoot rubber into their face to
fucking fill it up and then they pull
that bitch back and then she's monster
face.
Like you look at it,
you,
oh Jesus,
like you can't like.
But meanwhile she's right next to a 70
year old lady who looks fine.
You know,
you look at her,
you go,
hello,
how you doing?
Like you don't get weirded out at all.
You just looking at an older woman.
Age Ism is a weird thing and that you.
The self talk that happens around it
that people do is like,
it's a fucking trip.
Like what people run from in that way.
It is.
Well it just feels like there's
something they don't do the shit that
would do it.
It's like,
don't you want to move?
Well all the time,
don't you want to fucking like be able
bodied and all?
No,
no,
no.
But I could get some surgery to do
something like fuck.
Well they just want to look good.
Right?
Like there's some people that look good
until their face moves,
like they can convince themselves they
look good because they're like looking
in the mirror and then everything looks
okay as long as they stay still.
But once they start talking and you go,
hey,
you're fucking cheeks are moving man.
Right.
Like one time we were in the green
facial expression.
We were in the green room at the Improv
and Breyer in this member when Joan
rivers and her daughter had like a
reality show and I was high as anyone
wondering who do I want to fuck her
daughter?
No,
no.
Oh,
that's how either one of those were an
option,
but I was looking at we will really,
really high.
It was me and des and you know how that
goes.
So we're,
we're in the,
in the green room and we were looking up
at the screen and I couldn't,
I was freaked out.
I mean just like nervous and terrified
at Joan rivers face because her face was
like a rubber Kabuki mask.
Absolutely.
As if,
when you're looking at it,
you're like,
it looks like somebody is about to
explode.
It looks like there's an impending
something happening and you're not sure
what,
but it's like,
it's so fucking not right.
But let's just looked frozen.
It looked like frozen and rubber and
weird and she died getting operated on.
Right.
It wasn't surgery though.
I don't think it was plastic surgery.
Is that how Kanye his mom died too?
I think so.
I think she died from plastic surgery.
Anesthesia going,
they're going under for hundreds.
No bullshit.
It's weird that we live in such an
advanced society,
but they're like,
just putting people to sleep.
We might kill him.
Bono.
It's so rare though.
It's you have to be a poor health to go
on.
Gone under a bunch of times for
surgeries and I've had both my knees
done one knee twice my nose.
Done,
I've got a lot of shit fixed and they,
they just put you under in the front
like you never hear of a fighter when
they go under.
It's usually older people.
What have you had done?
My knee.
My shoulder three times.
Damn.
Yeah,
you shoulda done times.
I was overachiever.
They did.
They sculpt it first and then I rip that
one out and then they did another one
where it was a real aggressive thing
that changed my anatomy around in that
shoulder and then like they like your
bicep head goes in and they cut off the
bone where it goes in on one of them and
they moved it and screwed it in
underneath to be like a physical blocks.
So when it dislocate,
which then you fast forward 15 years
later and I was having a lot of ac joint
hurt like trouble and there's just
rubbing together and so this other
doctor,
he goes in and he's going to clean that
up and he says,
it'll be great.
Awesome.
He looks at my x rays.
He goes,
oh my God,
who did this to you?
And I go,
that's not very encouraging.
He goes,
just nobody ethically would change your
anatomy like that,
like this.
And I was like,
it was a cutting edge shit at Michigan
State University fucking 15 years ago.
Like,
I dunno why,
but it's been solid since then.
That's my good shoulder.
So that guy do it again.
Uh,
that guy just cleaned up my ac joint.
That was forest surgery.
So when they cleaned it up,
like what do they do?
Like my friend Melissa from the UFC,
she's had her shoulder done,
she has a,
they shave it,
they put some kind of fake synovial
fluid maybe back in it.
They try to influence a
cartilage growth.
Perhaps hers was bone growth,
like when you have like any sort of an
issue,
like a lot of arthritis and rubbing,
like you see that a lot,
a lot of time in spinal stenosis,
around the spinal columns you'll see
growth like on the edges of the,
uh,
the spine of the discs.
Well,
not on the disc itself,
but the,
the hard pieces,
the spine and the disc is the stuff in
between these times.
Yeah.
And the um,
what do they call those things?
What's the spine bone?
What's a bone?
I think we did spine bone,
spine.
I know just what you're talking about is
the,
your backbone because in between the
semipermeable like pumice creek,
that's the mushy stuff.
And that's the stuff to cushions
everything.
Right?
And the bulk of your vertebrae.
Thank God very much.
Jamie.
I knew there was a word.
How do you remember that?
Seems like that's in my lexicon,
but I've had a rough day.
I've been running around.
But the um,
the edges as you,
your disks get smaller if they,
if you're losing disc degeneration.
Right?
And by the way,
a lot of doctors will start to tell
people that it's disc degeneration,
disease and they'll let you know that,
oh,
it's a disease.
You don't have to worry about it.
Right?
Its use,
its use.
It's not a disease for the most part.
It's most of the time when they say that
what it is is you've been abusing your
body because I've talked to a bunch of
fighters and they'll say,
well,
it's degeneration,
just desta generation disease.
I'm like,
oh,
well it has nothing to do with you
fucking headbutting dudes.
One hundred miles an hour like shooting
for doubles and run it into people's
hips suplex to over and over again or
tossed or whatever.
This isn't.
This isn't a disease.
We're talking.
This isn't herpes concussion,
this is your,
you're beating fuck out of your body,
man.
But I'm the edges.
They develop like bone spurs,
like the bone tries to grow and almost
like your bone is trying to fill in the
area where it knows that the spinal disc
isn't there anymore.
It's weird how your body fights for
homeostasis.
No matter what,
like going into that,
that's like they said,
my shoulder,
there's no scar tissue and this one,
that's probably what keeps it from
getting dislocated.
The scar tissue keeps it in place.
Wow.
I got to get on that,
on that.
Uh,
stem cell shit dude.
Stem.
So Shit is the Vegas.
You've still got to give me that guy's
info.
Oh yeah.
Well that's Dr Davidson from the UFC is
the one who connected me with the
people,
but do they?
They've done a bunch of people now,
a bunch of UFC people have staggering
results.
Yeah.
You're saying Roy Nelson did his knee or
Daniel cormier is knee stem cells.
If either of those guys at Aka,
I would just do every joint.
Just even if there's no problem,
I'll be like,
I,
you were the coach you back,
just get in there and just do it.
But that's what Ludwig did.
Pretty low.
Preemptively got both shoulders done.
I think he did his hips to.
Dude,
I can't imagine the fuck.
He's such a savage and the whole knits
for somebody like that.
Like him,
like Winkeljohn should do that too.
Like you beat the fuck out of yourself.
Brandon Gibson,
all those guys.
You professional holder,
that's worse than fighting.
Yeah.
For your shoulder.
Don't health.
That's horrible.
Especially if you're holding mitts for
some fucking.
For Jon Jones.
Come on.
Well Jon Jones hits hard,
but like imagine like,
like,
like travis brass guys are Travis
Browne,
allister,
allister.
Especially allister when he was on this.
I don't know if that's true or not.
I believe it's true.
I believe it was proven.
I don't know what you're saying is so
dumb.
That drug shit fucking stupid.
You know,
when I was in high school I had to write
a paper and the paper that I wrote was
that you should legalize every drug and
and I was all the kind of thing,
a 13 year old,
right?
I was all hyped up on,
on,
on Nwa Gangsta rap and I was like,
how in the fuck did easy Egan oozy?
Like he doesn't look like anybody that
should have Uzi.
That's true is because he can sell to
end.
The black market is the only thing that
makes crime.
I'm like,
why do we have a black if they want to.
But that's the thing is like everybody
is all fucking excited about marijuana
being you all plots.
Everybody's a fucking pussy.
You're out there like look at and smoke
a joint on CNN.
Well guess what?
You still got fucking 500,000
guys that are locked up.
You should be protesting that every
fucking day of pop.
Really actually legal like in those
states,
they should just be letting dudes out by
the fucking dozens every minute.
That is true.
If you were in Colorado and you're in
jail,
I'll be like,
what the fuck?
What the fuck?
And then how many of those guys are in
there and then they fucking catch a real
case in there because now you've got to
fight or you're an arrival.
Fuck,
that's horrible.
That does happen.
All that shit should be legal.
The only thing that,
and people are like,
well they,
if they do just tax,
everybody's like tax that the
government,
but that's on the idea that the
government gives a fuck the government.
I mean it makes more money.
It's not like if I can tax you who wants
to buy weed?
I wondered how do I tax everybody?
I make them all scared and then I am
prison guys for this illegality and then
I can get the public dollars because
look at isn't it scary that we got these
black and Mexican guys that are selling
dope and we need to put them somewhere.
That's a business.
That's a huge business.
The whole business and that's why it's
like a business though.
There's another business.
The other businesses,
legal marijuana,
will you make more money from tax
dollars from legal marijuana in
Colorado?
They do.
In this year in Colorado,
they made more money from tax dollars
from marijuana.
They did from alcohol for the first time
ever.
Okay.
But what I would love to see,
very high.
What I want to see then is those numbers
versus all the public and federal money
that comes from taxpayers that goes into
law enforcement,
whether it's at sheriff,
drug enforcement levels,
dea levels,
FBI law,
like all the different funding,
which is fucking huge.
And all the prisons shit like where's
all the.
So all the public tax dollars show me
that the taxing on pot is more than
that.
And I would agree,
but wharf.
I bet.
I bet you're right.
Well especially with drug enforcement is
weird because you will,
you,
you're looking at a blanket,
you know,
you're looking at pills,
you're looking at heroin,
coke,
the marijuana,
drug enforcement,
legal,
make it all,
make well make it all legal and at least
you're gonna get taxes from stuff that's
already been sold anyway.
And then you can use that money for
education,
use that money for treatment.
But the people that are in law
enforcement,
the problem with the law enforcement
when it comes to drugs,
it's like they're fucking lobbying to
keep shit illegally.
They do a lot of.
They don't want it legal.
They know why would you.
And then when you've got.
I believe it's the biggest union in the
maybe in the world,
but in the country as the correctional
prison guards.
So you got prison guards the biggest,
but they.
They lobby there.
One of the biggest contributors for drug
legalization,
keeping drugs illegal.
They lobby hard to make sure that drugs
stay illegal because it keeps them in
jobs.
But you know what man,
you just got to figure out alternatives
for those people.
Do you think people that are prison
guards want to be fucking prison guards?
If you could find some sort of a
positive job if you could.
But I bet a lot of those guys are like,
I'm in power over some fucking bad
motherfuckers.
And they liked that.
The consciousness is fucked up because
they're like,
well,
if you've got that job,
you're a prisoner,
you're a prisoner all doing.
I mean,
you've been chosen to be a prisoner and
you think you're free,
you're fucked.
You're a head guy.
He just don't know until it's a guy
that's Kinda got that kind of
consciousness to where he doesn't even
know he's fought qm.
Imagine the feeling that you must get,
like they shut those gates behind you
and you're working with all those people
that are in there for life and you got
to go home at night and then you're
going to go home at night and you can
quit and leave anytime you.
But your work environment is filled with
all these people that are just doomed.
They're doomed.
Occasionally.
They arrived.
Yeah.
I don't watch that.
Freeway.
Rick Ross a documentary last week and I
thought,
man,
that is crazy.
Like you're like,
you know,
like more money than it.
Like get anything.
You're living a life that like is is
like if Bill Gates had an exciting life
type,
whatever you wanted to do,
any,
any vacations,
any anything,
and then you go into nothing of prison.
Then you come out and he's just like
printing tee shirts or whatever he's
trying to do and trying to stay busy.
Just trying to hustle.
Fuck yeah,
he does like speeches and does a bunch
of different shit,
but he's just trying to hustle and stay
straight.
Yeah,
that's.
It's hard man.
It's also crazy because he went in and
he was making all that money,
millions and millions of dollars and you
couldn't read millions a day,
millions a day,
couldn't read and then figured out how
to read.
Then figured out how to fucking read law
books and then figured out that his case
was bullshit and then got it overturned
because he was in.
He was under the three strikes law,
but they tried to try him for going
criminal enterprise,
not a,
not a or whatever.
It's like it was one robbing spree that
it,
that it wasn't secular events is how he
did it.
Like so there were saying Ohio is a
separate thing and he's like,
no,
because I was on a continuous criminal
spree,
like my whole life was a continuous
criminal spree.
Well the three strike thing,
they tried to,
they tried him for two things at the
same time and it's not how it works.
You're supposed to go away and then they
catch you again and you go away and then
they catch you again at three strikes,
but they tried to do it for him with
more than one different things tagged
onto one arrest.
That's not how it works.
Oh.
And then they planted a bunch of shit on
him as father to put them in jail to
win.
That's the thing.
It's weird that they let them out that
that worked like that work because he
was right.
Yeah,
but the problem,
I'm going to be talking about this a
lot.
I think the problem with law enforcement
in general,
like one of the big problems is that
people want to win.
When people get into game,
whether it's Jujitsu or it's fucking
ping pong,
you want to win,
or like the drug testers,
like they're not looking,
they're not wanting you to have.
I mean that's not true.
Some guys probably are,
but they're not looking for you to have
a free test.
Like I want to catch this dirty guy and
they see all the guys is dirty.
You know what I mean?
But I mean that's the hustle,
right?
That's,
that's what they're trying to do.
They're trying to catch people cheating
so they get this motherfucker like every
day you're playing a game and the game
is catch the guy with the rubber Dick.
Do you think they should?
Oh,
therapists.
There was an eight or.
Yeah.
Jeff Manson made that famous.
Did he?
Yeah,
he didn't.
What was the first guy that I know that
I'd heard about a wizard later with?
Those guys are fucking.
I think all that shit should be illegal
to like when they do gene splicing or
whatever the fuck is next that they're
going to do.
Like they're going to have miles that
and inhibitors and all that kind of
stuff.
You're going to have a thing if all
these fucking useless fucking nerds that
are regulating this shit or like we want
to have clean athletes,
whatever.
Okay,
so you're going to have a crowd of
fucking people at the mgm that are all
in way better shape and condition than
the actual fucking fighters that are
competing.
That is for sure.
When the future.
When that does happen,
we're going to have to have a totally
new conversation because I think right
now what's going on is they're just
trying to prevent the first drips of
water that are coming out of that dam
and they're putting their fingers in it.
It's like stops and the,
you know,
stopping the rise of the machines.
Elan Musk,
you're not going to do it.
It's common.
What are you going to do with the rise
of New Mexico?
Of this roll?
Baby Roll.
I'll write it out.
How do we do this?
I'll survive.
Well,
tell me how we do this freestyle.
I don't know.
I can't.
I can't plan because a ranch,
we've been talking about that for
decades.
Do it.
All right.
Come on man.
What state you're making some fucking
watch it actually movie.
I see you can get shot and then sicario
right now.
Are you in that whale?
And I heard yelling in Spanish.
Shit.
Motherfuckers really.
I heard that movies don't,
can anybody speak Spanish?
And I'm like right here.
I looked around,
there's four of us and I looked around
and there was fucking bunch of Chicago
dudes in me and I was like,
well,
if one of these guys and none of them
raise their hand.
Boom.
And then I got on my text to fucking,
uh,
the guy that coaches Jujitsu for us at
10th planet in Santa Fe.
And I'm like,
Hey Ruben,
how do I get through tax?
I,
uh,
yeah,
through text or texts,
he fucking.
I'm like,
dude,
you got to write it out phonetically.
I don't know the real sound right?
You just gotTa get one of those worlds
and practiced over and over.
It was in the moment.
It was like going to film 20 minutes
later.
Oh,
right.
Then they're like,
hey,
we want to add to scene in is awesome.
Oh Shit.
A little known secret.
Wow.
I'll tell anybody too late.
That's awesome.
I love that.
Yeah,
Dude.
Just make shit happen.
You know what I mean?
Like,
just freestyle,
that shit.
Like Howard is going to work.
It was like the whole movie thing and
going,
how did this happen?
I'm like,
fuck,
I don't know.
Like I try to ask you.
I'm like,
do I need an agent on it?
And you're like,
fuck,
I don't know.
And you know,
one of the best things that I've heard
about it is a fucking pauly shore.
And he goes,
he was at the poly shore and said,
now he was given advice to like three
other little actors like Benji and a
couple people that were comics at the,
at the store.
And he goes,
uh,
you know,
the truth is,
is nobody knows how to do it.
And I just took that and I go,
okay,
fuck everybody.
Everybody that tell you how to do it,
they never done it.
All those people are coaching,
acting or they're doing whatever.
And I'm like,
I'm just going to run with this and
fucking do it and I'll show up and I see
the guys that are there.
And I go,
I'm like,
well,
I don't know that I'm great,
but I know I'm better than that guy.
And uh,
will you also have an unusual look?
I do,
I do.
I've been told that a lot.
Not Paying off,
but you know,
you're a big giant dude.
You got a crazy beard,
you know,
you know how to fight like you have all
these skills.
Handsomest man,
intelligence,
green eyed devil,
you've got a lot going on.
How all that came.
And then I just got,
I just kept,
you know,
what I was used to live like thinking
another shoe's about to drop,
right for a long time.
And I thought it was just not going to
end up good.
And because like I didn't correlate that
my actions were getting my results in a
lot of ways,
you know.
And uh,
and I think,
you know,
a big part of that is just being
accountable for your life.
Like a guy told me,
he says,
you know,
you're all fucked up and I go,
why?
And he said,
because you think you're a good guy
because you base yourself on your
intentions and the whole world is
reacting to your actions.
And I was like,
what?
Don't they know that I'm saying I
intended and I'm like,
none of that shit,
you know,
if you step on a dude's shoes and you
didn't,
you didn't mean to.
His shoes are still fucking dirty.
And uh,
and so like just bringing all that shit
into my everyday and I think the whole
thing more and more that I think about
is heightening awareness and the more
you are aware,
the less dumb you are and the less dumb
you are,
the better off you do.
That's a really good.
You can train yourself to be more aware,
you know?
Yes you can.
And it happens all the time and you
don't just get it,
but you get layers of it,
you know,
layers.
The hole.
That's all great way of putting it the
whole way.
You just said it is a great way of
putting it.
The,
I think a lot of people think that
they're a good person,
they'll do douchey or they're trying to
get away with something because they're
hustling,
they're broke and you know,
it's that constant self reflection and
people are like,
well,
how are you successful or whatever.
And I'm like,
because I'm a loser,
you know,
like,
I don't remember.
I remember talking with you and you're
like,
I always felt like a loser too.
Like when we'd go on the road and Shit,
and you're like,
because I'm living a life that's
different than other people live living.
I'm not a nine to five guy or whatever
the thing is,
you know,
and so you're living this life that's
out of the norm.
And it's like,
and thank God you get to be an uncommon
man in that way.
The other way would have killed me and
you and Eddie and Ari and you know what
I mean,
and Duncan md and you look at all of
that and I go,
that's no fucking mistake that we're all
doing well,
happy positive.
And I go,
man,
I owe everything to the people that I've
chosen to have around me have been
graced about my life.
Huge,
huge part of your life.
And you also,
you get power when your friends are
doing well.
Like when I see you in movies,
I get power when I see you in John Wick.
Okay.
I got power from that and I was like,
Ooh,
we all,
it's like an inquiry.
It's like,
how do you stay inspired?
He stay around inspirational people.
You know what I mean?
That.
And that's the thing for me.
And so like whether it's the gym I work
out at or,
or uh,
you know,
what I'm putting in my body or anything
like I'm living,
like,
all that shit matters,
man.
Where I'm living.
I used to live in Hancock Park and then
I moved to Venice and I'm like,
oh my people are in Venice and I want to
be near the ocean.
And like fucking,
that's a different vibe down there is a
different vibe.
It's very crowded,
but it's a great vibe.
It's so nice,
man.
It's more relaxing.
It's like being in New Mexico for me.
So,
uh,
Jim likes to each other though I don't
like to the crowdedness of go.
That's why I could never look at,
look at like New York.
I'm only at like Deuce Jim.
The place where I work out at and train
a lot is like,
I know where that is outdoors and right
across the top I'm just,
they're posted up.
We do podcasts there.
Fuck around.
Like it's Rad.
It's fucking Nice.
And then everything's walking distance
that your friends Jim,
do you?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
And so you live up near there?
Yeah,
just like,
I don't know,
that's nice areas.
A lot of good restaurants,
a lot of great.
If you had a place to park your car
parking's better than Hollywood beats
the shit out of parking in Hollywood.
That's true.
Hollywood is so ridiculous.
You can walk like my favorite
restaurants or like clubs on Lincoln and
then Oscar's down on rose and those are
just both five minutes from anywhere.
Like it's easy or there's a great
Italian restaurant in Washington too.
It's like there's a lot of good places
down there like you said,
and uh,
and there's always value.
No,
fuck.
Utilize Valet.
If you're fucking,
you just got to drive the right car.
You can drive your car.
I have a pickup truck.
I'm a Goddamn American.
I don't have the Rogan money yet.
I didn't have that.
You know what the WHO does this is it to
my pat like I've got.
So after breaking bad I did,
I got some money off of that and I was.
And then at that same time,
a friend of mine from New Mexico,
this guy,
Rico Taylor,
he calls and he goes,
hey dude,
I'm,
I'm a.
and he was best friends with my friend
Marcos who started in level with me.
And so noah was like,
everybody I fuck with is all people that
I love and that had been tied in to for
a long time and everybody's doing good.
It's Rad.
But he just picked up a lambo because
he's like any.
And he goes,
he goes,
Hey,
is it realistic that I get A.
I put 60 down on it and I'll pay it.
I don't know if it's four grand a month
or something and um,
you know,
does that sound reasonable to you then?
And I'm like,
fuck,
that's crazy at my house.
What the fuck?
That's a mortgage.
That's an apartment in New York City for
33 years old and you can fucking do that
and be fuck yes.
Do that.
Live unreasonable life.
Do that thing.
So we got that money.
What happened with that was it seeded
these bars,
concrete cowboy.
And so we got one in Austin.
We've got one in Houston in five weeks
we'll open,
we've got one in Dallas and it's paid
back like six times invested.
But I gave that money going,
I don't have any more money in the world
and fuck it.
I had been broke before.
Here's my money.
And fucking I knew that Rico would take
care of it.
I knew he'd be a good steward of it and
if it didn't work it didn't work and
whatever.
And like that being free about it.
And like I did a couple things,
like it made me go,
the money's not you,
it doesn't matter.
Like that's a replaceable commodity,
that's nothing.
And also it's like I've been rolling the
dice my whole life,
so let's roll the dice and then we
fucking just started taking off with
that.
And then three years later mother
fuckers driving a Lamborghini.
Fucking rad dude ran a shitbox as though
tell him those things.
I wrote,
I wrote that thing.
Well you know what he says,
because like you just,
you just roll it for two years and then
you can sell it back,
you can make money on it.
And then.
And then I said then why?
He says,
well then you're just in the flip.
Then you got a Lamborghini.
Every year you get a new one.
I telling you to.
I don't want to do that.
I like what I wanna do is I want to get
one of those.
I got four by fours or $200,000.
It's not even that I had this 65.
I don't want to do.
Yeah,
but I called that dude before he was on
your show and I was board.
Yeah.
And I go or I emailed him.
Then he called me back.
I go,
Hey Rad,
I'm like,
this guy's calling me.
And,
and uh,
he must've thought I had some Jay Leno
money or something.
He's like,
Oh yeah,
I used to work with guys in your field
or whatever.
I'm like,
what's my.
what,
what is my field like?
I don't even really know.
And it's like,
well,
an actor and I go,
oh,
okay,
cool.
And uh,
and he's like,
yeah,
to Redo your really.
It'd be like,
you know,
around 400.
I'm like,
you're talking to the wrong fucking
crazy.
I don't know,
ground up like,
you know,
the whole digitized and,
and Redo the whole undercarriage and the
whole brake system and this know
$400,000,
I don't know because anyone can come in
under 400 a boy tait fletcher on
instagram
because those,
a broncos are too brought to the,
done to the test.
He's got those though and then he's got
like the reformers and then it's always,
there are different price points and I
think if you bring your own box of
hazards to him,
he probably thinks about it a different
way.
Who knows what,
he does a bunch of different kinds of
cars,
but one of the coolest ones he does his,
those old Toyota land cruisers.
Yeah.
He takes those uh,
fj 62.
They don't even look that cool.
And then he puts a corvette engine in
them.
He puts a modern corvette engine in them
and fucking completely to see that one.
The white one.
I like that with all that billeted
fucking steal that one.
Stupid expensive.
That one's like way,
way into the twos.
Like high twos.
There's a used one I saw on youtube or
on Ebay or somewhere like 1:40.
They were really.
Yeah.
Wow.
That's a bargain.
But a diesel fucking diesel.
Awesome.
A diesel power.
Wang and really see.
He does amazing stuff.
That guy,
he's a real.
He's a real engineer and an astute.
I.
Well you go to,
I'll take you to his place if you want
to go and check it out.
I called him.
I was like,
when are you there?
He's like,
oh,
next week or whatever.
Yeah.
Let's go.
Come with me.
I'll go with you.
Because he's doing a blazer now.
A K five blazer,
those old Chevy Blazers,
if he's going to do it,
it's going to be insane.
Fuck is going to do an icon version of
the blazer.
So he's gonna completely update the
suspension and all the components.
But yeah man,
his,
his employees or his,
uh,
customers are just rich as fuck.
I mean those are the kind of,
what is the Jay Leno's of the world and
all that.
I mean,
I heard him on your show and he was
like,
yeah,
Dana wanted one but he didn't want to
wait or whatever.
And I'm like,
holy fuck.
That's.
Yeah,
it takes over a year.
I mean he has full time employees
working on your car for over a year.
I mean that's why it costs $200,000.
But when you go there,
you get it.
Like when I went to his shop and like,
oh,
I get it.
He's like,
yeah,
you could cut a lot of corners here and
there and have it look the same and cost
$100,000.
But this fucking guy is doing everything
like that.
What the best
that I can get?
What's the best buy his stuff?
It's not like driving off the thing at
west coast customs or something like
that or wherever it is and it's like,
yeah,
see and if you've got a problem,
come on back and we'll try to be like,
that's the dude that is like,
he cares about every piece that comes
through.
Oh No.
He not only just care that guy.
If he doesn't care,
he won't build it.
Right.
He won't build it.
Yeah.
Like if he would've said no to Dana,
how he just saying no.
Like being like,
that's not.
That's outside of my book.
Those has to do is wait around and say
contact me whenever you got one for
sale.
Bronco number one just went up for sale.
He could throw,
throw money in an account and go here.
I'll pre pay for it.
Just hollering the unit when it's done
or whatever.
Well Dana's you're still going to want
it in a year and patient.
You're still going to want it next year.
He'll be like,
can I get one now?
Well,
you could have if you were to give me
money last year,
but now it's another year.
Well,
it's more now.
I think he's in a 2018.
That's the thing about the broncos
getting better at anything.
It's like you're always,
you're,
there's gonna come a day when you want
to get better.
Fucking do it now.
Like that was one of the best,
like one of the.
So many coaching,
like sports has given me so much,
but I'm like.
Then arsdale one time he would do like
guided meditation sometimes after
practice and so there's fucking 40
sweaty guys laying on the mat.
So he turned the lights off in the gym
at Jackson's and uh,
and he'd go,
Hey,
I know you guys.
We did a lot of technical wrestling
today and you think,
Hey,
I'm young.
There's a lot of time and I'll be able
to get this.
I'll put this together.
I'll piece together.
I got a little better today.
He says,
I just want you to consider that there's
a guy that's demanding to be better
right now.
There's a guy that knows he needs to get
it today.
And you're going to have to fight that
guy.
So he's like,
fucking turn your fucking learning curve
up.
And like he would really speak into that
kind of a voice of going.
It's not just,
it's not just when it happens,
it happens.
It's like demand that you get better
now.
And that's a powerful way to look at
stuff.
I think there's some,
some wrestling mentality,
man,
those wrestlers are fucking.
That's a different breed of guy.
They're like,
I need to do this.
Well,
I think you have that with boxers you
have that would kick box.
You have that with anybody who is just
fanatical about improvement.
You have to have that insane,
insane.
Just the drive to believe fiction and
belief.
Yeah.
But you got to be obsessed,
man.
If you're not obsessed,
you're not going to beat the guys
obsessed.
I remember when I saw fucking foundry
Ellen's,
when he first came down,
the first time I'd ever seen him was
when I never knew anything about him
until he beat up Stephan Bonner and I
was live at that fight and I was like,
holy fuck.
And he was just learning back then,
didn't know,
and the throws I was like,
and Stephens is maybe bigger than me.
He's fucking nuts.
Not Small.
He's good.
He's adept at everything and he's
hitting them with elbows,
like their jabs and knees and then
throwing them like crate anytime it'd
get close to them,
throw them.
And I was like,
holy fuck.
And then,
I don't know,
a month or two months later he came to
Jackson's and he's there and I'm like,
I was eight.
And I knew he wrestled,
like I knew a bunch of tough wrestlers
from,
from uh,
New York.
And
I was like,
uh,
where'd you there Moitai though?
Because like Tom Watson,
or he'd just gotten back from a Dutch
kickboxing camp and dudes go to Thailand
all the time and there's all that.
And,
and he goes,
uh,
youtube fuck,
fuck,
like dudes are dying and you're just
like.
He's like,
well,
I look at it and I go,
whoa.
And then I believe and I'm like,
holy fuck,
like no proper training.
He just watches shit on a video.
And you're like,
don't watch the matrix.
He's a special talent.
He is a special talent.
One of the problems with John is that he
absolutely has worked hard,
but it has come way easier for him than
it has for other people and I think part
of that is because he grew up with two
super athletes for brothers.
Kenny wouldn't match you just getting
your ass kicked all the time in your
house by giant super athletes.
Both his brothers are NFL fucking
allstars.
Yeah,
he's,
he's got a super athlete.
Always joke about it is whatever comes
out of there.
Just Nike should sponsor.
We're all super athletes.
So true.
It's so true.
I mean,
he,
his level is just right out.
They used to beat them up or whether
they're just like,
I'm not.
The toughest one in my family is like,
my brothers will beat my ass.
The younger brother,
his younger brother beat his ass.
Like his younger brother was talking
about it.
Like in an interview they asked for tmz
and he's like,
oh,
I'll beat his ass right now.
It's like,
what the fuck?
We don't remember when he watched,
uh,
when,
when he chokes the Oto and I'm like,
he doesn't even really know how to like
I'm looking at that or when he choked
bader I'm like,
Yoda.
Choke was a great job because he knows
how to push.
He's the first one doesn't cover the
head,
covers the head,
but he also,
he pushes the arm,
you know,
he pushes his palm back just learning
and sees that he's learning in these
moments.
We so strong.
How scared I was like,
like Beta.
He looked great against Rashad fucking
look like at different athletes,
but he's a different athlete over the
last four fights.
Bader is,
he's been number back then when he would
just relied on wrestling that Jon Jones
fight.
When do you see a sun kissed kid
wrestler pull half guard like that.
And he just was like,
I don't want to fucking,
I don't want to get in a bad position.
Maybe I can hang onto this.
Yeah,
he was just overwhelmed.
I mean that's a kind of power that like
he'd never felt in.
That's a huge top of the food chain
wrestler.
Like,
let's see how special John Is.
You shouldn't look at how good glover to
share his looked against everybody else,
but John,
well Phil Davis did beat his ass,
but Phil Davis beat his ass when he was
fighting out of Connecticut and his
shoulder was all fucked up for the John
Jones fight and there's a lot of things
wrong with this camp.
Go overhead is has the right mentality
to as far as like a stocking and getting
really aggressive towards cones and
taking the center because John just
takes the center of the ring and makes
everybody running.
The circle around him was like.
That was one of the fascinating things
about their fight.
Glover was like loading up on and John
was just aware of everything and he's
like,
no,
you can't fight them.
I know you guys are looking like they
want to put them away and it's like he
sees too much to be able to do that.
You have to really.
How are you going to surprise him with
one shot?
You know?
It's incredible though.
When you think about that.
It's incredible that he has that sort of
awareness with relatively small amount
of time striking.
Yep.
You,
when you consider his entire life.
In fact it's only 27 wins.
The title at 23,
you know,
the growth is in 20,
22 or 23.
They want the title to 22.
Like so.
I mean I hate what happened with him.
I hate to see a guy run into that,
that classic Cliche of partying and just
messing up his life and,
and then the,
the hit and run.
So God damn,
I think it's that youth stuff,
you know?
And it's the thing that I'm like,
I would just ask everybody to be
gracious looking at it in that way
because it's shit that maybe not
everybody does,
but a lot of young dudes,
you go through that shit and he went
through it at a later time maybe,
but a way public time.
Like he's,
you know,
that's the thing that when you're so
publicized like that people are going to
see all your words and there's nobody
that's walking without words.
It's like,
that's one of the problems with the way
we view.
I think politics,
I think everything,
it's like,
you know,
pee before the Internet,
like all those politicians are
pretending that they didn't fuck kids or
have affairs or blood or whatever.
Come on.
That's jared.
Um,
but I know what you're saying and all
that kind of thing.
And it's like when,
when you live with transparency,
like we have a lot more transparency
now.
It's like everybody's seen.
There's no cover ups of scandals except
nine slash 11.
But beyond that they chose black
helicopters.
Yeah.
I,
uh,
I wonder if it's going to change
politics in the future if you're going
to.
People are going to be forced to just be
human and,
and that's the thing.
Grow and will be a real person because
that speech type style of delivery with
a not real,
you know,
that they do with,
ladies and gentlemen,
the president of United States.
Sure.
My fellow Americans today is a day that
will live in infamy of speech writers
that have this template and they want to
put that template.
And it's also like the tone,
the way they,
they speak,
it's all fake and I always wonder like,
are we going to come to a point in time
where a guy gets onstage where a woman
gets on stage as the president and
speaks like a human and says,
here's our situation.
This is where we're at.
We have,
we have a real problem with Syria.
We have when going to run for president.
We,
Kanye West,
I think Atlanta,
Kanye,
Kanye up and debate.
So for sure you would run trains on that
debate.
He was racing a train trying to talk
over you.
It has a connotation that I gave you
your time,
sir.
That'd be awesome.
I'm not Taylor swift.
That would be awesome.
You know,
I think,
I don't know,
I feel like uh,
you know,
we,
we take for granted from old ideas,
you know,
and it's like it goes back to polly's
shorter going,
nobody knows how to do it.
There was no path when you make your own
path,
right?
That's the thing.
Because Paul came from standup and
there's absolutely no path and stand up
like no one because at least like with
acting role,
some open mics,
Fletcher,
let's do it.
I think the same thing.
I don't want to do it again.
Oh really?
Yeah,
he's down.
He wants to kill it again.
Cool.
You know,
I had eddie do it like he probably these
days,
like eight times.
Yeah.
What did he say?
Well,
he was like,
you know,
he's like,
I had the stroke that I thought was just
awesome and it just,
it was about hookers and it just didn't
know,
you know,
the one and uh,
anyway,
but you know,
you look at all these,
all these old ideas that people haven't
even like this,
this whole stigma of like what we have
low attention span.
We're looking at it wherever my phone
is,
we're looking at our phones all the time
or this and that.
But you know,
you look at that and you go,
okay,
if I were a corporate media thing and I
wanted to put out a fucking new
entertainment thing and it's going to be
anywhere from an hour to three hours
long and it's just going to be guys
talking,
any corporation would be like,
that's never going to catch on.
We need sound bites,
we need MTV news like we need fuck.
And you look at podcasts and you look at
what they are and people are fucking
more invested in that because it's real
because there's authentic voices to it.
Well,
you know,
that was one of the number one things
that people said to me when I first
started out,
like,
you can't do three hour podcasts right
now.
Why or why not?
And they said,
well,
because no one's going to listen to
three hours.
I go,
well,
they don't have to write.
You can just shut it off like I don't
get it.
That's why I had like an argument is
about as long as you just having fun.
Who gives a fuck our.
He was adamant about it.
You have to enter your podcast.
I'm just telling you right now,
you have to edit your podcast.
I go,
why?
He goes,
because it's too long.
I go,
well,
so what?
What does that mean?
And also more importantly is that a road
that you've walked you have experienced
with yours being too long,
but everybody was compelling but nobody
had any experience at all.
But they thought about it like a comedy
central show,
like an hour long show,
which then speaks to the thing about old
stuff,
old ideas.
You've got to put away your old ideas if
you want to be on the tip of the sphere.
Don't even think.
I mean,
my point of view was like you and I long
before we ever did podcast,
we always had these conversations before
a show or after show or hanging out.
We would talk for hours,
hours and hours.
And it seemed to me like a half hour
into the conversation or 45 minutes,
shit just started getting cookie,
you know?
And then,
you know,
an hour later we're like,
yeah,
yeah.
And then blah blah blah.
And then the stories come out and I
remember this one time and those are the
fun conversation and you get to know
each other and then,
and then he would make that into an
audience and the fuck.
Then they get to know you and then
there's not like,
you know,
there's not all this,
uh,
these barriers between us all.
We're all,
we all see our similarities and there's
less dissension.
There's less animosity,
there's more understanding,
there's more graciousness and
generosity.
And like,
if we could get that way with everybody,
if everybody felt that way instead of
this corporate dominion though,
here's what CNN says that we need this
to be.
You have direct feedback from other
people about what you're doing.
Right?
And that feedback has been super
valuable to me,
man.
Even the negative stuff,
the negative stuff like you don't,
nobody likes to hear criticisms about
what they do,
but if you consider it and find warriors
enter a truth in that,
you could find out a lot about your
style or of you just interviewing people
or talking to people where you make
mistakes and you're not.
No one's perfect.
You're not going to make mistakes.
I mean,
you're not going to have a podcast that
every word comes out perfect.
It's just not possible because you're
free dollar ads.
Yeah.
I freaking lost.
You stumble on all the time and it
doesn't fucking matter.
But if somebody were dragging,
yeah,
they would want to do it again.
Do it again.
We're going to do it again.
You don't have.
I mean sometimes I have to do it again.
Sure.
But the reality is that this,
this medium is new and no one had it
before and this medium is like they gave
these kids the controls like the gave
these kids the ability to broadcast a
radio show and then they just did it
their way and then it go,
well,
why don't we just start talking?
Let's just see what happens if we don't
have commercials in the middle of.
The thing is like as long as you're
having fun,
was the person involved in it?
Who gives a fuck?
It doesn't.
It doesn't matter what the result is.
In a way it's like,
it's Kinda like it's like a fight or a
comedy sketch or what?
When you go up and you try a joke,
it's like there's not an and you're
trying to figure it out and do it the
best you can in real time.
Right in real time with no script and
no,
but that's like being in competition.
It's competition is where greatness
happens.
People figure shit out in the crazy way
inside of that kind of pressure and so
if you step on stage,
you've got an increased amount.
It's not like you're in your living room
in front of your mirror trying to say a
fucking joke.
It means something different so you grow
more in that competition.
The second mean more the fucking
moments.
Meanwhile,
all of that stuff and you don't get that
if you're not willing to throw it out
and expose yourself live and that's like
putting this live on the Internet.
Like that's a huge exposure and either
you're an authentic person that's got
something or you don't.
And and it becomes like.
I think it's super visible and I think
it's super important that we all get to
that instead of all these masks that we
wear all the time.
You know,
it's like,
and to me it doesn't matter if you're
like,
it's like,
are you saying that I'm sure if he only
feels differently now laughs about it,
but like if you're.
So does that mean that you don't have a
conversation?
This is more than 15 minutes with your
friend,
like 40 minute thing.
It's just like he thought it had to be
like an hour because a show is an hour
but not a real hour,
42 minutes because we got to have to out
for commercials.
Most people do the commercials in the
middle of Shit too,
you know?
And I was like,
man,
I tried what you ever watch that show?
Uh,
there's a new fear.
The walking dead is the new walk now
seeing an ad for a really dope.
So good.
I thought the walking dead was going to
be shit.
And I watched it and I was like,
and then I watched like six or 10
episodes and I was like,
this is stupid.
It's the same episode again.
And then I watched another 20 episodes.
I just couldn't stop watching it no
matter what.
Fear the walking dead is interesting
because it's less special effects.
Got Less zombies and it's better and the
fucking,
the way it's shot,
it's shot so well.
Whoever the director is and whoever the
cinematographer is or the cameras that
bad motherfuckers because they,
they,
it's done so well.
It sounds like a really good movie.
It's cool and isn't.
There's very few cut the shit moments in
it.
It's really good.
This new show that's coming out is a
westworld world.
This show with Anthony Hopkins.
Is that like the old movie with Yule
Brenner?
Yeah.
Same Shit at Harris and Anthony Hbo.
What I was going to say is I watched
that show the other day for the first
time.
I usually watch it on apple TV,
apple TV.
The other night I watched it on TV,
TV and I sat through the fucking
commercials.
I can't do that shit.
I can't do commercials.
It's ruthless and that's the thing is tv
is going away.
It's all going to go this digitized.
Why can't they have like,
who the fuck is paying for all those
commercials?
Right?
Why don't they have make a big deal out
of it?
Say a fucking ram trucks.
Ram trucks going to sponsor the whole
fucking episode.
We're going to have one commercial in
the beginning.
Ram trucks is proud to present fear of
the walking dead.
Just do it as a goddamn just to attest
and make them dope on the superbowl
commercial.
How about make one?
Yeah.
Make one where a guy in a fucking ram
truck is running over zombies.
Crushing their heads and fucking headed
off into the distance and see.
This is the thing though.
Driving it's old ideas.
We need to start a production company.
That's what I'm saying.
What else do we need to do?
We need to do something else.
Oh,
we need to make native ran a little 15
minute kids commercials.
I guess we're going to need that to
kids.
Kids.
Short films.
Yeah.
We need a ranch in New Mexico.
New Mexico is spot.
It's a good spot,
but Colorado is good too.
I mean,
it was pretty beautiful and nice and
gain rich and not all fucked up with a
pollution yet and weeds free and legal
there.
We'd screen legal if that's your thing,
you know,
that's my thing.
I like friendly and no matter what,
I don't have any use for weed and I love
it.
Free and legal.
I would like it if everything was free
and legal.
We need less loss.
We do.
We need less laws,
less people enforcing those laws and a
more common sense,
more freedom,
more allowing people to do whatever the
fuck they want as long as it doesn't
hurt people and then put restrictions on
shit that does hurt people that's in
place,
right?
That's not in place right now.
Financial Shit.
Like how about the fact that none of
those guys that caused the financial
crash of 2008 or in jail so crappy about
that whole thing about being accountable
like I don't hang out with like if you
weren't accountable for your actions are
responsible,
I want to fucking hang out with you.
It's like it's the kind of thing and
it's like,
why would I accept less from my
politicians or from anybody that is that
going to be accountable?
It's like everybody's got to be held
accountable and that's the way good shit
works.
If I started with this,
when you improve,
if I start fucking level surveys and
it's a shit product or we don't do due
diligence in marketing or whatever,
the fucking thing isn't,
it fails.
Nobody's fucking bailing me out and I
could put all my money and vet and go
broke.
Like that could be the thing,
but GM,
they have a failing business model and
we're going to go ahead and write them a
check for a trillion.
Like,
what?
What the fuck is that?
Oh,
you mean like the bail house?
All that shit.
It's like,
that doesn't make any sense.
All that too big to fail.
Shit.
Shit shouldn't be too big to fail.
Did pay back all those loans though and
they are profitable now and they have
improved and made incredible vehicles
now.
So I see your point in some way.
Let Shit die,
but God it.
Then you'd have no 2016 corvette and
that thing's pretty sick.
Who needs a corvette?
If you drive a corvette,
you are.
Do.
You don't have a corvette?
Stop it.
That's not real.
That's a,
that's an old school corvette.
It's not like one of these brand new off
the lot years.
Nineteen 87 corvette like stops 87,
19,
87.
The dark years.
They're all dark years after fucking 19.
What?
Seventy two.
Um,
yeah,
but until about 2000.
Thirteen,
2014.
The newer ones are pretty dope.
Dude.
You can't ever.
You're born with the Lamborghini.
You can get corvette overlap.
Yes sir.
You know,
why would resale and then I would buy a
truck.
How about at a house?
How about America and keep America
strong.
Cuban American.
The best thing about keep America strong
as what they pull the uh,
the uh,
the NASA space shuttle with.
What did they poach?
A Toyota Tundra.
Oh no,
that's awful.
Hundred percent awesome.
Good,
good,
good.
I'm like,
how did that get through?
Toyota are good trucks.
Fuck yeah,
that's my favorite tacoma.
They don't like.
They don't ever break.
They're coming out with a diesel too.
I heard.
Well,
that's why everybody fell in love with
those land cruisers.
They used to say in Africa,
if you want to get into the Bush,
you bring a range rover,
you want to get out,
you bring a Land Cruiser.
That's,
and that's why I love that Dude John,
because he's all about making it last
forever instead of all these like,
oh,
I'd love to have a Mercedes or bmw or
something like,
now that I'm able to,
it'd be great.
Accepted it.
I'm not,
I just can't fucking buy something
that's going to crap out and 60,000
miles they all have an expiration date
where there's like,
now there's real problems forever with
the rest,
you know,
and I don't,
I don't.
It doesn't need to be that way.
I don't want to support that kind of
culture.
That's rape culture to me.
How dare you.
That's why I liked those lexis trucks,
those.
I got that Lexus Infinity,
those are dope and they last forever to
not as good.
They look good.
I've had that.
Our hands.
I love Lexus.
The Lexus is a better truck.
I had a letter looking and then I got an
infinity and then I,
you see my new,
my new.
I haven't seen stope spatial inside.
Yeah,
I'll show you.
Oh,
they make awesome trucks,
man.
They may cost some trucks.
They also the lexus trucks,
they're actual real four wheel drive
truck because based off the Land Cruiser
Platform,
so they raise up.
They have a locking differentials.
Like if the shit hits the fan,
you could actually go off roading with a
Land Cruiser.
You can go off roading
with a Lexus Lx five 70.
It's the same car.
It's the same as a land cruiser,
but there's a lot of electronic shit
that the old ones didn't have.
The old ones that.
What people liked about them is you
could just drive those motherfuckers
through the desert,
take them over a mountain.
They just,
they're so durable,
you know,
and Jonathan Board what he does to them.
It makes them way more durable.
He puts polyurea coating over the entire
floor of the car,
like that shit is never rusting through
ever.
He puts these side,
these rock sliders on the side of him
that also act as side impact means
somebody hits you from the side.
He put solid steel bumpers on him.
American made bumpers,
these giant fucking bumpers with a
winch,
a worn winch to fucking pull you at
8,000
pound winch to pull you out of fucking
trouble.
He's got a jerry these jerry cans in the
back that carry water like these,
uh,
he puts these roof racks,
what we need for the ramp on the front.
That so that they don't rattle it speed.
When you're on the highway,
it's freedom ranch.
Let's call it the freedom.
Yes.
Somebody probably already took that in
Texas
and you know what we do?
We call him Tim Kennedy to be our
engineer for how to,
how to do the security perimeter and
what all we need in there and exactly to
survive.
He get bored while he wanted to stay.
Like,
I'll come visit you guys now and again,
I need adventure.
You have to fucking go off and do
something.
And was like,
let's go shoot pigs.
Ota a helicopter.
That's the big thing.
I'm like,
let's.
Is that what?
He doesn't do that.
He's crazy.
That's my next trip to Austin to go to
that.
Yeah.
Awesome.
Well,
that's the thing about Texas and we want
to have a ranch in Texas.
They're already exist and we have game
ranches and you can shoot all the pigs
you want.
Well,
not just pigs,
you could shoot.
They bring it,
all these African animals and so there's
no regulations on Africa that was like
a,
it was one of these high fence ranches
and they had a lot of that exotic game.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You know,
uh,
you want to jump over an airplane,
jump out of an airplane,
you know the dude from that MTV show
just die doing that.
I don't know who he is,
but my friend Andy Stumpf,
he,
uh,
he does.
He does,
he does wing suit shit.
Fuck him.
So he was a seal team six guy him and
fuck that.
And he's fucking,
he's wild.
You've got to have another show.
Would you wing suit it?
I wouldn't.
Wing suit,
like you got to know some shit.
I have never jumped out of an aircraft,
but he used to teach.
He taught my cousin who he went through
buds with Andy and Andy was an
instructor.
He lives in San Diego,
bring them up and him together.
I will.
And uh,
does he drink?
Oh,
I see.
Oh yeah,
I know he drinks.
Yeah,
he will.
Maybe he will enjoy some new way of or
Cerveza live,
but he's,
he does this shit to uh,
to um,
do the uh,
uh,
the navy seal foundation.
And so all the monies go to that.
He is trying to break forward.
I just give them a records and the
single jump.
Yeah,
they would love that.
I'll just give them money.
Yeah,
I don't wanna I don't want to jump in
and helicopters.
Oh,
I do.
I'm going to jump onto the plane with
them.
You know what's really thrilling?
Bowhunting.
Good enough.
That's good too.
But you know what dude?
So another friend of mine,
he
this Army Ranger and he's fucking,
he's retired.
He's gone from that.
He's and he's,
you know,
it's weird.
Retired and he's 26 or something,
but he started,
he started fucking around with the boat
when he got done.
And he's a real,
like he doesn't talk to anybody who's a
real soloist,
kinda likes to go sit in the woods by
himself.
And he started messing around with bows
and I go,
oh,
you shoot a compound bow or what are you
shooting?
He was,
no,
he makes his own,
of course.
And so we went to recurve right first.
Then he started making his own and I go,
why is that?
He goes,
well,
because it's like the other ones like
shooting a rifle.
He's like,
it's just,
there's nothing.
He says this.
And so he's like,
all he wants to be on horseback and
shoot him like he's a fucking trip.
And that,
those guys are a trip.
That's some different level shit.
When you talked to those guys that are
special operators like that,
like I'm listening to Andy and Andy's
talked and he's like,
he's talking about like,
oh there's a swat team guy with us
sending you.
And he's talking about his MP five.
And he's like,
why do you have that?
that's a fucking useless weapon.
Like I hit a guy eight times in the cast
with that across the room and he walked
into the other room.
I mean,
he laid down there,
but it's like,
he fucking like with the puck.
He's like,
well,
I just use it for,
for a sport,
for target practice because.
Oh,
that's okay.
Then he's like,
you really want to get it just right.
Just under the eyes and above the teeth.
You want to get in that area.
I'm like,
Holy Fuck,
what anybody says above the team,
person above the teeth.
Oh God,
amazing.
And you're like,
this is one of the kindest,
friendliest guy.
And then you hear and you're like,
holy fuck.
Some of the nicest people I know were
special operators.
So I talked to him too.
I'm like,
how come there's a.
He gave me a real insight into that,
about how come there's not,
I'm more like would withdraw from war
from guys that are special operators
than regular guys.
It's like everybody that has ptsd,
like there's a ton of it.
Um,
and he goes,
yeah,
there's not a lot in our community.
And I go,
why?
Why is that?
He goes,
well,
because if you're a regular guy on the
ground and you're you,
you can't engage,
you have to be reactive.
You have to be fired upon or whatever.
There's rules of engagement and he goes
for us,
we're predators and we're going out to
engage,
and so it's a different mindset.
You're,
you're in a place of either being
defensive or offensive and if you're
defensive,
you're pray in a way and you get to be
reactive to that,
but he's like world hunting and he's
like also by the time you get to that
level,
you're very dialed in about who you are
and what you're doing,
which is super interesting.
That does make sense.
He's like,
it's like because he talked to Tim and
Tim's like,
like,
that Shit's not present to him at all.
He's like,
yeah,
no,
I'm fucking.
When he was on the podcast,
we were talking about it.
He's like,
you know,
we're talking about people that are
throwing acid on girls that were going
to school.
He's like,
yeah,
I killed those guys.
Yeah.
Yeah,
and when you say it like that,
I'm right there with you.
Yup.
If I was there,
I get it.
I get it 100 percent.
And that's the,
that's the type of guys you want.
Fuck,
yes.
There's not a lot of those guys out
there.
I mean there's a reason why it's so
fucking hard
to become a navy seal.
There's a reason why it's so hard to be
a ranger.
It's,
it's not.
No,
that's the kind of shit like marcus
trail talks about.
He goes,
you've got to be,
you know,
if you get through,
but you've got to be willing to die,
you know?
Um,
you know,
my,
uh,
my cousin,
he just got,
he got,
he is in seal team two and he got a gun
fight and then he got shot up and he's
recovered now and I think he just
screened for seal team six and it's a
year after his injury,
but two of his friends died and in the
pool and they're in,
they're in training.
Yeah.
Then there's,
I mean it's completely controlled
environment and I was like,
what the fuck?
You know,
what?
A lot of that is my friend Eric.
Chris said when he was going through it,
they,
they make you drown and resuscitate you,
that it's part of the training that's
like the beginning of buds for
everybody,
but these guys are already active duty
combat seals.
And I started it and then like a few
weeks ago it dawned on me and I think
about like,
you know,
everybody's got safety and comfort.
Like here's where we live,
right?
And then like Greg Jackson always say,
you need to be comfortable where other
men are uncomfortable.
Like you need to raise your breaking
point to where it's unreachable for them
and,
and you can smash there's right.
And like,
so there's.
So there's safety comfort and then
there's death over here.
And so if you're pushing it and like a
combat arena,
like for me it's a certain thing,
but then you get more and more,
it becomes opaque where death and your
discomfort is and those guys are so used
to being uncomfortable.
And then the worst situations possible
that they probably can't see it.
So they're underwater and a pool and
they're doing whatever they're doing.
And they join,
it's just too late and they don't,
you know,
I think it's something like that
probably where they're so fucking tough.
Those guys that all,
they,
they erase all there there warning
flags,
whatever.
Our body puts up his warning like,
you need to stop this now or you're in
danger.
I think that it just goes away for those
guys.
They,
that shit doesn't exist for them anyway.
There's levels of people,
man.
Level levels.
There's levels of competency is levels
of excellence and there's levels of
toughness.
Yup.
And then there's people that put
themselves into situations.
You Go,
you know what man,
this to the average person,
you would go,
this is just not a smart place to be.
But to them it's,
it's home.
That's where they're at.
There is where they live.
You're like,
this is very uncomfortable for me.
I don't like.
There's a nerdist theater kicked up on
the couch.
They're like,
this is great.
My friend Cameron Hanes sent me a text
last night.
He's got awesome fucking water life.
You love that guy.
He's in Colorado right now.
Bow Hunting.
He bajans constantly.
What I love about you is,
hold on,
I'm say he was bow hunting,
uh,
two weeks ago with his friend Roy,
who we,
who got him into hunting,
this guy from Oregon who's his best
friend,
got him into hunting.
This guy's a guide up in Alaska and they
got a moose really difficult on during
the middle of the fucking snow storm and
it was six inches of snow.
They're trudging through.
They had to find these moves and they
finally got one and it was like this big
triumphant that moment for him.
He sent me a text yesterday that Roy
died yesterday,
fell off of a cliff wall,
sheep hunting,
700 foot drop and died.
And this is the guy that he was just
with.
And this is one of his best friends,
if not his best friend.
And he died the day before yesterday,
fell 700 feet.
And this is that.
That's what we're talking about.
It's like this.
Is there always that close to that?
I mean,
especially when you're sheep hunting
these rocky,
steep,
steep.
Yeah.
It's a nice travel,
real loose gravel and,
and cameron was supposed to be sheep
hunting with him on that trip,
but they had to call it off because the
snow was too dangerous.
It was so much snow.
It snowed for 10 days straight.
They couldn't get to these mountain
areas and if there's snow also and
you're trying to climb up these
mountains,
you don't know what the fuck you're
stepping on.
Your stepping on some blues rock
underneath that snow.
The snow.
That's cap that's coming in and you go
right through.
Right through and then you're fucked.
Yeah.
And uh,
he fell 700 feet to his death.
Crazy.
Yeah.
That's how.
How did,
how did cameron turned a corner to where
he was able to monetize his life to
live.
It's only recently he's been doing it
forever and he's been doing it forever.
He just hustled,
man.
Full time job.
Oh really?
It's a full time job.
He works for the Department of Water and
power and Oregon all day.
Nine hours.
And then he gets home.
He fucking runs.
He lists savage man.
He's it.
He's just tough as shit,
man.
Guy Does ultra marathon is anything.
Well,
he's just tough mental toughness.
Yeah.
That's like the main strength.
That guy has incredible mental
toughness.
He's like a brother and a lot of ways
with the endurance aspect of it.
Yeah,
that kind of thing.
Just gritty determination.
Just hard work,
man.
It's cool.
It works hard.
Cool too because he's not in a.
it's,
you know like if you're a fighter,
you're a football player,
you're in the army or that gets directed
in a way for you,
but that's a real soloist thing that he
does and there's a lot of guys that
hump,
but there's not a lot of guys that are
like that guy who's like,
I'm going to go ahead and strap fucking
bunch of plates on my back and run up
the mountain this morning.
Or there's not a lot of guys that
trained to hunt like he trains to be an
apex
or when you hunt with them,
you realize that like he and I were
hunting in Colorado a couple of weeks
ago and we went up this hill and this
fucking dude runs hill.
So often I'm in pretty good shape.
I'm falling behind.
I'm fucking huffing.
Yeah,
I mean we're,
we're,
I mean,
I'm trying to keep up with them,
but I'm breathing heavy.
I got to the top with him.
I'm like,
he's not even breathing right.
I mean,
he's not even fucking breathe in.
I mean he's,
he's fine.
He's like,
he could have a conversation with you.
Whereas I'm like,
man,
that's fucking Steve.
Steve.
Like,
I'm like,
this is the difference between a guy who
runs hills and a guy who doesn't.
He,
he prepares for that specific
environmental constantly running hills,
constantly lifting weights,
all that.
And you know,
people criticize them.
You don't need to do that stuff.
You don't need to do that stuff because
they don't want to do it and they don't
like that someone is doing it right.
But that fucking guy killed several bull
elk every year.
Kills Moose.
Every time he goes out,
he's killing something and that's all he
eats.
He high protein,
organic meat constantly and he's
inspirational.
That's what I love about a man,
that guy.
I've run into so many people that are
inspired by that guy and he forces them
by just watching him.
It forces them to get off their ass and
go do stuff and go,
go lift weights,
go work out.
I mean a guy like that you had to go and
if I do 15 percent of what he does,
I'm winning and he works all day,
you know,
I didn't.
I thought for sure that was his full
time shit.
Yeah.
You mentioned way more from bowhunting
that he does from his work.
Crazy.
But it keeps the job he doesn't want to
anymore.
I get a pension or something at the end
of those.
He's got kids and insurance and all that
shit and that is a ton of kids to wife
kids.
Whole deal.
Yeah.
Good.
Speaking of which,
I gotta get the Fuck Outta here.
Tait Fletcher.
We've got a days more often.
Dude,
why don't we do this so it's fun.
Yeah.
I love it man.
Take motherfucking Fletcher on
instagram.
That's tea.
I T I don't know who the fuck.
T a t is.
Not me telling them to kick rocks.
I'm new all Cerveza,
caveman coffee,
CEO.com.
This shit right here.
Caveman nitro.
This is the shit we got our new
packaging for our concentrate.
Delicious.
All that.
Goodness.
This stuff right here.
This is my all time favorite.
I know.
Real well.
It's fucking goes through it.
That little cunt.
I'm going to bring them some.
We got.
We got pallets and pallets inside La
Right now.
Jamie just got all salivating.
Alright Ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you much.
Love.
See you soon.
Bye.