I tried to explain to my low that you
can't wear sunglasses indoors unless
you're black.
And he put them right back on.
You almost took them off,
but you put them back on in spite.
Well,
I said,
I've got plenty of black gay man.
You should mind your own business.
You have had plenty of very difficult,
very difficult,
especially with that jacket on.
Oh,
you like it.
It's adorable.
Thank you.
I don't know.
I like to,
like I said,
military it up a little bit.
Sometimes you want me to take them off?
You do that.
Please explain to the people listening
what exactly this jacket is because some
folks are not watching.
Obviously I've lots of friends in the
military.
It's the best I'm forces in the world.
Merck should be very happy about it.
Um,
it's occasionally,
you know,
he wandered into the commissary and
just,
you know,
pick up a few little few little items
and adjusted of course,
because,
you know,
she's tufts very boxy,
very boxy.
So I took it to a nice Taylor in,
um,
in Beverly Hills,
you know,
had the,
had the sleeves pulled down.
It's very nice.
It's like some sort of a navy jacket or
something.
Like what is that exactly?
It's an army dress jacket actually.
But this was an air force place.
Is that a military appropriation and
you're allowed to,
is that the stolen valor?
Are you allowed to other no,
no,
no.
It's any stolen valor.
If you're like misrepresenting their,
remember though I forces and you know,
if I had like batches on or something,
then that would be bad.
I like to think of this more of a,
as a source of fashionable amash.
It's a respectful gesture.
Ah,
Nice.
Yeah.
Those stolen valor dudes are very odd
when they get caught.
We've seen a lot of those videos.
That's a disturbing little mental
illness to pretend to be a war hero.
It is.
And you know what's interesting,
they always get caught out because
they're sort of very clever but not very
clever.
So what they'll do is they will think
that they've got all the badges right
and they'll kind of like,
they'll have a friend who sort of lets
them into the commissary so they can go
and pick up these badges.
Like,
pretend that part of the tank unit or
whatever,
and they'll,
but they'll get something slightly wrong
because they're not serving and they
don't have a superior officer.
It'd be like,
that's,
you know,
they're just,
they're just getting the middle of
something wrong.
And of course,
for all of their weird autistic
obsessions about the,
uh,
getting,
getting all of the uniform stuff
perfect.
There are people out there on the
Internet who are vets who know the
difference.
And so they were these amazing wars.
There's a,
there's a name for them in Britain.
We called them waltz.
Like Walter Mitty is,
who's Walter Mitty.
Uh,
Walter Mitty is,
I know that name.
Yeah.
It was the most recently there was a
movie,
I think it was,
was it Matt Damon?
Um,
yeah.
Anyway,
it's,
it's a,
there's just,
it's,
it's become,
it's a novel on a novel and a movie in,
it's become just a name in culture for
people who pretend to be somebody else.
The secret life of Walter Mitty.
Oh,
that's right.
Yeah.
So in the army,
they call them walt's people who pretend
to be vets or pretending to be sort of
service officer serving personnel who
are not is a very bizarre mental
illness.
Eds.
It is.
Yeah.
It's so uncomfortable watching them get
called out to,
oh,
there was one guy that I love it.
These marines cornered them and they
started asking him questions and start
falling apart.
Like,
Woo.
Yeah,
no,
it's so awkward and clingy,
but I live for those moments in life.
They are fun.
If,
so speaking of awkward and Cringey,
what the fuck is going on with your
country,
man?
Well,
I'm so happy for the first time.
No,
I've never,
I mean,
you know,
Michelle Obama said something terrible.
She's like,
I was proud of my country the first for
the first time or something like that.
You know,
about something trivial and ridiculous,
which I found distressing.
And I don't want to say that because
it's not true,
but I did suddenly think there might be
hope for your,
after all,
there might be hope,
particularly for the best country in
Europe,
which is England,
uh,
and the best sort of nation in Europe,
you know,
the United Kingdom finally unshackled
from this hellish,
um,
this hellish continent on a suicide
mission into is the migration and a
economic doom.
Finally,
the UK has got a chance to prove that
it's better than all that and it can
reopen,
you know,
better trade relationships with Asia,
with India,
with America can re,
you know,
reassess,
renegotiate its relationship with all
the countries around it.
The European project for me,
I mean I know a lot of Americans have
sort of believed what they've read about
the coverage,
you know,
from,
from the media on this.
But I'm definitely in the Brexit camp.
I think it's fantastic and not just
economically,
um,
cause I think things will bounce back
and Britain will be better than ever,
but,
but culturally and it's readable.
It's what's so essential.
Britain has a slightly different
national characters.
The rest of you,
it's never really fit.
And I think Britain now has an
opportunity to save itself from the
suicidal open borders policies of Angela
Merkel from the inevitable decline and
fall of Europe is a continent.
Generally Britain's got a chance now and
it didn't have a chance as part of
Europe.
And Merkel is the one who when those
attacks were going on in Germany during,
uh,
New Year's Eve,
where the Islamic guys are grabbing all
those girls,
her advice was for them to dress
differently than stay within arm's
length.
I mean,
in feminism we call this victim blaming
when you tell people that they did
something that contributed toward their
rape.
Uh,
but of course in the hierarchy of
oppression and victim hood,
according to progressive's,
Muslims rank higher than women.
Muslims rank higher than anybody else.
In fact,
nobody knows why.
Well,
it's because of the wars.
it's definitely right.
It's because they hate the west as much
as feminists too.
And so you think it has something to do
with the fact that we invaded Iraq and
Afghanistan and people feel a little bit
guilty about the fact that a million
people have died?
Well,
white guilt has driven all of the worst
things that have happened in Weston.
Oh,
all of them.
All the worst things that have happened
in western culture in the last 30 years
have all been driven by white guilt,
feminism,
black lives matter the whole lot.
Uh,
you know,
these,
these are not good reasons.
Feminism is driven by white guilt.
Of course.
Look,
I've a theory about this.
It's very straight forward.
In the nineties we had Marilyn Manson,
we had Trent Reznor,
we had a nirvana and people were cutting
themselves.
You know,
there was a,
the emo thing,
and when I was growing,
I mean I didn't obviously,
but when people were growing up,
they had an outlet for all of that sort
of repressed rage and self loathing.
Well,
kids these days don't have that.
And the inevitable result of social
justice.
What they do instead is they sort of
hang on to this as a protracted self.
Hatred is protracted,
self harm,
social justice.
They go out into the world and hurt
people who look like them.
So these awful,
you know,
middle class white feminist women just
want to hurt other
middle class white people because they
feel like,
you know,
the world is terrible.
Uh,
you know,
it's a very weird phenomenon,
this social justice thing and I think
it's mainly driven by self loathing and
um,
once you understand that their behavior
becomes a lot more,
it makes a lot more sense.
You know,
you start to understand why they are as
they are.
I think a lot of heat is definitely and
self-loathing and it,
there's,
there's an opportunity today that they
have that they never had before to
organize and find likeminded folks and
get together and form of the crazy
people,
fully gangs.
Yes,
they all do it again,
but they bully gangs and you know you,
when you start to understand that this
is a sort of psychosis,
when you start to understand this is a
sort of like mental illness,
this is something that they should have
got out of the systems when they were
teens,
but they didn't because they had no
culture to help them.
They know I grew up on Marilyn Manson
and Nirvana.
These kids grow up on like Selena Gomez
and Justin Bieber and that sort of like
flat anodyne eternally fundless grinning
garbage.
They don't ever get it out of their
systems and now you have 35 year old
bitter bastards working for buzzfeed.
You still,
it's got to go somewhere and where does
it go?
It goes into social justice and this is
what's happened.
Don't you think that there's a
percentage of them?
Some of them genuinely feel like this is
a unique opportunity to write some of
the wrongs,
that our culture is sort of encouraged.
What is our culture or intimate sexism,
racism.
Nobody says there's no sexism and no
racism in this,
in this country either.
Even in this country.
No serious person says that.
Nobody really believes that I'm
squeaking in my chair.
That wasn't anything else.
Nobody really believes that.
Nobody,
nobody says it.
Look,
we live in,
you know where you live.
I'm hoping that if at one day,
but you know you live in the greatest
country in the world.
It is a country driven by democracy,
freedom,
property rights,
capitalism and all of those western
values.
The values on which,
you know,
freedom of speech and the second
amendment to all of those things that
went into building America and making
America wonderful are exactly the same
things that are responsible for women
having the vote,
having access to the same opportunity,
the same opportunity,
the same access to institutions,
to education,
to the workplace,
having equal pay,
which of course they do.
You know it giving gay people rights.
Look at the places in the world where
gay people have rights.
They are modern,
western liberal capitalist,
capitalist democracies or the left hates
all of those things and hates the West
for precisely that,
you know,
for size of the reasons that the West
has been nice to them.
You know,
and frankly they don't go after this
assist hat,
white patriarchy.
Well the patriarchy,
you know the western capitalist
Patriarchy is the only people that like
you,
the only people who like the gaze,
the only people who like,
you know,
blacks and women,
all the rest of it go anywhere else in
the world and it is not a particularly
pretty situation,
not a particularly happy place to be if
you're not born into the right group.
If you're in America,
you can pretty much do say and be
whatever you want.
Now,
there are threats to that and I,
my college tourist is hoping to sort of
head off some of those,
those threats brewing in American
universities,
but these,
what are these people really hating on?
They live in the best country,
the most equal country,
the greatest country,
the country with the most liberal values
anywhere on the planet and they're still
not happy.
We'll fine.
That's okay.
There are obviously things left to fix.
No one's saying there's no sexism,
no racism.
But why are they so silent when they see
these horrific things happen elsewhere
in the world end when I'm left wing,
politicians decide they want to bring
those horrific things into our
countries.
You're Justin Trudeau wants to bring all
of these,
you know Syrian,
they're not refugees.
Of course they're migrants.
You know Angela Merkel in Germany,
you're talking about moment ago.
She,
you know,
opened the borders.
Are there 2 million Syrians in Germany?
Nobody really knows.
We know it's at least 1.21
point 4 million fundamentally altering
the fabric of Germany and importing with
it,
bringing him with it.
Did we have a crash?
Are we still recording audio?
Okay,
what happens?
We're just going to reboot.
So if you're watching this on youtube,
you're not watching this,
you're not seeing anything.
You're not seeing anything from Ed map.
People are right now.
Do you know what it is?
Cause really minded folks.
Cause we said feminism and Islam and
Merkel on together,
they came in European Union,
they came in,
they sat in union,
they sent a bomb through the pipes.
We've got,
we've got the stuxnet is in,
is in here.
Yeah.
I mean I don't think anybody is saying
that there's no racism and no one's
saying there's no sex and we agree on
that.
But don't you think that the,
the,
some that there is,
should be combated in some sort of a way
we'll show,
but that's takes,
takes care of itself pretty much.
I mean that when was the last time
somebody said it's like a genuinely
sexist are genuinely racist remark in a
friend group you were out and say in the
bar with and didn't get corrected by
people?
Well,
my friends who would all be joking,
but a lot of everybody,
I mean how many,
how many white supremacists to do you
really think,
oh,
in America compared to black
supremacist,
how many genuinely misogynistic women,
women hating men?
Do you think there are in America
compared to the women,
the young women that third wave feminism
has bread or the third wave feminism
though is organized,
whereas the misogynist men,
most of the time they're isolated living
in cabins in the woods and shit.
We have to speculate because we never
meet any because we don't know any,
I don't know any,
I've never met one,
but I've met plenty of man hating
lesbian monsters who would be perfectly
happy to see men rounded up in camps.
I've never met her real misogynist.
And I,
and I try.
I try.
I try,
but I mean,
wouldn't they be my fans if they
existed?
I mean,
you know,
I'm always being accused of providing
cover for these people,
but I've never found any,
well,
that doesn't mean they're not there.
I mean,
you're dealing with people.
What about the people that murder women?
I mean those are real people.
Well,
the right rates of in this country been
going down for 30 years.
They have been going down one.
Right.
But it's fantastic.
But they still get,
they still happen.
But you're never going to get rid of
that.
Right?
That is something,
no,
no.
You cannot like language police your way
out of bigotry.
No one's saying Kevin,
which please don't you think culturally
we've evolved past where we were a
thousand years ago.
We all agree on that,
right?
Sure.
But you don't have to think of how we're
going to eradicate rape.
That's not going to have her.
No,
no.
Really.
Of course not.
That's insane.
Well,
one thing,
once we get to the point where we could
read each other's minds,
we have some sort of a embedded chip
that allows us to,
how can you imagine anything worse than
that?
It's going to happen.
Anything less than that?
I think we're kind of halfway there.
Each other's minds.
I don't even know how to read my own
mind.
My God,
don't you know?
I know and actually it's,
it's actually,
you know,
look this,
this masculine energy,
you know that everybody in this room has
inside of it.
Like when you say that with your hands
open,
like a jazz dancer,
you're
blonde tailored army jacket.
This masculine energy can not be
contained.
Listen,
Joe,
this masculine energy as like just
waiting to bust that.
Okay.
It's an explosion.
It can't be contained as a fuck you.
I'll try that again.
This masculine.
Maybe you could coach me through it.
Okay.
It's so hard,
but you've got sparkly dog tags on.
They collect.
Oh,
sorry.
That's such a nice time last time having
a nice time.
This stuff.
Wait,
we are having over time.
Uh,
I can see this which way?
This three hours is getting ready.
Just,
just roast to Milo time.
That's fine.
Bring it a friendly my friend.
Actually my hair,
my hair was since you bring it up,
it's not as nice as last time I had,
I had a lovely looks great.
No,
it's okay.
Um,
all right.
Uh,
there is,
there is a masculine instinct and
impulse to create,
you know,
to destroy,
to be,
you know,
to do certain things to competitiveness
driven by hormones,
you know,
to the testosterone instinct.
You know,
um,
and Camille Pauley was talking about
this in the 90s,
you know,
it's got to go somewhere and you look at
the,
I'm not suggesting that the men are just
going to rape me when you have to deal
with it.
What I'm,
what I'm saying though is it,
if you bully men out of the public
square and you sort of demonize and
ridicule and,
and almost make it legal,
uh,
healthy,
normal male behaviors,
which is happening in schools and
colleges for sure.
And it's also happening in the public
square.
If you make it okay to say almost
anything about men,
if you,
um,
sort of bully man out of the public,
out of public life,
a bad things happen.
You know,
and people have that that has to come
out somewhere and on to your point,
fortunately we do live in a,
in,
in evolved enough times where most of
the time it's just men letting off steam
on the Internet and comment sections.
I think,
uh,
but you knew that that dark,
what I say dog,
that,
that sort of dangerous energy that is in
all men,
which is what women like him out,
man.
It's certainly what meant like about men
in my case.
Um,
you know,
root of all the best sex.
The reason we went to the stars that be
built civilizations,
you know,
um,
the stuff that makes men awesome.
Does have a flip side to it and it's,
you know,
it can be dangerous,
men can be dangerous,
but it also can be managed of course.
But it can't be managed if you lie about
it.
It can't manage the,
if you pretend that you can talk your
way out of it and it can't be in
particular.
And most importantly,
women can't protect themselves from it
if they are lied to about it.
And this sort of,
you know,
masculinity.
So fragile managers socialized to be
violent.
They're not just socialized to be fine.
You know,
this is a hormone thing.
Men just all more aggressive.
You know.
And if you,
I mean is for instance in colleges,
right?
If you,
if you tell women that the worst things
ever going to happen to them,
if somebody's putting a hand on their,
on their leg,
and you call that sexual assault and you
put that in the sexual assault
statistics and you know,
you tell women,
oh,
you can wear whatever you want and you
can go out at 3:00
AM wearing a miniskirt and no man has a
right to look at you.
And you know,
you know,
no victim blaming all the rest of it.
You're telling women in fact that they
can put themselves in danger and um,
bad things are going to happen to those
women.
We do live in most of those times,
but we also have to recognize that there
is something,
there is something dark and dangerous
about men and it is what creates,
it's what it is,
what has driven human civilization to
the heights that it has arisen to.
But it is also why men for most of the
prisons,
right?
The sublime geniuses and the knuckle
dragging apes of our species are both
male.
Right?
And that's,
and you can see that in a variety
different things.
People don't take it very seriously.
But you can see for instance,
in Iq distribution,
one of the suggestions that might be the
case,
you know,
sublime musical and artistic geniuses up
in the very top end of the Iq scale
where women tend not to exist.
Likewise,
you know,
down in the knuckle draggers,
70 and 80 Iq,
women tend not to exist down there
either.
Men are more variable than women in
general.
Men are more complex I think,
than women in some ways.
And this,
you know,
there's the idea that you can just sort
of buzzfeed your way out of rape and
civilization is just insane.
Buzzfeed your way out.
You know,
if you,
if you just,
if you publish enough listicles about
how masculinity is so fragile and white,
you know,
straight white men are the root of all
evil,
that that's somehow going to stop rape.
No,
in fact,
I think that's probably
counterproductive.
I think that's probably going to think,
going to push some men too,
but you know,
boil over because they're sick of being
lied to and lied about.
But the good news is rape has been going
down for 30 years.
American college campuses are probably
the safest place you could possibly be
as a,
as a young woman in America today,
despite what the left tells you,
the lies it tells you about.
Um,
uh,
you know,
about all sorts of things we're in,
we're in a good place,
but the left won't say that or
acknowledged victory because I'll put
them all out of business.
Well,
there's a strange thing with masculinity
where it,
there's,
there's ways to manage it.
And one of the best ways to manage it is
martial arts.
And it's one of the things that's at
least encouraged,
uh,
with,
with children and with young men.
And I think it's,
it's,
it's critically important to exercise
that demon out of your system,
get that aggression out,
whether it's through some form of
sports,
but there's obviously problems with
that.
One of the big ones being cte,
that's the same thing with the footage.
CTE.
It's chronic brain injury,
chronic traumatic encephalopathy.
I have to be beating each other in the
head.
You could just,
you know,
you could do athletics,
you could do something,
you know,
but,
but my point being one of those,
the,
one of the reasons that martial arts are
such a good
vehicle is because it calms down one of
the main issues with men and aggressive
behavior,
which is insecurity.
Insecurity leads to a lot more
aggressive behavior.
When men are more secure,
they're less likely to engage in
ridiculous behavior.
Right.
And what is the one product you okay?
Yeah,
I'm sorry.
It's the fucking butter coffee.
Oh.
Um,
one of the,
I don't want you to die.
I don't want this to be your last
episode from the gym.
I'm healthy as fuck.
Don't worry.
You look wonderful.
Thank you very much.
Bigger than last time you've been
bulking out.
I've been lifting weights.
Pump it up.
We should talk about this.
I just had to train him.
Did you really?
I lost and nobody will know this because
I was such expensive clothes,
but I,
I lost 40 pounds in four and a half
months.
What'd you do?
That's amazing.
Just not your face.
Looks very thin.
Yeah.
Like from last summer was I saw you in
October.
Right.
You know,
look at this done by July 1st compton.
Uh,
and I lost like four inches off my waist
and like four and a half months.
Just being disciplined,
making sure you worked out well.
It really just diet and now I'm working
on,
you know,
brushing it.
Cut Sugar out.
Yeah.
That's the big one.
Everything really.
Yeah.
Just,
I was just used to just protein and
leaves really rude.
Um,
yeah.
You get blood work done.
Um,
no.
Uh,
I haven't,
but I'm,
I do it like twice a year if like
insurance and everything is like off the
charts healthy.
But to uh,
go,
go to a really good,
uh,
some doctor that understands nutrient
levels and the mechanisms for absorption
and tell.
He can tell you like what you're doing
wrong,
what you're doing right.
What you need to add.
I just heard something,
I'm on a battery of,
of supplements now because I've just
started wanting to lifting program.
I've got the,
we call them crazy pills cause I can
never remember the long names for
things.
You'd know what they all are just these,
you know,
these things for Gaba,
things,
things for Mitochondria,
things for testosterone,
all sorts.
Yeah.
But it's like when you have you back
next year,
I'm going to be,
well,
I want to do,
I want to,
I want to go to Yale this year and to
give a talk on cultural appropriation,
which you mentioned earlier and you want
to do it in a skin tight leotard.
No,
that's a different date.
I want to do in full native American
costume.
Oh,
I want my tits out,
so I understand.
Yeah.
So yeah.
Is that cultural appropriation?
That's a weird,
weird,
yeah.
It's just a line.
The left tells you to,
to try to control you to prep two I met
you feel racist.
Tamiflu and secure.
Well,
you say the left some people that are
very insecure,
they want to do that and like that,
that one small boy who got attacked by
that girl in school and she was
threatening to cut his hair because he
had,
because he had dreadlocks.
He look really good with them.
He looked better than he would've looked
without the dreadlocks.
He did.
No,
I'm serious.
Yeah.
No,
I'm sitting there,
listen,
it's not,
the problem with that is of course,
you know,
dreadlocks or not an African American
thing.
I mean,
but this is precisely why the Greeks,
the Romans,
I mean,
they go on forever.
This is what I'm going to say to them.
This is precisely my point.
You know,
cultural appropriation isn't this sort
of like weird racism that ends in like
1950 or whatever the left thing.
It's how artworks,
it's cultural appropriation from history
include Picasso Volkner,
you know,
you're just,
you're gonna,
you're gonna are you gonna Start Saying,
oh,
wagner shouldn't have been a,
you know,
drawing from the norse Eder and from,
from the Neba lung and lead and all of
these sort of norse myths that he use to
craft their,
bring this knee belonging because that's
cultural appropriate.
These people are insane.
They've never read a book,
they've never read a book.
They don't understand how history and
artwork.
And it's so frustrating to see
impressionable young,
smart people start to soak this stuff up
because they just never hear the
alternatives,
which is what my college tours for
because I,
I,
it's just shocks me.
It's horrifying.
It's just based on such a,
uh,
his such historical ignorance.
What's a target of recreational outrage?
There's,
yes,
it is.
Yeah.
And it is recreation.
We,
right,
but they've found an area like that
woman who was picking on that boy with
the dreadlocks.
It was very cool girl and boy,
whatever.
It's very clear that she was a bully and
he was a small,
tiny,
feeble little guy and she was fucking
with them for the sres.
Yes,
she was.
And,
and you know this is this the self
loathing thing,
which so often turns into bullying and
when you hear you do you know about her
background as well,
right?
She grew up in foster care.
She had a very horrible child.
Damaged as all hell.
Yeah,
man.
She wants to,
she wants the rest of the to suffer like
she thinks she's suffered.
Maybe she did suffer,
but this is probably,
she probably did and I'm sorry about
that.
But no,
to cultural appropriation,
like having a go at somebody for wearing
dreadlocks is not the way to get over
your damage.
The way to get out of your damages
therapy and drugs,
you know,
just just to deal with yourself.
It's a,
it's just sad that this is something
that has become a thing and it's a
repeating thing when I'm going to cut it
off at the root because it's a nonsense.
It's garbage.
I don't know if you're capable
completely on your own of cutting it
off,
but oh,
I'm going to salute you and your
attitude.
I'm going to do it.
I'm going to do it just with that Indian
outfit.
Oh No,
no,
no.
I've got,
I've got a huge variety,
a variety of outfits planned for this
year.
I'm going to wear everything.
Everything the left finds offensive.
What is the most offensive native
American stuff?
It's usually the people that were the
most maligned crest,
I think native cause it's Yale and
they're very hypersensitive.
Can it,
cause the smart kids aren't violent.
Like some of them have been.
The smart kids are just like,
just lose their minds,
you know,
and just start like spurting out.
Um,
so I think the native American stuff
annoys in the most because they know
it's because they know the cultural
appropriation element of it is such
rubbish.
And if they actually cared,
they would quit.
They would quit the college that is like
on a,
on a burial ground or something,
you know,
whatever the hell Yale is built on.
Um,
I think it's because they know it's so
absurd.
And insane.
Of course they're even more upset about
it because the stakes are so low.
Um,
I think native Americans going to be
good.
I'm not sure if I can do black face.
I have to ask my editor about that.
You can and you must.
I can.
Why can't you,
Dave Chappelle did white face on TV.
I mean,
I think I can.
Why not if I can.
And so did Mariah Carey's ex husband,
did he the pretty one?
Nick,
uh,
nick cannon.
Nick Cannon did take place.
Yeah,
he did.
I think it's fine,
but I know that it's impossible to be
racist against white people.
Don't,
you know,
I'm not the most adorable thing that
people have created to try to justify
black racism against white people.
That it is not possible.
You know what it is and it's,
and it's this amazing combination of,
of,
of ignorance and condescension because
they're stupid and they'd never read a
history book and they don't understand
how bigotry or hatred works or,
or any,
any kind of historical function or any
psyche,
psychological process whatsoever.
And at the same time they're trying to
explain to you how you actually don't
know what racism means.
You see,
racism isn't just,
you know,
thinking another racism as good as
yours.
Racism is actually a complex system of
prejudice.
Oppression.
You only have to,
it can only be done if you have power
and why people have power.
Black people don't have any power.
That's,
it's not like there's a black president.
That's weird because at my college
talkers,
black people forcing me off stage while
the university administration told
Chicago peanut pd not to intervene.
I mean,
what are you,
is this,
well this is at Depaul,
a Catholic University,
which has some of the most enthusiastic
abortion advocates on campus anywhere in
America.
I heard,
and I don't know if this is true that
this took a port.
No,
they do.
It's so one of the most left wing places
in the world.
It does have to funny expression,
enthusiastic abortion advocates.
Are you kidding me?
No,
I'm not joking.
I'm,
this is,
this isn't just me.
They go like,
you know,
is it Lindy West that guardian nuggets,
she's like,
you know,
shout your abortion was that it was a
feminist Hashtag it trended.
They're proud of it.
They're proud of murdering babies.
They are perfectly happy to talk about
it.
They think it's a mark of pride like I'm
is,
I don't make this stuff up.
I just laugh along with everybody else.
You know,
I didn't invent this.
They love the portions.
It's like,
it's like a badge of honor.
It's like scout badges,
you know,
like how many of you had sister,
I'm a serious,
these people are insane.
I'm,
I'm a favor of abortion.
As long as you can't tell what it looks
like Monday be your charge to shock me
and am on unshockable as soon as it
starts looking at,
I mean I'm never,
I'm not,
not a person that would ever step in and
say you can and can't do anything with
your body as long as the baby's in the
woman's body.
Technically we differ on that one from
that one.
Somebody else.
Well,
I'm,
do you think there's a different,
I'm hardline on,
cause you can't tell anybody what they
can and can't do with their body.
Well,
it isn't just about the woman's body.
Once she becomes pregnant,
she's responsible for another body,
another soul,
another human being.
And let's don't get into the soul thing
cause we had a very,
a very unproductive conversation about
that last time.
But,
but just,
you know,
this is another human being and that
woman has sole custody if you like.
And,
and so you can trust or of cells,
if it's like literally four or five
cells get sucked out,
stop it.
Stop it.
You're just,
look as a gay person,
I have to be against abortion because as
soon as they start working out what the
gay gene,
whatever is it,
you know,
instead of going to get chopped because
nobody wants a gay kid.
If you've got the choice.
Okay.
If from Sally cone,
the stupid in America,
early colon,
Sally Cone Cone,
k,
O,
h n is a lesbian Jewish lesbian feminist
on CNN.
She's the stupidest woman in America.
Really?
She's the one.
Yeah,
no,
no.
She had up against stiff competition.
She is the stupid zone.
And America,
she's the one who said after Orlando,
um,
no,
I'm serious.
She is,
she's the one after Orlando who said,
Oh,
you know what actually like,
you know,
um,
conservative Christians,
you know,
treat,
treat us way worse than,
you know,
any of my moderate Muslim friends and
all this.
She doesn't,
she just used a Muslim who had been
trained in the,
you know,
it had been indoctrinated in,
in this mosque in the north of Orlando.
What does it in Sanford and Orlando by
this guy who would,
um,
who,
who had been there three weeks before
and he was on the record as saying,
the compassionate thing to do was to
murder all homosexuals.
You know,
this is what happening in Orlando.
This guy growing up in that environment
went out,
murdered 49 gay people and maimed
another 50,
and she's upset about people who won't
bake cakes.
I mean,
does she,
is the stupidest woman in America
Anyway,
um,
what we're talking about,
I don't even remember.
No.
Cultural appropriation.
Abortion.
Yes.
The Gauging Sal Khan.
There we go.
Uh,
no,
she,
um,
she famously,
well not famously because she's not
famous because she's,
she's just a source of amusement on
twitter.
But,
uh,
she,
she's on CNN weirdly.
Uh,
she said she'd like a gay kid.
She specifically wants a gay child,
which I thought was just sort of weird
and I just want a healthy kid.
Well,
why not just want a child or want,
you know,
a smart,
athletic,
beautiful,
popular kid.
No,
she wants a gay one.
Why?
Because she's a narcissist.
She doesn't care about anything.
It's going to happen to that child and
it's lifetime.
Any of the unhappy things that might
happen to that child.
And I'm not talking about bigotry or
whatever.
Let's say we cure homophobia.
Great,
but I'm having sex with somebody and
cannot create a child with a person I
love.
And the,
in the act of intercourse,
like that's kind of kind of rough
frankly.
You know,
it's not great and a lot of people don't
go through their lives thinking about
that.
But I've have that has occurred to me in
the past.
You know,
there are many reasons why you might not
choose to be gay,
all else being equal.
And you know,
she's just a sort of narcissistic,
sociopath and Weirdo.
But most people,
I think,
you know,
if,
if we believe the gay lobby,
which lies and says people,
gays are born this way,
which of course is rubbish,
uh,
if we believe them and we find,
and if scientists come,
I mean maybe,
maybe they're right.
If they are right and scientists come up
with this,
this gay gene,
well was the first group of people to
go,
it's me anyway.
I don't,
I,
you're,
there's a lot of shit going on in these
conversations.
These sentences,
they go one way and another way.
Yeah.
That's how my brain works.
I'm sorry.
We were talking about,
we were actually talking about being
born gay is a real thing.
He said that's what it's obvious.
No,
it's obviously a mixture.
It's obviously a mixture of nature or
nurture.
But the gay lobby lies and says it's
all,
well,
they did this and the ats that the
reason they did it as I'm in the
eighties and nineties,
because the religious right,
we're saying,
um,
that being gay was a bad moral choice.
It was a bad lifestyle choice,
right?
Remember the expression and uh,
of course,
Christian Christians would say,
hate the sin,
love the sinner and all the rest of it.
And there was this problem because gay
people or gay,
the gay lobby,
by their logic there,
right?
What can we do with this?
Aha?
What if we're like blacks or what if we
like women?
What if this is just what we are?
Because that makes them bigots.
So they invented this born this way
thing.
And the truth is that nobody knows.
Well,
did you ever see the study that was
done,
I believe is out of the University of
Rome with a,
they found a direct correlation between
very promiscuous mothers and gay
children,
right?
Well,
there's some,
there's some people who think that
things like that,
uh,
might have dual effects.
There could be genetic or even epogen or
epigenetic.
If you buy into that stuff can be
epigenetic factors in the room and
hormonal stuff that,
uh,
that comes about as a result of a woman
having a high sex drive that might
result in a gate kid,
but also when the kid is born.
If the mom's still a whore,
then maybe I'm just saying,
right.
Um,
you know,
if,
if Mommy's putting,
if Mommy's,
you know,
spreading her legs all over town,
uh,
could that affect a child's sexual
development?
Of course.
So that,
that one,
I do remember that one though.
I didn't read it closely.
I do remember that one.
And I think that what I came away from
that with was if you have,
um,
if you have a hoe for a mom,
there's probably multiple reasons you
might end up gay,
but they're there.
They didn't go that far with it because
when you start accusing that mean
you're,
you're making these,
I mean,
I think you're probably on point with
it,
right?
But that's not something a university
would ever say.
No because they're idiots because they
don't actually want to get to the truth.
They want to virtue signal.
Well,
there's a little bit of that,
but it's all,
it's also one of those things where it's
just really problematic.
Would you can't,
you can say that and ironically then
yeah,
you can't prove it.
When you say tell the truth about their
sex lives is like expecting fat.
People tell the truth about the
calorific intake,
it just doesn't happen.
Well they believe that somehow or
another it was some sort of a variation
on the x chromosome that made these
women right,
not just psychologically attracted to
men,
but that there was obviously there's
some sort of a physical attraction that
heterosexual women have towards men and
that should vary and it will vary on a
wide scale and the extreme end of the
scale.
They believe this just these women that
are just almost like you roll a dick in
front of them,
they're like a kitten on a ball of yarn.
They just can't help know how they feel
and that these women will pass this
trait on even to their male children.
Interesting.
See my mother's quite frigid.
So it just goes to show the,
the,
the etiology of homosexuality is,
you know,
multiple is,
is varied and complex.
Anyway,
that might be the only point I'm making
is simply every credible sciences,
every reasonable person knows that it is
almost certainly a mixture of nature and
nurture and that that mix can change
from person to person.
Right?
All of these things can get mixed up and
ended up with somebody choosing to fuck
a guy or not fucking guy.
Right?
Right.
But the,
the gay lobby,
because they were scared at the,
you know,
and because they wanted an easy answer,
I came up with this,
you know,
whatever.
Now it's embedded in culture.
Lady Gaga born this way and it's a lie.
I mean,
it's a lie saying that,
saying that if something is like not
black and white and it's like probably,
actually it probably about 50 50 saying
it's entirely black is a lie.
And that's a lie.
And the gape gay lobby lies to gay
people and that's partially born this
way.
Doesn't make a good song,
partially partially born this way.
Sounds like something you'd see on a
planned parenthood for me as like
something that David Daleiden has
exposed in his,
uh,
in his undercover videos.
Uh,
I on returning to the abortion thing,
I don't,
what don't you think that it's like many
things like even homosexuality we were
talking about,
there's a lot going on there to discuss
and when you're talking about a very
small cluster of cells,
for me it starts at conception.
I think from that moment on,
you're locked into this nine month
journey with the human inside your body.
Yeah.
Well,
if you want a merger,
it then go ahead and murder it.
But be honest about what you're doing
and don't call it women's bodily choices
because that is sociopathy and that it's
two cells.
It's murder,
I think.
I think I'm thinking going to have to
say yes.
Wow.
That's a hard line.
You're a hard liner,
sir.
I'm not hotline on very many things.
Aside from the friend that feminist to
ugly and stupid and eastern mysticism,
what is it that 48 days where they
believe the soul enters the body.
That's the formation of the pineal gland
and the seat of the soul.
Isn't it like 48 days?
Can we just know about it?
I'm a 48 day cutoffs and mysticism was
not an area that I've,
uh,
no one had researched.
It was a new house to no one in it.
Then it's still a house.
It's still a house.
Yeah.
But if it gets wrecked and no one has
any memories,
it's no big deal if you say so.
I,
uh,
I'm just playing devil that devil's out.
Get you.
Do you,
do you do that?
I like that.
I think you've got,
what's the,
do you believe in the Myers brigg stuff
like the e n t j stuff?
There's explained that to people.
Well,
so there's basically,
it's,
it's this system of personality types.
And apparently if you,
if you can do sort of a 50 question test
or whatever,
it come up with a single intg NFP and
it's supposed to be at to predict what
kind of job you would be good at and
predict your sort of characteristics and
behaviors and who,
who else in the world you'll get on with
and how you'll succeed in life.
So I've got like the lawyers won the
devil's advocate one.
I think you have it too.
And it's a sort of voracious appetite
for information.
Love to read and find out.
But everything love to talk to smart
people love to be provocative and
interesting and sometimes adopt
positions you don't necessarily hold
because the debate is fascinating and
love just the cut and thrust of
intellectual argument discourse.
Yeah.
Uh,
I think you have that too.
Yeah.
So yeah,
that's well,
if you believe in such things.
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
I do.
But I think also I'm a different person,
you know,
every six or seven months.
I mean,
I think I'm constantly evolving and
growing and reevaluating or at least
attempting to,
and I'm definitely a different person
than I was 10 or 20 years ago.
So if you take that into consideration
that that's my problem with a lot of
these tests,
what they're doing is they're sort of
testing who you are right now.
And one of the problems with those
definitions is the self defining aspects
of it.
Like you start saying,
well this is me and this is who I am
instead of just,
and then it becomes so fulfilling
prophecy.
You think you're locked in.
That's another one of the things I like
about it.
I should stop complimenting you.
Ah,
it's another one of the things I like
about is you have a,
a great,
uh,
have well developed sense of
intellectual humility and,
and you're always sort of open and
learning.
And I liked that because I think you
have to be,
I mean there's no way I like,
I like that in this day and age we have
so many subjects that you can extract
information from.
It is impossible to know everything
about everything.
And all the subjects that we're
discussing,
they all change.
There's new data comes in constantly.
And to pretend that you know everything
about everything is just you couldn't,
you can't,
you could do that in 1992.
You can't do that today.
It's funny what they say about facts and
science have a half life of seven years,
you know,
everything that you think you know in
science becomes wrong in under a decade,
in every field,
in nutrition,
biology.
It's just constantly changing.
I find that fascinating instead of
radical uncertainty about everything
around it's varied.
But I think this is,
this is why people would like to grasp
the certainty.
And it is why I'm going to hand you an
argument here because this is it.
Cause I know you don't like religion
very much.
This is why people like faith so much
because it gives them an anchor in a
very uncertain disinter mediated sort of
very uncertain,
uh,
you know,
globalized,
confusing world wherever you want to
sort of uprooted and thrown in this
Maelstrom were nothing.
You know,
nothing seems,
seems constant or true.
Local communities has been broken down
by,
you know,
big,
big states that take the role of parents
and blah,
blah,
blah.
You know,
um,
I think,
I think people clear to that stuff,
but they also,
of course,
cleave to less helpful systems of belief
like feminism.
I think you're right.
And I think you can equate those two
together.
And I think that a lot of what faith
does,
even if it's not based on a real thing,
it's a scaffolding for four for
security.
It's a scaffolding for a reasonable view
of the world you live in.
Having some moral guidelines that you
can follow that allow you to live a life
with more positive moments or negative
moments because you're sort of
gravitating towards those in a Christian
sense.
Right.
And,
and you know,
I've,
I don't get involved in conversations
trying to sort of persuade them of the
existence of God because it's comes so
completely pointless.
But let's just say that these,
this is a variety of belief systems from
which you can choose or which ones are
better because there are some that are
good and some that are bad.
Um,
and I would say feminism and the race
baiting of black lives matter and Islam
are bad.
Uh,
Christianity on the whole is good or at
least has had pretty good effects.
Pretty good influences.
Also had some horrible facts,
especially in the past.
We weren't going to do this,
we weren't going to do this session.
Sure.
Whatever.
But Islam hasn't gone through the
enlightenment.
I mean,
I just think it,
Jesse,
did you guys getting one?
You don't think it's impossible.
It's a possible change.
I think it's highly unlikely that Islam
will ever get to it.
I don't think it's ever going to engage
properly with the modern world.
I think it just needs to be eradicated.
Wow.
Yeah.
And I've come to this conclusion after
Orlando.
I've seen what I've stopped being polite
about as low as was stopped being polite
about it.
I just think gay guy as well.
I he wasn't he gay?
I mean what's,
is that just a rumor?
Self healthy hating gay Christians.
They don't shoot up nightclubs,
but they could,
I mean,
look,
the guy who shot up those people in the
movie theater in Aurora,
Colorado,
that guy wasn't Islamic.
He was just some nutty,
fuck.
This guy just happened to be gay.
Self-Loathing,
had guns.
You know,
we're reading,
we're reading into a nutcase and various
different things and you,
and,
and as you correctly say,
and I think have pinned on your twitter
account.
We have a mental health problem.
This company off a gun problem.
Uh,
which I think is,
is disguise observation.
This particular guy clearly drew on
things that he was being taught by his
faith and let's be,
they know,
declared that he was doing it in the
name of his faith and in the name of
Isis,
right?
At some point,
you've got to take the guy at his word.
Dave Chappelle has a great joke about
it.
I don't want to give away as bit,
but essentially it's like,
it's quite a bit,
just do it.
He just,
he goes,
you can't claim something right before
you do it.
Like right about,
eat a girl's pussy,
go woo Tang.
Like,
he can't,
he can't claim here in the Wu Tang clan
just by saying it right before you do
it.
I think it's fairly obvious from this
guy,
this guy's history.
I mean it was on the FBI watch list.
A bit started.
Yeah,
it is fun,
but it's fun.
At some point you've just got to accept
when people say they're doing it in the
name of a law,
I guess.
Okay fine.
We get it like good.
But you know like him saying that he was
doing it for isis,
that he pledged allegiance to isis.
He didn't have like a history with Isis.
It was on the FBI watch list twice he
was,
he was a bloody Islamic radical.
Right.
I mean,
you know,
there's no reason to have anybody with
those surnames in this country at all.
Oh,
file.
What about Aziz Ansari?
Oh God.
He deserves to be deported solely
because he's so unfunny.
He's so funny.
I would deport boring unfunny people
before Muslims,
before feminists,
before vapers cyclists,
vapors.
Oh,
vapers I've got to go.
Vapers have got to go.
They've got to go over the wall.
Deport how even the blue cigarettes or
you talking about the people that are
holding onto like the water bottles,
the punk thing,
those people shouldn't just be deported.
They should be.
They should be executed publicly.
There is a set,
there is no rehab.
No,
I'm serious friend Jonathan has one of
those.
Jonathan and Canada,
if you're hearing that.
Of course he does.
He's Canadian,
Canadian.
Good man.
He lives in Alberta.
Ooh Gosh.
Can you imagine,
can you imagine living in Alberta is
beautiful in the summer.
Oh please.
But it,
you're surrounded by Canada.
Canada's one of my favorite places in
the world.
Why?
Because the people are off because it
reminds you how great America is.
They're awesome people.
No,
they're not.
They're very nice.
They're the nicest fucking people in the
world.
They really are.
I don't like Nice.
I don't like Nice me and I'm nice.
Your lovely little exception.
I have a exception.
You don't look nice.
I think that's how I get over it.
You know,
you look like you're about to rob me,
which I think is the only reason I can
put up with your nice personality.
You know,
cause like I said,
it'd be like clutching my wallet with
one hand on my Dick with the other.
Just kidding.
Yeah,
I didn't mean it.
Canadians,
they are nice.
They're great people.
It's a big fence.
A lost country.
Russell Peters,
new Canadian.
I love them to death.
New Kit.
Well the new prime minister,
um oh,
he's doing stuff.
He's so good at doing some odd stuff.
This new thing about these,
the identity cards of having the option
of not having a gender.
Yeah,
you could just,
you could fill out attack helicopter if
you want to send they're neutral.
You can be gender neutral.
The national anthem,
the Canadian national anthem.
They're taking Kim and her out of it or
something.
I've done it.
The Kit.
No,
no,
I,
I didn't make this up.
The kid,
you can look this up if you're listening
because I know I didn't make this up.
The Canadian national anthem,
they were moving like gender specific
references or not to say these people
are insane.
Well,
here's what's insane about it.
What are the numbers we're talking
about?
The people that are issued that have
massive issue with a male or female
gender personally?
Well who are neutral?
Well,
lots of,
lots of young kids because they're
confused and because they've told us to
think to do these people's frontal lobes
haven't formed yet.
Right.
And they're being taught by culture and
by their professors and by everything
around them that you know,
there have to be a man or a woman.
They can just,
it of course,
of course it,
this is what,
this is what some of the,
um,
this is what some of the transgender
people calls.
This looks great.
Canadian parliament is close to adopting
a bill that would change the national
anthem o Canada to make it gender
neutral.
And is this because of the new prime
minister?
This is true.
And when I said it was gay,
I don't necessarily mean that he sucks.
Take hold.
I'm sure he has.
Um,
oh,
for sure.
Looking at it.
Oh,
that is a face just begging to become
on.
I mean this is,
this is no that,
no,
I know.
I've seen.
I've seen men like this in clubs before.
Wives pick them up afterwards.
Oh No,
I know.
Lives.
Pick them up.
Of course the wives are in on it.
We just accept the wives have their own
boyfriends.
Whole Sordid affair,
disgusting,
reputable way up to where it should
live.
No,
this man,
are you kidding me?
Justin Trudeau,
mcm box,
sloppy gay hair and oh no,
no.
He's got,
he's got that puffy figure.
He's got that puffy figure that sort of
like over there.
Handsome man.
He looks gay and I don't mean gay in the
good way.
I mean he looks like a fag.
I mean he looks lame week because he's a
cook.
He's a cook as a cook.
I didn't know there was a cup full
definition of cock until a week ago.
We got into it with Joe Schilling on the
podcast.
I thought Kuk was just a guy whose wife
gets fucked and he sorta cries and well
that's the porn thing.
In fact,
if you've ever had a crank,
a crying lank.
No,
no.
It's cool cranking.
Oh,
I mean gnarly.
So the cock would sit there and cry.
It had a crank off to brexit when the
pound plummeted and I checked how much
of my portfolio was worth.
You're upset.
Kind of happy at the same time.
Yeah.
That's a crank.
So,
but don't you think that that's a
temporary drop and you just,
we just have to deal with,
of course,
of course.
Of course.
Yeah.
No,
it's going to rebound,
rebound.
I mean,
you know,
if you actually,
if you actually don't listen to it,
if you don't read like what Bloomberg
and Msnbc or tweeting and you zoom out
on the,
the,
the pound and zoom out on the footsie.
Actually,
it doesn't look so bad at all.
Uh,
you know,
it's,
yeah,
it's a lot of scam or it's weird to me
that everybody was always so concerned
about a one world government that was a
big fear.
There was a big fear of a new world
order,
one world government.
It was one of the big conspiracy fears.
But then when England decides to be its
own country and exit the European Union,
everybody's terrified.
The Sky is falling with the different
people,
the different groups.
So you had,
I mean there are some very smart people
I speak to who think that globalization
is basically over and that this push to,
you know,
to,
to have this push for open borders
around the world hasn't worked and
people don't like it.
And the,
you know,
if you look,
if you read the work of like Jonathan
Heit or whatever,
you will discover that this sort of
racism thing,
it's the level of evolutionary thing.
People like being with their own tribe
and that's not a racism thing.
And it's just that,
that,
that is an evolutionary advantage
because you don't have to get over all
of the cultural barriers and just get on
with doing shit.
Uh,
you,
um,
you're seeing all across the world,
not just in Europe as a result of the
globalist policies of Angela Merkel and
all the rest of it,
uh,
in Germany,
brexit in Europe and the rise of trump
and America,
people returning to nationalism.
By which we don't mean,
you know,
racism by which we mean simply pride in
nation culture and lesser in the West is
the best.
You know,
we are,
uh,
you know,
Europe and America,
the best bit of the world.
And people who,
you know,
can't get wrap their heads around that
don't understand why people might wish
to preserve the,
the cultures that created Mozart and
Shakespeare and Wagner,
they don't understand why.
They also don't understand the economic
pressures on those people who had the
global one world government conspiracy
theories.
Well,
they tended to be lower income people
who are worried about centralization of
power away from them.
And you know,
the,
as you know,
it was these,
these liberals,
American liberals who crowing about the
Browning of America or this kind of
stuff,
or they're worried about their culture,
their families,
depressed wages,
economics as well,
all that kind of stuff.
The people who are worried on the other
hand about this now are the elites.
So you're talking about two different
groups and I'm like,
this is the main,
this is the main route.
This is really the main fight.
Now this election,
uh,
in America and most of the big elections
and referendums over the next 10 years
are going to be about two things.
One of them driven by economics and one
of them driven by culture and politics.
The economics,
the economics.
One is,
is you know,
elites versus the proles.
It's the,
it's the moneyed international few
versus the rest of us.
Proles being proletariat for people.
Right.
You know,
the,
the sort of the
rest of us who are worried about wages,
worried about immigration and worried
about culture.
What about the,
the,
the fate of our country.
And the other one of course is men view
women,
which is entirely manufactured by the
left.
Um,
and I think the more I see the American
election entirely through the prism of
men versus women,
I think trump at trump versus hillary
is,
um,
is a,
is a clash of the titans between,
you know,
the strong,
blustery,
um,
outward looking,
strong male archetype versus the status
establishment feminism of,
you know,
if,
if Clinton and the Democrats,
this,
this election really is men view women
and it's not nice to put it in that way,
but the left did it not,
have you seen the compilation of the
things that she has said that she did
versus the things that the FBI has said
that she did?
Oh my God,
that woman,
I have to be careful that I miss.
I have a day job aside from having,
doing fun things like this.
I do have a day job as an editor at a
Breitbart,
so I have to be very careful what names
I call people.
Yes.
But markable Rooney Mara lies are out
there and can say it very clear,
remarkable,
very obvious.
She did not tell the truth.
She,
she lied about how many device,
if you go to,
there's a instagram page that has a
compilation of it,
I think it's called liberal tears.
It goes back and forth.
Yes.
It shows what the FBI said she did and
what she said she did.
She said she only used one device.
She never sent anything that was
classified and they said she's multiple
devices,
sent many classified things and they're
gone.
I mean it's the difference between with
the SPD FBI statement was what she said,
but then she's clearly being deceptive.
But the Department of Justice is on her
side though.
I mean,
you know,
they,
they said the,
uh,
it was it Camy Komi Cami,
I caught Mary's name to get,
the guy says,
the guy says we've never prosecuted.
He said he's in his yesterday for,
we've never prosecuted somebody for
doing what Hillary did in a way of
trying to sort of explain away why they
weren't pressing charges.
They have,
they've issued press releases about
people in the past.
I tweeted it yesterday about Petraeus.
General Petraeus is the whole reason why
he was removed.
They have,
they have issued press releases crowing
about finding these guys in the past.
You know,
this is,
I mean this just shows you how dumb Fox
News can be sometimes thinking that it
was going to be an indictment here.
Everybody knew Democrats don't indict
Democrats,
right?
Well,
an presidency,
Hillary was never going to be indicted
with Obama in the White House.
It was not going to happen.
Not only that,
if she does get indicted and she gets
removed from the race,
who the fuck is there on the democratic
side?
Joe Biden want Bernie back,
get buried,
keep burning.
No,
I like him and I like to do to the
Bernie supporters fall into two camps
there like the crazy gender activists
and race baiters but I think that's
probably only 20% of Bernie people and
the rest of the Bernie fans aren't that
dissimilar from trump fans.
You know,
there are people who don't like this
tablet.
I'm sick of being lied to or you know,
are fed up of the consequences of
globalization on,
on,
you know,
native populations if you like,
worried about all sorts of things.
And they express themselves very
differently from the trump fans.
You know,
don't use the same language and it,
but even the,
I mean the polls are saying,
what does it,
20 30% of Bernie supporters might come
over to trump and the election.
That doesn't surprise me at all.
No.
Cause they're very similar people.
I liked Bernie supporters and I like
Bernie Sanders.
I think he's all right.
Hillary is the enemy.
Well she is the establishment.
I mean she is as established a
politician as he could possibly get and
she has deep,
deep,
deep in the system.
Yeah.
And there's just a lot of darkness to
that.
There's a lot of danger to that.
Does a lot of danger to embracing that
just simply because she has a vagina.
My wife is going to vote for just cause
she has a vagina.
Your wife need no,
I wouldn't say that.
Uh,
I do all those things to her.
It doesn't help.
Um,
aren't you looking forward to this?
Here's the video.
Here's the,
here's,
here's the video.
Listen to this.
Listen to this,
um,
classified material to anyone.
There is no classified material.
110 emails.
Email chains have been determined by the
owning agency to contains classified
information at the time they were sent
or received.
I provided all my emails that could
possibly be work related,
several thousand work related emails
that were not among the group of 30,000
emails returned by Secretary Clinton.
I thought using one device would be
simpler.
She also use numerous mobile devices to
send in to read email.
There were no security breaches you'd
use.
Possible hostile actors gained access to
secretary Clinton's personal email.
Kevin.
It was my practice to communicate with
State Department and other government
officials on there.
Dot Gov accounts.
Hostile actors gained access to the
private commercial email accounts of
people was home.
Secretary Clinton was in regular contact
from her personal account.
Um,
no doubt that we've done exactly what we
should have done.
They were extremely careless handling a
very sensitive,
highly classified.
This is dre,
nicely structured and judge for
themselves.
We cannot find a case that would support
bringing criminal charges on these
facts.
To be clear.
This is not to suggest that in similar
circumstances,
a person who engaged in this activity
would face no consequences.
Americans will find that to,
you know,
interesting.
And I look forward to having a
discussion about them.
Nice.
She's a crook.
She a crooked hillary.
Crooked Hillary as the sainted God
Emperor Donald Trump.
That's just,
that's just a liar.
I mean,
you know that is just a liar.
Aren't you looking forward to the
debates though?
I mean I am,
but the problem is like he's going to
Crucey,
he starts name calling and all the jazz
that goes along with that.
And he says preposterous things about
Mexico,
about them being a bunch of rapists and
next thing you know he didn't say that
someone's doing the rabbit said that.
Never said that puncture of rapists.
Well he didn't say it that way.
No,
he said Mexico
is not sending as best people and that
many of the people who come over are
rapists and criminals.
That's all true.
And what has happened since the
pronounce the the conservative press has
been more alert and awake to this and
had been and been reimbursed.
And if you like,
look at it,
we're finding these guys that are caught
on a cleaner court for raping and
killing and stealing things and they've
been deported six times.
We're finding all,
you know,
there's this,
this poor girl got murdered by an
immigrant,
been deported four times.
He's not wrong.
You might not like the way he says it,
but he's not wrong the way as it is
definitely problematic and it really
hurts the people that x size,
that word from your vocal problematic
because it's don't you know it's a
progressive word.
That's what they sound campuses.
Actually I find what you're saying
really problem.
You need,
no,
I'm serious.
You need to get rid of this.
We need to get rid of this a problem.
And when you can communicate and that is
a social justice dog whistle.
When people sit,
when people hear you say problematic,
they think saying that word feminism
problematic was ever I know.
But language language sometimes
accelerates past us.
You know,
um,
well recharged.
Retard.
Retard is fine.
[inaudible] is fine and retarded is fine
and love you gay for I can't give you,
I can't give you a cripple pass,
but I can give you a fast pass and you
can have a fast pass for gay,
queer and Faggot because they're fine
too,
but people are not going to accept it.
You could use it.
I do.
Someone told me,
I had a discussion because I called my
dog a faggot and one of my,
one of my comedy specials and uh,
it was just,
it was a stupid bit.
And the guy said,
this is where it was really,
it was a comedy central guy.
He goes,
only we can use that.
And I go,
what?
And he goes,
yes,
it's our nigger.
And I said,
that's the gay shit I've ever heard.
I said,
no,
but that's true.
I don't,
it's a real conversation I had with a
real person.
But no,
I don't agree with all of this.
I think boards should be liberated.
And once you liberate them,
you rob them of their ability to hurt
people.
You rob them of their ability to wound
and you stop giving them power.
And more important than that,
you don't just rob racist,
sexist,
and homophobic of a word in their
arsenal.
But you also rob social justice warriors
of the ability to bully and police and
publicly shame people for using loads
that are fine.
Well,
the problem is when you give words
magical powers and so words are about
content.
And you know,
when you know,
when someone does like what was the
Louis Ck joke?
Uh,
he goes,
what if someone's just being a faggot?
He knows he doesn't have anything to do
with being gay.
Like did you know the people from
Phoenix to called Phoenicians?
Oh,
shut up faggot.
Yeah,
I agree.
I said,
I recorded episode of my show yesterday
with Ann Coulter and she said,
that's gay.
And I said,
I hope you don't mean homosexual.
I hope you mean gay in its prestige,
meaning in my view,
which is rubbish,
lame crap.
Hillary supporting immigrant loving,
you know,
that's by immigrant loving.
But my dad's family were immigrants.
I mean bad immigrants,
you know what I mean?
I didn't mean like my family are bad
immigrant.
I don't mean handsome,
charming,
successful,
blonde haired British immigrants.
I mean Donald Trump's rapists,
those bad ones,
the brownies,
no,
it's got nothing to do.
It's got nothing to do with skin color.
It's about culture.
And you're,
you know,
and this is what's happening in item of
all people.
I don't have a problem with brown skin,
but as you know,
but um,
it's about culture.
And when you import,
you know,
as an,
as happening in Germany,
these barbaric,
medieval,
um,
attitudes to women and gays,
bad things happen.
And actually that doesn't just service
to the barbarians and that is a real
problem,
right?
And that's a problem that the left just
does not want to face it.
That there are cultures dislike.
There are some of the,
they're,
they're terrible people in all cultures,
right?
We can all,
there are cultures that are not as good
as ours,
right?
Briefly,
system choice.
We shouldn't import them here at our
prison system is filled with people that
have done terrible things,
right?
So even in the best country in the
world,
there are people in this country that
have done terrible things,
but there's,
there's a general attitude about women
in the Middle East that has been
supported by the people that are in
charge of the countries like Saudi
Arabia where the women could not drive.
It's endemic.
Well,
that one,
I'm with them on.
No,
sometimes no,
no,
no.
Sometimes sometimes good things can
happen for bad reasons,
you know,
and the chicks don't drive accidentally
stone.
They've accidentally stumbled on a good
rule.
Women should not be behind the
heterosexual male.
If a,
I want a girl to come over my house and
fuck and a should be sending a car full,
Huh?
Oh right.
But what if I was send your chauffeur
central sheriff,
then you should have some sort of,
some sorts of disreputable midnight
trust someone.
Sometimes it's good to be able to ask
good old carriage for her.
She comes over with their own pillow.
You know what I'm saying?
Without own pillar.
That's a good girl.
Do you make people not now,
obviously some girls like jerome pillow,
so fucked up women are a mess.
No guy comes over a girl's house or own
pillar.
I mean,
I own pills.
Give me an idea because I have very,
I've got those,
like there's lovely $250 ducked down
pillows.
They're lovely.
But I live out of hotels.
I should start taking my own pillows
everywhere.
It's not a bad idea because I sleep in
my own bed about three days every two
months.
And it's,
it's like honestly,
it's like such a luxurious experience to
be at home watching that much.
You know,
I live in hotels,
I'm in,
I'm in a hotel in West Hollywood,
um,
all this month.
Uh,
yeah,
no,
I just don't go home anymore.
Well,
I know you're constantly doing these
tours.
I saw the one that you did with Steven
crowder and cause you know,
if Christina Hoff sommers showing the
shirts,
she was amazing.
I loved that show.
I love her aside from mine.
That was my favorite show of yours.
Yeah,
she's fantastic.
She's fantastic.
And crowder gets a lot of shit,
but he makes some great points and he's
it.
He goes,
well he's,
he kinda,
you know,
silly and he does a lot of funny stuff.
I think he's funny.
You see the brexit thing that he did?
No.
Oh,
I always have to catch up on stuff like
to see if you could find it when him and
his cohost,
uh,
when uh,
what was the guy named Nigel Farrage
that his name?
The guy who orchestrated the brexit and
there's a video of him addressing,
I guess the parliament.
Is that what who is addressing oh,
European Parliament.
Yes.
Just roasting them.
Basically.
He's roasting them and then crowd here
go live.
Go full screen.
So we could,
but yeah,
don't play it.
Go all the way back to the beginning.
Hold on.
This is what happen with brexit.
We just have to,
Nigel Faraj,
he's got a hat on who looks British,
very British.
And so it was a weird looking dude.
His cohosts looks like the Queen.
Finally he's going to hold their hand,
the referendum after the for the year.
It's very funny.
And indeed this has gone viral.
He explained in his words as to why the
brexit happened and he sat down,
he educated them,
he tried to enlighten them.
Buddy also made it staying just a little
bit.
So we want to show you some highlights
from these clips of Nigel.
Fuck Gosh,
let's roll clip one.
Isn't it funny?
You know what?
I came here 17 years ago and I said,
but I wanted to lead a campaign to get
Britain to leave the European Union.
You all laughed at me.
Well,
I have to say you're not laughing now,
right?
Oh,
this reminds me of a great,
um,
can we pause this for a second?
Yes.
It reminds me of a great,
I think it's a monk monkhouse joke.
And he said,
he said something like,
um,
10 years ago I told you I was all going
to be,
I told you all I was going to be a
comedian.
Well,
no one's laughing now.
It gets crazy to watch.
They get,
they go deeper.
Why is this?
Oh boom.
Love that.
I don't care what you say about him,
but that man is a p.
I.
M.
P.
Yes.
Nobody's laughing now spelling that out
in my head.
You expect this fragment to get better.
Don't,
like I said,
we're going to people who are far more
authoritative on the brexit.
Just kind of like the UK with the
American election.
It's entertainment.
Sorry,
it's been a,
it's been an intense few weeks.
This is last week of cultural
appropriation.
Moms,
brexit.
Good on you guys.
You got some independent chair going to
be entertained this evening.
Sons,
we have some other clips.
Don't we ask them a clip?
We have some more clips where he sat
down and he talked to them about,
uh,
I mean he just read them the riot act.
So let,
let's,
let's get to some of the substance of
his,
his comments were all the next clip.
But what I would like to see is a grown
up and sensible attitude to how we
negotiate a different relationship now.
Now I know,
I know that virtually none of you have
ever done a proper job in your lives.
Oh,
okay.
I get it.
No,
I,
I like Tim.
He's right.
No,
he is.
That is a real issue with politicians
and also university teachers of course.
Well it gets worse than that.
Professors,
universities,
it's worse than that.
It used to be the case in America that
the faculty ruled the roost and the
faculty,
you know,
could pretty much do what they wanted
and colleges.
But the balance of power has shifted in
American universities now toward
administrators.
So what,
it basically the people who run the
money because uh,
because universities are now giant,
partly taxpayer funded,
partly government owned businesses that
need to bring in donations and need to,
uh,
keep the admissions numbers up and have
these gigantic campuses.
We'd luxurious facilities and all the
rest of education is taking very much a
back seat to the business of providing a
home or even as some people want a safe
space away from home for four years and
charging vast fees to do it.
That becomes sort of holiday camps.
Very well appointed holiday camps.
The people with the power now in
universities or the administrators.
And to be a university administrator,
you need to know even less than to be a
professor.
You need to really,
I mean,
in fact,
it's almost compulsory to go through
life with a cluster of conspiracy
theories in a victimhood and grievance
politics and total ignorance of history
to run a university in America now
because you have to pander to and
believe a variety of things that simply
aren't true.
For example,
about campus rape culture.
You need to not only enable but fund
feminist groups on campus and all sorts
of an a variety and the diversity office
and the women's,
you know,
in the women's studies department and
this Obama,
all these things that are happening on
campuses,
you know,
putting other kids tuition fees,
putting the tuition fees are people who
are studying engineering and maths and
physics into academic departments and
student services and all sorts of other
things that simply peddle lies to
children.
They are spreading conspiracy theories
based on shoddy advocacy research and
um,
barmy social social science nonsense
from the 1970s and filling it
vulnerable,
impressionable young people's heads with
it.
And it is obscene.
Like what kind of conspiracy theory?
Well,
at the patriarchy,
the patriarch is a conspiracy theory.
The Patriarchy is the,
you know,
is,
is an idea of dreamt up by feminists,
which basic,
I mean,
what it really boils down to is my life
is bad.
So this is the,
this is the thing that,
the thing I don't like about Bernie
supporters,
they go to the world and they start on
this basis.
It's my life's bad.
Who's to blame for it?
Which of you are at fault for my life
not being as good as I want it to be.
Now this is the,
the victim hood in grievance,
sort of politics of,
of the social justice left,
particularly then sort of middle and
upper middle class social justice left.
Now these women's studies departments
tell young girls if there's anything
wrong in your life.
We were miserably unhappy and anything
ever bad,
anything bad ever happens to you?
It is the patriarchy.
It's this sort of voldemort s conspiracy
theory that can explain everything.
And of course as anybody with any sense
who actually reads books knows that any
explanation that's a bit too good to be
true generally is.
And the Patriarchy in fact does not
explain any of the things that are wrong
in women's lives.
And if you look at the real data,
you discover that if there is a
patriarchy,
it ain't doing a very good job.
You know,
of course,
you know 97% of workplace fatalities are
male men have fallen behind in
education.
There is no wage gap.
And in fact women have a huge
competitive advantage going for many
jobs,
blah,
blah.
Everyone who's listened to us regularly,
we'll know all this stuff by heart
already,
but let's explain the web get wage gap
thing because it's one of the things
that gets trumped,
trumpeted out,
trumped,
tried a bit from where,
where people don't,
I get a semi just at the sound of the
word now you don't understand.
Told The New York Times I was trump
sexual and I was trolling them,
but they saw that I was trolling them,
but they printed it.
Good job.
Recognize the troll.
And I think they did too.
But they are obligated to do you
personally find Donald Trump sexual
attraction on it?
Yeah,
I'm trump's actual,
it's hilarious.
Yeah.
I don't think they know what to do with
you,
but that's beside the point.
That's explained what the issue is with
the wage gap.
Okay.
So there's two ways to do it.
Um,
one of them involves a little bit of
economics and people at home sometimes
like Uconn deal,
but steals dirty math is what it is.
They start taking you be checking on
this,
but listen,
if you're at home and you're thinking,
I really can't be bothered with this
buck the fuck up 75 cents to every
dollar of lies,
lies,
lies.
So there are of course reasons why men
and women may have different roles in
society.
In some of these,
let's,
let's pick an example.
Mendham bear children.
Now of course the left is trying to
check.
I saw,
Oh God,
sorry to go off track.
This is how my brain works is I'm so
scattered,
but the Guardian in June,
I was just so this other story about
this guy who was like,
try this trans guy trying to breastfeed
a kid.
And his quote was like,
children,
no,
it's not.
It's not children don't know what gender
you are.
I thought that was a joke.
I thought that was someone was like an
onion type.
It's not,
come on.
No,
it's the guy with glasses that has a
baby on his tail.
Oh No.
I started laughing when I saw that.
I thought it was like an almost
certainly Canadian.
Do you know what?
I could look it up.
I would,
I wouldn't put a lot of money on it,
but I put a bit,
but let's,
let's get quickly.
Oh my God,
this is real.
I'm a transgender dad in a gay
relationship.
Who breastfeeds the Guardian.
This is real.
Yeah.
Gay tranny breastfeeding the kid and he
says,
Hey,
kids didn't and what Jen d this is so at
the end of my pregnancy,
wait a minute,
wait a minute.
Wait,
wait and wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
So he was born a woman then that it is a
woman who knows.
Oh,
it's a woman who transgender man,
cause he's got a mustache and a goatee,
which means hormones and is now becoming
a man.
Yeah.
So basically he's a man.
Breastfeeding a child.
Kid is going to get like super
testosterone,
which we're told that we're not allowing
female.
He's a man to demand where we have to do
this.
Now he is a man.
You can't even refer to him as a former
female,
whatever,
that transphobic demand.
So I was right.
I wasn't trans phobic is full,
big phobia means fear.
No.
Well irrational fear.
Yeah.
Um,
and there's nothing irrational about
fearing trainees.
They're fucking terrifying.
But I serious,
this is so scary.
I was on a chat show with somebody,
right?
And she's,
she was like this,
this man who is now a woman.
And she said,
um,
I like icon.
She though lease,
you're doing the proper thing.
Dammit,
I'm going to get fired.
We have a company policy about this.
And she said,
um,
I've worn the female garb and I've worn
the male garb.
Men Don't know they're born.
I get so many.
You know,
as I walked through life as a man,
people treated me,
you know,
perfectly normally.
But now people look at me very
strangely.
It took every ounce of my self control.
Not to say you're a man in a dress.
Of course they look at you weirdly.
You're terrifying when babies cry at
you.
They're not crying because they're
transphobic.
They're crying because you look
horrifying.
Did you see Caitlin Jenner or brew
install bruce?
No.
Bruce.
Wow.
How style at Breitbart is to insist on
Bruce when ellen was grilling here,
her,
him know about gay marriage.
And then she was saying she's a
traditionalist.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But that's why the missional girl
fucking rubber face or face can't move.
She shouted up full of Botox.
What the fuck?
What the fuck ever happened to loving
yourself?
That's what confuses the shit out of me.
I'm telling you,
it's self harm extended out into the
rest of your life because you didn't
pick up a razor blade when you were 15
honestly,
kids cut yourself.
No,
I'm kidding.
I don't know that that's what it is.
But there's something very bizarre about
in collage exoticness hormones into
their body and getting their chin
slashed off so that they look more like
a man or a woman.
I very firmly believe,
very firmly believe that we will look
back on this period in time like we do
now on Victorian electroshock therapy
and wonder how we could ever have been
so monstrously callous as to allow these
people who have mental mental illnesses
to mutilate their bodies.
And of course how idiotic and and and
authoritarian it was of us to expect the
taxpayers to pick up the bill.
That's what that gets really weird for
sure.
But I mean,
I feel like if somebody wants to do it
and it's their body,
I have no right whatsoever to tell them
they can't do.
Oh,
you do.
But it is very,
you do is you should,
why should I be so stupid?
My God?
Anybody be able to tell?
Just let it do it.
I mean,
who cares,
right?
Yeah.
Well,
why not?
We don't allow people with mental
illnesses on the whole to live out their
delusions excepted when it isn't a
medical interest.
When we do what is mental illness?
Okay.
Let me ask you this.
If a person's pays their bills,
they're nice to people.
They functioned normally,
they pay their taxes and for whatever
man,
they want to be a man to man,
but they want to be one tough.
You know what?
This is a serious answer to this,
which is that it is by no clear,
and you wouldn't know this just by
reading the media,
but it is by no means clear that that is
the most effective and humane treatment
pathway for people with this particular
group.
Right?
Greed is not clear at all.
Now what we should be doing,
unless you just want some sort of
chaotic,
free for,
I know,
I know.
The easy argument,
that easy libertarian argument is let
people do what they want themselves to
not hurting anybody else.
Just don't make the taxpayer pay for it.
Right?
Well,
yeah,
fine.
But my natural,
I mean,
I think my compassion kicks in at that
point and says to me,
do we want to allow people who are
mentally ill to mutilate themselves?
If somebody was,
uh,
a schizophrenia,
would we give them the razor blade
they're asking for because they want to
hack off their own arm.
Okay,
what do we would know what size?
Double e tits.
And they've got just,
just good Kukoc could sense that's all
would have a girl.
Gastric surgery is different.
Hosters tips,
plastic surgery.
It's just plus.
Well that's,
that's tending into the same kind of
disorder and we shouldn't let them do
that either.
Maybe there should be rules about
what's,
how big,
you can go.
A little plastic,
a little bit tit rules in this country.
A little plastic surgery is just good
grooming.
But,
um,
I,
you know,
I mean,
I,
I couldn't imagine a day,
oh sure.
We have tit rules.
Imagine Day.
Well,
no,
it's not about the site a,
okay.
It's not about the size of the breast.
It's about the mental state of the
person who wants to change their body.
And that's flubs preposterous.
Jessica Rabbit tits.
If they want to pay for them themselves
and themselves,
I don't know.
I mean if they,
you know,
if they want like pendulous breasts and
size of watermelon show sideshow,
no,
I don't think you should be able to do
that.
It's because it's awful.
Okay.
Should you be able to tattoo your whole
body?
Well,
it depends.
If you're like my arm.
Totally tattooed.
Yeah,
it was pretty hot.
Is that a yeah,
you should be allowed,
but you should be allowed because it's
hot to you.
But some people don't like it.
Well,
they're wrong.
Well isn't that subjective?
But yeah,
the woman.
Shouldn't those giant boulder tits be
subjective as well?
When the girls get those big thick blue
veins,
those are bizarre.
Those neck veins big.
Do you like your tits?
I like normal ones.
See Cup's fine.
Show me what's so,
you know.
Okay,
so like this dee dee's a little,
I'm not a connoisseur resists,
so I don't know what cops is that it's
like a C Cup.
Yeah.
That's nice.
So breast?
Yes.
Yeah,
look good.
Yeah.
But you shouldn't get them if you're a
man.
Yeah.
Well,
yeah.
Well Bruce has him,
right?
He has them now.
Yeah.
That was the things about him as he went
on the Diane Sawyer thing and said,
he still wants to be,
bruce still wants to be a him stolen.
So we called to him and then immediately
after,
because of all the attention gets his
jaw shave down,
has massive facial reconstruction
surgery.
I mean it was like,
it was instantaneously and changed his
name to Caitlyn and it was also right
after the Diane Sawyer injury or injury
interview that he plowed into that lady
and center into oncoming traffic and
killed her.
And it was,
it is.
So he was,
he was that he was going to get
discussed.
I think he was.
He was declared innocent of that.
What do you mean declared innocent?
Wasn't,
he definitely wasn't the car,
wasn't he acquitted of manslaughter?
Yes,
but I mean he's definitely taken us
being careless.
Definitely hit that car.
But of course he's insane.
He's insane.
He shouldn't be allowed behind the
wheel.
He shouldn't be given guns.
He should not be given access to
surgeons struggling with the office face
to try to make sounds with his mouth or
her mouth or would it look at this?
Have you,
it's quite good in that dress frankly.
But,
uh,
that is that this is,
this is,
you know,
this is an insane person.
This is a person whose mind is he needs
therapy and well,
that's a person who grew up with uh,
well existed with a bunch of incredibly
famous,
very powerful women and probably
secretly wanted to be like that.
One of them.
Look,
all I'm saying for sure for sure outside
of our,
you know,
joking around is that it is by no means
clear that transition surgery is the
best route for these people.
It does not,
according to all of the data we have,
all of the studies that it does not
significantly or at all really affects
suicide rates or depression.
What people who've had this surgery do
not get better,
uh,
as possible.
A few of them do,
but not many.
And 40% of them who have it want it
reversed.
My suggestion is shouldn't we just be a
bit more cautious about it?
Well,
you are certainly saying some very uh,
conservative things about that in terms
of like how you should approach your own
body and your life,
like getting sexual reassignment.
Nobody,
I mean,
I don't want,
you mean conservative like right wing.
I mean like cautious,
cautious.
I think we should be cautious before we
moved to they,
our bodies because there's no coming
back from it.
And there's a lot of regret once you've
cut your cock off.
That's it.
Yeah,
that's it.
Everything else in life you can reverse
your reputation.
You can restore within the hard work and
you know,
and,
and a commitment to read it to
redressing whatever wrongs you did to
people.
You Korea,
you can make it better.
You can fix almost anything in life.
But you cut your genitals off.
Biological reality is biological
reality,
right?
And you can fix almost anything else
about yourself,
almost anything else about your life.
But there are certain facts,
certain anatomical facts about,
about men and women.
And once you cut that thing off,
that's it.
It's done.
And I'm just suggesting that maybe we
shouldn't do it,
for instance,
to children for start giving them
hormone therapy.
We shouldn't allow people that should be
just standard.
There's no way.
What if but yeah,
but I'm saying shit,
what if somebody with 1819 you know,
1819 years old and says,
I know and have known for 10 years that
I'm a woman.
You know,
would you let them change and stuff?
I thought I wanted to be married.
You'll frontal lobe isn't even fully
formed at that age.
You're not even really a person yet.
You know you are and you are a a
burgeoning person,
right?
You are growing into the person you will
be and that's why you can abort them.
Stop it.
They're not really people yet.
This level of software story has been a
few.
So you might be 800 plus podcasts
guests.
The first is someone said Sophos tree.
This is unless you said it during the
last episode.
Sophos stream.
This is the,
this is this.
So it's the headline on Breitbart
tomorrow.
Joe Rogan in favor of 18 year old
abortions or abortion.
How many weeks is that?
How many weeks is 18 years?
That's a lot.
I'm bad at math.
My issue is,
wasn't there a time where we said you
should just love who you are,
like love who you are and if you can,
these people do who you are.
But there's the big difference between x
sort of accepting who you are.
And there's some people that just have
unfortunate genetics,
right?
And there's some people that may be wish
of,
they're a woman or made me wish there
was something else.
And there's one thing between,
there's a difference between dressing up
or pretending,
but once you start getting into full on
injecting female hormones into a male's
body and changing things,
and then physical surgery,
I am not against it.
I think I am.
Like you said,
I'm silly libertarian.
I feel like you should be able to do
whatever the fuck you want to do with
your body.
But it is a very dangerous road.
And there's there,
there is a host of different people out
there that will tell you that they've
done it.
And it was a huge,
it was a huge mistake.
Yes,
they're all 40% of,
but no one has to address that.
That is something that the left never
wants to address in their embracing of
the transgender culture,
which I embrace to do whatever the fuck
you want to do.
I'll say it again.
Yeah.
No,
I like,
I just can't get behind it because I see
how,
isn't it dishonest though too?
Never discussed those people that were
crucified is,
but for them,
look,
they forced us to take a moral position
on a medical issue,
right?
This is not a moral issue.
This is a medical issue.
If it is the case that people have a
disorder or a condition,
if they have dysphoria,
whatever word they want to come up with
for it,
that means that they were born with the
wrong brain in the wrong body.
Nevermind the fact that we're always
told that gender socialized,
you know,
or can apparently suddenly,
abruptly.
Now you can have a male brain such a
thing as a male brain and the leftist
gender as a social construct and last
year trends,
in which case you've got a male brain of
everybody.
What a load of crap.
These people,
these people really expect us to believe
this shit.
They think that we have the same level
of cognitive dissonance that they have.
They think that we are as dumb as they
are.
They think that we don't think things
through like they don't think things
through what we do.
We do think these things through.
And so to most people that are home and
they are like told on the one hand if
they even bother to get this far into a
guardian editorial,
that you know that gender is a social
construct and you know all of this kind
of stuff and yet at the same time that
masculinity is toxic and at the same
time you can have a mat and the only
time you were allowed to feminine
virtue,
like really like sexy clothes,
short skirts as if you're chasing a
trend.
And if you're a trainee,
if you're a girl,
yeah.
It's like,
Oh,
you're so empowered.
You're brave and fabulous.
Like a stunning and brave is the phrase
stunning and brave.
There's nothing heroic about cutting
off.
Your firefighter should get the pump off
and cutting their cocks off.
You know,
it's just strange that a woman who wears
short skirts and high heels and a lot of
makeup,
that is a pay as long as you're a man,
right?
As long as you're a married man,
you see where even better at being women
than women or women on deer.
Yeah.
With Glamour magazine,
woman of the year,
six months after being a woman,
he one woman of the year,
if there's bitches had been trying to
win that fucking award for this 30 40
years of good ladies out there.
There's some good girls who missed out
on that.
Is there anything men can't do?
We're better.
You know,
I've had male cleaners and female
cleanest men.
Always better.
I've had male cooks and female coaches.
Male cooks always better.
I'm just saying,
what do I mean?
This is the problem with a trans project
is profoundly sexist because you know
the transplant and homophobic,
by the way,
because I've convinced to this,
the transport is profoundly homophobia
because what it's telling parents right
now,
and this is,
this is the 40% of the one at route when
it reversed,
and probably then some they're telling,
if you're a young boy and your feminine
and you liked playing with barbies and
you're attracted to other boys and you,
and in your confused child,
mind you,
you and your parents,
dumb,
liberal,
infested,
infected,
intoxicated mind.
Somehow this becomes,
oh,
you must have really supposed to have
been a girl.
Uh,
no,
they're just gay.
And if you leave these kids alone,
all the evidence suggests that they grew
up into perfectly well adjusted young
gay men.
But instead we're telling them,
and is this also provides an escape
hatch for parents who can't cope with
it.
The fact that kids are gay,
because what it says to them is,
oh,
it's okay.
You haven't given birth to a queer.
You've just,
you,
there's nothing wrong with you.
This kid's got a disorder,
you should have had a daughter.
So this gets parents out of having to
like go through the,
all of the difficult a rigmarole on
their heads.
Like what did I do to turn my son gay?
Well now you don't have to because now
they have a disorder and now they're
supposed to be girls.
Right.
That's so homophobic.
So homophobic and the trends thing is,
is profoundly anti women because all it
seems to be demonstrating,
and I mean the effect of it,
at least all it seems to be
demonstrating is that men are better at
being women than women are.
And I no,
I mean look at Caitlyn Jenner woman of
the year.
We didn't do it.
It's bullshit award just because there's
so much attention being put on a,
no one really thinks she did anything
fabulous.
Well,
no,
this isn't about all the women that have
done amazing things for women.
This is what the left does is it forces
you to take it.
Yes it is.
It forces you to take moral positions
on,
you know,
on medical issues in this case.
Right.
But it also makes you lie.
This is how you know the left thinks
it's one and it's getting over
confident,
which is why I'm winning on college
campuses because they've forgotten how
to argue.
But the left is getting over at comp
overconfident and he's making it is it's
enforcing this stuff when people now,
if you don't want to be a bigot and lose
your job and liberal newspaper column
and not be appear on TV anymore and
become persona non grata,
you have to tell lies that you know
aren't true,
that everybody knows aren't true.
For instance,
the Caitlyn Jenner was a woman.
Nobody believes that no one,
not the journalist who I,
he still has a penis,
not,
well,
okay,
fine.
But let's say it's even more
problematic.
Like she's offensive.
I'll give you that problematic that
let's take another trans person,
right?
Somebody who's had everything.
Somebody who now has one of those
hideous,
oozing inverted vaginas.
You know,
the surgery is terrific by the way.
I describe it in detail to anybody
thinking of having this done to them on
youtube.
Oh God,
really?
Yeah.
Oh,
even I haven't done that.
Can Watch it.
No thanks.
Uh,
it,
you know,
take a take a woman who has had all of
this,
okay.
She's had all the surgery or the woman
is living as a woman could almost pass
or does it?
Nobody believes it's a woman,
not the journalist writing the stories,
not the doc.
Stop it.
Oh,
do you know,
interesting little tidbit.
I think I might even have said this in
the last show.
It was a long time ago and I'm sure
different people are listening.
Do you know why so many trainings get
beaten up?
Cause the,
the left is always saying,
oh,
we gotta protect the Trans Community
because there's like disproportionately
the victims of violence,
you know?
Do you know what happens?
Why?
No.
Why tranny prostitutes get beaten up so
much.
Why?
Yes.
Because they lie and say that they're a
woman and the guy finds a penis and then
they'd beat him up.
No,
they steal money.
they what did the first one that gave us
a much obvious explanation,
but it isn't the reason.
What happens is that,
I mean men aren't dumb when they see a
trainee.
They know it's a tranny,
right?
I don't know who these guys are like in,
in your imagination who you think don't
know a man when they see one.
But most people know a man when they see
one,
even if it's at hormones and it's got
like a,
I've seen some close ones.
I've seen some ones.
I've seen someone that you've ever seen.
Bailey J no belly.
J transgender woman.
She is the most compelling argument for
someone who was born in the wrong sex.
Well,
I don't think hotness is a compelling
argument for medical,
like 100% 100% well,
lots of men are pretty,
that's not,
she's got a big Dick.
There's better pictures of her.
No,
I'm not into it.
That right there.
Kapow come on son.
Not into a big fat dick to post it on
twitter.
That's one of the weird things about
Like you can be flipping through twitter
and all of a sudden you just see a giant
Dick.
You're like,
oh,
all right,
well I follow a couple of porn stars
because I'm friends with them.
But if it was a bit,
of course they use the twitter accounts
just to promote their work.
So I'm sort of like,
I've got like one,
no,
I've got like Felix Salmon from fusion,
somebody from the Wall Street Journal,
a colleague tweeting about Elon Musk,
tranny porn.
It was all the time after time.
Uh,
what was I saying?
Yes.
Nobody,
nobody believes no one,
nobody,
not a single soul believes that this
person is a woman.
Right.
Might look like a woman,
might be hot my,
you know,
all the rest of it.
But nobody believes it is a woman where
we have to say we have to use pronouns
that suggested we have to warp reality
language and you know,
uh,
and passports or the infrastructure of
the,
of the country has to be remodeled
around people with mental disorders.
Imagine if we did this for any other
kind of mental disorder.
Why?
Because the left has made this as they
put on the front cover of Time magazine
with Laverne Cox,
the new civil rights frontier.
While,
I'm sorry,
wait a minute.
That was the new civil rights frontier
was the cover of Time magazine with
Laverne Cox,
the hot black one and the new civil
rights.
Laverne Cox is the one in orange is the
new black black training,
um,
front cover time.
I see it.
Then you said,
well I'm sorry.
No,
fuck you.
Civil Rights is about black people.
Stop trying to take it is not about
women.
It's not about gays and it's not about
fucking trannies.
Civil rights about black people.
Stop doing this.
The lab,
what the left does is it tries to
present these issues.
Totally unrelated.
It's a little pet projects.
It's a little flexing of muscle.
Let's say.
It's like the left is at home being
like,
let's see what crazy thing we can make
people say they believe in today.
Just because we can,
you know,
let's,
and this is,
this is I'm convinced we all get
together.
You know that there must be some kind of
like left wing build a burger.
It happens like in Toronto,
it happens like in Toronto or something
and they're all together and they're all
like,
what is the craziest,
most insane,
most counter intuitive,
most like medically impossible,
most ridiculous thing we can come up
with and make everyone believe it and
say they believe it.
Because if they don't,
they'll lose their jobs.
I know.
Trannys perfect.
Right.
That's,
and then of course you've got the,
you know,
anyway,
whatever.
This is what they've done.
Nobody believes this,
but you have to say it.
It's so wrong.
And when you realize what their real
motivations aren't,
you understand why they don't care about
the science and why they're not
interested in exploring what we were
talking about,
that the treat different treatment
pathways,
they don't care about motivations,
whether it's political,
it's entirely political.
Um,
you know,
the left wants to tear down everything.
They want to just deconstruct the
differences between men and women
because they're there because they
cannot cope with the fact that women
aren't as good at some things as men.
Well,
by the way,
men aren't as good at some things as
women,
but you don't talk about that because
that doesn't suit your narrative because
you want to paint women as victims all
the time.
You know,
you want to pull apart the,
the,
you know,
they were,
they,
they want to,
they want to pull apart and destroy
everything.
Well,
isn't it bizarre to
that in this time and age of gender
neutral pronouns and these strange new
pronouns that they want to stick to the
traditional male female pronouns when it
comes to transgender people?
Of course they did without any
variation.
Like it's a she of course.
But this,
this,
this gives you an insight into what's
really happening.
I mean,
I think it tells its own story,
right?
They don't really believe it.
Well,
that's that,
that is one of the best examples of it
because they don't really buy it.
I mean,
this is like what this Justin Trudeau
situation where they're trying to have
gender neutral options and your
identification and the thing in New York
that's going on where shopkeepers and
employers can be sued by for up to a
quarter million dollars from this
changing use the right bathroom or,
or use yes.
Including artificial invented pronouns.
Like Zi Aa,
a quarter of $1 million.
I mean you're here her,
yeah,
here.
Zaire.
Geez,
you're I've been gone.
You know I'm good at grandma lucky.
No,
I'm my mother's German and so I'm good
with all the different data of genitive,
blah,
blah blah.
There are 18 new I call key gender
pronouns.
I can't keep track.
I mean one can I'm I'm like Donna total
language.
No.
Do you know like I did linguistics?
I don't like where are they coming from?
Uh,
I'm trying to remember.
I used to know about x themself.
Look at this one.
See Em self don't know xm self.
Is that Zim self?
I'm trying to write down I them x,
Y,
Z.
Gee,
this is just,
this is it.
I'm convinced the left wants to make the
world as ugly as possible.
They want everyone else to be as ugly as
they are.
These pronouns are the ugliest words
I've ever seen.
There are beautiful,
they're beautiful words and there are
ugly words and these are ugly words.
Let's look at what feminists are doing.
They know that I had a podcast about
this with a great guy,
Alex Kazemi and he is really,
really clever,
brilliant writer from Canada.
I love this guy.
He's friends with a lot of people in
Hollywood that you would,
you would know in like very,
very smart,
interesting.
And,
and he was talking about my show two
weeks ago,
last week,
two weeks ago.
I don't remember,
uh,
recently and it's good.
Episode 14,
I think,
uh,
about how beauty has become marginalized
in mainstream culture.
You know,
because feminism has told what,
you know,
the body positivity stuff,
encouraging women to get fat and get ill
and die,
which is just the worst kind of
sociopathy and selfishness and,
and just just outright lies that we tell
each other.
I'm convinced the left foot because it's
populated,
and this is all the studies say this by
just proportionately ugly people.
Because if you,
if you do the,
the,
um,
the politicians thing where you take out
Democrat and Republican,
uh,
like politicians and you ask people to
rank them in hotness,
it's almost exactly 50,
50,
you know,
and there are studies on this.
They'd left,
doesn't even disagree.
It doesn't even didn't bother denying
this anymore.
And Republicans are just way hotter.
Calkins are harder than Democrats.
Every study,
every survey,
Republicans,
absolutely all those lovely skinny
blonde bitches with Fox News ones for
sure.
There's got to be a lot of hot,
so hot.
Really like a row Vicky Yoga teachers?
No,
no,
no.
The new left,
the new social justice left the,
the fat,
ugly,
quivering.
Lena Dunham left those piercing blue
hair stuff.
Well,
these are the people running culture
now.
It's not a nice here and they are trying
to make everybody else's ugly as they
are.
But there's a bizarre trend to,
to him embrace having an obese body.
It's disgusting.
But I wrote about is that like what,
where is that empowering?
Why is it empowering to be unhealthy,
listless out of energy.
It isn't,
but what they're trying to tell the
immune system,
how is that empowering?
It's not.
Um,
and what,
what,
you know,
JC penny,
the retailer did this video recently
with a load of ham beasts.
You like that?
Like that?
I like actually ham planet.
It sounds so much better coming out of
your mouth.
If I call him ham beasts,
it sounds mean,
but you,
it's like hum beasts.
Hanbys or ham.
So
you like ham planets as another one of
my favorites.
Well,
play I guess planets,
they have their own gravity.
They have a lot of mass ham.
Feast is Nastier.
Ham planets this or him beast.
This is a bit lighter touch,
isn't it?
No.
Um,
these people,
uh,
fat,
miserable and unhappy with their own
lives trying to persuade the rest of us
that it is not just neutral but a
positive and happy and joyous thing.
Almost something to be admired and
always something to be imitated.
Being so unhealthy that your chances of
diabetes go up,
all the rest of it,
your chances of disgusting being
disgusting got 4000%.
Uh,
you know,
um,
it's very,
very strange to me.
It's very weird and it's part of this,
it's part of the left's campaign to to
make um,
ugly.
You know,
like there was a,
rush limbaugh used to say this and I
think he was right about this,
that feminism is how ugly women get
attention.
How it's,
it's a way for ugly women to get
purchase in the public sphere,
right?
This is how ugly women get,
um,
uh,
positions and he's right about that.
And this sort of social justice left,
you know,
the gender queer fat blue head facial
piercing thing is so horrifying and it's
just a way for ugly,
marginalized outcasts to make themselves
feel like they're hot people and they
want to drag everyone else down because
why?
It's a form of self harm.
It is extended adolescence writ large.
And what my guests said,
Alex,
cause he was very smart and insightful,
said,
you know,
this is it.
How,
how did we normalize Septum piercings?
How did,
you know,
we lose fantasy and aspiration in
culture.
We need those things.
We need people to look up to and to
aspire to and to admire.
And it's so horrifying that now the hot
people are feel marginalized.
Look at the cover of men's health and
how much uglier than men on the covers
of men's health,
men's health or getting right because
they weren't really relatable models.
Yeah.
The bodies or about the same.
But look at the faces,
look at how their shot now.
Now they're like friendly and
approachable and not too hot.
You know,
used to be fucking stunning people on
the cover of men's health like five
years ago.
They're getting uglier.
And you can see it even in magazines,
men's magazines.
That's a trend.
Yep.
Well,
look at the acts commercial,
the axe commercials,
this cheap deodorant,
right?
Uh,
and they,
you know,
they've got a new ad out you can find on
youtube,
which is about,
you know,
nevermind the six pack.
You know,
you've got the nose or whatever and it
says,
ugly guy with a huge nose.
Nevermind.
You know,
the biceps,
you've got your bike.
Or some shit like that encouraging men
to,
to be ugly and Dorky and unattractive
and nerdy and horrific.
Justin the same way that feminist had
been doing this to women for decades
already.
This isn't that just a manipulative ad
campaign to try to find marginalized
people and capitalize on dragging them
into your group and selling them some
shitty fucking deodorant.
It's trying to legitimize and then
ultimately to um,
celebrate irresponsible lifestyle
choices.
You talking about this as if some grand
conspiracy,
like there's a cabal of fucking lefties
out there with the evil plan to build a
book in Toronto?
No,
I believe it's,
it happens.
How else can we explain this?
It definitely happened.
Just a lot of marginalized people out
there and they find comfort in groups.
People always find comfort in numbers
and when they find someone that they
think is beautiful and privileged,
they try to lash out at them because
they've been jealous of that person for
a long time.
I just think as a whole person,
I'm feeling very personally victimized
by,
you know,
the messages that society is sending me
right now.
And I think I might go home and caught
myself.
Mm.
Yeah.
Well don't do that.
No,
I want to just think about it.
I,
I see what you're saying and I see these
trends,
but I think that you're dealing with
incredibly small numbers of people that
are very vocal.
They wheel disproportionate influence.
They have the power and they campus,
no,
no.
Everybody I talked to is like so dumb
about this.
Um,
they,
they get things done.
They make companies apologize for
things.
They change policy,
you know,
the feminist about video and video games
and say,
well,
we don't want to take your video games
away.
And then suddenly grand theft auto
disappears off the shelves of target in
Australia.
They get things done.
These people are not harmless.
These people run culture.
These people have the power to affect
what the decision making of massive
multinet considerations.
Yes.
Because they're loud because they're
organized and they have just enough not,
they're not smart that you know,
that are kind of like dangerous smart.
They just like a little bit clever and
with a little bit of like,
you know,
bare bones,
sophomore at college education in gender
theory or the rest of it.
They sound smart enough that they can
give this veneer of thoughtfulness about
something that is just hateful and
insane.
You know,
and it's so weird to me that we have
allowed the worst people in society to
run the rest of us.
We are allowing the people who hate men
to tell girls how they should be women.
We are,
you know,
that race baiters and black supremacists
to explain to us how we should treat,
you know,
how we should negotiate,
complex racial issues.
We are allowing hideous fat monsters to
tell girls no,
these people look like something recife
thy Murphy.
They look like they're from a Scifi
movie.
Put them next to Jabba the hut.
I like close your eyes and open them and
it takes you a second.
You know,
like these people would be unknown to
the America in the 1950s.
If you look at the pictures of like
women in the 1950s and you know,
you know how,
how elegant and it's felt and beautiful.
They looked and you look now and this
stuff hurts women than most.
It hurts women horribly because it's
women who are suffering from the obesity
crisis.
It's 60% of American women who are now
seriously overweight and more women are
getting obese at greater rates than the
men are.
Right?
The women are getting fatter faster than
the men.
Or did you read the new study that was
just released?
The women of today in 2016 are as heavy
as men from 1960 [inaudible] the first
time ever that's ever happened.
Right?
But the thing is that w um,
the number,
the number of women and the rate of
increase is skyrocketing for girls.
Why?
Because these ham beasts are telling
them that being fat is fine and that fat
people can see where Howard people can
do anything thin.
People can do it.
We'll shut the fucking fridge.
Then if you,
if you could do everything that thin
people can do,
close the fridge,
the downward,
the ice cream scoop.
Look at this.
The average American woman weighs 166
pounds.
That's a lot.
That is a lot.
That is,
that's obese.
That's a law for a woman.
That's a lot.
You know,
that's crazy.
That is the same weight as the average
American male from the 1960s and look
men,
and not completely,
you know,
men and not,
uh,
um,
immune from this effect.
We're all getting fatter,
but women are getting a lot faster,
a lot faster.
But that's a disturbing a number.
Like for,
for that to be the average weight of a
woman,
that's obesity.
And that's also diet.
I mean,
that's not like lifting weights on these
women are done.
Crossfit,
you can go in,
squats says you don't need to do
exercise to lose weight.
It will be better if you did because
your whole body gets stronger and
better.
And you're the expert in this.
But all you need to do,
if you want to lose 200 pounds,
just stop fucking eating.
Right.
I got in trouble on twitter that you
won't have seen this,
but I got in huge trouble and treated
for fat shaming someone at the gym.
Um,
and I was like,
no,
this is disgusting.
I don't want to have to look at this.
Right.
Well this is how first and then they'll
go to the gym.
Fat Shaming works right.
And I was doing this person a favor.
I was doing this person a favor because,
no,
I wrote an article about this.
I'm serious.
All the studies say as long as you wrote
an article,
it must be true.
You're getting snippy again.
My,
my,
my peace drew attention to the real
point of my comics,
which studied this.
The studies show fat shaming works.
But did you point out an individual
person and highlight them and did you
identify them?
No,
I just did it from behind.
Oh,
so that it didn't show their face?
No.
Okay.
It's perfectly fine.
And,
you know,
look,
this is how people get thin worrying if
it could be them next,
right?
You could somebody tell us,
are you using argument for that?
You know,
look,
I encourage you to go read the piece.
Um,
and it's,
it's quite enjoy your writing.
So I'll check it out.
Thank you.
Uh,
if you're listening to this,
I think it's,
if you go to,
I think if you've got a bright bottle
comm slash minor,
that sort of stuff,
buying about me so it will be there
somewhere.
Uh,
you can,
um,
you can find it.
And I wrote two things at JC penny.
Um,
well I wrote a thing about the JC penny
thing,
seeing this fat shaming thing.
It was disgusting.
Somebody's very hurtful comment
underneath it.
They sit down.
This is 1600 words of tenuously
connected fat jokes.
If I didn't know better,
I would have got the impression that you
were claiming the moral high ground
merely as an excuse to call people hand
planets.
I was very hurt by that criticism.
I think it's accurate and excellent.
That's a good to be a criticism and is a
second.
What I,
what I explained in my followup piece,
he's like,
do some good.
Call someone fat today.
It works.
Don't believe these bullshit studies
that come out.
There's the only serious study that says
that fat shaming doesn't work is from
University College London and it is
hopelessly flawed.
It deals with a tiny group of like 50
year olds and upwards.
And that's not what this is directed is
not what the messaging is directed to
because they're using young 25 to 35
year old singers and writers in these
commercials telling 20 year old girls
they can eat what the fuck they want.
This is not about 50 year olds,
right?
So don't believe this stuff because it's
not true.
You've got to dig under the surface fat
shit.
Of course fat shaming works and anyway,
so I got in trouble for this,
this tweet,
but I was doing that person trouble
though.
Like what?
What does that mean?
Negative attention.
But you knew that that was coming
anyway.
That's not true.
Well,
I'm,
no I don't,
cause I tried to do a,
I tried to do it like a,
you know,
they did those like celebrities read
mean tweets thing.
I want to do my own version of that and
I couldn't find any criticism.
Everyone loves me so much.
I'd like please,
but no,
seriously I went out,
I thought my fans were unshockable and I
have found something that they don't
like and it's fat shaming.
Well if you're listening to this,
like you know,
buckle up buttercups cause there's a
plenty more coming.
This is no,
this is not,
I'm not going to be,
I didn't back down for feminism.
I didn't back down for Islam and I
didn't back down for black lives matter.
You think your quivering acids are going
to make me,
are going to make me do a uturn well
you're wrong.
No,
this is,
you know,
this is something I don't want to see
when I go out and that person in the gym
to your point about,
you know,
working out that person,
the gym,
it doesn't need to be in the gym.
He was like 350 pounds or something.
The gym is worthless.
Don't bother lifting anything.
True.
Yeah,
no,
it is.
Exercise is a great way to lose weight.
You it's not.
It's cardio is pointless.
Cardio is a masochist.
To Way to lose weight is completely
pointless.
You can do some wacky like nutrient
partitioner that you're entering into my
realm.
Well,
it is not true at all.
350 pounds.
What is he realistic distinctly going?
It will elevate his metabolism,
will aid in his body burning off at,
the main thing that needs to do is just
calories in,
calories out,
and he'd be 350 pounds.
The best thing you can do is just stop
eating.
This is a person who is clearly taking
in seven hours,
10,000
ice either because it's a day stopping
eating actually slows your metabolism
down because your body thinks it's in
famine mode,
the right things,
the right to change your gut bacteria.
There's a bunch of different factors,
but one of the,
one of the big ones is sugar,
sugar and simple.
When I say stop eating fiercely,
that's a shorthand for don't go to
Mcdonald's anymore.
Unhealthy food.
Obviously.
What has sugar and the carbs,
their body would miraculously shrink.
Well,
I've done it.
I'm literally,
I have,
I've told you I've lost like 40 pounds
and four inches off my waist and like
four and a half.
You can comment on it.
I can be,
if you're fat,
it's because you're lazy.
Like stop saying that.
It is some kind of like hormonal
deficiency or,
or some emotional disorder.
Don't stop inflicting yourself on the
rest of the world.
I don't want to see you at the gym.
And two,
you are an acceptable size.
I don't want to see you.
You are horrendous and you are putting
me off my workouts.
Stay home,
eat better food.
If you have to run,
get a running machine delivered to your
house.
Amazon has them.
They start at $100.
I don't want to see you and I don't
care.
And I,
you know these people,
I was on Reddit.
I was like a huge thread on reddit lost
like the last three days.
You know,
this monster is like fat shaming,
some poor,
innocent guy,
the gym,
he's not innocent.
It his,
his actions have consequences.
The rest of the world not least
aesthetic consequences.
I don't want to have to look at you.
Well,
um,
I think that if someone being fat at the
gym throws you off your workout,
you are not dedicated to your task.
Sir.
Well maybe my not my attention,
my salute.
People that are fat that are taking a
chance,
they're doing something different.
Making it to say,
hey,
you're turning your life around.
Do it hard.
Do it at home.
Like I saw this guy at the gym doing his
legs were like hanging out of his
shorts.
Enormous fat guy,
but he had the balls to go out in
public.
Like that didn't work.
He shouldn't,
he should stay home in Shaman stove.
I just agree.
It's terrible for the immune system.
The Punch cards from whatever disgusting
takeout.
You're going to delete the numbers from
your phone for the local pizzeria,
ordering some Kale,
some protein,
seven like vegetables and fruit and
start drinking water and have a good
healthy life.
But do it at home until you aren't
acceptable size.
And I don't look at you and want to
vomit because frank like,
you know,
fine,
I'm easily distracted as you can tell
from my scatty conversation.
Right.
But I v I,
you know,
I'm very easily distracted.
I'm trying to focus on finishing my
[inaudible] and my attention is drawn to
this like gigantic,
just,
just celestial body entering in,
you know,
to the sound of thunder and lightning
cause it's got its own fucking weather
system.
You know,
I just,
I'm sorry,
I don't know what it is that surprises
people so much as a gay man would be
bitchy about weight,
but I just,
I'm sick of it.
I'm sick of it,
you know,
just stop it.
You're selfish.
Horrible.
People like the disabled,
like people in wheelchairs.
Incredibly selfish.
So no,
no,
no.
Do you know what we have to do?
You know what?
We have to do this.
Your trolling,
is God too far?
Do you know what we should be crippled.
Stay home.
You know what you look like in our
children?
They are monsters.
No,
they have to their look joy.
We have to do an England now.
I was a of before I was a generalist,
right?
I used to build houses.
It's why I can afford,
can survive on a journalist salary now
and we,
you know,
there's it like an ordinance,
you know in,
in England where you have to put the
light switch is not here where everyone
needs them.
But here where the wheelchair people
need them.
Why I'm not selling my house to,
so I'm not how to say my house to
somebody with no legs.
Like what the hell is going on this,
these,
this is the supposedly these tiny little
minorities and people who say they speak
for those minorities who don't because
most of the people that I know,
you know,
I know veterans who are in wheelchairs
who would probably laugh at the
conversation we just had rather than
getting offended and then we'd say,
yeah,
put the light switch is wherever the
fuck you want.
But no,
these sort of stupid lobbies where all
of us has to calf to count out these
tiny slices of society.
It's ridiculous.
Know you have to put these lights,
which is done with it inconvenient for
99.8%
of the rest of the population.
And then you,
uh,
these,
these disabled people were demanding
like concrete ramps on the way up to the
council building so he can go and
collect their disability benefit and
their welfare checks twice a year.
Just get someone to help you.
There was somebody in the UK who filed a
lawsuit against a council.
We didn't have accessible ramps.
My God,
these people are out of control.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with a wheelchair ramp.
No,
probably not.
I might have got a little bit,
you get a little look,
I've got a little carried away.
She stuck with the fat thing cause I
don't know,
I mean the fat thing I was,
I was sympathetic on and there is a
thing there where you're making sense
were making people feel bad instead of
saying you're beautiful.
No matter what you are,
you're not place.
It's unhealthy.
And it's not smart.
This beautiful at any size,
it's not true.
You know,
at the Nep is young and unusual.
It's unique.
That's why it's so special.
Well there was,
you know,
there are objective beauty standards for
men and women.
Sure.
Uh,
and most,
you know,
there are people who most people find
hot and those people tend not to be the
size,
the size of houses,
you know,
or,
or how about are never,
and usually when people say that they
are hot,
they're being disingenuous,
they're applying these artificial
standards,
making a fake standard bullshit.
What do you think by the way of the,
cause I was talking to,
he was actually,
I think it was in culture as well.
I was talking to somebody today about,
you know,
all this kind of like sexual harassment
stuff,
um,
sexual harassment stuff that women do
now when they've been touched on the leg
or whatever.
And Anna has this theory.
I actually,
I don't know whether it was,
I shouldn't drop her in it cause I can't
remember.
It was a part of the conversation on the
podcast.
So let me just say,
this is my theory.
So this is not ankle to theory.
She is not guilty because I can't
honestly remember whether she said it's
on all the way she said it.
But there's,
what do you think about this,
this sexual harassment craze right now?
It's really just a way for women to tell
you they've been hit on,
isn't it?
It's really just a way for women to
saving up the somebody well known,
but not just that,
but somebody was expressing sexual
interest in me because all of these like
quote unquote rape stories from campuses
that don't actually involve any sex.
Um,
of course the ones that do involve sex
rape stories are all for all frauds and
hoaxes.
Um,
the ones that don't,
the ones that involve sex,
they sort of,
they're all hideous.
Someone touched my breast.
How awful.
What's a woman really telling you there?
She's telling you that,
uh,
someone was sexually interested in her.
It's the sort of bragging,
isn't it?
Well,
it only does.
One does really touch your breasts.
Are we supposed to know now?
And it's always people,
some guy just comes up and grabs your
tit.
Oh God,
that is sexual assault.
It's not.
Our parents' generation would have
turned around and said,
Kia,
keep your fucking hands to yourself and
moved on with their lives.
They wouldn't have gone into university
administrators and tried to destroy the
guy's reputation in life over.
It's not that big a deal because I might
touch your to get over it.
That's a big deal.
That's a no person that doesn't have any
respect to somebody else's body.
It's rude,
but when you enlarge the take those
people out of campus,
you shouldn't be allowed to do this.
That someone's pussy that you'd be able
to grab girl's ass and squeezy.
Obviously there's a line,
but listen,
but you can fuck with someone
emotionally.
We don't do that.
You're making physical contact.
You on inappropriate where an adult,
you know what appropriate behavior is.
18 and 19 year old kids who are coming
to college and this is where you,
you,
you know messily exploring their
sexuality.
Yes.
Exploring other people.
There are all sorts of confused,
awkward situations in those years at
college.
What we should not do is be going in and
legislating which colleges are now
trying to do legislative,
the sex lives of people who are
discovering each other and don't know
what the rules are yet.
Right.
Everybody knows you don't walk up to a
girl and grab her and they know they
should
learn and the best way to learn is what
is a woman's at school.
No,
no,
no.
The Way to learn is a woman,
Tony Man,
and saying,
keep your fucking hands to yourself and
your friends saying,
dude,
what are you doing?
That's how you or your friend goes,
dude,
that was awesome.
I got it on camera.
Well,
they're always going to be people like
that.
You can't,
you know,
you want to on a mass recommendations
because he touched him.
So his reputation is shitty.
Well,
Sean grabbing strangers,
tit,
no,
you'll see all this is,
this is a mistake.
Your natural instinct toward chivalry
and gallantry,
which is to your great credit,
is I think blinding you with the reality
of what's happening on college campuses,
which is young boys are effectively
being criminalized for normal
exploration of their sexuality.
There's a very specific example you're
talking about unwanted grabbing a
breast.
I do think that there's a lot of people
trying to hit on people in a clumsy way
that gets misinterpreted or that's an
issue we talking about physically
grabbing someone's tip,
which is really crossing the line.
People grabbed each other for kisses all
the time.
Like in its student nightclubs.
People were just like,
you know,
like go in for a kiss and maybe like
their lips touch or something.
Is that sexual assault?
Just gimme a break.
That's is people now that's different.
Yeah.
We're talking about unwanted tit
grazers.
So that's worse than like putting your
tongue down someone's throat when they
don't want it.
Well,
if they don't want it,
you should probably know when someone
wants to be kissed.
Yeah.
But you know if that's exactly my point,
they don't,
you're at college,
you may have been to an all boys high
school.
Right.
You made learning come to terms with the
other,
you know,
with the opposite sex,
you are discovering your own body,
their body.
You might not even know if you're gay.
Right.
Or you don't know what the rules are.
You don't know what the rules are.
I know what the rules are.
18 year old kids do not know what the
rules are and to have their entire half
their reputations destroyed forever is
obscene.
And I think there's a difference between
when did the scenario you're describing
now,
which is like a nightclub scene.
Two people are close to each other,
guy moves in for a kiss,
takes a breast and goes in for a kiss.
I mean these things just happen.
My God,
have you,
if these,
if these campus administrators walked
into a gay club,
they would,
their heads would explode with the
amount of like inappropriate cock
touching and all the rest of it.
But that's excludes dudes with dude's.
There's no Yang.
It's all younger lesbians don't have sex
at all,
do they?
Well,
if they do,
it's not the same.
If that's another weird thing I wanted
to bring up about transgender people is
that a lot of them become lesbians.
They turn into women,
but then they,
they wanna have sex with men.
This is sort of another way that they
regret comes out,
isn't it?
Well,
that's a Bruce Jenner thing and I know
several other ones as well.
Or this general lesbian,
did we have to call it?
Do you have to call him a lesbian now?
Well,
he just,
Bruce Bruce Jenner,
winner of the 200 meters is not as well.
What's weird is when you go back to that
era of the Olympics,
like what does it say?
Does it say Bruce Jenner one or does it
say,
Katelyn,
do they changed it?
I've looked,
no,
no.
They've changed it.
They've changed it in wikipedia.
In wikipedia it says,
it says worse even than you think it's
as Katelyn Jana was the winner of the
men's too.
That's what it says now.
That's what that is.
Madness.
I'm serious.
Just says,
God,
that's so crazy.
I know.
I know what that is.
Uh,
that is a sign of the times what
happened to us?
Why did we get so bizarre and how did it
happen so quickly and services,
uh,
gave up the culture wars.
That's a simplistic gas.
No,
it's,
well,
sometimes the sequester accelerating.
There's an accelerating attitude that
that somehow or another is prevalent
throughout college campuses throughout.
It's the,
the,
it's not the same left of the 1960s and
the 70s it's this new left whereas the
left is mutated slightly.
It's got more hardline and crazier,
but it is the same people.
I mean the campus,
you know,
the,
the same professors who around in the
70s and eighties and now still work in
the gender studies department and the
same people that have got their views.
But my point is the right doesn't really
embrace much different values and rules
than they did in the 70s,
80s and nine.
No,
that's not true.
You just have no idea what they do
because they've completely exited the
conversation.
The right has not bothered to engage on
kit,
on university campuses.
Uh,
it has not put up a fight in education
or entertainment.
It is not part of fight in the,
in the media.
It's not put up a fight anyway.
It's given.
It is,
it doesn't fought and lost the culture
wars.
It merely handed them over to the left
because the right the right is full of
dorks.
And geeks and loses and Weirdos who are
obsessed with money and power.
It's all they care about is Wall Street
and Washington.
What they forgot is that people don't
vote for Wall Street and Washington.
People vote according to their values
and they learn their values through
culture,
through art,
through what they watch on TV,
the music they listen to and the the
right just handed that over to the left
and the left has run those things for 30
years.
And that's why things are so crazy
because the people running it had been
unopposed for 30 years.
So they've user called evermore wildly,
wildly hysterical and crazy because we
all need healthy opposition,
you know,
but you don't think there's been a
comparable sort of shift in the right
where the left has gotten wilder and
crazier with their idea is the right is
not the right or it hasn't gone crazy.
If anything,
the right it's going to be terrian.
If you look at the most exciting bits of
the right,
perhaps breitbart where I work,
um,
I think a large proportion of trump's
voters,
and I think a lot of just conservatives
in general reacting against political
correctness and responding to the worst
excesses of nannying pole clutching
culture.
I think the writers become a
libertarian.
I think Pearl clutching,
you know,
sort of like fainting couch comes up,
right?
I think for many on the right,
um,
the reaction gets political correctness
has pushed them in a libertarian
direction.
And if you want to be a libertarian
today,
you pretty much have to be a
conservative.
And I think also,
um,
the other thing has happened on the
right is the death of really of,
of the reduced influence of religion and
politics,
which you will probably find welcome has
meant,
I think for people under 40,
the social conservatism of their
parents' and grandparents' generation is
effectively dead and gone.
And the most exciting young
conservatives don't look like all
conservatives.
They're not like rich old white man who
you know,
hate gay marriage and our,
sound faintly racist after a couple of
glasses of wine.
They are young,
interesting,
quirky,
funny,
dissident punks.
You know,
who only find room to grow and be
dangerous and difficult and expand on
the right.
I think I fall into that bracket,
but also a lot of trump's young fans
fall into that bracket.
People who just want the freedom to say
do and be anything.
There's nowhere for the left arm.
There's nowhere left on the left for
them.
That is a bizarre shift.
Yeah.
That is a very bizarre shift we're
getting.
Being accepting of that kind of behavior
is much more thought of as something
over,
it's now a conservative thing.
That's bizarre.
It's now a conservative thing and I
don't think any,
I don't think anybody can realistically
claim otherwise.
If you are a dissident,
a mischief maker,
if you believe in pushing boundaries in
sex,
culture,
art,
philosophy,
literature,
whatever,
whatever it is,
right?
If you want to be dangerous,
you have to be a conservative.
And the left did this,
the right,
it didn't do it.
The right didn't win any arguments.
They just,
the left just got overconfident and got
carried away and alienated the rest of
us.
You know,
I could've,
I could've been like a center lefty if,
if,
if they were more sensible on,
I don't know,
economics or whatever.
But on social issues,
I'm a perfect example.
You know,
I'm,
I'm foul mouth and young and gay and
love black whatever and all the rest of
it.
I shouldn't,
I shouldn't be a conservative on paper.
Right.
But I am,
because the left is ejected me because
I've got the wrong opinions about things
and because it won't let me talk how I
want to talk because you have honest
opinions about feminism,
honest opinions about social justice.
And so,
so I'm,
I'm persona non,
gosh to the left,
I only got one place left to go.
And,
and this is how the left has created,
you know,
hundreds of thousands if not millions of
trump voters.
You know,
the,
the nannying and the,
and the,
the controlling that school mom
missioners you know,
where they want to order your crayons
and treat us all like children has
pushed so many of us over to the right.
And I'm like,
I'm,
I'm far right now,
I'm as right as it gets.
You know,
I'm so,
so I'm so far right on economics or the
rest of it's social.
Obviously a bit more,
get more complex,
but you know,
on the borders,
on trade,
you know,
I'm a,
I'm a trump guy now I might have ended
up very differently if I hadn't been
ejected by the left.
But do you have any problems with trump
with his behavior,
with any of his past statements?
Nothing.
He's a perfect angel from heaven,
but that's,
you're,
you're being silly.
Oh No,
I think he's great.
Well,
what's he done well?
Like,
okay.
Tell me what the worst things you think
he's done it.
Well,
business wise there's been,
uh,
well this is one of the things that Joey
Diaz has talked about in the podcast
that he knew back from a long time ago
in the construction business.
Trump was famous for having these
projects and not paying people and
there,
it doesn't sound very likely if trump
doesn't sound likely,
where are these people?
Who are they?
They wouldn't have come out in the press
by now.
I've come out in the press,
there's quite a few of them.
You know,
he'll,
he'll pull some of them up so you can
see some of the stories.
But was it a what one New York paper?
I've,
I've heard a couple of times too.
There's a bunch of like smaller time
contractors that would take him,
oh please.
Some dis,
some,
some disgruntled little mom and pop
shop.
Then a mom and pop
through.
I didn't get construction company and
they would get a bid to work on one of
his buildings and they would spend all
this money on it and it would start
working and then he wouldn't pay them.
And in doing that,
crushed a lot of her business has a
history of not paying his bills that
offers some insights into his
personality.
USA Today is posted an explosive
investigative story about what appears
to be a deep aversion presumptive gop
nomination nominee Donald Trump has to
paying his bills.
The short version,
USA Today claims is based on what looks
like some rather impressive reporting.
Trump has for decades looked for just
about any excuse he could find to stiff
everyone from plumbers to can't make
this up.
Lawyers who represented him and
nonpayment lawsuits.
That's kind of fun.
It's kind of boss.
Every bad story about trump has a
punchline and that just makes you think
fat.
At least 60 lawsuits along with hundreds
of Liens,
judgments and other government filings
reviewed by USA Today.
Network document.
People who have accused trump and his
businesses of failing to pay for their
work and any it doesn't sound goes on.
It doesn't sound good.
I'm not going to defend that.
Good.
Thank you.
Um,
that doesn't sound good at all.
I,
I have a quiet,
close follower of trump.
I didn't know that.
So I will,
I will look into this,
a mom and that my dishwasher in Florida,
Glass Company in New Jersey,
a carpet company,
a plumber,
painters,
48 waiters,
14 waiters of lawsuits that God,
I mean it's him.
I think,
you know,
dozens of bartenders and other hourly
workers at resorts and clubs east.
When you run,
when you want to imply,
you know,
this is $1 billion empire,
you're going to get things like this.
And when you do it for decades,
it's not going to be difficult.
I mean,
the Washington,
Richard Branson doesn't have those one
to let me know,
but if he ran for president,
we might find out that you would have
to,
you know,
cause he's not that kind of guy.
Oh please.
He's a very altruistic guy,
is he don't,
she is.
No,
I think Richard Branson is one of the
worst examples of a sort of,
um,
you know,
quiet power bond,
this globalist elite that wants to break
down borders and destroy all our
countries.
Richard Branson is about as close to the
devils.
It's possible to get a no,
no.
I do know impression of him.
Oh,
come on.
Neca island,
the guests he has at necker island.
Do you even read this stuff?
I mean,
for somebody who's,
you know,
what's Necker island?
Richard Branson's island,
where he lives this wonderful guy.
You know so much about,
well,
why?
I don't know about where he lives and
just nobody's business.
What does he do much evidently?
Cause that's where he strikes all these
deals.
But I mean,
what does it,
what's so awful revisit the subject of
Richard Branson on his island?
Well,
just the guest to see has on this island
very suspect.
The globalist.
It's,
I mean,
it's basically like build a book,
you know,
little,
politicians,
Bang.
Nice feeds them some guava smoothies.
I just can't,
I just can't relate to them.
I just hair.
He is disgusting.
Collin control wearing flip flops on the
roof from his own fucking island.
What a madman.
Paula,
I just,
I just couldn't relate to ginger's.
I'm sorry.
Oh,
how dare you.
I mean,
he did,
but he seems to have a very positive and
a very inspirational message.
It's good at branding himself that way.
Yes.
You think it's all bullshit?
Well,
you're looking at me sideways.
I'm just asking you an honest question.
Just have these weird,
like I listen to you all the time
because I find your conversations with
people.
Very interesting.
You just have these weird,
no,
there was,
this was,
this was an uncomplicated sandwich,
so don't think we yet.
Okay.
Thank you.
Anyway,
by the way,
my favorite story.
Okay.
He wins.
Look at her.
My favorite real well,
he wins.
He's got this naked girl on his back and
she's,
uh,
she's not any less pit of degenerate
sexual encounters.
Necker island.
You mean he's balling out of control
tubs every day.
He's like,
he's like I said a shit damn bull's area
and you know,
he's like Dan was Dan Bilzerian without
the personality,
you know.
Okay.
Anyway,
so what's wrong with,
by the way,
the compliment question that that's not
a real thing and compliment sandwich.
No.
Um,
the,
my favorite story about Jennifer Lopez
ever,
and I don't know if it's true,
but I'm thinking of like making people
do this with me now,
um,
is,
you know,
she was,
I don't know if it's true.
I hope it's true.
It's one of those stories like Mariah
Carey is like,
you know,
Oh,
I'd love to be talking about Africa.
You know,
I'd love to be thin like that,
but not with all the flies and death and
stuff.
That's not true.
She never said that she should have said
it a hilarious no,
it is good.
Like the justine sacco quote,
she was that woman that got fired.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
The AIDS joke.
Yeah.
It was just kidding.
I'm not white.
I'm just kidding.
I'm white.
I hope I don't get aids.
Just kidding.
I'm white.
Fairly funny.
It's funny.
Fairly fun.
I'm,
it's funny.
Yeah,
I thought so.
It's inappropriate.
That's why it's funny.
Few Gorka,
I liked this,
this fee for Jennifer Lopez thing and I
hope it's true.
Where she's like,
she,
she cuts off and integrate.
She says,
you don't do this very often.
Do you?
And he's like,
what?
And she's like,
compliment,
question.
And he just looked so hard,
isn't it?
Of course they're real,
I hope so.
I hope so too.
Isn't it?
Great compliment,
compliment,
compliment question.
I make my,
I make my assistant do that now
sometimes when people are interviewing
me like just to fuck with them at the
beginning to get them on a back foot
because they don't quite have the balls
to,
cause I was like,
I'm not a star.
Like I'm just like,
you know,
I made a little name for myself in the
campus stuff and I'm like,
people know me quite well as a
journalist and the rest of it,
you know,
I'm becoming popular but I'm not there
yet.
I'm not,
we're not,
we're not at Joe Rogan levels of
notoriety yet compliment.
But I get him to do it because even even
with my sort of lowly profile such as it
is,
people still aren't quite comfortable,
confident calling me out on it.
And they were,
they're not brave enough to laugh.
So I have my assistant just interrupted.
Sorry.
Could you just compliment,
compliment question.
I'd love to see the look on their face
and they fucking process of that.
Why did they go do it?
It's great.
They just freeze and then they do it and
then they do it.
They have to,
you know,
I love your work.
You're really great.
And your hair looks nice today.
Can I just ask you about see easy,
not hard,
easy anyways,
anyway.
Um,
yes.
No,
I was going to say,
you have these weird,
you're like,
you're like the most skeptical person in
some regards and you'll be like,
no.
Like,
you're like a truffle hound.
You know,
you want to get down,
try and you want to what?
A truffle hound is a very,
very obscure reference.
Well,
not if you had a lot of truffles.
No.
I,
um,
that,
that's what they use in Italy to pick
them up.
They use truffle hounds.
Do you know that?
Yes.
Yeah.
Sometimes these pigs too,
right?
They do.
They use pigs too.
But pink sometimes have a habit of
eating,
eating the truffles.
Indeed.
Set truffle anchors.
Dogs don't like truffles.
Uh,
no.
You're like a truffle hound,
you know,
just sort of like rushing around for the
truth and talking about studies and you
know,
way,
way higher standard of debate and
conversation than you normally here,
you know,
and these kinds of on these kinds of
shows,
you know,
this is why we are so popular.
And then sometimes you're just like,
no,
he's a really nice guy.
He seems like a nice guy.
You didn't say.
Seems you didn't say seems and Ian and
you didn't know about,
should brands didn't know about necker
island on the name of his island?
No,
he owns an island.
Me,
he owns a lot of shit.
He owns Virgin Airlines.
Well why do you think you said no?
Why do you ever fly virgin?
Yes,
it's virgin.
Atlantic's very upper class is good.
It's a good song when they tell you the
fucking seat belt thing and they have
that nice bar that it's lovely.
It's very,
very good.
Very good.
An Interior is nice.
Do you know frank?
I,
on the rare occasions that I had to fly
coach,
um,
I always try to do on virgin cause even
even economy on virgin is quite nice.
Yeah.
They're nice plans.
He's got it nailed.
Yeah.
Good.
But,
but probably not a nice guy.
Uh,
who knows,
not us.
He seems like if I had to pick out like
the philanthropic,
well surely there's Bill Gates.
Yes.
He's a nice guy too.
Yeah.
I think Bill Gates is a nice guy.
He seems to be a very nice guy.
He seems cool.
Yeah.
Well he does a lot of legitimate charity
work and donates millions and you one of
these people that you can afford to at
that level mean it's all right off for
him for sure.
But I think bill,
the bill and Melinda Gates thing,
that is genuinely what they do now.
You know,
that's their life now.
They're trying to really like fix things
like malaria and all the rest of it.
Beautiful.
Yeah,
no it is.
It's great.
And,
and you know,
it's,
it's interesting.
I can't think of another example of
somebody who was so hated for like two
decades as he was when he was running
Microsoft.
So completely successfully reversed
there and reputation in just 15 years.
You know,
there's an interesting,
totally and completely one 80.
His,
his,
uh,
public,
reputation.
Yeah.
How did they do that?
One of the things he did,
I think sincerity and intelligence and
you know,
he just started speaking honestly and
plainly,
and he did less but better.
He wasn't,
he wasn't a fame whore.
He wasn't demanding attention.
He just said,
here's what I'm going to,
here's what I'm going to do in my life
now,
and spoke simply and seriously and
actually did things.
And who's that crazy guy that he had run
his company,
the big,
fat,
Bald Guy when run Roma bomber,
I lot around screaming and yelling and
he's sweating and he's out.
It looks good.
I love,
I love Steve Former.
I loved him.
That video is off God damn classic.
But if I worked for Microsoft would be
terrified.
I'm like,
I have to,
I have to muster up this level of
enthusiasm.
Although I get fired.
Yeah,
there he is.
Look at this.
Yeah,
the monkey something.
I love him.
This is nuts.
He's still like this because there's
this,
there's a video of him like at
basketball games and he's like this in
the front row in the basketball game.
He's,
this is just who he is.
Bruce from sterling.
Yeah.
Oh that's right.
Yes.
He would know that.
He probably orchestrated the fucking
wire tap.
It was probably a long chess game.
That son of a bitch.
That is one of the most bizarre things
ever because if you listen to what that
guy said,
that cost him the clippers.
That is one of the weirdest.
And you're wondering outside my area,
Donald Sterling was the guy.
Well it,
it enters into your area.
Tell me about the,
tell me about it.
Cause it deals with social justice.
He was a clippers owner to one of the
bigger basketball teams,
right?
The Los Angeles area.
Um,
he has his girlfriend and he says,
I don't want you taking pictures as
black guys because she takes a lot of
pictures of these black guys on her
instagram page.
He goes,
I don't mind if you fuck them,
but I don't want you taking pictures
now.
They conveniently left out.
They conveniently left out the,
I don't care if you fuck them,
I just don't because it embarrassed him
because everybody knew it was his
girlfriend and she fucks everybody.
Yeah.
So she's got pictures with all these
stud athletes,
right?
Everyone knows these shut athletes or
bone in her writing a trainer is Tim.
He said,
I don't like you taking pictures.
What'd you show me there?
So here it goes.
Bothered me a lot that you want to
broadcast that you're associating with
black people.
Do you have to the man believing to be
sterling says you can sleep with them.
You could bring them in,
you could do whatever you want.
The little I ask you is not to promote
it on and not to bring them to my games.
That's nice.
That's him just saying,
please don't humiliate me because you
know,
you,
you're my girlfriend.
Yes.
And um,
you are ritually humiliating me in
public,
but,
and he's just asking her not to do it,
but she specifically said black eyes.
Like what if she brought in some fucking
vikings,
giant bearded ax wielding.
It's a complement to the black people
because he's,
he's identifying them as like a,
as the master race they are.
Um,
and he's like,
you know,
I'm just some little white guy and you
keep going out with these like massive
six foot four athletes and you're
humiliating me.
Please stop it.
Yeah.
And obviously if she was a coal burner
and she's just going out and fucking
black guys and she's just got coal
burner and so what they call them?
Yeah.
Or,
or a snicker liquor.
Put a Kolber.
Yeah.
Holy Shit.
That's funny.
Or a a loco,
which is the other one I left too.
It's a good one.
Yeah.
Like that,
but not as much as Colbert and corden.
It's just like an old nowhere.
I got it.
I think it might be something like 1940
is racist thing,
but I'm going to reclaim it because I'm
a allowed because I am one.
That's the rule,
right?
Yeah.
That's the rule these days.
That's the rule these days in coal
burner,
sir.
Yes.
That's the rule these days.
I can say whatever I want as long as I
am it.
Um,
no,
she's only fucking black guys and she's
not really putting out for rich white
husband and he's boyfriend.
She has a water,
he has a wife.
Who Cares?
This is example of the media,
right?
And just,
just cherry picking to say that everyone
is racist when everyone's not racist
because his primary motivation in this
statement had nothing to do with race.
And you could say,
why did he need to say black at all?
But who cares?
That wasn't what he was asking her
about.
It wasn't the thrust of his remarks and
the media because it is populated by
children,
not by adults.
Uh,
did this to him.
If it sounds like,
I mean,
I don't know,
I'm speculating.
The literal,
literally the tiny bit you just told me.
But um,
but it doesn't sound,
it doesn't seem,
it sounds to me to be in your words,
problematic.
Yeah.
And well,
here's another issue with it.
It was a private conversation that he
did not think was being broadcast.
And people are allowed to say fucked up
things that maybe they shouldn't have
said and it doesn't have to be shared to
the whole world.
And then he loses his team.
This is the craziest part about people
bastards.
The president of the NBA makes his
speech,
first of all,
it looks like Nosferatu.
Right?
He looks like he just fucking,
the guy,
old president president,
he looks like you popped out of a coffin
and he sits straight up and he reads
this fucking canned ridiculous speech
about the horrors of what this guy look
at him.
Look at Nosferatu wow.
No,
no white to his eyes.
It's all black.
You wouldn't see him out in sunlight.
Right.
That's a demon.
Even of the white stuff is all red blood
behind.
He's scary.
He's like a pure blood.
You know the ones that are like Paler
and older than are the vows.
He wasn't,
he wasn't made.
He was born,
born vampire.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
And Anyway,
he was very unreasonable the way he
described it.
Look with what the guy said was not
nice.
It was sorted.
It was gross,
but more gross.
I would have said if I was him,
how gross is it that we're listening to
this man's private conversation and
judge him?
I want people to say this stuff in
public.
Not only that,
the guy was drunk,
okay.
He was drunk.
He was with his mistress.
I didn't care about anything.
He said,
that seems completely reasonable
statement to me.
Well,
you're allowed to say fucked up things.
Okay?
If you'll go from cheating on you with a
bunch of black guys,
you would not say,
why are you cheating on with me?
All these guys,
you would say,
no,
but listen,
isn't it?
If you,
if you had a girlfriend,
of course.
No,
go,
whatever.
Cheat on you because look at you.
But Oh,
so it was nice.
I know,
I know.
My boss now is so,
so used to these,
um,
these sort of a flippant compliments.
He now no longer believes.
Then he says,
you have to give me the same exact
compliment three times,
so I know you actually mean it because
he's a three.
Compliments,
compliments and then a statement.
Yeah,
a compliment,
compliment,
question.
He's like,
if you don't give me on three separate
occasions,
unrelated,
separate occasions,
the same compliment.
I'll know.
It's just you being flipping a
flatterer,
which I think is reasonable,
but no.
If you had a girlfriend and she
was cheating on you and she was
exclusively cheating on you with black
guys,
when you had a conversation with her,
you would not say,
I don't mind you sleeping with all these
men.
You would say,
I don't mind you sleeping with all these
black men.
You would do that.
That's how people talk because it's a
group that is very identifiably,
not you and what you're,
what you're implicitly saying is what is
it that they have that I don't have?
Well,
obviously that's what's going on there.
He's being racist.
He's identifying a pattern of behavior
from her and it's like that's how we
would all talk.
But he specifically broadcast that
you're with them.
It's even more bizarre than that.
Puts even more bizarre because,
cause he said,
I don't mind if you fucked them.
Isn't that the best fucking boyfriend in
the world is funny too that they bleeped
out fuck.
And they put in in parentheses sleep
with like they change.
People are dumb.
They change like the,
like the trend,
like the Orlando transcript,
which wasn't allowed to have any mention
of Islam or isis whatsoever.
What do you mean?
Did you know that?
No,
no.
The way that people,
this,
I hate this cause I'm like a free speech
fundamentalist.
I want people to have conversations like
that and far worse in public all the
time.
Everywhere because I want to rob words
of their magical powers.
Uh,
I want to know what people,
what's really going on.
Really think I want people,
if somebody wants to use the n word
because they don't like black people,
I want to know about it.
I want to know who the racists are.
I want to know who the sexist so I want
to know,
cause I wanna be friends.
I'm kidding.
I'm joking.
Joking.
Totally joking.
Very,
very reasonable.
I want to know people are,
and when you force people to sign up to
bogus speech codes,
nobody knows who anyone else's.
It doesn't change their intent.
And in fact it can make it worse because
when you press that,
exactly.
And then we'll open it up and then you
get drunk for a bottleneck and we're on
the same page.
We're on the same page.
I want all this stuff to happen in
public.
I really do.
Yes I do.
And I was going to say something else,
but I've forgotten.
Um,
uh,
oh yes.
I hate this.
You know,
this bleeping and censorship stuff,
department of Justice,
Scrub Islam references for the
transcripts of the terrorist police.
You're great.
You're amazing.
I want to go to find this stuff so fast.
You're saying this is true.
So,
and then they got ridiculed and
humiliated into releasing the actual
full transcript,
which I think still wasn't quite there.
But I hate this.
I hate this instinct to,
I hate any time that people don't quote
properly.
Whether it's to like,
you know,
because Oh god,
people can't cook.
What's where,
why would they think that would be okay
to do?
Why would the Department of Justice do
that?
Because it's an it because I mean,
look,
it's,
you know,
Loretta Lynch,
the Attorney General,
these people are Democrats.
They are pandering to Islam.
It's very simple.
There are pandering to Muslims,
the pandering to Muslims and
demonstration.
They don't give a shit about gay people.
That is bizarre that they would want,
I don't give a shit to take out the
references to Islam.
He described like,
he's like,
he's like saying,
oh La la,
la La,
you know,
like,
giving,
doing the,
doing the Shahada.
God knows what else.
Saying,
you know,
in the name of Allah,
most of,
most of all,
most great,
I'm doing this terrible thing.
You know,
I'm doing this for Isis.
I am a proud Muslim.
I'm killing in the name of Allah and all
the rest of it.
I think even when they put the
transcript back,
I think they changed Allah to God,
you know,
just to wind up Christians just to Piss
us off,
you know,
just to wind people up.
Um,
just,
just to sort of muddy the waters,
you know,
just said,
oh,
I said religious,
religious images,
massive.
That's a massive piece of deception.
It's discuss the words like that course
of course,
and the censorship and changing all the
rest of it.
But I think that you have the power to
do that.
No,
it's obscene.
That is a direct violation of the press.
Direct violation of journalism and
distribute information that's so
distorted like that.
Almost worse than the motivations behind
the fact they did it is the contempt and
low esteem in which they must hold the
public and the press to think that,
that we would think that was okay and
put up with it and not know what was in
the gaps that they redacted.
Yeah.
Have they commented on this?
No,
they just,
they got bullied.
They got so ridiculed by all sides that
they released a new transcript where
they think fewer explanations.
I don't know if it was complete,
complete,
complete.
It was much better because it was insane
that they think they could do that.
It's insane.
Well they didn't get away with it,
but imagine them thinking they could get
away with it.
What that says about their opinion of
the public,
that's almost worse.
Well,
it's not just that,
it's the,
their sense of entitlement,
the amount of power that they think that
they can walk reality.
Yeah.
I mean that is warping reality.
It's 100% more pro.
I mean,
cause it,
it creates space for people,
for idiots like sally cone to say this
was,
you know,
homophobically motivated fucking wasn't
a transcript or is it not a transcript,
the transcript,
you're suppose to be able to hear it on
the script.
What the fuck did he say?
Oh Wow.
That's,
and they sense it.
Every single mention,
and this is not like,
you know,
usual rightwing kind of like,
why aren't your naming Islam kind of
stuff for this attorney general,
Loretta Lynch refused Wednesday to say,
who made the decision to remove
references to the Islamic state and its
leader from the publicly released
version of the transcript of the nine 11
call involving the Orlando nightclub
shooter.
The goal of course,
what listen to this,
the goal is of course the greatest
transparency.
The initial thought was that we did not
want to provide a further platform for
the propaganda of the killer bull shit.
What a load of crap.
That's a lie.
Of course it's a lie.
Of course it became an issue.
We decided we would go ahead and release
the full transcript.
Lynch said when's she must've released
the full one if she said it.
I get,
I guess,
I guess they have,
I mean,
God only knows if they,
if they really did really sit or if they
change certain words,
who knows.
Uh,
but um,
that when we have no way of telling,
and this certainly does not inspire us
with confidence that even even the,
even the released one,
look at this statement right here.
Um,
hold on a second.
Do we trust them even to have released
the real one now that we know what
they're,
what they're doing.
Once you say you released the real one,
it's just like,
it seemed like it's going to get out.
Press on.
Who decided to remove the references to
Isol as well as the name of the deceased
shooter,
Omar Martine.
Lynn Lynch remained vague.
I'm not going to go into the detail of
the process behind it.
Lynch said I review was not to further
spread the propaganda,
but once it became a distraction,
when we release the whole transcript,
what tell me and you know that we know
how you know it's a lie,
right?
I mean,
or at least how,
you know how stupid these people are.
They release,
this is the,
this is the deadliest shooting in
American history,
right?
The deadliest mass shooting in American
history.
It is the biggest news in the country
for weeks.
They released the deadliest mass
shooting in America.
It is.
It is,
it is.
There was one,
there was showed to other ones that were
really similar,
which one had more,
could just google that.
Orlando was not the deadliest mass
shooting in American history.
The Google that because there was this,
what can the assumption is one of the
top five.
Um,
this is,
you know,
this,
this is horrible.
It was horrible.
But I'm just,
just for clarity's sake,
I think I would like to know if I'm
wrong about that,
but it just assume that,
you know,
it's the biggest news story in America
for three weeks,
right?
In the eyes of the world media we're
watching and this guy dialed nine one
one right?
And made a phone call immediately before
or whatever it was,
you know,
to think that you can gerrymander that
is so dumb.
Just so mind bogglingly stupid given the
suspicion with which normal people
already hold the authorities,
you know,
and the politicization swirling around,
this is so stupid.
But think also if,
if what she was saying was true,
right,
what we did this to stop,
you know,
the spread of his hateful messages and
to avoid,
you know,
more attention beyond Isis.
What's more attention on now?
Now that funding has gone,
all anyone wants to talk about it in
that transcript is the words that she
kept out.
All anybody will ever want to talk about
in relation to that transcript for the
rest of time is how the government cut
out the names of Isis and even his own
name.
You know,
like the cutout.
Anything remotely Islamic looking,
any Arabic words,
anything [inaudible] cleansed it so that
if you had only read that transcript and
you knew nothing about the case,
you might think the guy was just some,
you know,
straight white male homophobic shooter
from Charleston,
you know?
Yeah.
They were trying to hide his name there.
Exactly.
They a bunch of weird name.
They hit his name like we didn't know
his name.
They hid his name so that if you read
that document,
you could have been persuaded to believe
that this was some,
you know,
redneck,
homophobic Christian killer,
which of course the left was saying,
you know,
um,
oh,
this is no better than blah,
blah,
blah.
You know,
all of the kind of like excuse making
and molly coddling and pandering and
weaseling and,
and Oh,
let's use,
let's use a Muslim killing gays as an
excuse to attack the questions again,
you know,
uh,
all of this stuff that the left was
doing,
the government legitimized and assisted
when it redacted that transcript
appalling.
Well that it's ridiculous to think that
they thought they'd get away with it,
but it also shows how much fear they
have of Islam and Muslim people.
It's true.
It's,
there's a massive
fear in this country and that was the
same fear that led them to suppress the
images from Charlie Abdo that got those
cartoonists killed.
Nobody.
I mean,
there was a massive failure of the press
or no one,
and we ran them.
You guys,
Breitbart did,
and Kudos to you because that was a huge
issue.
And Time magazine,
The New York Times,
all those people denied.
They'd be like,
no,
we're not.
We're not running that.
We don't want to die.
Yeah,
yeah,
we did it.
I knew.
It's funny.
We always sold,
you know,
the left is so stunning and brave,
responsible for all these great,
you know,
um,
social triumphs and civil rights
victories and all the rest of it.
Uh,
it seems to me that it's,
it's conservative taking all the risks
now.
It looks that way to me.
I mean,
I'm going at the end of the month to
Sweden.
I didn't think I told you this.
You wouldn't know this yet.
Um,
I'm getting at the end of the month to
Sweden to lead to gay pride march
through a Muslim ghetto because to me
it's been nice knowing you dude,
and a black,
glad I got to come on before the end of
the month because to me it seems like
the point of gay pride,
if there is one any more is,
and it's,
that's very much in debate in the west.
Uh,
surely this was the point of gay pride
was always to,
you know,
just sort of March defiantly through
areas of social conservatism and
reactionary,
you know,
religious bigotry in all the rest of it.
Well,
that's only coming really from one
direction.
Now I don't think there's very much,
I mean it's,
it is an absurd,
it's an absurd and ridiculous,
lots of perspective to suggest that
somebody who doesn't want to bake a cake
for some lesbians is equivalent to a
creed that wants to know,
that throws homosexuals off roofs where,
you know,
100 million people live in,
in Islamic countries where the penalty
for gay sex is death.
Uh,
where,
you know,
British Muslims,
100% of British Muslims think that
homosexuality is not an acceptable
lifestyle choice and 52% of them.
What gay sex made illegal.
This is coming from one religion,
just one,
and stop lying to people that you know,
that there's some equivalence between,
you know,
the discomfort occasionally felt by
Christians about gay marriage and
Muslims murdering homosexuals.
Just fucking stop it because nobody
believes you anymore.
We were talking about this earlier,
that Michael Shermer had an excellent
article about that,
about Islam being the one religion that
didn't go through the enlightenment.
Yes,
it's,
it's a very illuminating article.
It really shows you how sort of isolated
their ideology has remained and it's one
of the very few ideologies from that
long ago.
It remains fairly untouched.
The reason that I think for that,
and it,
he may have touched on this in the
article,
is there a structural differences
between Islam and every other major
world religion?
Right.
So if you take the,
the Quran,
the sooner and the headaches and you can
keep it together.
This is the,
this is,
you know,
Muslims will say this is the final
perfect and unalterable would have got
the Quran right.
And it's supported by the [inaudible] of
the sayings and doings of been molested.
Um,
no other religion makes a claim for
itself.
They know that God will never come back.
In fact,
other religions make a specifically
specifically opposite claim.
Uh,
and you know,
and no other religion I think apart
from,
apart from Islam has proven itself so
resistant to it.
You know,
to,
to maternity and,
and so in capable of adapting to modern
circumstances,
Christianity for instance,
does a wonderful job of aligning itself
with capitalist societies and adapting
and changing with the times.
And,
and in my view,
maybe not entirely in yours,
but in my view certainly in the last
hundred years has been nothing but
nothing but a net positive for public
life.
Now Islam of course,
you know,
it sort of locks down into the social
attitudes that people had when Islam was
founded.
Yeah.
Christianity isn't Christina,
you know,
you've even got the Anglican church,
now women bishops,
gay marriage is probably whatever,
you know,
there's the Christianity is adapting to
this stuff and is changing,
but you know,
it's not,
Islam has some problems.
I mean,
another structural problem of course
with it is that even,
even Islam zone scholars say that where
the Quran contradicts itself is of
course it does in many places because
parts of it is just sort of plagiarized
old testament and the rest of it is just
mad.
Um,
where,
where it contradicts itself as a
principle of abrogation which means that
reverses versus that will reveal to
Mohammed later,
chronologically in time a supersede the
earlier ones.
Well the problem is at the earlier ones
that the peace,
love and understanding ones and later
ones when he was a warlord of the ones
that kill,
kill,
kill the infidel versus all right.
So according to Islam zone scholars and
they don't think there's any real
disagreement on this.
The belly coast verses in the Quran take
precedence over the peace,
love and understanding versus,
and of course you know,
the other structural problems with
religion that prevent it from it,
from engaging with maternity and
intellectual inquiry inequality for
women and gays.
Will,
the rest of it have led to things like,
and people have heard me say this
before,
but I think it's an interesting,
just to just one little data point.
There isn't a single world class
university anywhere in the Islamic
world.
Not One.
Why I think you can fill in the gaps
yourself,
but you know,
to,
to claim that that is somehow equivalent
as a,
as you know,
as we say to these,
to this,
you know,
to memories pizza is,
is insane.
It's completely absurd.
And for the government to,
you know,
to,
to deny gay people the right to educate
themselves and you know,
and deny gay people knowledge,
they need to protect themselves about
threats at home.
And it is now dangerous to be a gay
person in America.
Why?
It's not fucking memories pizza,
it's Muslims,
uh,
to deny people the ability to educate
themselves on that is unacceptable and
unconscionable.
An unforgivable.
And so I'm doing two things.
One of them is we're going to do the
shoot back party at the Republican
National Convention,
which I'm going to show up to,
which you know,
which is just get,
you know,
on the gays.
Uh,
and the other is back policy.
The policy.
This is the [inaudible].
There's little party,
the Republican National Convention,
just,
you know,
reminding gay people that the best way
they can protect themselves is not
pander to,
is not the NRA going to open its doors
to gay people.
I don't see any reason why the NRA is
not already.
Um,
just take them all in all then yeah.
Might be a good thing at this point.
Hillary is losing a,
I don't think the NRA is worrying,
worrying about membership.
I think their membership grows every
time as well as catastrophes,
because every time,
every time,
you know,
there's a,
there's some other,
I mean,
I don't know,
but I'm guessing,
I mean,
I think the energy at the NRA is
probably quite healthy,
quite healthy and membership growth.
It's quite healthy.
But really the people who benefit are
the arms manufacturers.
Good,
good.
I want lots of market competition in the
arms trade.
I want cheap,
reliable firearm.
So every home has got 12 of them.
Good.
Your country,
you're not even allowed to have them.
No.
I'm not allowed a pistol in my own
country to protect myself.
Despite the fact that government is
letting you know,
hundreds of thousands of people who want
me dead.
And this is not just me being a crazy
right wing lunatic.
Um,
although Ammo,
all of those things,
it is,
this is,
this is a Gallup poll a couple of years
ago polled 1,001
British Muslims,
100% of them said to homosexuality was,
you know,
it was unacceptable.
And then a later of percent,
hundred percent that's higher than
Palestine.
When 96% of people in the pew global
data say that homosexuality is
unacceptable,
100% and 52% of those people weren't gay
sex made illegal.
This is not crazy.
Muslims in Racker,
this is people two streets away from
where I live or even one street away or
even in the same building.
I don't fucking know.
They all think I'm unacceptable.
I don't want this in the west.
Get rid of it and lack of mode.
No,
I'm not going to go out and I'm not
going to go out.
I'm not going to go out and shoot them.
But somebody in a fucking like,
you know,
somebody comes dressed in,
flowing white white clothes with a beer
called Mohammed knocks at my front door.
It looks aggressive.
I'm putting my hand on my,
on my hip,
you know,
and making sure that I'm not in danger.
Yeah.
Damn right.
I am.
And,
but you can't do that in your country.
Well,
why do you think,
I mean,
is that where you're going to come over
here?
Can you move here?
Um,
well,
I see you seem to fit the profile.
You make good money.
You're expected.
You have a great job in a Republican.
I don't complication,
I don't think I'd have a problem getting
a events.
So pretty easy,
right.
But a green card,
um,
just learn a bunch of goofy shit about
our country that we don't remember.
I'll have to get married first.
I've talked to some people that have
learned a,
become Canadians that have come over
here and gotten their green cards and
they know a lot more about this is,
this is the best country in the world.
And it would give me nothing but
pleasure to see what I'm saying.
Nothing but pleasure to,
uh,
to,
to come and live here.
So we'll see.
I'll,
I'll keep you posted on that.
Yeah,
some do.
But you know,
this,
if the left is not going to be honest
about,
um,
the risks to gaze,
we've got to educate ourselves.
Stop listening to dumb as pictured
celebrities.
Stop listening to politicize reporters,
stopped listening to the governments
that listen to Obama and Hillary.
Like trump,
by the way,
is the only his speech after Orlando
magnificent,
most pro.
Well,
he's just saying,
look,
this is,
this is a problem for the gay community.
We cannot allow this stuff to come in.
I'm going to protect you.
I mean,
you know,
you need to,
you need to arm yourself and you say,
oh,
blah,
blah.
You need to read a speech.
Cause it's a lot more complex and
nuanced than that.
Then that suggests genuinely great
speech,
which suggests to me that Obama might be
kind of like a,
almost like a Cameroonian politician.
Not,
sorry,
not the country,
but I mean like David Cameron.
Uh,
um,
in the,
in the sense that,
you know,
he can,
he can sort of falter now and again,
but when the moment calls for it,
you know,
he rises to the occasion.
A Bush was like that,
you know,
the,
uh,
w speech after nine 11 was pretty
spectacular.
Uh,
so,
you know,
trump,
trump has very,
very strong,
I mean,
I think trumps the most pro gay
candidate in American electoral history
on either side of the divide,
frankly.
I really do.
But anyway,
we gave,
people need to take this into their own
hands,
frankly.
And,
uh,
so I'm going to Sweden where a year ago
the Swedish authorities say,
uh,
told a gay pride march that it was
needlessly provocative for walking
through a Muslim area of Stockholm.
Now that's,
that's,
I mean,
really needlessly,
needlessly provocative.
This is gay pride,
how much gay stuff goes on in the Muslim
world,
because isn't that a big issue as well?
Right,
because of the suppression.
Yeah.
Anyways,
so yeah,
we should get onto that because that's
interesting.
So I'm gonna,
I'm gonna,
I'm gonna ride.
I hope that my security guys are golden
pony.
Please say yes.
I'm going to ride a horse.
Yes,
you are into the Muslim ride a horse.
I'm hoping so.
Yeah.
Uh,
the security people asking me not to do
it because they can't protect me if I'm
much higher.
Right.
Because anybody could take me out from
anywhere,
but I'm,
I'm hoping to persuade them to let me do
it and I want to ride in with like,
I want 20 people in a v shape with like
Milo banners behind me,
like proper full game of thrones style.
I want to be able to write this or
they're going to be of course,
which we'll take it,
we'll take all our people over.
We'll have,
I'm sure there'd be plenty of volunteers
and this March anyway,
and it's going to be me on horseback
marching into the Muslim ghetto and then
giving a speech about Islam and gays in
the very hot of European cookery,
this country,
Sweden,
which has given itself over completely
to Islamic immigration,
which is now the rape capital of Europe.
Because the true,
yes,
the Rape Camp Malmo Malmo in Sweden is
now the rape capital of Europe because
of uncontrolled Muslim immigration.
And the police there have been
instructed not to record the ethnicity
or religion of a silent,
so they don't even ask to Yup.
They don't even have statistics on who
does it any more similar to the Loretta
Lynch Trent redacted transcript.
This is what people don't see color.
I just see people.
Exactly.
And men are rapists.
Cause this is what the left does.
It's like you import a load of Muslims,
Muslims start raping and stealing from
everybody and the responses.
This is toxic masculinity.
Hmm.
That's a,
that's a hilarious,
I love that term.
Anyway,
what are we going to do about that?
What is swollen plan to do to try to
mitigate some of the rape?
Oh,
do you know what they've done?
You know,
don't you know,
you gave me a cue question.
Surely you did.
That was,
I thought that was a,
I thought that was a canny.
Kenny.
Uh,
uh,
what do you call it?
T up?
Yeah.
Well,
Sweden has issued women with wristbands
and these wristbands say don't rape.
That's Sweden's answer to the rape
crisis.
Yes.
Sweden's to the rape crisis is an issue
with wristbands that say don't rape.
And to forbid the police for mentioning
the ethnicity and religion of a silence
that Sweden's answer the rape crisis,
I can't fix that,
but Milo's answer to the rape crisis and
deport all the Muslims,
deport them,
get rid of them.
Has anybody else suggested that anyone
in their countries or any debate about
how to handle this?
No.
What are they doing?
They're just sticking their head in the
sand.
Yeah.
Wow.
So I'm going to,
I cannot fix the woman problem single
handed,
but I can perhaps embarrass the
government about the gay problem.
And I certainly hope to do that.
So end of the month,
if you have enjoyed any of my
programming or writing or anything,
uh,
enjoy the next three weeks because after
the 27th of July,
that could be it.
Whew.
That's a ballsy move,
man.
To go to one of the most,
probably I will say do it.
Don't do it.
One of the most troubled areas and
Sweden and to walk through these
neighborhoods with,
no,
these are obviously immigrant
neighborhoods,
right?
These are people that are Muslim cancer.
It's exclusively.
When did these people move into this
area?
When did this start taking place?
I think over the last 10,
10 years,
Sweden's been,
ha ha,
you know,
has taken in hundreds of thousands of
them a year for the last 10 years I
think.
And that doesn't sound like a lot to an
American,
but Sweden doesn't have many people in
it.
Like Sweden is not very populous.
There are a couple of towns and that's
really the overall population of Sweden.
A couple of million,
I guess.
I'm guessing like 4 million or
something.
I think you're right.
I think it might be less than that.
And I,
I think it's a fairly small geographic
area too.
So they're on top of each.
Well does it,
I think this is a big stretch of it up
north where basically nobody lives,
it's just like snow or something.
And then down there's like three or four
cities and yeah,
I mean,
so,
so two,
300,000
people a year is not to nothing.
I've been to Stockholm.
It's gorgeous.
Beautiful.
But it won't be for long.
It will be Al stock home soon.
Oh boy.
I'll stock alice.
So the only thing is you used to hear
Abba and give it a couple of years and
all he will hear is,
oh Whoa,
what would they,
a Stockholm,
what would the uh,
numbers for mass shootings.
So that was,
was did you,
uh,
it's the definition of what someone is
using for what a mass shooting is very
varied.
So it's like,
it's in one place if it's,
which is where the questions are coming
in and uh,
they also don't count them if it's maybe
a,
a military.
Right.
What are the other options are,
what are the other,
uh,
candidates for the number one,
this a massacre.
A couple of massacres.
Wounded knee massacre,
right?
The Saint Louis massacre.
Yeah.
Those are the two ways,
right?
Yeah.
The Saint Louis one in the a wounded
knee one were to,
I remembered other names of people
there,
right?
Yep.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
Well it depends on our definition,
but any,
in many cases,
horrible tragedy.
Right.
So I don't understand how sweet and
thinks that they're just going to calm
the situation down by not mentioning the
gender or the name of the assailant or
basically just can't say it was Muslims.
It did it.
Uh,
I bet everybody is.
What it does is it means they are now no
national statistics on this.
So nobody can say 97% of the rapes are
committed by this portion of the
population.
Fix this.
The government's answer is not fixed the
problem,
but obscure the data.
They're going to ruin their whole
country.
They already have.
That was joe.
Yeah.
Malmo.
This was a feminist.
Progressive Paradise.
Sweden was like a left wing paradise.
Sweden was one of the few countries
where leftwing politics worked.
You know,
they,
they as taxes for everything in Sweden.
Like if you,
and this is,
I swear this is true because I have a
Swedish friends told me that the TAC
like property taxes in Sweden depend on
like how nice your view is,
you know.
So if you have a nice ocean view,
they will charge you more like local
council tax.
I know what you call it in America.
Did you like the property tax?
Is that property tax?
The tax you pay to the city to like to
do the roads and stuff?
Well yeah,
there's,
there's property tax that you have.
There's,
we have a lot of taxes over here anyway.
So one of these taxes,
like if you have a nicer view,
they literally have so little to do in
Sweden.
The government is just sitting around
dreaming up new taxes for things and
working out how they can charge people
more money for things.
But it was,
you know,
that's how I feel.
Appraisal fairly effective.
I mean the country was nice place,
you know,
what was the thought process between
letting all those people in there and
just open minded and just crazy left
wing lunatics who refuse to accept
reality?
They think they think that language
shapes reality.
They think if they call,
you know,
if they think if they,
if they say lies often enough that it
becomes the truth,
you know,
which of course in some cases it's true,
but,
uh,
you know,
if you say,
if you say Muslims are peaceful often
enough,
it does not seem to come through.
Uh,
there was,
there are limits.
There are limits to this,
uh,
to the power of positive thinking.
Is there anybody that thinks it's a good
thing to have those people there?
Are there,
are there any arguments?
This is a positive sort of multicultural
benefit to Sweden to think so.
I think Swedish people get it now,
but it doesn't,
I haven't seen any signs.
Yeah.
But only now.
I haven't seen any signs that the,
um,
that the government gets it.
And indeed in Sweden of course,
you know,
it's very heavily socially enforced
consensus.
If you even mentioned immigration called
a racist and Sweden and you know,
there's no discussion of the papers
until very,
very recently.
Um,
it's not on TV.
People just don't.
So it asks about it bill out over the
top before people start calling it.
Exactly.
Basically everyone needs to have a
daughter or a friend's daughter who was
raped before anything will happen.
Choose Christ.
Yeah.
Oh well,
so queasy Sweden.
Yes,
and then here's the big picture.
How do you take these people from these
places where they're coming over here
and doing these horrible things?
How do you educate them?
How do you change that?
How do you don't want to just share
them?
I want the how does anybody ever,
I mean,
if you're going to engineer humanity,
humanity,
I care about keeping my family safe and
keeping my culture in tact and I want
them deported or I care about those
things as well,
but I also think that as a civilization,
we should look towards optimizing the
rest of the civilization.
You should.
You should invade their country's killed
our leaders and convert to Christianity.
As Ann Coulter said,
Oh God,
do you have a better solution?
That's suppression.
That's not going to work.
They're going to secretly build up.
They're going to make a dirty bomb.
Does come in.
Iraq has been neutralized as a threat to
the world.
It's a fucking mess either fighting over
each other,
the shows,
they're not coming for us anytime soon.
The move wars everywhere to us anytime
soon.
Iraq has been neutralized as a threat.
That worked out pretty great from where
I'm sitting.
Well were weren't they like a fake
threat in the first place?
I mean the only reason why the it back
cause we armed him and supported him.
I in general think that America is one
of the reasons America is cool is that
it is the only country.
If you're sitting from outside America
is the only country that's got your
back,
is the only country that will go and
help other people out.
You know,
out of sweet like fucking things up.
Yeah,
it's pretty cool.
That's,
I mean that's how I ended the day.
There's something,
there's something to be said for that to
every like every country in the world
likes to rag on America,
but where do they come when they need
help?
They come to America because they want
the boys,
you know,
they want,
they want your boys to make it rain,
right?
That massive amount of military moment
momentum and that military momentum,
like it supports a lot of people in this
country and it just supports a lot of
arms manufacturers,
a lot of,
there's a lot of industry involved in
the military and so we spread out and
the way to keep that military mode
moving and the way to keep it
operational is you have to have it all
over the world.
So we're in every fucking corner of the
world.
Well,
I'm glad to America is,
you know,
one of the things I want people to
remember in this election and remember
just generally in life is America's
fucking great.
America is wonderful,
you know,
it's not perfect.
There are all sorts of things that
everybody would like to change about it.
And the business of improving on America
is,
is what politics is for.
But America is pretty fucking great.
And speaking of somebody who is not an
American,
I am so happy.
I'm so glad that America does have,
you know,
like a finger everywhere in the world.
It makes us safer.
It makes us more secure.
America's the only really powerful good
guy in the world.
And thank God for you.
Thank God for you,
the state of the world,
if it weren't for America and you know,
it's a sort of brinkmanship like con
really,
you know,
if all the bad guys wants to act,
America couldn't fight them all off at
once,
you know.
So if they were smart,
they would all just do what they want.
You know,
like Russia would be like,
yeah,
okay Muslims,
you have Europe and we'll have America,
you know,
like that in China.
God knows,
you know,
that could happen in America,
couldn't take them all on at once,
but the,
the risk of going to war with America is
so great that the world doesn't,
it,
you know,
is,
is essentially peaceful.
You know?
Thank God for you guys.
Thank God there's one superpower.
Yeah,
this one's super as imaginative as King
Jong,
Il.
Thank God that that super power is
America and not China,
not Russia,
not Iran.
India.
And it calls.
It could and it could be if,
if the left succeeds in destroying this
country.
But don't you think that the people that
are on the left,
they,
they don't believe that that's the case?
Yeah.
They don't believe,
they don't believe America is a good
thing.
They don't believe it said was a good
They don't believe there are global
because the children with no
understanding of geography,
history or anything else,
they don't appreciate how America keeps
the world's safe.
And you can disagree with individual
military actions and many reasonable
people,
and I might even be persuaded into this
position,
this position,
many reasonable people think
Afghanistan,
Iraq and all of the recent wars are a
disaster.
Why going to Vietnam?
Right?
Perfectly reasonable,
respectable points of view that I do
respect and I enjoy discussing with
people cause I like finding out about
these things that I don't know
everything about right.
Love to have the discussions.
Very important that America reflects on
what it's done before.
So x better in the future.
But to say that it's to suggest that the
world isn't a better place for America's
presence.
And preeminence is absurd.
Well,
in this stage of the game,
when you're looking at the alternative,
the alternative being Putin being China,
you know,
I mean we,
we do have some legitimate dictators
that are out there in the world that
killed their adversaries.
Of course.
I mean Putin is,
he is the most gangster of gangsters
when it comes to a public leader,
like a guy who is,
it's,
there's no shadow dealings.
He's killing people in broad daylight.
Yeah,
yeah,
he is.
And you think about that as,
again,
we came back what we said earlier about,
you know,
America's values and this was it.
Margaret Thatcher used to say this to
country,
not founded on nationality,
whatever it founded on principle.
Yeah.
Um,
and I think that's true and I think
Americans are quite keenly aware of
that.
So why they care about the first and
second amendments and some of the others
and why they care about freedom of
speech and liberty and prosperity and
you know,
freedom and property rights,
all,
it's kind of stuff.
And,
and,
you know,
obviously the,
the capitalism that has made all of that
possible,
this has created a country in which
pretty much anyone can do pretty much
anything now.
That's great.
You can,
even,
if you are so inclined and so insane,
get other people to pay to turn you into
a woman if you want to.
That's how tolerant and permissive
American society is,
you know,
now I might think paying for that
insurance companies are paying for that.
Is that what's going on in America?
I think,
um,
well yeah,
whole that's what tends to be,
cause there'll Paul,
so if a girl identifies with a man,
they,
they can change her.
I know in well they very rarely pay for
themselves.
I think it's a mixture of,
um,
of insurance companies and Medicare and
Medicaid because there were poor because
they're all poor.
Well,
transsexuals,
transgender folk as the left wants us to
call them,
uh,
are vastly,
disproportionately a socioeconomically
underprivileged.
What about Bruce Jenner?
Rich as fuck.
Yeah,
but he's,
he's an outlier most,
most,
most transgender people.
Well,
it sounds like a rebel to be.
Yeah.
And he's not,
he's not that,
he's not that cool,
uh,
leather straps to be strictly accurate.
All you can say is that transgender
people are disproportionately poor and,
uh,
socioeconomically underprivileged.
They come,
they come from low orders and tend to
have much in their bank account.
So yeah,
it's,
I think it's a mixture of,
you know,
insurance companies like health stuff
you have here,
which always miss.
It's so confusing to me.
These weird,
complex things you have,
just get rid of them.
Uh,
you don't want this,
this creeping national health service
you seem to have here.
It's,
it's crazy.
But,
uh,
yeah,
I,
it's,
it's certainly in the UK,
it's completely taxpayer funded and
everywhere in Europe,
Canada,
transgender operations,
completely taxpayer funded.
Yep.
Now,
how do they determine whether or not
someone's valuable or viable doctors do
that?
They just say,
yeah,
this guy.
But meanwhile,
the doctors have a vested interest in
performing more of the surgeries.
Yes,
they do.
Oh.
And,
uh,
of course,
if somebody is really insistent and this
happens more than you would think and
it's not reported on very often,
it's very difficult to find someone to
go on record about this stuff.
But you'll find that very often when
somebody wants to go in for the surgery
and the doctors know no,
they will start kicking up a fast,
they might accuse the doctor of
transphobia asked for another doctor.
People basically who people who want
this stuff or mad.
So they act like mad people.
So they will go doctor shopping and they
will go round every doctor until
somebody says yes,
they will acute,
they will,
they will like beg,
borrow and steal for money to,
you know,
to do,
to do crazy stuff to themselves.
They will insist in and cry foul and
bully and yell at doctors until they get
what they want.
I mean,
doctors are only humans.
Some of the must just want an easy life.
You know,
somebody comes in and says,
I want to be a woman in there.
Clearly unhinged.
At some point of Dr.
Number 17,
somebody is going to be like,
do you know what?
Fuck it.
Well,
I think you managed to Piss all the
right people off today.
I'm glad.
If you've been offended by this show,
good.
I think you probably converted 17 or 18
people to voting for trump.
That's all I ask.
That's all.
I was 20 people a day and I would have
done my bit.
I think you probably get,
it's probably closing in on 20.
It's splendid.
Um,
how many transgender people are mad at
you right now?
Oh No,
they shouldn't be mad because I,
you know,
yeah,
they should be mad based.
Probably be pissed.
Really pissed.
Yeah.
It's a,
but I think you had some very reasonable
points about what a,
what an odd business that the whole
thing is.
America is in a weird place.
What's also the ideology that we are
being forced to accept.
And Kurt Metzger,
who was on the podcast,
very smart guy and a funny dude,
he grew up a Jehovah's witness.
Is that what it was?
Or a Moonie showboat.
Jehovah's Witness.
He grew up in a call this a to dual
ones,
right?
Yes.
Um,
couple of them go door door,
but
the Mormons do too,
right?
I don't know that jeff has messages.
The famous,
they have the cash town makes me,
I know that just yet.
Anyway,
point being he acquainted it correctly
to this,
this sort of box thinking where you're
not allowed to think outside that box.
It's just like religion.
He's like,
I understand this kind of thinking.
I grew up with this kind of thinking
like you can't make me think like this.
I know what you're doing.
Like this is not rational or objective.
You're not talking about these things in
a fair way.
You have a very biased,
very predetermined pattern that you're
forcing people into subscribing to.
And if they don't,
then there's something wrong with them.
They're bigoted or assholes or they're
trans phobic or they tried to
pathologize.
You know,
if,
if it's me,
they call you was self-loathing gay men
or toxic male,
masculine,
hate myself.
I just don't agree with you.
Well,
it's a weird thing when you can't agree
or you can't disagree with someone.
Like you're,
you're,
you're not allowed to debate it.
The discussion is closed and this is a,
it's,
this is not like as simple as is hot,
hot is cold,
cold,
you know,
his metal hard.
Now these are things,
these are complicated.
The etiology of homosexuality is complex
and nuanced and maybe different for
different people.
The correct treatment pathway for
transgenderism is complex and nuanced
and may be different for different
people.
The left simply doesn't make space for
the,
for how complex life really is.
They demand this sort of conformity from
everybody else.
You know,
if you're gay,
you can't be a Catholic,
you must hate yourself and one of you is
in confidence.
Yet they demand that we accept their
crazy self descriptions.
You know,
I'm a gender Queer nonbinary,
whatever the height of hypocrisy and at
the same time,
you know,
we,
they expect us to,
if not believe,
at least publicly go along with lies,
lies that over simplify the complex
realities of life.
Now people are messy and imperfect.
We are all on a not to get too,
you know what have a bucket veeder I
don't know.
I don't even have a vocabulary for
mysticism.
Um,
you know,
not to get too happy.
Woo Woo.
Yeah.
Not to get too woo woo about it.
But we are all on a journey through
life.
But you know,
growing as you said at the beginning of
the show,
evolving,
becoming different people every,
you know,
every,
every six months or even sooner.
And you know,
life is complicated.
And one of the things that depresses me
as somebody who enjoys reading and
learning is the oversimplification of
life by the left into into okay people
and bigots and if you don't agree with
specific and very often insane points of
view,
points of view that contradict medical
science points you with a contradict
common sense points of view that at a
bare minimum are highly debatable if you
do not go along with this stuff,
this ever increasingly mad stuff,
you know this stuff that is his
wandering off into,
into crazy territory.
You were in big land and the left has
excluded so many of us for so long,
gays,
blacks,
you know,
printed of blacks feel totally anti
black lives matter.
I would imagine most of them in fact,
and these people are called,
you know,
Uncle Toms and all the rest of it.
And it happened on stage one of my
talks.
If you don't go along with all of this,
there's something wrong with you,
you're pathologized all the rest of it.
Well the left has created by doing this,
the outright me,
Donald Trump and a whole army of
disaffected liberals,
it's own former supporters who are tired
of being told what they can think,
say,
do,
how they can dress,
how they can speak,
cause they can hang out with,
you know,
what belief systems they can have.
And it has alienated and entire young
generation from left wing politics.
And isn't it hilarious that it kind of
spawned out of a dispute about video
games?
Yes.
I mean the meek inherited the earth in a
sense.
Who would have thought?
Who would have thought the stab being
meek?
Yeah.
Well you know it was fucked up when they
tried to take the video games.
They fuck.
Well because they were involved,
they'd done it in comic books.
They don't in fantasy down into Scifi,
but they took on the smart play,
took on the smart,
exactly.
Took on the PSI fans of the Comic Book
Fans Are Nice but gamers card shit,
hot,
smart.
They are autistic as fuck.
Which is why I love them because I am,
they are smart.
They are determined and they'd like to
organize because they used to they,
I mean they problem solve for a living.
Yes.
They're looking at this problem like it
was a,
you know,
like,
like it was again,
what are the victory conditions,
you know?
Yeah.
And you don't need to kill everyone on
that side.
You just need to get the flight from one
point to another or you just need to
this kind of stuff.
So game has realized,
I don't need the press to like us,
you know,
and you can call us misogynistic
harassers on the Internet if you want
to.
All we want is these feminists lunatics
to get out of gaming and for people to
leave the creators alone to do what they
want.
And for,
you know,
for journalists to start reporting
honestly about games and stop hating on
their own,
on their own,
you know,
uh,
audiences or just fuck off.
You know what's interesting too is how
much bullshit they've exposed in that
industry and in the people that are
criticizing them who make video games.
Yes,
actually are they're guilty of doing the
exact same thing that these people are
criticizing,
exposed hypocrisy.
They've exposed collusion,
double think collusion that,
that litter match underneath,
um,
you know,
sort of overwhelming weight,
but it's around harassment.
Um,
it lit a match underneath so many
different people in so many different
worlds when people looked out and they
realize that you can beat them,
you can beat them if you don't give a
shit what the press says about you.
And why would you,
and Donald Trump has proven also that if
you don't give a shit what the press
about,
what the press says about you get
stronger,
not weaker,
you know,
uh,
if you don't care what polite society
says about you,
you can win.
You can beat them.
And this has never been done before,
at least not done for 25 years.
Uh,
you know,
and I'm not saying it's not about the
right winning over the left,
but it's about freedom and
libertarianism and the right to do,
say,
think what you want to play.
What do you want?
It won.
It beat the cultural scolds.
It beat the feminists.
It beat the,
the,
you know,
the offense brigade Gamergate one.
And it's has ignited so many fires in so
many places with so many unexpected
consequences and wonderful,
uh,
you know,
snowball effects elsewhere and culture
and politics and society.
It's remarkable.
And we all,
I think,
who have been give emboldened to speak
more plainly encouraged to contradict
people more often reminded that it is
not bigoted to have a different point of
view and that you are entitled to your
opinion no matter what it is and
entitled to say it without fear of being
called a monster or you know,
suffocated by safe space culture.
All of those people have video games to
think as you correctly suggest it.
It sounds,
you know,
it sounds ridiculous,
but it is true and you know,
it's,
it's been a remarkable thing.
I was very happy that I was at the
beginning to,
to watch it all unfold.
Milo,
we live in strange and exciting times,
do a lot of fun stuff was going on
there.
This are much better than the last one.
The headphones made it,
we didn't talk over each other.
We didn't.
I feel like this is a really good,
I would,
I'm going to enjoy listening to this,
one of my favorites.
Thank you,
sir.
I really enjoyed it.
Thanks so much for having me as the
worst.
That's it.
Your fucks.
We'll see you soon.
Thanks everybody.
Oh,
we'll be back tomorrow.
We're going to do a fight companion.
Me and Joey Diaz Strap in.
Yeah.