Oh Shit.
We're live ladies gentlemen.
The Joe Rogan experience podcast
is brought to you by on it.com.
If you go to o,
n n I t you can check out
all the different products,
the new tropics,
the uh,
sports exercise shit like shroom
tech sport, fascinating stuff.
It's based on the quarter subs
mushroom, which somehow or another, uh,
helps your body process oxygen Benner,
it gives you a just a bit more endurance.
You can feel it, especially if
you take four. That's what I do.
I take four before Jujitsu, shroom
tech sport, check into that shit.
If you're really into
working out or if you,
you're going to high altitude people have
had success with that stuff. If there,
uh, if you're, if you're like living
at sea level and you go into altitude,
you can, it takes your body
awhile to deal with that.
And that's supposedly is where they found
this quarter. [inaudible] mushroom. The,
the,
the story behind it was that cattle were
eating these mushrooms and they were,
uh, a bit more active. And so the,
uh, the cattle range of people said,
well,
what's in these mushrooms?
And they started eating them and
apparently it helps your body.
When you're at a higher altitude,
you have less oxygen.
It's just a good endurance supplement.
Not, you know, it's nothing crazy,
but it gives you a boost so you can
feel, um, what does, what is Alpha brain,
all this stuff.
The information is much more,
it's much better described
by the people in on it.
If you go to the website,
check it out, look into it.
If you try it and you don't like it,
there's a 100% money back guarantee
on the first order of 30 pills.
My version of on it would be a totally
different website if it was me describing
it or if you were describing it and mine
would be like, Yo, I'm taking new mood.
Did a bunch of x this not this weekend.
Help you when you did x,
did it help you brain? Well,
I think if you're,
if,
if you remember roll on and roll
off and all that stuff like that,
that that's what you know,
it's the, the, it's, it helps,
it helps your brain grow back.
What it needs to grow back in
my website and your website.
It gets my brain juice going again.
All of them, Alpha brain and
new mood, all these nutrients.
It's nutrients that that aid in
your brain's ability to produce
neurotransmitters.
And I always say that that coming out
of my mouth is just a bunch of noise.
I'm just repeating things
that smart people have said.
I'm not really smart
enough to understand the,
even the idea of neurotransmitters,
what they really are.
So I shouldn't even be
allowed to use that word.
But since that is what
scientifically, that's how it's
described, I use that word.
So just understand it's coming from
the mouth of an idiot who's really into
vitamins, but it works. Uh, check
it out. Use a code name. Rogan,
save yourself 10% off. We also have
a kettle bells and battle ropes. And,
and uh, I've talked about these
many times in the podcast.
One of the things that I think if you
really like lifting weights with one of
the things that's cool about lifting
weights as you can with your willpower,
take your body and turn it
into a stronger, better body,
like a body that works really well.
And I said to a friend of mine,
we were having this discussion about
this and he's, he doesn't work out.
And I was like,
if you could take a pill
that could instantly turn
you into like a super athlete
and instantly turned you into
like a Michael Jordan, you know,
would you take that pill?
Well you can,
like someone can be Michael Jordan.
You just have to work out as hard as that
guy did. Like it can be accomplished.
Like you can transform your body
into a body that works better.
Like you really can, not with a pill,
but with your app, your own will,
your own will and exercises.
And my favorite way to work out is with
kettlebells and that's why we started
selling them an on a.com. Um, I
think for functional strength,
it's one of the best exercises
in the world. It's all your,
everything that you do with kettlebells
pretty much is your use your whole body
as one unit to move
this cannon ball around.
There's hundreds of videos online for
free on youtube if you want to buy him.
Steve Maxwell has excellent ones,
is a guy named Mike Muller.
He's got excellent ones.
All different videos that can show
you how to workout with kettle bells.
And it's, in my opinion, one of
the best workouts for your body,
for anything where if you, if, if it
would help you in whatever you do,
whether it's a sport, you
know, whether it's at work,
if you have to pick
things up at work a lot,
if it would help you
to be stronger and to,
to have a body that can
move things heavier,
better than kettlebells
are going to aid you.
For me and Jujitsu made a huge
difference in my endurance, like,
uh, the, my ability to,
to, to keep going, uh,
in like high pressure rolls when you're
rolling with somebody who's really good,
something like kettlebells makes a big
difference and you're focusing on the
alien freaking people out. And, uh,
alienware's not our sponsor,
but a sucker punch entertainment hooked
us up with these cool Alienware laptops
and we uh, we like them
because Alienware uh, is a,
a big company and they support
them and may fighters. So,
so we're kissing their butts so we're
kind of kissing their ass. Yeah.
So that's it.
You dirty bitches.
Go to [inaudible] dot com get yourself
some weights. Get you swole on.
You know what I'm saying, son?
Get your battle ropes and gear.
Justin Helpern is here and we're going
to get down to the nitty gritty about the
San Diego Los Angeles Commute.
And what's the difference between these
two mother fuckers? Give me a sec.
Oh yeah.
Use a Coney Rogan
experience trying my day.
Joe Rogan podcast.
That was probably the worst one ever.
Dj Red Bin.
No, it was, it was
interesting. It was definitely,
you definitely threw a curve ball. I need
to get more sound effects or something.
Yeah, you shoot your fucking awesome.
Know what you got buddy. Your Echo,
echo and fade that's underneath it.
It's perfect. So old school, Justin,
what's up man?
How you doing? Thanks for having me.
I'll please. Thank you. Thanks for on.
So you were, you're the dude to created
the shit. My Dad says Twitter account,
which became a cultural phenomenon
as you man. Yeah, no, it's crazy.
It was just that I was just, I was a
bad mother fucker. I listen, that's me.
My Dad is,
I dunno.
Is it all really stuffy says or do you
kind of juice it up a little bit of right
now and then,
oh, you edit it to get into
the 140 characters and Twitter.
Cause like he couldn't talk his
sentiments. Yay. I definitely, I mean he,
he would fucking flip out if I,
if I,
he cause he checks it like once every
two months to make sure it's like stuff
that he said.
So
how does he feel about this man that's
gotta be a trip all of a sudden your,
your, your, your likeness is being
portrayed on television by Captain Kirk.
Yeah. That he, that he was
like, the show is shitty
and I don't, I don't totally
disagree, but, uh, he didn't,
he honestly didn't give a shit about
William Shatner or the TV show it all.
He liked the book that I wrote.
He was like into that.
He's more into reading
than he is watching TV.
Have you ever thought about putting a
camera on him? Does he want to do that?
He would hurl it to the
ground. Yeah. He's not,
he's not into that at all. He's
just, he really that guy. Yeah.
I mean he weird line though. You've,
you've kind of drawn, you know,
you've like depicted him.
Yeah.
Well I was really worried about telling
Niggas ain't even tell him at first,
you know, first couple of months I didn't
think I just, it was for my friends,
so I was like, nobody's going to
see this, so there's no, we're,
I shouldn't bother him with it.
And then when it's like blew
up and people were like, Hey,
are you interested in doing a book? I was
like, well, I should tell my dad first.
When did you start the Twitter account?
It is crazy. I started in August,
2009 and by I think like August 21st I
started August 3rd August 21st I had like
300,000 followers.
It was nuts.
Like it just went viral and then
probably like two weeks later,
is that a million? Holy Shit.
Yeah, it was. It was like
right when Twitter was like,
you remember that like Ashton
Kutcher race to a million?
Like that kind of bullshit was
going on and and so it was like,
it was in the news. Like if it
happened now, I don't know. But,
but back then it was like perfect
timing. Wow. It's amazing.
That's incredible.
So just out of the word of mouth,
basically people just
sharing it with themselves.
It literally went viral
to a million people.
Yeah. Yeah, it did. I think like it
was at like 10,001 day when I went to,
I went to bed,
it was at 10,000 and then rob Corddry
tweeted it and then he like tweeted a link
like I like this. And it was rob Corddry
rob, of course, he's like comedian. He,
he was like a hot tub time machine
and the daily show and stuff.
He was just like, uh, I'm
sure I know him. Yeah, yeah,
I'm sure you cross paths with him at
some point and he had like a million
followers or something.
And so when he tweeted it out,
then all of a sudden the next day it
was like 100,000 is kind of just going
faster and faster and people kept sharing
it and then it was like, all right,
well what am I going to do now? How old
were you when this was going on? 29. Wow.
And was, what is this like, I mean,
you're sitting there going, okay,
what do I need that, what would
it, what do I do with this? Yeah,
well I was living at home,
so like I was,
I was riding for Maxim
and I was living at home.
I just split up with my a girl or sheets,
whatever was made to be more frank.
Um, and, uh,
and so I just like didn't know what the
fuck I was gonna do cause I was just
sitting there and I was like
living in my childhood bedroom.
It was like really depressing.
So yeah.
And then when all this stuff
started happening, you know,
I'd been riding for a while and I had
been up here riding and waiting tables and
doing all that stuff and then been
writing for magazines last couple of years
before that. And then this guy reached
out to me and he's like, maybe you could,
you know, is there, maybe
there's a book in this.
And so then I started to sort of sit
down and write some essays about just
stories up me and my dad and
then sort of submitted them.
How many stories do you have? I got
a lot of stories. He's crazy. Um,
but uh,
for the book I wrote like 12 essays.
So like if that book was single
spaced and in like normal font,
it'd be like nine pages. But,
but, but uh, yeah, I mean, I,
that book was like, yeah, around 12 or
13 essays, maybe like 160, 170 pages.
And I kinda just tried to keep
ones that didn't feel redundant. So
is your dad just like
always on about everything?
Does he always have something
funny to say about everything?
Is he just that guy all day?
Nah, he, he's not, he's not like,
he'll be just like quiet for two hours
and then he'll just like explode on you.
Um, he just like a lot of Shit
pisses him off. Right. You know,
and so,
and he doesn't have a lot of people
to talk to because he doesn't have any
friends. So yeah. For my mom, uh, I
mean that's the way he wants it though.
Like he doesn't, he doesn't want, yeah,
he really doesn't. He's like my best.
He's like, my best friend
lives in Tennessee. I see
him once a year. I'm like,
that's it. That's not a good, best friend.
I think the ball, why has he chosen?
That's, that's mean that behavior is a
cause. Like Jude not want to have friends.
He just would rather be able to not say
like say whatever he wanted unfiltered,
but he always just tells the truth.
So you kind of lose a lot
of friends along the way.
You would think you would gain him.
He the ones he has like two or
three and they're super close.
Like they're grizzle all guys that say
shit like I died for you. You're like,
when would that ever come
up? But okay. So yeah.
But I mean like he, he, he's not,
so he's not always on, but yo,
he's got really like interesting. He grew
up in the south and, but he's a doctor,
so like he grew up on a farm.
He was in the military.
He was like a tobacco farmer until he
was like, you know, 1516 so, you know,
I think he's got a unique perspective.
Wow. Yeah. That's a pretty intense life.
But he doesn't want to do anything
publicly. He doesn't want to like be,
you know, I mean if you ever
interviewed him on anything,
Yeah. You know, I did for this, for
my second book that came out, I did a,
I was like, well, I was like, you
didn't want like you have a lot of fans,
you want to do that? Like nobody gives a
shit about me. Like they want to see you,
do you want to like,
I was like,
do you want to do like a
video interview or something?
That's if you buy the Ebook, you get
like, you know, whatever. And he was like,
I'll do it if it's you, me
and the camera. And I'm like,
well what about somebody to run the
camera? He's like, fucking, I'm out. Like,
all right, fine. I'll run the
camera and be inner. Yeah.
So I was like me turning on the camera
and then running over and sitting in the
thing.
Wow. What is, he just doesn't
want another person in the room.
He just doesn't get along
with people that well. Wow.
So he's just a grizzled old dude.
Like I feel like maybe that's
how they made them back
then. I don't know. But, uh,
I mean, like the thing, the weird thing
is if you came up to him on the street,
he'd be like a perfect gentleman.
You know? Like he'd be totally, yeah.
Who would he be keeping it together?
He doesn't really want to talk to you.
Not really going to be rude to you.
He just doesn't really want to.
So he picks out a couple of people, like
his family and he's like, this is it.
This is, these are the
people I talked to. Yeah.
They're not talking to anybody else.
Yeah.
That's how my grandfather was also really,
my grandfather was really
just like one of those like,
scream at your wife doors, get
over here and just like, not like,
I'm not a happy,
I grew up with a grandfather who was a,
he's a great guy,
but him and his wife
fought like cats and dogs.
It was crazy.
My grandparents,
you still fucking scream at each other.
They would scream at each other that I
was like, fallout four, five, you know,
it was like this little monkey watching
these crazy old Italians don't wash be
Zhao, don't you fucking rush Mary
screaming at my grandfather. I'm like,
whoa. That's what I remember. I remember
at a very early age going, Whoa,
the relationships can go this far south.
Fuck man,
dude. I think, I feel like people
back then, they used to do like,
they love each other.
Yeah.
It's a little harder life and nobody's
getting divorced as much as they are now.
Yeah. It's a totally different
world, man. It was a dangerous,
scary world back then. That was
it. That, you know, they lived,
they lived through the world wars, the
depression, like that kind of shit.
My grandparents came over here during
the depression, you know, that's like,
that's when they arrive. They arrived
like right in the middle of the shit.
So the fact that they were saying it all,
you know,
the fact that they made it through and
had family and actually have those family
like go off and that survive on their
own in the wild. It's incredible.
Yeah. I feel like it was, I mean, I know
it sounds Kinda like cliche to say it,
but it was just a way harder existence.
Yeah. You had to be way tougher.
You had it to be, you had to be someone
who dealt with a lot more tragedy,
that's for sure. Yeah. For the most
part, you know, he just, you know, you,
I think the world was just
a harsher, more, you know,
more animalistic place almost back then.
You didn't want to hear any,
we didn't want to hear any bullshit.
Yeah. It's unfortunate, man.
So many people from those really
hard errors grew up without much joy.
You know, they have like funny shit to
say. What is this angry, fucked up funny.
Yes.
Well my dad was a,
he grew up on a tobacco farm when
he was like 10 he worked the farm,
you're like 10 he fell off a wagon and
rolled over her arm and it crushed his
elbow. When they took him to the doctor,
the doctor's told his dad, he was like,
I can amputate his arm and he'll live
for sure. Or I can give them like these,
this medication, and maybe there's
only a 30% chance that he lives.
And he said his dad was like,
let 'em die. There's no,
there's no room in the
world for one arm farmer.
Holy Shit.
Just like how it was back then. The doctor
was like, all right, cool. And then just,
it gives him the stuff. Wow. Yeah.
That was his dad's had let them
die. Yeah. He said, let him die.
There's no room in the
world for one arm farmer.
Holy Shit. Imagine thinking that
when you're 10 that you, you,
you're not even, no one cares about
you. Your arm is broken. And then like,
let them die
as, this is how crazy my dad is. When
he told me that story, I was like,
that's so fucked up. He's like, what
are you talking about? He saved my arm.
I'm like, are you insane?
Like that's, Oh my God,
Jesus Christ.
I've been watching all these
documentaries recently about neanderthals,
you know, and about, uh, you know,
this is like people that
are talking about not like,
they're pretty much pretty sure that
most white people have some percentage of
neanderthal in us.
And imagine if you for some reason had
to go back to that time and survive.
Imagine how hard that would suck to be
making spears with fucking rocks and
animals seeing you.
I mean,
would you just like take your clothes off
and just walk into the ocean and drown
and would you just give up? I mean,
would you even want to get to today?
I've actually thought a lot
about that cause I was like,
I thought about like how far back in time
I'd have to go to actually be able to
invent anything. That was cool and
I don't know how to, anything works.
I just used those. I would, if that
was the case. Yeah, I would just, Oh,
do what you say.
Think like, man, do I really,
I think your, your survival
instincts would kick in,
but you know, you wouldn't
have this, you know,
this esoteric search for happiness is
deep search for how like everybody has.
Like I just don't know where I'm at
at this point in my life. Like, okay,
you know why?
Because there's no fucking struggle.
You're getting through your day hopping
in your range rover with your little
tiny dog and there's just
no real struggle. Okay,
so you're confused and you're sad and
you might be happier if you were chasing
animals with a fucking
point. You stick. Yeah.
You might be happy if you are running
a farm. You might be, might be ma'am.
I mean you can even see it today and like
really shitty countries. Nobody's like,
hmm, should I pursue a law degree? You're
like, no, I just want to stay alive.
Just fucking stay alive.
Yeah, there's a Lotta,
there's a lot of weirdness to this life.
I know this life is w we,
we might not be set up to handle it.
You know,
we might not be set up to,
to deal with all the pressures that
technology and society and all this,
all this information that's
coming at us all the time.
Not might not be set up for that shit.
Well it's like you were saying before we
started like people get crazy when they
get online.
Yeah. Some people do. It's a,
some people it's like thick had finally
lash out. They could fuck the world back.
Like the world's fucking them, you know,
they just feel like the world fucks them.
Like everywhere they turn it's like this
is not working out. You know, you're,
you're looking at television, you
know, that's not my life. You know,
you're looking at there.
The reality is most people out there not
doing exactly what they want to do and
they want to be angry at somebody
and all day the most of them work.
And if you're working, most of the time
you have to keep your fucking mouth shut.
You can't say what you want to say.
You can't, you're in an office.
So with a bunch of people
you could actually get sued
for trying to crack jokes.
You know, you can't say anything
sexual, you know, if you do,
you're going to go to court. I ain't
going to get sued for sexual harassment.
It's like it's really restrictive
environment and then they get online,
they don't like you fucking suck,
fucking kill yourself,
drown in aids.
And it's like these,
it is concentrated attack on like
Brittany Spears or you know, or anybody.
That's what it is. It's like this just
fucking this, this little volcano of hate.
It just pops out. It's because
he's poor folks live a shit life.
I had ones when she might add,
says first started getting popular and uh,
like I got a,
I got a book deal out of it and uh,
I was checking at replies the day
it did and this guy had filled up,
cause you can only have 140
characters per tweet. Right.
He had filled up like 15 or 20
tweets just to haul caps. Faggot.
This is actually my dad's us. It
was just nonstop. Uh, he like,
he spent like probably like 10
or 15 minutes just doing nonstop.
But there's something funny about
that though. Did you laugh laughing?
Like I took a screenshot of it and
set it all my friends and stuff.
That's fucking great man. That
is great. When it's silly bitch.
Is there a,
a tweet that you did that it's your
favorite one that you still like look back
and I'm like, man, that was great. And
that's like one in particular? Yeah,
I mean there, cause like for me, he's, he
said them to me, you know, so I was like,
there's context to it and stuff.
And this one time he, he, he,
he like loves our dog more than
like people in and he brought our,
he took the dog to the dog park.
He walked in one day I'm sitting on the
couch and he's like, he's like, well,
I guess, uh, were, were banned from
the dog park. And I was like, Oh fuck.
What happened? He's like, I guess it's
okay to Barak and it's okay to hump,
but if you do both at the same time,
it freaks people out.
It's just like the thought of my dog
is like angrily raping other dogs like
there.
And then my dad is somebody having to
come to my dad say something about it.
Like it wasn't what he said
that was so funny on me.
It was just like that
scenario. We laugh. That's,
you were one of the first, uh, uh, Twitter
followers that I remember that. Like,
what's it like? Cool. Like I found
this, this, this, the hilarious Twitter.
And then my girlfriend, I told her at her
at the time and she was like, oh my God,
this is the best thing ever. And she
told her, Megan, I just watched it like,
like become like something
I thought I found myself.
And then growing to just being everywhere.
You were pretty much being retweeted by
every single person. I know at one point,
uh, have you, cause I have you,
yeah.
Like are you over it now?
Are you [inaudible] gotten
to a point where you're like,
I just want to write books
now and, or, or is it, do you,
are you still in love with
Twitter doing the Twitter thing?
I mean I gotta be honest like it,
it was such a lucky break for
me that I sort of just feel,
I mean it sounds cheesy,
but I feel just like really grateful
for everything that's happened.
So to me it's never like it didn't
wear off and like, ah, I do this,
I got this dumb thing here. It's like,
well that fucking made my whole career.
So yeah, I mean to me I
still, I don't do it as much,
but I definitely don't have like that
same kind of feeling where it's like I'm
over this. So like something
that I really connect with,
I guess he must've been so site. Do you
totally hit the lottery? It was exotic.
It was exactly like hitting the lottery.
There really was.
That's amazing. What did you
want to do before you did that?
Did you always want to be a writer?
Yeah,
I had worked up here.
I'd waited tables in La and I like I
had sold a screenplay and like quip
stupidly quit my job and then had to go
back to it. I have to run out of money,
but like I had been, you
know, struggling as a,
as a screenwriter for a while and then,
and uh,
so this was exactly what I wanted to do,
you know, sort of like gifted to me. Okay.
Wow. And from there you do,
how do you get this TV deal?
How's that happen and how do they did
William Shatner to play your dad and like
where did it all go? A
foul? Because it's a, it's,
it's a fascinating that they've found
a way to make something that's really
funny. Not that funny. No, it's true.
I mean it's really like, that's exactly
wait would happen. It's like
find the center and pour
water. Um, it, uh, you know,
like I wrote the book proposal and I had
sent it out just as a book and the book
was just like, are rated like the
Twitter feed, you know, but with stories.
And then as soon as it got out there,
then network started calling being like,
we want to do this. And I remember saying
to my, I have a screenwriting partner.
I remember saying to him, I'm like,
how could we do this on a network? It,
he's says fuck every other word, like
we can't do it on a network. And,
and then, uh, and then I was like, wait,
I need to just shut up and it just
like do this, you know, and try and,
uh,
it just,
I remember early on we
sat with the standards and
practices person at CBS cause
we ended up, I pitched it and
we sold the CBS and, and uh,
when we sold the standards and
practices person was like, all right,
here's the list of words that you can't
say or even like intimate, you know,
and uh, intimate and, and uh,
it was like everything he says.
And I was like, all right, this is,
that's ridiculous. This is gonna suck
about your conversation with the standards
of practices. Person can be mad. Dang.
Yeah. Usually like why you
can't blind, it's really,
it's amazing what you can and can't say.
What people don't understand is like
cable, you can say anything. Yeah.
And the only reason why they don't say
everything is just their own discretion.
It's the idea that sponsors don't
want to be on a show that, you know,
says fucking cunt and whatever. So,
but the FCC doesn't regulate cable.
Yeah, it's crazy. I mean, yeah,
it was, I guess. And I also like,
because after we did that, when we
got Shatner to s to set to star in it,
um, I was like, well maybe
you know, like he'll,
it'll when coming through his
mouth it will sound different.
But it was just like,
my dad's like unintentionally funny.
He's not like cracking jokes
really in Sitcoms, you know,
it's like set up punchline
set up punchline and it,
and it just didn't fit that format at all.
I think with Hbo and Showtime,
I think in that works look ridiculous.
Tried trying to just only
use limited language like,
and with movies and like what kind of a
fucking stupid anti evolutionary concept
does that, oh, we're going to pretend
forever that these words are forbidden.
Like really, we live in a 2012 of the
Internet and we've got forbidden words.
You can't broadcast them.
And if they, if you do,
they can come and take your numbers.
Who will take your numbers away?
You know what the fuck kind of
science fiction movie is this.
There's certain sounds you can't make
with your mouth. There were illegal.
Even though the indistinguishable from,
you know,
other words that you can
get away with saying,
I mean everybody knows exactly
what the fuck you're talking about,
but if you say it with a certain sound,
certain sound that comes out of your
mouth, I think it's getting better,
but it's still the same. You can't
say can't on television. Yeah,
I bet at capital happened.
Can't see she's up can't because
sometimes someone's a cunt. You know,
you can't say that.
You could never say that on television
now there there's no substitution.
There's no substitution for that word
in the right context, the right forum,
he should be allowed to use it. Do you
think about the right word? Got dammit.
Do you think it would happen though?
I think it would happen like right
before a woman becomes president.
That will probably go through
whenever we had.
It's not legislation where going to pat,
you should be able to use all
the words so it's so stupid.
It should always be about intent. And
what is your intent? What are you,
what are you trying to say?
It shouldn't be about words.
Shouldn't be about magic words.
That's craziness. You're,
you're artificially giving these words
power and making them ridiculous.
Eliminating them from all
discourse during the day. You know,
while you're at the business who can't be,
you know this fucking hunting
coffee machine can't say that.
That's why I went to like that old
guy that was a selling Winnebagos.
You remember that dude? Yes.
I or another viral sensation.
You ever seen that Brian? Yeah. The guy
is awesome, right? Why is it awesome?
Because he's a fucking nice guy. Tried to
sell it a be on his ass. A fucking shit.
I'm fucking can't remember
this fucking pizza shit.
And of course I fucked my lines
up. You know, he gets going crazy.
Really Fun to watch because
you're looking at this guy,
he was like this button down poor fuck.
Who can't swear during the day
and you get to see like it's,
I think it's like real moments.
So that's what's enjoyable.
So when I see like a bull shitty sanitize
thing on narrow TV, you're like, well,
that's not how real people talk or
how weird must have been
for you because you will,
this is coming from your dad who's
fucking hilarious to you and you know,
so it's inspiring to the, you write all
his shit down and put it out to people.
People respond to his exact words that
millions of them we'll do get onto your
Twitter and follow you.
So it's very obvious at that
combination in the exact form works.
But they're like, no, no, no.
You got to scrub it with bleach.
He just couldn't keep scrubbing it with
bleach until you have like this dead
version of what it could have been.
So stupid.
I mean,
that's the is exactly kind of stupid.
So dumb. They're the
same people. You dummies.
The same people that subscribed on Twitter
or this same people that would watch
the TV show are the same people that
would buy the products that they're,
they're pitching in their commercials.
It's the same fucking people to
pretend it's not and you're just,
you got to do something different by not
saying fuck. It's just, it's so dumb.
Yeah.
It was especially frustrating cause like
the Twitter feed had done really well
and then the book came out in the book
did really, really well and I was like,
all right,
so the two things that stay exactly
true to what our have done well and then
they're like,
I have,
well we're going to change it and we're
going to largely at fault just like
anyone else. I was
like, maybe it can work.
Yeah, of course. You wanted to believe
it works. You, you hit the lottery.
All of a sudden you have a TV show.
Of course you wanted to
believe it would work.
I mean I'm talking total
Utopian Society obviously,
but I just kind of feel like that has to
be one of the things that fucks us up.
It has to be when when language is
restricted and there's certain words that
actually have magical powers,
like if you say them someone without doing
anything physically, if you say them,
people get actually lock you up and find
you and do all sorts of things to you
if you say them and do the, you know,
the jurisdiction of the airwaves.
That's that's,
that's insanity.
That's a crazy notion and the fact
that we accept that. It's almost like,
except that you accept censorship
in any form you're going to,
except all the other craziness that
goes along with being governed as well.
It's like it's important
to make it all ridiculous.
Like this magic word thing might actually
be a key component to keeping people
close minded. If you can really convince
people that there are magic words,
it's such a dumb idea.
It might be like a mind prison
locks you hit. It locks you up in logic
to the point where you're, you're,
you're unable to analyze
the rest of the world.
It's like this complex thing
of don't say content. You know?
It's like this lock idea,
this segment in your brain.
You're a box which you
choose to only operate in.
Yeah, it's so crazy. It's funny too
cause like on regular basic cable TV,
like sometimes there'll be like the,
you know,
Hispanic station or whatever and they're
saying their version of fucking shit
and pussy and con. Yeah they are,
but it's in Spanish and so it just,
just because I, we, you know, most
people don't understand that language.
Then it's cool. I got to learn Spanish.
That's what it is. I got to learn Spanish.
Fuck it. It's just so stupid, man.
It's like that's why people are so
turning to the Internet, not speak well.
That's a terrible sentence.
But that's why I think the Internet has
so much appeal to especially the younger
people.
It's like if you grow up with it,
it's really hard to go sit calm after
you go. You know like the style,
project.com never been a style project.
He was like the original right
style. Yeah. Getting them,
it was one of the original,
like if there was something fucked
up out there on the Internet,
he would have it on his website.
If some new shit went down,
you'd go to his website and he would
have it, whatever. It was like,
like crazy video situation shit.
Yeah. It's like naked girls
most fucked up things that dude
would have it, but it's, you know,
it's out there if you want to look,
it's,
yeah,
I mean that's the thing is like I think
pretending like it's not out there does
no one any favors.
So not helping anybody needs these fucking
stupid shows where you're not allowed
to use all the words like wow.
Enough already.
Yeah.
And the funny thing is is like it just
feels like you said it especially dated,
it's insulting.
It's insulting
it where there's,
how many wars going on simultaneously
and what we want to pretend that like
words are bad. This that's so,
it's so anti evolution of it.
It's so stupid that there was
forbidden words. I mean that's,
it's such a dumb premise that like if
you just accept that and that becomes a
major part of your society when you're
talking about your ability to communicate,
that becomes a major point. And
then it's like, well, wait a minute.
These words are totally forbid and you
can get arrested for him only if you use
them in in one certain
way if you broadcast them,
but you can use them and reach
the same amount of people.
If you do it on cable or the
Internet. That's cool. That's okay.
But so it's only censored in one way,
but in this one way it's
like really bad for you.
Like if you get caught
like going on the news go,
unless you [inaudible] like don't
take a lot of money from you,
they could find you. You like, you're
forcing people to hear that. Like the SOS.
There's something to that.
The fact that you planned did,
it's probably like some first
degree type activity. You know,
they could probably like find you for a
really substantial amount of money for
purposely using magic words on,
on the radio or on television.
That's God.
That's maddening.
Yeah. It's funny when, uh, uh, I was
promoting this book, um, I wanted to s uh,
you can send out a tweet
that's like promoted so that
all of your followers will
definitely see it.
Cause you know,
people log in at different times and you
miss tweets and all that kind of stuff.
And so I sent out this tweet,
it was just a quote, my dad,
and then it had like by
the book, Blah, blah, blah,
after and it had like shit or fucking
the quote, I can't remember. And Twitter,
it was like, oh, we can't,
we can't promote that. We
can't show that. And I'm like,
but you're showing it to people who
already subscribe to my feed. Like Shit.
My Dad says in the title,
and they're like, yeah, but
we can't have, we can't, uh,
put something on somebody's feed
that has any profanity. I'm like,
but it's my fucking, they're already,
they're already following me.
I'm just making sure they see it.
It's like, it's bananas. Like it's,
it makes no sense. And that's in there,
like worried they're going to get sued.
You know?
I hope that that's something that
the Internet's going to dissolve.
Well, it, it's going to,
because like that's what NBC is not
going to be a television channel in five
years. It's going to be nbc.com.
It's, it's killing. It's killing the,
the live television broadcast,
which I know it seems crazy,
but it's nbcs not going to have money
broadcasting and spending all that money
when it's going to be, everyone's
going to be on the Internet, you know?
Well,
you know,
some shows I think we'll be successful
because it costs a lot of money to make
them things like game of Thrones
like that, the, you know, that's,
that's a really, you need a studio. You
need a bunch of bad motherfucker. Yeah.
But that's not broad pointing together.
Right. Well and that's what's it,
that's what's keeping the language.
That's what I'm saying.
It's that it's the language.
It's only because of live free
broadcast out like NBC, ABC,
CBS. But it's still, I think you're right.
I mean even for a network show, if you,
if you really want to like it costs
a lot of money to do that. Yeah.
It was going to say it lost or it's
going to say lost. Do you need,
you would need like a
real studio to make laws.
So I ain't mean they're going to have to
figure out a way to make money doing it
that way. I guess. I mean, what, what
do you think is going to happen? No,
that's what I'm saying.
I'm saying that the only thing
that's keeping censorship and,
and shit like that off of, of television
is the, the those channels. Right.
And when you think that they're going
to go though, you think there'd be just,
they're going to be an HBO work,
they're going to become an HBO on a cable,
a well your ear or deepen
the television industry.
You actually like what,
what did,
what did you executive produced that show
or something like that writer and it's
like your produce. How does it work? Is
it, are we onto that? Is that, I think,
I think what's going to end up, I
mean, fourth, the fact the line now,
but I think it's,
uh,
to end up being where you can just
subscribe to each channel, right?
So if you don't have the good shows
people want, then fuck you. You Die.
You know?
For some folks it would
be advantageous to,
to stick with the way they do it
now and like not swear, you know,
this is probably a lot
of people out there.
They'd probably like Dr. Quinn Medicine
woman type TV shows and like there's a
lot of money in selling those people
things. But how do they do that?
How they balance that and have
like good comedy at the same time.
Because if you really
want to have good comedy,
unless you're some Larry David type
genius that can create something like
Seinfeld,
you know,
most of you so straddled down as to what
you could have really said and talked
about.
Here's some good,
I mean the fucking radio is one of,
I mean there's shows a lucky,
crazy experience man. They,
they snuck in and we all snuck in and
barely got by every year like this show,
like never took on,
took off at all until it was canceled.
And then it did like really
good and like repeats.
But it was a perfect combination of a
really funny show at like a super lucky
position to be in. You know, where it's
just, but then realizing that that's,
that's not even really enough.
Like you have to have someone who like,
they have to like promote you. You have
to get out there too. It's a weird,
the world of,
uh,
creating a sitcom that navigating the
waters of where you are at in the lineup
and it's a very, very, very
tricky situation for success.
And they also pump,
like I,
I was on a show [inaudible] on our show
last year that got canceled on CBS after
two episodes and there's a fucking
terrible shows, a disaster.
Some of them are so bad. It's scary. Yeah.
This one and this one was, was like that.
It wasn't really it,
it just was one of the things where
it was just a huge cluster fuck. And,
and they spent, I mean, this must
have spent 5,000 million dollars,
like in early promotion for the staff
and then two episodes just boom,
gone. It's crazy how they do
that and it happens all the time.
That's why they're so like hands on about
shit. Yeah. That's why they're there.
You know, it's expensive
to make a pilot man. Yeah.
That was a part of a super expensive
pilot ones where they made a fake jungle
set. Wow. It was, yeah,
it was a by the same guy who
produced a news radio, Paul Simms.
It was called overseas or something like
that. I think it was called overseas.
And uh,
it was crazy expensive to make man Leanna,
a whole like big fucking studio space.
It was trees and they had a pond.
They had a fucking pawn.
It was so crazy like that. We were
going to do this and pretend, I mean,
I dunno if it would've worked out all the
comedy. Yes. It was common, like lost,
but no, no, no. It was like, um, I'm
looking at, I don't remember the premise.
The premise was something like,
I went over there for one reason,
but I got stuck because I have a
good heart or something like that.
And next thing you know, I'm
overseas, whatever town, you know,
it's just that it's a
vehicle to develop comedy.
I don't even remember what it was.
I don't remember.
It was like they were
working with orphans.
I Dunno what the fuck it was that we
were over there doing, but this, this,
this idea that they would spend so
much money on this pilot, I mean to,
to make this fucking set alone.
It was ridiculous. It was so big.
It was a fucking fake jungle, you know?
And like why, how much is this gonna cost?
How much it's going to cost all the time.
You've got to maintain this
fake jungle you have out there.
You're going to drain all
that water though. I was,
the mosquitoes are going to grow in it.
The fuck are you doing?
But that must mean, you know when it
works, it just bucket loads of money.
When you find out like what
Seinfeld earned, you know,
I don't want to blow up his spot, but that
dude made some money and you go, whoa,
like a real hit, like a
Seinfeld. There's, that's like,
they're printing money. It's just,
whoa. It's like, it's crazy. It's like,
what do you like came up to a little boy.
How much money do you want?
I want $100 billion.
Here's $100 billion. Wow.
It's so crazy that you can make that
kind of money from a sitcom. Yeah.
It's funny I was on,
I was working at Warner Brothers at the
time when Charlie Sheen was going bat
shit. Right. Oh that must've been awesome.
It was crazy cause you'd sometimes
see him and it was like this are,
you saw him like come in as whacked
one time banging on the studio door.
There was no one there though.
And I just fucking kept driving.
I'm like cough card cause
I was like I don't want to,
I don't even want to be witnessed to this.
Like whatever.
But it was making so much money
and I remember people were like,
is he going to come back? Is it not
going to come back? I'm like dude,
it's coming back.
They'll figure it out.
They'll make up fucking CGI Charlie Sheen
and no come back cause it's making so
much money for people.
Well it's interesting.
They just moved on to Ashton Kutcher
and everybody's like that's cool.
We'll take it. I'm like, it's still really
fun. And we like it. We don't need to.
Charlie is it doing good now? I don't
even know where it was doing really good.
Yeah. I think it's still, the link's
doing great. I think it's doing great.
It's weird why Ashton Kutcher's funny.
You know, he can act as a handsome fella.
Great Bone structure. I think that
would be very pleasing to the ladies.
You know, I think they like it. I think
everything had worked out well. They got,
you know Charlie Charlie's a little crazy.
It's probably turned a lot
of those gals off. You know,
like I want to support the show,
but that Charlie Sheen and his behavior,
it's a conundrum, you know, I
don't want to support that. Oh Joe,
I'm sorry. I was gonna choose
a subject to completely, so
when you did your father,
you derailed it.
We're in the middle of a good God damn
Charlie Sheen breakdown Charlie Sheen and
figuring out what's really going on.
I was thinking,
cause you have sheen fever.
I just,
something popped in my head
right now and I was like, oh,
I remember we had that conversation of
all these people have been telling me
they would fuck George Clooney,
Clooney,
like guys that we know and I couldn't
remember who one was Brendan Walsh shirts.
I just remembered Sam triple.
He said he would fuck Obama if he could.
Jesus think you're even
supposed to say that. Yeah,
you got [inaudible]. You can't see
that dude. Don't say that. Well,
I was told I didn't say it. I really
don't think you can even say that.
Like have sex with the president. Yeah.
That's one of those things that be you.
You're kind of like you. You're not
allowed to saying that you, you can,
it is illegal to state that you would
want to assassinate or do harm to,
but I think it's probably rape in the
but is probably in there too. No, no.
I think you can. I think what Sam means,
like if you say that the same umbrella,
that's like a terrorist threat dude.
I think what Sam was saying is that that
Obama would want to have sex with them.
Like if he was gonna take up,
a lot of it came to them and like
came up and was like, oh damn.
When we were allowed to imply that.
Especially considering the fact
that he's married and has children.
Well if he probably illegal
to imply that it's probably
is no salt on [inaudible].
You can't fuck Obama in any
way or leave him alone. Man,
I didn't know I want to stay for
the record that I did not want.
I'm not the one that said at Sam Tripoli
did. He shouldn't talk like that.
It said smart people, they go,
there's no need for that guy was like,
I around just what is it?
What kind of ideal planting
out there in society.
You don't want to be the list with the
under the heading of people who said
they'd fuck Obama, Chad.
Dude, it's a small list to,
you'd be surprised. I bet by
the time they get to me, oh,
there's only five people that said it.
Oh Shit. I bet. One out of every girl,
every two girls would want have sex
with a mama. They've decided that,
well if you put it that
way, smoothie, oh I forgot.
I was thinking in my head, what would it
be like one hour three and I was like,
no one do we have to figure
out a fake number five.
But about 80% of the people would you
say no 90 you think 50% of the population
of women would want to fuck Obama if
they, if no one could find out? Yeah.
This would be a lot. It'd be a big
number. First of all, if you know,
if they both were like on a deserted
island or some point though,
if you got him into some
crazy fantasy situation,
a bone might be able to fuck 99% of the
women king of the hill though. Yeah,
he wins. Yeah. It's like this is probably
some gay women who would fuck them.
Oh for sure. For sure. Just
sort of story. You know,
especially the gay women that are gay
because like every guy that ever met an
asshole, there's those guys
too, you know. They was,
I called them give up gaze the render.
Yeah,
girls just meet too many Douche bags
and I'm like, I give up, I'm going gay.
Cause girls will do that. They
can do that man. See I think what,
what Sam's thinking is that like Obama
would get one room at the w and then he
would get the one that's connected to it,
you know?
And they would just both on lock it in
the morning in the middle and then Sam
would come in there were like
wearing no clothes and just start,
you know like going down on Obama,
something like that. That's what I,
I think that's illegal too.
You know you're going to have a
drone flying above your head. Stupid.
I want you to stop. You
really need to stop. I think,
well I didn't say it the
same for whoever this guy is.
He trying to send up the river
by talking through his mouth.
Maybe what he said then you should
have told them. Listen my friend,
how about you keep this
fucking shit to yourself. Oh,
we're all going to wind up
in the [inaudible] Bay. Maybe
that's journal material.
They're going to dress you up in a burka,
the dude and stick you in a box.
You're just going to disappear.
And this is all allegedly,
I don't remember what exactly.
I don't know what I know that
Sam said he wants to have,
he would have sex with Obama.
Well I think I'd have to be
mutual and I think that wrong.
Just trying to be funny and I don't think
he was successful. That's what I say.
I said it's just ridiculous. It's
actually the present. How dare you,
but it's okay to say having sex with
Bill Clinton right now, right? Yes. Yeah.
You can say,
you could say like if you're a girl,
like you'd look to,
you do whatever you want to start
Clinton's deck. Cause he likes that too.
But you don't get in trouble. You
don't think so? No. I think it's,
everybody just keeps it on the hush hush.
Now they know what happens when
it gets out. You don't want that.
You don't want to be Lewinski
skiing nettle. Right? Yeah.
That's so crazy. Like,
even today, like you say her name and
I was like, oh, come on the dress.
Boom, Sherlock lock, boom.
What a nutty time man.
What a strange time in our world where
everything got so desensitized that
everyone in the world was able to get the
information that there was calm on the
dress and that she sucked on his cock.
Like there was no question.
So everybody talked about the whole
country, the whole country. So she sucked.
His cock can come in the dress.
She shucked with God.
I mean it was a national dialogue the
first time ever that any distinct sexual
act between someone of royalty,
a president of United States of America
was even engaging with some sort of sex.
But outside of his marriage and with a
20 year old chicken just works there.
Oh my God, he's a look. Stir
like this isn't a guy in a band.
This is the fucking
president United States.
And he's going like straight Mick
Jagger on this chick. That's,
that's incredible, right? If you
really stop and think about it.
Yeah, I, you know, it's funny, I never
thought of it like that, but it really is.
It's like that's the basis
from Boston has that story.
Yeah, exactly. The basis from Basel.
It's perfect. That's perfect feed.
Yeah, man, we, our whole world
changed. It was like, okay, okay, okay,
what is really going on?
And people don't give a fuck really.
Well they didn't because he was doing a
good job as a president and they're like,
well listen,
everybody heard the stories about John F.
Kennedy and how about the most of these
guys? In order to get to that position,
you've got gotta be some kind of a freak.
You gotta be some kind of a crazy guy
that wants to be at the head and the
leader,
even if it's for the right reasons.
Even if it's like with complete
good justice and grace and you're doing
all the right way to get to the very top
to very activity, too many tippity
top, you gotta be a little crazy.
You just got to,
you got to be to even want to be there
to even want to be the guy runs shit.
You've got to be to be the guy who says,
I know there's 300 million people,
but everybody sit the fuck down because
I'm going to talk now only me to 300
million and I'm your leader.
I'm the leader. I'm the
leader of 300 million people.
Are you talking about
how was that possible?
This is a crazy position to be in.
You have to be a crazy person
to acquire that position.
You have to be crazy to chase it.
Yeah. I mean if you heard
any of your friends be like,
I want to lead 300 million people,
they'd be like,
you're a fucking psychotic narcissist.
You'd be out of your fucking mind.
Get outta here.
Stupid.
It just,
it's almost like the job only exists
for people who are like real live
superheroes who are really going to
try to change the world and people are
completely full of shit. Like that's it.
It's the only caught selling room. It's,
there's no room for anything else. There
is now a lot of middle there. It's like,
it's like people who aren't even a
real person, they just go in and they,
you know, that game that you play, we
try to almost touch hands, you know,
he tried to like see like back.
I would try to see how much you can
keep it together. Like how crows close,
you can get an anticipate each other's
movements. That's what they're doing.
But their particular line
steppers that's what's going on.
Yeah, that's it. It's just takes a
huge ego. Yeah. You've got to be crazy.
Yeah. That the idea that you're going
to run that whole giant mass of humans,
that's nuts.
You gotta be fucking crazy to even
attempt that because even the dumbest
smallest decision you make every
day affects tons of people.
Will they all go gray
like almost instantly,
the first couple of weeks they're
like, oh, the fucking pressure of,
you know,
saluting people and you're end up fucking
air force one and you're flying around
the world and you realize the reality
of what's really happening. You know,
and you hear the body counts and you,
you hear the numbers counts that how
much money and the defense contractor
budgets and this fucking craziness and
that craziness and they're using drones
and now you got to go on TV and pretend
Osama bin Ladin just got killed.
You know, they didn't girls all
by law and just shut the fuck up.
The guy had been dead forever. That was,
that was one of the dumbest things ever
drowned him. He really, really,
we got no pictures just because we don't
want them to know. We really think that,
yeah,
I don't believe it.
I say horse shall you always believed
the opposite. I say shitty things,
but that one, that one, I say horse shit.
The reason why I say horseshit is because
there was so many people that were
saying that guy was dead already.
There were saying that he was under going
dialysis. They're saying, right. Yeah,
like a big fucking kidney man.
And then there's other people
that have said this photos, they,
they're using that.
They say there's a one video of the guy
watching television in his apartment and
it's like, oh, it looks like it's a song
been lawn. They're saying, no, no, no.
That's my friend. I know this
guy, this guy, he looks like him.
Everybody looks like him. When they get
to be a certain age, you know, I mean,
they all look like Osama bin Ladin
at a certain age. We get crazy beers.
It's like,
you know,
that's just a certain look and there's
not a lot of distinct features in a
fucking giant beard. That's
when, when I have my own beard,
when I grow my beard out,
it covers your whole face.
It's like this big crazy mass of hair
and everybody with a big crazy massive
hair looks pretty fucking similar. You
know, just most of it's just crazy hair.
So he's like, this is not though
some, I've been loving this.
She's my friend and not him.
It wasn't his house the other day.
I don't know if they really did,
but I think that would be
a story that if I, if I, you know,
wanted to release the frack
that Osama bin Laden was dead,
I would hold onto it for awhile and
then I pretend maybe they needed,
they needed to shoot one of the people
there that were not supposed to be
shooting. Maybe that was, that's
what was going on. And then they,
then they were like,
oh, we got him. Maybe,
maybe they were just testing out
some new fucking ways to Jack People.
They went awry, you know, they crashed
a helicopter. They were like, look,
we've got some good news and bad news.
The bad news is we crashed a helicopter.
It good as it is. We just
killed Osama bin. Ladin me.
Well they had that dude on ice.
They were waiting like we need,
we need a time when we're going to break
out this and just use it as I get out
of jail free pass.
It's got like a special button.
He pitches and then they fucking,
they open up the freezer,
bring out this frozen popsicle,
Osama bin Ladin and it takes some
pictures with him. Come on man.
And then they throw him in the water. All.
Okay, cool. Yep. All right. I believe you.
You don't have to show me anything.
That was the weirdest thing.
That was the weirdest thing to me.
It was just like they went through this
crazy thing of like searching for years
and years and years, but then
they're like, you know what?
We got to get him in the water.
Like now what,
what was really frightening to me was a,
when all the people were cheering like
on the streets in like DC near the
Capitol and they were going Jew who has
hey. And I was walking and I was like,
wow, how many of those people are
getting paid to do that? First of all,
is it a little like professional
cheerleaders that they
brought in from like the
most communist schools?
Possibility to accent them in.
Got Everybody fired up about
you say you say it's ridiculous.
It was packed. And the funny thing
is like they would, they would,
they wanted to show it like on CNN stuff,
but then every once in a while it'd
be like the most drunk frat dude ever.
Like come up and look
just like deviled bird.
But the camera Justin in your
pharmacy, sorry, it becomes a,
you know, a cultural event, you know,
it's one of those whatever you, yeah,
it's like the, you know, the
death of our enemy. That's a huge,
it's a huge ticket to pull out. We're
going to say nothing. Nothing at all.
I was just wondering who do you think
killed Biggie? I, you know what?
I think he's alive and two POCs
alive and they live in Sweden.
I liked the way you think, dude. Logic
reason you putting it all together.
Um, you are, you, are you like
politically active at all?
Like do you look at this Obama
and Mitt Romney election and yeah,
I mean like, you know, I
have like my views on it.
I always think like I'm
never like informed enough
to like engage with like if
somebody gets like crazy then I'm
like damn, we're always talking about
the defense contractor
started this situation but
80 follow your mother fucker.
What's a sport? The biggest thing
I find like creepy is like, uh, a
Romney just kind of reminds me
of one of those guys who's like,
just like son you a mattress that just
like, yeah, you'll love it. And I'm like,
anything you want to hear, he'll
tell you. So I'm always like, ah,
he almost has no shot.
He almost has no shot because of the fact
that it's going to come out when they
start the debates and the real rhetoric
and hate starts flying when it gets
closer and closer to November.
His Dad was born on a fucking farm.
Like a,
like a cult in Mexico.
Yeah. Yeah, I know. That's so crazy.
Cause I had read that and then I was like,
why isn't that out? And I'm like the
first one that told us about this, Brian,
was it Bolelli Daniel Bell. Ella. Yeah.
Danieli Bolelli Elliot was telling
us about doubt that um, it's,
they have these places where they decided
they wanted to keep polygamy going.
So they moved to Mexico, set up shop.
They had whole communities in Mexico.
Yeah. And that's where Mitt Romney's dad
was born. It's crazy. And just the other,
the other day he was just
like, he was like, listen man,
who was talking to this crowd?
It's like my dad's from Mexico.
Like I understand where you guys are
coming from sort of thinking like,
I bet your experiences a little different.
Yeah.
You're out there with fucking Pedro
pound and corn into flour tortillas.
Fuck Outta here bitch.
You live in on a crazy farm
where everybody gets to
fuck hundred women. Yeah.
He wasn't working. I'm
fucking Makina Dora. I mean,
I mean we're not hating man.
You know,
I think it's a ballsy ass move to move
to another country and set up shop.
You know, that's what the,
the Mormon society to do.
That's a ballsy fuckin move.
Imagine how much you must like having
three wives to be like, fuck it,
I'm moving to Mexico.
That's fucking bull.
That's the old way,
the old way,
they can't take away the gods way here.
It is written just so really it's,
it's,
that's the one that's so
obviously showing it's pimp hand.
Whenever you get like the, I won five
wives or unlimited about a wise man.
Come on man. What's really
going on? He shows his pimp
ever like I,
I've thought about it many times having
the mammary love to have like a Harem,
you know like the way the, the salt
and her Brunei allegedly rocks it.
I always found that to be
the most fascinating cause
he's not married to any of
those. No, he has apparently this,
you know when you talk about like Forbes
500 or who's like got the most money,
I don't even think they
include royal families.
I think like these guys have like
unreported income. I think they're,
they're like,
they're beyond our calculations of what's
possible when it comes to wealth and
what I've heard some people do that
have like this kind of money. Let's, no,
let's not say any names at all.
I heard that they will go and pay
like the hottest women on the planet.
Let girls were like professional models.
They just pay them insane amounts of money
like any girl, really beautiful girls.
And it may be have posed nude somewhere
and just he'll find them and to just say
offer to them, they offer them crazy
money and so they have to do it. They all,
they feel like they have to do it.
And the next thing you know that go there
and they're are part of like a disco.
The guy has his own private disco
and so it's fucking bad ass too.
Cause you're talking about someone
with insane amounts of money,
like insane wealth.
Everything is gold gilded.
Perfect craftsman ship the finest food.
Yeah, I thought the most battle Ram. Yeah.
And he goes down there and it's just him
and he's the guy you know is
gold underwear on and he's
moving through the crowd
and he's paid all of these women
essentially to have sex with him at his
choosing whenever he likes, when
he ever, he likes, he just chooses.
So you might fly there and never fuck
him. Yeah. Yeah. He might not like you.
He might not be into that.
He just wants a bunch of them there
that are unbelievably hot and you know,
depending on who you listen to or which
different dude who was rocking it this
way,
you know they would do,
would have like 30 women just waiting
and they're like Penn House pets.
They're like fucking
like legit hot models,
not the top of the food.
I wish a wish that man would write a book.
You know, just like you want
to talk about being a baller.
I mean if that kind of wrote a book,
they be like,
that's so let me tell you how I
rock it has the name of his book.
Let me tell you how the
discount that chapter one,
this is what you would do if you had,
you know,
a fucking trillion dollars
or whatever this guy has.
He's like to pay them a half a million
dollars a year is nothing. It's nothing.
I was reading this thing that
said like Vladimir Putin had like,
he just collected a bunch of hot chicks
and had him play like horse polo naked
and he was like, I'll, I wish you all
to play horse club, but just naked.
He's an animal.
You don't get to be a guy like food
unless you've been a part of some shit.
You been a part of some shit. That's
a manly man. He's a scary dude now.
He doesn't give a fuck. You Imagine
Putin was mad at you for some shit.
How fucking tripping. That would
be. How terrifying that would be.
You have to go to the other
side of the world. Yeah,
you gotta you gotta move
to the Philippines, come
a kickboxer or something.
He kind of fuck you better run bitch.
You don't want to be hanging around
with that guy's mad at, you know, he,
he probably, I mean he got to where
he was just like straight bully power.
I don't know what he did,
but he scares the shit out of me.
I remember Matt Damon had a really
interesting interview where he was talking
about Sarah Pailin and a Matt Damon.
Damon is very astute,
politically, very, very well read guy too,
like surprisingly intelligent. You know,
you see him in movies,
you think he's always a really good actor,
but then you hear him
talk and you're like,
this guy's very bright and very well read.
And he had this great analogy about
Sarah Pailin being like a Disney movie.
And then all of the sudden this woman,
you know with her, her Moxie is going to,
you know, stand up to the evil Russians,
you know? And he was like, you know,
I need to, and he was
saying like, I need to know,
does she really think the earth is
less than 10,000 years old? I really,
I need to know this. I was
like, fuck yeah, yeah man. Yeah,
you do need to know.
We all need to know that
that changes some decisions
20,000 years ago. Nothing.
There's a lot of people that still
think that that's the new earth.
I D I mean we're talking
about millions of people.
I know there's a lot of people that you
might be tens of millions that believe
that
when do you start believing
that I wasn't her?
Like does it change your
decision making on everything?
Yeah. Yeah. There's so god
it up. It's just such a,
it's such an extreme like belief to,
to be that God it up. It's one thing
to have an idea that, you know,
there's some sort of feels like there's
a forest to controls the universe.
Maybe there's a gold were all attending
to, maybe there's, maybe there's a, uh,
a next wave of understanding after this
is over and just like a psychedelic
experience. It'll all make sense.
Maybe. Maybe, maybe, maybe, but,
but your idea is crazy.
Your idea about a fucking
dude in the cloud and,
and he died and he came back from the dead
and what the fuck are you saying, man?
Have you seen the,
the creation museum out here and uh,
and in Pomona? No, I did not know
it was, there was one in Pomona.
I was going to go to the one that's on
the other side of the country. Yeah,
like Kentucky. Yes. It's
supposed to be amazing, dude.
There's one out here. It's not as good
as the one over there, but it's like,
it's pretty decent size. You gotta write
this down. It's there for a decent sized,
and it's like a,
it's like Jesus riding dinosaur.
Oh No. It does not have Jesus.
Right. Jesus riding a dinosaur,
like a whole sculpture. It's
like Jesus Riding, uh, you know,
a raptor and it's in Pomona.
Yeah. It's like, it's like Audis here.
I think it's been promoted. Right.
How many people are going to see
that? Like as a goof? Is it most,
you know, when I was there, it
did not seem like I was like,
me and a couple people were there as a
goof and then it seemed like everybody
else was like, Kinda into it and it
was like, they were like, ah, you know,
it was like a nonprofit organization just
about like Jesus riding dinosaurs and
shit. It was weird. It was a four
year. Wow. That's so crazy, man. Yeah,
it was people who were into it, man, they
were like, fuck yeah. Jesus rode that
Jesus rode dinosaurs.
How dare you.
Yeah, I liked it. They were like, because
at first before there was dinosaur bones,
they were just like, you know, no pro
labor, like Jesus lives, blah, blah, blah.
Then the dinosaur bones came and they
needed to come up with an answer,
so I liked that they went with like,
yeah,
Jesus just like wrote them so I
would have gone with something else,
like maybe Jesus was scared of him,
kept him over in a pan or something.
Then the whole young earth
theory so spooky. It's, it just,
it's so weird that you can get people
to believe something like that.
It's so weird that no matter how many
scientists who have these elaborate
descriptions of how the earth cooled over
billions of and matter changed and the
atmosphere changed and different forms
of life and there were mass extinctions
and here's the fossil
record. No, not buying it.
No Horse Shit,
bad science.
I have a book written by people who swear
that the world is flat and the sun is
17 miles away.
I'm going to let that one influenced me.
I think it all stems from just
people being freaked out about dying.
Oh yeah. For sure. That's a
big part of it, man. It's,
you need something, you know,
look, I have a four year old daughter
who's just started to ask questions like,
what happens when you die? You
know, and that's what they,
they start thinking and it's a scary
idea for a little kid and it's, you know,
the idea of a heaven and God is a
very comforting one for, for people.
It's almost like,
even if it doesn't exist,
it's a very useful tool
because it actually does
provide people with a feeling
of relief, you know,
if you can, it's like,
it's almost like if you can
suspend disbelief for a movie,
you could suspend the little pudge,
Jesus,
and just kind of go along with it and
it'll provide you with like a framework
where you can, you know,
you can make sense of life.
It'll carry you to whatever
the fuck it is when it ends.
So what are you, what do you tell her
that it's a very interesting conversation.
Um,
I,
I tell her that no one knows what
happens when we die and that some people
believe that you go to heaven.
And then we discussed what would
heaven B and then I said, you know,
no one really knows what happens but
people hope that you go somewhere and
everything is beautiful and perfect.
So my wife has explained this,
that there, and as, as she becomes more
and more frantic about who's going to die,
it becomes more and more ridiculous.
Why keep not having you get whatever
you want. Yeah. TV You can watch.
It starts off as like a rational sort
of conversation and then I realized,
what am I doing?
She's for like,
this is like a fucking serious concept
to try to digest for four year old.
And I'm like, let's go over the
potentials for what happened would be,
that seems like a better way.
Direction. It just said she
become a star and then like,
you know when you're 13 just go, hey,
you know that star Shit. You're not,
you gotta wait til they're 13 and by
then she'll be pregnant. Brian. Okay.
You gotta talk to them before
they're 30 Brian's like till like,
it's like having a plan.
You just water it when it's young and
then leave it in the sun for a while and
13 he can't tell a 13 year old.
That's fucking crazy shit that I told
you it wasn't real. There's no answer.
There's no answer.
So just say it's a star and
let her believe that and
they shall become a hippie.
That's funny. My Dad, I remember
my dad when I asked him that,
my dad said I was just a
little kid and he was like, ah,
it's just darkness
forever.
Whoa.
Yeah. And I was like, whoa.
That's what my mom told me.
I was like traumatized by it.
And I went to,
and I remember going into my
mom's room and being like,
do dads just statute said and it was dark.
Right? And she's like, he doesn't know.
And she's like, Sam coming in here and
tell me it doesn't, you don't know.
Nobody knows. He's like, I know that's
what it is. It's darkness forever.
And then you have the role
play.
That's hilarious. Yeah.
I think my mom said,
you just go to sleep
and you just don't wake
go. My stepfather told me
probably nothing. So you probably,
you know,
he was the one when I was seven years old,
when I started asking these questions,
I was really religious until my
parents got divorced. And uh,
I went to Catholic school for a
year and Catholics code is wrong.
The religion out of me, I had
no, I was like, this is crazy.
Total 100% horse shit. And then, um, uh,
uh, a year later we had the
conversation like, what? Well,
if that's not real, if this Jesus Moses
Shit is something somebody made up,
then what happens when you die? And he
was like, oh, it's probably nothing.
Probably just sentence,
dude.
I can't remember crying that hard
when I was like a little kid,
you know,
just lying in my bed.
Ooh.
Just the terrifying notion that somehow,
and none of this was going to end and they
would just stomp. Yeah. It's so weird.
The same with me. I was like, I would
get like panic attacks thinking about it.
I'd just be like, what do
you mean forever? Yeah.
What the fuck is forever in the darkness?
I know. What the fuck does that mean?
It's weird that everybody
loves going asleep.
You know people love going to sleep
because you know you get to wake up,
you know,
so you're willing to like stop for a
while cause you know you'll come back but
nobody wants to die. Not
that. My buddies, my buddies,
a paramedic and he told me that he had
this call the other day and it's like 95
year old dude who was like riddled with
cancer hat instead of having a do not
resuscitate. He was, it was like full,
it was like bring me back full code.
Like anything that happens pretty man.
I'm like dude that bummed me out so much.
Cause I'm like,
if a 95 year old dude who's like
riddled with cancer isn't ready to die,
like I want to be so fucking freaked
out at all. The bad guy's like, Nah,
I don't want to go. Some people
are afraid of everything, you know.
But death is something that
everybody's afraid of them.
And if you're not,
it's probably life is miserable for you
to the point where death is favorable.
Yeah, he must be sick. Something's
wrong. There's an imbalance,
whether it's a behavioral and bounce or
a societal and balance, whether you know,
somebody did you wrong to the point
where you, it broke your brain.
I don't know what the fuck it is,
but if you really want to end it
for yourself and that's it, it's a
terrible place to be
than that and that like,
like I'm not really afraid to die like I,
because I have Jesus in
my heart and all that.
No, but I mean, no, I'm not. I'm not.
I think that it's because of mushrooms.
I've had so many where I thought I was
dying and I, I was like, you know what?
This is, this has been good
and blah, blah, blah. And
I'm like, oh wait, I die. Oh
yeah.
It would be awesome if there was
something that you could believe so
wholeheartedly that it calmed
you down and you're like, well,
I'm not worried about it. If it ends,
we're fine. We just go to this. Just like,
you're not worried about going to sleep,
you're not worried we're going to go on
asleep cause you know you're gonna wake
up. I know where I'm never worried
about going to sleep. I'm like,
Oh let me go to sleep problem. It's
great. I wake up beautiful. If,
if we had the information that we have
about coming back like we have about
sleep, you know, maybe it's just
then people saw the things you think.
So I think if people knew like once you
died it was like fucking shaking an acid,
etch a sketch.
People would do really fucked out things.
I would hope not.
I would hope the opposite.
I would hope if they,
if that first of all would freak people
out just to know that you definitely
would come back. That would just be such
a trip. It'd be so scared to try again.
Yeah,
that's true.
And also like what if you came back
and they fucking terrible situation.
What if you were like a spoiled Twat?
You know, living on long island,
it's just balling out of control in
a mansion and then you come back in.
You're in new Uganda. Yeah. You're in the
jungle and you're gonna. You have aids.
You have a big bloated belly
like that could be you too.
You got just some crazy lucky role.
The DNA dice that you're here in
America in 2012 just that alone.
You want to try this again? You
get a, you're going to play fair.
You're going to take any
spot all over the globe.
Like what do you come back [inaudible]
come back as you are you doing?
You are on the same trip every time
trying to get it right. Is that it?
Yeah. Like if we're going odds, you're
like in some fucking tiny town in China.
It's like drinking water, drinking
water from like no puddles. Yeah.
Warm Brown puddles of
water that people step in.
That's where you're getting
your water. Fuck man. Yeah.
There's a lot of spots on
the earth that are just shit.
Roll the dice to be there,
man. Big Time. We're lucky.
Southern California. So lucky. It's
delusional. It's good. I could live.
Weather here is so incredible all the
time that no one ever has to deal with
nature. There's no storms to
stay indoors from, you know,
this snow shoveling of the streets,
you know, getting the snow out or
no,
just a giant astronauts asteroid of a,
an earthquake that's coming towards
that we all know is going to happen.
They're going to die. Well, I mean, like,
we know that there's a ticking time bomb.
I, it could make a big deal because I
grew up in San Diego and you don't give a
fuck about anything when you grow up in
like, the weather's perfect and like,
yeah, you get an earthquake every now and
then, but like a little bit of shaking.
I like every two years.
Look at Japan.
Just look at the recent tragedies
lately that just destroyed. I mean,
Tokyo is pretty much gone like that,
that I don't know if they
would ever recover. They, they,
that country as a whole is pretty much
fucked and they don't want to talk about
it, but it's pretty
much these gone, right?
Um,
I don't eat mean
economically. The Fukushima
areas. Fuck yeah. The,
the area where the meltdown happened,
right.
They're already seeing mutated animals.
Shit.
Bonnie's born with no arms or ears or
weird shit is going on at red and going
just going to San Diego.
You go by that naked gun,
huge tit reactor and he just like look
around there and like, oh shit. You know,
it just takes one earthquake
and that shit's fucked. Yeah.
Didn't you think about that
when you went by? Absolutely.
Holy thought about that as we went by it.
I was doing by it.
I looked at that thing.
I'm like,
what a nutty place to put
this right next to the ocean.
You fucking crazy insulin assholes.
And you know why they put it right
next to the ocean. Shit goes wrong.
They can flood it with ocean water to
cool it off and and awesome and that water
goes right back in the ocean. Yeah.
That's what they did in Japan.
They fucking poured millions of
gallons of ocean water on the,
the actual inferno of hell and then they
pour that water right back in the ocean.
It's unbelievably toxic.
I mean,
it's fucking going to jack
everything and they're like,
it's too what we gotta do. We gotta
do we gotta do it? Tough Shit.
So everything gets checked on it there
that you need millions of gallons that,
oh, she's a son, they made a son.
He'll be fine. It's a little baby son.
I mean, and do you know what nuclear power
is? Did you know that it's just steam.
They just did the nuclear heat,
you know that melts water,
make steam and that powers all these
reactors. That's what that's like the,
that's that's the mechanism behind it.
Producing electricity.
No idea about any of that.
I have no idea either.
I just figured it was somehow or another
they take that nuclear energy and they
put it on a wire and it goes
to in your hairdryer? No,
it's like it's the same sort of idea.
You know the force behind it.
I think in the steam behind it is what,
what powers the generators.
But it's essentially, it's a nuclear
reaction that they can't ever cool off.
You can't like can't shut it off.
Stupidest idea every if,
if the fucking thing meant meltdown,
you're done.
You just have to get away from it. You
can't cool it off. It does. That's like,
that's so nuts.
Like I,
we can have wind power where we have the
windmill spinning or we can have this
fucking thing that's impossible.
The cool this son that if it'd be,
apparently they had a backup plan up
to like a certain amount of, you know,
earthquake and this far exceeded that.
This was like a really ridiculously
powerful earthquake and they lost their
backup generator and so they
knew they had like eight hours.
We've got eight hours to get the
fuck outta here. He can't fix it.
Like what are you talking about?
How arrogant are human beings that they
would make something where that could
even possibly ever happen and not
have any way you would say, okay,
before we build it, do you guys really
know how to shut this off? Is there, okay.
And what happens if that happens and what
happens to the power doesn't come back
on then what happens? Oh, then, oh,
then it just eats through the earth.
We don't know when it stops,
it goes through the core and it just
keeps going and probably comes out of the
other side or something.
The fuck they don't know.
It's never happened before that and
they went, okay, we'll build it.
We'll say sounds good. Crazy.
Sounds good. Go build that.
How many guys want to build?
You want to be like a few hundred of them?
Just leave them around. Yeah, let's
put them near fault lines and shit.
So let's add some earthquakes to la.
Let's add some earthquakes to all this
fucking people that we have here that's
added to the nuclear shit.
That's attitude.
The fact that we don't have
any water as less handling.
We don't have any elect our
electricity. He's fucking gone, dude.
We live in the dumbest place in the whole
entire roof. No, Vegas is the dumbest.
This is the second. Second Dennis. Well at
least Vegas. I did a Fresno. Fresno fuck.
It sucks. Yeah man. I've seen some spots.
It's suck a lot worse than Pasadena.
Yeah,
well it's tricky, that's for sure.
We're, we're certainly susceptible.
And the more they find
out, like, you know,
the archeologists are constantly
uncovering these lost cities now.
Like they've found a few of them off
the coast of Spain and one of them they
think might be Atlantis and they
found one recently that was like,
it was underwater as
recently as 8,500 years ago.
So this is like crazy old stuff,
you know, and it's, you know,
old pottery and it's old,
different fucking we're finding out that
like shit happens and goes wrong all
the time on this planet.
You know,
it's always getting hit by rocks from
outer space and there's fucking volcanoes.
The blow up every now and again and the
earth moves and giant thousand foot high
tsunamis wipe out miles
in and then pull back.
And that shit happens all the time
in history. You know, we just,
for whatever reason,
are willing to gamble that it's not gonna
it's not gonna happen on my watch. No.
I mean basically that's what it is. Cause
it's eventually going to happen. Yeah.
I mean it's an avoidable d we,
you know,
we've harped on it too
many times probably by now,
but the just the asteroid number alone,
when they find out how many hundreds
of thousands of asteroids are hovering
around inside of our solar
system and you're like,
what the fuck are you talking
about? It's not like, oh,
I heard there's like a hundred asteroids.
No,
there's like thousands of thousands and
thousands of these fucking things just
flying around and one of them could
just call her Ghrelin towards us.
We've been hit before many times and
most likely that's responsible for the,
a bunch of different weird shit where
they finally these ancient civilizations
and they don't understand how
they were sophisticated back then.
It's by we've stacked up some progress
and been knocked down a few times.
The very date of,
Oh,
I think it's like they're like
a 12,500 years ago or something.
Right now scientists are a growth is a
bunch of people over the country or over
the world rather that are agreeing that
there was some sort of an impact that
happened then because they're
doing all their core samples,
they find some sort of a glass that's
only created in like nuclear blasts or
extreme impacts or you know,
things along those lines like tongue
goose got like that kind of shit has to
happen.
Like some crazy impact and they're finding
a lot of this shit at 12,500 years.
So they think it's really possible that
we had like a massive meteor shower
12,500 years ago. It might
have fucked up, you know,
50% of the cities of the world,
you know,
but back then think about
12,500 years ago and didn't know
how, how does that
information get to us if you,
if every half the city's did get
jacked by these giant rock from space,
who, how many people would remember
that story? What would that story be?
By the time they figured out how
to make paper again. You know,
I got to feel like if you were alive
for that, you got to remember that.
It's like, yeah, you remember the one
time we got hit with it? Yeah, I remember.
I remember that.
What do you think they,
the people that survived even
knew what the fuck happened.
Cause maybe it was just like dumb luck.
You know,
like they probably a bunch
of asteroids came down,
a meteor shower just fucked up.
Boom, boom, boom. Like maybe,
maybe some places like
it just didn't hit them.
And so those are the ones that survive.
Then they had to go and look
at the rest of the world.
That would be equally freaky to know
that it could happen to you any day.
Do you get, if you lived in a
place where you didn't get hit,
but you heard all these crazy noises in
the background, but you and your tribe,
you guys are fucking cool,
no problems whatsoever.
And then you venture forth and it's
like Lord of the rings everywhere.
You look as burnt out and
smoking and like what the fuck?
Everyone's dead.
Everywhere you go is just bodies.
Just pieces of hands and
feet and fucking heads.
Cause everybody got hit with giant rocks
from the sky and pulverized into but
just she would groups of people smashed
on the highway with big rocks. Boom.
That would be almost freakier than dying
to know that disk just happened a few
hundred miles from you and you,
you know,
you get on your horse and find
it and you see how nutty it is.
You see how none of the damages and know
that that could happen at the sky can
just all of a sudden be
just a swarm of fiery rocks.
Yes.
Especially like before science or any,
anything to explain anything or God, I
feel like everything people saw back then,
they were like, what the fuck
is this? You Imagine? I mean,
how weird is it that w when
did we become so, so conscious?
Like when did we become so aware of all
the possibilities in our environment?
I mean it was a slow, gradual process
where the human brain evolved, right?
It's not like we were always
this smart right from the get go.
Somewhere along the
line it must have been,
I mean that's probably what
religion is really all about.
It's probably like some sort of
psychic training wheels, you know,
it's like you're not quite
ready to grasp the polled.
None of us are.
So it's like let's give you an ideology
to believe in that puts you on the right
track.
Cause you know this,
this feeling of God and love
and everything that it's
totally the right way to
do it. It's totally the right way to live.
So how, how do you need to get there?
Do you need to get there through yoga?
Well then you go yoga,
you go yoga and find that spot. Could is
the baby Jesus more you're liking? Yeah,
like singing. I'm really good with groups.
Okay, go that way. He just, you know,
it's like the psychic training wheels.
As we get through this, this weird spot,
get through this weird spot,
we start to awaken and see how fucking
crazy this world is and realize sometimes
the sky becomes of a light with
flying rocks that are on fire.
Fuck.
It's like
nobody's going to stop that man.
If,
if all of a sudden we got caught
a meteor shower, that's, well,
that's just what it is.
Yeah. Well, yeah. Imagine you're there
and you see the flying rocks flying.
First thing you'd be after you run
for your life, then you're like,
well obviously somebody threw that at me.
That's gigantic.
Freshly back bends. Yeah.
That's how he back then. Oh,
we're being attacked by God's
Haiti's cause I'm Braga, you know,
like you throw your a caveman or whatever
you throw shit, throw rocks is under.
If that was like where the
origins of of Haiti's [inaudible]
hell fire and all that shit came from,
I wonder if that was that, you know,
you've gotta wonder like when, when did
they first figure out the idea of hell?
Was it when they first saw
volcano? It makes sense. Yeah.
If you for, if you were fucking
capers and you show a volcano,
hell totally makes sense. You're
like, you do not want to go there.
You will fucking burn forever.
I mean, it looks like, yeah,
you would burn forever if you could exist
and somehow or another not disappear
instantly into the lava and just have
that feeling of being burned by lava
forever. Probably the most terrifying
thing a person could ever experience.
Well, definitely. Imagine you
don't know it's 10,000 years ago.
You don't know anything about science.
You see a volcano erupt and then
some shit comes out of it that's just
disintegrates everything in
its path. You're like, yeah,
that's probably the bad place.
Mark W,
well, most people don't realize
is the Yellowstone volcano.
This is one of the biggest volcanoes in
the earth. It's a, it's a super volcano.
Yellowstone is something
called a Caldera volcano,
and they didn't even discover this
until I think like a decade ago.
I think when they started using
satellites to map things out,
they realize that it's a
crater and that Yellowstone,
I think it's like 300 kilometers wide or
something crazy like that might be 600
kilometer. That'd be 300 miles. Yes. Not
only is it active, it's a super volcano,
which means it gets up to a
peak and then the peak explodes.
The whole thing explodes and just
leaves behind a whole team. Yeah,
it kills like a giant percentage of
everything in the continent because it's
such a huge volcano.
I mean it like,
it becomes like almost like a
nuclear winter type situation.
I think it fills the sky with
ash. I mean, I think it's,
it's such a massive volcano
that you really could call
it a continent killer and
it happens every six to 800,000 years
and the last time it happened was 600,000
years ago.
Yeah.
So if that did happen and there's not
a goddamn thing we can do to stop it.
If Yellowstone decided to blow and it
went called dare on us and fucking erupted
on us. That's a wrap for
black. Most of the west coast,
a huge chunk of the country.
I mean is, it's done, dude.
It's a fucking horror movie.
It's the road.
It's that movie Viggo Mortensen
it's that shit. It's that shit.
That's the only time it's okay
to say you would fuck Obama. Yes.
Then you can get away with anything,
then you can get away with anything.
And Don might have happened in a let,
to a lesser extent to our ancestors.
It's very possible that might have
happened. That might be with, you know,
when they find all these crazy
structures and shit under the ocean,
that might be what happened
is people might've got jack.
Yeah. You gotta imagine.
Yeah.
Because it's also like, you
know, if that should happen,
like seems like crazy shit
happens every like 50,000 years.
Like it's got to happen.
Like you said, we've,
we've probably gone farther in technology
then, you know, two steps forward.
One step back.
Yeah.
Yeah. I agree. Yeah. You know, except
for when you look at, uh, uh, buildings,
you know, some of the crazy
Egyptian buildings and shit. Like,
how the fuck did they do that?
You know,
if there really was an ancient
civilization and figured
out how to do that, like,
well, they, they might've been ahead
of us, you know, I dunno. I mean,
that seems like in a lot of
ways it seems ahead of us.
The construction methods that
the giant stones they moved like,
but it's pretty clear that
everybody gets nailed, you know,
it's just no way you can avoid it.
The little things like, you know, the,
the tsunami that killed everyone and
Thailand, you know, that was t to us,
it was a huge deal.
You know,
to us humans think about the
numbers in the body counts,
but to the world population, it's
nothing, it's nothing, it's nothing.
It's,
it's weird how many different things
like that could happen in mass scale,
like frightening scale thousand mile,
you know,
fucking, uh, I think it's 45,000
mile an hour. Asteroids. That's,
that's like what the speed that most
of them are travel that, you know.
And there could be a mile wide,
five miles wide.
It's like,
it's crazy thing too.
Like even if you look at like
the plague as reading this,
I was reading something,
it's like it killed three
fifths of the people in Europe.
Like what if that happened now? Nice.
Like people would go, but like Thailand,
you know we go bananas at the Thailand
thing. It's such a small percentage.
Like three out of five people in Europe.
Every three out of five people die.
Well what,
what happened was it was the plague.
Something that was transmitted by rodents.
Yeah.
Cause the fleas carried all of the plague
and then the rodents would get on the
boats.
They'd run a clock across the ropes that
get to the shore and then the fleets
would come out and bite people.
Oh Jesus Christ. Get everybody.
Then they end up at Applebee's.
Fucking
Gary is the plague. Did you
know that a guy in um, uh,
where the fuck was it that he got tested?
A guy got bitten by an animal
and he got tested for the play.
I think it was a cat
and he tested positive for the plague.
It was like it was in the
Pacific northwest. Okay.
I want to say cause that there's been
a couple cases of the plague like in
California.
Yeah.
Fuck. You know that's like
some old school pirate shit.
You hear the plague? Yeah. Yeah.
It's connected to boats, right?
Like what the fuck man,
the plague really
must've sucked.
Fat Dick live in Baghdad for he fits
to the people die from the plague.
Everybody's like stinky all the time.
Time. Yeah. A lot of rape going on.
Probably tons and probably people are
assholes who just dying and when people
died easier and quicker, they were
probably like way more conti. Right.
They didn't last that long.
They just fucking got all their content
and they probably were much more likely
to commit violence on each other.
They are probably much closer to animals.
Oh yeah.
How far back do you think you can go and
still rocket seventies think you'd be
happy in the 70s yeah, that'd be
having this, that can be happy.
In the 70s I would miss my phone now Matt.
A lot.
I'd miss being able to call people and
we, it never made this interview, man.
I never spoke a word to you
until we walked in the door
and said, hey, what's up?
You know, it was all done through, you
know, texts and emails and all that jazz.
It's kind of fascinating that it couldn't
have happened in the 70s even just
like,
yeah.
Have you ever like tried to go pick
somebody up at the airport and forgot your
phone? Yeah. It's like you might as well
just turn around and go, oh yeah. Oh,
it's so weird what we accept.
It's so weird.
I could probably do the 60s but
no earlier sixties or interesting.
You get some cool cars.
You could,
you could be driving around
in a brand new 1964 Mustang.
Holy Shit. And it would be real. You know,
like this is a fucking
real brand new 64 Mustang.
You feel what it was like to have
one of those things back then.
That might be fun. That might be fine.
You would know so much more than them.
It would be stealing. You could be
able to fuck every chicken meat.
All you have to do is keep talking to him,
keep talking to him long enough.
They'd be like, he's a prophet
ahead. I have to go with him.
He has the answers that I seek.
You could totally start a call to be like,
Fuck Charlie Manson.
Charlie, sit the fuck down.
I'm gonna tell you some shit about the
future. This is what's going to happen.
There's going to be pills that you can
take and you'll be happy even if your
life is shit. That would be, I like that.
That's the first knowledge you drop on
them. That's the first thing he tell him.
Tell him you will one day be ruled
by pills to control your emotions
and then they can lock you in a cage
if you say the wrong words. Oh no
dude, I would buy into that
cold if I was in the 60s yeah,
the 60s would be an interesting time
to go back to with all the knowledge of
today would have the knowledge like
imagine if you knew like political shit.
Today's the day they killed Kennedy. Cause
you imagine how much you want to bet.
How much am I bet they kill Kennedy today.
You're just as bad as you.
Don't try to stop it. Stop it.
He does. He just go to Vegas.
You go can,
I bet they fucking killed the president.
You want to bet pitch and they'll,
they'll, they'll take your money. Vegas,
we'll take your money.
But then that's back sixties Vegas
where it's all gangsters and shit. Yeah,
they kill you for being
right. They're like, listen,
we know when Kennedy is going to die.
We're going to be a part of how stupid.
Fuck we're going to, we're going to make
the driver go really slow in Dallas.
Yeah they did.
That's different.
You don't want to be part of that
part of the 60s that would suck now.
Definitely they killed people back then.
They had problems with them like JFK,
RFK and they just sat and ate them.
Sneak up behind them in
front of a bunch of people.
That's the crazy shit like RFK was.
He was,
he was running for president who send
me just like walked up to him with a gun
and shot of, yeah, dude, I was at
the place where they did it. We, uh,
we filmed some fear factors there.
Oh really? Where is that? At?
Some hotel in downtown. I think
they're, they might be tearing it down.
I think bill burr was really upset
about it. Wait, that's here in la.
Bill Burr was really upset about
it. It was, and he's so right.
He's so dead on as always. But he was
like, ah. He goes, no one he has any,
any idea history, you know,
if that was back east,
you couldn't fucking tear that down and
put a fucking parking lot there. He goes,
no,
it'd be like it.
There'll be a plaque there so you could
know that this is where the shit went
down. It's so true. But in la
they were like, yeah, Robert
Kennedy was killed here,
or whatever. It's, this
is, it's a strip club now,
but now it's like, yeah, the downtown is
that, she said weird here. Your place.
Have you been a skid row yet? I
have, Whoa, her legs like first,
like one of my first weeks up here,
I was trying to go to a Laker game and
I and I made a wrong turn and all of a
sudden they was like
fucking 28 days later.
Like it's just like so packed with it was,
I've never seen just the
concentration of the sale.
You can't believe it unless you say
it. It's, it's really, it's true.
Can't believe unless you say
it's, it's, it's staggering. You.
You think we're exaggerating. You're
saying there's no way anybody would it,
they've become a tribe.
It's a tribe of homeless people and
there's maybe thousands of them.
So I saw something else.
I said, no, no, no.
I saw something and said there was
100,000 homeless people living in downtown
Jesus Christ. Jesus Christ.
You know. Crazy. That sounds,
that's like an arm 100. That's what I'm
talking about, man. Skid row is weird.
We filmed some fear factor stuff,
a lot of it in downtown La on buildings.
We do like things when people out across
buildings and shit like that. And, um,
we were always like right
around the corner and sometimes
we had to like do shit.
Like that was like right there in the
thick of things and so you would go around
the corner and like when you leave work,
if you went around the corner and took
a left and then took another left,
you're in a Zombie movie. You really
are like, you fucked up. You're,
you're on the wrong street and people
are asking you for money and they're
touching your car and you're like,
what is going on?
I didn't see any of that
in San Diego by the way.
And Sue's good.
And also the marijuana shit was so
much stricter. Yeah. He was like,
like even the body guards or
the bouncers of every club,
we're all ex military or something.
Like I said, they were like, Oh,
you smoke a bong, you better not be
smoke weed. Yeah, they gotta relax.
They got to relax on that. Every,
that it's good. It's, there's,
there's good and bad in military presence.
It'd be more good than bad if they let
them smoke weed soldiers who smoked.
We would be like the best soldiers
to have the bill like lesson.
Everything's going to work out. We're
going to, we obviously fucked up.
We're going to slowly back up. By
the way, we have a show tonight.
If you're listening to
this live right now,
there's still tickets available so you
can still get down here at the ice house.
It's a super show. Like
we always do these, um,
whoever's in town and we got
Ari Shaffir, Doug Benson, dom,
I rarer dove,
Dove David off Jesus fucking Christ.
If you've never seen dove, he's very,
very funny. He's fucking hilarious.
Very unique too. He's um, he's
like one of my favorite guys.
Watch and dom [inaudible] one of my all
time favorites. Course Tivo, Jayson,
t bell, Brian red bands going to go up and
do my favorite joke. We do my favorite,
which Joe,
you know the joke came and talk about it
cause I don't want anybody to know the
joke. That joke. Yeah,
yeah. That one. Yeah.
I have a new one that I'm in
love with and do that too.
But I got to hear that other joke.
That's, I love that joke. And a,
that'd be tonight if it's
15 bucks at the Ice House,
10 o'clock show and uh, and I have a,
I'm doing like half hour, 40 minutes,
something like that at the end. Who would
they not get drunk and I might go long.
Who are the comedians that
you like would pay to see now?
Like the ones your favorites? Ah, I paid
to see anybody. Good man. I love comedy.
I mean I don't have to pay
really, really. Cause I, you know,
most guys are going to like ask them
and they'll let me come into their show.
But I'd still love to go see comedy.
Like we just saw dice clay at the Riviera
and Vegas. I fucking loved it, man.
Me and Brian, we were like little
kids. We w how fun was that show? Oh,
it was great. So much fun. Exactly what
I wanted. Yeah, it was, we all were, uh,
were hanging out and um,
we were in Vegas for the UFC and
it was Friday night and I was free.
We didn't have anything to do.
And a opie and Anthony, you know,
you know those guys. You ever done a
show? Jimmy Norton and Anthony Kumiai,
we're in town and there, um, one of the
guys that works on show, Sam Roberts,
he was in town too.
And so we all went out to dinner together.
So while we're out at dinner we'd go,
let's go see dices show. So we text, dice,
dice, text back. We'd go
there and it was like,
like we were like little kids were like,
we get to go see a show.
Like I got to go see dice at the Riviera.
I was so happy.
Like I fucking love to
go see like a good show.
I didn't have to pay for
it cause dice hooked me up,
but I would be happy to pay to see
that. That was really fun. You know?
I mean when I was a first start now,
before it was successful,
it was really hard for me to go see too
many comedians because I would like,
I'd feel like like God,
I Suck and listen to that guy.
I don't even want to even want
to go on stage now and, and
then I would be like weirded
out by other people's acts.
Like I didn't want to watch people
do better than me, I didn't want.
But then once you get to a
certain little level of comfort,
you realize why he became a
comedian in the first place.
It's because you love watching stuff and
laughing at it and so then you get to
figure it out again and
then be a fan again. So me,
it was like the first 10
years of my comedy life,
it was like a cycle of like
slowly figuring out that
you just have to like enjoy
it,
like and just laugh at everything and it
don't just because you're a struggling
comedian don't not enjoy comedy
because comedy is like the best form of
entertainment. That's why you like it
in the first place. Right. You know,
don't not like it because you suck at it.
By the way, Joe, I don't know if you know
about this yet or, or, or not, but, uh,
Steve, uh, car leasing from OPA
and Anthony [inaudible] happen.
Uh, you know, I don't know. I got to, I
got an email today from Iraq. Uh, and uh,
but there, there's a memorial fund
for his family. I'm, here's a,
I remember last time I talked
to him. Oh yeah, yeah. Is the,
uh, the address I tweeted if you want to,
if you want to Twitter, Twitter it, uh,
but tell people that are listening to
this on their phone where they could find
it. Um, yeah, it is. Let's see. Well,
the addresses go fund me.com/v h zero EDW,
which makes no sense, but
if you go to my Twitter, uh,
it's red bin or go to Joe Rogan's Twitter
where I'm sure he's gonna tweet it,
right? Yeah. Okay. Yeah, I'm
going to retweet it right
here. When it says on, um,
on Brian's is,
I'm very sad about this.
Steve was a great guy and today's date is,
is what
is it?
The 18th.
So if you'd go to Brian's Twitter feed
on the 18th and fans of Opie and Anthony
know him, he was a really nice guy. He,
I remember he had a really cool tattoos
and he's a really cool guy. I the socks,
I don't know what happens. Terrible News.
Yeah. Yeah. I, uh, I saw Sam's email.
He sent me an email as well and uh, he
gave us a URL, I believe, didn't he?
Uh, yeah, that's the one
I just twittered okay,
but can he give it out to people?
I just didn't know what I just did it,
it makes no sense. It's like back slash
and all bunch of numbers and words.
So it's one of those, okay, well,
it's on my Twitter. I retweeted it.
It's on Brian's and we're
very sorry to hear that.
He was a great guy and
hopefully he's in heaven. Yeah.
Or darkness. Darkness. Like
your dad would say that's,
that's fucking disturbing. Heaven's better
having Sue's it better. That sucks man.
I hate hearing shit like
that. How old is he? Oh,
I don't think he was very old at all. I
don't even think it was 40 was he? No,
he was in English. I think it
was in the early days. Yeah.
That he lost a ton of weight,
right? Yeah, I think so. Yeah.
But that was a while ago.
But yeah,
but it looks like they've almost reached
their goal, so that's great. Um, they're,
they're trying to raise 30,000 so I have
so many openings for the fans. I guess.
That's good. Come through.
That's awesome. Thanks
everybody.
And thank you Brian for bringing,
that's frigging the show down
to screeching halt. It is a,
that is a bummer though,
man. So I, I have some,
an update of a past episode wherein I
smoked moth poop and a little bit of
orange fluorescent orange
stuff came out of it.
I found out that it was actually shit.
So like I didn't know for sure.
She didn't know if it was eggs or
styling something use. He smoked it.
This is the problem.
The kid did ecstasy two days ago and
he hasn't been the same sentence.
I don't know whether I should call us mom.
I'm thinking I need to call
his mom and say, Mrs Red Ban.
We got a situation here. Yeah, it's
show. Yeah, Brian's friend. Yeah.
He's um, it's just, uh, I don't,
I think, I think you fucked up.
I think he smoked too much. Mark.
Thank you. Went over the other side.
I don't know what,
I didn't tie his ankle and I don't know
if we're ever going to get them back.
Dude, I did ecstasy once and
I couldn't read the next day.
I can't believe you do it so often.
I don't do it often.
I do it every three months. Maybe
that's a lot months. It's for me.
That's terrifying. Oh, and I don't do x.
Do they do, do Molly, which is better.
Better wait about it.
Huh?
Okay. I have a bad, I had a great
experience and a bad experience,
a great experience, and it felt
really good, bad experiences.
The next day I was useless.
I was dried out. It's like,
I felt like I would literally
had been dried out like my brain,
like a sponge that was out in the sun.
That seems like that's the
worst part for me. It was.
I mean I think everybody's different
in how I have bad sleep apnea too.
So I think I'm always a
little bit depleted, you know,
when it comes to a shit like that. If
I, back then I wasn't on top of it.
I didn't know now where like
this mouthpiece that keeps me,
I have a big tongue and have fun.
No,
you don't need to know all this shit
about me, dude. Okay. My point was,
um,
maybe uh,
maybe that hindered me from coming back
as good cause I wasn't getting very good
sleep, but it was hard for
me to bounce back mentally.
I don't think I was the
same for several days.
The next day I remember feeling really,
really stupid,
like think and I went on stage and
try to remember my act, but it was,
it was not good. It was just a really
mediocre show. It wasn't a good show.
I remember for like three or four days
thinking this is a fucking terrible idea.
I learned so much about myself, but I was
like, I'm never doing this again. Fuck
yeah. I one time I went college, my
neighbors, uh, they used to sell weed,
coke and everything like that and I
played baseball in college and uh,
so I could never eat, couldn't
do any drag, sees you got
drug tested all the time.
And then uh,
I had this fucked up injury again,
I'm telling you too much information.
But anyway,
they gave me this shit to smoke cause I
wasn't getting drug tests anymore and I
didn't know,
but they had just like,
I guess they had sprinkled coke and
something else on it. Whoa. Yeah.
And I didn't know,
I just thought I was smoking weed and
so I smoked it and I was just like going
out of my fucking mind. Like I knew it
wasn't. We'd like 10 minutes into it,
I was like, my heart was beating
super fast and I was getting,
I was sweaty on just
one half of my face and
the other half was like, it's
perfectly dry. The other,
I was just like dripping sweat and
for the next two days I thought I was
retarded. Like I couldn't, I
couldn't think through thoughts.
Like it was freaking me out.
I've never done coke,
but the whole coke culture of getting
really high and then crashing through the
fucking bottom is so unappealing to me.
I don't understand.
It scares the shit out of me.
Yeah. No, that's why I like,
cause I like being kinda up.
So that's why I, same thing,
I've never done coke because I know
I'll do it and then I'll really like it.
And every, everybody, I, every time
I'm with somebody who, who does coke,
they're always just like
looking for more coke. Oh yeah.
Like you have to sit and enjoy it. I liked
it that much. I liked it for a month,
but after a while that, that feeling of
always looking for it. I, at least for me,
I was like, yeah, this sucks.
Why do I want to keep on doing something
that I want to keep on looking for?
And I keep on spinning like
$100 every couple hours. Yeah.
You're an interesting dude,
Brian.
And that a lot of people don't
realize like you go, oh, you know,
Brian doesn't have a, it doesn't have
a lot of willpower. You actually do.
You have a lot of willpower and you
lost an insane amount of weight really
quickly. You lost like
70 or 80 pounds. Right?
How many pounds did you lose?
I don't remember.
I think it was 75 pounds or 70 pounds.
And he did it over a really short
period of time, four months.
And it was really shocking to watch
him just shrink. And I was like,
what will you, when you put your mind to
shit, you can, you can get things done.
But most of the time you just decided
not to put your mind to think, oh,
I put my mind too much.
Too much.
Now what did you do to lose
all that weight so quick? Uh,
I just did white weight watchers,
but I did half the points at
like a hacked weight watchers.
I did half the points and, and then I,
I just did a lot of zero point things.
Like all vegetables.
I just ate vegetables nonstop to,
I couldn't eat any more vegetables.
Did you feel good worked out when
you were really light like that?
Did you feel good? Yeah. Um,
I don't remember if I felt the same
as I do now. I didn't feel any better.
I don't remember feeling going
like, oh, I feel great. No,
you were exercising a lot too
though, right? Why don't you, uh,
I was exercising five, four days a week,
five days a week. It's a lot for you.
Like how often you do it
now? Uh, once, let's see,
I've done it twice in the last six months.
That was great delivery,
man.
I walked a lot of comic con
he don't really be funny.
You should say that on stage.
That was funny. That was
really good delivery. Yeah,
but like somebody just asked me that
exact same question today and I was like,
you know what?
I walked probably a good five miles this
last week and that kind of comic con,
but I do a lot of that shit where I'm
like, oh no, I mean I do exercise,
move your body from one place to
another without equipment. Right.
I Walk to Starbucks, that's
what he gets. It is working out,
moving his body unassisted.
You will be the first amongst us to
give in to having one of those fucking,
those uh, those freeway things.
What are those things? Segues.
That's how you're going to get a ride.
I want to, I want to go on a segway.
That's what does guilty pleasures that
I haven't done yet. You know, like,
I just want to treat myself to a segway.
You never, you really never done one.
They're amazing. Pretty cool.
They're super cool. It's a gyroscope.
The only issue with those things is,
um, they, when they were shut off,
they would just shut off and people
would just fall on their ass and it's,
you know, you really get jacked
like old people like, you know,
fell and got fucked up. I hear the
new ones are just fucking bad. Yeah,
the new one's let you know. They like beep
and shit. They let you know it's dying.
Get off me bitch. I'm going
to die. I wonder what they
did. The guys created them.
He drove off a cliff on one. I think
the guy who really need it. Yes.
He fell off a cliff on
one. Yeah. Um, whoops.
What?
Fuck that man.
Imagine watching that happen in the
beginning of a Coen brothers movie.
The Guy, he's fucking zipping
her alarm on the Pacific highway,
waving the people hanging in and he looks
down at his phone and check his text
messages and write as he types l o l
to something that's not even remotely
fucking funny. Why the new ones
are fucking amazing. I'm hungry.
Lol. Boom. Off the cliff and
you watch him flip. Don't,
don't, don't, don't, don't tell dunk.
And the coyote's moving
to check these new models.
Start chewing them apart at night.
Yeah, they're dope as fuck duty.
Kevin James used one for that.
Paul Blart Mall cop movie.
And then once he use it for that,
he decided to bring them with
him when he does any movie.
Cause it's like the best way
to get around. I got on a
big satis specially so he,
he had a couple of those
on I shown me and him.
We used to go around the Boston
common with them. It was so fun.
How fast are those go?
Probably like as fast as you can run Max
speed 20 miles an hour or 12 miles an
hour. Know they, they have um, ones
I think that cops use that go faster.
I think I'm thinking of those. Yeah,
I've seen those ones. Cause what does,
what does a person have fast person run?
Like what do they worn?
Like 30 miles an hour or something like
close to like, like you saying bolt,
what does he do? He does like
close to 30 miles an hour, right?
Isn't that funny person who was a car?
They wouldn't be shit.
Weak ass fucking bitch. 30
miles an hour. Mr. Segway hard.
That's annoying. It's annoying when
you have to go 30 miles an hour. Yeah.
You're like,
I can see if you're on the highway
and you can only go 30 miles an hour,
you'd be like, oh, this is going to take
for it. Well that's you running full lip.
The fastest human in the hurling,
his body against gravity.
That's a,
anytime people are like, oh, this guy is
such an amazing athlete. I'm like, I can,
I just saw a fucking bear run like 35 40.
And he's like a fat slow bear,
big giant ass fucking animal.
You see what those things look
like when they lose their hair? Oh,
you look amazing. It's their hair.
Yeah. There's a bear that has uh, some,
some form of Maine's probably and uh,
there's pictures of it like with no hair.
It looks like some creature in like,
like a never ending story or something.
It doesn't look real.
It like a hobbit type picture say
is if you can find that it looks,
it looks like dark crystal actually. Yeah.
Look at that. Oh my God. Come on, man.
How strange is that? That's horrible.
I had a dog that had mains like that.
Not that bad, but giant patches
of her body. When I found her,
I rescued her giant patches
of her body would like that.
That's apparently where the Chupa copper,
they think the myth comes from too.
It was coyotes. They get that
age. Coyotes would have mains.
They lose all their hair and they look
for Riki. They look really fucking creepy.
Have you see if you can find one of
those coyotes with no hair man. Ooh,
what does that, he's got to pick
pink shirt on. Ms Paint for us
a frosh. How was that
still in use? No wait,
what was it called again? Where are we
talking about coyote with main change?
Eh, you know the, the, the images,
one of them was on I think one of
those like monster quest type shows.
They were trying to say like,
someone thought they had a
Chupa copper, right? Yeah.
And that's what it turned out to be.
Turned out to be a coyote.
That it had the mange or they lose all
the hair on their body and they just look
really freaky cause it chipped. It has
no hair to have you seen that? Yeah.
That's one of them, man. Huh? What are
you doing? Are you going the other way?
It's um, there's a chip that has no hair
to that one is really frightening. Yeah.
Pull that up.
The chimp with no hair is crazy because
you really start to think like how
terrifying it would be if this thing was
trying to bite your dick off. Like wait.
It probably would do if it got
alone with you. You're actually,
it looks like a girl at like an
gross grown bar. Yeah. Look at that.
That's horrible late.
Do you see the full image?
His body is enormous to his
muscles are fucking huge.
Pull that one up right there. Look
at that. Click on that. Gee, he's us.
Look at the size of his fucking muscles,
dude. That's like, yeah.
And that's a chimpanzee.
These muscles are way stronger than yours.
So that, that creepy looking
beast has probably, you know,
strength of a 500 600 pound man.
Maybe even more if he was like a
ripped 500, 600 pound that. Yeah,
like a superhuman. I mean there,
there's so much stronger than us.
They think he can hurl
his body through the air,
grab ahold of things with one arm
and slinging his body to their side.
Do you ever seen one of those guys get
angry in a cage and hurl themselves
around?
Dude, I, I uh, I live right by the
zoo in San Diego. May go all the time.
I got a pass.
Oh, that a wild animal
park. That's awesome. Zoo.
And uh,
one time I was at the monkey cage and
this guy was just like banging on the
glass trying to get the monkeys
to pay attention to him. Stupid.
And the monkey
came up like it was, I was
like, I don't know what it was.
It was like a Bonobo or
something like that and it just,
it just fucking rock the glass
once and put a crack in it.
And then like all of a sudden, like all
of the fucking, you know, zookeeper,
people came in and ship it.
Like it was just,
it looked like a monkey that looked like
a hundred pound monkey and it was so
fucking strong that it put a crack in
this class. Yeah, it was a chimp. Oh Wow.
Cause we shouldn't really say monkey
chimp that people get angry. It's racist.
They get angry with me is
incorrect for apes, monkeys,
hotels is, that's what that's I
call called monkeys to the chimp.
Then this was a chimp.
Chimps are super fucking strong and a
hundred pound champ could fuck you up.
Oh yeah. Fuck you up man. And imagine
like those gorillas, that's just like go.
That's one of the greatest movie scenes
in any movie ever was when the gorilla
comes out and starts running shit on
that planet of the apes movie. We're all,
the champs were thinking they were bad.
I asked,
are we going to have a little battles
to see who's the most fucking Badass and
the smart Shims, like I'm just going
to make friends with this gorilla.
That was an odd that I was surprised
how much I liked that movie and love
gorillas, man. When gorillas go crazy,
I love it. It's primal, you know?
As long as I'm not there,
so it's not actually terrifying.
I'm totally rooting for that gorilla.
The gorilla comes down,
just just goes crazy and all
the chips are like, oh shit.
It's kind of funny when you think
about it, man. He's fearless animals.
He's fucking super animals that are
going to take over downtown Manhattan.
They're still terrified of that gorilla.
I would love to see it's,
I know it's impossible.
I would love to see how much a
huge gorilla could bench press.
I bet they could throw
around some insane numbers.
If you look at their body structure,
it's so ridiculous. Like a big one,
like a big mountain gorilla.
What do they wait like 600 pounds
or something like that? 800 pounds.
He imagined how fucking
strong that thing was.
Being there is so strong that they don't
even have to climb in the trees to hide
from the cats and shit like that.
Cancer aren't going to fuck with gorillas.
That is too much work, man. You know,
you get in a tussle with a gorilla,
you might not win those. They have
fangs too. Yeah, it's the offense to it.
Really fixed skin and they are
so much bigger than you. Man,
this is so big and so strong.
It's so crazy.
It's weird. They have little decks. Super.
We humans are the primates
with the largest penises
and it's all related to how
many sexual partners are our females
are likely to encounter. Really? Yeah.
The gorilla kingdom is a patriarchal
set up where he's got a Harem and those
girls are all monogamous.
There's no sexual competition between
him and other rails. He has his own,
he's had his Harem, so he has a little
Dick. He doesn't have to have big Dick.
Where's chips have big dicks? Those chimp
bitches are freaks and they freak on,
you know,
and then with human beings they
found that the more promiscuous,
and this actually the animal kingdom
as well,
the more promiscuous the females are,
the larger the testicles are of the males.
You know,
it was even theorize that their specific
sperm that go after and kill other
sperm,
that's their only job duty is to go
after and attack the sperm of an but it
turns out that that was just
kinda of crazy speculation,
or at least it's a mostly agreed by
smart folks in the know about the subject
that that's probably bullshit
or most likely bullshit,
but fascinating nonetheless
to think that your balls grow,
which is fact that you develop more
sperm when you're around horse.
That's real,
man.
That means that since I
went to San Diego state,
I should have gigantic fucking really
was San Diego state filled with with
slutty girls. San Diego
state is like, yeah.
It's like if you're too dumb to get
into like a good school. Oh really? No.
You still wanted to party and fuck
a bunch of people you were in.
You were a girl.
Sounds like a movie.
How can we pitch it?
You write it and I know a dude who knows.
What's that dude's name? Justin
Timberlake. We could do it, man.
We can make this happen.
Dude. One time I was at
the, I was at the zoo,
it's been at the sperm thing and this
monkey was in the corner just jacking off
in the corner of the zoo,
but,
and all the other monkeys were
in a circle talking and uh,
and so he jerks off and he
finishes into his hand, no way.
Finished it into his hand,
but just standing there,
he's not doing anything yet.
And then he walks over to the group
monkeys that's talking and he smears it on
this one monkey's face and then he runs
away. Right. And so I'm like, oh my God,
I saw it. So she doesn't freak
out or like go crazy or get upset.
She just like calmly
wipes or face smells it,
and then licks it.
And then she walks over to him and
puts her ass up and they start fucking,
whoa.
Yeah.
So the way he got her to fuck him
wants to come on her face real quick.
Oh my God. That is, to me, black cats,
those big black cats are the
scariest fucking thing I can say.
Even for whatever reason,
more scary than tigers because tigers
you like almost feel like he could never
fight back. Right. And if you've got
to talk about a Jaguar, it's like man,
maybe might be able to live
cause they're not that big.
Well there there'll be 200
pounds fucking but account.
Look at the muscles on that thing. I mean,
come on man. If that thing, one of the,
fuck you, is that a Jaguar? Fucking a
cheetah? No, no, no, no. They're, they're,
they're both leopards and
the leopards are black too.
Like the uh, like what the black
ones, what they are is like,
he actually has spots on them. They're
just, most of his body is a spot I've had.
They vary a little bit. I, whenever
it sounds like a car alarm, right?
They look so bad ass. It's such a
freaky co creation. By, by nature,
I mean look, look at the, just
the physical form of this thing.
Just designed only to kill,
should really strong,
really fast and wants to attack
things that move in front of it.
Like a ball of yarn. It's got such
a kill driving. He rolled a ball
in front of it.
It jumps on a ball.
She's written back getting the Dick and
to the, she helped him. Yeah. She's,
she's gay marines around reaching down
right now, trying to get it in. Oh really?
Yeah, she is. Yeah. And uh, he'll get him.
He's trying to get this wrong whole
pitch. Let me try it again. I got to have,
let me help. All right. Got To get back.
Look at the size of his fucking
arms. Jesus Christ, man. Oh,
here we go. He figured out the lounge
position that's got a lounge style.
He's like sitting back and he's got
his hand on her shoulders like, bitch,
you ain't going nowhere. Just let
me hold on. You're right here.
The size of his fucking body.
He shot off.
Oh, and she's just checking in.
She knows how to properly do it.
You hold it in there and get,
make sure all the come gets in your
vagina's pregnant as what she's doing,
isn't she? She's keeping the common, the
vagina. That's what they do. A on some,
some sides of this in Los Angeles,
the size of her bones,
like when she puts her hands up,
look at the size of the bones in the hand.
That thing would fuck you up.
Oh my God, it would fuck you
up. Look at the size of that.
It's crazy that they only eat
like vegetables too, Huh? Yeah.
Gorillas are insanely aggressive.
Sanely strong and they eat like Broccoli
or where are they getting their protein
rubbed? Get those big ass muscles.
Well I'm believe it or not,
most vegetables have very
high levels of protein,
especially leafy green vegetables.
We just think of protein is only being
associated with animals eating steak or
so, but there's a lot of protein and
Kale. Kale is a massive amount of protein,
so does Broccoli. If you eat like mad
quantities of that stuff, you can get all,
almost everything that you can get from
meat except like the weird shit like
aggression, you know, get the, the,
there's something aggressive
you get out of eating meat.
I think there's something,
I really do firmly believe that there's
some something that happens when your
body processes the fact that it's eating
animal protein that makes you more
aggressive.
I really do believe it does.
Is there any part of you,
Joe, that if at the end,
the following phone photo
that gets you kind of turned
on? All right. Ready, ready,
go.
Hmm. Wow. You got to think that's
tight. It's all swollen and shit.
Like if it's completely, there's no way
that could be loose. Look out painful.
It looks, if you get it cleaned out
really well done, like they took my door.
Am I feel so good? It might be worth
it. Yeah. You might if you don't,
if you could look off at the horizon, why
you fucked that thing. Yeah. I mean look,
it's basically like a fleshlight.
Right?
How big is that? I don't know. That's
about, it's like a humongous, uh,
uh, pumpkin. Yeah. It's
hard to, I don't know.
I think there's a small monkey.
Would you take it?
Would you take that if it
was detailed and cleaned out
that that being an ass was detailed? Is
that what that is that a baboons? Yeah.
It is. Right? Yeah. What
a weird, a weird animal.
Baboons as it looks like a dog sorta.
Yeah.
She had to pull up another picture
of a baboons head man, baboons, a.
They've also figured out how to raise
dogs. Have you seen that now? Yeah.
Baboons are so smart. They, um,
they actually steal puppies, um,
from,
uh,
from the mothers and they raised them
and they raised them as guards and they,
uh, they feed them and they
keep them around so that
they can sleep and the dog's
stick around. The dogs would bark
and something's going on. Yeah.
That's fucking amazing.
Fucking incredible, man.
They're smart enough to
realize that if you keep dogs,
take them when they're puppies,
he keep around,
they lock onto you and you're the daddy
just keep feeding them and then they,
they bark when some shit comes around.
Yeah. I was watching this nature
show the other night and it was,
all these wolves were
hunting air following them.
And so there's all these wolves
and, and they were, it was,
they were in between these two mountains
that sort of funneled into this one
little place. So all the wolves are
together, all of them leave. But one,
one stays in this little like funnel
and then they scare up some animals and
animals run down to the funnel.
And then that wolf that's waiting
there for him like jumps on him, right?
So it means they like made a plan and
somehow non-verbally told one of the
wolves, like, you stay here and we'll
scare up pray that'll run to you.
And then you fuck it up. She's
crying. It's like, it's crazy.
Like how are they communicating like that?
Like is that happening? It's amazing.
His baboons.
Yeah. What a weird looking animal. Right?
Look at their faces. They leave the
safety of the cliffs to forage for food.
Let's look a lion monkey. Check out
those assets that has a really weird ass.
Why is the answer now as
the females up to 40 pounds
as a heritage?
Wow.
That's incredible. Confusing
me. But it's amazing.
They fight on these walls. Oh, he just
beat the shit out some bitch. Oh fuck.
She got crazy. She did eat
is better. Oh, she's mad.
She's really like letting him know,
but she fucked up.
He looks mean.
What a creepy fucking animal.
How much dry is baboons travel?
Overland and large groups for a reason.
There are predators here,
leopards,
hyenas and cheetahs
that face.
So freaky looking man.
They did it and it was like
dog's snouts insects. Wow. Oh,
like Avatar. Totally. Avatar
Shit. Look at that. Then.
It seems conscious. They've got
companies, but it looks like an animal.
Another army of baboons has
also made camp on these cliffs.
Oh Jesus Christ. How much spelled
trouble have Boone trouble?
How much dry is baboons will fight
over flies. Why is Oprah doing this?
She loves baboons
like all of us.
She likes the baboons gas as much as ID
really aren't like avatar creatures. Man
is out there playing the piano.
Awesome.
I'm so happy that Africa exists.
Yeah, but it can suck my dick.
I'm not going there. I'm not
going there. That is a crazy spot,
man.
Look at all this
while we're looking at Q.
Imagine if this was in like North Dakota.
You managed it.
If like you're driving in North Dakota,
you have to deal with fucking
packs of angry banded.
It would be hyenas.
Would it be completely hilarious though?
Like if a game show came in there and
just built like a toys r us or like a
restaurant and just see how long it lasts
back on country. All the garden Africa,
Pat Boone's man,
this is insanity on fear factor.
You had to have done some kind of
weird animal shit at some point. Well,
we avoided most dangerous
animals except bowls.
That was the dumbest episode that we
ever did. There was only two episodes.
Why ever protests and what we were
doing. Oh, he's just jacking people.
Oh, it's fabulous. Ruthless.
Did he kill her? Oh whoa.
That's fucked up life.
I was the life and death to Sundays at,
there's only two episodes, a fear
factor that I ever protested. I said,
we shouldn't do. Not shouldn't
do, but I was like, I was
like, wow, you got serious.
One of them was riding a bull. I was like,
this is, you guys are crazy. We, it was,
we had an old stunt team. Then when
the, in the early days of fear factor,
they took, they were, you know, stunk guys
were rough dudes. You know, they're like,
I have someone's gonna get hurt.
You know we're going to be all right,
but someone might get hurt. They were
willing to take like way more chances.
So they put people on these bowls and I
go, hey man, I go, are these safe? I go,
these are fucking bulls, man. How do you
know there's going to be safe? He goes,
well, these are these training
bowls. Then. Then I even
that aggressive, I'm like,
do they know their training?
She did. They know.
I think they just think their boats.
That thing is huge.
Like a bull is another avatar creature.
A bulls are ridiculous. This giant,
stupid fucking cunt of an animal with
huge horns and you're got to ride it and
it's locked in a cage.
They're going to open up the cage.
You're going to hold on this bowl,
the fuck outta here.
That's one of the dumbest things I've
ever heard in my life. I was like,
you guys are just totally rolling a
dice is whether or not these people are
going to be okay. And that's exact
what happened over and over again.
People are flying through the air, man.
Everybody got launched off, but you just,
you're going to get launched off
period and you might get stomped.
You might get kicked in the face.
You might have to get your whole head
reconstructed, but that's not a joke.
Could stomp on you. Poor cow.
We got the size of his deck.
It's got strong on it and shit.
Dirty bastard mill this size
of that fucking bowl, man.
It's gonna melt that shit.
Look at the size of the muscles
on that ball again. Each grass,
that's all he's eating.
And he's aggressive as fuck.
Aggressive as fuck from eating.
Hey, fuck you up. He's huge.
He's got a giant Dick
and he eats. Hey, wait,
what was the other one you
protested and look at this bowl.
Sex was the other one where their fear
factor episode. That was the donkey.
Semen one donkey. Semen. They, uh,
I thought that was the dumbest
thing I ever, I was like,
you can't get people to drink. Come
on man. I don't care if it comes,
we're a donkey. Not like these volumes
that they were, it was like 24 ounces.
It was such a stupid amount of carb.
It was like,
there's no way you could do this.
This is not right. You can't do this.
And they were like, whoa. It past
standards and practices and you know,
we could do it. And I'm like, okay, Hey,
what's both sex as a term in sex road?
Bull sacks.
I Dunno, what is it? Because
when I googled images I,
there's a lot of crazy shit that
came on was probably some gay shit.
Don't be looking at that. And if you
do it, don't throw up in the keyboard.
And they said, don't panic.
Yeah. Straight out into the back.
This door's locked for your safety
because we were worried about you.
But if you unlock that and go straight
that, that star babies out of the way,
the other way.
Powerful.
Oh, powerful. Justin Helpern.
Yeah. Cool Dude. Right.
Southern California kid. Are you up in
San Diego? We're going to be this weekend.
This weekend.
I'm in Calgary.
Bitch shows sold out the first show
sold out the second show. This one
tickets left for the 10 o'clock show.
It's a at the Jack Singer concert hall.
I tweeted it today. Um, I
can't, I can't tell you the,
the link because it's so stupid. It's
one of those a million, you know,
character long links. But
it's um, if you go to a,
my Twitter today,
it's today is uh,
the 18th of July and it's a this Friday
night, so it's too nice for now. It's me,
Ari Shaffir and Duncan Trussell first
show sold out and then we got a 10 o'clock
show that still have some
tickets available and then
as a UFC the next night,
harmful Calgary making shit
happen up there in Canada.
I love Canada, Dude. That's where you
gotta go when the shit hits the fan.
Coover yeah, that's a
good spot. Perfect view.
A lot of extra.
See a lot of Asian chicks,
mountains skiing.
I know how much you love to ski.
If there was a redheaded Asian,
I think that would be the best
combination of Pantera. Do you ever see,
cause I saw a blonde Asian in San Diego
and it was such a weird combo that
that's,
that's rare if I was blonde bleach
blond or was it a freak of nature?
It was,
it looked like white hair.
Like I looked like matrix that the guys
from the matrix shoot bleached white
bleached it and it was really cool cause
it was like a blonde girl that looked
like an alien till you
get down to those pubes.
Those buttle here is that she
hasn't kept up with, yeah,
just don't have hair.
They don't know that they were
designed to try to get rid of the RFA.
There's,
there's different kinds of Asians but
like Stan hope there's a whole bit about
uh,
Asian porn about it being like,
like rat Harris are like, is he, I
forget what he says. Rat whiskers.
Pubes but they don't have like arm
pit hair's usually or
the carers or face hair.
Like you never say we're
talking about pubes so sorry.
Oh, no. I was talking about,
oh wait,
I don't remember.
San Diego is one of my
new favorite places to go.
Hanging out at the American comedy
company made me realize like how,
what a great spot that is. Like that
whole area, that little hangout area,
that area call it again, remember
where all the bars where it's call it.
What's that area? Brewery. Not The
brewery district. That's Columbus.
You're your San Diego. Gaslamp gas gas.
I've just seen such a great spot, man.
We were just there for a,
we did some shows in American
comedy company and we were
like, what a nice area.
It says like everybody's walking around.
It's like really cool.
I like the Indian dentist hotel by
the way. That places. Yeah. Nice.
It's that 10 year, 15 years ago. That was
like skid row. Really? The whole thing.
That's where,
that's where I like more
Republican government,
you know? That's why I like like
conservative government. That's why.
That's one of the things I like about
a place like San Diego and its military
presence.
They like have way less bullshit going on.
Oh yeah. You know, San Diego is like,
even even when like there'll be
some at the bar Saturday night,
there'll be some guys that lightly this
and they'll be some fights and stuff.
But it's pretty well policed.
I mean like,
and it's not like I never let
it get to be where skid row is.
Anello they would never let it get that
far. The La skid rows were digitals.
It's crazy.
I think it wouldn't happen in San Diego.
They would never let it happen.
And there's some bad things about that.
Like where they keep trying to close
the pot shops down and they, you know,
rest people for, they're really
aggressive by alcohol after midnight,
unless it's at a bar. They're aggressive
about that. But you know what,
that's how you keep a nice
community. That sucks. But it's true.
That's the only way they
could make downtown work.
Downtown was crazy before then.
Wow. So what started the change?
There was just some developers
came in and were like, listen,
we're going to pump a ton of money into
downtown. If you give us the permits,
we'll pump the money and why.
And so our government,
I mean now our governments
all fucked and San Diego, but,
but what's wrong with it now?
I'll all the hell that councilman
stuff got busted for like, Oh yeah,
he's trying to fuck her and
stuff. Yeah. So we're broke now.
Cities actually kind of let banks,
did he get sued that and uh,
he handed out some contracts to do
through on strip clubs and stuff. Oh no,
he didn't really, there was a bunch
of shit. Oh that's beautiful. Yeah,
he was rocking it. Old School.
Yeah. Oh yeah. Old School
corruption style. They were,
he was trading contracts
basically for hookers. Whoa.
Like the strippers would,
you know,
like he go and they'd fuck him and
strip for him and all kinds of shit.
And then he would hand out contracts to
the owners and he's living like a king.
So when he came along, that was Hayden. I
obviously had a good racket and
they were hating on him. Dude.
Everything was going fine.
It's a good place to live.
Guy Like that run and shit is going to
be happy all the time. So, but yeah,
downtown they totally like revitalized it.
And so it was just these one group,
this one group of developers that just uh,
starting with the money and then it
all, it's amazing. It's amazing. Yeah.
It's something to learn from.
Cause I, I'll tell you that, uh,
that place where we're, the
American comedy comedy is,
is really awesome and fun.
Yeah. It's really cool cause that Brian's,
that a chicken and waffle place. 24.
Oh Jesus. Right next door to it.
Yup. So fucking sweet area man.
And there's a lot big
police presence there too.
A lot of cops we saw tons by the way,
which is good. Keeps people from Duchenne.
Yeah. But no, no place to
smoke weed. But that knowing
anywhere in San Diego, this isn't that
bad. Dewey. Yeah. They don't fuck around.
They don't fuck around. They treat it
like it's like cocaine or something. Yeah.
Same say coke. Wow. They go federal,
they go federal on you in San Diego.
They don't have to and they do. Really?
Yeah. How bad do they do it? Like,
what did they, do anybody know
anybody who's been arrested yet? Or,
my buddy was just smoking a joint on
the street. I'm stupidly, he's drunk,
snow, smoking a joint on the street
and he was in jail for five days. Uh,
he had like all kinds of charges
brought up on them. Like, oh they,
they like bullshit stuff like
intent to sell and stuff. Like,
like stuff where he's just a guy smoking
a joint on the street, you know? Wow.
I was sweating a lot of joints
this weekend. They just try to,
oh one big conventions come in.
Then they're chill.
Oh, they play Nice, nice
comicon. You're not gonna,
you're not gonna get busted for anyone.
Wow. That's weird. That's even creepier.
So this guy was in jail for five days.
Did you?
Five days is it,
couldn't figure out why they,
like they kept saying he can leads like
window it. He was broke. So He's like,
what? He's like, when do I get
out there? Like, I'm not sure.
They're like held him for five days.
Why did they do that?
Because they just wanted to make a point.
I mean they did.
So they don't even charge you with
anything. They're just hold you.
He ended up getting charged. I can't
remember. He got charged for, but he had,
he had it. It was a big fine, you know,
it's like a shitload of community service.
It was like worse than getting
a Dui. Wow. That's correct.
We're just smoking one joint. Jungo was
us. So maybe like a year and a half ago.
Wow. Fuck. San Diego.
Real life.
Yeah.
That's really do that in the state of
California because the state of California
is really, when it comes to
drugs, especially when it
comes to schedule one stuff,
which means scheduling on means that it
doesn't mean it's the most dangerous,
but it means that it's,
it has no medical purpose.
So like the thing about marijuana is it's
lumped in there with like crystal meth
and things that are useless.
It's a lot of like lumped in
there with like the worst drugs.
The idea is that it's,
it has no value but then scheduled to
his cocaine scheduled to his heroin
because there's medical
uses for them. Wow. Yeah.
So it's fuck that.
It's ridiculous.
So federally they're allowed to
go after it as a federal crime,
even if under the state, you know, it's
legal. It's a very tricky situation.
Like the DEA can always come in and
bust these medical marijuana places
federally because federally
it's a schedule one drug.
Still the classifications insane. I
mean it's, at this point in time, look,
first of all, Tommy Chong
guy on our phone, our show
is perfect example of that.
He's been using this hemp oil to a,
to treat his cancer.
He has cancer of the prostate. Yeah.
And He's, he's 99% cancer free now.
Holy Shit. Yeah. And he's been using
this hemp boy shit and the psych,
I just use it religiously. I changed my
diet. I started eating healthy and boom.
Hmm.
Sons of bitches and the federal government
would come in and make that illegal.
My cousin is a farmer in Brooklyn.
Yeah, exactly. Now he's a farmer up by
humble. Uh, they, oh Jesus. He has a real,
he's a for real, but he sells
to like dispensary's and stuff.
So it's like kind of on the up and up.
I mean he sort of, he didn't always,
but he's, he told me, he's like, yeah,
at any time the feds come in here
and throw me in jail like crazy.
And they take all your money.
Yeah.
And they just choose one to do it.
And anybody that's making any noise,
like they had that show, we'd wars
remember that show? Yeah. Well I saw that.
I'm like they're going to get Boston.
Boom.
They got busted like right
after the show got. Yeah.
But the guy who made it was one of the
guys that were featuring on the show.
Who's your head? He runs this
big medical marijuana dispensary.
And when you run a,
I mean I think there's something somewhere
in the provisions where it's like
you're not supposed to
make like a lot of profit.
And so like when you are a part of a big
thing of medical marijuana collective,
you're responsible for,
even though a lot of money is coming in,
you have to like make sure that it goes
to places like goes to like you have to
give some of it away to charity,
pay your employee and he can't
make it a lot of money off of it.
And when there's millions of dollars made,
they just assume you're
making a lot of money.
It doesn't matter what you're doing with
the numbers, whether it's legit or not,
in their opinion, they're like, this
guy is too big. We've taken them down.
And so they just go after you.
And if you have a safe by take your money
and fucking good luck and that back,
they take all your pot and they
probably going to sell that, you know,
I don't know what they do with it. It's
if it's legal in the state, I mean,
who knows, who knows what they're
gonna do with it? I mean they, I mean,
why would they burn it when it's probably
worth millions of dollars? They would.
What do you want to do here?
Yeah. What has happened all
that pot. It's a good question.
If you asked how many chunks
as they steal it, what happens?
Like they get a huge drug bust crossing
the border. They burn it. They burn it.
Yeah, they do in Mexico. I know they
burn it in Mexico. They burn the coke,
they burn, they burn. I don't
know if they do that anymore.
Was it one was a one of the shows with
Anthony Bordain, I forget where he was.
He was in some South American
company country rather,
where they had this giant bust of cocaine
and he was there while they lit the
cocaine on fire. Yeah, and he was
like, you know, like they were all,
all the cops had thrown this stuff into
like this ditch and they going to like
pour gasoline on it and light on fire.
I'm like,
I would not want to be anywhere in
any shape connected that fucking
event that looks like it's causing some
drug dealers some serious fucking money
and you're going to put that on a TV
show. I'd be like, Oh fuck that man.
Not My show. Bitch. Did you read that
thing? There's a thing in New York
Time magazine a couple
of weeks ago about this,
the biggest drug dealer in Mexico,
like drug cartel guy and uh,
and what part of the essay?
They said that he was having trouble
figuring ways to get it to the u s so he
just kidnapped some scientists and
had them build him. A submarine
does ship fucking coke.
Oh.
Oh my God. Where did he
kidnap a scientist from? Ah,
I can't remember where they said,
but like you basically just grabbed
your scientist. He was like, hey,
build me a coke submarine.
Oh my God.
Could you imagine exact fucking
job and are you going to get out?
They were going to let you free.
Why would he ever let you free
built him a coke submarines.
He's going to let you free. You're in.
Once you build the cokes out marine,
you're in, as long as you keep producing
shit for him, maybe he'll keep you alive.
Yeah. Eventually you're gonna run out of
Shit to do and you know too much. Yeah.
You know where the coke machines parked,
they gotta fucking coke machine that goes
underwater. I mean that's what it is.
It's a real live coke machine.
The crazy thing is, is like
how much money is he
making that he's just like,
I don't know if this is going to work
or not, but just here's a couple of Mil.
Probably even more than that.
It's probably many,
many millions to create a submarine.
I mean have to bring in
some serious engineers.
You'd have to bring in some fabricators.
Me, you want to start from scratch?
Like how are you going to do this?
Where are you going to get
this submarine used to?
You're really going to build one man.
That is no joke.
What's going to propel this thing? What
do you, what are you using for fuel? Oh,
you're igniting an underwater,
you know what you're doing.
You need to have subs really specialized
education to build off fucking
submarine. All right. That's
no small achievement. No,
you're going to have to call some
other people. Dude. I wonder how many,
I wonder how many scientists he kidnapped
that. Yeah, it was crazy
cause it said that, uh,
it said that he had built these giant
tunnels underground that had like
bathrooms and, and, and all kinds of shit.
And then one of the tunnels got found out.
That's when he was like,
I'm so sick and tired of like
building these great tunnels.
I'm gonna build a submarine.
Wow.
And imagine how terrifying it is to
being in a submarine filled with coke.
Oh my God. Dude in the ocean filled with
coke and you're totally, by the way,
illegally there,
you're not supposed to be there.
So at any point in time they
can just light you up with
missiles from a distance,
you know?
Also two dudes made it like under duress.
So that might be some problems with it.
It might be a bomb.
I might wait to get underwater
water and blow you up. You can't,
you may mill the fucking sub, but then
they'd probably killed the guy for sure.
Imagine if the sub blew up
till the guy who made it. Yeah,
they'd probably kill you anyway.
They really kill you if it blows up.
That's the thing. It's like if you do
too well working for a drug cartel,
you're going to die. If you don't
do well enough, you're going to die.
That's terrible job really.
I really don't recommend it to anybody.
It's the most chaotic idea ever.
You're going to get involved in the
world of international drug selling.
You know,
it's like the movie Scarface.
How many of future like crazy tycoon,
drug dealer dudes that movie
inspire and really bad rappers.
Do you remember the episode of the law?
Was it um,
Larry David curb your
enthusiasm? We had, I'm crazy. I,
Kyla is the rapper guy.
It's one of the funniest episodes ever.
It's really hilariously ridiculous.
Over the top rapper dude who
loves Scarface yet Scarface on 24,
seven in this house.
It was so perfect.
What a shit way to make a living man
trying to sell coke. Fuck. Like, you know,
it's going to end and it's like,
it's like you're on a train and you don't
know where it's going to hit the wall,
but you know it's going to hit the wall,
but until it hits the wall,
you can party. Yeah. Well, that's
what they said. They said that,
so he lives this guy,
it seems El Chapo and he lives on the top
of a mountain somewhere in Mexico that
has just like guards all around it
and he just has like whores flown in.
He has a whole soccer teams flown in
to play for him. Oh my God. Jesus.
But your basic prisoner, you
can't like go out to dinner. Yeah.
Well he serves sorta royal family
and said he's like a royal family.
I mean basically right. We were talking
about earlier, very similar. Yeah.
And why, why does it exist?
That's where it gets really cute.
It's all because of the reason why
organized crime exploded in America,
in the,
uh,
the early days of the 20th century was
because alcohol was illegal for a few
years.
And during that prohibition,
that's when the organized crime families
that were selling the alcohol got
strong cause they were making a fuck
load of money. Yeah. And then the,
once you have money, you have momentum,
you have momentum, you creating crime.
People are getting rich and there
was a lot of money in selling booze.
People want to boost.
The government was fucking stupid and
they tried to keep it from the people and
it became chaos. And that's
exactly what's going on in Mexico.
A big part of what's going on in
Mexico is because of the drug war.
And because Mexico is a poor country
that's right next to a rich country.
And the best way to make money when you
connect it to the rich country is seldom
illegal shit.
Cause the best way is there some
shit that I have that you can't get.
You need heroin. That's funny. I have
heroin and then next thing you know it,
they're just selling you what you need.
It's, it's just supply and demand.
You know they are like hustling.
They're right next door to the machine.
What does the machine need?
The machine needs coke.
You've got to get a coke and you don't
even need to be like their product is so
good that you can have a fucking retard
sell it and he can sell out of it.
Like you don't even need talented.
Actually coke,
coke gets those,
the coke role starts happening and
people want more and more and more.
And you chasing the dragon with
it. That's a, it's a dark thing.
When you watch someone chasing that,
that Coke Dragon,
it's a different thing than chasing
the heroin drag and the heroin drag.
And it seems like the people
are having actually having fun.
I like the heroines freaky
to me because it seems like,
like when you talk to people that
have had it and it had the experience,
like it sounds so beautiful. It did. It
doesn't seem like it. You know, it, it,
it remains at one point in time,
almost almost worth some aspect of the
loss that you're gonna get from these
because it's such a mind blowingly
beautiful thing when you do get the trip,
but it eventually a row erodes. Yeah. I
have a buddy who did a lot of heroin in,
in college and he like made it out and as,
and you know,
unless people are just like that
fucking evil dragon, hate it.
Like when they talk about their
drug addictions, he was like, man,
heroin was so great. Yeah. He's like, I
can't do it cause it just fucked me up.
But like it was so great.
It's supposed to be like the most
beautiful loving feeling ever.
But it's such a trick because it's
horrendous for your fucking body.
It's horrendous. It's really dangerous.
What does it make addicted to it?
Do your teeth fall out if
you're on heroin? Meth.
He probably just not
taking care of yourself.
It's not like the drug
makes your teeth fall out.
He just become a fucking cockroach methods
and a lot of coconuts from grinding
her teeth and stuff like that.
God, yeah, that's fucked up.
How many drugs there are that can
jack you legal or illegal. It's just,
it's amazing how many things that we
become physically connected to and you
know, and it's, I don't understand
the physio, the physical part of it.
I can completely understand like people
that are obsessed with things and get
gambling addictions and
things along those lines.
I can understand that kind of addiction,
but the physical addiction doesn't,
it doesn't. I don't have
that, that that gene,
whether it's for alcohol or a
cigarette or I don't have that,
but I know people who do,
they can't do anything.
They can't have a one simple sip of
wine and then next thing you know,
they'll be on this nutty downward spiral
where they're doing shots and they're
out of control and they're saying things
they'll never remember it. I mean,
that's how, that's a weird
fucking aspect of being a human.
It's got to be genetic. Partly
genetic. What's the benefit
of it? It's weird. Yeah.
I Dunno.
What's that?
What's the drug that people are taking
it and they're like eating people's faces
off bath salts. That's right. What the
fuck is bath salt? Yeah, we'll the,
it's funny that the cops are
trying to pretend that it was weed.
Like if that guy was on weed and
he did that, he's just an asshole.
It doesn't matter what drug is taken.
It's not weed swinging
it eat someone's face.
I think it was just he was a crazy
person. It could be that too. Yeah.
It could not.
It doesn't have to just be under the bath.
Salts aren't detectable
because it's not exactly,
don't even know what the test is.
Exactly.
Don't they don't have a test for it
cause it's all bunch of different shit.
They apparently change molecules and
Kevin Pereira was explaining it to us
scientifically they take,
can take any sort of a molecule and
they change it by an oxygen molecule.
Doesn't necessarily change the effect
of the drug. It's still effective,
but it became, it becomes a
different trip. And in this
trip, you know there's one,
some people were doing some wacky shit
and you can buy it over the counter at
places you can buy it.
A,
you know they called called
bath salts because you're not,
it says not for human consumption
so you can just buy it.
That's how they get around selling. Right,
right. And then people smoke it sort of,
sort of, but you know, Salvia is just a
plant. Have you ever smoked Salvia? Yes.
Let's that like,
I don't know because I don't think
I had a really quick of machines. I,
I've talked to some people like Ari who
like thinks he might have lived like a
whole month at another and chin.
Then I'll say that again without coughing.
He, he felt like he lived a
whole month in another dimension.
And then when he came back,
his instantaneous, um,
like it was like he went in and out here
for five minutes and he remembers most
of the,
most of the time in that five minutes
as a month long journey that he had with
these families and he created friendships
and there's a great sense of loss when
the trip was over because he would never
see his friends again. Salvia. Yeah,
she said that, um, me and him had
a long talk about it when really,
because every time I've seen
him do to salvage, not that,
well, you don't know man.
Maybe he didn't tell you exactly what
happened and his fucking freaky little
five minute trip,
I didn't get there.
Taco and he was drowning and he couldn't,
people were looking at them and all
this other stuff. So not conscious.
I don't know how many, it depends how,
it depends how deep you go and do it.
Like when, when I, when I've done it,
I've done like the 40 times
or to 60 times Salvia.
And what it felt like to me is
if you've ever done like a whip,
it like a balloon where it's like Wah
Wah Wah Wah, like last, like whatever,
three minutes, five minutes. It
was like that. But of mushrooms,
like you're just getting thrown into the
most intense mushroom trip or acid trip
ever.
And then it goes away and
like five minutes and then
you just feel like shit for
like an hour or two hours afterwards.
He just kind of feel like crappy,
like worn out.
Well you got to take a lot
of it and you've got to do,
it's got to be strong and you
gotta to do it the right way.
It's gotta be heated to a certain
way. I didn't crack lighter. Yeah,
I didn't get it right.
I got it to where it was like
how to add a body experience.
Just really simple out of body experience.
Like I was over my right shoulder,
like hovering, looking down at myself,
and then would come muck and waves.
I look at myself. And when
you from up, that was it.
And it only lasted for like five minutes.
And I think feel like it was longer
than five minutes. No, no, no.
It felt pretty quick.
I didn't even feel time.
I don't think that's why I'm surprised
that Ari felt the said dad because you
don't really,
I don't think you ever even think of time.
You just feel like you're dead. Yeah. I'm
pretty sure. I'm pretty sure it's Ari.
I mean,
I don't,
I can't believe I would fuck up and not
think that maybe it was somebody else,
but I'm pretty sure it was all right.
He said he had like a whole like,
month long friendships. That's not,
that doesn't seem like Salvia, well,
maybe it is, man. Maybe you just needed
to take it at the right time, you know?
Who knows? Trying hard enough to make
fucking friends and your trip. Yeah, man.
Maybe you're not really reaching out
while you're tripping. Hmm. I think, uh,
I think it's possible that, you
know, you get different Salvia,
that's different potency and you take it,
you know, see, this is more like salary.
This is when I did it. This is you.
Yeah. Wait, this is actually you.
He's actually tramping here.
You'll go,
you're taking a shit ugly.
You're shitting out sand seashells.
I was on a water slide or something like
that and I thought my face melted off.
How you feeling?
Oh my God, Dude. Stop this embarrassing.
Played it before a million times. We,
you and I? Yeah. When we do,
I don't, no, I don't think
so. One of your other friends.
It's ice house chronical. I wasn't
there. How dare you? No, I mean,
you've seen this before.
I've showed it to you.
I really don't think I've seen him.
Really? That's craziness. Yeah,
it was craziness. I've seen Ari's, I
saw already when he got mad at. Yeah.
Let me just check. It's not good legal.
There you go. Bam. That Shit's illegal.
Well, they didn't, that's
not 100% legal anymore. Well,
they're slowly starting to sneak it out,
but it's not scheduled.
It's not like schedule one, you know, it's
like me going sampling marijuana. Yeah.
They've started to make it
legal or illegal rather. Um,
but they didn't know there's some
other shit that's, that's legal to,
there's some stuff that they don't
know about that's like, you know,
five methoxy dimethyltryptamine that
slide that's legal. You can buy that.
He used to be able to buy it online.
It used to be able to buy it from
a research chemical companies,
not for human consumption.
You'd be able to buy it online and
it would just blow your fucking mind.
You'd go to another dimension.
Totally legal.
That's not going to mean for human
consumption though. I think if you use it,
you actually in violation of the law by
virtue of the fact that it's chemically
related to something that's illegal,
it's like really close to her cousin
to something that's illegal. Yeah.
Like what scientist is sitting there like
figuring out what the fuck you up that
night. Asshole scientist,
asshole scientists.
Creative bath salts to bag.
You know,
this dude's out there working on the
cure for aids and guys like, Nope,
I want some scarier meth.
Some method.
Even meth people would tell you to quit
bath salts. We just getting
weirder and weirder as a society.
Have you heard of Ken Com? Yes.
That's not real though. It's not. No.
It's like a lifestyle.
Yeah. It's fairly horseshit.
A drug that uh, they make
with a poop. Oh yeah,
that's fake. It's fake. Yeah.
Fuck. I wanted that to be real.
It just thought it was real too.
I thought it was real too.
I think maybe people have tried it,
but I don't think it works.
It will trip you out
smelling shit. Dows your
drug of choice. Boy,
when you want to talk about
like how bad Africa must suck,
that someone's willing to believe that
because you were saying in Detroit
they're smoking their own shit. He'd
be like, no, stop making that up.
That's sniffing for shit water
to get high in Detroit. Stop it.
But in Africa you're like,
well, they probably are. Yeah.
I mean they get to figuring out
some way to get fact up to there.
You immediately assume they were right.
It seems like,
okay, what am, what else am I
supposed to believe? They smoke.
I smoke this shit.
He ever seen the one video on a African
fish farming where they have like a pond
filled with fish and the run in with
baskets. They, everyone runs in.
Everyone in the town runs in,
into the,
into the water and catches the fish
with nets and with their hands.
Thousands of people. And they run in
and they catch every fish in this pond.
It's a shallow pond. The catch them all
with their hands and baskets and shit.
And they do it all at
once. Huh? Who is it?
That's dot Merera powerful dot.
Merera let him come. Come on in.
They just run into the, yeah, it's crazy.
They run in. Have you seen that Brian?
The video where the dudes in Africa,
they run into a,
upon the fish for it. Pull it up cause
it's crazy. See if you could find it.
When I say African African pond,
uh,
fishing with their hands.
Village.
Janka see if you can check 'em butthole.
Yeah.
I don't know if you're going to
find it Lucia to no, that's not it.
You know that Sunday? That's a little
girl. How dare you? I don't know.
Africans catch fish with their hands.
Yeah.
You banging
it or is this a Google search?
Here's The fucking asteroid attack and,
and we're all just like back
to like basic civilization.
Like Africa is going to be like fucking
New York because they're the only ones
you want to do anything.
I know they could still like the people
in the Congo that like catch fish by
hanging from trees.
Have you seen those guys?
Justin Helper and Justin Helpern
tomorrow. Nice to meet you. Dot.
Merera shows up nice and
early for the super show,
which will be taking place in less than
one hour. Have a seat. Dumb, relaxed.
You've got a cocktail, you look
comfortable. You got your notebook.
The mother fucker never stopped writing.
Leverage. Laser gentlemen never stops.
He's a pro. Yeah. Any way you
want to sit. So Justin, let me,
let me, we're going to end this
podcast and we'll, we'll, uh,
start the icehouse chronicles in the
wild after we come back from a break.
But Justin, you have a new book out.
It's called I suck at girls. And,
uh, tell me why do soccer girls, you
seem like handsome, intelligent guy.
I looked at the cover and I said,
this doesn't even make sense.
I can understand that you have a
crazy dad and he's very entertaining.
But what's just a misprint? Was this
supposed to be at? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
That was the original title.
Uh, no. I mean it, most, it
takes place in the past. Uh,
I mean it's all chronicle
like nonfiction story.
My Dad's in a lot of them. I'm
not stupid. He's in it. Um,
yeah, I mean it's just basically like
a bunch of stories everybody has about,
you know, your fucking Shitty
proms and this then, you know, uh,
losing your virginity.
And
do you ever worry about running
out of dad stories? A resource?
It's been very good to you
with that vein and dry it out.
I know I might've tried it out with,
maybe I have a few. Uh, I mean
it, yeah. I don't know. I figured,
well, I'll let them all out there
and hopefully I won't need it
then we'll need it anymore.
That's my heroin. That's my
gen chem. Well, you know,
as a guy trying to make
it as a screenwriter,
what a fucking awesome break that was
for you. The whole thing was just so,
it's so fortunate and so
interesting. Yeah. I love
when stories like that happen.
I love when it shows that there's
a lot of like really talented,
funny people out there.
They just never do anything with it.
There's a lot of people out there that
are really funny and really talented,
but for whatever reason,
nothing clicks for them. They,
they can't figure out how to make that
connection to it manifesting itself in
the real world.
It was just,
they become these really funny people
that have jobs working for, you know,
whatever company I'm insurance
company or whatever it is,
and for whatever reason,
they just never fucking figured
their way into the river. They never,
never crawled to the bank. Just didn't
have the balls to jump in. It's too bad.
I mean, for me it was just like,
it was such a crazy break. Right?
It was like lightning in a bottle and
then luckily I had sort of been doing,
I'd been writing for a few years, so
it was like, all right, well, you know,
let me get my shot. Like let me
get my, let me take my at bat
surface. Yeah. Had that board. It's
beautiful. It's an awesome store.
I'd love hearing stories like that where
someone just is doing something good
and just by virtue of the fact that other
people are telling other people and it
spreads and then then everybody hears
about it. That's how I heard about it.
I didn't read it in any publication
or anything. Everybody was like, dude,
check this out. This guy's
hilarious. And I would go check it.
I read a few of them laughed out
loud. I follow. This guy is funny.
It's funny how it happens,
man. It's beautiful.
So there's a real organic occurrence.
Oh, thanks man. Yeah, it's been, it's
definitely like a, it's funny too,
cause like after the TV show
got canceled, people like, Oh,
you must have been so fucking pissed.
I'm like dude,
I got a TV show on the air
for write down fucking shit.
Are you stupid?
I'm happy that everything like nothing,
you know, there's nothing that
was going to bum me out of it.
That's a great attitude. And that's
so important to, for success in life,
to have that kind of attitude and just
enjoy it and appreciate it. Work hard,
enjoy it and appreciate it.
So many people and then something happens
and then it goes away from it and they
can never appreciate it.
They ever even did it. Yeah.
It's just neurosis trying to get to the
next level or stay on that level or you
know, get the next thing is you don't
feel like you're drowning, you know?
So a show business is a very weird
world man. It's very weird. Yeah.
It's so funny too cause like,
and since then have worked on a couple
of other shows, but on writing staffs,
other shows and stuff and,
and I've seen like that's how it is.
Like every writer I work on
the show with, he's like, fuck,
this is so this is going to get
the fuck am I gonna do next year?
This is fucking bullshit. I hate
this job. And I'm like, dude,
like two years ago I was waiting tables.
Like that's kind of a shitty job.
Like we're sitting around making Dick
Jokes for fucking 12 hours a day for a TV
show. You're a writer on a
television show, like is there,
there's not that many more prestigious
positions in Hollywood besides actor and
producer, writer, a creator,
the person who, the creative
force behind the TV show,
that's fucking huge. There's not a
lot of people to get to do that. Yeah.
That's a massive, huge bill. Fuck,
I can't believe the shit is going to get
canceled. This fucking piece of shit.
It's hard for people to appreciate
shit. It really is. Yeah.
Are a lot of negative content here.
And plus and in Hollywood,
it's also seems like unlike you,
where you just rode this, you know,
this opportunity and you capitalize
on and made the most of it.
Some people just get failure after
failure, after failure, after failure,
after minimal success. And by the time
they have a little bit of success,
there's so like condition to failure
and they're so worn down by it.
Their spirit is broken. Yeah. Oh,
they brought in cheeseburgers,
order food. He fucking
savage. Look at you.
You don't play games fucker.
Cow. Cow Can suck it.
And he got wings to Brian's like,
you're your die can suck my dick.
That's what he just
said. All right, let's,
let's wrap this thing up so Brian can
have his food. People want to follow you.
The actual you.
It's just an underscore
Helpern at Twitter. Yep.
So, um, the other one, Shit my dad says
is just shit. It's still shit my dad says.
Right. And um, is there
anything else? Those are a
website that they should go to.
Now if they want to check out an
excerpt of the book, it's just a,
I suck at girl's book.com. Just go
buy the book on audible. Awesome.
Why play games? Yeah, we already
fucked that up. I was just going to,
if I was going to do the audible app,
I would have done at the beginning next
week we have four Comcast, so we'll,
we'll get that all the add in there. Um,
so, uh, the your site is, your website is,
you don't have a website. Okay, so
Twitter, we've got that covered.
You got a Facebook page? I don't,
you don't says you don't need it.
Is it over? Is it over? Brian?
I think you're better off
nowadays with the Tumbler.
A tumbler ups for glitter tax.
That's why I just for that alone for
animated gifs of drag is better than
Facebook wings of dragons. That carrier,
I don't use any of them anymore.
All right. Listen to dirty
bitches. This fucking shows over.
We're going to take a little break. We'll
be back with the icehouse chronicles.
We want to listen to it.
You want to listen live and watch live.
It'll be unused Ustream on this channel,
ustream.com ustream.tv,
Ford Slash,
Rogan and
um,
if you want to get it in audio form and
is only available under desk squad on
iTunes and death squad is a whole
podcast network that Brian runs.
That's his shit on the side.
And it's also our gay little nickname
for us and dom are errors in the death
squad to write down. You've been
writing that down on top texts.
He writes down on tax desk squad
at the end. So when you got don,
my rare representing death squad,
you doing all right bitches?
If you're around tonight,
we've got a show in about an hour and a,
it'd be dom Irrera, Doug Davidoff, Ari
Shaffir, Doug Benson, Doug Benson, Tivo,
Tivo, Brian Red Band and Wa. So we see
fucking dirty freaks very soon. Thanks.
Thanks for everything. Thanks for all the
positive tweets and all the, you know,
whatever it is that you guys do.
Tuning into the show and, and,
and saying that you enjoy it is a,
the the best motivation we could
ever possibly have to do it.
It's a very unusual circumstances
we sort of stumbled into and uh,
we sorta just wound up in this situation
when we're doing this podcast is not
planned out at all, but now that it's
become a part of so many people's lives,
I definitely feel obligated and
we're not going anywhere. So A,
we want to thank you guys thanks
to on a.com for sponsoring us.
Go to o n n I t use a code name,
Rogan and save yourself 10%
of any of the supplements.
It doesn't work with all the other shit.
Look at you over there while I'm talking
about supplements or eating the fries,
shoving them.
Dirty fries are so delicious.
Wouldn't it be awesome if
Fry's were good for you?
That's what we need to get our
on scientists on. Yeah. No,
there wouldn't be the same
cause if fries are good for you,
you wouldn't feel as good. They
only feel, don't put them away.
I don't want it burger. Put it away. Put
it away. I got to show it now listen,
ladies and gentlemen,
this show's over.
Go get yourself some kettlebells and
get your freak on Justin. Halpert.
You're the fucking man. Thank
you, sir. Thank you for coming.
If you ever need anything, you need us
to promote anything. Oh, go buy his book,
his book. I suck at girls
available now. Go get it on Amazon.
You can get it on a kindle.
Put it on your kindle or go.
She by a hard form can get more money
with a heart for him. That's it.
Gets paid the same. So go, go digital.
You dirty bitches. Save a tree. All right,
we'll see you guys soon. Thank you. Bye.