Two,
one,
yeah.
Ah,
just a less than a month before
Armageddon.
And uh,
we're here in the bunker.
Lovely Woodland Hills,
California.
That's right.
Brian motherfucking Kaolin is here.
He is.
He's willing for Jill Stein because she,
like Brian wants 16 year olds to be able
to vote,
but we both think it's super rational
and a great idea because no one,
no one better to decide the future of
the world.
A hormonally flooded baby.
Yeah.
What do you think about the boner?
What 18 year olds drinking instead of
21?
I don't think there's anything wrong
with someone who is supervised who was
18,
who is sort of mentored into having a
couple of drinks with an intelligent and
very disciplined parental figure.
Like someone who's a smart dad or smart
mom who says,
listen,
I don't want you to be.
I don't want it to be something that's
so out of reach that you wind up doing
it and getting obsessed with it because
it's the forbidden.
Dang.
It becomes a big deal.
Yep.
How about a drink or two?
Right.
You know,
but they have to be like a really
conscientious parent.
They should be there with the kid,
make sure no one's driving,
no stupid shit,
but we all had beers before we were 21.
Everybody did all of us.
I also think that if you're going to get
people that responsibility to vote and
they can carry the can join the army and
go and fight and die and kings give them
a license to kill.
Yes.
It seems very strange to me that you're
not also allowed to vote and I mean I'm
sorry,
drink because it used to be in I think
19,
84 is when the law changed.
You were able to drink?
Yeah,
man.
It was like I missed it by just a few
years fuckers.
I didn't.
I don't think I did.
Yeah,
he did because 85.
I was 17,
so that was when I graduated high
school.
I think I was 18 and 85.
I was drinking in college.
Where are you?
Yeah.
Yeah,
for sure.
I drank in high school,
but I could drink in bars in Washington
DC.
I remember.
Oh really?
There are different laws.
I was 18.
I was an early 18,
January 26th.
I'm so mature now who are mature.
I say that about you all the time,
so let's say for a grownup baby,
that's the attitude.
I'm looking the other day at the,
at the comedy store,
and we run down to this other part of
the comedy store and there was a mirror
and both of us stop.
Look in the mirror and we pull our
shirts up and start flexing.
You start going,
oh,
look at my stomach.
Look at my.
Oh my.
Oh,
leaks as absent,
and then just as quickly through our
shirts down and ran away as I was going,
I said I just barked were losers.
We're fucking losers.
We're babies,
we're going up babies,
but everybody is until you have so much
responsibility that you're beaten down,
it's no fun anymore.
I didn't.
I think I have figured out the
delineation there.
It's fun to be immature and we are and
to be silly geese,
but I think the difference is you become
a real adult and you become mature when
you have other people that rely on you
and where were other people's happiness
to some degree is more important than
your own.
So you know what I mean,
and their development is causes you
concern or angst and requires your time
and sacrifice.
And if I could throw something in there,
the only way that silly goose stuff
works at all as if you've got your bases
covered.
That's right,
right?
Like,
it's really tough to be a silly goose if
you're behind on your taxes,
if you have massive credit card debt
that you're ignoring or there's these
stacking stress things,
these events,
these,
uh,
factors in your life that can really get
involved in your,
your happiness and your silliness.
So as long as you know your,
your ducks are in a row,
then you can kind of laugh a little bit.
It's stuff.
Well,
we've taken for granted the fact that we
have figured out a way to preserve our
biology and most countries in terms of
like we have life saving medications or
sort of preventions for keeping us from
things like malaria and diptheria and
all those things that used to really.
Because when they.
They always talk about when you go into
a country and you want to get that
country on its feet and you want to help
develop that country,
the first thing you'd have to make sure
of is that people aren't suffering from
chronic illnesses,
parasites,
diseases that,
that just make them feel shitty.
They've got the right nutrition.
So the first thing to do is take care of
your biology,
take care of that.
You know,
that sort of thing that you live in that
machine.
Because otherwise if you don't feel
good,
there's a little rudimentary things.
If you don't feel good like hookworm in
the south.
But when after World War,
I mean,
I'm sorry,
civil war was so endemic in getting your
feet and was like a,
like a ringworm type thing.
Now hookworm gets in your interest or
your feet because kids would that people
would always use the bat,
they wouldn't use outhouses,
they use the great outdoors and then
you'd walk around in your bare feet.
So what hookworm does is it gets into
your,
it guy gets it,
goes through your feet and then it
causes you to become anemic because it
latches on.
Um,
I don't know.
It had to have some mechanism where it
lapsed on the intestine or something.
Either way.
Huge portions of the south after the
civil war,
after the civil war were anemic.
I mean huge towns.
And in fact it was so bad that they
started renting,
running campaigns,
saying bought.
Use An outhouse or die was an outhouse
or die and they solved the problem.
But it was a major issue in
reconstruction after the war.
Major issue in this country in the south
when I lived in Florida,
people used to always talk about worms.
Now that I'm thinking about it,
like this was one of the first times I'm
remembering this.
I think one of my aunts got it.
I think she used to walk around barefoot
and Florida is so tropical,
you know,
there's so much.
When we lived there,
we see alligators all the time.
Oh yeah.
Like,
and this was when they were there were
um,
there were protected.
You ever have worms?
No,
I never got like,
I've gotten ringworm before though.
Yeah,
me too.
But this guy right here that you're
looking at it as the worms come out of
his ass,
told me this.
One of my most vivid memories was my
sister screaming and crying and I run in
and there's a giant pink warm coming
right out of her four year old ass or
whatever it was.
She didn't know what the fuck was
happening.
And I was like,
I was.
I was like,
it's a worm.
You just have told mom I was a six,
you know,
worried about worms coming out of your
system.
I was a kid.
I,
I'd had him and I was looking to snakes
and stuff.
I was like,
me,
my mother made it like,
look at you now.
Take this medicine.
Now what happens if you don't have those
warrants or if you don't take the
medication for those worms,
worms,
parasite.
Right?
So how bad can they fuck you up badly.
Look what tapeworm and the worms.
Parasites like worms were a major issue.
And if you remember New Guinea worms
which caused I think elephantiasis to
diocese.
Um,
but,
but they're awful like New Guinea worms.
Look Up New Guinea worms.
They would,
they would,
I guess if you want to look up something
and look up this video.
That red band was showing me the other
night at the comedy store about some guy
who had an insane amount of worms
removed from his gut that you went to
the doctor and the complainant's stomach
pain that was originally.
Yeah.
Oh Dude.
So there's a video.
Sanitation is such a huge factor in the
foot there.
Jim,
how dare you,
what I'm talking about?
Sanitation.
Cynical.
Just put it on for us.
So that the uh,
video.
So we don't get pulled.
Yeah,
yeah.
We can get a look at it here.
Twenty five year old bodybuilder.
That thing.
Is that it?
Yeah,
I think that's it.
Yeah.
So was there a real thing?
But they.
They can be deadly.
Check this out.
They literally have to read.
It says parasitic worms need a high
deal.
Okay.
This might be like one of those vegan
propaganda videos probably.
I'm looking at all these worms though.
Fucking shit coming out of this guy's
body.
I mean,
it is insane.
His,
his gut is just stuffed with these
squirming worms as he's pulling them
out.
It's like Spaghetti looks like moving
spaghetti.
Spaghetti looks like that.
You're not crazy.
That I can say look how much it is.
Yeah,
that's discussed.
You're looking literally at a large bowl
of spaghetti,
right?
Yeah.
Like I would,
I would be wondering if I could eat that
whole.
That was the reality for a lot of people
over time.
Look at all of that.
That was all inside that dude's body.
And take a look at tape worms.
Tapeworms are.
That might be a tape worm that looks
like a long tapeworm.
But um,
do they need animal protein to stay
alive?
Is that true?
Or could they eat anything to stay
alive?
Seat.
There you go.
Take it to I.
I don't know if that's true like a.
let's find out if that's true because if
that is true.
Well first of all,
if you've got bugs and worms,
you got a problem.
Period.
Right now it's supposed to get worms and
just because you get sick because you
get worms and the worms have food to eat
because you eat a certain diet.
It doesn't mean you shouldn't eat that
certain diet.
You still have a fucking warm living in.
You've still got a warm and loving it.
Yeah.
You got to kill that thing.
Figure out how about those worms,
that breakout of your skin and that
would be a tapeworm massive tape.
Worn.
Discovered inside a man who complained
to the stomach.
Yeah.
That's an even different kind of warm.
That other guy had small.
I guess there's a gang of different
parasites you can get.
You can get it from raw meat.
Look at that,
but that is something to know.
Find out if that's true,
because if they can only survive in a
person that's eating a protein diet or a
high animal protein diet.
I don't know if that's true because
people got plenty of worms in southern
India where they were very.
They were vegetarians.
That's,
that's nonsense.
The worms were a fact of life for any
human being.
They're just parasitic date,
whatever.
Right.
They can get.
But that said,
if you're consuming animal protein,
it's probably another delivery
mechanism,
right?
Yes.
Food borne,
foodborne worms.
However,
there's also the fact that you grew
your,
your irrigated,
including your vegetables in human shit
and animal shit.
And you know,
as part of the fertilizer,
when that fertilizer got on a piece of
lettuce or something that was raw or got
on your hands and you ingest it,
that's how you get things like hepatitis
a.
that's how you get other,
uh,
parasites.
Yeah.
That's the apparently the biggest form
of Ecolab poisonings from salads.
That's right.
And that crazy just like,
or was it broccoli or sounds,
but it was a type of Ecolab.
Right?
So it's not just run off,
you know,
that was so ruined.
The salt and sea.
You do you know about the salt and sea?
Oh yes,
of course we do.
You mean the one in,
uh,
in Russia?
No,
no.
The salt and seasoned California.
They were calling it the inland Riviera.
California's inland Riviera in the 19
fifties.
It opened up the Colorado River and they
flooded this valley in California.
It's about,
it's outside of Palm Beach.
I'm not sure how far.
Maybe a couple of hours or something.
I'm not sure it desert though,
but it's in the desert and for a long
time,
meaning,
you know,
a couple of decades.
It was awesome.
So people partied there.
Sonny Bono and share how to fucking
house there.
They would boat,
they would fish and swim and there was
all these like beautiful vacation videos
like visit the beautiful Salton Sea,
Californias Inland Riviera greetings
from the Salton Sea.
So they filled that fucking place up
with water and there was tilapia in
there and people would boat and all the,
like the hip people from the 19 fifties
they would go to fucking party at the
Salton Sea.
It was just the spot to be right.
Yeah.
Then the runoff,
the runoff from all the pesticides and
all the farmers use all got in that
water and the die off is so the fish die
off that the white sands around the
shores in some spots are actually just
dead fish bones like that right there.
That is all that guy is standing on dead
fish bones because they're tilapia or
like particularly hardy,
and they were like one of the only fish
that can survive in that fucking
polluted cesspool.
Now really it's Sonny Bono.
Before he died,
before we went skiing and wacked into a
tree,
his goal was to find some sort of a
desalination and filtration method for
taking all the runoff and all the,
all the pesticides and bullshit out of
the salt and sea.
He wanted to try to clean it up.
It was like one of his ideas of what
does that.
You just showed us that before and
after.
No.
Um,
but it's,
um,
it's an amazing story.
It's an amazing story because they just
didn't understand what was going on.
What is the,
is it the LLC that was a,
the picture.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
That was a real legit see that the,
uh,
somehow environmentally we know the
Russians or whoever was in that area,
it's fucked up.
How did they do that?
Dried it up.
Yeah.
I can't remember the reason,
but it had something to do with
irrigation and farming I think,
and maybe I'm wrong.
When I was in Seattle a couple months
ago,
uh,
I talked to this gentleman who runs,
um,
there's this like salmon thing down
there where you can go underneath one of
the bridges and actually see the ladders
where the salmon pass through and you
could see the salmon swimming up the
river.
It's really fucking bad.
Yeah,
it's really cool.
Like you go under the river and these
are just wild salmon that are doing
their thing,
but you get to look at them through like
a window.
So they took something that happens
naturally anyway and they just gave put
a window so you can go under ground,
check it out.
And then they made it like an awareness
thing.
They showed the salmon,
we're,
which sort of accounts the fish as they
go through in some spots.
But this guy was saying that at one
point in time they had carved a channel
into this lake and connected this lake
to the ocean,
and as they were connecting this lake to
the ocean,
they fucked up and it drained,
uh,
these other waterways.
And so the salmon didn't have a way to
get back into the lake anymore.
And so they died in mass.
Just millions of salmon just piled up
and took the path they always take and
just died.
And Rod,
I don't know why she just had this
toilet,
this image of when you were talking
about all the salmon that died and,
but they're swimming in one direction.
I,
I had this image of all the actors come
to Los Angeles.
I would always feel that way sometimes.
I remember driving and traffic to an
audition or something,
and,
and I would always get this image of
being a salmon swimming up river.
And more importantly,
I didn't know what the.
I wasn't really sure what I was doing it
for.
The guy was like,
I wonder if I'm doing this,
so I can see if I can win at this.
Impossible game or do I really want to
be on set acting like what's really
going on and what is acting anyway and
why did I get into this in the first
place and who am I heroes?
Oh yeah,
De Niro and walk in and Chino and.
But then I know what they're really
doing and do I just want to be in the
movie and
be the guy in the movie or do I really
want to be an actor and why am I
spending so much time doing Jujitsu and
other things when I should be working on
my acting isn't interesting and if girls
weren't involved with I do it.
All right.
Those are
questions to lot to bring a lot to bring
out.
It's a lot to unbox.
It's hard to kind of get a on something
important to say.
Mick Westie bunk.
That video,
the warms.
It's not real.
It has nothing to do with me.
According to him,
there's a video of a three year old with
that many worms too.
Ah,
west is a smart man and mark to this
debunked that motherfucker,
so that doesn't make sense if it's
coming from a Vegan site.
Those are guys are always here.
Ron saw so added that it's what's shown
is called a worm Bolis,
but b,
o l u s,
he says it's an uncommon complication of
infection and has nothing to do with
eating lots of meat.
Yeah,
no,
it's an MC west.
He's brilliant.
He.
I met him when I did the Joe Rogan
questions.
Everything show and we were talking
about chem trails,
which he is worked really hard to try to
explain to people that are ultra
paranoid.
He calls them the training wheels.
They won't listen.
Conspiracy theories now,
they won't.
Won't listen,
but what?
What he had to say and what I saw from
the people that believe in them.
It's pretty obvious what's going on and
the problem with everybody freaking out
about these fucking artificial clouds
that are made naturally by jets as they
passed through the air with the moisture
in the air.
The problem with them freaking out about
that kind of stuff is the government
does do shady shit sometimes,
but you got to be able to differentiate
between what it's actually doing shady
shit and when it's just a chemical
reaction or just a natural reaction of
the superheated jet engine hits the cool
air and it creates this cloud.
I mean,
that's what it is.
They can,
you can,
you can do it right now.
You can go do it right now.
It's not hurting anybody,
but I,
I think,
uh,
my experience with people who are
conspiracy theorists is not so much that
they're looking for the truth.
I think it's a little bit more and I
want to be fair,
but I think it's,
I always noticed that they are more
interested in belonging to a club that
is in the know.
There's an identity attached to it,
so it no longer becomes really about the
search for see if you're,
if you're scientifically minded,
right?
If you,
if you're somebody who says,
I,
like Michael Shermer says,
I believe in the scientific method.
What that really means is you start with
doubt.
Doubt is always present because you're
always trying to prove what your
assumptions and your assumptions are
usually assumed to be wrong until they
are proven otherwise through trial and
error,
independent lines of inquiry that come
to the same conclusion.
All things being equal,
you know,
those are the things that we,
that is how we live.
I mean,
that's what the,
that was good.
It goes into the medicine,
the computer that you use and everything
else.
I mean there's,
there is,
there is a way to get to a result that
actually has tangible,
mathematical,
measurable reality.
Um,
and I think that conspiracy theorists
are as attached to being a conspiracy
theorist regardless of what that means
as they are,
as someone who would be,
I don't know,
it's an identity as opposed to a certain
for truth.
Well,
it's also like a default view.
Can't wait to default.
The default view is that it's a
conspiracy.
The problem with that default view is
that sometimes it's a conspiracy,
but if you're wrong,
a lot.
And conspiracy theories are wrong a lot
because they jump too quickly.
They jumped to conclusions too quickly
instead of actually looking at what the
fuck the facts are and then going,
okay,
well what's fishy about the facts?
All they do is concentrate on what's
fishy.
Right?
That's it.
They did try to narrow in on the one
thing that they think is the most fishy.
I don't remember these jet planes when I
was a kid.
I'm like,
bitch,
you don't even remember what call your
house was.
Okay.
You don't remember shit from when you
were a kid.
Of course you don't remember whether or
not there with lines behind jets,
but there's photos that show lines
behind Jack Horse and you show them
that.
They get those photos,
man.
Like,
come on,
this is.
I know there's a lot of shady shit the
government has done,
but this one has been tied up.
It's obvious with this.
Here's the problem.
When you pretend that those are clouds
and that these clouds that are coming
out of the back of these jets are some
sort of a chemical spray that the
government is launching indiscriminately
down on on civilization for mind control
or some nefarious purpose.
So whatever fucking nefarious purpose
that believe it's the worst,
it's the most obvious government program
ever because it's so ineffective.
Jack Shit like they.
It hasn't done anything.
People are living longer than ever.
Diseases are getting cured,
whether there they're more rebellious
than ever.
Everyone was for Bill Murray shirt on
and people would.
If Bill Murray was running for fucking
president right now,
people will vote.
They would vote for him.
Really awesome about the Internet and
about all of this is that I think like
all you hear lately and I agree,
is that the mainstream media is not
really a reliable source of truth
anymore.
They're not objective.
They're just not objective.
Look,
I don't,
I don't.
I don't like trump,
but I will admit that the New York
liberal media,
who I rarely agree with anyway has been,
has given him.
I'll fucking.
I mean he's not as.
He's his own worst enemy of course,
but there's no question that a lot of
it's either bought off or it's or it's
or influenced by by its owners because.
And influenced by the fact that it has
to be entertaining.
It can be for ratings,
but it's also not objective.
When I was watching Hannity on Fox News,
he wouldn't even let this woman get her
point of view out about Hillary and he
wouldn't.
He just kept interrupting.
So you know,
it's not about a discussion.
It's about pushing an agenda.
Exactly,
and I think what's what's to happen and
what has happened is you have things
like viceland and different independent
movements that are saying,
you know what,
let's get integrity back into journalism
because it's very needed and let's,
let's get out there and get real stories
that are going to take guts and let's do
some real investigative journaling.
I think they'll always be a marketplace
for that.
We want to know the truth.
We want the truth.
You're not going to have a full.
I know that Fox News
and CNN are give a lot of news to a lot
of people,
but I think as they continue to
discredit themselves with certain
behaviors,
people are going to be looking for more
advice.
Well,
they can't.
They can't fall back on that anymore
because they're the purveyors of truth.
You are the only ones here,
the only world purveyors of truth,
CNN,
Fox News,
NBC,
ABC,
CBS,
the big ones,
everybody that's putting out these
gigantic shows that are being viewed by
millions of people.
There's a small handful of you and if
you're full of shit,
it's a giant problem,
so if you're full of shit,
it doesn't matter.
All the good stuff that you do,
it doesn't really matter because you're
fucking us.
And I watched Fox News,
I watch CNN the other day and I'm going
back and forth between the two of them
and I would just watch one for now and
then watch what the other for now.
One of them just wants to talk about
nothing but sexual assault and they were
talking about how important it is that
we.
We don't use certain language in the
workplace and Don Lemon was telling
people's,
I've had Czech people have my personal
life and that amazing.
Just talking about gender,
it's about sexual assault,
but look,
the sexual assault allegations and
everything,
they're all serious,
right?
You don't want a guy who's a sexual
assault attacker who is in the White
House.
You don't want that,
nobody wants that.
Right.
But it's also important that you look at
all the fucking corruption that's been
shown about the Democratic Party,
but what they did to keep Bernie sanders
out the way they conspired.
Well,
Hillary Clinton and the Clinton
Foundation,
I mean there's the list of grievances
and corruption has been well documented
as a mile long.
It's almost like if I was Hillary
Clinton and I knew that I like,
there's a lot of dirt on me.
Like God damn,
I did some shady shit and now the
internet starting to expose my financial
dealings and these $250,000
speeches that she get to,
you know what?
I would wait to run against someone who
is so fucking terrible.
Someone's a horrible person and just
like maybe I could get donald to like do
me a solid.
And Donald's like,
oh,
I'll play it up.
Big Pussy grab and I'll say a bunch of
crazy.
She will leak some tapes.
It's not that far fetched almost.
You know,
talk about a conspiracy.
It was a Democrat,
you know that right?
Donald trump used to be,
I believe that's.
Well,
I don't think Donald trump was anything
but Donald Trump.
Ian,
I mean I.
I don't think that Donald Trump has an
ideology or philosophy because that
would require.
Oh,
he does.
He has an ideology and philosophy in
terms of what he can see in what he has
experienced and felt,
but if you're,
if you think Donald Trump actually has a
philosophy and an ideology that was
based on him sort of really thinking and
reading and take and stepping outside
himself,
reaching beyond himself,
you're out of your mind.
That's my problem with Donald Trump.
That's my problem.
Go to Morgan Murphys,
instagram page and pulled pork and
Murphy put this thing up today.
She's hilarious.
She put this thing up today about a
Donald Trump debating a scientist.
Put this up.
Oh,
it's,
it's.
He's just such a character like there's
never been a character like this running
for president.
I'm so torn like,
watch this.
Go fullscreen and press press place that
we get here.
Philosophy,
Maxwell's equations together in the
right way.
You'll get the velocity of waves moving
down in actual.
That's actually genius,
but here's he'll look at his facial
expressions.
He,
this is why I've started feeling like
life is fiction because his facial
expressions are literally what you would
see in a Dr Seuss book.
Like,
look,
he pulls his Chin in tight.
Look at that.
I don't mind any of that.
I actually find him.
I see all of that stuff that people talk
about.
Um,
I think to me is so a of minimal
importance.
Believe it or not,
there's so much of what he does is
actually entertaining and stuff like
that.
He talks,
he teases.
He's insulting.
If the guy was really up on issues,
if the guy,
if there was every,
any evidence,
he took advice,
just taking advice.
He can't take advice.
He didn't even prepare for the debates
at all.
You could see it.
He's just so off the cuff and I'll be
honest with you,
I'll be honest.
I'll be honest with you.
I think there's cheating going on and
she's broken and I'll collaborate.
Posey,
he's.
Someone needs to explain to him economy
of words.
It's super important,
but he doesn't know because he could get
to a position of like being a leader
like she like.
She's really good at that.
Her economy of words is excellent.
That's how her brain is organized.
His brain is not organized that way.
His brain is organized to be impulsive,
to be reactive.
If you to draw a picture of his brain,
like a side view of his brain?
Yeah.
How,
what percentage of it would just say
grab the pussy inside if you had to
break it up like wisdom health.
Like what?
What he's thinking about.
I think that the grab the pussy would be
much smaller than the part of the.
Brandon just said me,
you know,
that's my aunt.
She was a Democrat from 2001 to 2008,
2008.
He gave to John Mccain for president.
He gave to Hillary Clinton's campaign,
but then he was also as a real estate
developer.
He was very.
He was.
He gave to whatever political party was
going to get him the tax breaks he
needed or give them the favors.
He needed that.
That's really what you do.
I was secretly hoping that he was doing
all this asshole stuff running to get
the Republican nomination.
Then once you've got the Republican
nomination,
he would just completely.
I Quito,
the whole thing and Intel,
you know,
Hillary,
look,
I'm,
I'm going to be as reasonable and
rational as possible and I don't want to
insult you and I don't want to pretend
that things are any worse
than they really are,
but I believe that you're part of a
systemically corrupt system and I wanted
to just get to this position so that I
once now I'm here now I can just tell
you how I really feel,
but I feel like the system is broken.
It is and it's crazy.
It's crazy that we stick to it because
we could definitely come up with a
better one,
but we stick to it because it's old.
Well also though,
I,
I see,
I don't begrudge,
I don't like when people insult trump
voters and I'll tell you why.
I think there are a lot of trump voters.
I might be ignorant or not interested
in,
you know,
but I always,
I think it's unfair.
I think it's unfair to categorize
somebody who wants to vote for trump or
not vote for hillary.
I think it's very unfair and
condescending to consider them to be a
DM or a rednecks.
I think the problem with that is this,
Hilary Clinton is talking in very much
the same way and along the same
parallels that Obama did eight years
ago.
If you are a working class dude,
if you are somebody who has been left
behind through globalization and
through,
I guess just how the country is moving
technology,
so if you're a coal miner,
if you're A.
I don't know,
there are a lot of industries.
You are listening to this woman speak
exactly the way Obama did eight years
ago and your life has gotten worse.
It hasn't gotten better.
It's gotten worse.
Why in the world would you not?
Why in the world would out of
desperation would you not try this very
entertaining,
oh,
giant white guy who's,
who's got confidence,
who wants to break Washington apart and
who saying,
I'm going to make Washington.
I mean America Great.
Again,
it that that appeals to our emotions and
I don't think,
and I,
I do a lot of reading and stuff.
I don't think I would necessarily be
that different if I,
if I didn't know what else you take
acting and stand up away from me or
whatever.
What am I going to do?
Teach.
I don't know what I do.
Either way.
I would be pretty.
I'd be pretty desperate for a change and
I wouldn't be voting for Hillary,
but don't you think there's a giant
issue in,
in deciding that you're going to vote
for someone who says they're going to go
after someone and lock them in jail.
That's what a dictator done.
A set set of special prosecutor on her
and how?
Because if I was president,
you'd be in jail like she's,
she's,
but that's how it dictating him.
How a dictator dictator.
What do they always do?
When dictators coming to power,
their opposition gets locked up or
killed.
You can correct me if I'm wrong.
There's the president doesn't have the
power to do that.
You have the power to start some special
investigation on her.
The answer,
the short answer is yes.
The president can appoint an attorney
general,
uh,
from the Justice Department is on
attorney general,
I believe,
to investigate,
uh,
the,
special case.
Okay.
He could technically do that.
Wow.
That's not seem fucked.
You can.
She could do that to him too,
by the way.
Right.
It's,
it's much deeper than that because
Donald Trump will say things like this.
I,
if I told the generals what to do,
they would do it.
And I've always said we go in and take
the oyster.
You're paraphrasing.
I'm not phrasing that he actually said
that.
He said,
if I,
if I told them what to do,
they do it.
In other words,
hey,
I,
I know how to run the military.
Unlike these people he's had and our
general failed five deferments.
Well,
this is what I'm saying is that as a
dictator,
if he was in charge,
he didn't even know how that works,
but he really said that is what my point
is.
Yes.
He said many things like that.
He's such a,
he's such an obvious Megalomania may
megalomaniac such an obvious demagogue.
And,
and I don't,
and you're talking to a guy,
I don't like Hillary at all.
I think she's,
I think she's more of the same.
Yes.
But I think she's a corrupt human being.
There are a lot of examples of that.
However,
I'm not as uncharitable to say that I
think she's,
I don't think she's evil.
I think she has a vision for the world.
I think she wished she,
in her mind,
she believes she knows what's best for
the country,
but there's a difference because I think
she's willing to take big shortcuts to
gain influence and always has in her
career.
And uh,
and like what,
like what kind of big,
using influence,
using political influence to get what
she wants when,
when,
I mean,
if you look at the people that Clinton
pardoned,
I mean,
that part of scandal was the craziest
thing in the world would be.
Pardon Frank?
Rich,
take a look at the list.
Frank,
rich,
uh,
the,
he,
Hillary wanted to run for Senate in New
York and he needed certain counties and
he needed a large,
I believe,
Hasidic Jewish vote and he pardoned some
guy in a rabbi or somebody in there that
it was such a blur.
It literally,
I remember the democratic,
someone I think maybe was one of the
democratic pundents who said,
I don't know how you defend this.
It's just so obvious that he's trying to
buy his wife votes that he's trying to
buy influence.
And that was,
that's well documented.
I don't think a lot of Democrats would
disagree with that.
You know,
look it up.
Look up the uranium one deal.
That's just what they did.
One deal.
Who through Bill Clinton's influence,
this Canadian businessman bought the
cars like oil,
a uranium fields.
Well,
let's go one scandal at a time.
The first one,
did you find the first one?
Yeah.
The guy's name.
Mark richens Scott up before.
I think he was going to go down as like
the at the time,
largest tax evasion.
Oh,
that's right.
Time living in Switzerland.
He was prosecuting things right here in
the middle.
Yeah.
Hm.
Future.
He was a fugitive who fled to us during
his prosecution,
was residing in Switzerland.
He had $48,000,000
in taxes and was charged with 51 cases.
Accounts of tax was pardoned for tax
evasion.
He was required to pay a $1,000,000
fine and waive any use of the pardon as
a defense against any future civil
charges that were filed against him in
the same case.
Whoa.
Critics complained that Denise
Eisenberg,
rich,
his former wife,
had made substantial donations to the
Clinton library and Mrs Clinton's Senate
campaign.
What a surprise that Marc Rich,
who lives in Switzerland and you're
going to give him a pardon?
Do you think they're connected?
It was so blatant.
It was ridiculous,
but you can keep going with the pardons.
There are a lot of examples of that.
So to call Hillary Clinton,
not corrupt the uranium one deal.
God,
look that up.
What's that?
What's uranium?
Well,
well,
uh,
the,
Canadian businessman bought the Kazak in
Pakistan,
used to be a part of the Soviet Union,
a uranium fields.
Uh,
some of the,
some huge uranium fields,
I think some of the biggest in the
world,
uranium which you use to make nuclear
weapons,
oh shit.
And Bill Clinton helped him with his
influence,
a well documented influence,
help this Canadian businessman by those
uranium fields.
But here's the problem,
that Canadian businessman gave
$31,000,000
to the Clinton Foundation with a pledge
for 100 million more and he gave Clinton
a $500,000
check for speaking for a speech and then
$500,000.
Then when it came time for the Clinton,
for,
for the cars,
like oil fields to be sold to a Russian
company,
a Russian company that the State
Department and everybody else in our
intelligence,
he said,
our guys,
the Soviets are going to have a lot of
access to uranium,
some of the biggest reserves in the
world.
And this Canadian business has been sell
to a Russian company.
Um,
Hillary Clinton was secretary of state
at the time and she okayed that deal.
She was one of the people that had,
that had to give her.
Okay.
So now the Russians own a lot of that,
although those oil fields.
Oh,
and by the way,
look up the Russian,
the US Russian technology initiative
where we're.
One of the,
one of the movements is to have Russian
citizens in Russian.
I'm American citizens,
share technology,
share technology and technological sort
of ideas and stuff.
Um,
the problem with that is that,
that requires American investors.
Twenty eight of them were chosen,
were chosen.
Sixty percent were 60.
Oh,
I'm sorry.
And Hillary Clinton as secretary of
state was,
was spearheading that.
Of the 28 us partners that invested 60
percent gave to the Clinton Foundation.
Now come on now,
come on.
This is blatant stuff.
So we have to look at that.
You can't quit.
Great picture.
They got over it.
Could she look more guilty?
The report Russian government initiative
gave millions of dollars to Clinton
Foundation.
And what does that on while Clinton was
serving as secretary of state?
You don't think she knew that?
What's the website?
That's one freebie.
Kay was in the Wall Street Journal.
It's been well documented.
This is not.
This is not a conspiracy stuff.
This is every major publication in the
world would knows this and concur is
along the same lines,
the same story.
It's the same story.
They could,
they could print the same story.
It's not just what do they do with the
money?
Like what is the challenge here is the
money because here's the question that
she just recently got some crazy award.
Uh,
the
charity,
the Clinton Foundation received some
highest accreditation or it's a very
good car.
It's a very good question.
First of all,
be careful of those explanations.
Foundations have always been notoriously
corrupt and in every aspect including
getting high ratings,
but,
but there is no doubt that the Clinton
Foundation does a lot of good for
children with AIDS overseas for I think
things like malaria,
malaria nets,
they,
I think they even work maybe with the
gates foundation.
They do a lot of good stuff now.
There are a lot of reporters have
written about how it's a slush fund,
how it's used for other things.
I don't know anything about that and I
don't begrudge explained slush fund.
How would that mean they would take the
money from there and use it for their
own updates?
Flush look up slush fund.
I can give you.
I can give you a definition,
but for the most part it's.
I'm a slush fund typically would be a
place to put money that under the under
certain offices has said for this,
but it's actually used for other things.
A reserve of money used for illicit
purposes.
Especially political bribery.
Yes,
but you say,
but what you say is,
Oh,
this money is for,
you know,
curing this disease.
But it's used for other things.
So I asked him that might be unfair to
say that the Clinton Foundation's is
less fun.
That's what journalists,
especially from conservative newspapers
like Wall Street Journal will say.
Of course.
Yeah,
of course they're going to do that.
I mean,
what I was going to say earlier about
Tony back and forth between CNN and Fox
News,
it was one of the best examples I've
ever seen of the fact that they.
These guys are playing a game and this
is just the propaganda news network.
Now this is a propaganda news network
for the left and his propaganda news
network for the right and they're both
guilty guilty of both guilty.
No one's being honest about her.
No one's having this conversation that
we're having where we're saying,
look,
maybe wouldn't be the worst idea in the
world to get someone in there who's some
crazy rich guy who's this gigantic
figure that'll stir things up.
Like maybe like having a guy like him
would be a doorway to having someone who
has like some next level view of running
government and including people in the
process and,
and moving it away from this.
This,
the system is too restrictive and it's
too restrictive based on the times in
which it was creative.
The representative government model that
they needed in 1776.
It's a very different world today.
It's 2016.
I don't know.
I think that that the bigger culprit may
be less systemic like you're talking
about.
I actually think the bigger culprit is
the wrong ideas are starting to win the
day.
And here's what I mean.
Um,
if you,
let's just take the left.
Let's just take the hysterical left.
Uh,
and I think by the way,
I'm,
I'm more of a libertarian so that maybe
would make me maybe more swing.
We're both pretty left a lot of stuff.
Exactly.
I was about to say it was about to
categorize it.
That's the problem is these categories,
categories are
fucking stupid to.
It's super left on almost every social
issue on welfare,
on government programs to help
communities and boys clubs and girls
clubs and things along those lines.
You're making my point for me.
Exactly.
So when I say left,
what do I really mean when I say I'm a
libertarian?
What do I mean by that?
Because I'm not a total libertarian.
Right?
So here's a better way is exactly what
I'm trying to say.
Here's a much better way of establishing
sort of where you stand and rather than
say,
these people over here are wrong and
these people over here,
right?
Or these people are left to right.
What you're doing is categorizing people
and we know that people are all over the
place.
Look at you and I left this way.
I'm socially very liberal.
I believe in fair play.
I also believe in common sense.
I also believe in personal
responsibility.
That's where it gets weird.
You start moving right?
Isn't that interesting?
Well,
that's what happens,
but that's called.
That's called being occupying the entire
intellectual and emotional spectrum as a
human being.
What a surprise.
I'm a sinner and I'm a St Motherfucker
and a lot of times I'm in the joker,
joker,
and a smoker as well.
Come on,
midnight Toker.
Sometimes they don't want to run.
Fuck no,
I stand.
I.
I set my heels and I fucking Dr Steve.
Man,
I bought my own fucking tongue.
Whoa easy.
But here's the.
Here's the.
Here's a better way.
Here's,
here's the enemy,
not a person.
Here's the enemy.
It's this at one example.
It's this thought process.
We have a disenfranchised group over
here.
Let's call them transsexuals or let's
call them black people,
or let's call them women.
I can't believe you lumped all those
three people.
Well,
we do this with.
Let's just take.
Let's take.
Let's take the fact that women are
victims of sexual assault.
All right.
We've.
We've established that sexual assault is
first.
Let's define what it is,
but we know that for the most part it's
a problem.
It's a terrible thing when it happens,
right?
I'm talking about rape now.
Um,
there's,
there's a,
we know we want to solve that or make it
better or make women safer and make the
world safer.
I think what happens is a lot of times,
one group that one thought process in
solving that problem is as follows,
well,
let's find out who's doing the raping.
It's mad.
Um,
so what we're going to do is make it
better because we are going the way
we're going to make a bit as we're going
to take the power away from those men
and we're gonna get somewhere else.
And how are we going to do that?
Well,
there's only one way to do it.
You need a,
you need a big,
big,
powerful authority to actually be able
to enforce that.
You need laws and you need regulations
and union restrictions.
So the idea that by you will make
someone else who's not powerful,
more powerful by putting down people
that are already powerful by taking that
power away from them financially or with
laws as if that is going to make the
people who have been oppressed as it's
going to make their lives better.
I think that's a faulty way of thinking.
I don't think that empowers women.
I don't think that empowers black
people.
I don't.
I think rather personal responsibility
and making it so that that group can
figure out how to empower themselves and
the way you empower yourself is not by
taking power from somebody else.
I mean unless they were there,
you know,
a sadist and keeping you in a cage.
But for the most part,
I think that's a very important
distinction and discussion to have.
That's the discussion.
That's the debate.
I'd love to hear between CNN,
Fox,
but I don't.
Well,
I also think there's a big problem with
this right?
And left system in the.
You pick a side and you want that side
to win and it's,
it's,
it's almost like a civil war in America
every time.
The [inaudible] elections come up and I
think it's bogus.
I think the whole setup is bogus.
I think the distinction between the two
groups is bogus and I think we're so
used to having teams compete against
teams that we slide right into it.
I think what we really should be worried
about is who's,
you know,
there should be a set of things that
we're all worried about.
Who is ruining the party?
Who's,
who's,
who's doing terrible things,
who are they as it people that are
robbing people's that people that are
selling meth is the people that are
murdering people who's doing all,
who's ruining the party.
Okay,
well first we got to find them.
It might be the people that are driving
the narrative.
This is,
should be the.
This should be the entire focus of a
culture.
Okay.
Second of all,
where are the weak links in our chains?
Like we're.
How are these poor people supposed to
get by?
How were they?
They're born into poverty.
They're born into shitty parents,
like,
how do we fucking nip that in the bud?
So we have less people that are just
suffering through the emotional baggage
of being raised by fuckheads.
There are different.
There are different schools of thought
on that.
Right?
So that's what happens.
Yeah,
there are different schools of thought,
but let me keep going.
And then W,
W why?
Why the fuck would we fight Russia?
Like why are we in Afghanistan?
Why would we,
why would anybody do any of these
things?
Like at what point in time is it going
to be ridiculous for the idea of giant
groups of people to go over and try to
fuck up other giant groups of people
that are all in on it together for the
profits of some person who probably
doesn't give a fuck about you and is
super happy to let you go to war for
them so they can get more oil.
The same reason people argue the same
people that people.
The reason people have different points
of view.
The two party thing,
it's the two team thing.
It's the natural inclination that people
have to compete against each other.
Even on a global scale.
If it keeps ramping up,
I'm sure it works that way with like
billionaires that like they want to have
the biggest yacht,
like having a giant yacht.
It's not good enough.
They want the biggest yacht ever and
they keep competing against each other.
It's just isn't that.
Isn't that human?
Isn't that the human condition,
that conflict,
that need to impose your own?
Really,
you're on mark.
I don't know you.
If you would ever.
If you try to change that,
you're trying.
You're messing with human saints.
The problem is with having anyone being
a figurehead,
I think once you have who's a figurehead
and
that figurehead position becomes a
coveted position.
It's hard to get to.
It's very important.
It becomes a goal and once it becomes a
goal,
you're going to get the super
competitive people that are trying to
achieve that goal and then along the way
they start realizing that they can sell
influence and speeches and that Bill
Clinton got paid half a million bucks,
had talked to these people for an hour
and Hillary Clinton got 250,000
and talk to some bankers for an hour.
Like it's like there's so much money in
it that they start realizing like that
position carries with it an incredible
fiscal windfall.
It's called an economy of influence.
It's an amazing.
You know how Switzerland is ruled.
It's really interesting how they do it.
So they have a lot of different parties,
lots of different parties,
and the first three parties that when
are voted in,
they get to choose two presidents each.
Whoa.
And those.
And then the fourth party,
the party that comes in fourth place
with the fourth number of votes,
they get to elect one president.
So you actually have seven presidents
way better idea and not only have seven
presidents,
they all have regular jobs.
That's not their only job,
and so they meet,
they meet and they discuss legislation,
but guess what else?
Those,
those groups are the ones.
Those parties are the ones that elected
their own.
They're their own presidents.
Yeah,
but what do they have to worry about?
Oh,
someone's invading to steal our cheese
in our army.
Knives.
What's the great.
What's the great quote?
Who was descended?
Uh,
500 years of continual warfare in Italy
gave rise to the renaissance and 500
years of relative peace in Switzerland
gave rise to the cuckoo clock,
a beautiful clock.
And the chicks are hot.
Why build things when you can just fuck
all the girls that lived there because
they're just super hot.
Well,
this term onto something or does turmoil
create beauty and it may be.
What is innovation?
It's a form of destruction was beauty.
You know,
what's more beautiful,
peaceful day just overlooking a field or
the Vatican.
I have an answer.
I bet you're wrong.
Well,
do you know how the Greeks top man,
you're wrong.
You know the Greeks defined it in one
word that you enroll Jamie.
How becky?
You're fucking wrong.
What do you hold your breath and started
smelling trump?
What is trump's breath smell like?
You had to guess I can meet and for sure
a lot of flame and yon and they just
just meet and oppression and depression.
Wash and a wasp flies out.
Stinks you in the face once a little.
I don't know.
I bet you know what,
you know what the irony is?
I guarantee he'd be a fun guy to hang
out with.
He's a fucking blast.
For sure.
Use it.
He'd probably be one of my favorite
people even though Jeff Ross said he was
great when the,
uh,
they roasted them,
so it was great.
He said he even advised him to laugh at
the jokes about him and he's like,
you know,
it's like,
it's probably better if you laugh along.
Like you don't want people to think you
don't have a sense of humor.
And he's like,
you're right.
You're right.
That's great.
It's great.
I mean there's a,
he's a,
he's a great American figure.
He's,
well,
he's a,
I wouldn't say great in terms of like
the
overall influence that he's having on
people right now,
but as far as him being a great figure
in terms of like big,
he's a huge historical figure yet is on
an airline for awhile has been this
figure in this,
like this sort of a symbol of wealth,
but he's all.
It's also revitalized a lot of political
discussion
because I was forced to explain and
articulate and think about why he's
dangerous.
I was forced to look up words like
demagogue.
I didn't have to look that ladies and
gentlemen,
you know what I mean,
but I was forced to do all these things
and that in a way is good.
I mean that in a way you,
you to have somebody to go,
wait a minute,
wait a minute.
I,
I can't afford to be,
to not be politically committed right
now.
And here's another reason I don't like
Hillary.
The uranium one deal,
and here's the way there.
The reason I don't like trump,
at least it got me thinking and talking.
We're all talking about it and and
younger people are listening to podcasts
like this,
or at least listening.
Maybe they agree,
maybe they don't,
but hopefully both so that they can then
formulate their own opinion.
Eddie Bravo things.
We're going to war with Russia.
Alrighty.
Well,
Eddie's done a lot of the big fear.
The big fear in the conservative,
the conservative,
excuse me,
conspiracy theory world is this has been
explained to me that they think that
they're going to start a war with Russia
to distract us from the wikileaks
wikileaks revelations because there's
new ones that are coming out.
Apparently new wiki leaks.
Stuff's coming out and as if,
as if people don't have enemies,
everybody's anatomy in government.
They couldn't answer my question.
They cut.
Julian assange is a Internet connection.
What question was that?
How do you define beauty as one word?
Oh,
what is it?
It's what?
The Greeks and rambled for an hour.
I forgot what the fuck you suck.
I did.
Did Not wanna make sure Fran bold
Richard brambles.
Oh,
you're ready for it?
Yeah,
go ahead.
And this is how you define beauty.
How harmony.
Hmm.
Interesting.
So when you see a cheetah running,
why is it beautiful?
All moving parts,
all the parts and moving,
but if it's running it,
you're so beautiful.
It's horrible running at your kid.
Fuck you.
I get it.
If it's running at your kid,
is that beautiful?
Good question.
It's a horror show.
Beautiful beauty is without a doubt,
as the old expression goes in the eye of
the beholder.
Certain people like certain things,
certain people like certain kinds of art
that I find disgusting.
They love it.
They love certain kinds of music.
They love certain features on people.
They love certain looks.
As far as clothing goes,
it's whatever the fuck you think it is.
If it's beautiful to you,
it's ridiculous.
Anyway,
few physical beauty and the human being.
The difference between a person who's
cheeks are this wide,
like you know,
like five inches wide or seven inches
wide.
That extra two inches can make you look
like a fucking Weirdo.
Yes.
Symmetry,
symmetry and proportion.
I'm talking about just the way you look.
Not,
not that it throws you off because you
look at it,
the FIBONACCI sequence of a person,
like that's what happens when someone
gets a nose job,
you know if they have like a,
a naturally huge and they get that bitch
chopped down on something little will
look weird about their face to you
because your brain is used to looking at
things in a very distinct sequence.
The FIBONACCI sequence which exists on
nautilus shells and sunflower seeds and
all these different versions of it in
nature,
but it also you can use that sequence.
You can use that,
those measurements to show roughly what
a person's facial features will be like.
They're all kind of,
they say so when you surgically mess
with that?
Yeah.
You fuck with the whole outline of your
face.
That's like when you see someone and
their lips are way too big and their
mouth is stretched too wide,
so you know they've got started fillers
in the horn.
If it keeps going and some sort of a,
a,
a neck job where their faces pulled
back,
you're.
You're immediately like your math is off
on them.
Like you're looking at them,
you're like my math off.
Like,
why is,
why are your lips so big?
Like this isn't dogs I think will be
like I've seen my neighbor used,
do a lot of below.
My dog would flip the.
She'd come and go,
hey,
what's going on?
In my thought was like,
oh,
get the fuck away from me.
Like my dog immediately knew some shit
was wrong with the way she was moving a.
But that's someone who on coke,
she was probably aggressive to your dog
too and you're wearing around.
She's probably maybe,
or she was just talking with my dog was
like,
I don't like this fucking person maybe,
but I'm what the fuck we were talking
about,
we're talking about.
And then we got to do something before
that.
Clarity and how beauty is beauty is
dictates contextual,
right?
It's weird how like,
there's certain things if people just
decide or beautiful and there's certain
things that are beautiful to certain
people that just don't resonate with
others at all,
you know?
And certain people or certain looks.
You know,
there's guys that are legitimately into
morbidly obese women.
Yeah.
Really enjoy it.
That's what's at new podcasts would
disagree.
I listened to that podcast and Gad said
was talking about how even congenitally
he went through a whole litany of
reasons why hip to waist ratio and
breast size and all that stuff and,
and uh,
symmetry and proportion are biological
triggers for men and the idea that there
isn't a standard of beauty that turns on
men in general.
So,
you know,
and that's what I'm saying,
there absolutely is of course,
but there's certainly upset exceptions.
Yes,
there is a giant SPEC.
That's why some guys are gay because
that's their,
that's where they fall into the
spectrum.
Their,
their,
their beauty to them,
what they're attracted to his men,
you know,
and there's gonna be certain versions of
men that are attracted to all kinds of,
some kinds are attracted to giant lemon
that can carry them around.
Do you remember our crum?
I shared to hearsay.
Sad documentary is amazing.
Great.
I knew about him because our neighbors,
when I was a kid,
you know,
my parents were hippies.
We live in San Francisco from a age
seven to 11.
I lived in San Francisco and we had
these crazy neighbors.
He's gay guys.
My aunt used to smoke pot,
go next door and they would go get naked
and play bongos together.
This guy was black as the sky on a,
on a moonless night and he would get
high as fuck
and take all his clothes off and he was
gay and his boyfriend,
they would live together and they would,
they would all just get naked and play
bongos together.
My aunt would go down there and get
baked with them,
but anyway,
they had these comic books.
They had our crum and there was the
first time I was ever exposed to our
crump.
Weird guy.
Well No,
they would carry him.
Oh,
that's right.
Had giant legs,
enormous classes.
They looked like avatar.
Women like they didn't even look like
they were real powerful.
So he was,
he was into like,
like see,
like he's got this all this power
illuminating office,
woman's giant legs and she looks like
what you would see today,
like from some crazy mega crossfit type
chick,
like their big muscular legs.
That was what he was into.
I wonder if though those kinds of
examples are.
First of all,
I wonder.
I think everybody though,
regardless of what your aberration,
you're a perversion fetish is whatever
you want to call the word.
I think though that that still doesn't
mean that they don't and can't recognize
what would it be considered harmonious?
Yeah,
but it doesn't matter.
Like I tell her,
obviously he keeps taking drawing photos
of these girls with giant legs and giant
muscles and it says back that off a
little so I could read the how to have
fun with a strong girl.
I stand before,
before her trembling with anticipation.
Then she struts and prances around the
room,
boldly displaying her magnificent
physique.
She's full of narcissistic pride is
obviously enjoying the effect she's
having on me and it's him.
Our chrome,
who was just nerdy looking guy and he's
got boxer shorts on with a boner and
socks and his hairy legs.
Really hilarious writing and hilarious
artwork and that was what he was all
about.
It was all this weird perverted shit.
So I got exposed to this stuff when I
was like,
shit,
I guess I was like eight,
somewhere around eight or nine.
I was like,
what the fuck is going on?
Why is this guy into like giant women?
Like,
what the fuck is this?
Yeah.
And he had a bunch of different like
characters that he would,
uh,
draw and all of these weird comic books.
But,
you know,
it's,
yeah,
there's a girl at a giant in,
you know,
what's really weird her first day in the
city.
I mean this is,
I saw this kind of stuff when I was real
little.
Okay.
Well how do you explain this?
So for me,
look at the,
all that asshole hair.
It's amazing.
It's such a good piece coming out with
his nose in the air.
Um,
I,
I don't,
I don't know if that messes with my
head.
What does that title that's going to be
my next tattoo?
My first tattoo.
Her first day in the city.
If you're looking for it,
Google that original art crumb.
What does it say?
The rest snatches snatch comics.
Is that the snatch?
So he had a lot of vagina base.
He's stepping into her vagina and he's
looking around.
He's looking around at this.
Notice that giant vagina.
He's about to step to step into it.
Gosh.
Contract type hood.
Sure.
Get a type could sure get last round
here and not to step into her vagina.
Looks like a chicken.
Looks like I'm a tunnel.
Here's hoping.
Take City woman been.
Oh my God.
It's a metaphor.
But here's,
here's the thing that's confusing.
I am very attracted to crossfit.
Very muscular women.
I think that's hot,
right?
So I'd love to have one that can beat
your ass.
Nope.
I just like that power in the legs and
like a message you'd like them to
underestimate you and you without russel
them.
Is that your move?
I mean that has been in the past,
but that's less.
What's interesting.
I think when I see a crossfit woman,
like a woman who's just got a blow out
ass and powerful legs and all that and
uh,
back on her,
maybe I want to breed with our swipes.
So maybe primarily I want to be with
her.
So my kids are studs,
but I just find it physically very
attractive.
When a girl's got to an asset,
you should find our chrome.
He lives in Paris,
which you could hang out.
You could just jerk off together.
Well,
hold on because you're drawing Sarah.
Hold on,
hold on sir.
Because then there's the other side of
me that likes a super feminine,
petite,
curvy woman and that might be who I'd
rather cuddle with and date.
Whereas the other one I just want to
have animal sex with and so there's
this.
I'm kind of pulled.
Yeah.
Welcome to being a man.
Motherfucker.
Why you making this sound like it's a
big complicated issue.
Oh Man.
I'm just saying I have to say maybe I
just like all different kinds of went
over you.
This is what I'm into.
I like my shakes in white chicks.
Maybe there's a problem.
You're right.
What I'm saying is I'm attracted to
everybody.
Well,
that's part of the problem with being a
man is a genetically.
You're designed to spread them jeans
around as much as possible to ensure the
survival of the race.
However,
that's not really necessary anymore.
Like we used to die really young.
We were eaten by things left and right,
so we have this fucking insatiable
instinct to fuck all the time and get
rid of loads and make people,
but there's a lot of us now,
like we figured it out somewhere along
the line,
but we still have the genes of people
that live 10,000
years ago when your survival,
it wasn't guaranteed at all and it was
most likely that something would go
wrong and so the,
the likelihood of you staying alive past
30 or 40 was very low,
so there was like a frantic urge to
live.
Yeah.
You know,
I think if we knew that we had way less
time and that it was,
the death was way more common.
If we start 10 year olds will be walking
on pregnant.
Yeah.
And that's how it is normally.
I think we decided some someone roll on
the lawn,
rightly so.
That's not,
that's not healthy for our species.
It's not healthy for our culture.
It's not healthy for children to be
burdened down by the responsibility of
being a parent.
While they're still trying to figure it
out and they'd probably do a way better
job if they waited,
so all that stuff is sort of balancing
itself out now because people are
becoming more and more aware of it,
so we don't,
but we're still.
We still have the same genes,
so the same fucking caveman genes.
The genetics have to be like constantly
managed by the psyche,
constantly managed by discipline,
constantly managed by thinking,
you know,
whether it's yelling at somebody in
traffic or whether it's all the other
ridiculous male instincts that people
have to,
whether it's a star wars or to kick
their ass because they're rooting for
the wrong team and all that stuff is.
It's based on like these ancient reward
systems that we've got stuck in our
pilot.
Things like excitement.
It can be really weird things secretly
for excitement and ideas to get charged
up.
Yeah.
Being not as good word,
a naughty bus.
The naughty list.
Pernod is huge because my friend,
when I was with my buddy one time and
this giant woman giant a big Oh my God.
No,
I'm not joking.
Three hundred pounds.
Gabby Garcia big.
Yeah,
but,
but curvy are way more.
Have giant tits.
Jaimee.
She was every bit of six foot five.
Oh my God.
I'm not exaggerating with her shoes off.
I'm not kidding.
Oh my God.
Uh,
I'll tell you later.
I think you should be.
You're asking more detailed with this
story that everyone thinks she can beat
your ass.
There's,
she could eat me as a whole.
I mean,
I never had to fight for your life.
If you were in a hotel ballroom,
you got locked in there with her and
she's coming full clip.
She has.
This is for real.
She had no training.
Uh,
maybe I could tie her out,
but I'd have no.
The answer is probably not.
Wow.
Fuck her up.
She'd come get some.
You.
She's,
you're ready.
You're ready to get low.
If a giant woman,
I'll tell you right now,
there is a giant.
There is a size where that a woman would
hit where you.
Regardless you.
There is that number.
How tall,
how heaven can't hear this.
Just bet on me,
dude.
Really?
I'm gonna kick her ass.
No woman from ever getting into a street
fight with 350 pounds,
six foot five woman,
no woman on the planet.
I'm going to kick her out.
So she's there,
she's there and I and I,
and she says hi.
She recognizes me and I go,
oh,
I'm kidding.
Big giant women.
Don't try to beat me up.
These are just jokes.
These are all just silly woman.
Leave me the fuck alone.
Don't hurt me.
Just a bunch of waiting outside the
door.
Motherfucker.
She has a beard.
He sure you're a woman.
I'm just,
dude,
I know shot,
uh,
an antelope or some,
some animal in Africa that was a
Hermaphrodite knew it was a female
animal.
Antelope with crazy horns like these
crazy antlers that like curved in some
weird way.
We're actually digging into its head who
was actually a call animal.
They had to put it down because it's the
way its horn was growing.
It was like literally growing into its
head.
Oh Damn.
It was comfortable.
It was a very weird case.
And they also,
I guess they wanted to study its body
because they were pretty sure it was a
hermaphrodite wow.
Yeah,
that's a weird fucked.
Again,
all those genetic aberrations happened.
Yeah.
I was talking to this woman from South
Africa recently at this party.
I told you the story about all the kids
that um,
or
she grew up in.
She lives in South Africa for awhile and
it's really funny because she was
talking about mountain lions and now how
hilarious it is.
The people are worried about mountain
lions.
We would have to worry about that.
Rely on water.
Buffalo snakes,
all the above.
All of the above.
Um,
but she was talking about a kids in
silicone valley that are having problems
dealing with their,
they're hyper successful parents and the
lack of time and attention that's being
paid to them.
And there's like a gigantic epidemic,
suicides and all kinds of crazy shit.
They're cutting each other.
And it was a really disturbing
conversation.
And she called it,
what they call,
what they call it.
Affluenza.
You know,
that's the term for young rich kids.
But the thing is like nobody cared,
like they didn't ask to be rich,
but we blame them for being rich.
So like you don't look at a young rich
kid as like a young kid with problems.
You Go,
Oh,
poor rich baby,
you know,
like that somehow now that the money
that these kids have when they're 16,
they have a fucking fresh BMW.
The money that money provides connection
and love and,
and,
and that you mean something to your
parents because it's so unattainable for
so many folks.
Money and being rich like one of these
kids seems like,
well they hit the lottery.
I'm supposed to feel bad for them.
But you don't realize that like they
didn't ask for that.
First of all,
they didn't ask to be born that.
And it's not ideal.
It's not working out well.
You'd be way better off with a happy
healthy parents that were around and
went to your sports events and hung out
with Ya and did things with you and,
and were there all the time and gave you
a feeling of comfort while you're
growing up.
So you can grow up with like a sense of
security,
like there's a lot of these kids that
are grown up,
they are all fucked up because their
parents are never around.
So you don't feel like you matter or you
don't feel in many ways you feel like
you were thrown away and rampant drug
abuse,
man.
The amount of kids that are doing pain
pills today as apparently just off the
charts,
they're doing adderall for studying and
for for examinations and they're doing
pain pills all the time.
It's just become an epidemic with
people.
They're so fucking easy to get.
I know they're trying to curb that.
I try to make it more difficult to get,
but there's still a ton of money that's
being pumped into the system from the
manufacturers of these,
as you were talking about before,
about the use of influence and in
politics.
The company that makes fentanyl is that
I said I never figured that out.
So fentanyl,
they spent a half of a fucking million
dollars on ads in Arizona just to try to
make medical marijuana illegal.
Try to make it to to to do ads against
them in their recreational,
like why would they give a fuck?
Why are they doing that?
Like why would,
why would the makers of a pill like
Google that too?
Because it's another thing I keep
wondering about how much stronger is
that shit that oxycontin because it's
much
stronger.
Thought it was an elephant tranquilizer.
I maybe I'm wrong.
I don't know that what they were putting
in the heroin and everybody was dying.
Okay.
They that,
that I think is an elephant.
Tranquilizer,
fentanyl,
whatever it is.
I don't know if it's an elephant
tranquilizer they use on the elephants
and people,
but they definitely use it on people.
It was something to be stronger right
then then,
then,
then I don't know.
We're trying to find that out.
I think at least I remember the number.
inverse.com.
It looks like an okay story written on.
It says it's 80 times as potent as
morphine.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
Which is 80 times of times the animal
analgesic punch of heroin.
Well,
Jesus said,
there you go.
That's got to be good.
Yeah.
Well,
this is what people are dropping dead
off and the company that makes that shit
is trying to put out ads or pay for the
campaign against marijuana being
recreationally legal,
which is just fucking crazy.
It's crazy.
You know?
I know that they think that they're
going to lose profit from marijuana
being legal,
so I know that they're acting out of a
business purpose.
It's that's just what businesses do,
but you just expect them on something
that's so fucking important culturally
and such an important precedent like
that.
Any company that's against marijuana
becoming legal,
that is such a damaging position to take
and if you get away with it today,
by the time people examine this and by
the time it's looked back on five,
10 years from now,
whatever it is,
you're gonna look preposterous,
that you spent any money to try to make
marijuana illegal reason.
I think no reason why anyone should step
in and try to make it illegal.
It's the will of the people and there is
no medical evidence whatsoever that
shows that it's even remotely as
dangerous as a million different things
that are already illegal.
But that's,
see,
that's another,
that's sort of another example of what I
was talking about before,
which is that you can try to legislate
and pass laws and enforce sort of your
view of reality of World War,
what you think is good for people,
but what's it seems to me a better way
to go is to win the idea,
what do the idea that marijuana is not
as destructive.
For example,
in many ways I'm not an expert,
but in many ways to say alcohol,
which is legal.
Well,
it's just.
You don't even have to say I'm not an
expert.
It's absolutely scientifically proven
fact,
but that act.
But that took time to not only be sort
of enough experiment just in real life
and real time started to prove that to
be true,
but then that idea and that experience
had to dissipate into the national or
international collective conscious.
Part of that was because of Richard
Nixon,
Richard Nixon funded study.
They put studies together to try to find
out what are the bad things about
marijuana.
They couldn't find anything.
No.
This is way before that when reefer
madness was in 19 thirties,
the the shit that Nixon did,
Nixon pass a sweeping set psychedelic
act of 1970.
That made everything scheduled.
One those dmt and mushrooms and all that
shit and that Nixon did and yeah,
it was during his administration and
they also.
One of the things they did was they did
these studies on marijuana trying to
find things that were bad.
They couldn't,
and when the studies came up with
favorable results,
they buried them.
And this is also been proven,
so this is shit they knew for a long
fucking time.
It's just a team thing.
It's going back to that same thing again
is pro and con.
There's,
there's,
you know,
right and left and even along this
marijuana thing,
there's a bunch of people that are
scrambling to try to keep it illegal as
long as possible.
So that continues their profits with
painkillers.
Painkillers are worried that if
marijuana becomes legal,
if marijuana,
especially edible marijuana,
which is incredibly potent but doesn't
have any of the fucking downsides,
doesn't have any of the negative
effects.
No one's dying from it,
which is the biggest one,
right,
and it's been shown to help so many
people with seizures,
so many different diseases.
People that have aids,
people that are on chemotherapy is
hundreds and hundreds of different
things that it's been shown to help with
people with,
um,
uh,
what is it?
I'm glaucoma.
What is that for the ocular pressure,
international ocular pressure,
relieved that it's amazing for
inflammation for people that have back
problems and all sorts of other issues
regarding pain and inflammatory issues
that people have,
but these are the things that would
profit from keeping it illegal are the
same things to killing people and the
idea that they're allowed to do that and
that no one steps in and no politicians
talk about it being huge,
evil,
and a real problem.
It's one of the things that's left
completely off the debate.
It's not to diminish sexual assault
because obviously that's really
important.
It's not to diminish primary,
obviously that's really important and
those pay to play stuff and all these
accusations of corruption on both sides.
It's all very important,
but man sows that love.
That is.
And also learning how to distinguish and
learning,
learning how to distinguish what you
should label,
for example,
a psychedelic or.
Well,
not,
not just that,
but sometimes I wonder if if when you
call for the legalization of marijuana,
which I would do,
of course,
and I've always said that ultimately
it's all about letting people make their
own choices,
but I wonder if it's important to
distinguish between drugs,
like do you think that it certainly is.
Heroin and cocaine should also be legal.
I think as an adult,
as you Brian Callen the idea that me as
me,
Joe Rogan could tell you you can't do
heroin is preposterous.
Who the fuck am I?
Who am I to tell you?
Well,
you can do it under a doctor's
supervision or you could do morphine.
You gonna have to have a morphine drip.
You have a button.
You're pressing.
The morphine goes into your bloodstream.
Man,
I don't know.
All
I know is a lot of fucking people are
dying from pain pills and politicians
never discuss it and why don't they talk
about it.
Just stop and think about is is is the
big issue of one super rich guy who was
a pussy grabber or is the big issue half
a million people dying from cigarettes
in this country alone every year?
Is that an issue?
How come at issues and discuss if there
was something else that was killing half
a million people a year,
wouldn't we freak out?
I agree.
100.
If there was some new sport would have
parked.
Core was claiming a half a million kids
every year saying that are saying the
bigger,
more challenging issues than a guy who
is a groper.
I would imagine roper.
I think it's terrible to be a groper.
I think it's certainly something that
should be discussed.
That's not the problem.
The problem is they're not discussing
this other thing.
No,
they're not discussing how many fucking
people are hooked on painkillers.
It's giant,
massive epidemic and the idea that the
same people that are selling those
painkillers are actively working to make
sure that marijuana stays illegal.
He lets you know that you're in a crazy
system when the protectors and the
politicians don't bring that up at all
because who's driving the narrative?
Think about who's driving.
Think about drive and then the people
who are driving,
driving the narrative in the,
for example,
in the lip,
in the New York liberal media,
right?
That is why is it academics were
academics and why is academia?
Why is that driving the narrative on
everything from gender to even social?
Why?
Because we don't live in the real world.
We assume they're the smarter ones,
but they're they.
They have theoretical knowledge and I
think there's a place for academics and
I think there's an obvious place for a
strong intellectual energy,
but my God,
there's nothing.
There's no group more intolerant to new
ideas in many ways.
I would say religious people were far
more intolerant than academics.
I would think that academics on a whole
would probably be very tonal pens.
They just lean left.
They just leaned left almost,
almost exclusively,
except when it comes to like economic.
I don't think they're tolerant at all.
I think they suffer from collective
madness,
in fact.
Well,
gender mania,
I think.
Look at,
look at.
Look at this.
Let's take trump.
I actually resent the fact that first of
all,
obviously I've never been a fan of this
guys,
but I resent the fact that people seem
to be equating equating a groping and
even even a kissing somebody or talking
about it as rape,
sexual assault to a woman,
a woman who doesn't want it.
If he comes up and grabs you on the
poster is sexual assault.
I would agree with that,
but that is one of the accusations,
right?
Well,
I want to distinguish between what is
that sexual misconduct?
Is it sexual assault?
What is,
what is the girl loves it.
Then it's neither like if she,
if she pulls her panties to the side and
he goes,
oh daddy goes down it and like you found
a freak,
right?
You know,
but he took a big fucking chance where
you just grab the pussy.
She probably asked,
well you're an asshole.
She probably just say,
hey,
you're thinking about grabbing your
posts.
You're here.
What do you think?
Want to think about it for awhile?
I'll be out here waiting.
You've got to give her time to.
And not under pressure.
You don't want be looming over was a big
guy.
So he asked the Lord lawyer show.
I think these.
These are really important distinctions
because otherwise people that are a
woman who's held down.
Let's just take a terrible example,
a woman,
a stranger,
breaks into your house,
holds you down and rapes her,
right?
We would all agree that that is,
that is fucking horrifying,
right?
And if you've found the guy be hard not
to kill the guy and all that stuff,
but,
but let's make it.
Let's make a distinction.
Ready?
A big bully.
A guy like trump comes up,
grabs you and,
and,
and puts his fingers in your mouth.
That's pretty.
That's pretty invasive.
So hot.
That's fucking evasive.
And you're and you work for the guy and
you're scared to lose your job.
And he grabs you and he puts his finger,
came out and he goes,
come on baby.
Give me a kiss.
And because you're so afraid and so
overwhelmed,
you don't know what to do,
and he starts kissing you and you're
like,
oh Jesus,
let this be over with.
I'm sure that's happened 1 million times
in life with women.
And this is why women when they see that
shit,
they go,
I've met a guy like that.
I've been 10 guys like that.
And that's why the reaction for women is
like,
fuck this guy.
He's going to fall by 14 points.
However,
let's as as citizens and in this
discussion in the law,
you have to make a distinction.
Even the media,
because if you start calling that rape
or if you start calling that sexual
assault versus,
I don't know,
sexual misconduct or I don't know.
Wait,
hold on a second.
If somebody grabs you and kisses you and
you don't want them to do that,
it means that is.
It is a form of assault.
Not Assault punching you in the face,
but it should be illegal to hold you and
detain you and like and forced a kiss on
you.
Like you're violating that person's
physical space.
You're violating their humanity because
you're choosing to enforce your wants
and needs over what they want.
Budget.
Would you equate this problem?
Fucking,
you know,
and I know that there have been times in
people's lives when someone has grabbed
a woman and kissed her and she loved it
and they want up getting married and
having kids.
Yes.
You never fucking know who the hell
knows?
I mean like no one wants sexual assault,
right?
No one wants anyone to have anything
done to them against their will.
No one does this rational or kind in a
way,
shape or form.
But we all know there's crazy moments in
life,
right?
You know,
there's weird things happen with people.
People had sex without saying a word to
each other.
Dan Bilzerian was just talking about the
other day.
Sure.
He met some girl in Paris.
He purposely went out of his way to not
say a word,
see if he could do it and had sex with a
girl.
There's no consent there.
It's just implied consent based on
physical movement.
So,
so,
so.
So in other words,
still,
but my point is yes,
but my point is do you shouldn't compare
worst versions of rape and say that this
version of what you would call sexual
assault is not that big of a deal,
but you're kind of saying that by saying
that you're calling it why call,
but you're diminishing the horribleness
of the other people's experiences by
actually getting physically raped and
well,
the nights of their neck and getting
fucked by a book,
there has to be a difference right
there.
Has,
there is a difference that the physical
action is different in every single one.
I mean it's,
it's,
it's different in a girl gets pulled
over and the cop makes her suck his dick
get out of a ticket.
People have done that,
right?
That's,
that's a different thing than,
than uh,
than a girl who grabs her a male
employees dick all the time.
I mean,
that's a,
that's unwanted and he doesn't want to
lose his job,
but that's not as threatening.
How about this?
There's a bunch of different
experiences.
My point in her,
like anyone who's been grabbed,
that doesn't mean that I mean by by,
by saying that it's not as bad as
getting raped.
That's like saying,
yeah,
of course it's not as bad as gang raped
and murdered.
It's not as bad as getting raped and
murdered and they make you eat yourself
before they kill you.
It's going worse and worse and worse
saying is that I feel there's a
movement,
a movement to have to treat all the
perpetrators of that kind of behavior as
one.
And I think that's what standards.
So for example,
you have a guy who meets a girl.
She does,
you know,
she drinks 15 Margarita's,
uh,
you guys making out.
You're dancing.
Uh,
you go,
he follows her.
I don't know what happens.
Next thing you know,
somebody sees her.
He's on top of her making out with her
and he's fingering her and she was out
cold.
She's cold,
she's holding the.
Hold on,
hold on.
Now.
We now in California,
that's not considered rape.
Somebody had to sit down and go,
what's rape?
Let's define it.
Fingers in the mouth,
fingers in the vagina or penis in
vagina.
We got to make these definitions and the
law,
the law tends to make very strong
distinctions,
knows distinctions have been thought
about and fought over and stuff like
that.
And then we,
we penalize people accordingly.
Okay.
However,
it seems to me that in,
for example,
on certain colleges,
they now have investigative committee
committees,
investigative communities who decide
whether or not this was sexual assault
or whether or not this was rape,
where I think actually that should be
anytime there's sexual,
you know,
assault or rape,
shouldn't that be the police's job?
Shouldn't that be reported immediately
to the police?
And isn't that,
isn't that
or jurisdiction where there's a lot of
lawsuits based on the,
you know,
the Occidental College one,
that one where a guy and a girl were
exchanging text messages.
Uh,
she says,
uh,
you bring condoms?
He says,
yeah,
I got condoms.
Okay,
they're ready to get laid.
She says,
uh,
she texts,
her friend says,
I'm about to get laid.
They have sex,
and he gets kicked out for sexual
assault because he's drunk.
And she's drunk so he gets kicked out of
school,
she stays in the school and he's the,
he's the perpetrator.
But meanwhile there's so much evidence
that they're both just young kids who
got drunk and fuck.
There you go it into a life and his life
is ruined.
Let's.
He's suing the shit out of him and I
hope he gets enough money so I can live
in a Jay z video for the rest of his
life.
Fuck them.
You know,
like look,
every like any God damn person who has
ever been 18 or however old these people
were and been away from your parents for
the first time and been drunk and hooked
up with a girl like you,
you,
you don't know.
There's nothing evil going on there.
This is like two people that want to be
together to get together.
Like to call that rape in any way,
shape or form is.
That's crazy.
Well,
how about,
how about this though,
but see that,
I agree with you,
but that's so different than pussy
grabbing,
man.
Pussy grabbing and pushing people up
against the wall and kissing him.
That is way more a salty sea.
That's way more violation of your
physical space.
Gray.
See,
like if a big guy did that to me,
if a big guy just grabbed me and kissed
me and be like,
oh my God,
motherfucker,
what do I do?
I don't want this guy to kill me.
You know,
it's some giant seven foot tall,
350 pound dude wants to kiss you.
That's what it's like.
I'm sure a woman and a guy like trump
grabs you.
That's right.
Now,
if you're a dude and you're into having
big dudes grab you and kiss you,
you like fucking bonus.
I nailed it today.
But I'm saying that if there is a
movement to again,
that the enemy is.
There's a movement to lump all behavior
under the same sort of dark.
See,
I don't think there is,
man.
I think there's a movement to make
people more aware of behavior like that.
Hold on.
How about this?
This is where I think things get crazy.
A woman has sex,
she gets drunk,
she has sex with a guy,
and then she speaks to somebody who says
you were drunk.
Um,
and do you have regrets about it?
I have regrets about it.
Well,
if you have regrets then that that's
rape.
Now somebody says that to her and she
goes to a committee in her school who
does an investigation and now you're
being investigated because this girl has
regrets.
Six months later,
this is where,
in my opinion,
madness starts to this very scary.
It's very scary because now you've got
have mob mentality over there.
It's all he's hearsay the guy.
The worst thing that can be branded as a
sex criminal.
My God,
I ruined your whole fucking life and
it's easy to get.
The distinction you have to do is have
one person who hates you,
accuse you of.
There you go.
Bam.
So now what?
So,
so I'm just saying we better start
making these distinctions are mines
forget that.
That's where the white nights will step
in and say what is most important is
women safety.
And if I have to be wrongly accused,
I had a conversation with a guy who
actually said that on a podcast.
He said that if,
if he was wrongly accused,
that he would be happier with that than
with a woman facing some sort of sexual
assault,
which is this first of all,
as if they're in any way,
shape or form connected.
Personally,
it goes back to my point,
wrongly accused means you have a shitty
system and someone lied like it
shouldn't.
That shouldn't be the case at all,
but that it shouldn't be an option.
That goes back to my point.
You're not gonna.
You're not going to liberate women by
falsely accusing.
Men were so.
This guy's like signing up to be the
diminished party signing up to be the
more vulnerable parts.
I'll take the hit,
take the hit.
I'm a white knight.
Yeah,
it is a light,
but it's also not happening to him when
he's talking about it because it was
happening.
You'd be freaking out screaming your
innocence from a rooftop yelling about
how you used to be a feminist because I
can't believe this is happening because
10 injustice.
Yeah,
it is an injustice,
but there's a gang of injustices there.
The grabbing and the pussy grabbing,
that's an injustice to write.
It's just like what's.
Where's the level?
And I think one thing as men that it's
easy to think of is,
is it's,
it's easy to forget that when you're a
chick,
there's a whole nother element when
you're dealing with men and that element
is size,
strength,
and even though violence is five,
highly unlikely in any work place
scenario,
you still feel like if you're.
Your body knows that if the shit went
down,
Donald Trump could choke you to death.
Yeah.
Don't,
don't you think your body would know
that?
Not only does your body know that,
but women all around you.
If he grabbed you,
he's bigger than you.
You know that,
right?
Yeah.
He grabbed you in wanting to kiss you
and just grabbed you and kiss you.
Would that be assault if he grabbed you
and him alone?
He grabs you,
grabs you.
Package.
Yeah,
and he shoved his tongue down.
Usually pins you up against walls.
That assault.
Yeah.
I beat his ass though.
What of your heart?
God got me confused.
And what does he smell?
Good does he,
does he have trump breath?
I think,
I think you're totally right about these
committees in campuses and universities
and I also think there's a real problem
and telling young kids are victims when
they might not necessarily be victims
that you know,
you,
you enforce this sort of victim
mentality and then you get people really
hooked on outrage,
getting hooked on outrage as opposed to
getting hooked on acceptance and working
on your own,
your own self and your own thing and
your own issues,
but you're also taking power away from
women when you do that.
So,
so what he's saying is that,
okay,
so women have to be protected at all
costs and that's the most important
thing.
And I,
I will be there,
I will have legislation there,
I will have committees there and all of
us are going to protect women on campus
and because they can't protect
themselves,
they can't,
they can't look out for danger.
They can't see because I win in most of
the time.
Know that what?
Even a 100 men are safe.
There's always one seminar.
Let me stop you there because here's.
We're going to go back and forth because
you and I agree on this,
but here's the question.
All right.
How do you stop campus sexual assault?
Now that we know that there's a lot of
it where they're trying to stop or
getting people in trouble for shit
that's not really sexual assault,
but we also know that there's a lot of
guys that are fucking douchebags and
guaranteed someone's going to get drunk.
It's happened before.
They've caught them on tape or people
are passed down.
There's a train of dudes out the
bedroom.
How do you stop people from doing shit
like that?
That's the real question.
It's not like accusing more people
because then you're going to get people
that are even more frustrated with the
opposite sex.
If you find out that guys are getting
locked up in jail for doing the exact
same thing,
their girlfriend
was both being drunk and both having sex
and the guy all of a sudden is a sexual
Predator because he's drunk.
There are two ways to do it.
The first is you raise awareness,
but that the second is you.
You learn we're not to place your
energy.
You learn.
We're not to be pointing your guns
because when you do the other,
when you diminish,
yeah,
you,
you are not making the problem better.
So we're wasting a lot of time and
energy in by,
by,
by sort of condemning and going after
this ankle when we should be like,
what,
what?
It goes back to what does that wonderful
saying?
I don't care what you think.
It's how you think that what's more
important is not what you think,
but how you think.
It's like a woman says,
these radical Islamists are bastards and
my opinion,
you know,
we should just eradicate all of them.
Well,
you sound like a Nazi.
You're thinking the way,
not the Nazis and nicest.
You're thinking exactly how your enemy
and the person you're criticizing us.
So it's really methodology here.
Hey,
you would know this.
This is a good question for you because
somebody said when he wrote this the
other day about how when we call Isis,
um,
when we first started having conflicts
in the Middle East after the Iraq war,
it's a Sunni and Shia in Iraq,
and then there's all these other groups
and factions,
the Taliban,
there's al Qaeda and there's a Boko
Haram,
there's all these different factors.
We sort of kind of lumped them all
together and decided they were one big
enemy.
That's a fact.
And I want you to say this,
like that guy and the drug commercial
that's eating the salad and the guy
goes.
So you're saying that if I buy drugs or
support terrorism,
so,
so she,
the fact that I,
I think to draw the distinction though,
Taliban,
what is Talib?
It means student.
So if you're a Taliban,
you're a student of the Koran,
you know,
you're a student,
uh,
al Qaeda.
Okay.
That means the base loosely translated
sort of.
This is the base.
This is as now.
Is this what they call themselves a?
I believe they do,
yes.
I think these were,
these were names that were given to
themselves and then,
and then a Boko Haram.
Haram in Arabic means a bad,
like you say,
like an Arabic.
A lot of times when something happens
that's bad,
you always say you had,
um,
you know,
like that's fucked up,
almost.
So Boko Haram is sort of a slang,
I believe,
loosely translated idea that everything
western is bad.
Whoa,
okay.
That's outrageous.
And it also part of those folks drugs.
It also has happens to be the fact then
the case that these are all Islamic
movements,
but when you say Islamic movements,
be careful because what you're really
talking about is puritanical.
The notion that there is a puritanical
strain.
There's only one form of Islam and that
Islam is the Islam that the prophet
preached in the what,
what century is it?
The 13th or 15th or whatever it is.
So,
um,
that is,
if there's any glue to those groups,
it is that they essentially adhere to a
very strident,
puritanical form of Islam with no room
for interpretation.
There is only right and wrong and they
are willing to resort to what they would
consider to be jihad,
which the root of which means struggle,
but then what they,
what they considered to be,
you know,
violence isn't,
is a,
is the only option and Islam must sail
in a sea of blood because that's the
only way it happens.
So there's all this sort of idea that,
you know,
will use the slave fix that.
So,
so,
so that again,
what is that?
That's an idea.
It's an ideology.
You have to kill the bad guys,
but you also have to win the workplace
of ideas.
I mean the battlefield,
the battlefield of ideas,
that's very important.
Not only that,
when the casualties are so one sided in
terms of like all of it is taking place
in one part of the world versus in our
part of the world where we're engaging
in a completely different spot in the
country.
It makes martyrs,
you know,
it makes a lot of people get excited
about joining the cause.
They,
they see the imbalance and the conflict.
They also see.
They also see though that when they go
through Istanbul airport and they get
into Syria and they die really quickly,
that it's,
uh,
it's,
they're starting to realize very quickly
that it's also a death sentence.
You don't want to fuck with the
peshmerga.
You don't want to fuck with,
you know,
the American Special Forces.
I mean,
these guys are just getting.
And now the Russians in you're,
you're asking for if you want to join
isol now,
please go ahead and have a real issue
with isis and Eisele a key.
They keep changing their name back and
forth,
uh,
wasn't,
it wasn't Isi at one point in time.
I still state right?
It means the,
uh,
too many,
um,
too many different isis.
This stick with one year,
a new band.
They want to create a challenge.
Your name,
they want credit,
caliphate,
you know,
they want to create an Islamic state,
which means there are no those
boundaries.
Syria,
remember Lebanon,
those were British boundaries.
Those were,
those were created by the British after
World War One a,
in some cases world war two,
but for the most part,
those are British boundaries.
Not so recent.
Think about how recent that is,
folks.
Very recent.
It's ridiculous.
That's not even a hundred years.
It's nothing.
I think that the problem with Islamic
fundamentalism is not as much a worry
because they're not offering anything.
Communism had a something that lasts
that that ideology lasted 70 years,
but I think it lasted so long because
communism was something that you could
kind of.
There was a compassionate element to it,
you know,
don't believe in God,
believe in reason,
and let's live on communes and all share
and be nice to each other.
That idea is pretty potent and
especially the young people who are
trying to figure the world out and who
love each other and any sanders.
Yeah.
I'm Goddamn Kami.
Right.
Well,
he's definitely a social thing to Bernie
sanders stepped in right now.
He would win.
Like if he ran as an independent,
it'd be like,
look,
I can't let you people do this.
Fuck the Democrats.
I'm going independent.
You don't need the libertarian.
They don't know what they're doing.
I can do this.
We could figure this out folks.
This is a disaster tooled.
How dare you.
It just looks a little up in step in
right now.
Has Got Shitty posture.
He needs one of those neck things.
You're hanging from the doorway.
Yeah.
He looks too old
and he's just to please man,
don't forget about what he looks like.
He almost got in.
He got real close look,
man.
Uh,
I think also that Bernie Sanders,
how dare he say such horrible things.
He's,
he's,
he's pretty.
He's,
he's,
um,
I just think people.
He's not very presidential and plead the
presidency is a symbolic post as well.
It's very much a symbolic post.
What would you listen to what you just
said?
He's too old.
He's tall.
He's too old looking.
He doesn't seem very presidential.
That's what the electric say.
Well,
why?
Why would you say that though?
Well,
that's what I'm saying.
That's when would,
when you don't think that if he stepped
in now as an independent,
that he'd have a real chance.
At the very least,
he would confuse the fuck out of the
system because there's a giant movement
of people that wanted to see him in
place.
You want to see him as democratic
representative.
Yeah.
And those people be super energized if
he did step in.
I Dunno.
I Dunno about that.
Oh Wow.
I don't know.
I think for sure for sure.
I think there's still a giant movement
of people out there that love that guy
and loved that he was.
He seemed to be like a guy who wasn't
greedy.
He seemed to be a guy who wasn't
corrupt.
Like how is this possible?
I don't think he is cropped and I don't
think.
I don't think he is either.
But that was.
That's the number one issue with someone
like the Clintons.
And then the thing is that everybody
thinks that that's the only way to do
it.
Like the,
the what,
what people that support the left.
The people that are really into being
Democrats,
they have this thing that they've sort
of resigned themselves to,
hey,
this is politics.
This is how they do it.
This is politics as usual.
When,
when you have an example of a guy like
Bernie Sanders,
you go,
well,
no,
it doesn't have to be like,
look at that guy like that guy didn't do
it.
Cal Come.
They have to do this,
they have to get that money to speak.
They have to do all this shit.
They have to talk to the banks.
They have to.
Are you sure they have to or is it just
this is what the.
The people that do the things that you
liked the most.
They also do these things.
Is that okay?
That's okay for you,
but sometimes I think that that things
start to happen by default,
so if you started,
let's just say we we could return to
kind of scramble everything up and go
back to set point zero.
I feel like in 30 years we'd be right
back to where we started.
Like somebody talking about factory
farming.
It's talking to a guy who has been in
the food business forever and I was
talking about.
There's a book called the tornado effect
about when how food flavoring.
When scientists figured out how to make
a corn chip tastes like a Taco,
it kind of changed everything because we
were able to isolate flavors.
There was a machine that allowed us to.
Because we didn't know why strawberry
tastes like a strawberry on ours,
tastes like an orange,
but um,
and I had this guy on my podcast on the
Brian Council and,
and uh,
the,
the guy who writes this book about how
food flavoring changed the way we ate
and it ended up,
it allowed us to take very non
nutritious food and make it nutritious.
Trying to figure out how you're gonna
bring this back to factory farming.
If we ended up and he was talking about
how we need to get back to sort of,
you know,
family farming and farming and stuff.
But I
talked to this guy who was in the food
business.
He said,
you know,
the problem with that is that family
farms are a great idea and we do
probably need more family farms,
but what would happen is probably in the
next 20 years we'd be back to factory
farming.
I said,
what do you mean?
He said what would happen is that some
farms wouldn't be as efficient or they
wouldn't be as good and in another farms
better and that farm and say,
let me buy you a farm.
I do a better job,
and then that he'd say,
let me buy this farm,
and then he had all of a sudden he'd buy
all the farms in this area because he's
really good at organization automation
and everything else and that would start
to happen.
Then a bigger company to come along and
say,
let me buy all your farms,
man,
you've got market share here and I can
do this even better because there's a
better way to do it.
Not only that,
keep the prices stable because we're
going to have a lot of eggs.
So when I hop I have doesn't have to
say,
well today,
since we only get our,
our eggs from a local source today
they're the eggs are $5.
Whereas yesterday were three 99.
That's kind of what would happen because
it would depend on production and
distribution.
And so he was kind of saying,
you know,
it's nice to think that we need family
farming,
but chances are with such a huge
population that we have to feed the way
we do it as quickly as we do,
we'd probably be back to,
hey,
we're running out of chickens who can
make a chicken that can mature in six
weeks.
Well that's the big issue.
The big issue is the population and a
big issue
will do their best,
you know,
they do their best to recycle.
They do their best to try to figure out
how to pollute the least and consume the
least and leave the smallest carbon
footprint.
And some people are very conscious about
it.
But there's a lot of things that people
overlook and one of them is all the
vegetables that you get from the grocery
store,
no matter what,
if you think you are somehow or another
Karma free because you're only eating
vegetables.
Man,
I hate to tell you,
but that whole thing of growing
vegetables in mass is only slightly less
controversial than growing animals in
mass.
It's all weird.
There's a lot of displacement.
Wildlife.
There's a lot of pollution of the
environment due to pesticides,
the runoff from the salt and sea that I
was telling you about.
That's all directly attributed to
farming and most of it is agriculture.
It's great.
It's fucking pesticides and shit.
It all flows down down river and you're
fucked and there's a lot of other issues
like first of all,
it's not natural.
It's not natural to keep growing things
in one spot.
That is just not how the world is
supposed to be designed.
It's supposed to be a gigantic cycle of
animals dying and their bodies rotting
and their bodies fueling the plants that
they actually eat,
and then animals eat them and they die
and their bodies rod and fuel the plants
that grow around them.
We've circumvented that thing with these
giant things we call cities.
We figured out a way to stack all these
people on top of each other and then we
had to figure out a way to get them all
food because the fucking buildings kept
growing and the people kept needing more
and more and more and they're running
out of room fuck.
And so that's the problem,
the problem is we got the cart way ahead
of the train,
we're what we're way ahead of it.
And we didn't,
we didn't anticipate for 7 billion
people,
we didn't anticipate for 300 million
Americans and
we're kind of doing it right now,
but even with our vegetables,
we're fucking up giant chunks of land,
you know,
even with our vegetables.
And do you think it's not easy like this
idea that it's easy to feed a bunch of
people at 20 million people with a Vegan
Diet?
Goddammit,
it's not,
it's not easy to feed 20 million people
with any kind of diet and it requires a
lot of resources and organization and,
and you know,
sort of consolidation.
Yeah.
No,
but I would imagine it's not saying
factory farming from animals is awesome.
It's disgusting.
It's scary that it got this far and he
got this far while we weren't paying
attention to it,
all of us.
I think pretty much all Americans at one
point in their life had to be told of
factory farming.
And then when,
what the fuck,
like this wasn't something that was
discussed when we were in high school.
When I was in college,
there was never a word and I was barely
in college by the way,
but when I was in college were the same
age.
That's what I'm.
What I'm saying is no one discussed it.
It wasn't this gigantic issue.
I don't think we were quite as aware.
That's another creepy things.
Those AG gag laws were to legal,
to film these horrific conditions that
pigs Robert concerns have to live in.
That's you can.
You can go to jail for letting people
know about animal torture that's being
taken place where they're hitting a
fucking cow in the head with a wrench.
I saw this crazy video of this guy
crowbars a cow in the head.
The first time I ever saw the first time
I ever learned about factory farming was
there as a pamphlet in my college and
they were talking about how smart pigs
are and how they.
They.
They showed a picture of a pig chewing
the bars independent within and how pigs
go crazy because they want to roam with.
They're too smart to just sit in that
pen and I got so claustrophobic that I
didn't eat bacon for a year out of
compassion.
I was like,
I can't eat bacon now to Kenny Baker.
And then he was right back on the big
show.
And then I read a book called fit for
life,
which was all about being a vegetarian.
Try that for about six days.
Didn't work for me.
I just can't do it.
Well,
vegetarian is way more healthy than just
going straight Vegan.
As far as like own,
I say way more healthy,
meaning that it's easier to be waiting
on healthy.
Like you can pull off the Vegan thing if
you're super on the ball with your
essential fats and you make sure you
take,
what is it,
Dah da.
And there's a pet.
What is the,
the,
the um,
Omega threes and sixes that you can get
from the fuck.
Is that stuff called that you get from a
flag from Kelp?
Flaxseed,
flaxseed,
flaxseed.
But apparently the biological stuff is
better.
There's Omega threes and sixes that you
can help an animal though.
No,
it's plant kelp is not thinking about.
I'm thinking about Krill.
Krill.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
That's an animal.
Well,
you know,
here's another thing that a Sam Harris
was telling me is that mollusks,
if you.
At least if you look at them on paper,
there's more of an argument to be made
that plants are intelligent than
molochs.
Really?
Yeah.
Models.
They don't feel shit.
That is a little blobs of snot.
It is living.
Come live in com that lives in a shell.
You know,
they're weird.
There's a weird little things and
apparently they're super,
super primitive.
Will all what we decide that they are an
animal that should not be eaten.
Whereas a plant is something that should
be eaten based on whether or not they
move.
Wait,
wait.
What's a scallop death?
Not the same as a mollusk.
Well,
this Gallup is a mollusk clams mussels,
scallops.
There's a lot of different shelled
organisms,
but they're super,
super,
super primitive.
I did not have nerve endings.
Like,
yeah,
they don't feel pain.
Like that's the other thing about
lobsters.
Lobsters is creeping.
Where do they are?
Apparently they don't feel pain.
Too primitive to feel pain.
There's a great essay by David Foster
Wallace called consider the lobster and
it's all about this.
Yeah,
I don't know.
I mean there's a thing called the
lobster liberation organization to break
into restaurants and they take lots and
they throw them back in the ocean.
What kind of a one?
Kind of a radical group that's trying to
get proof for that group.
I just want to get that phone call from.
From jail.
I'm in jail.
Which you do.
So we met from the law to get into a
fistfight.
What did you read?
This pamphlet would judge me.
No doubt.
I uh,
I let a lobster free what I let lobsters
free.
Oh,
those giant Cunty roaches.
That one.
Just bite your fingers off.
You let those things for dummy.
They are members.
Delicious insect family.
I guess the other they are.
That's why if you eat cricket,
a flower like that,
it was a thing in protein bars.
If you have an allergy to shellfish,
you can break out.
And that's so true,
and I can validate that by fear factor,
fear factor.
We gave people roaches and one of the
dudes that we gave roaches was allergic
to shellfish.
So when he ate the roaches,
he got sick due to Roche.
Yeah.
It wasn't like very overrated is.
No,
it's not.
It's not terrible.
Tasting is not a big deal.
It wasn't.
It wasn't hard to do hate the body that
I just.
I had a giant one.
It was a Madagascar hissing.
Cockroaches.
Yeah.
It was like a live on that.
I mean,
could for sure.
One hundred percent.
Yeah.
You could live on that same weekend.
Live on crap.
Where'd you afraid it was going to bite
you or no?
They don't bite.
That's kid of a bug.
Fuck.
I'm tests of bug,
but poison didn't have poison.
I knew I was going to Jack.
I'm quick.
Was it dirty in there?
Yeah,
whenever.
So it a peanut butter and Jelly Sandwich
and drop on the ground.
If you're hungry,
you pick it up and you just ate a
Goddamn cockroach.
Bad Dude.
People been eating them forever.
We were insectivores probably before we
ever figured out how to kill animals.
Fuckers.
Yeah.
Oh look,
no bond deal,
dude.
It's no big deal.
They'll look at young Joe Rogan was
ending that young man.
Full head is fairly young.
Fairly.
C'Mon dude.
Look at these poor girls.
Dude.
You just did it.
It's,
it's not that big.
Show this and let's not even move on
with this.
You're not really that.
It's um,
I coughed a lot.
There was a lot of little parts and
stuff that we're going down the back of
my throat,
the whole um,
little legs and shit,
you know,
because it's,
you're chewing up this hard,
hard skeleton and trying to swallow that
too.
That made me gag a couple of times.
But as far as like taste,
it's really nothing.
It's like almost like a void of taste
and Merlin Mann.
Allah gave me the back of the deer's
eyeball.
Oh yeah,
that's right.
It was fat.
And he said to that just like chewing
gum.
And I was like,
no.
He said it tastes like dough.
Yeah,
like dough.
like bread dough.
It did SORTA.
It looked like bread dough,
interesting.
Like it's fat behind the eyes.
While I appreciated the fact that he eat
that too.
He eats everything.
Hell yeah.
Know that guy has more respect for,
uh,
a downed animal than,
any,
any hunter of.
Yeah,
buddy down to dude,
you did I miss.
Well,
is this a thing?
Here's the other thing,
like everybody can't do that.
That's a really important point to point
to bring up whenever we're also pro
hunting and talking about how great it
is to eat animals that you've harvested
yourself,
you know exactly where they came from.
You.
They're wild.
You know,
they've never been abused and never been
raised in slavery and Fed antibiotics
and hormones.
They lived wild until you shot him.
Yeah.
But everybody can't do that.
That's,
there's a problem with that too.
Like even even admitting that,
like even saying that like for me
personally,
it's the better option.
I enjoy that option.
I think it's the best option.
It's still everybody can't do it,
so it's,
we're fucked no matter what.
But we've come a long way with just
feeding people.
Half the world was starving in the
seventies,
of course with.
We just weren't back to what we're
saying,
you know,
factory farming.
That's how they did it.
I mean they figured out how to do it.
Large scale agriculture,
indiscriminant combines that chew up the
amount of animals that die when they
chew up the fucking grain and corn and
all the different things.
They.
It's a fucking horror show.
My friend John Dudley who lives in Iowa,
he has a farm and he says when they run
those combines,
when they pick up whatever grains or
whatever they have,
they run these big giant ass machines
and he says,
you'll see the buzzards circling in the
sky.
Like they literally know that things are
just.
Oh,
you mean like rats and rabbits and rats
and rabbits and deer fons and ground
nesting birds.
Fuck,
I never thought of that.
All those animals don't realize that
these,
what they're living in is temporary.
They look at it as,
oh,
this is an awesome shelter.
I'm going to go in here.
It's thick with all these branches.
No predators are going to find me.
I'll just go here and nest so,
so that.
Now the green tea,
I've never heard this grain combines.
Have you ever seen a green combine?
Now Jamie,
Jamie,
pull it up and you'll get an
understanding,
an understanding of what kind of volume
you're talking about.
So,
so in your bread you're saying with the
grain,
because you have a lot of animal.
That's totally that.
It's not just that,
well,
I don't know how good it is for you and
how much of it gets baked off,
but the problem is it's not animal death
free.
It's just not right.
We were showing something.
Brian put up this video the other day of
a grain silo in Russia and now these
pigeons fall into the grain silo and try
to eat the grain.
Then gets sucked into the gears as the
the silo or the machine is turning up
the grain so they land on the grain and
try to get some of it and then they get
sucked into the gears over and over and
over and over again.
We're launching like 10:15
of them and like of course of a couple
of minutes get sucked into this machine
that chews up the pigeons.
And so.
So when they say what does the machine
taking the grain and making it finer,
is that what it's doing?
Well,
yeah,
but let's,
well let's not,
let's see.
A large view so we can get an
understanding of the mass.
So that's just,
that's a small one.
Look at large scale grain combine and
see if you could find a video of it,
but they have these fucking hundreds of
feet long and they're just chewing up
giant chunks of these crops and when
they're doing these large scale
agriculture,
like that one right there.
Perfect exam.
But isn't that,
isn't that just clear cutting?
That's not actually using any of that
stuff.
No,
it's using it.
That's how,
that's how they chew that shit up dude.
Yeah,
but that's not,
that's not a,
that's actually isn't a cornfield.
They,
they pick the corn.
That's actually um,
I believe that's a truck going through
it and taking out all those they can
replant.
I think it is possible that that's what
that is,
but there's a bunch of different kinds
of machines they use for that same kind
of purpose,
meaning for whether it's they're just
going to replant them,
whether it's their harvesting.
Um,
there's got machines running over that
ground all the time,
like see if you could find the big
combines,
they spread out like a t and it's like,
so there's a truck and then to the right
and the left,
they spread out on either side with
these just years that chopped down the
plants and then get them ready for
harvest.
And they also do it when they're,
um,
when they're making hay,
you know,
they do that.
They have these machines that they drive
through and chop everything down and
they roll it up for hey,
like here.
So that's a combine.
And that thing,
as that guy pulls it,
that thing is chewing up every fucking
thing that's down there.
Everything and animals,
especially Fonz is one of the weird
things about deer fonds when they're
really young,
they just stay put.
So they,
uh,
if they hear things,
you could literally walk up to a baby
deer fond and if the mom's not around
you can touch it because their instincts
until they get old enough to run away
from stuff,
their instincts are to stay put just to
ensure survival.
So a lot of them get chewed up in this
and there was some estimation that I
read when they were talking about the
problems with this and the ways they
were trying to figure out how to
mitigate wildlife loss from use of
indiscriminate combine.
It's like this.
And they were talking about each pound
of grain.
How many animals has to die.
I don't remember what the number was.
Oh,
this is the video of the pigeons that
gets shoved into this,
uh,
for the grinder.
Yeah.
Oh Dude.
He goes on forever.
You guys?
Yeah.
Whoops.
Oh No.
And they keep doing it.
So they're not smart enough to figure
out what's going on.
Look at that one.
Whoops.
Oh Shit.
Fuck.
This is insane.
Yeah.
Then this is going away there.
Granted,
fly.
You made it.
You made it to fly.
Well how about that?
One in the end,
she's just watching his buddies go down.
He doesn't say a goddamn thing.
One of them jumped right in the middle
of was like,
Hey,
look at this.
It's amazing.
Just flag it.
There you go.
Guys said WHO's going to get smart now?
This one's.
This one's gone.
Say it dude.
Oh,
last week.
I bet you could make a lot of money.
This is what.
This is a gambler's dream.
I got the one right.
Is this one going to get down and I'd
have to have stacks of money on the name
of this video.
Jamie.
Oh Dude,
you went to facebook exploding.
Oh,
that's not it.
What was the pigeons are being sucked in
with the green on a bread making plant
in Russia.
Russian pity comes up.
Okay man.
You too.
But.
So the point is to make gigantic groups
of people happy and fed even just with
vegetables.
You need a lot of that stuff going on.
So it's not nice to anybody.
It's not nice.
I mean this is,
again,
this is not defending factory farming,
which is obviously disgusting and
horrible and it's a.
it's one of the darker aspects of human
civilization,
the fact that standard in the United
States that that shit is really,
really,
really common and that's how we can
afford meat so cheap,
but even vegetables,
even vegetables,
it's not like growing your own shit.
Ideally what we're supposed to do.
Those were all supposed to grow our own
shit.
We're all supposed to have a piece of
land and you're supposed to have
vegetables on it and he's supposed to
have a few animals that you raised,
whether it's for for milk or for cheese
or for meat or for whatever.
That would be the way you could do it.
It's just not scalable.
People would starve.
Well,
it's not scalable in terms of the way
we've decided to jam everybody into
these cities.
It's just not well.
Again,
I think that was just what would happen
anyway.
By default,
people organize.
You feel safer in cities.
You get more access to food and shelter
of course,
but if you.
If you stop and think about the
requirements,
like the food requirements of all these
people,
people are.
It's so easy for someone you and me
included to say,
oh,
I don't have time to fucking gather and
hunt someone,
go get my food.
I've got to do comedy.
I got to set,
I got to do at the Improv.
I'm going to go to the store and buy a
sandwich.
You know,
like you want that access and it seems
like the only way you can get that kind
of access to supermarkets and fast food
restaurants,
the only way is this system that we've
got now,
like where you've just got massive
amounts of animals.
They're getting slaughtered it.
It allows for thought and things that
you see if you have to live.
If you have spent so much of your time
just feeding yourself and your family or
whatever that,
that,
that somebody was talking about.
Well,
where?
Why did Greek philosophy philosophy come
out of grace where they had all that
time to think?
Well,
a lot of like certain.
I think it was the historian William
Mcneil said,
well,
they were able to export timber,
olive oil
and wine,
and so they made money.
Their economy.
You could actually have some leisure
time,
you could buy leisure time because they
would trade,
you know,
for all those,
for those goods that were wanted
everywhere.
So what happened was you had,
you know,
there are people that made a lot of
money and they could sit around and
think [inaudible] they could be somebody
was there to feed them and they didn't
have to worry about things that the
climate was temperate.
Uh,
so you didn't have to.
We're really worried about the winter as
much.
I mean it gets cold,
but not that goal.
That's so fascinating because that
mirrors what John Anthony West said
about Egypt.
He was talking about the early days of
ancient Egypt and the Nile River being
such a fertile area and the food just
blew up out of nowhere.
Like it would just,
it would just,
it was easy to,
to,
to grow things also is also animal
grasses that grew.
Anyway,
you know that there was barley and there
was I think millet and there was,
you know,
that that's a huge factor that you
didn't know you could cultivate and the
natural grasses that just grew anyway,
we're also wheat.
The,
those were there so you didn't have to
kind of import them from other places.
So it's like we need these kinds of
situations like these city type
situations where we have massive amounts
of resources,
but we're doing it on a scale that no
one else has ever done it before.
We're doing on this really bizarre scale
and we have to recognize that this is
all incredibly recent in terms of like
human history,
like to jam millions and millions of
people in cities.
I mean there had been a few cities in
China that had done it,
you know,
there's a few places around the world
that had done it,
but they were essentially primitive.
They were,
you know,
like you're talking about what they've
done in terms of developing a city where
it had a million people in the year,
1200 versus what has to be done in the
year 2016.
First of all,
you have electricity,
you have power everywhere.
You have sewage lines running
everywhere.
You've got all these people shitting and
pissing into tubes and then pumping
water through this fucking pipe that
gets rid of it somewhere.
You got to get rid of all that shit.
Piss water.
You've got to figure out a place to put
it.
You've got to have treatment plants for
I mean you have to bring in truck boron
over bridges and the same places where
everybody else's and they're filled with
chickens and pigs and fucking and
cabbage and you just got to constantly
just keep bringing them food and bring
it out there.
Shit,
bringing in their food,
bringing out their shit.
You know what else that does for,
for agricultural communities that the
benefit for [inaudible] when
agricultural communities we go to war
with,
like you know,
a nomadic tribes or with with the
exception of the Mongols,
but with nomadic tribes and other like
native Americans for example,
is that when you come from a tradition
of agriculture and cities like that
where you have contact with animals,
nasty diseases,
nasty diseases start to breathe and then
you build an immunity to it,
but guess who doesn't?
The people you come into contact with.
So,
so many of the people like the native
Americans,
they were killed by bullets,
but they were mainly killed by things
like influenza and the European diseases
that they
had zero contact with.
Well,
that's interesting because a Dan Flores
wrote up a paper thing was called bison
diplomacy.
Bison ecology.
Bison,
Bison Ecology or reading his book right
now about coyotes and he wrote this book
about the Buffalo and he said that the
mass numbers that people had seen of the
buffalo when there was,
you know,
millions of them roaming across the
plains.
It coincided with the native American
population dwindling substantially
because of disease by Europeans.
When the Europeans came over and brought
diseases,
it wiped out a giant percentage of the
population and he.
His contention was Spanish,
right?
Is that,
who can say yes and French too,
right?
I think it was mostly Spanish,
but yeah.
But anyway,
Europeans that came over and they
brought a bunch of dirty daddy candy
bags and their pigs and I'm on also
horses of course,
but they said he said that the native
Americans with a firearm and with horses
were already on their way to extra
padding the buffalo from a lot of its
range before they got hit with these
crazy diseases so that when you saw
these millions of Buffalo,
it was a direct response to a lack of a
predator.
Wow.
A lack of a competent Predator,
one that they used to have in the native
Americans that would follow them around
with the native Americans that were
introduced to firearms.
I believe he was talking about firearms
and um,
maybe even spears and bows and arrows as
well.
But the horseback was the big issue
because being on horseback you can just
get right to the buffalo,
you just follow.
They don't,
but they didn't even know what the fuck
you were,
you know,
they let you get right up on them like
they never got jacked by horses before
they get jacked by wolves and they got
jacked by mountain lions and they never
got jacked by a horse,
a horse with a dude on it with a fucking
spear of my side,
which is run up on them and kill him,
kill a ton of them.
And then they would all feast and they
would follow the buffalo herd around and
just keep jacking him,
you know,
and most likely that this,
uh,
this Guy Dan Flores is saying that they
were on their way to diminishing the
population's greatly.
And he points to the early European
travelers who came through.
They didn't talk about the Buffalo.
There's no,
no mention of the Buffalo.
They talked about all these other
animals.
They talked about elk,
they talked about deer.
They talked about bear,
who talked about antelope.
They talked about all these plains
animals that they discovered and
encountered.
They didn't talk about buffalo from.
From how far back?
Way Far back when they first started
coming in [inaudible] 91.
So that.
Yeah,
so the early settlers accounts did not
include these massive populations of
Buffalo.
So when they had gotten to these crazy
numbers,
like when they started killing them for.
There's a bunch of different reasons why
they killed them and one of the reasons
why they killed him was there for
another one was their tongues.
They would kill gigantic herds,
just thousands of Buffalo.
They just take their tongues and leave
their bodies to Rye.
They use their tongues like they ate
them.
They were there.
A delicate.
Yeah,
there was,
I guess it was valuable at the time
and they also,
they used it for the meat market so they
would kill them and they would take them
and they would sell them to market.
So there were,
there were market hunters and they were
just indiscriminately white bow,
just giant numbers of them.
So without a doubt the the native,
the native Americans were on their way.
But we showed them how to do it.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
There are always stories about sort of
cowboys with their shoulders that were
black and blue because they were
shooting buffalo all day long and then
they would take the tarps and stretch
them out and it covered like a square
mile and some crazy night.
Not that,
but like football fields of just tarps
that were spread out and then rubbed
with oil,
I guess to make,
you know,
so that the tarp.
So you created a buffalo skin,
uh,
hide and at night you'd hear the coyotes
fighting and snarling over the,
sort of the licking the highs and
chewing that the shoe,
the coyotes away.
And then they figured out,
they said,
why don't we just lace the buffalo
before we kill him?
Let's laced the buffalo with strict
nights.
It will scan them and list the meat.
Some of the meat with strychnine and
those animals need the strychnine and
they'll die.
And then we can take those papers and
send them back east as well.
Well,
I never heard that.
Yeah.
What animals were they doing?
So,
so,
so all the boxes would come in,
all the coyotes,
all the wolves,
and then all the birds and so they would
take the feathers and send them to
Europe for hats and they will take the,
the coyote skins and they take the wolf
skin and everything else that they're
releasing.
Buffalo meat was trick.
Now there's a great book that did that
with wild horses.
Well,
they did that with Buffalo.
There was a great book called of wolves
and men,
I believe I read a long time ago.
And as they,
as they laid the railroad down,
they were shooting them from trains.
But as they,
as they did that,
that was really what cause the planes of
the great plains looked very much like
the Kalahari.
Apparently like a,
you know the African,
the African wilderness.
That's funny that you brought that up
because that's another book the floors
is working on.
He's working on the American Serengeti
Flores gets his fucking information from
you as a professor.
You're amazing.
Yeah.
I just did.
He taught at a major university.
I worked,
I worked from Mugu.
He talked about.
That's the reason why the antelope run
so fast,
so at the antelope run so fast because
they were there being chased by these
big cats.
Like we used to have a cat.
We still have a lion that lived in North
America that's bigger than an African
lion.
Yeah.
Oh,
that was a short tail.
I don't know what kind of tail it had.
We had a thing called a short face bear.
There was apparently damn most dangerous
bear that's ever lived.
Giant bigger than to bring that up
bigger than a polar bear.
Why?
Huge formidable Predator that they think
was one of the reasons why it took so
long for people to migrate into North
America.
It might have been that the bering
strait was the realm of the short face
bear.
I want no part of it.
Never seen those days.
Sure.
Haven't.
You need to see this.
And uh,
whatever the American lion was,
there was also a thing called a terror
bird that was this giant,
seven foot tall birds,
flightless bird with a giant hatchet for
a face that would just fuck things up.
That's,
that is the relative size.
That's obviously a replica that's the
size of a short face bear.
Apparently.
It was just an enormous,
enormous bear and look at that other
fucking thing is that.
That's a dangerous day at Don Dawn.
Dawn,
some other horrible looking monster with
teeth.
It looks like a deer with wolf teeth.
Well,
it looks like a hedgehog.
Yeah,
well,
like a buffalo,
which I.
Andy fucking pig.
Yeah.
God Damn Man.
There were some crazy fucking animals I
want.
No.
Part of that was really interesting is
that the massive them went extinct
somewhere around the end of the ice age.
They just all got.
We'll probably for the same reason why
the ice age and probably a lot of shit
going on.
A lot of factors.
That's how big it is.
Oh my God.
That's impressive.
Look at the size of that fucking thing.
That's just a Kodiak bear.
I could easily be a Kodiak that easily
kept their 11 feet high or some shit.
Yeah.
The big ones are.
Are you kidding me?
Yeah.
There's a great video.
You want to shit your pants.
It a great video from a guard booth in
Alaska where these guys are inside,
like one of those part ranger guard
booths and they're watching this bear
walkthrough.
That's the size of a bus complete is a
fucking tank.
It looks like a few like a VW bus and
and they're,
they're in there and go,
oh my God,
look at him,
and the thing just strolls right past
the guard booth and you get a sense
because they're inside this building,
but the building is only 10 feet from
this animal.
So you get like a really clear sense of
proportion of how big it is and you're
like,
oh my God,
fucking crazy.
It's like 11 feet long and it probably
weighs,
you know,
who knows how much,
how many,
how much do I have?
Fifteen hundred pounds.
You never,
you feel such a good way to feel like
food and shoes.
You're so demeaning of you.
That's why going to zoos makes me always
feel a little shitty about myself.
I'm the weakest link in the chain.
I'm just a ball pink piece of fucking
food.
I suck compared to your guns and cars
and shit that's brain and figured it
out,
but when you see this thing,
got it.
No bear giant bear walks.
Past Guard booth in Alaska.
I'll find it.
You want.
If you want to be a big cat before
you're eaten by a bear because bears
just start eating you and you're alive.
Big Cat to get the back of your neck and
quite.
Yeah,
they get your face.
They don't want to fight.
Now they want you to die so they could
eat you.
Yuck.
Bears are so vulnerable.
They don't feel the need to kill you
first.
It's not necessary.
They just hold you down.
Here it is.
Watch this.
So these guys around the guard booth and
this thing starts.
Lumbering.
Tourism.
Grizzly.
It's so big.
It's so.
What's the name of it?
Jamie says,
must see huge brown bear walking pass.
Brooks Lodge.
Ranger station.
So as these guys are sitting there in
their truck like,
look how close it is,
what it was on the road doing these.
These guys are stand there.
Watch out walks right by there.
I mean that things tend to fade away.
Oh my gosh.
They don't even swear and they're so
nice up there.
I look at that.
No,
watch this.
Look at the lady walking down the road.
See down there.
What is that?
A dude might be a dude.
So let's say lady might be a lady,
but either way it just decides not to
walk over and eat her.
Like she's just out there.
If it went into a dead sprint,
that'd be around.
It's catching her.
Oh,
for sure.
You never getting away from that thing
and that she didn't even see that bear?
No.
She would have heard it coming.
She would have heard of breathing
properly.
Yeah.
I wonder what it would've done if we'd
have checked to see if she had a gun.
Oh no,
I wouldn't eat in her.
I mean what it like just run up to her
and eating her.
Because the thing they say about
grizzlies is it's way less likely that a
grizzly bear is going to kill you for
food and wine.
More likely they're going to kill you
because you stumble upon a mother with
her cubs and she's protecting her
because grizzly bears don't necessarily
look at people's food,
but black bear apparently are more
opportunistic predators and there's way
more way more incidents of black bears
attacking and killing people for food.
Then there is a of grizzly bears.
Grizzly bears definitely have done it,
but it appears that a black bears do it
more for food more for predation.
Brunello was telling us about a story
about,
oh shit.
Running up to a dog.
It scared that a dog is a that's from
American Werewolf in London.
Video ended right as a set of people
that were filming it.
Oh really?
Yeah,
because they were fucking with says mom
Barrett tax.
Oh wait,
okay.
I don't need to say that.
It is A.
Anyway,
bears scary.
Not Good.
Don't get eaten.
But it was telling a story about a
friend of his,
a.
I'm going to fuck the story up,
I'm sure.
But,
uh,
I think that just the story was they
took this guy out for the first time
hunting ever.
He got attacked by a 500 pound predatory
black bear in his tent while he's
sleeping.
Bear comes in the tent,
mauls him.
Somebody wakes up,
shoots the bear,
hits him in the wrist,
breaks his wrist,
and then the bear gets out of that tank,
runs in another tent and they shoot it
500 pound predatory black bear.
So that's a bear.
That's how much you weigh.
One 71 72,
shred it.
So I'm somewhere in the range of 200
pounds.
So you and I and then a lot more.
Another 100 plus pounds,
another 125 pounds and it's a fucking
bear and you're by yourself and you're
sleeping.
It's your first time ever hunting and
this thing comes through the door.
Just all hot fucking funk breath.
Never taken a bath in it's life.
Just looking to rip you apart while you
fast twitch muscle and dense bone.
Your friend shoots you in the wrist,
your friend shoots at it,
and I don't know if it got a pass
through and the the the bear's body and
then hit him because that sometimes
happens,
but either way you get shot in the
wrist.
Bear mauls.
You were talking about how the new it
used to kill seals and they would use
polar bear bone.
Now,
how do you kill a polar bear?
Do you know how,
but I know how to killed wolves.
You know,
they used to kill wolves,
whether used to take a blade and put
blood on it and it was just keep looking
and bleed today,
but I believe with polar bears,
they would kill them missile.
When they were sleeping,
it was find out where they were sleeping
and they would come in there and stabbed
the shit out of them while they were
sleeping and then they would take that
box.
It was extra hard and they would put at
the end of their spirit and that's how
they would kill seals.
Did you ever wonder how inuits who lived
in that ice region got water?
Because remember what the water is,
it's all saltwater,
right?
Ice Is all salt water.
So how do you get water?
How the fuck you get water is polar
bears Dick.
Very good.
And,
and I,
and yes,
most of the time you're not very
scientific.
Oh,
do I am okay.
But you have to.
Apparently they would be able to see
what the old guys,
the old old ice by the color of it,
the older the ice,
the,
I guess the,
the less salt.
So you would find really old ice.
And that was the ice that you would
meltdown as water.
Where's the fuck?
Yeah.
So the,
the Arctic explorers who didn't hook up
with the inuit always died.
They just froze to death.
They didn't,
they couldn't find food.
It sucked.
And the ones that immediately made
friends with the nun,
uh,
they,
they came back nice and fat.
They had plenty of seal meat and they
would always have to get rid of all
their clothing and where exactly what
the intuit would wear,
what kind of a fucking crazy person
decides to go to the Antarctic.
Uh,
the British who wanted to find a
different way routes from trade,
but just think about what kind of a
crazy person and you feel like that's
what I want to do this.
I want to go home and be the first guy
to go to Antarctica.
Bad asses.
I'm just gonna walk across that frozen.
It looks like nothing that had the
Messiness,
that story about,
I can't remember the name,
wasn't shackleton was another guy who
was an explorer and he,
he,
his men were all starving and dying and
he knew he was going to die,
but he was a British Aristocrat,
you know.
And,
and when you were in Britain,
you had a duty,
you've got a duty to,
to essentially use your free time to
make the world a better place.
And so,
uh,
he famously stiff upper lip,
grew up on a life of discipline,
never showing every your emotions
properly carted away to boarding school
at six years old as they always were.
Definitely did some buggery,
uh,
as to do that.
Right.
That was real common.
Still is,
uh,
the opera class to send their kids to
school at seven,
the older classmates and like,
hey jay stuff,
there's a lot of problems.
Uh,
but uh,
he said famously,
um,
as he knew he was going to die his,
his foot,
apparently it was gangrene and he looked
at his men and he said,
I'm going for a walk and they may be
some time and he just,
wow.
He just rather than convenience and with
his death,
because that would be very unblemish he
walked off and frozen stuff.
That's a bad ass because,
because keeping up and if you read some
of the letters as they were dying and
starving to death,
their letters are incredibly formal and
still poised and always taking into
account that they had to keep up
appearances and that they had to uh,
always remind themselves that they were
there for a bigger cause and that their
personal discomfort was just not
something you inconvenience anybody
with.
That was the highest level of
civilization they will capable of
expressing before emojis.
See now you could send someone a text
message and say,
I don't think the dis dis shit is going
to work out.
Yeah,
the piece out if you want to sell fam
and then you'd have like an Emoji with a
peace sign and then like you and then a
gun dude,
if you want to see the antithesis to the
Emoji and the American culture as it is
now.
Good.
Youtube a debate between James Baldwin,
the Great African American author and
William F Buckley at Cambridge
University in 1965.
Everybody who's listening please do
that.
Just set up to do with emojis just
because that was debate and language and
formality and hieroglyphs and cadres
goes.
They're all,
they're talking about.
Uh,
the,
the question was,
is it was the American dream at the
expense of the American Negro or does it
not?
And that is the debate.
And Ms Dot Buckley was close.
Choose that.
It is not an Mr Ronald Reagan's visit.
It is.
And James Bond gets him a rousing
speech.
Nineteen 65.
I brought the cotton to market and I
picked the cotton for nothing,
for nothing.
But I would always be an inevitable and
then William Buckley,
he gets up and.
But the formality,
the theatricality and the fucking
language,
the way English was spoken by the upper
classes are the educated back in the
day.
This is so great.
He's 12 years old.
No,
no.
That's not the beginning of that bait
flowing dresses for university.
He's.
Yeah.
And fast forward to James Baldwin
talking.
It's actually quite amazing.
We can't really play it anyway.
We'll get yanked off of youtube.
That's somebody else's content that
somebody else owns us.
It's really important to watch though,
I think.
Well,
that was my though was that.
Do you think that the reason why that
formality was so appreciated and
accepted and it was so highly regarded,
was because that was the highest level
of civilization that they had before
technology,
before technology and before being.
There was a limited amount that you can
influence the environment back then and
you could have more influence yourself.
You could more educate yourself.
You could,
if you wanted to go somewhere,
you got to get on a boat.
Okay.
You got to get on a boat with everybody
else.
He had to get on a train.
If you want to get across the country,
you had to get on the train.
If you want to write something,
you had to use a quill and you had to
have a little thing of ink and yet a dip
it in there and that's how he wrote
period and it was a limited amount that
you could do.
Like you know,
you couldn't just go home and sit and
watch television.
You couldn't a code,
a video game.
He says less distraction.
There's less distraction and the the,
the level of ability that you could
where you could express civilization at
its highest level.
It was basically like code a few
machines that people had built,
a few combustion machines,
the trains,
things along those lines and then the
rest of it was just like houses and
rule.
I don't know if that's.
I don't know if that's accurate.
I think it might also be that I like.
I think that's part of it and I think
that's a valid kind of a description of
maybe part of what was going on,
but I think something else is going on
with those,
with those debates.
I think that when you the reason like
something like firing line watch,
firing line with William F Buckley,
popular show,
it's molasses.
You,
you've got to read.
You're listening to men speak about long
ideas.
Actually.
One of the things I really appreciate
about your show because you're having
such smart people on having real
discussions,
but then how the fuck did you get on
here?
I have no idea what barn,
but I think he got me.
He fucking got me again,
but.
But back then like there was.
It feels like political commitment and
winning these arguments between right
and left as they were known had actual
ramifications because the.
It feels like politics and whatever
happens in an election today means less
to people and has less of an effect.
At least an immediate effect because
back in those days,
65,
the wars that were going on with
ideology and wars with fascism and
communism and capitalism.
People were actually dying and having
real wars.
They were national awards that were set
to defend not only resources but those
ideologies and entire movement,
and I think that there was the sense
that if this side wins,
then that side of it is going to come
over and take us over.
There was this real ideology between
this and so I think that those debates
people took very personally because they
probably knew somebody who died
defending the world against fascism.
They were afraid of the red scare or
they were committed communists and they
were being persecuted for it because
they couldn't get a job in Hollywood.
There's a real,
a culture war that had actual tangible
ramifications that you could see every
day.
My God,
the Vietnam War,
Americans were dying every day because
there were.
There were sent out there to make the
world safe for democracy.
Right.
That was a factor too.
I think that was not a factor.
I think there certainly was a lot going
on there with that,
but we were really talking about people
even before that era.
I think when we were talking about the
guy from Antarctica that I'm going out
for a walk maybe some times.
Yeah,
I think there was something with the
intellectuals of the day where they were
way more uncorrupted by,
by the world that we live in today in
terms of.
You mean like they had a sense of duty
and I think there was,
it was a very,
very important position,
right to be the who disseminated the
information in 17,
95 made decisions and made decisions and
was in charge of like libraries and
books and it was teaching universities.
I mean you've got to think of like what
different British universities were
around the 17 hundreds,
like quite a few,
right?
I bet you could name like,
like isn't Yale for the seventh when
yell was founded in late,
late 17 or I think Harvard as well,
or at least I think didn't Thomas
Jefferson wrote about a Cambridge,
Cambridge Oxford didn't.
I think Isaac Newton went to Oxford
gala.
17,
11.
Incredible.
Wow.
So like back then raising and that was
the.
So you think of let's just go to 17.
Oh,
one in 17,
11,
the intellectuals with the highest
expression of civilization because there
really wasn't that much technological
expression.
There really wasn't that much that had
been done.
There's where there was guns,
there was some machines.
I don't even know they even have a
printing press.
I don't believe they did in 17.
Oh,
one.
When was the dependent printing presses,
but with added,
was it?
Yes.
Oh,
that's right.
That's when Martin Luther was.
Um,
yeah,
they had a printing press back then.
Yeah.
Um,
um,
what's his name?
What's,
who invented the printing press?
I can't believe I'm forgetting this or
certainly didn't have typewriters.
So they,
they'd have to type face things.
So they would probably read off
manuscripts in schools.
So like when,
when they were in schools and they would
write,
I think they interpreted.
Did they have typewriters printing,
press.
Gutenberg.
What year was the typewriter?
Probably back then.
Here's what's crazy about it all.
This is something that I've been talking
about on stage is a how recent all that
was.
It seems,
it seems so far away for us,
but this is the way I describe it,
like people live to be 100,
that's 300 years ago.
It's three people crazy.
It's three people go whoa.
Thirteen years there with 17,
so they had 13 years of no typewriters
and then written by scrawls things with
sell written by Inc and I'm sure you
know,
it took a long time for that diffusion
of that innovation when you think the
typewriter really like totally kicked in
for 18 hundreds.
I bet that 19th century,
or maybe it was the 18th and the 19th
century before it was mass produced with
the industrial age when you could make a
lot of them for cheap enough to buy
would imagine.
Isn't it crazy to that?
We still use the cordy.
Uh,
the way the keyboards are assembled,
it works is to use the court.
He configuration it does work,
but it's not the fastest way to do it.
And some people are dorks.
No,
some people are dorks and they learned
the other way.
What's the other way?
Dove racks or something like that.
So you find the most efficient typing
configuration,
there's a second type of configuration
that's more efficient and not a friend
of mine tried it,
he tried to learn it and he said it was,
but it took them too long and he would
have to like reprogram computers when he
got them and enough to buy this certain
keyboard.
And if you had a laptop you were fucked.
This is the.
Yeah,
D
Devora,
black man or coal Mac.
Okay.
So there's two different ones.
Qwerty is what we have.
But a scroll up again so I could read
that.
So alternative keyboard layouts
explained should you switch to devor,
ach or coal muck.
So Cole,
c o,
l e m a k or D v O r a k.
So there's two different configurations,
like we see that configuration,
like it doesn't have quarterly at the
top.
The very top is like those Arrow keys
and the dot and the comma.
And then it starts with a p.
that's the first letter on the first,
uh,
the first column.
And then the other letter,
it's a as in the same place,
but as isn't in the same place right
next to a is.
Oh and S is way the fuck over there with
your other pinkie is.
It's really confusing.
But apparently if you really learn how
to type,
that's the best configuration because
your,
your hands can flow more smoothly.
And I think the scroll back up there
please.
So we can see that.
I think that configuration was,
if I remember correctly,
they invented that because the old
typewriters used to bind if you smash
keys next to each other too quickly.
So they decided to spread it out a
little bit.
I'm old enough to remember that.
That's pathetic.
I was.
Fuck,
I'm not kidding.
I remember that.
That happened in my with my mother's
when I was trying to type.
I'll be at Calgary this weekend,
just weekend.
I'll be there this weekend.
Thursday,
Friday,
Saturday.
Yuck.
Calgary.
Come see me.
I love Calgary.
I'm bringing heat to have big factory
farming up there.
They don't.
Not sure they do,
but I love color.
I love Calgary.
Trying to pay the people of Canada.
Don't you love Canadians to do.
We were talking about that.
Yeah.
The nicest people in the world.
Yeah,
so I always like to go to Calgary.
I'm going to.
I'm doing Massey Hall on December ninth.
Tickets went on presale today.
It's with Russell Peters and big Jay
Oakerson.
Really?
The two of you guys and a big chase?
Yeah.
Wow.
And that's December,
ninth night before the UFC.
That's impressive.
Yeah.
That's going to be the time.
What about you?
What are you doing that night?
I'll be in.
Well,
I know.
I don't know that night to say,
what are you doing in December ninth and
10th?
I'm going to be.
I know where I'm going to be in at the
Fort Lauderdale Improv.
I was going to ask you to come with us.
I would love to,
but the Fort Lauderdale Improv is one of
my favorite places to perform.
Yeah.
It's a fun place to.
While I'm especially if you like drunks
that are trying to escape from New
Jersey while we're plugging things,
because Brendan Schaub will beat me up
if I don't mention that fighter and kid
live will be in West Palm Beach November
11th and twelfth and in New York.
Gramsci Hall.
I think we're almost sold out a November
third.
Excellent.
Some CS.
Go see them.
Hilarious show.
My netflix special comes out this
Friday,
October 21st.
So available for download.
A.
People have been asking if you can get
it in other countries.
That's a real good question.
I will ask that myself and I'll find
out.
I'll get back to you.
You know,
since you told me about dairy and not
putting it in your coughing.
Uh,
I have not had the same throat issues.
Issues.
What kind of.
Well apparently,
and I didn't know this,
but Brendan told me that I was always
going.
Yeah,
no,
definitely.
And my wife said the same thing.
I was doing that with butter coffee.
I switched.
If you hear it and you say,
Hey,
I don't hear you clear your throat as
much,
you're always going to have to clear
your throat when you talk.
As much as I do a lot of bullshit coming
out of my mouth.
I got gotta,
but I drink black coffee now.
During the podcast I'll still drink
coffee with a grass fed butter and mct
oil,
but I don't drink it before podcast.
I don't drink it during a podcast I
should say.
Some people get bummed out like Steven l
he lives with that shit when he comes
in,
he's gonna come in and a couple of weeks
we have to give it to him because he'll
be sad.
He'll be sad.
Well there's nothing like really good
coffee with,
but I can't do any kind of a cow dairy
anymore.
I liked.
I know you said that you let you like
goat milk,
goat milk to raw milk and I like butter.
Butter.
I can kill.
I love butter.
I'll tell you when my daughter was
little,
she could not.
She,
if she drank milk at all,
she would throw up when she was really
little.
I could not drink milk.
We try,
you know,
it's hard to gauge when you have a
little kid,
see what they like,
what they don't like and what a.
But goat milk went down like that.
Like nothing.
It was really interesting.
She was,
I mean we're talking like she was a
really young baby.
She loved goat milk and for whatever
reason we stopped buying it and now we
buy just regular cow's milk.
They didn't really enchanting experiment
with with goats and kind of proving that
when you eat a food that's super
delicious,
like say you eat a peach and you love
peaches,
then you meet another peach and you love
but there's somewhere along the line
where with foods that are also giving
you nutrition,
you stopped as a trigger.
So whereas when you flavor food that
doesn't have any nutritional value,
you'll just keep eating it.
Like to read us.
You keep eating,
keep eating and keeping and it tricks
your body,
but there's something about this guy did
this experiment where this professor at
the university took these goats and he
starved them a phosphorous.
You didn't get many phosphorous in their
diet and they started doing weird things
like drinking their own urine and
drinking each other's urine and pawn at
the dirt and weird shit because they
need phosphorous.
So then he would feed them two different
samples of food,
but the coconut,
the coconut flavored,
and there was maple flavored food.
Uh,
and so the coconut flavored food,
when he'd feed them the coconut flavored
food,
uh,
then he would put a tube down their
throat and fill their stomachs with the
phosphorous.
And all of a sudden the goats were
instinctively going for the coconut
flavored food.
Now,
the,
the thing you'd say is,
well,
wait a minute,
maybe they just like coconut flavored
food.
But then he took the maple flavored food
and the coconut flavor food,
another control group.
And when those goats would eat the maple
food,
he'd stick the tube down their throat
and fill their stomachs with phosphorus.
Now the goats didn't know that they were
getting.
And so that control group would always
go for the maple.
Whoa.
Because they could,
even though they didn't know they are
getting phosphorous,
they just somehow equated the
fact that they were going to get the
phosphorus from that.
So they think that human beings have
this strange mechanism in their,
in their sort of brain and body where
they,
once you are eating a food that has
nutritional value,
so if it's sweet like dates,
it's got nutritional value as well or
whatever it might be.
Somewhere online we get satiated no
matter how delicious we find it,
if it's a natural foods.
True.
Because nobody eats like a giant bowl of
peaches.
Yeah.
You might eat two of your crazy right
and this,
but you'll eat a fucking pie.
Fuck yeah.
You lead a buyer,
you'll lead with ice cream.
You might eat that whole pie,
especially when it's artificially
flavored.
That that triggers this weird.
And one of the things in this book,
Dorito effect is that this guy talks
about the fact that that has kind of
thrown our,
you know,
that that's one of the things,
one of the culprits of obesity perhaps.
For sure.
Yeah,
for sure.
Flavoring,
flavoring for sure.
One hundred percent that totally makes
sense.
And then the sugar thing.
Yeah.
Chickens take chickens because we grow
them so fast.
So,
so usually like after World War Two,
the fastest chicken they could grow,
they had a contest was to get it to the
point where you could eat.
It was 14 weeks and now we've got it
down to six weeks and yeah.
So now you what you're eating his big
fat babies.
The problem is that the oils aren't the
same.
They're not as nutritious as an heirloom
chicken and chicken.
It's grown to eight when it far just
like the chickens you have,
they like worms and whatever they want.
I don't eat my chicken,
so.
Yeah.
But if you ate that chicken to be the
oils and the meat would be different and
it'd be.
And it'd be also more flavorful.
Um,
but because chicken has no taste,
we had to figure out.
There's a lot of things you had to do to
a chicken to make it take.
You've got to Brian it,
you've got to flavor it.
You've got to do all kinds of shit.
And it was way better than children.
That wild Turkey that we shot with
vanilla.
Fuck yeah,
that was delicious.
I,
I cook that whole thing on the grill.
I marinated it in my standard marinade,
which is newman zone,
balsamic vinegarette taste.
Just marinate and everything in that.
So good.
Yeah.
The red beat,
the darker meat was different.
Like the breast plates of like the way a
Rinella did.
He breaded it and fried it.
And I used to do this good.
I used to joke about when we did our
live podcast,
Brent and I about how I called it
Rogan's gift when you bought me that bow
and arrow.
And first I talked about when we hunted
Turkey and I was like,
kill a Turkey with dressed in the field
map and we cut it and it was.
I mean I didn't shoot it,
but I've secured Joe's hips when he shot
the Turkey and I go,
we got it.
We brought it up and it tastes just like
Turkey,
you know,
and they don't lock.
And then I go to this whole fucking
thing.
Remember when he gave me the bow and
Arrow and I was like,
I looked at,
I was like,
I didn't know what to say because I
don't know anything about boys,
but I think I saw the whole thing and I
went,
got me a fucking hoyt and you were like
carbon fiber.
I go,
whole thing,
hundred percent carbon fiber.
Now you like trying to show somebody who
really appreciate the gift,
but you don't know what to say about it.
Fuck,
I can shoot one shot,
one Arrow because you want to have me
over.
No,
you'd never.
You'd never organized it.
I'm not going to be the one who does all
the work.
You were so trusting.
The greatest is crazy.
The fuck that.
The grant and Swiss you with that expert
Guy Archer and the greatest tax was,
are you going to have me come over and I
was going to shoot with you guys.
You got so into it.
I got a text from you and you go,
hey brother,
this is not going to work today.
I got a lot of really important work to
do with this guy.
You're so obsessed with it.
He told me we need it needs to.
You need to be looking at one person,
like if you're working with one person,
you're working on their archery form.
Oh,
if you're working on two people at the
same time,
you're not even going to get half the
work done with either.
That makes sense and he wants to do
something with you and Brendan,
he wants to do something where he hooks
you guys up with hoyt.
Both teaches you and you guys could all
make a video.
It can make a video of you guys shooting
bows for the first time when.
But he's like,
it has to like,
he's like,
I can't do that and work with you
because work with me.
I'm many years advanced.
Not,
not saying that I'm really good because
I'm not.
I'm so far advanced from you guys.
Like he would have to work with you.
So specifically on every little thing
and there's so many different things you
have to think of when it takes a long
fucking time.
Like give me an example of bone arrow.
So give me an example,
because I would imagine how you stand,
how you breathe,
how you pull back.
There's a ton of different things.
It's how you hold the bow.
What technique used to draw back what
muscles you're pulling with.
You have to be super conscious of
pulling with the muscles and your
scapula.
Like,
Whoa,
where's your elbow position?
How will you torquing the bow?
How are you gripping the bose,
the bow,
crossing the lifeline on your hand.
If it is,
that's a problem.
You've got to readdress it.
How you gripping it with your fingers.
Do you have a death grip?
Do you have a loose grip?
Is that affecting the actual trajectory
of the Arrow is at torquing when you
release it,
when you release it,
do you punch the triggers?
The Arrow flying randomly left and
right,
and all sorts of different directions.
There's so many forever.
It takes forever.
And I'm not even like one 100 of the way
there,
but I'm three years ahead of you.
Do you think,
do you think that the,
uh,
here fucked?
Do you think that when you get really
good at something like just take our
trays and example,
I know there's a book called the archery
book,
but do you think that when you master
something like archery,
like do you think that's almost enough
to learn about life or do you think that
that's a little bit romantic?
I think there are elements from anything
that you get really good at that apply
to life.
The idea that learning something,
getting really good at it,
you learn about life has been disproved
over and over again by extreme winters
who are gigantic fuck ups in their
regular life.
I think when you get obsessed with
something to the point of excellence to
the point where you're the best at it or
one of the best added or you're in the
running to be one of the best at in your
fucking brain does not have much room
for a lot of the normal shit that
everybody else has stuffed in their
head.
You're not going to be online on forums,
gossiping about celebrity bullshit or
you know,
talking shit about the latest movie or
talking shit about the latest song.
You will be obsessed with one task and
that does not necessarily make you a
balance person.
You might not have time for your family.
You might have time to talk to your
friends.
You might not have time to have friends.
I mean you might be in recovery
training.
You might be doing a million different
things to try to accentuate your
abilities in basketball and primarily a
male characteristic.
Of course,
that's a feature of the male brain and
the ability to exclude everything else,
but one thing,
it's very rare in women,
but you see it and it's an aberration.
You see it.
A lot of women athletes you see in a lot
of women's superstar athletes for sure.
It's also much rarer.
Apparently,
I mean worse.
Yeah,
well that's why when someone like Rhonda
Rousey comes along,
you go,
oh,
look at that.
There's one of those,
you know,
there's a female version of the super
winter exists,
you know,
and they seek out male versions of those
super winters and you know,
they have super winter babies that's a,
you know,
standard stuff,
but it's,
it's to me,
I don't think it's indicative of
learning about life.
It's learning how to get really awesome
at one thing and that might translate if
you can step away from the madness and
the momentum of whatever the fuck it is.
You're obsessed with that ability to
really completely focusing on one thing
might aid you if you can completely
focus in on life,
but the idea that an athlete or an
archer or anybody else is doing anything
obsessive,
Lee is actually focusing on life.
That's,
that might not be the case.
That's a good point.
I never thought of that.
That's a good way to articulate because
even like you see like great artists
like Paul Jackson,
pollock,
whoever they were,
they,
they weren't that happy.
I mean they,
they,
you know,
a lot of that,
a lot of examples of like,
you know,
great authors are great artists or
whoever they are,
and they,
they were so obsessed with their
expression that they also live
depressive lives now.
Whether or not whether or not though
depressives tend to obsess might be
another question,
but that's probably both.
Both things are probably true.
You know,
I was a giant prince fan still am.
He was like one of my all time favorite
musical artists.
So you know,
when I found out that prince had all
these issues with his health and he's
taking pain pills and he was addicted to
pain pills,
it was almost like in denial about it.
I was like,
no,
that guy's too smart for that.
Like that guy is like,
he's smarter than the system.
We figured out how to make a symbol to
get out of a contract because he had to
use his name.
So he was the artist formerly known as
Prince and became a mean.
That was what.
That was all bad.
They will look,
you can't use the name Prince.
It's like,
oh,
for real motherfucker.
Do you know how famous I am?
I'll make a symbol.
I'll be,
I'll just be assembled locks this and.
But then when you hear prints like
interviewed,
which you rarely do,
you see as art,
which is amazing.
You know,
I still to this day,
I think the purple rain,
you know,
like it's one of the greatest songs when
the greatest.
It was a great movie musical album.
Yeah,
let's go crazy.
I mean he had some fucking jams and in
that time he was revolutionary.
He's just weird little androgynous guy.
And then just like the whole thing was
crazy.
The dancing is like hair.
Oh my God,
I should have known.
Oh my God.
The way,
ways that it wouldn't last.
And he had that hair all done up at a
high stiletto heels.
It was amazing.
My friend,
my friend Tommy,
I'll never forget my friend Tommy goes,
he's so fucking gay.
And then he goes in there and he goes,
but he's fucking awesome.
While he wasn't gay,
it wasn't good.
He was heterosexual and he wasn't even
really like gay people.
That's one of the weirdest jobs is
witnessed and it was.
He kind of said some homophobic shit
that people get really mad at him about,
about one of the reasons he was trying
to equate,
okay,
stop.
He was trying to equate all of these
different things that were going on in
the world with people not following
God's way and sticking their dick in any
place they want and people are like,
Whoa,
whoa,
whoa.
Did you just say that?
Yeah,
let's go crazy.
You're the guy.
The fucking addresses in purple and
talks about being a pervert,
but he's very,
very conservative and a lot of ways
wasn't it?
But what were you saying about to say is
that he also was into chem trails.
He also believed that the government was
spraying the sky and that's what was
making everybody angry.
So when you listened to him talk and you
hear him like discuss things,
you'll realize,
oh,
okay,
what?
What he said about Kennedy.
I was funny.
He said,
you know,
what I've noticed is that when a plane
would go by and you'd see these trails
and everybody started acting crazy and
they'd be fighting and I'm all I'm
saying is take a look at it,
just take a look at it.
And I was like,
I won't,
I won't take a right here.
I love you as a musical genius.
I won't take a look at it,
but there's also a problem that when he
said that he was probably 50 and when he
got famous he was probably 20,
so 30 years of being completely
insulated and isolated people kissing
your ass and you saying a bunch of
poetic shit while you were alone in
Minneapolis and he did right.
Myopic enough to never read a newspaper
or anything.
I mean,
no,
I don't know.
I don't know what he was like.
I don't know what he was looking for.
That's what he was like,
because I know,
I know somebody.
My friend's brother was in his band.
Really?
Yes.
Your friend's brother taught with
prince,
my friend Rico.
Somehow many different types of aids.
Did he get well?
Uh,
no,
he rica simone was just wonderful guy
who died of colon cancer and his brother
fucking what was his name?
His brother toward prints and,
and he knew prince and man,
that dude was,
he did,
he really did play every instrument
fluently and he had high standards and,
and he's just a,
like,
nobody worked like him.
No body but it,
it required almost all of them,
right?
I mean it just,
it.
He was so devoted to just music and well
it's obvious.
I mean his,
he was,
his style was so diverse.
You just mixed it up a lot,
you know,
he would like remember raspberry beret.
It comes out of nowhere.
I mean he,
he was different when he's saying that
Tom Jones cover and that high operatic
voice,
you know,
I,
I didn't meet him but I stood next to
him at a party.
Prince,
do you?
No.
Prince,
do you know how small he was?
How small was it?
I'm going to go ahead and say,
and I don't care if NASA comes and shows
me like his measurements.
He under five feet tall.
Really?
And I'm not kidding,
he was straight up under five feet tall.
I couldn't.
He was in high heels and I couldn't
believe how small he was white and he
walked by me twice and then he was
standing in a group and I was,
I was,
they're invisible because everybody else
was way too famous and I just kept
looking at him and I was like,
don't stare at a print stuff staring
prince neck normally you fucking
asshole.
He was a,
just a little bit above a dwarf.
Wow.
For Real.
He was absolutely tiny.
Shockingly.
You think you the most pussy ever for a
little tiny guy?
Probably don't know what his sex life
was.
I don't know.
You know,
who knows?
Used to bank Carmen Electra,
right?
I know he wrote a lot of songs for
people.
I don't know.
I was never in the room.
I shouldn't say bang.
I worked with Carmen Electra.
I did too.
What a doll.
She's pretty such a cool,
very nice.
She's fun.
It was friendly and professional and I
wonder why she hasn't.
She's a good person to probably just
chilling.
I wish good things.
Do you read this year?
So I'm a good guy.
Here's his job.
I was doing a series that I thought was
going gonna make me a star yet.
Another disappointment.
Yet another disappointment with
gentleman.
I was doing fed actress.
Oh yeah,
man,
I remember when you were high on that.
He lost a lot of weight.
I got a lot of attention for that.
And then,
uh,
was Christie.
Allie was like,
inner peak,
but I hadn't famous Broadway directors
calling me,
telling me I was great on the show and
they wanted to put me in their plant.
I was so excited when they trying to
fuck you or they're just trying to get
some Dick.
No,
no,
probably not.
I wish I'm not that good looking.
What happened?
That was a showtime show,
wasn't it?
It was a big deal because of the name.
It was like very controversial.
Like wow,
she's so bold.
That name.
Yeah.
Since she was like one of the first
people to have like a,
a great sense of humor.
She's about eating herself into a
bizarre shape.
She's just,
she's smart and a force of nature.
She's a scientologist in her house,
her house many times,
and she had so many animals.
She had to blind lemurs.
You know,
Christie would be the one who was like,
you got a blind monkey.
I'll take it.
She had a rabbit,
a giant desert hair that couldn't use
the back.
Its back legs.
Do you not feel the need to temper?
She's so smart with.
She's a scientologist.
Well,
having read,
going clear as you have a.
and having been in class for over 10
years with many scientologists.
So I remember the class that was
mentioned in that book.
I remember when I used to go visit you.
Do you remember when you and I went to
watch a guy sing songs?
Yes,
and he was fantastic.
He was wonderful and hassles and his
shoes,
his choice.
He said something interesting about it.
He'd been scientologist for 20 years and
go,
he call and he said,
I have a scientologist did.
Somebody asked me that.
He said,
let me just let me put this to rest as
I'm a member of the church.
Tells you what does that mean.
I,
I've taken a lot of classes there and
I've got nothing out of a lot of classes
and some classes.
I've gotten a lot.
If you want to call me a scientologists
then go ahead and then we just get to in
class.
He was a fucking great teacher,
but his.
I mean he's in a,
not A.
I think it makes him in Jeffrey Tambor,
who's The star of transparent,
used to be a scientologist for years and
he quit and it's called.
He blew.
He ran.
He got out.
Do you get in trouble when you do that?
No,
but there's David miscavige.
The secretive sort of leader has never
been painted in a very favorable light.
Especially if you read that book.
I don't know though.
Yeah.
It seems like a naughty little group of
humans.
It does.
It does,
but I'm.
Allie was in that naughty little group
of human.
Yeah,
like any,
like any group,
anybody who belongs to any group,
you're going to have dogma.
You're going to.
You're going to need tradition and story
to to keep that group together.
You can't have a group without having
stories written by a guy on a captain's
outfit on with metals he gave himself.
Yeah,
he was,
uh,
he was probably very crazy and crazy as
fuck.
Apparently,
there's a great new documentary that
I've been hearing about called Holy Hell
about some guy who got involved in some
really nutty cult in 1985 and was in a
cult for like 20 years and a documented
a bunch of crazy shit and is going to
put a documentary out about it.
Wow.
Yeah.
And the cult leader is apparently he hit
his past as a gay porn star and he was
there.
He is at,
as we have the ABS on that guy,
but people are always going to be long
to call.
People.
Always going to want to group up with
their version of the truth.
A documentary villain for the ages and
unprecedented closeup look.
We watch with bated breath as the mask
slowly,
slowly pulled away,
pulled off.
Um,
what I always thought baited was B,
a t be a t,
e d,
what does it even mean?
Baden Bat ed.
Bated breath.
Like,
oh,
I thought I thought that it was ba
because bated breath,
I never knew what it meant,
and the in great suspense very anxiously
or excitedly,
he waited for a reply to his offered
with bated breath.
I never knew what the,
I knew what it implied,
you know,
that you waited and it was highly
anticipating it,
but I never knew led.
It was spelled that way or what it was
supposed to get out of weird words that
you'll hear sometimes time ago.
Not a long,
like,
um,
I heard somebody use the word
solipsistic and I was like,
yes,
of course.
Yeah.
I've said I've got to go back to a
definition on that one and I never did.
It just means.
Has anything else ever baited?
Is it only bated breath?
I've only heard it used in context of
bated breath,
but it's not a weird,
that's a very bizarre word.
If it's only used with breath,
that's it.
You know,
some people are so good with words.
Like I was listening to a,
I was reading the lyrics of Bob Dylan's
a after we won a Nobel prize for
literature.
Solipsistic solipsistic means means
essentially that you can only be sure
that you exist and you're not even sure
anybody else use theory that the self is
all that can be known to exist.
Hmm.
That's a weird word.
It's a very limited view of the world
killed Bob.
Dylan won't respond to them.
The people trying to give him his prize.
It's like Bob Dylan,
fuck off.
If you look at the lyrics of chimes of
freedom and and look at what he was
writing when he was in his twenties to
take a look at an Indian.
He had an interview I listened to and
they were talking about these lyrics and
he said,
and that's something he said,
what do you mean?
He said,
I had no idea how I wrote that and I
could never do it again.
That magic is gone.
And he says,
people look me up and they'll come out
and asked me about organic farming and
he goes,
what do you know about organic farming?
He was absolutely nothing.
They just put all this stuff on him
because he was a great lyricist and a
great thinker.
Obviously he wrote all along the
watchtower.
Hell yeah,
he wrote,
he was such a fucking influence of
springsteen was just doing a BBC
interview and he said it was the first
time I'd ever heard anybody describe
America the way it really was looking at
as far between sundowns finished and
midnights broken tool.
We ducked inside the doorway,
thunder crashing as majestic.
Bells of bolts struck shadows in the
sounds seeming to be the chimes of
freedom flashing.
Yeah.
He was,
uh,
an interesting voice of a generation.
Listen to this part,
flashing for the warriors whose strength
is not to fight flashing for the
refugees on an unarmed road of flight
and for each and every underdog soldier
in the night as we gazed upon the chimes
of freedom flashing.
He's a young guy reading it because I
read a book.
What's that?
It's probably high as fuck.
And he ruined all those.
I don't think he was.
How dare you?
You don't think he was doing drugs?
Bob Dylan?
Um,
itch please.
I,
uh,
I think mom was doing drugs.
I don't,
I don't know.
I don't know enough about of Shit for
sure.
That was.
He was smoking weed and Lsd for sure.
I would imagine.
Well,
La,
who's that rock historian who said that
the rock and roll is the greatest.
When they were doing,
they were doing psychedelics and they
were smoking weed and cocaine and heroin
came in.
It was when the music pat.
That's when Lou Reed and that's when all
those guys,
the Mamas and Papas and all those guys,
you know,
after Haight Ashbury,
I think 1968 that that when when heroin
and marijuana and cocaine came in,
the music basically died.
A lot of time was smoked.
Says according to Eric von Schmidt,
the early sixties contemporary of
Dylan's in the Cambridge folk scene.
Cambridge folk scene.
Good Lord.
Smells like feet.
Where he dylan in a singing pow.
Richard Farina usually got together a
lot of pot with smoke,
so yeah,
it was probably just doing a lot of pot,
but if they were doing a lot of pot,
I guarantee you they did some acid to
get ahold of some mushrooms.
Psychedelics and we'd probably are not
going to be your enemies as an artist,
but I would imagine heroin and cocaine
don't usually they.
When do you think it's going to come a
day when we require that of politicians?
We require psychedelic experiences.
Like we require education.
When Bob Dylan turned the Beatles on to
marijuana while you got them.
Hi,
this is outrageous.
Um,
when do you think it's going to be a
requirement for politicians?
Like,
I think every politician should have a
mushroom
trip.
I don't think that's a lot to ask.
I think you should.
You should have to have survived us
threshold braking experience,
a real breakthrough experience.
I would start with politicians having to
go to another country for awhile and
just seeing how people keep them here at
dose him up.
Fuck all that.
Travel.
Travel's dangerous doses.
Just doses.
Just,
just fucking put them in a room for a
bunch of people are gonna.
Watch the doors.
Keep them in place.
Turn the lights off.
Keep keep them silent and just dose the
shit out of them.
I just think we,
we all know everybody that's had one
that knows that there's giant benefits
to them,
but it's poo pooed in society as being
like a drug that's detrimental to your
health.
It's detrimental to your,
your,
your function as a kid or you don't know
where that droves coming from.
So that's why change it.
It was legal,
used to be right and sure until Nixon
that fuck.
Nixon fucked up a lot of things.
People don't realize like when people
were doing an ass in the fifties and
sixties,
it wasn't even illegal.
You know,
there's a lot of stuff.
Marijuana was illegal,
but mushrooms weren't illegal until
1970.
It's amazing.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
But there's still stuff that's not
technically illegal.
That's way more powerful than that five
methoxy DMT.
You used to be able to buy it.
Not for human consumption from chemical
companies online.
He used to be able to buy like a fucking
coffee tumbler full of it.
Yeah.
I'm not joking.
You could smoke and meanwhile and
effective dose.
It's five Meo DMT is in more potent
psychedelic ounce per ounce gram per
gram than nn dmt.
It's the most potent,
it doesn't have the visuals,
so it doesn't give you the visuals,
but as far as like,
um,
effective dose,
it's the most potent,
so a small amount can get you fucked up
and used to be able to buy that stuff.
Well,
pot was illegal.
You used to be able to buy five Meo dmt
online and if you smoke did,
you just got shot through a cannon to
the center of the universe.
We cease to exist,
the terrifying trip because you
absolutely thought you were dead,
like you absolutely ceased to exist and
you became one with everything and it's,
it's a very weird non visual experience.
Whereas DMT is filled with all these
patterns and this beautiful feeling that
you get the five Meo dmt is like this
powerful white geometry.
It's all just pale white and all these
weird sort of microscopic fractal
geometric patterns that are sort of
dancing around you.
But one thing is invisible.
Like what do you,
what do you like about psychedelics?
What do you think,
um,
is typically the benefit of the second?
I think there's a lot of benefits to any
experience and extreme experiences give
you more benefits.
You take in more data knowing that that
psychedelic experience is possible.
Just knowing that that experience that
you can hit,
you can hit that note that you can get
into that,
that dimension,
wherever the fuck it is in a psychedelic
experience,
it makes you look at the that is
unchanging around you without drugs and
it makes you go,
oh well this isn't all there is.
Like there's another thing that you can
get to really easily.
You can get to this other thing really
easily and although it's not regular
everyday drive through starbucks,
stuck in traffic,
waiting for your phone call,
so the alarm goes off in the morning.
You don't want to get up.
It's not that world,
but it's still an accessible world
that's right there.
That's mindblowing.
Well,
I think what you said Eagle dissolvent,
but even prior to that is the idea that
it shows you what is possible or what is
out there.
That's,
that's to me the most important element
for change in a person's consciousness.
When you are shown that there is a
higher bar or you're shown that there
is,
there are other possibilities,
more illuminating possibilities because
a lot of times you can live in a,
in a world where your vision of reality
that's given to you and that's that
you're privy to on a daily basis is so
limited that you don't even.
You need to be shown that there is
something higher to aspire to.
Yeah,
for sure.
You know what I'm saying?
And so I think that's kind of the value.
Maybe that's one of the biggest values
to quote unquote education or the
biggest value to exposing yourself to
experiences like you're talking about.
I think both of them are valid and both
of them are important.
I think you should have like difficult
tests.
I think it's probably good for people to
try to run a marathon.
I think that's good for people to try to
rock climb.
I think it's good for people to go on
long difficult hikes.
I think you learn from that just like
you learn from education and I don't
think it's.
I don't think they're mutually exclusive
and I think they combined together for a
balanced person,
a person who tries to do and tries to
accomplish difficult things along with
becoming educated.
The problem is that this whole
competitive thing that arises amongst
people where you want to be the best at
something like we were talking about,
which sort of defines you in this way,
that requires a lot of tunnel vision and
it requires you to not be fully balanced
and not be.
You know,
one of the things I had a problem with
when I was teaching,
when I teach martial arts,
I,
I noticed that smart people were way
more nervous before fights and I was
like,
oh,
I see what's going on.
They are aware of the variables like
whereas these dumb people that you would
teach or the people that weren't as
smart awareness,
curious,
they didn't have nearly as much of a
problem with competing.
I'm like,
this is really fascinating.
Like this really smart people are aware
of almost too much.
Yeah.
Well,
David Foster Wallace in this incredible
essay called how Tracy Austin broke my
heart.
It was.
It's really story about Tracy Austin
when she won Wimbledon at 14.
Oh,
and and he said then she wrote a book
like on her experience and trying to get
a physical genius to describe what they
do.
Part of the reason that they performed
so well under pressure.
Sometimes it's not because they're dumb,
but their brain,
they don't have the kind of mine that a
writer would have,
which is to ask a thousand questions to
be introspective to the point where
you're essentially neurotic or going
around in a circle.
You can't have that.
You've got to be able to shut that down.
That's why when they ask great athletes
to describe what was going on in their
mind,
when they got that ball over the end
zone,
it's invariably kind of disappointing
because they never really know how to
explain it.
What they say is,
I just knew I had to get the football
cross line and we just executed and my
team was there.
It's not hard.
I just did this thing recently about
climbing this area of Yosemite that's
incredibly different.
Difficult to pass.
What is,
what is it?
It's.
It's just.
It was just released.
I think the video is called heaven
something heaven.
Alex honnold heaven.
I bet it's very.
He's talking about as he's moving and
he's doing these years.
I'm not thinking about anything.
I'm just executing and he goes,
I'm just executing the movements and
he's literally upside down climbing this
thing thousands of feet up in the air.
It's.
It's horrific.
When you watch them do that and you're
like,
well,
I dunno.
I mean I guess he knows what he's doing
and he's done it before,
but when you watch him do it,
he free Solos.
Heaven that's experiential is hard to
put into words,
right?
I mean he's,
he's,
he's the ultimate experiential guru.
A guy who you.
But look what he's doing.
Oh my God is not using.
Oh No.
He doesn't use any ropes.
You look at.
No,
it's heaven.
This is what it's called.
But if you,
if you see how he's climbing this thing,
this,
this one area.
I don't know what mountain is that?
These are.
Maybe it is El Capitan.
Is that?
I think that's El Capitan.
I think that's all cat.
But anyway,
what he's doing is he's climbing up.
If it's not straight,
it's leaned back.
So he's hanging as he's climbing and
he's climbing thousands of feet above
the ground,
like look at the trees below him there.
Look at that fucking picture.
When they find guys that fall off El
Cap,
they can't really find much of their
body apparently.
Find out if that's the name of this
thing,
how many pull ups can he do?
Did you ask him to do that?
I want to know.
I don't know.
Maybe you told me.
I'm so nervous.
He didn't say what the mountain is.
It's.
I think it's Yosemite.
Just carry a small shoot on the back of
his body.
Please just go.
Yeah.
Well He.
No,
no,
no shoots.
There's no shoots.
There's no getting out here.
Apparently it's,
he knows what he's doing and he can do
it.
Who's done it before?
But there's a lot of free solo climber
dudes that see the stuff that he does
and even old school climbers,
they go.
It's not a matter of if,
it's when it's a matter of when there
was this whole,
um,
television show they did about it,
where there's these old school climber
guys were kind of upset with them.
You know,
they're thinking that what he's doing is
taking far too many risks,
but he doesn't think so.
He thinks he knows what he's doing and
he knows how to do it well.
I would imagine.
I would imagine the route is called
Heaven at glacier point.
Glacier point is the mountain.
I would imagine the feeling,
but by the way,
good job Brian Gallon.
I watched I,
one piece of stone.
I'm like,
it looks like Al Capp.
I've fucking,
I've climbed 10 times.
We're both wrong about 100 things in a
podcast all the time,
but harmful jamie here with the google.
I'm sure my uranium one will get a,
you know,
I'm sure they had some picture.
Oh,
come on.
Oh my God.
Look at that picture.
That's insane.
On what?
What is that?
Is that a 45 degree angle?
I don't know,
Dude.
That's horrifying.
Is that Jamie?
You would know is that it's close to a
45 degree and not get tired.
How does have you ever rock climbed?
No.
Is the most exhausting thing.
You your fingers and hands.
I mean you get so pumped so quickly that
you,
you just,
you literally can't use your hands and
I'm talking to you as very fat fingers.
Like it's really interesting cause he's
a very thin guy.
He did the podcast.
I know when I was talking to him,
his asked him to show me his hands
because you have fat fingers.
Yeah.
He's a friend of mine.
Got Damn.
It just doesn't have.
I mean they're not small hands.
What's the way do you think?
Very light.
Yeah.
It was probably 1:50
tall.
If I had to guess,
probably like a five,
11,
six feet.
How tall is he fucking done,
dude?
No,
I just want to know what his body type.
I think he's a real light and long and
thin and strong for that kind of stuff
because all the time and he just knows
how to climb and he knows what he's
doing and he stays super calm while he
does it.
That's one of the things that he
emphasized.
This is him at the very top.
See,
look how every movement is like really
measured.
Dude.
He's the master.
He's a master at that kind of stuff and
he lives in a van.
He,
he lives in his van and he drives around
and just finds places.
Parks and climbs.
He's incredible.
He's,
he really is.
It's interesting.
He's like Samurai or something freak,
that's for sure.
But I mean,
he's made this name by being this guy
who does the dangerous scary climbing
stuff that nobody wants to do.
When I read that book,
the Book of five rings by me and month
Masashi like I got the same sense that,
that was the experiential,
like his life,
the margin for error in a,
in a sword fight.
Uh,
and also he said how you practice has to
be almost life and death like until
you're no longer doing it,
like the,
the,
the extreme notion of living always on
the edge.
Um,
and that,
that feels like the exact same path,
mindset and probably probably result.
I don't know if you've got a lot of
ways,
God forbid he dies,
but the appearance seems,
see sort of when that becomes a
necessity or that becomes,
I guess how you or what you crave,
this sort of intimate relationship
between life and death.
This sort of like,
you know,
I think it would,
he craves,
is doing it like getting some slow.
The flow you get into it knowing that
there's a massive risk behind it,
but still being able to execute
flawlessly.
That's what he craves,
you know?
And instead of it being a sword coming
out of him that he has to check instead
of that,
it's him figuring out how to climb a 45
degree face that's hanging 2000 feet
above the ground or whatever the fuck
that is.
How many feet do you think that is above
the ground?
When you look down and see those trees
in the background,
it looks like more than 2000 feet.
Yeah,
it does.
How many feet do you think you can climb
in a day?
You know,
because a mile is what?
Five thousand feet?
500 something feet.
Now a mile is 1000,
300,
434,000,
280 yards.
Dairies,
losses.
It's $3,000
along with yards to fuck 3000 foot
vertical wall.
So almost a month.
I got like three quarters of a mile up.
Three hundred feet above the crown in
that over overhang with me and 40 feet.
You're climbing out 40 feet.
Come on,
my God.
Oh my God.
Let's wrap with that.
Let's end with Alex honnold.
You're a bad motherfucker.
Motherfucker.
He lit up when Brian was going to
introduce them to porn stars though.
He was like,
what?
You know them really no points.
Yeah.
You ain't.
You Ain't get no pussy up there on the
mountain.
Even a zen monk can fall for those.
You know those cars.
That's why they stay abstinent.
Massive distraction from your climbing.
Oh yeah.
Brian Collin,
the fighter and the kid.com.
TFA K t you qrs this weekend Lbgtq I a
calgary,
Calgary this weekend,
a csn in West Palm Beach.
November 11th,
twelfth,
November fourth or third gramercy
theater in New York City.
Fat K.com.
T Dot k.com
for the fighter and the kid.
Shit,
that's it.
Friends.
We'll be back tomorrow with Trevor
Valley.
I'm a paleontologist archeologists type
dude.
He's been on before.
He should be a lot of fun and that's it.
You folks see you soon.