Oh,
an unusual early morning for me,
an early morning episode of the podcast.
Ethan,
very nice to meet you,
man.
Thanks for doing this now.
It's my pleasure.
So drug policy alliance.
How far are we away?
Let's let's get this done.
Come on.
Well,
it depends what it is,
right when it comes to legalizing
marijuana.
I mean we got momentum that nobody could
have believed we'd had just four or five
years ago.
Right.
So in that sense things are flying.
I don't think it's in the bag yet
though,
you know,
I might.
One of my biggest concerns is the sense
of overconfidence where this whole thing
could trip up.
Yeah.
My biggest,
my biggest concern is that,
and it's also like Jeb Bush and guys
like that,
like if those guys or that fat fuck from
New Jersey Christy,
can you believe the crapola coming out
of his mouth on this stuff?
Somehow he's going to identify that
niche of the Republican party that wants
to keep locking up people for weed and
that Rubio was saying stuff like that
the other day.
So I have a theory.
Yeah,
I have a theory.
I think what he's trying to do is make
sure he's never president and really do.
I really think that that guy is so
deeply in embedded in corruption in New
Jersey that the moment he actually
becomes a serious candidate for
president,
I think the shit is going to come out of
the closet.
Like a broken fire hydrant.
Yeah,
because I think also his popularity has
fallen so low in New Jersey right now
that he just wanted to get out of town.
I think that's why he's running for
president.
It's better than dealing with stuff and
trend and acknowledging all the screw
ups he's had.
I mean,
I'll tell you something,
that we lead drug policy alliance lead
that effort to legalize medical
marijuana in Jersey.
Back a few years ago,
governor core resigned last billy sign
was that one and then Christie came
around.
He did old and Donald and didn't want to
do it.
Wouldn't have rutgers university grow
the weed.
They didn't want to grow the weed.
It was weird.
And then finally he went on vacation
like by 18 months,
his term,
he came back.
He goes,
I want to do this now,
and I kept wondering whether you had a
puff on vacation,
who knows in New Jersey,
still hobbling along.
You know,
Christie,
the funny thing also is when it comes to
ending the drug war more broadly,
he's highly unpredictable.
You know,
we took on the bail bond industry,
the private bill button,
the trees,
just trying to keep people locked up for
as long as possible.
Local jails and Christy liquored up
coming on our side,
you know,
bond industry was working to make sure
that people stayed in jail.
I gotta tell you,
if you look at all the corrupt actors
and the prison industrial complex,
you know,
you get to prison guards union,
you get the private prison corporations
to private bail bond industry.
I mean if ever there was a sorted gang
that had to be it.
And so we led that effort.
We got Christie to come along with us,
push them back,
you know,
so Christie's done some decent stuff.
He'll talk about addiction as a health
issue.
There was an issue,
you know,
people dying of overdoses and we wanted
to deal with that.
And he was initially vetoing it.
Did we got Bon Jovi involved?
He wanted to get a photo op,
but by Jovi.
So whose daughter had odd unfortunately
lived.
So he came along then.
So he's been a mixed bag.
But for some reason on this marijuana
thing,
he's just going over the top anti
legalization.
I don't really get it.
I think he's.
I really honestly think that he's trying
to make sure that he's never president.
I really do.
I think he understands the tide and I
think he's terrified.
I think he has a lot of skeletons in his
closet.
He's involved in New Jersey politics,
New Jersey politics is so much more
corrupt than New York politics,
which is the most corrupt part of the
country.
Yeah.
Although,
you know,
we're breaking some records in New York,
you think just last six months.
Both the head of the assembly and the
head of the Senate have both been
indicted,
you know,
so you know,
it's neck and neck between us in Jersey.
New Jersey's got that strong tradition
history.
I remember Christie made his name by
being the federal prosecutor going after
these guys.
Then he gets himself involved in this
bridge gate scandal,
you know,
with a guy on one side of the bridge,
shut down traffic for two days because
somebody had done something they didn't
like.
So I think Christy had his moment back
in 2012,
2011 when he was hot and riding high in
the polls and his whole bullying act was
going over.
Well I think he's down in done with
already just wants to be out of town.
Well you can only shine like that as a
bully for so long because if you're that
guy that's yelling and screaming at
everybody else and she's sticking your
fat gut out there,
eventually people start going,
hey man,
what about you?
I mean,
you know,
the sad thing,
that's the way Giuliani was,
the only thing that saved his ass was
9:11,
9:11
comes along.
Sudden he goes from being like 20
percent of the polls to 90 percent and
he's the heroic mayor.
But quite frankly people were burnt out
on his act and it was only.
And God forbid we do a crisis like that
gives Kristi a second run.
Well,
Giuliani was like the antidote for mayor
Dinkins.
Yeah,
that's right.
Dinkins was like this really calm,
laid back guy and really racist people
would call them.
The janitor folks who weren't around
back in the nineties in New York don't
know that.
First of all,
time square was a completely different
animal.
Like you go to time square now it's this
beautiful tourist trap.
It's all neon lights and shining stars
and I kind of missed the old time
square.
It was a CD,
it was CD.
It's now got overtop the other way,
you know where it's like Disneyland on
42nd street.
Imagine that though.
If you could ever go back to New York
City in 19 eighties and then see what
times square was like and then come back
again.
You know what it is.
I mean,
because I live in New York City and so I
live in the center of the universe in
which you realize is that there's only
so long in the center of the universe
can go on without,
you know,
people reinvesting in it.
It's the island of Manhattan has got to
be the most amazing island in the world
and I'm,
it's just glowing these days.
What do you,
what do you like about it?
Well,
first of all,
I mean,
I like being in this,
you know,
some people say it's a nice place to
visit.
I want to live someplace else.
For me,
I want to live in New York.
I want to ride that energy and then as
long as she can get out often,
I mean the key is being able to get out
of town and I'm out of town about half
the time,
so I get to go out,
see the stars,
see the ocean,
you know,
take hikes and then go back and write
that energy.
I love the fact that it's a pedestrian
city.
I don't own a car,
right?
I can walk to work,
I can take the subway,
you know,
and then I want.
But this past weekend for the first time
you,
Californians and others might not
appreciate this,
but you're all over the place.
I drove my bike from the upper west side
of Manhattan down to Brighton Beach.
About a 20 mile bike ride over the
Brooklyn Bridge through Brooklyn,
along the New York harbor.
It was gorgeous.
And the next day I took my bike up the
Hudson river or to dikeman street.
So there's great beauty there.
Everything's there.
I could,
I could live my entire life and not go
more than five blocks from my apartment.
And everything's available.
So the diversity of people live in
there,
you know,
everybody comes through there.
A and New York,
New York's just a center.
It's happened to you.
It's perfect for you.
It's perfect.
Friendly.
Jeff,
my manager actually is a great friend of
mine.
Has been there forever and he couldn't
imagine living anywhere else,
but he also has a house on an island
that he visits occasionally and he'll
stay there for a week and just sort of
like tell you know what,
there's this place called fire island
which spent an hour outside of New York.
Yeah.
And so there's the fame,
you know,
the,
the pines is the famous where all the
gay community is.
And then there's all the other little
towns,
uh,
you know,
and I been out there twice this summer.
It reminds me almost of Venice.
It's an island with no cars and take a
one on my office is half a block from
Penn station,
jump on the train one hour than a half
hour ferry and also in his gorgeous
little island that's got no cars on it
and you just relax.
And the no cars things is what keeps
people away.
There's a lot of deer on that island.
They used to be more,
you know,
now they're putting all this birth
control stuff in the water for the
theater.
Isn't that hilarious?
Yeah.
You know,
doing,
you know,
in the water shouldn't say the water
because that would be good.
Everybody.
But yeah,
they had to deal with that solid thing
there.
What are they doing it for food or
something?
Leaving in something like that cost
hundreds of thousands of dollars by the
way.
Is that right?
Yeah,
they're trying to do the same thing to
the Hamptons is a real dear issue.
And there was two options.
One bringing hunters and they were going
to hunt at night.
Snipers.
You reminded me there was a piece in the
Wall Street Journal years,
years ago,
maybe decades ago.
The Institute for Advanced Study is like
what?
It's this gorgeous place next door to
Princeton University and it's where
Albert Einstein was some of the greatest
philosophers and scientists.
It's where they go when they're in their
older years and do their thinking,
bucolic setting,
and they were overwhelmed with deer.
So the question was what to do?
Well,
you couldn't shoot them in this bucolic
place,
right?
So what they do is they hired archers,
professional archers to kill them with
bows and arrows,
and there was this uproar.
You know,
this song,
you know,
all of a sudden,
they're with a philosophers.
That bucks of deer bites the dust.
But yeah.
You know what way does it,
you got to deal with that stuff.
Well,
it's food to these same people are
eating cheeseburgers.
They're eating Turkey sandwiches,
they're eating dead animals that are
killed in a way more horrific way and
live in a way more horrific condition.
I know I've always thought I have an
obligation as an occasional mediator to
actually see the process by which the
food I eat is produced.
I have to admit I've never made good on
that commitment to myself.
I just started doing it about three
years ago.
I started hunting three years ago and
I'm addicted to it now.
I love it.
I get almost all my meat from hunting.
I had bear last night.
I served bear to my five year old and my
seven year old.
Wow.
So you know me,
I grew up Jewish and closure.
I'm still kosher.
It's the one relevant,
my traditional upbringing.
And so traditionally Jews don't hunt,
you know,
although it's weird.
You may choose from the south,
you know,
Jews who hunt.
It's kind of a contradiction in terms of
the Jews in the south that hunt.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
You know,
it's part of the culture,
part of the tradition,
you know,
most of those Jews don't keep kosher so
they don't care.
So there's gotta be some and then you've
got texted Jews.
They're a special breed.
They got to do it.
He just text and Jews,
they probably had a like Jews in Lebanon
and we were talking about yesterday.
Um,
when you,
when you say that your kosher,
what exactly does that mean?
Like you have to have a rabbi kill your
beef and he is like say some Voodoo and
then cut its throat more or less it,
it's,
you know,
I mean basically it's this,
some of it's ground in the Bible,
you know,
in some clause that says,
do not eat the meat of the calf and its
mother's milk so you don't eat meat
together with dairy.
And then they say you may meet,
it's got to the animals.
Got to have a split huff.
Intuit's cut,
right.
Could be a cow.
Actually,
venison would be okay.
Cow deer,
sheep.
Then it needs to be slaughtered in a
special way,
which for Millennia was the most humane
way of killing that.
It'll bleed,
has to be absolute,
perfectly sharp in the last couple of
decades.
There's now a dispute because in Europe
they're beginning to band the kosher way
of killing because it's no longer than
most humane way according to the
science.
That takes more time if you ever seen
it.
I haven't thrown up rough.
I've seen it.
I went to a butcher not to a butcher
rather to a slaughterhouse.
Once we're kosher,
kosher one,
will they do kosher as well?
Um,
it,
it was a slaughter house for fear
factor,
fear factor stunt there.
And it was,
the stunt was these people had a dunk
their head in these giant buckets of
blood.
So we had to have this cow's blood that
was chilled to slightly over 32 degrees
and we can only keep it for a short
amount of time or could possibly contain
pathogens.
So it was really cold water or really
cold blood rather.
So they gave me like a little tour of
the place and explain to me how they do
it.
And they have this area where the cow
goes in,
they locked the commonplace in a piston,
goes through the cow's head and kills
them.
But they're like,
you know,
the guy was pretty adamant about and
he's like,
we have a rabbi that comes and they do
the kosher slaughter and it goes in.
It's way worse.
Yeah.
They hold the collar in place with the
thing and then they slice it snack and
it's it boxing exactly from Millennia.
It was a more humane way because in the
old days you just knock it over the head
and all this stuff has been kosher way
was if the blade was not razor sharp,
if they had the tiniest nick in it and
you discovered that afterward the animal
is not kosher.
So there was a way of doing it that was
supposedly better,
you know.
But you know,
it is.
It's the one true.
I grew up,
my dad was a rabbi,
I grew up traditional and all that
Sabbath observant and this is the one
thing I'm still keeping.
Its like why?
Why do you keep it?
It's partially my own sort of
commitment,
my Jewish connection and sort of daily
reminder of that.
It's partially a family thing,
like a family,
you know,
we grew up this way and partly
superstitious that this is part of my
bargain with the cosmos,
with my bargain,
with God.
You know,
that,
okay,
I'm going to do this little sacrifice in
my life and it's,
you know,
I've led a blessed life and uh,
hey man,
maybe this is part of it.
Why risk advice stuff in it?
The only way I can.
I've had,
I've had some of the things by accident,
like I've had hand by accident and
probably a trip by accident.
I've never had it intentionally.
Don't think I've had bacon.
Although when I eat in the diner,
they got the bacon grease on the eggs.
I get,
you know,
I love the smell of Bacon.
I'll say that.
You've never eaten it?
No,
because it's just,
it's just this thing about bear big.
And could you eat bear?
Oh No,
it's split huff too.
It's good.
That's it.
But they don't have a split.
Whoa.
I have paused.
That's something they need to split.
Oh yeah.
That's the thing.
So.
And the only exception is if you're
starving to death and you can eat
anything.
Chickens find chicken that.
Because that goes into the separate
category of poultry.
Oh,
right.
So you can't shoot birds,
but you can eat that.
You can shoot them.
Will not.
I don't think so.
I think it's also going to be
slaughtered a certain way.
So there's kosher chickens as oppose
your chicken kosher duck.
And you're living in New York.
You got a lot of choices when you travel
around.
Mind you,
the kosher industry,
food industry is growing faster than the
organic food industry proportionally
really going to tell you.
I mean,
doing this thing here with you and uh,
you know,
in California you go to Manhattan Beach,
now you go whatever,
you got the,
uh,
the trader Joe's big kosher sections.
And it's not just Jews,
it's all sorts of other people who still
see it as an effect.
To some extent it is,
it's more reliable,
good quality.
The highest ends not going to be kosher,
but in terms of reliable,
good stuff,
you know,
people say Kosher is a pretty good bet.
That's interesting.
More than organic.
I would never have imagined,
it's not bigger than organic,
but it's growing proportionately faster
and that's partially because you have
orthodox Jews are the fastest growing
part of American Judaism,
right?
Liberal views like yeah,
liberal Jews like me have one kid,
I got one kid,
two kids,
right.
Orthodox Jews are having,
you know,
five or 10 kids.
So they're growing incredibly fast.
Right.
So they're a market and you have Jewish
Orthodox Jewish communities that popping
up all around the country.
Manhattan beach out here in California.
La has got a big orthodox community,
you know,
and then there are people on the African
American people see it as basically,
you know,
they hear this kosher is better.
And then remember the Muslim Halaal is
very similar to similar rules.
No pig.
The slaughterings I think somewhat
similar.
So a lot of people out of Muslims by
kosher food because for them all I know.
Is that something the Jews won't buy.
Hello?
In place a kosher.
But I think Muslims,
some Muslims will buy kosher because it
meets the Heloc and the headline reads
Muslims more tolerant than Jews.
There you go.
Here you go.
Here and a half.
There's that area around canter's Deli
in La.
Have you ever been to cancers?
I don't think so.
Oh,
you got to go.
Best Deli in all of La by far so good.
The pastrami is off the charts.
The Best Pastrami in La problems though
with some of these delis.
They used to be kosher.
Now they're just kosher style.
It's like they got the Pastrami and
stuff like that,
but it turns out because it's expensive
to pay the rabbi to bless it and
slaughtering,
so I have to make sure it's actually
strictly kosher.
Wow.
You really do did into that high,
you know,
it's been my thing.
I got to tell you,
I've had more people,
more friends and others rag on me than
anything.
And I say people say so would you ever
stop?
And I say the only way I'd ever stopped.
I think you said if they made it a law
that I had to keep kosher.
If they made it a law,
you had to keep kosher kosher that very
next day.
Well who would make it a law?
Well,
that's what I'm saying.
It's not gonna happen in America,
but I look what's going on in Israel
where the religious parties are becoming
more and more powerful and dominant and
you go to Jerusalem and their frequency,
or here's the rules on the Sabbath.
Here's the rules on this.
Here's the rules on that one can
envision a generation from now that it
Israel,
you might have,
you know,
the religious folks driving everything
and make a law like that.
If they did that and I'm still alive,
I'll stop.
So if they did that in Israel,
you would stop in America.
Probably just had a protest.
Just that approach just because you want
bacon.
That's what's up man.
You know what happens?
I'll tell you the hard,
the hardest thing you keep kosher.
I've never had lobster and shrimp.
I've never really had.
The hardest stuff is when there's a
beautiful steak or a beautiful piece of
duck or a lamb out there and it's
basically no different in the kosher
stuff,
but I can't eat it because they didn't
pay the rabbi to bless it and they spoke
differently.
That's the one that hurts,
right?
People I to do.
I got to tag onto what people.
They say,
Oh,
do you mind if I order some pork or as a
lobster?
I say,
please,
whatever you do,
don't order a beautiful lamb chop or
steak or something like that.
That's actually going to torture me
there.
I'm eating my damn piece of fish for the
eighth time that week and you know,
it was a beautiful state that I can eat,
so it's fish.
Always Kosher.
Is that the rule is if it comes from the
sea,
it's got to have fins and scales.
Jesus Christ.
So octopus is off the charts to you name
it.
All that stuff's all God have fins and
scales.
The shellfish is off and scallops and
for that matter,
things like shark and skate and even
catfish is the one I cheat with a little
bit and this is a debate about
swordfish.
I go with,
I,
I'm part of the school that says
swordfish.
It's kosher,
but my dad was a rabbi.
He came down that side.
I'm going,
my dad.
Does your dad still alive though?
Dialogue that I would have fucking had a
lobster that moment.
That dude was in the.
Oh yeah.
Hey,
he didn't even grow up keeping kosher.
He loved rabbit.
You know,
he loved God.
He became a rabbi.
He had no choice.
You know,
it just seems so odd to me that a
rational man like you,
so obviously intelligent and educated
would follow that.
You know what's good about this?
It gives me a sense of empathy for other
people with their rational attachments.
Attachments to drugs.
Exactly,
exactly.
Or irrational attachments,
anything.
My view is irrational attachments are
fine.
Maybe even good so long as they don't
hurt anybody else.
My keeping kosher doesn't really hurt
anybody else.
Right.
And there's all sorts of other
attachments to religious things,
to types of Gods,
to habits,
to name it.
It's not hurting anybody else.
I can kind of,
you know,
I got that little empathic sense for
what it means to be irrationally
committed to something.
All right,
man,
look at you.
You're looking at irrational thinking in
a rational way to do that.
You know,
you got to be just totally rational.
That'd be kind of boring too.
It was.
So let's get back to drug legalization
because we've got right now,
we've got two states that are across the
board.
One hundred percent.
We've got Washington state and we got
Colorado.
What's on the ballot right now?
Remember also Alaska and Oregon joined
the group,
uh,
last November.
So we have four states that are
illegally there.
And Oregon's can open up sales I think
in a few months.
And Alaska should open up sales.
I can't remember the end of this year,
beginning of next.
So we've got four states that have
legalized each one of them doing with 55
percent of the vote,
typically getting more votes.
And the guys who are running for
governor,
attorney general in those states got
that.
Those years,
big dc did everything except legalized.
They basically said you can grow your
own,
you can transfer it,
but they're not,
they haven't.
They haven't set up formal sales yet
because people worry that Congress will
sort of put a hammer on them.
Right.
So you can't go to a store know those
stores in DC.
There's a little movement on Capitol
Hill right now that might allow some
room there.
But the guy,
you know,
the,
the city council,
the mayor in,
in dc who are on board with
legalization,
but they're just saying,
do we want to provoke congress because a
lot of those guys would just come down
hard,
you know,
they're used to treating dc like the
plantation,
right?
If it's one of the great absurdities in
American politics that you got a
population of what,
six,
700,000
people,
I think it's as big as a few of the
smaller states,
but they got no representation on
Capitol Hill.
They got a member of the house who can
vote.
They got no members of the Senate,
they can vote for president.
Right.
And then they got congress basically,
you know,
the ability to veto any law.
They pass.
So.
And they have an extremely fucked up
situation as far as the haves and have
nots in their own town.
They really do.
Although there's a shift in the.
I mean DC was recently like two thirds
African American.
Now as it's become more gentrified,
it's still about 50 percent African
American.
Well,
the,
the issue is not just the African
Americans,
the poverty,
the poverty is in massive poverty and
crime in certain sections of DC and the
fact that that's the nation's capital.
They can't even clean up their own
backyard.
Yeah,
no,
that's completely ignored it.
When it was really highlighted when
Marion Barry was president,
and I should say as garden centers,
Mayor
Mayor it,
it's gotten better since those days and
the sense that there's been more to
address those issues has been some
gentrification.
Poverty is not as bad.
They still got bad crime rates.
It's not as bad as Baltimore's bid a
bunch of Baltimore's one of the worst
places in the country right now.
Detroit,
New Orleans.
Although you've got a few places out
here in California,
I have a hard time.
You.
Oh,
for sure.
CCS Weird in that you can go from really
nice to really bad in a couple of
blocks.
I was shocked when I was driving through
dc because I was like,
this is crazy.
You've seen these really a cute white
couples with the little stroller and
they're in these really nice brownstones
and they have a Volvo parked in front of
the house and right next to them as a
bmw and then you go two blocks down and
you see people drinking on the street
and there's kids with no shoes on and
is.
It's garbage piled up.
I was like,
this is
really nuts.
It could be partially about
gentrification.
Properties list expensive.
So first typically gays will move in,
right?
Because they don't have kids to worry
about and such.
And then after that you get some young
couples and others moving in and so you
begin to get that.
You saw the same thing in parts of New
York City,
upper east side or lower east side.
Um,
you know,
it's when things begin to change that
way that you get that kind of stuff.
Wasn't that the big complaint about New
York City's at so many rich financial
people have moved in that the entire
city is kind of used to be this artist
community and there's now that's kind of
Brooklyn now.
The funny thing is now they're saying
Brooklyn's moral becoming more like
Manhattan and Queens is becoming the new
Brooklyn and I got to say living in the
upper west side where it's,
I mean I'm lucky I'm in a rent
stabilized apartment there,
but,
and I live in a beautiful tree lined
street in a little apartment,
uh,
you know,
but then you see the banks moving in and
taking over the street corners,
right?
And you see more chain stores coming in
and so Manhattan has become this
beautiful place,
but less and less affordable now
Brooklyn people,
like most of the people work for me in
New York living in Brooklyn,
but now they got to move out to the
further further away from Manhattan part
of Brooklyn and Queens and the Bronx and
Upper Manhattan are becoming the places,
you know.
I mean,
look,
the city's happen.
It's great.
It's amazing.
The downside of our economic growth has
been at the same thing with Wall Street.
Wall Street is the,
the gap between rich and poor in New
York City is,
is horrific and huge.
On the other hand,
Wall Street is providing massive amounts
of tax revenue and New York City taxes
itself at a very high level,
so we actually have better services in
New York City that most parts of the
world.
My friend Shane was living in Brooklyn
and um,
me and my family came to visit and we
hung out with him one night and we had
this apartment that overlooks the
Manhattan skyline and we were looking at
it and I was like,
this might be the best looking view on
the planet.
Like there's something about that.
There's,
there's like,
I think there's two types of amazing
views.
There's amazing views of the mountains
and nature,
which is pretty stunning.
But there's something about the
Manhattan skyline that is so insane that
someone built that.
It's like,
it's gorgeous because it's all lit up
and the shapes are cool and then he has
the history behind it and you're looking
at all this activity and bustling people
back and forth.
And then there's also the magnitude of
the amount of effort that was put into
creating something like staring you in
the face to face.
Usually I'll be on a plane that's coming
from north,
from the north,
say from Albany or Montreal or wherever
it's coming from and it lands up going
down the Hudson River.
Right.
And you know,
Manhattan's basically a long island.
It's like,
I don't know,
15,
20 miles long and about a mile wide or
sell and you look down at that thing and
Manhattan and New York harbor and
there's a statue of liberty and there
you can see Staten Island and Brooklyn
Jersey around it and then you see the
empire state building and then you see
the freedom tower.
You see central park in the middle of
it,
one of the largest,
you know,
inner city parks in the world.
It brings tears to my eyes still.
It's just incredible.
Yeah,
it was pretty awesome spot.
But you can't get weed there.
Well,
what do you mean you can't get.
You can get a weed anyway.
You can get to talk to David Lee Roth.
Got arrested.
Trying to get weed there.
You know,
you've got to be either really unlucky
or dumb.
What kind of compress David Leroy Leroy
passed.
Are You sir?
I got to tell you,
I think our delivery services are very
well developed in New York City,
right?
But they're always under the wire.
Like that was always the problem that I
have in la.
Before it was legal.
I used to deal with this dude named Jake
the snake.
That was his nickname.
I'm not kidding.
And he wasn't a wrestler.
Jake,
the snake was so annoying.
He was so annoying and he,
uh,
he would sell a W.
I would get it from my friend Eddie and
Eddie would get it from jake the snake,
and we would have to deal with this guy.
So this is like we'd have these
conversations with this guy and now and
then,
you know,
and it's like.
And I always felt like it wasn't a bad
guy,
wasn't he was a bad guy,
but it was annoying that you had to deal
with this dude who was willing to do
something illegal because like there was
some criminal aspects to it.
There's always going to be like.
And I got to say I'm lucky because one
of the perks of my job is I can just
rely on the kindness of strangers.
I mean forever I go,
people are going to euthanasia and want
to try a little bit.
Hey,
they got this one is,
it's hard to take it home with me.
Right.
But even in New York,
people are kind of.
So I haven't had to buy weed and a very
long time.
I'm happy to say good for you.
Yeah.
Now you saw that,
uh,
my job has got some very nice elements
to it and this is one of the informal
positive benefits to it,
you know,
but New York is now they finally the
state just approve 20 outlets for
medical marijuana.
So most of those are going to be in the
city.
It's still going to be very strict
system.
We led that effort in New York last year
to legalize medical marijuana.
Unfortunately,
governor Cuomo acted in total bad faith
and made a system that is far,
far too tight,
a no logical reason for it.
But that said they just,
the state just approve five companies to
have five gross sites with 20 I outlets.
So we're locking down the profit aspect
of it.
They are.
I mean my God,
it's going to be a boondoggle for these
five.
You know,
that God,
it's so fucked up.
Why do that?
That doesn't make any sense.
Is that the case for tomatoes?
Is that the case for any other piece of
produce?
Anything grown from the earth?
What about lettuce can buy lead us
anywhere.
I imagine if there was a company in New
York that locked down the lettuce market
and the only way you can get a salad
from this one fucking company.
Yeah.
No I agree with you totally.
Just kind of hear what's going on at
Ohio.
Right?
And Ohio is going to have a kit to vote
to legalize marijuana in this year.
Twenty 15.
The only initiative on the ballot this
year as opposed to next year is from
Ohio when I was in the papers today.
Because the initiative just qualified
yesterday.
Right.
And what they found that when we
basically what happened there was 10.
I think it was roughly 10 business
interests got together,
right?
To put an initiative on the ballot.
They each ponied up like over $2,000,000
a piece.
Right?
We asked for our help in drafting it and
we said we help them draft it to get
some good stuff in there,
but the one thing they did that nobody
likes is they put into the initiative
that only the 10 investors are
technically the properties they own will
be allowed to produce marijuana
wholesale in Ohio in perpetuity.
Right.
It's like you always say,
this is an agricultural product.
We're going to have a constitutionally
mandated oligopoly.
We're only 10 properties can grow for
the state forever and ever,
and so I'm profoundly toward because
that oligopoly model in the constitution
sucks and we're talking about this
yesterday.
Yeah,
it's bullshit.
It's bullshit and you should pass on it
and just get weed illegally.
That's what I say,
fuck those people because what they're
trying to do is they're trying to take
something that's good and profit off of
it in a way that only they can profit
off of it and lock everybody out and
they think they're being sneaky.
They can go fuck themselves.
Well,
I'm torn because on the other hand,
if this thing winds this year,
Ohio is a major swing state in American
politics,
2016,
all the candidates are going to be vine
and Ohio.
Meanwhile,
the thing will only be in theory because
it will not have been implemented and
there's all sorts of people trying to
block the oligopoly provision,
so what an Ohio when this oligopoly
provision,
if it all works out well,
this thing winds opens up.
The national discussion forces.
The candidates talk about this issue,
puts it in Ohio in a major way.
Meanwhile,
everybody's so revolted by the oligopoly
model.
You already had the state legislature
trying to knock it out with a
competitive initiative.
The thing is going to land up in the
courts anyway.
I don't see any of the other states
adopting this model.
I mean,
none of the other initiatives on the
ballot in 2016 had this oligopoly
provision in it.
I think the sense of revulsion as kind
of doing that sort of thing.
So my sense is if it all works out well,
initiative winds,
the oligopoly thing never gets
implemented.
That's why you're here.
Anything we need to hear this.
This is beautiful.
We need to hear this kind of stuff now.
Do you face any pressure at all?
Um,
to not talk about the fact that you
smoke weed yourself being the fact that
you're a part of the drug policy
alliance and you have to have put ties
on and meet with some serious folks.
You know,
it's been an evolution Joe,
because I would say when I really got
going in this in the late eighties,
I was very careful about that because
that was the height of the drug war.
Right?
And,
and,
and I that my dissertation research,
I wrote my Phd at Harvard and it was on
the internationalization of criminal law
enforcement,
which is three years earlier.
I had had a security clearance.
I'd worked in the State Department's
Narcotics Bureau.
I'd wrote a classified report on drug
trafficking,
money laundering.
I traveled all around South America and
Europe interviewing dea guys and foreign
drug enforcement guys.
I'd written a dissertation and the book
an international drug controls will cops
across borders,
so I just knew these guys and they and
they had opened their doors to me and
now three years later I'm out there
saying we got to talk about legalization
and at that point when the drug war was
like,
mccarthyism on steroids,
right?
It was just so.
I was very discreet.
I never would deny that I had smoked
marijuana,
but I would never talk about being
occurring consumer.
And then as things began to ease up into
the late nineties,
early two thousands,
I began to be a little looser with it,
but I still would say go to the cannabis
cups would invite me and I maybe showed
up at the hemp fest in Seattle a couple
of times,
but I'd still be careful now.
The Times are changing.
Right.
And it's a lot like the evolution with
gay people in America,
right at the points at which different
people would feel comfortable coming out
and all this sort of stuff.
And so now I'm quite comfortable saying,
yeah,
you know,
I smoke weed.
I had been occasional consumers since I
was 18.
It's been a net positive in my life,
you know,
and I actually even a few years ago on
psychedelics it,
you know,
we do this big biennial conference on
and a few years ago it was in la,
um,
and I,
and I said,
this was kind today,
did it.
I said,
you know,
I'm Jewish,
right?
And so once a year I fast on Yom Kippor,
25 hours,
no food,
no water.
I think it's good for the soul to fit to
a fast once a year.
I'd say that's the way I view doing
psychedelics as well.
You know,
that people should keep doing
psychedelics at least once a year,
well into their elder,
elderly years because it's a good way to
stir up the emotional sediment in
intellectual sediment and stay honest as
you grow older.
And so I think,
you know,
I felt coming out about that as well.
I think the times,
you know,
we're,
we're in a day and age in America right
now where we can talk about this and
need to talk about it more openly.
And what is your second dog of choice
that you like to do annually?
Well,
mushrooms is sort of the standard.
I mean that's one just over Christmas
vacation,
you know,
I just did a sort of mega dose and it
was,
it was really clarifying how many grams
is a mega dose,
you know,
from a quarter ounce,
six,
seven grams of dried.
My son's.
Yeah.
No,
you don't want to fucking hear.
You don't want to be around it.
Sasha,
Sasha Shogun used to call me a hard
head,
you know,
it's like by which he meant,
I need it.
I need a big dose to Iowasca done a few
times,
both in once in a Santa dime ceremony in
one sit.
A just a more laid back way.
And that was really amazing.
You know,
Lsd,
that one.
I mean,
I,
you know,
I've enjoyed it.
I've never done a megadose with that.
Uh,
you know,
I think it's a,
but it's not resonate with me the way
mushrooms.
Have you ever do dmt?
No.
Well,
um,
well,
sort of,
you've done Iowasca.
You've had a milder version of it.
I mean,
there was one time somebody had made up,
a guy knows a good scientist had done a,
made up a,
a thing that was a combination of dmt
and ketamine and Ah,
you know,
that was a,
that was.
No,
no,
no.
He was actually,
he was an interesting,
interesting guy and he did it and found
that he had found that he was dealing
with significant depression and he found
that this Combo actually lifted his
baseline depression.
And now there's all this research about
ketamine being fairly effective as an
antidepressant.
We've actually had a friend on Neal
Brennan who talked about it.
He's a good friend of mine who's a stand
up comedian.
He was a,
the cocreator of the Chappelle show.
Very funny guy and put his head like
some troubles in his life and went
through legal in Los Angeles,
went through legal ketamine treatments,
depression,
and he goes,
he wasn't exactly sure what that was
going to be like.
So he sits down,
they do it intravenously,
right?
So he sits down in this doctor's office
and they will walk him out and he goes,
dude,
I'm on a 45 minute journey through the
university.
Goes in.
It's like the strongest fucking trip
I've ever been on an I can't believe I'm
doing this in a doctor's office.
So I gotta ask you,
I was reading your bio before and I saw
that you have an isolation tank.
Yeah,
use it.
Have you ever read John Lilly's?
Sure.
Scientists I've read that I read,
uh,
the deep self have read a couple of us.
I remember reading that book and fishes
that itinerary science.
And for your listeners who don't know,
right?
John Lilly was the great,
you know,
Pioneer state teaching communications,
communications with whales and dolphins,
dolphins and all that.
And also the person who may have
invented the isolate he did did.
And he goes through this period in his
life where he starts injecting ketamine
every hour on the hour.
It is isolation tank like 12 to 18 hours
a day,
almost kills himself in the end lives to
be like in his mid eighties.
Um,
and that's the way in which he ventured
into trying to figure out what the world
is all about.
My friend Todd Mccormick did deep has
his tank.
He owns his tank and he did ketamine in
that tank with lily.
Is that tied to that?
Yeah.
Todd Todd did ketamine like,
like he was about to do the tank and
lily asked some,
do you want ketamine or.
No,
and he's like,
when John Lilly asked you if you want to
do ketamine before you get into his
tank,
you say yes.
So he whacks him with the ketamine.
He goes under and apparently he was like
screaming or something while he was in
there because he's out of his fucking
mind first of all,
because the tank by itself is a
psychedelic experience and shut the door
as long.
I mean,
you're,
you're more aware and you can shut it
off at any time.
It's more of a conscious decision to
enter into the psychedelic state,
but when you add that to the academy and
apparently it's just this unbelievable
journey through the mind and todd was
just not prepared for it.
So Lily,
we had another tank next to his other
tank,
gets in the second tank,
wax himself out and visits him,
goes and visits him in the fucking
ketamine dimension while they're both in
a side by side parallel isolation tanks.
Like that's something to tell your
grandchildren about.
Kid about won the world series.
So you've done Ella psychedelics in your
isolation tank.
I've only done mushrooms and edible weed
in the isolation tank.
The edible weed is my favorite.
The high doses of edible weed is one of
the most underrated psychedelics today.
There's a lot of people that don't
understand that if you get a really high
dose like a,
and it doesn't even have to be a big
thing.
That's the thing.
What they're doing today with these
concentrates and Hash oils,
they have these fucking gummy bears,
man,
gummy bears that are 250.
Some of them like what does achievement?
She was 500 milligrams.
They have 500 milligram thc Chiba Chews.
If you eat one of those and get into the
isolation tank,
you will go on a journey that I liken
to any DMT trip,
any mushroom trip,
but the vedic texts,
a lot of the Hindu scriptures,
they were all written by people who are
eating hash.
Like a lot of the really crazy visuals
and the Buddha and all that stuff.
You see that shit when you eat it.
Is there any jokes?
I tell you for me,
I mostly associate the high dose edible
with just being knocked on my butt and
just like,
you know,
didn't go high enough.
Yeah.
Well that could be it because there had
been some good experiences and not
quite.
I know what you're talking about,
but I haven't gone to that level with
it.
I've only gone a couple times by
accident.
You know,
the,
the real accidental ones in places where
I didn't know that I was going to do it.
I've had some terrible journeys on
planes were like right before,
like I'm like,
I don't like flying.
It's annoying.
I got to do it too often so I'll take
something like right when I pull up to
the airport,
I don't want to have anything on me when
I'm going through security.
Right.
So I'll eat like a cookie or something
right before I go.
And then like as you know,
the bags are going through and then I go
to starbucks,
get a cup of coffee,
then I sit down at the gate and I'm
like,
Oh fuck,
I might've taken too much and then give
the ticket,
get on the plane.
And then once I sit down I'm like,
okay,
at least I know I'm going to be here for
the next six hours.
And then the universe dissolves.
And you could shot through some worm
hole to the center of your mind and you
reexamined your childhood and like,
fuck,
I don't mean I gotTa tell you I've done
that.
Edibles and planes a few times,
one time to somebody,
like you said,
don't want to count a plane.
Had a little nibble before Chicago to
Laguardia.
I landed all my God,
please somebody get me home here.
You know,
on the other hand,
at the time thing of finding yourself on
thinking,
God,
this stuff knocked me all the time.
Why don't I just do little edible
instead of a sleeping pill because I
don't like some of the sleep people
effects.
It didn't work.
It was kind of fidgety and it was closed
and you know,
so I've stayed away from the edibles on
the planes.
They're very tricky because you,
you really have to be in the right state
of mind and you really have to treat
them with respect.
I think edibles have always been
associated with silliness and I think
that's the trick that they've played on
us.
Like have a little pot,
Brownie man will be,
we'll get crazy.
I know it's not silly.
It's serious business and the fact that.
I mean,
it's funny because now with all the
concerns about edibles that,
you know,
somebody asked me the other day,
what's the thing that most surprised me
about the evolution,
this whole marijuana reform thing last
five,
10 years and it's been the emergence of
the edibles.
It.
If you had asked me five,
10 years ago,
I would not have anticipated that
edibles and drinks and all those.
We playing such a major role in legal
marijuana.
Oh yeah.
Well they're paper pens to vape pens,
but at least those are the vape pens I
might've seen because of the antismoking
stuff coming in and the e-cigarettes
coming along,
but the edible stuff and the gummy bears
and the chocolates and all this sort of
stuff,
breath strips.
If you had one of those now don't very a
full one.
Is that right?
Yeah.
You got to break them up.
You gotta break them up drunk.
Me and Tommy.
Shakira was a good friend.
Mine stand up.
Comedian.
We tore one in half and ate it on a
plane.
We're doing some gigs in Florida,
popped it on the way to a.
It was a nighttime flight,
a Redeye,
and we landed and we both turned and
looked at each other and go.
We were like,
how terrifying was that?
Fucking terrifying.
What was in that like?
I.
Well,
I got to tell you much stealing from
this.
From a policy perspective.
I mean,
we're doing everything we can to have
some responsible regulation in this
area.
You need better testing.
You need to know that if you're buying a
cookie,
that stuff's going to be evenly
distributed.
Find a chocolate bar,
distributed people got to figure out
their dose.
You know,
I found for me,
like right now I know about seven
milligrams.
It's just kind of a nice cat.
Seven relatively low dose.
That's really hard to find.
Usually the lowest 20 though.
Well,
what I'll do is I'll get a candy bar
that's broke it up into bits of 10.
It'll split it a little more than half
or something like that.
So that's like a calm,
mellow,
calm,
nice to kick back,
relax.
Maybe go for a swim,
go for a massage,
maybe go to movie.
I mean it's that level,
right?
And the higher level can be good too,
but it's got the risk of knocking me on
my ass to higher level to me is like
this,
it's a potential like a,
like a treasure hunt.
Maybe treasure hunt for ideas or an
exploration of maybe there's something I
missed,
you know,
maybe like because I'm always trying to
like dig down into my psyche and find
out what I don't like about me or what I
need to improve or what I need to work
on more what,
what,
what aspect of my career,
my life I need to be putting more
attention to.
And usually the pot sort of lets me know
about that in the pot,
in the tank.
That's my big exploratory journey.
They eat a cookie getting the tank and
then get out and go.
I gotta go to work.
It's interesting for me.
Pot sometimes does that,
but it's unpredictable when it's going
to work that way,
you know?
And then I grabbed the opportunity.
I may be sitting at a concert and had an
edible or smoke and all sudden like my
brides fly and stuff down,
you know,
listen to music.
But,
but for me,
the thing about the mushrooms,
which I don't like to do it is when you
get older it takes more of a toll.
You don't recruit,
you know,
like I do mushrooms and the next day
it's like I'm,
I'm burnt out.
Really?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Now that wasn't true when I was in my
twenties,
early thirties about my fifties.
Now you know,
did you ever try five htp and when you
come back from it,
I was just talking about that this
morning.
I don't think I have tried that.
That's a big one because for mushrooms
are in DMA.
Well for either one but much more so for
Mtma then for mushrooms because that's a
direct effect.
That's exactly what it's doing.
But mushrooms as a toll on it as well.
And a lot of people that have done the
heavy mushroom trips have found success
in taking um,
l,
Tryptophan and five htp afterwards.
L trip to fan actually converts to five
htp and five htp convert to Serotonin
can get those over the counter.
Yeah.
We actually sell.
So I'll get you some.
Do we have any new mood here?
Do we have in that?
So we have some.
We get you some.
Yeah,
yeah.
This is it right here.
Yeah.
Oh No,
no,
this is.
Thank you.
Yeah.
That's a combination of five htp trip to
fan and all that stuff does is it gives
your brain the building blocks to
produce human neurotransmitters.
That's what it does.
It keeps you being the building blocks
and that stuff to
produce serotonin.
I have to say,
well,
what am I great regrets?
Is that the,
you know,
first did it I guess in the early
nineties when I was in my early thirties
and,
and I loved it,
you know,
and did it both for going to occasional
rave or be with my wife at the time or
friends.
But I have to say now it just doesn't
seem to work for me as well anymore.
That's a downside.
Begins to exceed the upside.
And it's a bummer.
I've only done it once and the downside
was so strong.
The upside was amazing.
It was an I,
Amanda done too much.
I took two tabs and um,
uh,
the,
the experience was beautiful and it
taught me so much about insecurity,
so much about like the way I behave in
the way people behave and interact with
each other.
How much of it just based on insecurity,
you know,
it was weird like,
ah,
this sounds gay as fuck,
but this is exactly what happened.
Me and this dude,
we're on a couch.
We were holding hands and we're talking
about how good it feels to just hold
hands.
And we weren't scared to like,
hold hands was another dude.
It was totally nonsexual.
It's so funny because I remember one
time we have a close friend and some of
these friends are like leading academics
and drug policy,
drug studies.
I mean major figures and we'd become
good friends and we would occasionally
get together and do you know,
do it Mtma thing like once a year.
And I just remember one of my friends
who's distinguished professor him,
just four of us were sitting on the
couch and he just laid down on top of
our days and we all just put our heads
out of.
And it was so loving,
so wonderful.
So I know you're talking about
nonsexual.
It's a weird thing.
The MTMA apparently they say I've never
tried.
Not only did it once,
but people say that it's really hard to
have sex when you're on it.
Right.
Well,
the thing is with the goal,
it's not the sex drug.
It's a hug.
Yeah.
Right.
I mean that's the thing and it's,
it's something you can't get aroused on
it,
but it's,
you know,
at some point the I,
that's been my experience.
You can get aroused.
They're all that sort of stuff.
But at some point the energy is shifting
towards more hug energy,
loving energy,
you know.
Whereas for example,
psychedelics and sometimes and go into a
highly sexual direct.
Well that was the argument that Mckenna
had for mushrooms being the catalyst for
human evolution.
Do you ever,
you know,
about all that?
Do you know Mckenna's?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I mean I kinda liked the theory,
the notion of hunter gatherers and
hunter gatherers who consumed silicide
mushrooms or whatever.
We're the ones who are going to be
better at whether it was warfare thing
or a whole range of other things,
so it's intriguing and terrence was a
remarkable speaker who's the best
speaker who was so fascinating
technique.
I only met him a few times,
but one of the last times he called me
up because I think you were supposed to
speak at Ucla or USC and at the last
moment they were gonna prohibit him from
speaking or whoever was loaning them the
hall or something like that,
and so he just called me up and I called
the local Acu and I got on it and we
solved the problem.
Wow,
that's great.
That's beautiful.
As you lead to one of the speeches.
I think so,
yeah.
And his brother,
Dennis Mckenna,
he and I were both at the first World
Iowasca Congress need Biesa last
October,
and that was something.
I mean,
here you have it.
It was either it was an ebc because he
beats his right.
The party island and Iowasca is not a
party drug.
It's a serious thing,
but there were about a thousand people
in this conference will not be,
so you had leading academic scientists
like Dennis Mckenna,
you had shamans both new age Sharmans in
traditional shamans from La,
from Latin America.
You had people who were.
There was a guy,
Polish guy who would do an occasional
iowasca ceremony where he would invite
musicians who would then make music
together and the influence of Ayahuasca,
and then I was invited because the
organizers wanted to know how does
Iowasca connect to broader drug policy
reform,
so that was quite a gathering.
Dennis is amazing.
I love that guy.
I've had him on a few times now and had
some beautiful conversations with them.
It's just I'm always like,
I can't believe I'm sitting here talking
to Dennis Mckenna.
He's.
He's psychedelic royalty.
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
now he really is.
And the stuff.
You know,
it's funny.
I've never gone on one of those Iowasca
tours down in south.
Have you done that?
Nina did.
Occasionally.
What?
I hate bugs apparently Dennis does too,
so he does them in a different part of
Peru.
It's not.
It's a dry climate.
It's not a moist jungle climate.
He's like,
you don't have to go to the jungle.
And I'm like,
yeah,
well I go to the jungles fucking
mosquitoes man,
get eaten alive.
But for some people it's like part of
the beauty of the journey,
it's like the suffering of dealing with
the bugs and the like.
My friend amber got bit on the leg by a
spider and our whole fucking leg turned
black.
Like a black and blue brothers.
Giant Qj yes.
So people do these things out in the
forest and they,
you know,
they start walking off in the middle of
ceremony.
Nobody ever finds them again,
but Jaguars.
Yeah.
No,
I was perfectly happy to do my first
IOWASCA experience in Santa Barbara,
California.
That's perfect.
Yeah.
No bugs,
no bugs.
Just rich people.
Yeah.
Yeah,
exactly.
Exactly.
The only thing that hard is the plastic
surgery around you.
That's true.
But I'll tell you the Iowaska think too.
It reminds me when you read about the
the emergence of LSD and Mescaline in
the fifties and the guys who went around
dosing people,
cary grant,
famous actors,
politician cary grant used to dos para.
Not He didn't those people,
but he became an enthusiast.
Who's that famous,
who's.
She was a famous female swimmer who then
was in movies.
I forget her name,
but you know you had famous people doing
it,
life magazine writing about it and I
think Iowasca is almost a bigger version
of that right now.
You're having IOWASCA ceremony is
happening all around the world,
not just the US or North America and
South America,
but in Europe,
Asia.
I mean it's extraordinary and so many
people describing profound and
transformative experiences and it's not
totally without risk,
but the benefit risk ratio is so
enormous.
What is the risk though?
Well,
I no physical risk.
The risk,
the risk is only psychological and if
you are psychologically unstable person,
you really shouldn't be doing anything
to perturb your consciousness.
If you have issues with psychosis or
bipolar or you know,
there's a lot of people that have.
The other thing with powerful
psychedelics is if you have a
cardiovascular risk because you're,
you're,
you're so stimulated,
so stimulated and then the thing is
because Iowasca,
you know,
every shaman makes the batch of
different ways so you're not exactly
sure what's in that stuff.
And then there's thing about making sure
the person's safe while they're under
the influence,
you know,
it's like the horrible story.
What happened with that guy in Colorado
with the edible,
right?
Who had never done it before and he
jumps off the balcony or the horrible
stories about people doing lsd and
thinking they can fly.
So,
you know,
Bill Hooks joke on that.
Yeah,
Bill Hooks.
What a tragedy.
Someone jumped out,
he goes,
what an idiot because we thought it
could fly.
What did he take off from the ground
first?
This whole bit about it,
about a young man on acid is a,
a bit about a positive drug story.
And his thing was like all the media
ever tells you about is these negative
drug stories by the guy jumped off the
roof.
Well,
I mean it's part of it.
As marijuana is becoming more legalized
in our society and hopefully around the
world and as we move forward in the
psychedelics to begin to open them up as
well and maybe not too old to new
psychoactive substances and some of the
synthetics which may have some upsides
to them,
but the key is going to be putting out a
door and out there about what it means
to use safe.
I mean,
for example,
get doing mushrooms,
real estate and going to a concert with
50,000
people around or 10 times people around.
Generally not a good idea unless they're
also on LSD and you know them all.
That's true.
That might work.
Okay.
But maybe.
But that's a scary thing.
It's like people think,
oh,
let's go do this as a party drug and all
of a sudden all sorts of information
overload and losing perspective and all
this sort of stuff and people that are
always going on or do you see going to
burning man?
Right.
And I remember meeting a guy who'd done
some weird drug and and he had just
totally flipped out.
He thought an animal is trying to eat
him alive,
right?
While he was flipping out,
and fortunately,
you know,
Rick Doblin,
the guys had maps and set up these kinds
of,
you know,
safety zones and so they were able to
get this guy away from the cops because
the cops are going to shackle him,
put them on a helicopter and take them
to a jail which could have been horrible
and instead they gave them to rick and
rick is able to talk this guy down and
you know,
do it.
But we have to be weird that when,
when people are taking these powerful
mind altering substances which can have
these wonderful things as you and I have
experience,
we got to be aware that there are people
who are not as stable as they think they
are.
People who have deep seeded shit going
on and they don't know what's buried
that's going to come flying out people
or don't understand that yet.
If you're going to jump jump from the
first floor,
not the fifth floor.
So we got to make sure because the jump
from the first floor,
the ground floor,
the ground,
exactly,
you know,
but that it's going to be so key because
I mean,
look,
just to shift away from the silos for a
second,
one of the issues we're working on big
time is trying to reduce the number of
people dying from overdoses involving
either heroin or pharmaceutical opiates.
So last couple of years,
more people have died of an accidental
overdose involving heroin or other
pharmaceuticals than in a car accident.
It's the number one cause of accidental
death in America today.
I mean,
it's absolutely crazy stuff.
Right?
And in fact,
when we say overdoses suggests you took
too much.
Most of what our overdoses or drug
combinations,
they're typically doing this opiate,
your pharmaceutical,
opiate,
oxycodone,
whatever it might be.
It might even be prescribed to you with
booze or with Benzos,
valium type drugs.
Right?
So what we're trying to do is to put out
there the notion that don't care if you
do it.
Opiates,
don't combine it with booze.
Don't combine it with tranquilizers.
There's a miracle drug called Naloxone
and we're trying to make that stuff as
widely available,
reverses the,
it's like an antidote for an overdose.
Make it available.
We're passing nine slash 11 good
Samaritan laws.
So if people are around and a buddy
there's overdoses,
they don't just flip out,
they call nine slash 11 right away,
the way with a heart attack.
So,
you know,
it's true with the psychedelics and
marijuana,
but even with the drugs that we see as
less elevated in a way,
but that huge numbers of people are
using life,
the opiates,
it's really important that we become
more and more of a society that
understands the notion that we need to
make it safer to use these drugs.
Right?
We got to keep people from getting hurt
the way that
people get hurt.
But we had a guy on here yesterday,
um,
uh,
his two guys,
Chris and Mark Bell,
uh,
who,
they were a part of a documentary called
bigger,
stronger,
faster,
which was about steroids.
And now they have a new one called
prescription thugs.
And it's all about,
uh,
the,
the opiate pill industry and how many
people die from it and how many people
are addicted to it and the numbers.
I wasn't prepared for the numbers when
we had the.
And we started exploring the numbers.
They were talking about this from 2010.
There was eight point 7 million people
abusing these pills on,
on a daily basis in this country.
I mean,
that's a staggering.
Well,
I mean,
nobody really knows the number,
right,
because what it means to abuse it and
whether it is abuse,
but it,
you know,
20 years ago you had a massive problem
of the undertreatment of pain,
right?
That people were so flipped out about
using opioids,
had people who were terminally ill,
children who are terrible burn victims,
people going through a traumatic,
you know,
post operative recovery from surgery and
stuff like that.
We're not having their pain treated.
And the failure to treat pain
appropriately can shorten people's
lives,
lead to major depression,
lead to other drug taking and all that
sort of stuff.
So over the nineties,
early two thousands,
we began to solve that problem.
So now it's opiates are used much more
correctly,
but then what happened is that we,
we really have in America is an epidemic
of chronic pain,
right?
Lower back pain,
Sciatica,
chronic fatigue,
fibromyalgia,
carpal tunnel,
I mean the tens of millions of Americans
may be close to 50 or 100 million
Americans go through some chronic pain
episode during the course of every year
or two,
whatever it might be.
And it turns out that for many people
going through dealing with chronic pain,
opioids don't work that well,
right?
They just don't work.
They're appropriate for sort of severe
pain and they're appropriate for some
chronic pain patients.
So what happens is people start taking
this stuff,
they have chronic pain and they're
taking opioids and the doctor's given
the opioids and then they're building up
tolerance.
So they're taking higher doses which is
building the risk,
right?
And then maybe they're combining it with
like a value type drug to reduce their
anxiety,
or maybe they're taking alcohol because
that makes him feel better.
And then what happens is at some point
your heart,
your breathing stops,
right?
And so what we need to do with that,
that overprescription of these opioids,
it's not just by physicians who are
criminals and are doing these things for
money.
It's not just black mount market
marketeering.
It is stuff.
It's also a lot of people just trying to
help doc good meaning doctors trying to
help people who are suffering with pain,
by giving them the opioids they think
they want and need.
When it turns out,
that's probably not the best way to deal
with it.
Well,
there's an issue that people have with
pain that comes from work,
from sitting down all day.
There's an issue that people have from
not taking their body as important or as
taking the health of their body as
significantly as they should.
I think that there's a lot of people
that just don't.
They don't know the consequences of
sitting at a desk with bad posture all
the time.
Like these chairs that you're sitting
in.
These things are special ergonomic
chairs that make you kind of support
your body weight up straight.
They're called Pisco chairs or this
company called Ergo Depo,
but before I got.
These are sat in regular office chairs
at the end of every episode,
out of my fucking back,
the middle of my back killing me,
and this eliminated them.
Ergonomic chairs are very important.
Sometimes people like to sit on those
balance balls.
That's important,
but what's also important is taking care
of your health and fitness,
taking care of your body,
like yoga.
If more people did yoga,
the you would have way less back pain,
less joint pain,
way less stress,
but they don't have the time or if they
do have the time they choose to have do
that.
Time to go get drunk.
What you like.
That
me and I've had more people tell me to
take a yoga than any other piece of
advice in my entire life and I just
can't get into it.
Have you tried it?
Tried it many times,
you know,
and I just,
I just know that you know,
I'm sitting.
You know what I realized.
I'm in your beautiful Ergonomic chair
here,
Joe,
but I'm slouching.
So now I'm going to sit up straight.
Let me readjust the mic here.
You know,
and then I'll feel better.
I'll breathe better,
you know,
it's like I gotta tell you something.
What do you mean by you can't get into
it?
I just don't enjoy it.
You're not supposed to enjoy it the way
I will say an hour and a half of suck.
But you know,
other parts of life suck quite all I do
that,
you know,
I wouldn't say the ideas that there's a
benefit for that suck.
What are the things I love about weed is
I love to stretch.
When I do,
we get into my body,
you know,
and that's the thing.
It's just whether it's swimming,
but the only time I like feeling that,
you know,
stretching my I hate,
hates trish in my hands,
but when I'm high,
well,
you know,
that's what Mckenna believe that yoga
was in the first place.
Yoga set.
Mckenna had this one lecture that was
talking about a yogis and that the real
secret about sod dues is that their
highest fuck and what yoga really is is
it's almost like
a how to manual on how to properly use
cannabis and that they believe that
eating cannabis especially or smoking
hash and then going into the yoga poses
would they would achieve these higher
states of consciousness and so they
would pass this down from generation to
generation and the Indian in India
rather,
the Hindus have a long history of both
eating hash and smoking hash and he
believed that that was the dirty secret
of Yoga.
The Yoga was really all about how to use
cannabis correctly,
which is why it feels so good to stretch
when you're high.
I'll tell you a few things about that.
What did I think it was the San
Francisco Chronicle just last month or
so had a piece about yoga where they
basically asked people to smoke before
they go and do the yoga class.
The other thing is have you seen as will
they say?
What was the result?
I mean,
people.
It's the same thing.
So many people are like me.
They get more into their body.
Right?
That marijuana helps in that respect.
You know,
the other thing is,
have you seen this book that was just
reissue called Zigzags Ed?
No.
You should have this guy on Alan Alan.
I'm a diner and zag zig zag zed and the
paint.
You know Alex Gray is the guy,
the friend of mine.
Alex is the one who did the artwork for
it at Albert died or did the writing and
as I recall what the book is about is he
was struck by all of these kind of Zen
spiritual leaders in America for whom
their psychedelics experience in their
younger years was pivotal to their
evolution and to their becoming a master
of some type of meditation,
but who would not talk about it.
Right.
And it's.
So.
It's very interesting because you know,
there's also,
you have in some of these spiritual
world,
whatever,
that they're looking down on the use of
marijuana or psychedelics that you
should keep your body as a sacred vessel
and keep it free from these substances.
But in fact,
you see a lot of evidence that these
things go really well together.
Well the issue is legality and also most
of these people have actual jobs and
when you have an actual job and you
start talking about drugs,
people look at you like you're some sort
of a fucking crazy person.
If you work as an insurance company and
you say,
well on the weekend,
you know what I did this week and I
smoked dmt with my friends and I
experienced God,
what the fuck is wrong with Ethan?
I know it's crazy,
asshole.
Like.
And then you get passed up for job
promotions.
I think you're a loose cannon.
It can be detrimental to your interest
or your family.
Especially if you have children.
There's a lot of people that have
children that don't like to talk about
drugs or even admit they smoke pot
anymore.
I've experienced that resistance all
over the place.
Or what about the,
you know,
if your kids are inviting their friends
over and then you have to worry about
that.
Your kid's friends will tell their
parents,
oh so and so's parents smoke weed or
whatever.
And then all of a sudden you have the
neighbors and the fellow parents,
you know,
getting all worked up about that or tell
their kids they can't go over.
Well listen,
I go through that mean that's me.
You know,
look,
I have pot tattooed on my body now.
I have a DMT molecule on my left arm.
It's pretty well known that I'm in the
drugs.
I like them.
I think they're awesome,
you know,
but I'm healthy as fuck and a also
an independent operator as Ami.
But it's so true.
I got to tell you,
in my emails I get from people who have
solid employees for 20 years and then a
drug test popped out and they were
totally fine at work.
It's just because they got high in the
weekend and they lose their job after 20
years except that sort of stuff that's
going on.
I think by the way,
John Oliver maybe doing something on
this issue soon.
So it's a nonsense issue.
The idea that you can get high on Friday
and lose your job on Monday.
How come you can get drunk all weekend
and show up on Monday and we all tell
you something.
But now here's what.
I'll give you a policy dilemma.
So back in 2010,
the ballot initiative in California
legalized marijuana,
Richard Lee,
the fellow who was driving that and we
agreed,
we put in a provision there that
basically said people could not be fired
for testing positive for marijuana so
long as they were totally competent work
not high at work and there's one to
protect people who were having a joint
in the evening or on the weekend,
right?
The Chamber of Commerce flipped out.
Right?
And the problem is,
is you don't want to provoke some very
powerful bears and all this sort of
stuff.
So now when we're drafting these
initiatives around the country for 2016
and beyond,
what we find is we do not include a
clause protecting people because we know
the one thing that might get the chamber
of Commerce,
so will flip out,
you know,
and to basically defeat the initiative.
And then which had basically hope is
that as marijuana becomes more
legalized,
you can read hesitant.
And I think that's what's happening.
I haven't looked at it yet in Oregon and
Washington,
but my guess is that the number of
employers who are drug testing for
marijuana is decreasing.
Right?
I mean,
look,
it's always been a bad way to determine
performance,
right?
Because we know marijuana stays in the
system,
you know,
the craziness of drug testing.
If you want to get totally bombed at a
Friday night and be okay at work Monday
morning in terms of drug testing,
don't smoke a joint for alcohol and
cocaine is the right combination for
you.
That's a crazy message to same with drug
testing,
right?
So because cocaine's out of your system.
Exactly in the alcohol,
same thing.
It's stupid,
it's really stupid.
And these stereotypes are ridiculous.
These stereotypes and pot smokers are
dominant,
lazy,
and you know,
they,
they insult me,
you know,
it really drives me nuts and I,
I hate having defended because it's,
it's,
you're defending just ignorance.
Stereotypes that were propagated by
reefer madness.
I mean that was really started it all
off.
And the effectiveness of the propaganda
that hearst publications put out in the
19 thirties.
It's a magazine,
how well that worked almost a hundred
years later.
You know what else it is,
and I used to make this analogy more
often than I do today,
but I'd say you know something in
America,
50 years ago,
everybody knew a gay person.
They just didn't know they knew a gay
person,
right,
and therefore their image of who was gay
was determined by what they saw in the
media.
Somebody getting arrested in a men's
room or somebody flamboyantly walking
down Christopher Street in New York City
or people who are very,
very feminine right now.
Of course everybody knows a gay person,
right?
It could be their cousin or their
employer,
the it's all around the place and
therefore our image,
who is the gay person,
right?
Has become.
We don't have any associations,
is just the person who seems a feminine
or just a person doing odd stuff will.
Similarly with marijuana,
everybody in America knows not just a
marijuana user,
but a responsible marijuana user.
The problem is they don't know.
They know that therefore who's their
image of the person who uses marijuana
user,
they think of that high school dropout
or the kid with hemp leads in as broad
blond dreadlocks who's a troublemaker at
school.
They think of their friend's kid who got
in trouble with drugs.
That's who they think.
Now mind you,
the kid who just got straight a's in is
going to an ivy league school or uc
Berkeley or Stanford or whatever and
who's also smoking weed.
That kids being more discreet and nobody
knows he's doing.
We'd except his friends so we have a
biased image of who in fact the
marijuana user has been in America now.
As it becomes more legalized,
as people become more open and out with
it.
I had been struck at all the people I've
known for many years.
We're finally saying to me and admitting
to me that they've been using marijuana
or psychedelics regularly for a long
time.
Now we're seeing that thing begin to
shift in our society the same way we saw
it happening with gay people in this
school.
I think you're right and I think I've
seen a giant shift just within the last
15 or so years,
you know?
Um,
I started smoking pot when I was 30.
I'm 48 now,
so I've been smoking pot for 18 years
and before I smoke pot I thought it was
for losers.
I really did.
I got lucky.
I met my friend Eddie Bravo and he is a
really creative musician and explained
to me that it helps them like write
music and create music and he's an
interesting guy that I used to do
Jujitsu with.
That's also a weird thing about martial
arts,
a tremendous amount of UFC fighters
smoke pot,
I mean a massive amount where it's a
huge issue for them with involving drug
tests,
you know,
that they have to stop smoking weed for
the last four weeks or so in order to
pass drug tests.
When I say I mean more than,
more than don't more,
more UFC fighters smoke pot than don't.
Same thing.
True of the NBA,
the giant nfl
I had,
I met a football player ever retire full
player,
Marvin Washington at the end of last
year.
And he was spending about have all the
medical marijuana thing,
but he's really brilliant guy and he
cares about the broader policy issues.
We landed up drafting with him and three
other pro bowl,
you know,
pro bowl winners.
I'm basically a public letter calling on
the NFL to change it's marijuana testing
policy to admit that marijuana has
medical value,
that it's safer for many players that
when it comes to dealing with concussion
injury,
that marijuana may actually have a
therapeutic.
I mentioned to it,
not just made does without a doubt.
So the evidence there,
I was also encouraged to inflammatory
properties of it.
Do you see the US,
the International Olympics Committee.
What they've done now is I think they've
changed the level or when they test for
marijuana,
so they base their saying if you
haven't,
if you haven't used marijuana,
you know,
within the 24 hours before a match,
you're not our concern anymore.
So you see an evolution happening and at
different rates in different types of
professional sports,
you do.
And it's,
it's,
it's so important.
It really is because otherwise you're
basing your laws and your.
The way you punished me blind ignorance.
It's just foolishness and the idea
behind it is for what are you doing?
Yeah.
I mean it came out.
I mean part of this was we came out of
the drug war ideology,
right?
Drug testing sleeps into American
society and the Ronald Reagan days in
the mid eighties,
drug work goes crazy and the late
eighties,
everybody's feeling you have to drug
test most major corporations or drug
testing.
So we just got caught up in that.
Being in a,
a professor at Princeton late eighties,
early nineties and I saw the kids like
they knew they were going to be applying
for jobs.
We needed to be drug tested and it just
began to shape the whole way they
thought about this sort of stuff.
Yeah.
It's just so unfortunate because it
doesn't make you a bad person.
It doesn't make you a lazy person.
These are what's in what the thoughts
that are implied and testing people.
The idea is like,
Hey,
I am your employer.
I don't want you fucking up on the
weekend and then coming into work on
Monday.
All scrambled,
but there's no evidence of that at all.
Well,
I would say this,
I mean I would always want to do is to
give the other side what I think might
be true,
where might conform with own experience.
For some people,
marijuana,
smoking too much.
Marijuana does make them lethargic.
Some people smoke it at work.
If people look,
nobody wants kids wake and bake and
before they go to school,
right?
Some people can smoke marijuana 24 slash
seven.
It's sort of medical.
Does it harm the workability?
Other people,
it's a problem.
You know,
it can be a motivating.
For some people.
Look,
it's a drug and that means that some
people can use it in the wrong ways
problematically.
The problem is,
and this is where we fundamentally agree
for the large majority of people who use
marijuana do so responsibly and are not
having a problem with it,
and there's a huge number of people use
marijuana in a way that actually
enhances their life and there are many
of them who find it preferable to using
pharmaceutical medications or alcohol or
things like that.
There are people I know,
brilliant intellectuals and academics
who've done some of their best work and
come up with some of their best ideas
under the influence of marijuana or
psychedelics,
so marijuana can be a huge positive in
many people's life.
It can be neither here nor there in some
people and for some people to negative
there,
including Carl Sagan,
who was a huge proponent of marijuana.
I think that the people that have issues
with marijuana have issues and that's
one of the things that's been sort of
dusted under the rug.
You're blaming it on marijuana.
These people that smoke pot and it ruins
their life.
I mean,
I had a joke about it where I was like,
it's just because pot got there first.
It could have been anything that fucked
your life up.
It's usually some sort of an underlying
traumatic issue that you're trying to
run away from or hide or cover up.
Yeah,
I mean the problem of course is when
people in power a whole.
I mean I'll tell you on both ends of the
country,
governor Cuomo,
Governor Brown,
I don't know what their issue is.
Marijuana.
Well,
their issue is that there there's,
there's financial interests that are
trying to lead them in the way of
illegal.
John.
I don't think so.
I actually think that I've talked to
both of them about it and I can see and
both of them are Willie.
I think both of them had been decent
governors and other areas of their life.
I think some of the okay on sort of
rolling back some elements of the drug
war.
They're kind of mixed in that regard,
but cuomo just has this weird anti
marijuana thing.
I don't get.
And Brown talked to him a few months ago
at this same thing and when you're
saying,
okay,
well let's be specific,
like what?
It's not political for quote Como being
such a jerk,
a New York's medical marijuana law and
trying to carve it down so only like
five businesses can run this thing.
I mean all the stuff he did the.
It's got a medical model supported by 80
percent of New Yorkers.
Right.
There was no political reason for him to
do that sort of stuff,
but somehow some weird anti marijuana
things in there,
but then hold on,
but that doesn't seem like an anti
marijuana thing at all.
When you're talking about boiling down
to five businesses,
it sounds like a business look,
there may have been some of that theory,
but in been.
Well that seems like the only motivation
there's.
It seems to be there's no rational
motivation other than financial and in
Iowa know because in the end there was a
whole competitive process through that.
The five licenses,
it's hard to.
So whether the governor friends,
we haven't seen any evidence yet that it
was governor,
his buddies who benefited.
I think there was something that he felt
a need to be hyper controlling in this
area.
I think sometimes people go to that
ignorance,
he's got to know the financial massive
profit margin,
the massive,
uh,
the possibility for profit of these
people are going to experience that does
not ignorant.
He's got to know that you're talking
about something in Colorado that just
the tax revenue alone has been 100
million dollars.
A good reason for him to have done the
right thing.
Right.
The question is why does a guy like
that?
I try to sabotage a good bill and put it
in a bad bill in place once I,
you know,
I don't know.
I only know some.
Sometimes you think it could be
something involving a friend of theirs,
a kid of theirs,
their own personal experience.
I think it's something personal
oftentimes.
And with Jerry Brown,
I've,
I've heard rumors with both governors if
they used to smoke.
I've never heard I've other people say,
oh no,
these guys at Brown in California didn't
used to smile more shocking that he did.
Who knows?
But I mean,
I gotTa tell you Jerry.
Hi.
Right.
And I talked to Jerry.
Jerry think marijuana is the downfall of
American civilization right?
I mean,
but there's a part of that.
He actually,
he's don't say that publicly and
privately and he actually seems to
almost believe that at times,
and I think the other part of his brain
is smart enough to know that's
ridiculous,
but there's a lot of people who have had
a negative encounter with marijuana.
They've had a kid who started smoking
weed and waking and baking and went and
got into bigger trouble with other drugs
and I think they just like,
this is bad,
this is bad.
Or there people have had experienced
problems with alcohol and their family
and they think if alcohol was that bad,
weeds going to be even worse.
I think there's still that irrational
stuff driven.
Oftentimes by knowing somebody or
knowing of somebody with a associate
marijuana with bad things have happened
to that person.
I think Jerry Brown,
Jerry Brown has got a bigger problem and
that no one even knows he's the
governor.
The guy became the governor of
California after Arnold Schwarzenegger
and no one paid any attention was
literally no one even knows he's the
governor.
You never fucking hear governor Jerry
Brown,
like you said that,
and I had to and I know and I,
you said that I go,
oh yeah,
he's the governor.
Oh yeah.
I forgot sometimes that's a good sign,
but he used to be the governor a long
time.
Everybody knows Jersey and you know,
he ain't so
there anymore,
but he was the governor and he was an
interesting candidate for president in
the 19 eighties.
Right.
It was the eighties or nineties
to maybe what year was it?
Might've been [inaudible] 92.
The year that Clinton.
Yeah,
it was a long ass time ago and you know,
they would call them moonbeam governor
Moonbeam and they were making fun of
him,
but he had some unique ideas when it
came to running for.
I actually thought he was a really
interesting candidate back then.
I remember that.
I remember and I actually from New York,
you know,
it's fine.
When I bumped into a plane,
we're chatting and then we're making
Chitchat as the plane lands and he goes
to,
how's that?
How's that New York Governor Yours Doing
Cuomo?
And I say he's Kinda like,
Yo,
he's a pretty good governor overall,
but he stinks on the things that matter
when it comes to drug policy.
No,
it actually not all those things.
I said it to his face and we're ready to
get hit and now he left last.
Let's say you didn't see smiled.
He smiled.
Yeah.
No comment though.
I got to tell you,
you want to see something ugly.
Go on Youtube and type in the words rude
debate or type in the words.
Really rude debate.
And what pops up is me and Jerry Brown
pummeling one another and amy goodmans
democracy now show in 2008 when we had a
ballot initiative that would have been
the biggest prison reform ballot
initiative in the history of America.
And Jerry Brown was then the attorney
general and he did everything he could
to kill it.
And so we just went at it one day about
what,
what?
What's his rationalization?
I think at that point he wanted to run
for governor.
He wanted at the prison guards behind
them,
the prison guards union was making very
clear that if they were going to be
sport,
he had a blocked this.
They got every former governor and
governor,
governor and gubernatorial candidates to
get up and stand up against this.
I got to tell you,
if California passed that ballot
initiative prop five back in 2008,
it would've solved the big part of the
prison problem in this state at that
time.
That seems like I hear stuff like that.
I feel like it's treasonous.
I really do.
When I feel like a guy is doing for his
own benefit,
trying to block something that will be
beneficial to people especially
recognized and we have a huge issue with
the prison industrial complex in this
country and the idea that we had
privatized prisons in the first place.
The idea that someone's profiting off of
putting people in jail and the idea that
they're actively lobbying to make sure
that there's more laws in place that are
going to incarcerate people so that they
can make more money.
The idea that that's illegal is that
that drives me a bit.
I gotta tell you with the between the
prison guards union on the one hand and
the private prison corporations,
on the other hand please those guys,
I mean just thank God they hate one
another.
The prison guards union and the private
prison corporations,
because those guys have just been
feeding in that regard.
It's just money,
man.
It's just money.
Whenever you get money involved in
anything when it you getting money
involved in pharmaceutical industries,
when you get money involved in this,
the marijuana thing with these five
different corporations that are going to
control all the pot money,
fucking money.
My people trying to get
it is,
but the basic idea,
Joe,
were you saying before that that you
have a prison guards union that needs to
keep the prisons full in order to pad
their overtime pay or that you have a
prison?
Corporations that are making money if
more people get incarcerated and they'll
end up becoming advocates for laws that
lock up more people or advocates for
opposing the reform of laws that are
popping up,
popping up.
Too many people being a prison guards a
shitty job,
but those dudes need to do is grow.
We'd have to do.
You might know something interesting.
That's a great job.
Prison Guards Union did not oppose the
marijuana legalization initiative in
2010.
Really?
Yeah,
and I think the reason is,
is a,
I think there's two reasons.
I think one is marijuana prohibition
says a lot of people,
local jails,
but not that many of the state prison,
but the second reason is if you're a
prison guard and you're living in the
middle of God knows where,
you know,
California surrounded by nothingness.
What do you want to do when you get home
from work?
You want to get high.
Exactly.
You know,
in fact,
I,
my,
my guess is the prison guards union.
It's like anybody else right now,
they probably got members of their union
who are medical marijuana patients and
dealing with state laws that probably
prohibits.
They're using marijuana.
Do you think that with the current
climate that we have,
um,
with social media and the ability to
distribute information,
and then when outrageous laws are trying
to get past you can,
you can tweet them and facebook them and
people find out about them in this
online petitions.
Do you think that this,
this is lending itself more to
transparency,
this transparency is beneficial to
getting these more rational laws passed
or more,
more rational ideas promoted?
It's a great question.
I think it leans in our favor.
It's not the cure all.
It means that the ability of young
people to express themselves to
legislators,
the fact that more and more legislators
pay attention to facebook and twitter
and things like that,
I think that's generally good for us.
On the other hand,
what I also know is that we now see not
just on legalization of marijuana,
we see all this bipartisan consensus
that just too many people behind bars in
America that we need to reduce the
prison population.
That there's this horrible racism
permeate our criminal justice system
that the incarceration of black people
in this country is just an absolute
humanitarian and social and racial
nightmare.
Right?
So we see all of that happening.
We see bills being introduced to
reducing the prison population in the
states and had congressional level and
then a new drug scare pops up.
All of a sudden it's Flocka or best
salters synthetic cannabis or blah blah,
and then there's this knee jerk reaction
like,
you know,
criminalized first ask questions later.
Right?
And that's the thing we're still dealing
with that people will begin to come to
their senses about more sensible
policies and then they get scared and
when they get scared they do.
Some things don't do dumb things and
pass bad loss.
That's interesting because things like
bath salts only exists because what we
would call quote unquote legitimate
drugs are illegal.
So you find a work around why is both
Cynthia,
what's the market for synthetic
cannabis.
Most of that has to do with the fact
that people are worried about drug
testing for marijuana at all.
You're not going to get picked up.
I normally would choose if you had a
choice between regular pot or synthetic,
whatever the fuck it is.
What is that stuff anyway,
and what does it even coming from?
You know,
it it,
it's either synthetic cannabinoids or
maybe it's also,
I think Catherine own,
which is the ingredient that's in
caught,
you know the thing they choose issue in
east Africa,
east Africa and Yemen.
That's like a amphetamine.
It's a stimulant and it's sort of like
used the way the Indians to coca and
Bolivia and Peru,
Colombia,
so it's a.
When it's done in the chewing,
the leaf,
it's fairly innocuous.
When you extract the chemical,
you can then make it into something much
more potent and much more problematic.
See,
I was under the impression that even
chewing the leaves had more of a,
an amphetamine like effect.
It is.
It's the same thing like chewing cocoa
leaf,
right?
Chewing coca leaf releases.
It's slow drip of cocaine into the
system,
but it's basically almost a healthy form
of cocaine consumption.
Isn't that funny?
Yeah.
It's hilarious that the leaves itself,
like chewing the leaves.
Like I have a friend who was recently in
Peru and they,
they would all do it.
They give,
they give you like a bag of it and they
were on these hikes and they would chew
it.
And I liked,
what was it like?
He's like,
well,
it's like coffee,
but better.
Yeah,
exactly.
And it's actually has like flavonoids in
it and you know,
like a vegetable proteins or um,
what were the properties of vegetables
that are healthy,
like a vital nutrients like different,
like it's actually good for you.
You're chewing green vegetables.
When eight years ago the World Health
Organization organize a global study of
coca and cocaine.
It experts from 19 countries and after
this extensive survey,
what they found were two things.
One was that the vast majority of people
who use cocaine,
sniff cocaine,
whatever,
did not have a problem with it.
We're not addicted to it.
Even though there was obviously a
minority,
you had a big problem.
The second thing they found was that the
chewing of coca leaf by the Indians
probably headed net benefit from the
health perspective for exactly the
reasons you're talking about.
The we're vitamins and the leaves that
the,
that the,
they were consuming.
When you chew coca leaves during the
day,
you're consuming essentially the
equivalent of a few lines of cocaine,
which over the course of a day is like
having a few cups of coffee in a way.
Right.
And what they found is the only downside
was that to release the cocaine from the
coca leaf,
you had added a little lie and the lie
could hurt.
I think something had achieved the
enamel in the teeth,
something like that.
There's an issue with people that chew
coca leaves all the time to have these
rotten teeth.
I,
yeah.
That may be from the lime.
I don't know.
It may just be that they generally have
bed height,
you know,
teeth hygiene and those parts.
It's just like people say about meth
mouth and losing your teeth.
It's not about methamphetamine per se,
it's that nothing sort of,
you know,
reduces the moisture in your mouth.
And so you have to take extra special
care of your teeth if you're using
amphetamine with any regularity.
And most people know that people taking
amphetamine aren't taking extra special
care of anything.
Well,
the funny thing is this,
if you look at the 10 to 20 million
kids,
teenage boys in America taking Ritalin
or these things so they can focus better
in school.
Some of them being prescribed
appropriately,
others not.
It's essentially the,
as the amphetamine or
methamphetamine crazy and the
methamphetamine that people are smoking,
getting in trouble with.
If you take that in an oral form like a
pill,
it's essentially indistinguishable from
the riddle and the kids are taking in
schools,
you know,
I was reading an article on the sugar
and the,
the um,
the negative aspects of sugar,
processed sugar and how much of it is in
our diets and how much of it is and
things that you don't even consider.
And that's really essentially the same
thing when you talking about extracting
it from fruits because everybody agrees
at eating fruits is healthy.
And that's,
I mean,
when you're eating bananas and you're
eating apples and oranges,
what,
why,
why does it taste good?
Well,
you know,
there's sugar in it,
natural sugars,
but those natural sugars,
when you get them in that form with the
fiber,
with the planet itself,
with the vegetable itself,
is actually good for you.
It's actually the same as the coca
leaves,
three most powerful drugs knowing that
you have been kind sugar,
fat,
salt,
sugar,
fat,
salt,
sugar,
fat and salt,
and that the ability of the sort of food
producing corporations and their science
and their ability to produce products
that kind of,
you know,
hit that part of the brain in a be that
sort of is beyond your capacity when
they look at the explosion of obesity
and,
and people being overweight in America
and many other parts of the world.
Part of that is about the ability of
food producing companies to produce
products that hit that part of the
brain.
I remember Chris Rock,
he won't play,
do in a routine,
and he was talking about a Krispy Kreme
donuts and it was found the secret
ingredient of Krispy Kreme donuts
cocaine.
Right?
But in point of fact,
if you think about it,
I remember walking past the Krispy Kreme
donut outlet when they first opened up
and you could not walk past it without
this part of your brain twitching,
right?
In the same way that somebody is
addicted to drugs,
get to twitch when all of a sudden you
know they smell or see that drug in
place.
So the power of those substances,
there's psychoactive properties we're
used to them.
These are powerful drugs we know and
love,
but in point of fact,
if you ask what's doing more harm to the
health of Americans today?
Sugar,
refined sugar or cocaine or heroin,
could well be refined sugar.
Well,
there's an article,
like I said,
that I was reading that was they were
making the argument that it's a toxin.
There were saying essentially says sugar
is a very common toxin that people
consume.
But as you say,
when it's consumed in natural forms or
for that matter,
consumed in moderation,
no big deal.
But when you're taking large amounts,
when we see all the drinks,
yeah,
I mean just what you get in a glass of
Coca Cola.
That's way more sugar than you're
supposed to have in your day and it's in
a coke,
coke and how many people have three,
four cokes throughout the day and you
see these people with their guts and
they have all these issues with their
body and your face is fucking fat.
Like what is that that?
Well,
that's.
You're taking in too much sugar,
way too much.
When you look at people from the early
19 hundreds,
what they looked like,
I mean obviously a lot of that has
refrigeration.
They didn't have as much food.
People were much smaller than because
they weren't.
It was literally malnutrition,
so common aspect where we've gone
completely the other way now we have
enormous human beings.
People are way bigger than ever.
The.
It's a small world ride and Disneyland
had to be.
They had to carve their trench deeper.
They had to shut down the ride and carve
their trench deeper.
I was at Disneyland the other day and I
was with my daughters and their friend,
so there was three little girls and me,
but we couldn't sit in the same row
because you can't have more than three
people because they've got this thing.
I'm like,
I weigh more than the three of them do
together.
Like this is crazy.
Like you can't know with them.
What are the airlines going to adjust
the width of the seats to accommodate
this and.
No kidding,
right.
I travel a lot and my one nightmare is
being in sitting next to somebody who's
just kinda double size and all of a
sudden part of them's mic.
How about triple a,
but my friend Ralphie may a stand up
comedian.
I don't know if he flies first class,
but even if he does,
it's not first class enough.
He's 500 fucking pounds.
I don't know how.
I don't.
I literally don't know how he does it.
Although I did read that the country is
turning the corner on this.
That is actually beginning to come down
really fast.
People are dying.
Uh,
I think the message is beginning to sink
in,
really know some of it is just a matter
of just kind of being a little more
conscious,
you know,
I mean that whole supersize me stuff and
all this kind of stuff,
but once you get that big,
it's way past that.
That's lap band stuff.
Well,
Ralphie's had a couple surgeries.
I think he's had at least two of those
lap band things.
He blows through them.
You know,
when you,
uh,
I know several people who've had that
operation broke,
whatever.
They fixed the shrink your stomach down
and then you wind up having to go back
and having another operation because
you're stretching this tiny new stomach
out too much because it be,
it's a psychological issue more than is
even a physical issue.
It's the same thing when you're talking
about people that abused marijuana,
marijuana that's causing you to do that,
or is it some underlying trauma that
you're trying to smother with food,
with sugar,
with pot,
with alcohol,
with whatever the fuck it is.
It seems like the psychological issue is
as much of a factor as the physical
addiction.
And there can be no doubt there are
physical addictions to food and sugar,
but what is really going on there
that's,
that's overwhelming your life and making
you indulge in it.
And to some people would say,
and I think there's,
there's really something to this,
is that if we have an epidemic of
anything in our country and maybe in
many modern societies,
it's pain and it's a combination of a
pain that sometimes manifests
physically,
but it actually has to do with emotional
pain and a sense of emptiness and the
food and psychoactive drugs or ways of
filling this sort of stuff.
I mean,
I will tell you that we were talking
about back pain and all this sort of
stuff before and about the overuse of
opioids probably back in the early
nineties.
Two things happened to me in short order
that really affected,
really powerfully affected my
understanding of the mind body
relationship.
The first one was doing Mtma for the
first time and that was sort of just
kind of not just mind opening but openly
with my conscious.
Is there a mind body consciousness?
But the second one was I had gone
through three terrible episodes of back
pain and Sciatica and and I,
you know,
I did Mris and cat scans and I had a
herniated disc at the l,
four L,
five l five s one the whole sort of
thing.
I was 48 hours away from being operated
on,
you know,
I knew the operation surgery is risky.
And then I called a friend of mine,
Andy Weil,
Dr Andrew Weil who's a well known
integrative medicine guy and he said,
don't get the surgery.
He said,
go see this doctor,
this guy named John Sarno at the end one
you're talking about.
And soreness theory was all of this
stuff about herniated disc causing lower
back pain and leg pain radiating down.
He goes,
it's overwhelmingly bullshit.
And his theory is that what's really
going on is that it's,
there's nothing physically wrong with
your body,
that there's underlying emotional anger,
angsty feet,
whatever it might be,
and that your brain plays a trick by
turning this emotional pain and physical
pain.
And it does that through a process of
reducing the flow of blood around those
nerves.
And muscles,
et Cetera.
So without going on with this,
this approach,
Sarno approach worked for me.
I went from having this horrific pain to
sort of coming out of it very quickly.
Being able to pick up my little daughter
again,
do the sports I used to do,
and seeing myself as having a totally
healthy back though Sarno believes right
that it's not just lower back pain and
Sciatica.
Right.
And he uses.
This is not just faith healing.
This is what I mean pretty he,
he's his stuff is 90 percent supported
by the science on this stuff more than
any other,
any other theory of this stuff.
But his thing is that a lot of pain is
probably underlying emotional pain being
turned into physical pain and then we
deal with that through food,
through alcohol,
opiates,
whatever it might be.
And the reason why we ended up getting
into such trouble with drugs or with
food is because we're trying to address
this underlying almost existential pain.
Not by dealing with what's really
causing it,
but by trying to feed it things that we
think will cover it over now.
Sardo's.
Right.
And My,
I can't prove these right,
but based upon my own personal
experience and my reading and my
understanding what's going on with drugs
and food in this country,
I think there's a lot there.
Well,
Sarno certainly has some really good
points,
but there are definitely some physical
aspects to numbness and bulging discs
impeding on nerves and atrophy like
atrophied limbs,
which is a big problem with athletes
that have nerve issues were bulging
discs pushed down on nerves and it
actually cuts the nerve supply to the
muscles themselves and caused them to
atrophy.
That's real.
That's all real injuries are real,
but I think it's very important though,
that you recognize in it.
Everybody hearing this recognizes that
there are legitimate injuries that you
have.
Well,
it's hold on,
yeah,
through your discs,
bulge out and impinge,
impinge on nerves,
and you need to get that treated and
there's a bunch of different ways to
treat that that don't involve surgery.
Yoga is one of them.
Yoga is a really good one.
Another one is decompression because
I've gone through all this.
I've had some series bulging disc
injuries from Jujitsu and the,
you know,
I've had Mris that show this issue and
I've dealt with all it without surgery
so it can be done,
but click.
It's important to the.
There are people that have legitimate
injuries.
Yeah,
no,
no question about it.
I think even Sarna would say there are
people who have legitimate injuries.
How did you hurt yourself?
That's the whole thing.
See,
part of what Sarno points out is that
now that we have Mris and cat scans
being done commonly in our society,
that if you take 100 people who are
showing that they have herniated this,
right,
and you have 100 people who were showing
no herniated disc,
you'll have the same incidence of back
pain would whole show.
Is that the evidence that some when you
see that the people assume there's a
causal relationship between that MRI or
cat scan of the herniated disc and that
lower back pain now could be that you've
had a serious injury,
right?
You've been hit by a car,
you'd been at a sports injury where
there really is something going on
there,
but for many people there's not a
serious injury.
There's some little thing that kind of
triggers it,
but then somehow it transforms and this
and then he looks at people live in
other societies were lower back pain and
Sciatica or not sort of accepted reasons
for missing days of work or all this
sort of stuff and he finds much lower
incidence of these pain.
Right?
And the same thing.
Look at the carpal tunnel thing.
What's that about?
I mean,
people have been typing typewriters
forever and ever and ever and all of a
sudden we have this epidemic of this
thing,
right?
And then somehow that epidemic begins to
fade,
is replaced by something else.
Well,
let's hold on a second there because
carpal tunnel is real and we're one of
the reasons for carpal tunnel,
repetitive stress,
repetitive stress causes inflammation.
Inflammation locks up when you're forced
to sit at a keyboard in the same
position over and over again and
repeatedly do the same exercises.
You absolutely do.
Put undue stress on your hands and on
your wrist,
and if you're not prepared for it,
if your body's not conditioned and
you're you,
you're not a rigorous person,
you can have real issues with it.
My mom had to have surgery for carpal
tunnel.
I mean,
it's legitimate.
Then raise the question we had in the
1920,
30,
40,
50,
sixties and seventies,
tens of millions of American,
mostly women who were typing eight hours
a day,
12 hours a day.
Well,
first of all,
I couldn't type as fast because there
was the whole reason why the court,
he method was invented to keep the keys
from binding up because now we don't
need that because you have your fingers
just gently touch these things.
You can do it really quickly.
The other thing is diet.
Um,
there's a lot of inflamed inflammation.
Promoting foods are foods rather than
cause inflammation.
And that's just a fact.
Sugar is a big one.
Alcohol is a big one.
Process,
flowers,
wheats,
like things that your body has to break
down which breaks down to sugar.
Like this big thing in this country,
like gluten free.
This gluten free that go what?
What it is gluten.
There are people that have gluten
intolerances,
celiac diseases,
things on those lines.
People have wheat intolerance,
but I think it would.
A lot of it is is just sugar because if
you're eating bread that your body
breaks that stuff down.
Process,
flowers directly to sugar,
bread and pasta,
all that.
That white stuff,
that's shit's not natural.
You're breaking it down.
Your body takes that bleached process.
Flour and it converts it directly to
sugar and sugar causes inflammation and
that's.
That's a huge issue with people.
Yeah.
I'm no expert on all that sort of stuff,
Joe,
so I don't know.
I'll say that.
My takeaway from going through that pain
experience and all the reading I've done
and this thing is that when it comes to
treating certain farms of chronic pain
like this,
that the approach that works best is the
one that won most believes in,
right?
Whether it's Chiropractic,
whether it's yoga,
whether it's Sarno,
whether it's surgery.
The reason why surgery tends to have the
most immediate benefit right away is
because surgery is effectively the most
powerful placebo there is,
but when you see research that's showing
the three years after people who have
had back surgery are as likely to have a
back problem is that people did not have
the surgery.
You have to start questioning the
evidence around some of that.
Actually,
it's because of lifestyle choices.
I mean if you think about a person who
has surgery for a back issue and then
three years later they have more issues,
most likely they're living a life in the
exact same way,
which means they're putting the same
stresses on their body they were doing
before like sitting at a desk all day or
doing something like you're picking
stuff up.
Folks that work in warehouses and things
along those lines and you have to pick
stuff up all the time and your body's
not conditioned for it.
So you have repetitive stress in that
regard.
There's a lot of issues and you know
what caused it.
You may be right.
That could be it and that certainly can
trigger the pain,
but I'm going to tell you,
having been through the experience and
I've met many people a since that who
for whom at work I think and because the
Sarno approach,
if it works for you,
is one way.
You get to see your body as whole once
again and not as vulnerable and because
it pushes you to deal with underlying
emotional stuff that may be driving some
of this physical pain.
I mean for all those reasons,
I think my.
My view is when people ask me and I'll
say,
read sorrows book,
you know,
on back pain,
right?
Or healing back pain and I'll say if it
doesn't make sense to you,
try something else.
But the thing about desanto thing is if
it does work for you,
it's in some respects the most
miraculous of all the.
I think the Sarno approach is a great
approach.
Don't get me wrong,
but I don't think they're mutually
exclusive to taking care of your body in
a physical sense.
And I think that most people just don't
take care of their body in a physical
sense.
They don't exercise.
I think exercise is,
and especially treating your core as if
it is the foundation of your body,
something that supports you all day
long,
you're back,
you know,
there's very few people work out their
back in a sense of like long static
exercises like yoga where you're holding
poses for 30 seconds,
you know,
and doing one after the other and doing
it over a course of Oregon.
It's not fun.
Like you said,
he can't get into it because you don't
find it enjoyable,
but the benefits of doing that,
man,
I'm telling you,
I just got into it a bit less than a
year ago.
I've been doing on a weekly basis,
like fairly regularly.
The benefits are tremendous for me.
Your,
your back just feels way better.
Just feels like you have more.
There's more vigorous with it.
More with core exercises,
with Yoga,
with yoga exercises,
Yoga.
A big part of what yoga works is what we
call our core.
I mean it's literally your,
your,
your spine,
you know,
from your neck down to your back.
And that's a big part of what you're
holding these poses.
And you know,
you have to hold your in a straight
line,
like what are you doing?
You're,
you're,
you're supporting everything with your
back and with your spine sound like
lifting weights is,
it's a different sort of thing where
you're holding your own bodyweight.
Well,
I'll tell you something to return to
where our conversation got going.
One of the great things about living in
Manhattan is we walk and the result is
that there's a lower incidence of
obesity in Manhattan than there is in
most of the United States.
Makes Sense.
And that walking is one of the safest
even for people who don't want to take
out the time to exercise because walking
is the way we get places.
It turns out that we land up to believe
relatively healthy lives in a place like
Manhattan,
not was standing all the crazy.
What are you doing when you're walking?
You're carrying me.
What do you weigh?
One hundred and 80 pounds or something
like carrying that 180 pounds around.
Whereas that amount of energy and that
amount of calorie expenditure is lost if
you're sitting in the car driving to
work,
getting in an elevator,
going to your office,
sitting in your cubicle,
all that's lost,
all that's lost and it's probably
thousands of calories a day.
You're also making me think about when I
remember my experience with him Dma,
uh,
you know how there are some people when
they do an and they just like to sit and
get in a place and other people like me
just want to move,
move around,
know,
get the energy going and such.
You know,
I also found some times he only talked
about going back to the whole mushroom
thing.
I remember feeling especially that.
So it's the mushrooms you take them and
they start to come on and I can find
like,
it's like this energy force going into
your body and in some ways the best way
to deal with that stuff is movement.
It's running,
it's swinging around,
it's moving around,
like opening up your body to lift that
powerful energy.
Yet,
you know,
I think there's a lot of tension that
people carry around their bodies or
their bodies just aren't being used
correctly or they're bunched up or
they're not stretched out and are
confined and bound up and they have poor
posture and then the stress of life and
bills and all the things that are
weighing down in.
I think in that sense Arno's out an
excellent point that pressure and stress
and pain and just frustration just
causes you to be tense and everything is
fucked up and if you can address that
and sort of relax a little bit,
just that alone just to alleviate a lot
of tension and that's a lot of what
people carry around them.
That's also a lot of what people like
about pot.
Like you said that how we used to like
to smoke pot and stretch out what's
going on there.
You're releasing releasing tension.
He smoked pot like,
man,
I love doing that before a show.
I like smoking a little weed before show
and stretching out and that was one of
my favorite things to do.
Just sit,
sit in a dressing room before I go on
and just stretch,
warm up,
loosen up my back,
stretch my back out and stretch my body
out.
It's.
It's something that we don't do enough.
You buy your meat vehicle,
move that fucker around.
I know,
I know.
It's true.
Look man,
I work in an office a lot of the time
and it's just so easy to get in that
zone and you're in front of that
computer.
That's what you're doing,
you know,
and all the sudden you realize your
shoulders about.
You're exactly right when you're going,
especially if you have bad posture,
you carrying it.
Like if you're sitting like I,
you know,
when I had my back injury,
which was sports related,
but when I started getting treatment for
it,
I realized there's a lot of other
underlying issues and one of them is if
you're sitting in a desk and you have
poor posture,
the strain has been a lot of studies
done on this street is in a very
specific area,
so instead of being straight where your
back is carrying the weight in an even
form through the top of your head all
the way down to your lower back,
you're causing this undue spot,
this weird spot in the middle by
slumping where you get all this pressure
in this one area that really shouldn't
be there.
And over time,
like cab drivers that have a,
a thick wallet and they keep it in their
back pocket and they sit on there.
They developed bulging disks in their
back.
It's just the slow water that causes the
rock to go smooth.
Well,
the other cuts of channel through put.
I mean,
for me,
the thing I've learned from so many
people,
and it's basically the kind of common
ingredient and almost all spiritual
practices,
meditative practice is just simple deep
breathing,
right?
Because just having to fill your lungs
just,
it just forces you to have to sit up all
of a sudden if you want to fill your
lungs and that,
that breathing,
this just the slow breathing gets went
to focus to center.
I mean I know that when I'm stressed off
the advantages,
grabbing a drugs,
I think that's the wrong way to use
drugs.
Just trying to remember,
take a breath,
try to take five breaths,
10 breaths,
slowly in and out,
and that's one of the best centering
things.
There are.
Well,
you know,
I've been teaching that to my five year
old.
I kind of taught her when she was three,
when we started talking about it,
like she would get upset,
like something would happen.
Like she would like stubborn pto or not
even like a big deal,
like hurt or something would something
would get her upset and she would cry
which was crying.
And then I fell down and I do that.
I'd be like,
you've got to breathe in and breathe
out.
Let's do this together.
We'll do it together.
And I do it with her.
I'm like,
take a breath.
And you're like,
it's hard for them because they're,
they're hyperventilating.
But it made me realize like,
wow,
that's a lot of people that go through
that with issues in life,
you know,
you have some incredibly stressful issue
and it just overwhelms you and you take
this shallow,
panicky breath and you know,
it's one thing when a three year old
doesn't know how to deal with,
you know,
hurting herself or falling down or
whatever.
What is that made her upset.
But when adult,
you know,
gets to 50 years old and they still
don't know how to deal with stress as
kind of a tragedy.
It's like either you have.
We don't really teach that in our
society anyway,
you know,
it's interesting to,
uh,
my,
my niece has just started medical school
and I was asking her what she was
thinking of specialty shoes,
thinking about.
And I was saying to my,
I think if I ever decided to pursue
medicine instead of what I did do,
I think the single most fascinating area
of medicine right now is pain
management.
It is the most interdisciplinary of all
areas because it requires you understand
physical pain,
you understand pharmaceuticals and
biochemistry and understanding,
but it also requires
that element of understanding things
like breathing and exercise and the body
and it's that area.
I mean the pain is such physical pain is
such an epidemic in America today for
all these reasons.
You and I are giving different reasons
and agreeing on a lot of it,
but I think that becoming a more
thoughtful and sophisticated society in
terms of how we deal with this,
how will you alleviate it,
how we prevent it and doing so in a way
in which the government is playing a
positive role as opposed to a
destructive role.
Because right now,
right,
the role of the government,
these are the physicians who want to
properly deal with pain management is
intimidating them and scaring them.
Then the way in which the pharmaceutical
companies drive where drugs people have
means that oftentimes people don't have
access to the things they need.
Meanwhile,
the failure to think about the
importance of breathing in our society
of posture,
the things you're talking about.
Exercise is another element.
All this sort of stuff and on some level
I think,
you know,
look,
a lot of the drug problem has to do with
issues of race and class and stuff like
that,
but a lot of it also has to do with this
kind of pervasive sense of pain,
physical and emotional pain that people
are trying to treat and all sorts of
ways.
Yeah,
I think you're right.
I think it's also the requirements of
life are really unnatural.
The life that we've set up for
ourselves,
the requirements of managing bills and
dealing with taxes and dealing with the
stress of marriage and the nonsense that
comes with divorce and the chaos that
comes with all sorts of different
aspects of our life.
It just seems just overwhelming and then
the existential angst of your own
mortality compounding every day.
The futility of getting up every morning
when you want to stay in bed,
the alarm goes off,
hit that fucking button,
he get up and you put your fucking
clothes on just like every other day and
you drink your coffee and you do your
rituals and you go to a job that you
find unsatisfying.
That is the vast majority of Americans
and probably have people in the world.
I think that you live a fulfilling life.
You're doing what you enjoy doing and
I'm very lucky to feel the same way,
but I think that we're in the minority
and I think there's a large amount of
people out there that are longing for
something better than what they have.
Whether it's a better relationship or
it's a better connection to their family
or it's a better,
some rewarding thing to do with their
time.
Well,
you see,
I mean,
part of that explains why more and more
people are seeking out the church,
whether it's evangelical churches or
other types of truth.
I think so.
I mean,
look,
you see those numbers grow in these mega
churches that are happening.
The other.
I think that the numbers of people that
are involved in organized religion or
I think the ones who are going to the
conventional churches,
the more mainstream churches and
synagogues,
that's what's dropping the ones who are
being drawn to the angelical ones,
the ones where they sort of are more
attentive to bring in the spirit and the
body into the practice of religion.
Right,
but evangelical churches,
you know,
you,
you dance,
you move,
you do all this sort of stuff.
I think people doing the same thing in
the world that we know of,
psychedelics and doing these things.
People want to link their body,
mind their
spirit community.
That's look at millions of people,
young people now going to sort of the
whole kind of a dance dance world,
the nightlife world,
all that stuff.
Same thing that kind of almost
collective quasi religious communitarian
feeling of letting go in the company of
others.
I think people are so much want and need
that and it's a good thing for people to
do that.
It's not hurting other people or people
that are getting hurt in the process and
that's another thing we started.
Drug Policy Alliance is a whole project
and trying to keep young people safe as
they're in this whole night.
Life Dancing,
right?
People are taking all these drugs are
doing things.
Somebody said drinking too much,
they're overheating and people get hurt
and the question is young people going
out and enjoying themselves for hours or
days,
listening to music being another moving
train and even doing mind altering drugs
can be a perfectly healthy and good and
even liberating thing,
good for their lives,
but we need to make sure it's being done
safe.
That notion of making our societies as
safe as possible for people to open up
and let go,
whether it's with or without drugs,
I think is something we have to evolve
towards.
I think you're dead right,
but I also think that the issue is that
we haven't built a foundation of
stability in these people up to this
point where they're taking these
exploratory journeys of the mind.
I mean,
they're.
Their foundation is fucked up there.
You know,
there's so much going on outside of that
they need to take care of before they
just dive into the world of psychedelics
and it's one of the reasons why people
have bad trips.
I mean,
what is a bad trip?
You're resisting all the things that
these drugs are exposing.
You put these blinders on,
gone through this life and whether it's
childhood trauma or you know,
unfulfilled expectations that are
haunting you,
whatever it is that's that is causing
the quote unquote bad trip.
A lot of what that is is resisting the
message that these boundary desolving
experiences are giving you.
They're sending you as a message,
as a.
you're inherently unhappy.
You're unhappy in,
in almost like a cellular level and that
it's not as simple as just like diving
in and,
and having a mushroom trip and it's all
going to clear out.
You've got to deal with the foundation
of your own personality.
I agree.
The question is how do we do that really
board,
when you look at now,
I mean look at younger people who are on
the Internet,
24 slash seven.
It's constant.
You know,
that people will look to stand on any
corner and see the number of people
walking around looking at their,
at their,
you know,
little gadget,
right?
Looking at their facebook,
looking at this or whatever,
right?
People are interacting with the world in
an entirely different way.
Right?
And then of course the way society is
evolving so quickly,
you know,
entrepreneurial folks can thrive,
but for huge numbers of people,
there's no sense of security about what
the economy,
the society is going to be like in the
future.
I mean we are kind of hurtling into the
Artificial intelligence is going all
sorts of crazy
places.
All sorts of jobs are being displaced by
robotics and things like that.
So,
you know,
just talking with my daughter,
my daughter who's now 20,
about to be 27 and you know,
it's just,
it's,
it's a,
it's a whole.
The world is,
is the pace of change is so remarkable
in this regard.
There are so few guides and the ability
of the parental world to play a
constructive role.
First of all,
many parental,
mainly parents aren't that good as
parents or they're not that good at
helping young people,
you know?
Um,
but beyond that they're so disconnected
sometimes from what's going on for,
you know,
kids growing up in a whole different
way.
Right.
When I think when I was growing up in
the sixties and early seventies,
you know,
the pace of change which so much slower
than than it is now.
Right.
So I don't know what to curate all that
stuff is.
Yeah.
I think we're going to have to adapt to
this new world where people are getting
information.
It's just staggering rate that you got
to decide how to manage it.
And you know,
some like my friend Ari,
Ari Shaffir,
he switched to a flip phone and he's
like,
fuck this,
I can't do this anymore because he would
say he would tell me that he would get
up in the morning and then he would
spend like a half an hour going over
facebook and going over all this and
that before we ever got anything done.
Now he just gets up and does stuff and
if he wants to take care of all his
bullshit,
he does it on a computer.
So he sits down,
he says,
okay,
now I'm going to answer my emails.
Now I'm going to.
Instead of just constantly being
attached to social media.
Like I said,
I had a weird experience.
I accidentally signed up for facebook
two weeks ago.
I had this public facebook account which
like my staff managed,
but then my phone
got lost.
I had to reset the whole thing and I had
received my spotify account,
was hooked up to my facebook thing and
if that password,
next thing you know,
Bang,
Bang.
All of a sudden I created my own
personal facebook thing
and so now I'm trying to feel what do I
do with it.
So I friended a few people.
A few people I work with are all freaked
out that the boss is thread to them,
you know,
and,
and now I'm scrolling through and now I
understand when people are looking at
and it,
you know,
you just see you're talking about sugar,
fat,
salt.
Nothing more addictive than that little
gadget there.
Yeah,
it's very addictive.
I've backed off way hard over the last
few months.
Over the last few months.
I very rarely even go on my own message
board.
I have a message board on my website
that I've had since 1998 and I go on
there occasionally and check to see what
what's going on in the news or what
people are talking about are debating
and this and that,
but I find it to be.
There's a massive requirement of time to
check all these different things to
check facebook and twitter and then
there's social media.
There's websites that I visited,
his message boards that have visited
different websites that aggregate news
stories and it's just too much.
It's just to back way off of it over the
last couple.
I try to stick with the discipline that
there will be at least once or a few
times a year where I will go into a
total blackout on any communication
using that gadget.
I did a vacation a few years ago for
days where I did not pick up my laptop
computer.
Even my phone,
my,
you know,
nothing right and know for the first day
or two like my hand was like fidgeting,
you know,
like it was going through withdrawal
from that whole sort of thing.
But I have to say I got today six and I
had achieved a level of calm that I
associated with like,
you know,
biting surfing as a 12 year old on the
beach.
I mean it was so,
so good and I got to tell you something,
I haven't done it since I did it for a
few days over Christmas.
I am so looking forward to finding some
days the next week or two or I'm going
to do that again.
Almost brings tears to my eyes.
When I think about that level of
disconnection I think.
I think human beings need to do that.
Well I,
I certainly don't think the word
designed to deal with the influx of
information and the opinions of other
people are thrown at you on en masse.
Like,
like we get with social media.
I just think it's too much and I think
it's very addictive.
Communication is addictive in just being
able to,
like you always think you're going to
miss out on something.
There's gonna be some new thing that
comes out that you're not aware of and I
think that managing that is really
critical because we're not.
We haven't developed to deal with that.
This is a completely new thing and I
don't think we're designed even media.
I think just the movies and songs,
there's a lot bunch of people running
around out there that don't have a
realistic view of human beings because
their view of human beings is based on
heroes in movies and songs playing.
When people talk and everybody either
acts no bully or they act obviously
evil.
It's like these ideas of human beings
are shaped by 15
shannon when people are doing that,
you're getting as opposed to reading
reading novels as I did when I was
younger but barely do today.
You get a much more deeper nuanced sense
of human beings by reading novels and
you possibly can by watching a movie
watching a thing.
Right,
so you're exactly right.
Same thing with body shape,
body consciousness,
all the ways in which that's so screwed
up in our society once again,
shaped by the media.
I mean I'm trying to do my few little
disciplines like try not to look at my,
at my phone over the last year,
the last hour before I go to sleep
because they say you sleep better if you
don't do that,
you know,
just trying to find some space sometime.
Try to turn off the ringer,
you know,
more often.
Uh,
just some way of carving out that space.
Yeah,
I think that that's a good thing.
It's a good thing to manage what's
coming in.
It's a very,
very good thing to manage what's coming
in because you just can't.
You can't rely on all these other people
to,
to have access and to be able to input,
you know,
into your own mind is just too many.
There's too many people out there that
want to,
first of all,
how many people just want to bark at you
to get attention?
How many big review we're fucking doing.
Your job pot would already be legal and
you read.
They're like,
what the fuck,
man,
I don't even know this guy and he's
yelling at me that I'm not doing my job.
He doesn't know what I'm doing.
He doesn't even know me.
He doesn't want to know you,
what he wants his attention and he's
using this as a vehicle,
like a whiny baby screaming out for
attention.
And oftentimes
that squeaky wheel does get the say.
I don't even read a lot of that stuff
that shows up on various know public
allies when I speeches go up on youtube
and stuff like that.
But it's,
it's,
it's true.
It's just the other thing,
of course there's a power dynamic here
which is there for people who work for
somebody.
The risks that we're moving into society
where your boss or your employer expects
you to be accessible.
Uh,
you know,
so like I let my staff,
although at the alliance,
if they get an email from me on a
weekend,
which they might,
because I sometimes work on weekends,
there was no obligation and they'll
expectation that they answered,
I think told Monday.
Right?
I mean that just so people know,
there's a sense of space.
I have a friend who goes to work on
Monday and his boss will get pissed at
him if he doesn't answer emails from the
night before,
like he'll get an email at night and
he's like,
why didn't you respond to that email?
And he's like,
look,
I,
you know,
I came home and spend time with my
family is like,
look,
there's no excuse.
Check your email,
check your numbers.
Like what the fuck kind of a job have I
gotten.
That's not the definition of a civilized
society.
Isn't that what's going on with trump
testing?
Because if someone's telling you that
you can't smoke a joint after work,
what they're telling you is they own
your body,
their own your body.
Because if you smoke a joint at 9:00
at night and you go to work at 9:00
in the morning,
guess what?
That joints gone.
It doesn't.
The,
the,
the effects don't linger.
Quite frankly,
the employer has a greater basis.
If you come to work Monday,
nine morning hung over because that may
of way have been.
If you've been up all night because you
were in pain or having a fight with your
wife or your kid was sick,
that may affect work performance,
but the fact that you smoked a joint on
a Saturday or do something else and
you're finding a Monday,
none of their damn business.
This is ultimately about sovereignty of
our own minds and bodies.
Right?
I mean the core principle right here is
that we're all sovereign over our own
minds and bodies and that my boss,
my government has no power to tell me
what I do to my own body or in my own
mind so long as I am not hurting another
soul.
That has to be the core principle of a
free society.
Not only that,
it's the same sort of argument with wwe
in respect to doing crimes when you're
on these drugs like the crimes
themselves or the issue and the
punishment should be in relation to the
crimes.
They should have absolutely nothing to
do with what substance caused you to do
the crime.
Exactly.
That's exactly my you on this thing and
said if you used drugs and you don't
hurt a soul,
that's none of the government's
business.
If you use drugs and you go out and hurt
somebody,
well the fact that you use drugs so that
you were addicted,
right?
You'd have to be held just as
accountable,
right?
Somebody's drug addiction.
It cannot be an excuse that it will
allow them to do harm to others.
That said,
and there's a little position in the
middle that if a judge in his wisdom or
somebody else decides that you hurt this
person and it was driven by your drug
addiction and decides that you should go
to some treatment program instead of
jail because that's better for you and
better for society than that might be
the reasonable compromise,
but ultimately people need to be held
responsible for their actions.
Is affects other people that were very
well put,
the compromise
and.
But it's very difficult to leave that in
the hands of the judges because when
you.
The judges impose their own moral ideas
and attached the.
I mean there's been so many instances.
Just really recently there was a guy who
got in a fight with his girlfriend's ex
boyfriend and beat him up and the judge
told him that if he didn't want to go to
jail,
he had to marry the girl.
Like,
who the fuck is this judge?
And here's another one where this guy,
this young boy,
he was 19 years old,
he was on this social media application.
It's called hot or not.
Were you?
Someone decides whether or not they
think you're hot.
I heard it.
Yeah.
So he,
uh,
contacts this girl,
she's 17,
goes and drives to her house,
has sex with her.
It turns out she's 14.
So now he's locked up.
They put them in this,
uh,
this database as a sex offender.
Yeah.
And one of the,
the judge,
one of the judge's statements is that
sex should be something that people do
when they're in love and that it should
be this very important thing to sacred
thing.
And you shouldn't be involved in these
social media things where you just go
around fucking each other.
Like,
who the fuck is it?
Tell Ya we haven't.
My for drug policy alliance,
the problem with drug court judges,
I mean some of these guys are doing the
Lord's work,
but so many of them are simply imposing
their own moralistic views about drug
use.
They're telling people,
okay,
I won't send you to prison as long as
you clean and sober for the rest of your
life for as long as you're under my
supervision.
And if somebody wants to smoke a joint,
that becomes a basis for taking away
their freedom.
So there's something fundamentally wrong
with assuming that judges who are not
trained in these areas who have their
own biases and prejudices should be
determining the quality.
You know how people live a life when
they haven't done anything to hurt
anybody else,
comes down to human beings being put in
positions of power over other human
beings and once you can dictate what
happens to that person's freedom.
That's intoxicating feeling to a lot of
these guys and they or gals and they
just choose to impose their own
viewpoints on that person because they
can.
Because they gets.
That's how they get their rocks off so
that that's how they avoid their own
existential angst.
That's how they avoid their own
depression by imposing power over these
other people.
It's judge Judy,
right?
I mean that's.
That's.
That's the whole show is that she's
allowed to be.
Yeah,
the most Venal of all the actors,
but we're talking about the role,
which money is driving the prison
industrial complex in what you're saying
about judges,
the worst of all the actors or the
prosecutors,
those guys,
because it's all about power.
It's about interpersonal power.
It's about power within the criminal
justice system.
For many of them,
it's about making a name for themselves
by beating up people and thereby,
you know,
running for politics and ultimately it's
not money.
In many cases it's about power,
power and showing how effective you've
been as a prosecutor.
Kit
My record and then that sense,
I liken it to sports.
I think the real problem with
prosecution and even with police,
is that it becomes a winning and losing
thing.
If the guy got off,
you lost.
Not that the guy was innocent.
It's not that you were incorrect in
assuming that he had broken the law and
should be punished by the laws of our
society,
by the rules that we've agreed to govern
ourselves by.
No,
no,
no.
It's a game.
It's a game like basketball that's
driven game.
We've decided in America that we're
going to have an adversarial system of
justice.
Right?
That's a good way of putting it and,
and,
but what happens of course is that most
of the power,
unless you're rich,
is in the hands of the government and
the prosecutor.
It's why poor people are getting.
Look,
why does America have the highest
incarceration rate in the world?
Why do we have the highest incarceration
rate of any democratic society in
history?
Why do we lock up more black people at a
rate that forest [inaudible] the rates
of incarceration is Soviet gulags in the
thirties,
forties,
and fifties.
In part it's because we have an
adversarial system that's fundamentally
broken and we're the cops and the
prosecutors drive this thing
overwhelmingly,
and we're a few are the typical person
in that system who doesn't have money to
hire a good lawyer.
Stuff like that,
you are going to be removed and you're
going to be caught in a system where you
may never escape it.
You know why America,
we didn't use to be where we had a
incarceration rate that was basically at
the world average for most of our
history,
but the last 40 years we went ape shit
in terms of locking people up in this
country,
especially black people.
That's the thing we have to fight to
pull back from.
That's where we have to undermine the
power of the of the money driven
interest at corporations and the prison
guard unions.
It's where we have to challenge the
abuse of power by,
by,
by judges and especially with
prosecutors and they have to be pulled
back in a major way and the sheriffs I
should say because in California got to
sheriffs who are the ones trying to
build new jails and keep marijuana
illegal and all this sort of stuff.
That grows in judgment of power in the
hands of people whose job it is to take
away people's freedom and to use no
judgment and the ways they do that or
minimal judgment and the presumption
that if you violate a law,
you have to lose your freedom.
That's what screwed things up so badly
in our society.
That's the movement we're trying to
build to Ed and on that joke.
I got to go to the next meeting.
Beautiful.
You nailed it.
Thank you sir.
Really appreciate it.
Let's do this again.
When are you when you're in town?
Often I come to town fairly often.
I may be back here in October with a
ballot initiative in California coming
up in 2016.
You know,
so I'm here a lot and let's do it in
October man.
Come on back.
Let's work on that ballot initiative to
get people active.
Sounds good.
Thank you Ethan.
Really,
really appreciate it.
Great to meet you.
Great to meet you too.
I really appreciate it.
Thank you.
Alright fuckers.
See you soon.
Was Fun.
That was great.