Day One of legal marijuana.
Bert Kreischer.
It doesn't feel any different.
Does it feel less naughty?
Uh,
no.
I'm just worried that they're going to
clog up the dispensary's the people
will.
Yeah.
Because now you have to use the wait in
the waiting room sometimes.
Now that it's going to be legal.
I don't know how they're like one in one
out thing.
It's gonna be a fucking nightmare.
Are they allowed to just open up down
the general public?
Is that how it works?
I was just looking right before we
started.
I think they have until 2018 to start
issuing licenses and 2018.
They can't.
The current dispensary's can only sell
to their current patients.
Like they can't sell the people walking
in off the street.
They're going to change some rules.
Oh.
But 2018 before they start giving out
licenses haven't tilled that long.
They don't push it until that long.
Oh,
if they wanted to hold back and dig
their heels in.
Huh?
Interesting.
So we have at the very most,
a year before it just get,
becomes like Colorado,
which is Carla was goddamn while I'm
circling.
It happened in Colorado too.
It took him about a year before they
figured everything out.
Have you,
uh,
have you been down and gone down to like
the areas of Colorado where they're
selling pot now?
Yeah,
I went with you right?
Because you did,
you,
we didn't go down to the store.
I went to a couple stores on my own
without you,
I guess.
Yeah.
I haven't,
I've driven by them but I haven't gone
in and checked them out.
But that's what's going to happen here.
It's going to be crazy and it's going to
be better for everybody.
It's going to be better for the economy.
It's going to be better for people.
My wife doesn't,
doesn't smoke weed at all and voted yes.
I'm good.
Good.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Um,
she,
uh,
she voted for um,
us to prop 70,
64.
That might've been my favorite night
moment of the whole night last night.
It was pretty awesome by the way,
that I give 100 percent credit to Jamie.
That was like you gave me an ace in the
hole.
I was sitting off the side.
I don't even have a mic at time.
I don't think Jamie just goes breaking
news and hands me his phone.
I wasn't even reading it up the phone,
but I grabbed the mic and I go,
guys,
I have breaking news prop 64 has been
legally been passed in California.
The place went nuts.
Joe Lights at joint.
I rip my shirt off.
Started slapping the stage bill birds
high past that joint like he had indeed
passed to a couple of times.
He was like,
I'm good.
I don't smoke pot.
I'm a whiskey guy,
and then he was like,
fuck.
It took a legit hit.
Yeah,
he was stoned too.
That was wrong.
With that said,
let me
speed.
We'd shit.
I don't know what strain he's got,
but good.
Jesus Lord.
Oh mercy was such a beautiful night.
That was probably the most fun I've ever
had on a podcast.
I keep.
I've said that before because I had
some.
I've had,
we've had some fun ones together.
Oh Yeah,
but dad might have topped it off.
I don't think I've ever laughed any
harder.
Like borough had me laughing harder
than.
I mean it's just as hard as you can
laugh.
It was so fun.
Everything was fun.
Yeah.
The bar me,
you have me with that line because you
guys see that picture of trump looking
at his wife voting and you were like,
what did you say?
I said,
that's the look I give my dog when he
gets too close to my cat.
Hey motherfucker,
leave her alone.
That whole show was so quick.
It was so.
It was literally like a,
like they were doing double Dutch with
comedy and you had to know when to jump
in and went and I'm going to hop out and
I said this to you this morning or this
afternoon.
That first 133 minutes was not that much
talking over each other when something
happened that I wasn't aware of,
but people started to show it up.
They weren't invited and sat down.
I didn't know.
We're just sort of sorting that out now,
like there's microphones that were there
and you know,
there was people that we had asked to
come that we're kind of waiting to get
on and then other people that just sort
of walked in and got on.
I don't think it was clear to them.
I don't know how it was set up,
I don't know,
but it's chaotic when you have more than
two people just to people's hearts
sometimes to manage conversations,
but then you get three and four and then
you play it in front of a live audience
and then people just coming in and
jumping in.
So there was a couple of issues.
I guess.
I wasn't paying too much attention and
we were too drunk.
We were gone.
You bailed out when,
uh,
when you went into the set.
Well,
when I went and do a set,
that's apparently what.
And Sarah Tiana went at it.
I missed all the goodness.
All I'll tell you is that I've been
doing comedy 17 years.
I am well aware that bill burrs practice
of comedy is to assemble brilliantly
laid arguments that you wouldn't
normally agree with.
To go head to head with them in a debate
about porn would not be something I
think would be wise of anyone.
What was her,
her position was,
this is when I was leaving,
her position was that people watch too
much porn.
Then men like pouring too much.
Right?
Yeah.
And,
and it was about the condoms and for
moving to a different place and,
and then it turned into the middle
crossover states are just racists and
just broad stroking kind of.
It was what bill was doing,
I think.
I Dunno,
I was pretty fucked up at this time,
but he was,
he was disassembling what is this
elitist liberal movement,
which is,
if you don't agree with me,
you're a racist rape apologist,
sexist,
and bill just was saying that's not it.
Some people want change,
you know?
Yeah,
yeah.
That,
that is a real sweeping brush that
people from both sides like to use.
Right?
The people and the right to use it on
the liberals,
the liberals like conservatives,
unconservative,
we like to paint people like real
obvious,
put,
you know,
put them in a box,
make sure we can categorize them.
Yeah.
So I mean,
I said,
well,
I think I got,
I think I might have accidentally
started a little bit of it because it
looked,
all you have to realize is there's just
a disenfranchised part of America that
feels like they're not being
represented.
And then immediately I think Sarah got
jumped on me and she was like,
Oh,
you're talking about the racists.
And I was like,
I don't know.
You can't say that.
You can't say that I voted for him by
the way.
I voted for Hillary.
So I'm just saying,
Ha,
what I'm noticing.
I have an election.
So I.
But I,
you know,
I thought it was good of her to stand
her ground and,
and to hold into say her point and not
trying to backpedal and,
and I appreciate it
that.
But,
well,
you know,
the problem is the problem with that
saying that anybody that voted for trump
is a racist.
The real,
the real problem with that is because
the only other alternative is Hillary
and Hillary was very flawed.
That's just the way it is.
You know,
it's not,
it's not an anti woman thing to think
that someone who has all the ties to
corruption that she apparently does mean
you can go into it all day long if you
want to,
if you want to like look at the Clinton
Foundation or any of the other crazy
shit that those people were involved
with.
It's kind of legal,
you know what I mean?
Not really breaking any laws so you can
get away with doing all that stuff.
But all of it is learning,
deleted emails and all that.
Like what are you doing?
Like what is this you?
And I think,
I think there was a large portion of
America who just didn't want to show
their opinion because they didn't want
to be called a name
[inaudible].
And there's,
there's real concerns too.
And people don't want to say this.
There's real concerns about her health.
Really.
She hurt her head in 2012 because she
blacked out.
She,
she blacked out,
fell,
fainted,
and hit her head really bad,
like really bad.
And um,
apparently she was fucked up for like
six months and this was 2012.
That's only four years ago,
man.
And that's a really significant head
trauma.
And she was very eloquent into debates.
She's really articulate.
I thought she kicked his ass and the
debates.
I honestly did.
I thought she came off smoother,
especially that second one.
Like he would say some crazy shit and
she would smile.
I thought she handled it great and she
was so much more eloquent and so much
like,
so much more.
So much better economy of words.
The problem is,
is just,
it's so hard to trust that she's telling
you the truth.
You know,
there's just too many things that she's
been like the difference between that
Komi Guy,
what he said she had done with her email
and what she said she had done,
and you play them back and forth.
You ever seen the video?
They do that.
It's pretty shocking,
you know what he says is very different
than heard descriptions of what he says.
What he says is she violated some laws
and what most people thought in the
apparently in the FBI.
It's one of the things that people got
upset at Komi.
Apparently from this article I read,
at least they were saying that the
people in the FBI were very disappointed
because they thought that he should have
pressed charges.
They thought that when they looked at
all the evidence and all the stuff that
he talked about,
that he admitted that she had done that
you can't do with classified data.
She had violated all these laws like if
you were a regular person,
if you are really regular enlisted
person and you violated those same
amount of loss,
dude,
you'd be fucked.
You will be fucked.
Phil really puts you in a Goddamn cage.
One hundred percent.
Look,
I know this sounds silly,
but she just like,
they said,
hey,
we'd like to see your emails.
She just got rid of them all.
She deleted them all.
She deleted 30,000
emails and she did it after a subpoena.
At least some of them after,
so I didn't.
What was after the subpoena?
See how many find out how many emails
she deleted after the subpoena.
I don't know,
you know,
the absolute specifics of it,
but it's just,
it's my point is it wasn't like she was
this awesome alternative,
you know,
so people that want to change and they
felt like what Hillary represented is a
part of that big system as well as she
says her words and is a stately.
She is and she's a much better
representative of America in some ways
than he is,
but she's just too tied to corruption.
Like all of the stuff that she's done,
like all the,
the experience she has in government,
all that should be on her favorite in
her favor.
But for a lot of people it wasn't this
time.
For a lot of people that are like,
this government is just too intertwined
with these businesses that support it
and pay it money and they're going to
all these different foreign countries
and getting paid exorbitant sums of
money to talk.
It's like Bill Clinton was getting like
half a million dollars to fly to these
countries that are all these like really
serious,
like civil rights violations on their
people.
Yeah.
There was like something that Clinton
had done.
We kept trying to push this one through,
see if he could find that there was this
one like dictatorship that he wanted to
go into.
He wanted to go and do speeches and they
were like,
no,
you can't go.
They're like,
you're not supposed to visit that place.
These people are doing things we don't
we don't agree with.
And he's like,
yeah,
I got to go over there and I'm going to
do the speech,
so let's just try to get.
Like,
he just wanted to do that speech.
He just wanted that Cheddar.
That's.
I think it's what's interesting to me
now is as the population on twitter,
at least of people,
my friends that voted for hilary that
are now just saying,
fuck,
fuck the rest of the country.
Fuck,
I'm out.
This sucks.
It's like you like,
did you see that?
The Canadian website,
the immigration website broke.
It crashed,
broke.
All the Americans were like,
fuck this,
I'm moving to Canada.
Has anyone ever done that though?
Fuck yeah.
You think fuck yeah.
Especially Vancouver.
Oh yeah.
Warm like Seattle.
It's basically just in Seattle,
but I mean like weather wise is similar.
Yeah.
So it was probably identical,
but there was something different about
Vancouver that Seattle doesn't have.
What's that like?
I almost like this.
I'm like colonial,
like richness,
this European richness that,
you know,
that bridge driving into Vancouver with
couple of big lions and.
Yeah.
And you're like,
oh,
this just looks like Lord of the Rings.
He like,
it looks like it could be in Germany and
that everything's a little more lush or
a little more overgrown.
I don't know if Seattle see,
I like saddle love Seattle,
but the downtown's look similar,
but even still like the downtown
Vancouver,
the food's always seems just a little
bit better than Seattle.
Did you ever do?
Man?
That's a tough call.
They're both pretty fucking awesome.
You can't have shitty food.
And the Pacific northwest.
Yeah.
You know,
like Oregon,
Portland,
Portland's another place.
They have some fucking bang.
Do you ever go to that?
You ever do a go to that little TACO
truck circle that?
Yes.
Do they have a tie?
Cheeseburger?
It's a cheeseburger with that leg.
Satay sauce.
That peanut butter sauce.
Holy Shit.
And it's super spicy.
It's got Serratia and it fucking love
God.
Damn.
It's good.
Bill Clinton sought State Department.
Okay.
For paid speeches related to North Korea
and the Congo.
Why don't you?
He's an animal.
They're cutting kids' hands off and the
Congo.
I respect his game.
He's like,
there's a lot of paper for me over
there.
I guarantee get it.
I guarantee you when he.
When she got elected,
he was like,
fuck.
I guess she'll be around the house a lot
more.
Look at this.
It says the FBI about the deleted emails
between March 25th and March 31st three
weeks after the subpoena.
The campaign now says it only learned
when the emails were deleted from the
FBI report.
Wow.
How many emails?
Oh my God.
Thirty thousand 490 work related emails
on December fifth,
2014 and chose not to keep 31,830
emails.
She deemed personal.
Well that's interesting.
By the way,
do you know how difficult that would be?
I have 33 unopened emails.
Thirty 3000 on the opened emails on my
thing and sometimes I try.
It's just like spam and I try to clean
it out and it's a fucking nightmare.
Yeah.
It's not an easy to clean.
You're like select all delete.
But then you still.
It only takes one to like 800.
Yeah.
Don't take fucking forever.
It would take forever.
What were you saying last night about a.
were you saying like if they fuck,
if they went through our emails,
what animals would look like?
I don't remember what I said I did.
Were blasted.
We were talking about they went,
they went through all her emails.
I can do like they.
Because they went through the or the FBI
went through a bunch of emails.
Deleted emails,
right?
Yeah.
And I thought it was used.
I thought you said it last night.
I don't know,
but I was thinking I used to do this
test on my emails to find out like if
someone went into my emails,
how bad I look.
I use it.
It was cigarette,
right?
You just go into the search and then
type in keywords like type in the n word
and see if it's ever been typed in my
email,
type in the word faggot and see if they
like have done that.
Also the problem is we,
especially as Comedians,
we fuck with each other and emails.
We talk mad shit to each other.
I mean that's one of the funniest shows
in Hollywood is that roast battle,
right?
Like comedians enjoy.
Like I enjoy it when someone lights me
up.
It's funny.
Like Barilla last night said I had a
little rascals hat on.
Jose,
you're over there with a fucking little
rascals hat on.
Oh,
we'd like shitting on each other.
It's fun.
Yeah.
We like to say that we fucked each
other's moms.
It's funny.
It's funny that rose petals fucking
brutal.
Brutal.
It's brutal.
But like we'll say shit to each other
all the time,
like Ari and I do that all the time.
He'll say something like,
yeah,
I will.
I was fucking your mom all day,
dude.
I got tired just just out of nowhere.
Like wow.
My mom.
What was she like?
Salty.
Oh dude,
that's it.
I just was texting back and forth with
red other day.
Ours is a savage.
He just filmed his special and Austin
say we super happy speaking a
specialist.
Bert Kreischer Friday night the machine
September or November?
November.
Back in time.
Motherfuckers November 11th on showtime
at 10 PM.
The machine.
Yeah.
Fuck yeah,
that looks fun.
Dude is telling him that the Irvine
Improv.
I.
Oh shit.
We uh,
I tell I went back with you.
Ari.
Joey.
I'm Tom.
I texted everyone because everyone's
been doing specials and I've been on
travel channel for seven years.
So I was like,
hey,
what insights and you and I,
the consensus everyone had was like,
I'm not,
I don't do theaters the fuck am I doing
in a theater.
So I'm going to do it in a club.
That's where I do.
And I,
the other thing,
I was like,
I've been doing standup shirtless for
seven years.
I'm fucking doing it shirtless.
Which before was before that,
like that.
Why do you like just throwing that shirt
off just makes you free?
I'm a terrible.
I'm a Florida kid.
Last night I was in jeans and flip
flops.
And were you wearing flip flops?
So like he's got flip flops on.
Yeah,
that I didn't shirtless.
And then.
And then Tom and I got in that fat
shaming battle and you people get so
mad.
So mad about that.
I saw people being mean to tom be mean
to you.
Wow.
Folks.
You don't see that they're fucking
around.
Oh,
the worst was like when it was pulling
it,
like there was my wife's friend passed
away and I left a comment on her,
on her,
uh,
on her picture of her and her mom is
like four in the morning when I saw it
and was like,
Hey,
so sorry for your loss.
We'll see you today.
And then I guess someone saw me post on
there and one of the gop,
one of Tom's friends.
And they wrote,
sorry if your lost,
did burt sit on your mom?
And I was immediately,
tom finds that fucking hilarious,
but this lady is like hey.
And then it was just like,
yeah,
birch fat as fuck like this.
They just fill it up.
And she was like that your friends are
your fans are dicks.
I was like,
those aren't my fans,
I don't think.
But uh,
so we did the fat shaming battle and
then Tom,
Tom,
the thing from my specialty,
like
you did these shirtless,
this is going to get bad birds.
Him and Christina just did a big
preamble on the beginning of their
podcast about me shirtless.
Yeah.
You did it last night somewhere early.
I like you.
As soon as it comes off I feel free.
I know I can tell.
I'm like,
wow,
that's interesting because it's almost
like a psychological button that you
have to take that shirt off and you're
like,
yes.
Freedom.
It's like,
it makes you tingle.
Yeah.
It's,
it's my long hair.
My Thor Sampson's long hair.
I did it in a meeting one time cause I
was like,
I get,
I get meetings and I'll get like,
Pitt,
sweaty,
you know,
and then you can see it in the shirt and
nothing looks worse than that.
So you just take your shirt off.
Just walked in,
took my fucking shirt.
Oh my God.
Oh Wow.
That's a lyric.
Yeah.
Why not man?
Why does it a big deal?
Why is it the whole thing?
The thing that I'm stuck with,
standup is like,
especially during my next hour is like
we get caught up into these and I was
talking to Justin Brooke about this.
We get caught up in these mechanisms of
this is what we have to do.
There was a period where every comic has
to have a sweatshirt.
I'm new balance sneakers and a Hoodie
and you know,
everyone did the same thing and then you
see someone like Judah friedlander doing
something totally different and you're
like,
oh fuck,
that really separates itself from the
pack.
But you are my only.
My only problem is,
and I've talked to have thought about
this and I've talked to you about it,
is I don't wanna have to do stand up
every time in my fucking shirt off.
Like I don't.
Like I don't need to have my shirt off
to do stand up.
I like to have it off.
What was the last time you did a site
with it on?
Anytime I'm at the store.
Oh yeah.
Hmm.
How come?
I don't know.
I don't,
I feel like it's,
I feel like it's disrespectful and weird
way like because it's not your show,
just like 15 minutes.
That's 15 minutes setting too R and I
and I have done it by the way I have
done it,
but for the most part I don't because
I'm like,
you know,
I'm only doing 15 minutes.
I'm really there to work on material to
see if it works.
There'll be like Chris rock going up and
doing like his inflections,
like I need to see if this works and it
and that our man's a fucking beast.
Like there's no other place,
a better place in the world to find out
if something works.
Yeah,
it's a gym.
It's also like people have seen a lot of
goddamn comedy,
you know,
it's a lot.
I mean it's,
it's beautiful.
It's the best spot ever.
I mean that that room has got more
history in it than any room in the
country.
So you feel it?
Oh yeah.
And it's.
And it's,
for some reason it just doesn't.
Whatever the Mojo in there is,
you take a bit that would kill on the
road and you're bringing them there and
they,
they find its flaws.
They find the lazy writing.
They find the overcompensation with
inflection or energy.
And like I,
I took two bits in there and I worked
them out like last call.
It was probably a month ago.
Worked them out three nights,
then come to them on the road and they
just were so much better.
I was like wow.
And the stories too.
So like the other thing about the is it
doesn't necessarily lend itself great to
storytelling.
It's more of like a punch and Jab fuck
with the audience dancing type of thing,
but like they're there two.
I went up there and did 15 minutes and
told two stories in another working.
Great.
Yeah,
it's a,
it's definitely a good workout room.
Yeah.
I liked the belly room to the belly
room.
Might be almost better sometimes because
so intimate.
So small.
What is it like 80,
80 people?
I have no idea.
Do they have those?
Uh,
I think they're going to do an there.
Got a new material show there tonight.
Have you ever done that with Nick
Youssef?
I did.
I did that with you.
I did try that joke that,
uh,
about Helen Keller named frank came up
with.
Was that the new material night or was
that the standup on the spot night?
Stand up on the spot is Jeremiah Watkins
show where you just,
the audience will yell out topics.
You literally have no idea those
dentists on the spot.
Yeah.
It was that one.
But the other one is Nick Youssef show,
which is a new material.
It's like you only stuff that you're
working on,
like you know,
police yourself,
whether it's,
you know,
you've done it like 10 times,
it's not new anymore.
Like whenever,
whatever that number is where it becomes
not new,
but when it is new,
like this is like an opportunity to work
only on stuff that's brand new.
Yeah.
I,
my problem is I write on stage,
so like I like to take,
I like to just be on the fly and things.
I think the,
the adrenaline of the stage makes me
think quicker and then a lot of times
what I'll do is I'll write on stage and
I will go for the easier punchline.
Like meaning,
like I'll get the premise will be good
and sometimes I won't have the perfect
punchline,
but I go,
oh,
that could be so much fucking better.
Right?
Yeah.
That's why that stand up on the spot
show is perfect for you because you
could just get loose.
I love that.
That's a fun show,
Dude.
It's a great way to come up with the
material.
I think there's a bunch of different
ways to come material and you gotta you
gotTa do you gotTa do a mall if you can.
I tension to shit.
You know,
I haven't purged my act in forever
because I've,
I've,
I had,
I literally had to shoot a special for
seven years.
I was just working so I don't have
enough time and man getting this hour
out and putting it out and releasing it
and knowing mean I'm married to the
machine story,
but knowing that it's amazing what a,
what a,
what a blessing and a curse that is to
be like,
like when I met you,
if you had said to me that first time
you said,
hey man,
we're going to hang out and this is
going to change your life.
You're going to tell one story and
that'll be.
You'll be known as that.
It's going to be cool.
It's going to,
you're going to sell a book from it,
you're going to get tv shows and,
and you're going to do it our specials
from it.
It's going to be fun.
I would have been like,
oh.
They're like,
fuck.
Yeah.
And then you have it and you're like,
I get it was a date the other night and
I,
I'm like 53 minutes into my set and
someone's like telling the story.
Right?
And I'm like,
oh my God,
fuck last I'd have.
I've had people in the front row going,
don't worry man,
you don't have to do it tonight.
Oh my God,
it's fucking crazy.
You don't have to do it to like the
toys.
Women always.
Women are like,
hey man,
I,
I'll,
I had a great time.
Even if you don't tell the story and
I'll be like,
okay.
And then immediately it's,
it's
a dude who brought five of his friends.
He's like,
dude,
I told him,
you're telling the machine story,
you're telling them machine story.
And I don't ever want to let anyone down
if they do.
That is the coolest thing in the world
that anyone knows me for anything.
And it's a great fucking story.
It's a great store.
It's all it is.
I literally sometimes don't believe it
myself.
Like I go,
there's no way.
And,
but I've had people come to my shows in
from my class stand up on stage with me
100 percent.
True.
I wish I was there sort of like.
I'm sounding very dicey.
That's a great fucking story though,
Dude.
I remember when you were telling.
I was like,
what?
It was one of those do.
You've lived a very bizarre life.
Oh,
you don't fucking tell me you're such a.
it's very weird because you're such a
nice guy too.
You're such a nice guy who's also a wild
man.
Yeah.
You've got this event,
a weird combination of traits and now
you've had these wild fucking crazy
experiences,
but you're a super friendly,
easy to hang out with guy.
You guys seen as much shit as you've
seen,
all the different places.
You've been a little worn out by it.
I think when I got done birth to conquer
during that season I took.
I was like,
I need a break.
I can't.
I need to do stand up because you get it
just tears on you.
We,
we had a conversation about it once you
and bill burr one night talked about it.
That's right.
Yeah.
He said something.
You said something very fascinating to
me that night.
You're like,
how much money is enough money like
comparatively speaking,
like is it,
is spending the whole year away for next
for an extra like two double your money
doesn't matter.
Or can you get by on this and really do
what you love and be be filled with all
the friends and the work that you love.
My problem is I know how funny you are
and I know that there's no way you could
be at your best if you're off like
months and months at a time doing that
show.
I thought I was.
When you said that to me,
I was like,
I remember thinking like I.
I go up all the time,
but I was wrong.
I was lying to myself because I was
going up once,
twice,
twice a month,
doing two dates out of the month,
but there was a whole portion of the
month where I wasn't working.
I wasn't writing,
I wasn't thinking comedy.
That's the biggest difference when
you're in production,
you're thinking production.
You're thinking,
what's our call time?
What's our heart out like your.
That's where your mind's occupied.
When you're a stand up man is just there
if that's all you're thinking like and
that's how you get better at it and you
have to be going up all the fucking
time.
Like that's the other thing.
Man and I added me again changed my life
for the better by passing me at the
store and letting me be a paid regular
it,
it gave me so much more momentum and
passionate about it.
So I was like fuck,
I'm going up to the best place in the
world to do standup comedy and I'm
getting spots when I,
whenever I call and I'll get a spot
there.
Coolest fuck.
And I'm only home,
you know,
three days a week.
But if I'm going up twice a week or at
least once a week,
if you really feel the difference in
your act.
Yeah,
for sure.
And if you can go to other clubs too,
man,
like I like going to a,
sat at the Improv,
shoot over and do a set of the comedy.
So I've done three and nine,
which is big for La and New York.
They're laughing at us because those
guys will do like 10 different sets of
night hopping from one place to another.
But uh,
I've done um,
the laugh factory,
the store and the ha ha on one night or
that the Improv,
the store and the ha all in one night.
So different man,
you do a set in one place and you get
sort of a vibe of what comedy is.
Then you're in a set of just a
completely different energy in the room.
Completely different like vibe of the
people.
And then all right,
bye folks.
And then you run over and do a different
set.
And that was a totally different vibe as
well.
And mostly I was going up with the same
material.
So it was real strange.
So there's just like different fields to
different places in different crowds.
When Joey was,
we're getting ready for his hour,
he was hitting it mean easily to spot
tonight and uh,
and we live right next door to each
other practically.
So he just calls me up and he'd be like,
dog.
I got us down for two spots tight.
Like he would just call my avail in with
his and no,
we're going together and I go to the
dark horse saloon.
The uniform was a fun look like fun dead
room.
So when you like,
like meaning,
like it not packed out.
Joe is not promoting it,
I'm not promoting it and it's just
people coming in to see a show and it
was.
And you really got a vibe of like,
this works,
fuck Ya.
And then he'd be like,
well,
onto the Hahaha.
And I remember go to the job.
One time we went,
he was.
I said,
well let's go to the flappers in
Burbank.
When we go to the Haha.
I go,
we go to Burbank.
And he goes,
and then we'll go to the,
ha ha,
I got a thing lined up.
I was like,
I've never been to the Haha.
I pull up at our faces,
our names were on the billboard.
Our faces are out there.
They meet us at the car.
Bert,
you're running late.
You got to get on stage right now.
I'm like,
Joey,
what did you sign us up for?
Didn't even tell you.
Booked a show.
He really is one of the funniest,
funniest,
like me.
And you said this today.
Bill [inaudible] is one of the funniest
human beings alive.
Joey Diaz.
You can say that statement.
Exactly,
and it means the exact same fucking
thing.
We were just talking about that before
you got here.
We were trying to figure out.
I think it's the running in my running
for the two funniest people alive is
burned Diaz as my running for me.
I was crying last night fucking crying
and he just grabs the reigns.
Man.
He just grabbed the reins and ran with
it.
It was beautiful.
You know when your soul,
like,
uh,
like he just made that up on the spot.
There's tolls like a,
like,
uh,
what did,
what did he say?
The pixelation of your soul and then you
watch they're going to take one of those
squares.
So yeah,
he's just fucking on.
It was a great analogy.
You and him.
I said this to Tommy this morning.
We talked about the show.
I was just.
I was literally walking.
I was walking around,
giggling,
recounting it,
and I told her tummy,
I said,
man,
I wish you had been there just to see
burn Rogan because the two of you were
the driving forces.
Doug was,
was really bringing in the reins.
Like he would be like,
all right,
what we're doing tonight,
and you're like,
Doug,
they already know that.
And like,
okay,
I'm gonna go check on Manson.
You and bill were the ones driving that
and I swear to God when I say this,
I,
I literally started to move the mic from
my face because I was afraid I was going
to be.
I was laughing too much that you just
hear me.
Just,
there was a point where I thought I was
going to fucking pass out and I was like
breathing.
I never,
I have not laughed that hard in for ever
was also,
it felt like we were doing something
cool like we,
we all got together and we joked around
about this crazy thing that was
happening for us.
And apparently folks,
the live stream,
if you're listening sucked.
I didn't,
we didn't know.
We didn't know that you were only
getting it through one ear.
I don't know what to do about that.
Uh,
the videos up now though on youtube,
the videos been fixed.
Powerful.
Jamie.
A full video.
So yeah,
the videos up and if we fixed the audio
issues that were,
that existed before.
So it'll come at,
in both speakers.
Sorry about that.
That guest,
that was a really annoying thing to
stream like that.
But whenever I kept thinking this could
be.
I mean,
not,
I'm not,
I don't think anyone on that stage would
do it for this.
This can be a fucking TV show.
I mean this.
But why?
Let's just do that.
Do that again.
So bill,
second thing is the TV shows.
I,
I did something today for a friend of
mine.
He's got a car show.
And you went to him,
we were talking about suspensions and
this kind of crafts a Steve Strope,
he makes all these really cool muscle
cars and there's like this crew that's
talking to them and they got cameras and
it's like,
and they're nice folks and nothing.
There's nothing wrong with them,
but it's just everyone's got this.
Okay,
now stand over here.
Yeah,
we're going to,
we're going to come towards you here.
So as we come around the car,
like that kind of Shit and you're like,
okay,
be not now,
be normal.
You know,
you try to be normal.
It feels weird.
Right?
But if you're just doing it like we're
doing it,
like if you're,
if you're doing something like a podcast
like that,
just just a podcast,
that's it.
As soon as you start bringing in,
okay,
we're going to go live in five now,
can you pick it up from what you said
about,
um,
the machine can do that machine thing
again and you would have to do it again.
And you know what I mean?
Yeah.
If you wanted to do it as a TV show,
there'd be all sorts of other people in
the fucking kitchen.
Let me get it manages in the soup day
and you only do it for you to only do it
for 22 minutes.
Yeah,
exactly.
So that's where you lose the.
You lose the,
you lose everything.
It's live.
It's live and it's fun and it's friends
busting each other's balls.
I'm talking shit about the world,
about how wacky this world is for Dan.
Hope out at being for my fucking face.
Herpes cold sores.
You son of a bitch.
That's true story though.
Was mocking him because he gets them on
his penis and I was like,
oh,
but I got on my face
worse.
You could see them.
I love the way you start sentences
though is so simple.
I have herpes.
He was on fire.
It was all firewood.
Fitzsimmons said something that didn't
land.
Doug goes,
now I understand why talk shows have
lead in question.
Yeah.
He was a little hostile.
Some of the guests.
He was definitely a.
At one point he was laying in my lap.
That's one of my favorite pictures of my
life.
Was He sucking on your nipple?
He sucked on my nipple.
When Sarah and bill started fighting too
much,
he would try to break up the tension by
sucking on my nipple.
Wow.
Was a Sarah in,
but was it in entertaining the bill and
Sarah thing?
It was for me.
I liked it.
I could,
but I don't.
I don't.
I don't hate either of them,
so I don't like.
I'm sure to the average viewer who maybe
doesn't know Sarah but loves bill,
they're like,
why would you disagree with him?
He's the best.
Right.
But the problem with those conversations
is as much as I would probably agree,
that's just my opinion and there's got
to be someone out there that's like,
yeah,
Sarah.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
I'm sure there's people.
Oh,
there are definitely women that will.
I don't know if any women lot were when
the live stream,
but we had four women watching the live
stream.
You sure it was thousand humans at any
given time.
How many people were screaming?
It was like 35,
30,
3000,
something like that.
Where you go,
holy crap.
So there was,
there's been videos that were up that we
took down on youtube.
They were up and they were private,
but there was,
the sound was fucked up still.
That's why there are private.
We're trying to fix this out.
So the full version is uploaded now.
Oh,
I know how they found that unlisted
video because everyone,
every one of us tweeted the link to the
video on our facebook live pages or
facebook pages.
Oh,
I see.
Because I was looking for at this
morning and I couldn't find it and I was
like,
wait,
did we not record that?
I was like,
that would stink if we missed that.
Oh yeah.
That would suck hard.
I forgot to hit record.
Um,
yeah,
that was a dude.
We could do that again.
Next time we do it,
we can't just have people just walk on
stage and just sit down there.
I didn't know that that was going on.
And you know,
we have a specific amount of people that
we do it with because anything,
anything more than three or four.
Doug was putting people on stage because
he definitely put Brendan Walsh on
stage.
Oh yeah,
for sure.
But Brendan's a good friend known him
forever and he wasn't even on for that
long.
He's fucking hilarious.
He really is so funny.
He's so crazy to be here.
Doug was telling a story about Bingo,
having a seizure and hitting her head
and Brendan goes,
I've had a few girlfriends have seizures
when they don't cook the food.
Right?
Oh Man.
Oh.
So if you've been paying attention to
all these people's reactions,
everyone's trying to like figure out
why,
why trump won.
It's really fascinating.
It's fascinating to see people freak
out.
It's fat.
People are crying.
People are fucking cry or they stormed
out of a school in Arizona.
The kids marched out of a school to
protest the president elect.
Whoa,
whoa.
This is crazy now.
But there is a weird,
like there was a weird energy when trump
gave his speech last night.
It was almost like the bullies saying,
stop hitting yourself.
Stop hitting yourself.
Like he was like,
he was like,
now we can be like.
It was kind of weird because he has not
been like super inclusive and then all
of a sudden he's like,
we need to heal together and you're
like,
hey,
you totally feel that way.
But like part of me goes on.
Is there a part of him that fucking
hates everyone that doesn't like him?
Yeah,
for sure.
Yeah.
He certainly mean he's,
look,
he's a super businessman and super
businessman there.
They're like their game players that
play in a game.
So if you move towards them,
you know,
and you make a move,
they want to make a move to county,
you're moving fuck you up.
Like that's Donald Trump's personality.
That's why he sues all those people that
uh,
you know,
he's involved in altercations with.
He just fucking squash this shit.
He doesn't,
he doesn't like,
you know,
if people are talking shit about him,
but that's when once he become
president,
like,
you got to let all that go.
Like you have to know,
you got to let all that.
You can't be tweeting.
Jon Stewart at 1:30
in the morning calling him a pussy.
She watched that video.
Oh God.
Yet,
it's hilarious.
You can't be tweeting Jon Stewart at
1:30
in the morning calling him a pussy when
you're in your sixties,
but he can't.
He can't do that.
Can't do that anymore.
You definitely now either president,
please stop doing that.
Don't do it.
You could think it,
but don't do it and even if you think
it,
why are you even bothering?
What do you care?
They got to get rid of his twitter
immediately.
Nope,
he knows he's bleeding.
He's keep tweeting.
Who Cares?
Why not?
Oh Dude.
Political correctness just took a
missile to the Deq.
Now,
do you think,
do you think that's good or bad for
standup on?
Unquestionably good.
In every way,
shape or form?
Really.
Yay.
It's good because he's going to do some
goofy shit.
He's going to say some ridiculous things
a week in it.
Right now.
If someone.
If you said something like,
I like to go up and grab them by the
posies,
everyone will be like,
I.
That has to be acceptable because half
of America is not offended by that.
Do you seat?
I'm a believer in that.
The president in a lot of ways shapes
the mindset of the country because it's
just a natural thing that happens in
tribes.
You know,
if you have one fierce tribal leader in
a tribe,
guarantee you the warriors that are in
that tribal also be fierce because
they'll be under the guidance of the one
wild fucking guy.
I mean,
that's how.
that's how like fierce armies get put
together.
You have to have a bad ass fucking
general.
Well,
when your president is this guy who
rarely gets riled up about anything,
he's not emotional at all.
He's super articulate and really well
spoken and he's a great orator.
That's Barack Obama.
I mean,
that's what you would think of when you
think of a presidential person.
He's probably the most presidential guy
we've ever had as president,
but then you go with trump.
Like he's,
he's not doing that at all.
Like he's.
He's just rocking it at a totally
different way.
A hundred percent.
Yeah.
He's doing it like a businessman.
You fuck with him?
He's going to fuck with you back.
You know,
you fucking piece of Shit,
Jon Stewart,
you posey.
Its real name is leave at 1:30
in the morning,
but that's the kind of guy that can
fucking finance campaign for president
all on his own and when it's crazy it
ma,
I mean,
forget about whether you think it's a
good thing for the country or bad thing
for the country.
It might be the greatest success story
ever.
It might be like the greatest upset of
any contest ever.
One hundred percent.
There's no bigger upset ever.
Right?
Like what do you think the odds were
when Donald trump first entered the race
in Vegas?
That he would eventually become
president?
What do you think the odds were?
I remember watching,
I'm Seth Meyers,
state of the Union address,
and he said,
Donald Trump's here.
Donald Trump said he's voting as he's
running as a Republican.
I thought he was running as a joke and I
doubled over and I thought.
I remember thinking to myself,
what,
what an idiot healed.
He could never be president.
I literally thought he could never be
president.
And then to think that that's a fucking
reality.
Yeah.
It's interesting.
Has any celebrity other than we'll
Ronald Reagan.
Ronald Reagan's one I was curious about
because they said that I don't remember
the election,
I was too young,
but they were saying that despite the
fact that he had already been governor,
because that was like Kinda like he,
he had been an office.
They were shocked that anyone would vote
for Reagan.
They thought he was a fucking joke and
dude,
he destroyed Mondale.
Like I look at those county by county
polls where they show you what the
counties voted.
It's really fucking interesting because
you look at Ohio,
it's all red,
but Cleveland's blue and like Columbus
is blue and Toledo's blue and so.
But the thing is all the,
just outside the city,
everyone's voting for trump,
but in a city people are voting for the
Democrat.
But you look at,
if you look at Reagan's,
it's the.
I mean literally it's all fucking read.
Have you ever gone back and watched some
or Reagan speeches?
No,
I want.
I watched a few of them.
The other day I did.
I did a youtube rabbit hole.
I went down and watched a bunch of
Reagan's speeches there were so weird,
so weird because now that he's dad and,
you know the history,
it's so weird because it was in my
lifetime.
I remember these events,
I remember these things happening,
but uh,
he was onstage onstage and doing some
speech and he started talking about how
wouldn't it be if we were attacked by
some sort of an alien invader for
another planet?
Wouldn't it be easy for us to abandon
all of our differences and joined
together as one race to,
to face this alien threat?
And everybody was like,
what the fuck did he just say,
save the fucking president.
Just say there's aliens.
That's what I heard.
I already said,
the fucking aliens are coming.
They're coming.
Oh my God,
we got to get together.
That's literally what he said.
And it was one of those conspiracy
theorists dreams where someone like me
or like Eddie Bravo,
fucking look at it and go,
dude,
you hear what he just said?
Fucking hear what he just said.
He said if an alien species came down
here to,
they're coming,
you're going to let us know.
Slow to go.
Let us know.
Slow.
I used to think,
I used to think they should release a
tiger in every major city who chooses?
What about your kids?
Well,
I mean,
yeah,
that's just kind of.
We got to deal with the chips fall where
they may,
but the reason being,
imagine how tighter the communities
would get.
People will be cooler to each other.
They'd be like,
hey man,
have you seen the tiger?
Oh yeah,
yeah,
he's on the other side of town.
Oh fucking.
Thank God man.
Have a great day.
Can't you shoot that tiger?
Or is it like you gotta leave it feeds.
It feeds off people.
That's the balance.
Or baby come into neighborhoods for
gentrification.
Could you imagine if that's how we
rocked it?
We just left a tiger and every $100,000
you to keep her at the time.
Like,
God,
it's a game with you and nature.
Shit.
Wow.
I mean,
when I was in,
when I was in Tanzania with the massage,
they have,
um,
their tigers,
lions are there big fucking deal and so
they put,
I mean,
like they're crammed in together and
they got thorns like thorn,
big thorn bushes.
Sure.
Keeping them together and they're always
together.
They're always in clumps because they
got fucking lions everywhere.
Wow.
And I was like,
I bet that makes you a lot tighter when
you know you could get eaten by a
fucking line.
If you go take a shit by yourself,
you're like,
hey man,
you gonna go hang out while take a shit.
Well,
those people are so much more connected
to nature because how many animals must
act get killed?
Oh Dude.
I told you they cut a goat's throat in
front of me.
Like,
like,
Hey,
welcome to our jungle,
slit his throat and blend it into a
horn.
So you could drink it.
Yeah.
Just so casual.
Doesn't taste like a little like liver.
Wow.
Like a drinking liver.
It's probably super good for you.
Write it.
I didn't mind the taste other than the
fact that we get all in your 10 blood on
your teeth.
I didn't mind that and it was Africa and
I didn't want to get aids.
You didn't?
I didn't mind the taste.
Yeah.
Imagine me.
The first guy to get sick from that.
Like you,
you,
there's,
I wonder like what kind of bloodborne
pathogens they could be carrying in
their body that you're in,
but this wouldn't that be in the meat
to.
I guess you'd probably have to worry
that less with herbivores.
Right?
Then you would like kicked and drink
bear blood.
You couldn't do it?
No,
I don't think so.
I think you can get tricky gnosis if
they say something like 90 something
percent of bears of Kenosis.
Really?
Yeah,
but how do you have to cook that out of
them?
Yeah,
you have to cook it.
You Cook pork,
which is 160 degrees.
Oh,
I've been cooking pork.
Medium rare.
Well,
now that you probably can get away with
that because you're talking about
domestic pork.
See the standards.
They actually lowered the temperature.
I think they lowered the pork
recommended to 1:40,
which is really kind of like a medium.
Not like I'm not a medium rare.
I think medium was like 1:35,
but I'm A.
Anyway,
I forget my point.
Bears blow yet.
You have to cook bears.
He but,
but you don't have to do that with like
a deer and elk.
You can eat like elk Sashimi.
We slice it.
Oh,
I did,
I did.
We do that with a bison.
I think we ate part of the bisons heart
or part of his liver.
MMM.
Wow.
Raw.
Yeah.
People have done heart Ra.
I've seen that.
It's crazy.
It's going to dig that shit.
Yeah,
like there's a part of me that's like,
you know,
the big,
the anti,
the big anti.
The n word for guys like me is called
call me Bro.
Bros.
Bad.
That's like a,
that's the n word for like alternative.
Like hipsters.
Millennials do not think it's as Bad as
the n word.
I don'T think it is either,
but that's where like they go,
oh,
he's just a,
he's a bro.
Are you?
Are you blowing out?
I think we have to embrace that.
We have to take it.
I love being a bro dude.
I fucking love it.
I love it.
But yeah,
there's nothing wrong with that.
But when you used to be able to say
what's up bro,
to your friend and really think that.
Yeah.
And now it's like one of those weird
things like bros,
like a joke.
It's like a half joke.
Yeah.
But I say brother to everyone.
Pro science,
you know about bro.
Science?
No,
it's all I do.
I do bro.
Science degrees with sciences.
When you talk about something like I
might watch a youtube video,
memorize some statistics and then recite
it back.
That's bro.
Science bro.
Oh,
I do bros Lines that hell.
Do anybody who's abroad as brooks?
I'm a bro.
His story into.
Yeah.
I'm a sports fan.
I'm a.
I love that.
Your rabbit holes take you to a ronald
reagan's speech and mind.
Always take Me to either stop being a
douchebag videos or,
or uh,
or bullied justice.
Like instant karma.
I like watching the little kids.
Little kids fight like a.
When one kid actually knows how to fight
in high school.
There's this one girl and she's in this
fight with this.
Oh,
she's a fight with a dude.
She might have been in a fight with a
dude,
but she didn't have a wrestling match.
This kid,
and she clearly knows moitai because she
fucking knees him in the face.
Hey,
like,
like full fucking power.
Really good technique crushes this dude
crumples them and you watch and you go,
whoa.
I like that.
Somebody taught her how to fight.
Yeah.
So we taught our fights.
I'm head start a fight with her.
I think maybe she's the dickhead.
I dunno.
I'd like to get my daughter's into like
a base level is.
Yeah,
so it's a girl and a guy watch this
douche or is it a girl?
Is that a girl that she just flattened
or is that a guy?
A boy?
It's a boy due chief.
Yeah,
it is a boy.
She flattened him.
Holy shit.
we flattened him.
Show that again.
Jamie,
look at that.
She takes him down.
She holds onto them and boom,
boom.
Another name.
She through her whole body into that
knee.
She dId.
She just fuck that dude up.
Like that's a girl who's seriously knows
moitai that that would be like if you
tried to fuck with john wayne
[inaudible] daughter.
He gave her a hard time.
I want my girls to know him a little bit
of jujitsu just to protect themselves
from dudes.
Look at the fucking technique,
man.
Her knee.
Excellent.
Excellent technique.
Position.
Everything that girl absolutely knows
how to fight.
Like that wasn't luck.
Yeah,
like she just smashed that dude.
I'd like to take the guy's an asshole.
I'm sure he is hope so she might have
just decided to beat up a boy.
Send the message.
This is how I roll motherfuckers.
Where does she run off to?
Some other girls were chasing her.
She just ran off like super person.
Holy shit.
You know,
there's that fight.
There's that.
I always ended up watching this one
fight of these two guys in his parking
lot and the one guy's like posted up
like this and the other guy clearly
knows clearly knows like the beginning
at levels of an mma and it is.
And he fucks this dude up and you can
and it's just over and.
But there's this energy.
Do you remember?
Did you ever see a guy two guys about
start fighting and then one guy clearly
knows has fought before and he's done
like martial arts.
And then the guy's like,
no,
no street fight only street fight only.
And the guy's like,
no,
I'm not going to handicap myself so that
you can win.
So there's no fighting words.
What does that mean?
Street fighter street fighter.
I've heard that before.
Oh yeah,
And I've seen it in videos too.
I heard it in college.
There was this guy who knew how to,
who knew?
All brazilian jujitsu,
everything.
and there was a big block party,
k a s I used to a block party and he's
talking shit.
There was someone was talking shit.
And he hit his roommate's friend.
He had his back.
Just got to hit a roommate so that you
just came into get protected.
His friend,
his roommate,
and this other guy is like,
oh,
you want some motherfucker?
And he's just like,
okay.
It was the way he moved,
it was very clear.
He knew what he was doing and the guy
was like,
no,
no street fight going to be a street
fight and I'm going to be in like,
no,
and then he fucking killed him.
It's got to be a street fight.
What does that mean?
What does it mean you're,
you're the one that told me like one
time I remember her saying,
I talked to somebody,
this must have been five years ago,
and you were like,
do you know how to fight?
And I was like,
no.
And you're like,
why would you ever talk to someone if
you don't know how to fight?
And I was like,
I don't know.
I've been going on that,
that mindset that my whole life just
rolling the dice that they'll back down.
That's dangerous.
I don't talk shit to anybody.
She never talked shit.
Well,
first of all you shouldn't because it's
just not worth it and it's a bad path to
go down.
Then you get into arguments.
People were probably all going to get
into them again,
but it's not good.
It's wAy better for you,
for them,
for everybody to avoid those kinds of
conversations at all,
but when you start insulting people,
you don't know.
God damn it so risky.
It's so risky.
You don't know what they do.
They made.
That can be a killer.
You don't know anything.
I mean like literally a killer.
You don't.
You have no idea what that person does
and so for you to just meet some
stranger,
bump into them and then want to exchange
assault at each other,
you could have fucked up man.
You could be sitting right next to
lorenz larkin.
You don't know who he is.
You know you decide to slap them.
You get you do something stupid because
you think you're a tough guy.
Anything you can to intimidate him and
he just laid kicks you when you realized
like,
oh good lord.
Then he starts beating the shit out of
you slowly.
Whenever he wants to,
he hits you.
That's reality.
You could find yourself in a terrible
situation.
I don't even understand those guys who
just simply talked,
disrespectful to somewhat like that'll
happen when you're with like as a comic,
you're on the road,
you're at a bar and someone's a fan of
yours and another guy's a fan of yours.
You'll watch them almost like attack.
Like one guy,
oh,
the drunk is will be a dick and be like,
I guess we're all just gonna.
Sit up at the bar and you're like,
hey man,
don't do that.
Like the guy,
the guy's just wants to hang out too.
I can hang out with both of you.
It doesn't need to be one of the other.
Yeah,
I mean I go,
what the fuck you doing man?
Just to hAve a good time.
Like why you to I'm not impressed.
Doesn't make me happy that you're
mocking someone in front of me.
That's not funny.
Right?
Wow.
Some kinds of dudes can be douche bags.
No.
I mean there's something about men's
personalities and wanting to get ahead.
wanting to fucking move ahead and line.
I got to meet next fucking competition.
Motherfucker better not try to cut me.
You know?
It's such a weird,
uh,
there's a line and you're like,
hey man,
people get crazy.
Some guys will walk straight to the
fucking front of the line to take
pictures with their chicks.
Doug benson is.
It happened to me one time and he was
like,
why would you let that happen?
And I was like,
I don't like confrontation either.
That is a crazy move.
Okay man,
I'm not waiting in this fucking line.
Let's get a picture of kind of getting
them to do that.
And I tell them that it's align and then
they just stand there and I take the
picture with the person who's at the
front of the line and they go,
can we go?
Now I know there's,
there's an actual line you can't just
cut in.
Like that's rude.
Someone has to police this.
Yeah.
Lines are lines.
Give me anxiety.
What's the competition?
What am I going to get there?
When's it gonna happen?
We're up next.
How the fuck did she get in front of
him?
Was she in front of him before she is
cut?
Did she just cut?
Do somebody else the exact same amount
of people in front of you.
You start with,
she just fucking cut front line for that
guy.
Dude,
We were getting on.
I was on my buddy cal heads cruise and
that we were getting on back on the boat
from st thomas and uh,
the law,
there was a line to get back on the
boat,
but it wasn't a defined line.
It was just people like three wide,
four wide,
sometimes too wide lining up down the
side of the pier.
And there were people just walking past
the line and I would be like,
hey,
there's a line.
And he'd be like,
no,
no.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And just keep walking.
And I'd be like,
mother fucker.
Like,
it drove me nuts like I was losing.
And then these,
this one couple just got right in front
of me and I went,
hey,
you can't do that.
And I know I feel like I'm in third
grade.
LIke,
hey man,
no cuts.
No,
but no interrupts man.
let's go.
Like,
what did they say when you said you
can't do that?
They were like,
oh no,
no,
we're,
our friends were coming and I was just
like,
and then I'm like,
okay,
I'm drunk.
I'm not.
There's no reason for me to interact
with this person.
It's just one of those things like,
do I take the path of least resistance
and just go whatever.
It's one fucking person.
Do I raise it worth getting into an
argument with one per,
you know?
Right.
but there's something weird.
Oh,
it's a fucking dick gregory.
I fucking hate it.
Assholes.
I hope people do that.
People do that at the airport,
dude.
They do it everywhere all the time.
There's always someone,
but it's not that many.
You know,
if,
if you're dealing with thousanD people,
you're going to get one at least.
Right.
Just someone who just goes over the
rules.
don't apply to me.
How many now you don't need a thousand.
Maybe 300,
rIght?
Yeah.
Every 300.
It depends on what fucking.
If you're at a raiders game or
something.
Oh no.
Don't even get me started.
I've been going to rams games.
Fog in lines there.
Fuck that.
Football games are ridiculous.
Oh,
the ram stadium,
the coliseum,
it's like,
it's like going back to,
to like deadwood,
like it's fucking atrocious.
How much security do they have with
those things?
Not enough.
And they've got only one exIt for every
one.
Meaning,
like meaning,
like they don't have levels of exits for
tiers.
If you sit up there,
you gotta walk out this way,
if you sit down here,
you got to walk out this way.
It's a fucking nightmare just to funnel
it.
It is a.
Yeah.
And there's an have no refrigeration for
the uh,
craft services or whatever.
So like they run out of water.
No more water no more.
We're out and you're like,
yeah,
it's 90 degrees out here and there's
92,000
people.
Yeah,
we're done with it.
It's like,
it's literally must Be.
Would it be to be like in one of those?
No,
that's not as bad as.
Fuck.
I'm going to say one of those
shantytowns in africa.
There's no water at the football game we
had to leave.
We're going to get our air conditioned
car and drive off white privilege.
Oh,
that's super white privilege.
It's like living in a shanty town.
It's like rams game.
It's like a cardboard box under the
bridge.
Uh,
yeah man.
It's just when you're inviting that many
men in a gigantic arena type place and
then you having combat sport.
Like football is a combat sport in my
opinion.
You,
it's not a combat sport.
Like were you hitting each other all the
time with punches and kicks,
but you're running into each other full
blast.
You know what the fuck you're doing.
You get Bigger so you could smash people
better.
It's a combat sport.
God dammit.
That's what it is.
What's the dark?
Is there fights in ufc?
Oh,
uh,
occasionally.
Yeah.
Less than you would think.
Really?
Yeah.
You're going to get drunk people
together.
You know,
maybe one person's cheering a little too
loud for someone you don't like and
calling the guy you like a loser or
whatever people do.
I've seen some brawls,
but uh,
for the most part,
not really,
man.
You know,
I think a lot of people also go to see
mma.
Like if you go to see it live,
it's expensive,
you know you want to go check out the
ufc,
live it does things sell out like that.
This madison square garden thing that
people were going to be excited to be
there.
They're not going to fuck up the
experience hopefully,
but if you're next to the wrong person
ever in life in a live setting,
whether it's a comedy club or a concert,
you could be next to the wrong fucking
person and they could ruin the
experience
we were behind.
We were in front of the wrong person on
one game because there's this guy and
all raiders gear and he just kept saying
to people,
how long have you been around savannah?
Oh,
you brand new in.
Okay.
that's what I thought.
And you're just like,
why?
What do you.
What is this doing for you?
is he a mexican gentleman?
He just did them in a mexican accent.
did I didn't mean to.
I'm really bad at accent.
he's iris.
How long have you been a resident?
Would land are you from?
He said to me,
he said it to me.
My kids are sitting in front of me who
doesn't know that they're my kids.
Right.
So mY kids sit in front of you.
I'm sitting with my buddy,
eric,
and he's just like,
how long have you been a I?
And my buddy eric grew up here,
so he's like,
my whole life.
He wAs like,
oh really?
Where are you from?
And he was like,
I grew up in the valley or santa monica.
He's like,
well,
okay,
how about you?
And I was like,
um,
this is my first game.
I'm a big fan,
and I just,
he just caught off guard and he giggled.
He was like,
ah,
that's what I thought.
Yeah,
I know I'm from here,
man.
I'm from here.
And you're like,
okay,
irish people don't talk like that.
I know I can.
I'm really bad at accents.
He was like,
he was like,
I love the chorus eum uh,
that's,
that's like japanese from the 1951.
I'm so bad at accent.
He's like,
my man.
I said,
can I get some compensation?
Yeah,
to a rams game.
I just think football in general and
combat sports in general.
And he'd get a bunch of men together and
you give them booze.
Shit's going to go wrong.
Like.
And if you're only telling me there's
only one way to get out of there.
That's not in my book of safe places to
be.
No.
did you ever.
Do you remember the xfl?
Yes.
That was the um,
what the fuck's his name?
Vince mcmahon.
Yeah.
I went to an xfl game.
How was that?
Holy fucking shit.
That was what a prison yard must feel
like.
Really,
really,
like,
I rememBer I remember a,
a fight broke out and the cops went into
the stands from the field to get the guy
and the fans kicked the cops out of the
stands.
Whoa.
Like they.
And they had the guy and they put the
fans,
pulled the guy back into the stadium and
push the cops onto the grass.
And the cops just were like,
I guess like guys going free.
Holy shit.
They gave out that game.
They gave out like cardboard flyers.
Like,
I don't know what it was like,
you know,
so you could all hold them up and you'd
all make the same color or whatever,
but everyone was just turning them into
paper airplanes and they were throwing
darts and I saw dude turn around and get
hit in the eye with one and leave like,
oh and leave.
And I was like,
he had hit and I was a dark with the
paper airplanes,
but they weren't made out of cardboard
and people were turning them into paper
airplanes,
but they were flying like fine and it
hit the guy in the eye like three rows
in front of me and he just doubled over
and walked out and was like,
that kind of money just lost a fucking
eye for an xfl game.
I was like,
I got recognized a lot there too.
When did the xfl exists?
ProbablY 2001.
Wow.
and I was on a tv show.
What?
What should we on Back then?
The next show you were on it.
Oh,
that's rIght.
And vince mcmahon,
you came onto me three times.
Which I was.
Oh yeah,
that's right.
And vince,
vince mcmahon,
or someone came on to promote the league
and so we got as cast members,
we all got free tickets and we were
like,
oh,
this will be nice.
No,
there were gen pop and it was fucking
brutal.
But we had just promoted the games on tv
and a while.
I remember walking through and
everyone's like,
oh,
you're that fucking guy.
And I was like,
yeah,
what's uP?
I remember when you were doing hurt
burt.
God,
that waS the first,
uh,
tv stuff that I was aware of that you
were doing.
Yeah.
I was like,
oh my god,
someone's going to talk to this guy.
You gotta stop doing that.
I'm not fucking doing.
I should ever again.
Yeah,
like you'd let people choke you
unconscious.
You let some of the gracie brothers
choke unconscious.
Who did it?
Which was,
it was at henner.
He run.
Who,
uh,
who choked you out?
I can't remember.
It was.
It happened so quick.
It's getting choked out.
Is such a fucking scary feeling because
it really proves.
It proves your helplessness.
You're helpless for sure.
For one of those guys.
One of those guys gets a hold of you.
It took two seconds.
He just went and grabbed my kimono and
uh,
and just tighten it around my neck and
yeah.
And I rememBer reaching up to stop him
and hitting him once and then being
like,
I can't stop this and falling out.
And then I had panic attackS for like a
week because I knew it was like to
suffocate and die.
Jesus.
I literally,
I remember I'd be fucking laying in bed
and I just go,
those looking crazy.
Whoa.
I wish at that time.
You know what's so funny?
I'm horiaN is the father who early on
said to me,
you could benefit from jujitsu.
He's like,
why don't you come?
No charge.
Come
down and enroll wIth us.
We'll teach you everything.
Come down please.
And I was like,
yeah,
yeah.
My head,
I'm like,
oh,
I don't want to do jujitsu for god in
that would have helped me so fucking
much.
I still do it.
Uh,
I talked to eddie bravo.
We had talked about thiS one time and so
I think you are someone.
Maybe you'd set me up with eddie bravo.
Well,
yeah.
Well you know,
you live right down the street from joey
punches.
Go with joey.
Why went to he take you to a alberto
cranes place?
I talked to anybody's going,
right?
Yeah,
I think so.
I don't know.
He goes every a lot.
Yeah,
but I talked to eddie problem.
Eddie bravo came in and he had a black
eye and I went,
what happened?
Did you get in a fight?
And he was like,
huh?
He ain't even know he had a black guy.
He was like,
what?
I said,
your eye is swollen.
And he goes,
oh,
it's just from rolling is.
Yeah,
it's not that bad.
And I was like,
wait,
you get black eyes?
He was like,
yeah,
he can bumps from bumps.
And I was just like,
oh,
I don't want to get knocked my teeth
out.
It can happen when you were a
mouthpiece.
I've only gotten a black guy like maybe
10 times ever 10 times,
maybe,
maybe 10 times.
You knoW,
that's a lot.
I mean,
from jujitsu.
yeah.
Do you think all the times you're
rolling and rolling ever?
Yeah.
That's hilarious.
I've had two black eyes.
I have a lot of black guys.
I think,
um,
how many black guys have you had?
Maybe two or three out and not that
many.
There's um,
a picture of me when I was doing the ufc
had too fucked up eyes while I was doing
the commentary commentary.
Terry,
that was all from my same friend.
He got me with the knee and then he got
me wIth his elbow.
Totally accidental.
Ow.
It hurts so bad when you're scrambling.
If you know you move that way and that's
where he was going to put his knee and
he just,
he just fucking collide with each other
dudes.
Noses explode.
Happens all the time.
yeah,
I,
I not,
not that I don't want that to happen,
but I just don't.
Yeah,
I know.
but you got to also look,
be careful.
Don't roll with spazzes.
Don't try to be a world champion
superstar.
Learn how to do the technique correctly.
Be willing to tap and just try to learn
and have fun.
The gracies have a good saying,
they say keep it playful.
I think that's a good saying to learn
it,
you know,
because as soon as you get tense and
real rigid and real concern with the
outcome,
you,
uh,
you just don't do as well.
You know,
it's become,
it's too exhausting and you don't
concentrate on technique,
you know,
like if you're not worried about getting
tapped or you're not worried about
getting into a bad position,
you'll relax and sort of go with the
flow of things.
And when you find like a certain level
of efficiency,
then you can operate,
you can roll for like long times.
I've had roles with people that were
like 10,
15 minutes long or even longer because
if you get to a good place we can kind
of conserve your energy and you're both
moving at a good pace.
Good pace,
but keeping it really technical to.
It's an amazing martial arts.
Like one of the,
to me it's one of the only martial arts
that does as advertised.
Like when you look at martial arts,
you always think of what I would like is
some Bruce Lee type scenario or the
small could beat up everybody around
him.
Well striking.
That really doesn't work like that.
It just does it.
Yeah.
I was just doesn't,
you know,
brock lesnar is just as bad ass as
joseph benevidez.
As brock lesnar was chasing him down.
He'd be kind of fucked.
He just be kind of fucked.
That's just too much.
There's just too much man.
But if brock lesnar road,
like if he did jujitsu with like a guy
like gary tonin who just won the ebi
this past weekend,
he won the heavyweight division.
He's a 100 sixTy nine pounds,
I think it is.
Champion.
And he went up and he won the
heavyweight division two.
Oh five I guess is the way class.
But I'm.
That guy would choke out brock lesnar
most likely.
So brock lesnar when he's,
uh,
when he's fighting,
he's not doing jujitsu.
He doeS jujitsu and he's fucking
gigantic,
but he's not.
I think [inaudible] has got his blue
belt.
See if that's correct.
Brock lesnar got his blue belt on,
brock lesnar got his purple belt,
might be his purple belt.
Is he using mOre wrestling techniques?
Yeah,
he's a freak wrestler.
I mean absolutely.
You know,
as far as like amateur wrestlers go,
super successful two time.
Ncaa all american.
I saw a video of him as a collegiate
wrestler beast and there were,
I guess it's like a documentary that's
coming out or something.
Yeah.
And I was like god he was here and he
was fucking the same brock lesnar that
fucking scary.
Look what's he got there?
Blue belt?
Yeah.
I got a new blue belt.
Well,
so what's so what's it go?
It goes white,
white,
blue.
Well it Depends.
Some people get weird,
they hAd a bunch of stuff,
but this is most jujitsu schools because
taekwondo is very different.
but jujitsu is white,
blue,
purple,
brown,
black.
So some people put stripes and stuff in
there.
John john was never really ended that
john jack would just go from belt to
belt and eddie just goes from belt to
belt and um,
it's all just,
it's up to them too.
It's not like a test,
which is kind of weird,
like everywhere else in taekwondo,
you would have to learn forms and have
to learn these,
uh,
these little jabs at Japan.
They call them katas and these are a
bunch of like knife,
hand strike,
sidekick,
knife,
fence,
trike,
sidekick.
It's like a dance that you're doing,
you know,
just this preformed thing.
And you had to know these things in
order to get certain Belts.
So like if you were a purple belt and
you wanted to become a brown belt or is
it a red belt?
Yeah,
it was.
I think it went in taekwondo.
I think it went purple,
red for a member correctly.
Purple,
red,
green,
blue,
purple,
yellow,
blue,
green,
purple,
red,
black.
I think that's it that.
But it's different than others.
Some schools,
some schools,
they would not have the red.
They would have a brown.
I can.
Karate was always brown.
It wasn't red.
And jujitsu,
red is like the super master.
They have like a coral belt for guys
like hixon gracie and john jacques
machado.
They give them this red belt,
you know,
who gives it to them,
their master.
They asked to see someone of
commensurate achievement in jujitsu.
Like you have to get it from one of the
great masters.
There's,
you know,
there's a bunch of great masters out
there like henzel gracie hoists,
gracie,
you know,
there's like the old guard to like hixon
of course fixing gives you your coral
belle.
He gave.
He gave john jacques machado was coral
belt.
That's just so.
It doesn't get any,
like,
more prestigious.
You know who john jack is a,
he's a really special guy.
His jujitsu is so technical and he's
like,
he was also instrumental in making
certain techniques work in mma because
john jack was born with one hand is
deformed and all he has is a thumb on
his left hand.
He doesn't have any fingers and because
of that,
um,
he,
he figured out that he can't rely and
grabbing the jujitsu.
He can't,
or the kimono,
whatever you want to call it.
He cannot rely on holding on to collars
and grabbing sleeves and manipulating
people with that.
Instead,
he switched to over hooks and under
hooks and went to a more wrestling base
control,
so when jujitsu went from being gay
based,
primarily in competition to,
they started doing abu dhabi.
Abu dhabi was nogi and when when they
went with the abu dhabi submission
fighting championships,
john jacques dominated people.
Really one of the reasons why dominated
he's because he's awesome.
He's just a super high level world
champion black belt,
but two,
because he had never relied on the geek.
He was just about holding bodies.
He was all over hooks and under hooks
and it translated perfectly in mma.
Eddie bravo learned that from john jock.
He learned that from watching john
jacques and from training under john
jacques and getting his black belt under
him and so eddie developed his style and
eddie branched out away from the gate
though.
It's like a big controversial thing.
When he stopped wearing a gi and he
started teaching nogi jujitsu,
like people got upset at him and the
jujitsu community that he was abandoning
the gay.
It was like a big deal.
Yeah,
and he's a revolutionary man.
He really is.
It's in when it comes to jujitsu,
that guy has a crazy database of
information in his head when it comes to
like jujitsu moves and a lot of it he
learned because he learned john jocks
the at least the base of his style,
which john jack developed because he
couldn't grab onto things.
Really interesting.
That's really interesting.
No,
this is a silly question.
Could could Bruce Lee really fight?
I'm sure Bruce Lee could fuck up a lot
of people if you will.
Yeah.
You watched him throw kicks and punches.
That guy definitely knew how to hit
things and there's some video of him
sparring it.
Definitely where he did some sparring,
so that means if you've done sparring,
like if you've never hit anybody before,
boy,
that's a weird moment.
Like even wHat do you hit?
You hit bags.
You don't hit a bag either.
Okay.
Do you ever have anybody hold the myths
for you and no.
Nothing and just kind of try to hit a
person as a.
It's not easy to hit people hitting the
person is.
It doesn't feel like You think it's
going to feel.
It feels weird.
It feels really weird,
um,
after being hit.
Feels totally normal.
Does It?
When you get hit you're like,
there's no weirdness to it.
You're like,
oh,
that's just like what I remember when I
ran into my friend's elbow.
That's the same feeling.
Yeah.
Unless you get tuned up on your jaw.
Oh,
never popped a new job.
No,
that's a weird feeling because your legs
just stopped working.
I got dropped in a kickboxing match.
I got dropped with a left hook and my
legs just so they just shut off.
They were like,
shut off.
My legs just shut off.
They like,
stopped working like somebody.
I thought that when you got hit on the
john,
you went down like that because you were
hurt.
And because like,
uh,
like,
oh my god,
this hurts so much.
I have to fall down.
Like almost.
Yeah.
But it's not really that.
It's something hAppens when you get hit
with like a perfect knockout punch or
just a knockdown punch when your jaw,
when they connect with your jaw and your
jaw,
like displaces all that energy on that
pivot of your jaw and the brain stem and
your spine and whatever.
Fuck Is getting damaged in there when
your jaws rattling around inside of your
head,
but it sends a spark like a and your
shit just goes really?
Oh dude,
you just get shut off.
It's weird.
And mine was a like,
I would say a half shut off because I
was still conscious but my legs stopped
working,
but I was still super aware that I was
in a fight.
I knew exactly what was going on.
I knew I just got tagged and I knew,
whoa,
this has never happened to me before.
I never had my legs give out.
Like she didn't go to sleep.
No,
no,
no.
I was like,
onlY 50 percent there.
But I've of course seen every variety of
that and sometimes you'll see a guy gets
shut off with a punch.
Like someone just hit someone with a
perfect punch,
like you remember when manny pacquiao
fought one,
one mil.
Juan manuel marquez the last fight.
See?
Oh my god.
One of the greatest.
All time.
One punch.
Knockouts packing.
I was charging in and this is I think
the third or the fourth time they had
fought each other.
Maybe the third and one men.
Well mark as an corks.
the perfect right hand on packing house
face.
Oh I didn't see that.
I did face plants and he's out for a
long ass time.
He just face plants.
Yeah,
it was,
it was.
Watched it blow.
Yeah.
I mean that is a god damn perfect punch
when you can knock a guy like that
completely out.
So that's,
that's like,
that's the highest level that you
achieve.
Oh jesus.
Hitting that spot.
The highest level is eveRything stops
and they got to wake you up and you
probably don't even Remember what
happened,
but
I never got to that.
Um,
I never got hit and had that happen to
me.
But having that halfway thing happened
where your legs just stopped but you're
awake and you know exactly what
happened.
It's such a weird feeling of
vulnerability.
Like I didn't even know that was the.
He's a button there.
I didn't even know it was there.
Like you don't really know what is it
that happens?
Is it a nerve that.
Something like that.
Yeah,
something I've explained it and then it
had someone correct me and say that's
not scientifically correct.
We're talking which shocker bro.
Science.
But about something happens when you get
punched in the jaw that your jaw of
rattles against your spine.
They go,
well,
I'm not really.
I'm like,
well,
okay.
Well what does happen is like,
is it the spin of the head?
Like what is it that makes sense?
Because there's.
ThAt's one thing,
like what's happens if you get clipped.
He noticed that people's jaws,
they had fucking bounces around a lot on
the impact.
Like if you get caught with a really
good body shot,
you get dropped,
right?
Boom.
You get hit,
you get dropped.
Your body's kind of absorbing all the
shock of that punch.
but your head when your head absorbs it,
your shit just swivels around your neck.
We think about your head is like the
worst thing you could ever hit.
This thing is barely connected.
All wobbly and shit.
The bones are.
There's like little stacks of boston on
a big bone.
It's not like a big ass thighbone that
connects my fucking head to my neck.
Yeah.
Like what's wrong with this shitty
vertebrae?
Stuff with gooey gel in between pieces
of bone.
What?
What a shit idea.
Whose plan is this?
I made this.
I've been knocked unconscious a couple
of times now that I think about it.
I've talked about this at one time.
How many concussions as normal and I
think I've had like 10 concussions.
That's not normal.
That's a lot.
But at least seven.
I probably have a bunch that I was in
denial about because like inspiring,
like you would get hit in the head all
the time.
Yo jay me bring it the b,
I'm sparring.
You get hit in the head all the time.
Sometimes you get rocked and if you.
If you're sparring and you get rocked,
like what does constitute a concussion?
You know,
sometimes people have concussions and
they didn't even have a bad sparring
day.
They go home and then they,
they start throwing up.
Do
they feel weird?
They go to the doctor and dr goodyear
can cost and they don't even remember
the shot.
They don't even remember what got them.
Oh,
thank you for whatever reason.
Thank you sir.
The um,
for whatever reason,
you know,
that can happen to you.
I threw up when I got a concussion.
Did you?
That's super common.
Right?
Cheers.
I'm,
yeah,
I threw up.
I was in rollie massimino basketball
camp and I got knocked unconscious.
I want to for rebound.
They pulled my feet out and I landed on
my head.
I was like 13.
I had to go to the to go to the general
hospital and I was in a wheelchair.
They wouldn't let me get out of the
wheelchair and walk.
And I was like,
I'm fine.
And I was just a little low and then all
loopy.
And then I just started throwing up and
I was like,
I'm not sick.
I don't know why I'm throwing up.
So.
Whoa.
Yeah.
You don't want to ever admit that you're
fucked up when you hit your head dudes.
Like,
I'm fun.
By the way.
My parents did.
I don't even know if my parents called
me.
LiKe I look back at that and I wonder if
they,
like as a parent of a 12 year old,
I would lose my shit if my kid was in
philadelphia and she got a concussion,
I'd be,
I'd be on a fucking plane tomorrow.
We'll also,
when someone gets a concussIon like
that,
you gotta really keep an eye on them for
quite a while.
They kept me up.
They put me in the rectory.
and why do they keep you awake?
What's the logic behind that?
I don't that we kept like every hour I
think is you don't want to fall asleep
and go to sleep forever.
I mean die while you're cheating the
reaper.
Yeah.
Or are you.
See that's the question.
The people that died.
I mean,
when they've died of this state of week
two.
Is this a just,
you know what I'm saying?
Yeah,
yeah.
I don't know.
I,
they put me in with the priests and
fucking.
I know I just had a head injury.
What's it like hanging out with priests?
Uh,
I never really enjoyed it.
I just hung out with a lot of priests to
really know.
I raised my eyebrows.
Anything eLse?
You know,
it's so funny.
I could probably get.
I'm like oblivious.
You ever see those movies where the
sharks in the water and the people are
swimming and dance and have a good time
and then you're like,
oh,
it's going to get it.
It's gonna get it's gonna get it,
And then they just get out there like,
hey,
let's go do something else now.
And they don't get attacked.
But I was probably like,
that was with molestation really.
I'm certain of it really.
So it just barely missed you.
Every time I would have been a mark like
molesters,
wet dream because I was,
I was just,
I don't know,
I've always attracted those people in my
life to like,
people that take advantage of people I
molesters must have seen had spots on
me.
I remember watching the kid get molested
one time.
Oh no.
Not,
not like molested,
but like,
it was definitely a,
an assault.
We were in a kids camp of baptist kids
camp and uh,
I remember we were all in our bunk beds
and it was lights out and all of a
sudden the lights came on and they're
like,
oh,
these two counselors,
or like a hog tie in time and this and
everyone's like,
seth run and this one kid.
I mean they just came down to the bronx.
I had no idea what's going on.
It's one kid came running and they
grabbed him and they flipped him over
that rope and they hog tied him and
ripped his underwear off him and then
brought him into the shower.
And we all went into the shower and then
they had him in the shower and they were
like,
what are you going to do?
And then like it was fucking creepy,
like they didn't touch his dick or
fingers,
bottle or anything,
but just the fact that he was tied up
and like,
like thrown them in the shower and threw
him in the shower.
And I was like,
I remember going,
jesus christ,
note to self hide when they say hog
tying.
I went to camp.
By the way,
the same guy,
those same two guys that did that to him
taught me archery.
Oh
savages.
I went to camp with these kids had tied
this kid up.
They tied this kid up in his bed and
they took his bunk is a little cot cot.
They carried it out and he woke up as
they were taking them outside,
it was pitch black outside to pitch
black and you couldn't see a fucking
inch in front of your face.
And They took this kid deep in the woods
with a.
It gets yellow and put me back,
put me back.
They covered all of this shit with
toothpaste,
apparently toothpaste,
at least some toothpaste does not wash
out of your clothes.
Really?
Yeah.
Or if it does take a tremendous effort
so that this guy squirt toothpaste all
over this guy's and rubbed it in
this fucking piece of shit.
Oh fuck.
Kids away from their parents for the
first time.
And it was just a few weird counselors.
I remember I had this conversation with
his counselor,
you know,
or I guess what do you call him?
Boy scout leaders,
a scout leader.
He's like an eagle scout and the kid was
a 18,
which is like the last year that you can
be a boy scout,
you know,
and he and I were hanging out and uh,
he was uh,
talking to me about all his time in the
boy scouts and all the things he learned
about the boys and now they're,
they're kind of kicking them out because
you can't be in the boy scouts.
You're a fucking boy.
Loser.
Boy scouts are weird that way.
And I started to realize like,
this is due at the end of his career,
like it's over for you.
Your,
your eagle scout.
You peak two peaks at 18.
Oh,
put.
This was a huge part of his life.
I mean,
he had all these merit badges and shit
all over his clothes.
And they were telling him,
sOn,
you got to fucking stop you gotta.
Stop with your fantasy worlds.
Whether your badges and your fucking
ropes around your shoulder.
Those ropes of those little,
uh,
I don't know.
Lockton's reps don't.
They have those little ropes with the
flux,
that rope all about.
What are you doing there?
I would have definitely got melissa if I
was the boy scouts.
There was an article I wrote.
It's funny how you read things,
not wrote,
read rather.
It's funny how you read things when
you're a little kid.
Like,
I think I was maybe beef maybe 14 or 15
when I read this.
Some guy wrote it in the school
newspaper in newton south high school.
So it was talking about the,
the,
the things that they make you say when
you're a boy scout.
I promised to be trustworthy,
loyal blade,
brave,
clean and reverent or something like
that.
Yeah,
I think that'S the honest,
trustworthy,
loyal,
brave,
clean and reverent.
I think those are the commandments.
if I remember correctly,
maybe there's more of that,
but there was describing them and they
were just describing keeping your
thoughts clean and this guy who who
wrote an article was another high school
kid.
It's really,
really good point.
He's like,
my mind is my.
I can have whatever thoughts I want.
Like as long as I don't do anything
about them.
Like why?
Why should you try to control my
thoughts?
And like he's right,
he's right.
Like what is this thing clean?
Like why,
why can't you think terrible dirty
things?
Because it amuses you,
you know,
as long as you're not hurting anybody
then what is the point like?
Like I've never once thought about
fucking a kid,
but like are there people that are legit
think that like they must think that.
what do you mean?
They think that like I don't have to
control my thoughts was absolutely
people that are attracted to children.
And then,
so obviously there is something to blame
anyone that does that to a child,
but how then do you stop their brains?
That's what the brain's doing.
They're not doing it on purpose,
but their brains going.
That's the real debate when it comes to
like when neuroscientists try to analyze
different types of behavior,
destructive behaviors,
um,
what,
when you can look at any type of
horrible destructive behavior,
you,
you get to that one where you literally
don't even want to help them.
And that's the one you were gambling and
alcoholism and even being prone to
violence and are the different things.
There's all sorts of different therapies
and different ways that people would try
to move you away from that.
But I got to imagine there's very few
therapies that anybody wants to invest
in to try to get someone to stop fucking
kids.
Yeah.
Now just like we don't have any
tolerance for that at all.
And,
and I mean this is a really volatile
question to say,
but is it their fault?
Well,
it's a real good question and it's so
easy to say,
of course it is.
Fuck them.
You're,
you're having sex with kids,
you piece of shit.
It's so easy to say that,
and in a way you're right for saying
that you're right for thinking that
because you're angry because what
they're doing is terrible.
They're ruining lives.
We all know that,
but I think human beings are just a
combination of experiences and genetics
and environment and all the data that
comes into them and the decisions that
you make based on all those things.
They're not even like your.
Your life experience is way different
than my life experience and I don't know
what happened to him when he was a baby
that Made him this monster,
this 45 year old guy who wants to.
Yeah.
Like jared,
I don't know.
I don't know what happened to him.
You know who the fuck knows what torture
he endured when he was young?
I don't know.
You never know.
Maybe he's just a bad person that could.
That's a possibility too.
I'm not discounting that,
but what is it about that one thing in
particular that we don't have any faith
whatsoever that you can ever completely
get it out of your system?
Well,
you never could.
It will be like curing.
Try to cure him.
Crew me from being straight.
You say that right?
But isn't that crazy that,
that there's no biological imperative.
They're like,
there's no biological pole to have sex
with little kids.
Right?
That's just a crazy fucked up reversion.
It's not like saying you could never be
with a woman again.
You can never feel a woman's touch
again.
It's more like saying you can't gamble
again or more like saying,
oh,
the campbell campbell's that there's
something like a crazy perverted sexual
attraction connection that they're
having with people that they shouldn't
like young people.
Right?
Where's that coming from?
and if it's coming from them being
victimized and that's what a lot of it
is a lot of is coming from them being
victimized when they're young and they
in turn start victimizing other people.
It's tHe most common form of um,
how they think.
Pedophilia actually travels back and
forth almost like a disease.
It's really fucked up.
It's like a disease of the mind,
like you could give it to somebody and
fuck with their sexuality.
If you think about it,
if you read less to ken,
if you molest kids and you.
If you look at all these guys that wind
up being the lesters,
a lot of them were molested as kids.
It's horrible
man,
so and obviously a lot of them don't do
that and don't have the urge to do that,
but there's something that happens to
some of them where it becomes this
really fucked up thing that just keeps
passing on from person to person,
from victim to victim,
which is a horrible stigmatization if
you've been molested because you assume
if you tell people that everyone thinks
you're going to be molesting kids,
what a weird thing it must be.
To have that impulse to an impulse that
you know is hoRrible.
I'm so glad I don't have that because I
cannot control my brain.
I definitely cannot.
I definitely think massively horrible
fucking thoughts,
but that has never crept in there.
To the point where I think,
I can't imagine what draw it is to what
I,
the,
the withdrawal would be to be with the
child does not draw.
There's something broken.
Men,
some crazy disconnect in your mind.
I mean,
I look at sexuality and I look at.
I would like to be with someone.
I would like to share a moment with
someone accomplished that knows what
they're doing and I would hate to
instruct someone.
I would never want to sleep.
I don't even say that you say that,
but do you remember that movie?
Um,
10 with bo.
Derek?
Yeah.
Pretty hot,
right?
Yeah.
Okay.
Imagine bo,
derek,
and uh,
for whatever reason she's been an island
for the first 24 years of her life that
she's never seen a man.
And finally you and her meat and you're
hanging out and it's going to be the
night,
which she doesn't know what to do.
I think you fucking help her out.
I definitely,
I can show her the way and I definitely
tell her a bunch of how it works.
Like,
hey,
when I'm done to,
oh my god,
look at that.
She's so pretty with.
Interesting.
Is that that book?
Lolita.
What is that book?
I don't know.
I read it.
I want to say.
I don't know.
I read it.
I think I read it in russian.
Oh,
no,
west,
swear to god.
Can you speak fluent russian?
No,
I can understand russian though.
Wow.
Now how much can you read a nun anymore?
You used to be able to.
Yeah,
I used to because of the.
Because the.
It's a different alphabet and I can't
read it at all anymore and I thought it
would be able to pick it up a little
bit.
I have a diary written in russian.
Yeah,
when I was backpacking through europe
because we were all traveling together
after Russia.
I started keeping a journal and I was
just writing in russian because I was
like,
no one can because no,
I could be wrong.
The train and I could write whatever I
want and no one could really read my
read what I wrote.
It was a very simple journal like it was
today.
Eats meats.
I like riding bikes.
Yeah,
man.
You're a those kinds of life experiences
or just to go into the place where they
write those things and learn how to
write in that language and write your
own little blog and speak with those
people in there.
That's a crazy life experience,
man.
That's.
That's very enriching.
I've been telling.
I've been telling this story on stage
now of riding in in Vietnam through rice
patties.
How well when I called you on the phone.
Yeah,
that's a great story because we had been
drinking and smoking hash and I was
riding the motorcycles and you called
and I was listening to music and it
snapped me into reality and you're like,
what are you doing?
And I told you,
and you're like,
dude,
this fucking bert.
This is what it's about you.
Like it was a very.
It was a very pivotal speech and the way
I looked at that show because you're
like,
you like these experiences,
fuck the show these experience define
you and you need to talk about this on
stage.
You like literally think about,
look around,
remember your surroundings and bring
this up on stage.
And I was like,
I will,
and then I was like,
fuck yeah.
And the sun was setting and it was
fucking beautiful and there's oxygens in
the rice patties and there's birds and
I'm listening to spirit and spanish
caravan by the doors and I'm flying and
now and now I just had this conversation
with you and I'm looking at my shadow in
front of me racing me and that's my
childhood and that's my,
my.
And I'm like,
oh,
it's the greatest thing ever.
It was like.
And then my wife called,
oh wow.
It's like,
it works so well with joe.
We'll try it with her.
And she was like,
get off the fucking bike.
Well you have high blood pressure.
But uh,
but yeah,
but like that's the hardest part is
telling these stories on stage two.
Totally different reactions.
Be great if she coached you on,
right on bertha,
conquer you are the machine.
She screams at you.
I got,
I got the audio.
I told her that.
Jay oakerson.
It's so funny because they're like
rogan's your spirit.
Like it was a great.
I've got the audio.
I was going to post it and have someone
do a animate it,
but yeah,
there was.
I'm trying to write about those
experiences now on this new hour and
it's just,
it's really fun,
but you know what man,
you,
when you told me to tell them machines
story on stage,
I learned so much about this,
about the art of storytelling and the
art of stand up mess together.
The hardest part is that I remember that
how long it took to get that story good.
And every story starts with like only
one little funny part and you just got
to do it all the fucking time.
You just got to figure it out and work
it out and needed out and tell it as
many times as you can.
Yeah.
It's like you've got to figure out what
to cut out to.
Maybe a better way to describe what was
happening.
You know,
it's um,
there's an art to it.
Some people are just geniuses at it.
Yeah.
Some people that tell story and you just
go,
you just can't wait.
Can't wait to hear what happens next.
Some people,
it's their pacing to joey diaz will slow
everything down.
Dog,
let me tell you somethIng.
Nineteen 86 north bergen,
New Jersey is me and peter ham sandwich
and it'll go into this.
Fuck.
I mean,
it's like you like you're a little kid
like gimme the popcorn.
His father always carried a comb in his
back pocket.
He called him out with hiS campaign.
He comb his hair.
You remember those columns used to have
with the little pointy things would
break off and you'd only have like two
fangs and then you'd be missing a fang.
they'd have the other thing kind of like
move your hair out with it.
Wow.
The fucking part where it doesn't work.
The thing I was telling,
I was telling steve,
oh,
this I was.
I just had steve all mY podcast and we
were talking about the being being in
comedy and being at the clubs.
The thing of it iS,
is that often the funniest thing you say
you don't realize you're being funny
sometimes,
right?
Yeah.
And,
and we try have your friends around and
be like,
hey,
is that a bit?
And you're like,
no,
I feel silly for saying it.
Like,
no,
that's good.
Like joey that and that is what's great
about joey.
I swear to god when I say I have been
with him where he said the funniest
things that no one could write.
You'll never be able to find this
structure and write it.
Yeah.
I'll take another one too.
Thanks jamie.
And uh,
and you just like,
like,
like he said on my podcast wanted
autonomy.
I go,
my have a big dog is a dog and old trust
dogs.
I said,
why?
And he goes,
procrastinate.
When I first came to this country,
I get attacked by dogs five times.
The last dog walks past me and then came
back to bite me.
And you're like,
what the fuck man,
like,
and then,
and he just has a flat look on his face.
He's not trying to run a bit.
He's tellIng you his life.
Yeah.
He's just funny joe.
he just know how to do it.
I told them I was a guy,
cool guy that live near to best when
there's homeless people were breaking in
my house.
Joe drove by every night.
How many homeless people broke in your
house?
Really?
Because we're under construction.
We're renovating a first one broke in a
brumby's.
Very fucking similar.
You can't scare them.
Really?
Yeah.
I was sitting.
I.
We had dinner at my sister's house.
the girls went inside.
Everything's under construction.
We got like a big dumpster out front.
It looks like it's under construction
and I'm sitting off to the side smoking
a cigar in the darkness and this girl
just starts walking in,
walking up the driveway,
starts to go into our backyard and I see
her and I'm like,
wait,
do I know?
I must know her.
It's a weirD thing when you get robbed
that you're like,
it's like a such a confrontation that
you're like,
like if you ever been like been in
competition and someone's like,
hey man.
And you're lIke,
oh,
I must have this person high.
And then they attack you and you're
like,
oh fuck.
This is how it starts.
That was what happened in this growth is
just going back here.
And I go and we must know her and I go,
hey,
can I help you?
And then she was like,
oh hey.
And she said something like,
I work for the dwp or some child's
organization something.
And I was like,
no,
this is,
you're breaking into my backyard.
and I start fucking shouting at her.
And she just keeps walking towards me.
She's not fucking scared at all.
Priscilla is 130 pound bull mastiff.
A beast of a fucking dog is going at
her,
like leaping at her and all this.
Keeping up as a little tiny dog fence
that we had in our front yard at the
time.
Fearless this woman was.
You couldn't shake her hair.
I think a heroin addict probably.
Yeah.
And I was like,
motherfuckers,
we call the cops.
Then the cops show up.
I don't remember when shit's on crops.
I love them.
They showed up in three minutes.
They were there three minutes.
The woman
had already taken off.
I told them where they were.
she went and the guy was like,
yeah,
it's,
you know,
there's a new heroin dealer in town.
A lot of junkies and homeless people are
going to be loitering around here until
we stopped that,
but he's like,
I'm sorrY.
And I look at both my daughters are in
the,
um,
in the doorway and they're looking out
and I'm like,
hey man,
I told the cop,
so do you mind if the girls come down
for like two seconds and you just let
them know that they'll be like,
you're going to,
there's nothing to worry about.
And he's like,
yeah,
I don't know your girls going down.
So george and I'll come down and they
had lollipops and they put notes on it
that said,
you are our heroes.
And they gave him to the cops.
I'm only talking about a heart fucking
breaking moment.
These costs were like,
ladies,
first of all,
we will be circling this bark all night
long.
Nothing's happened to his house.
We will keep an extra good.
I out in this house and Georgia starts
pulling on my shirt.
She's like,
dad,
let's go dad.
Let's go.
I was like,
hold on george.
He's not done.
He's like,
dad,
I think we,
we should go to the house.
And I was like,
Georgia,
it's fine by the guy gives a speech and
we walked back to the house and I was
wearing this shirt and she goes,
you are wearing a marijuana shirt.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
cops don't give a fuck.
No,
I don't give a fuck about pot.
They want more people on pot.
Nobody just relax.
But it was bringing the homeless people.
We had a porta potty in our front yard.
Do you know anybody that's ever shot the
heroine actually shot him.
That's what hedberg used to do.
Yeah.
I didn't know him well though.
I mean that was when,
um,
you know,
he had gotten gang green.
Um,
and like I think it was 2003,
stan hope pulled me aside to tell me
that he was in the hospital and then
hedberg is like,
his leg was really fucked up and they
were worried he was gonna lose his leg
because he had gangrene from shooting
the same spot.
And.
But I didn't know him well,
he was more of a friend to stan hope,
but as a comic I was a huge fan.
Well,
as a person I was a huge fan of his.
But as a comic I really respected him.
He was a great comic.
Yeah,
just interesting to and really unique
and he just always made me laugh.
I just really.
And I always enjoyed like his,
his,
like headed such an observed style.
It made giggly.
It was so unique.
Yeah.
But he liked that heroin,
I guess.
Do you hear the reference a stan hope
made a,
a machete referenced last night?
No,
I didn't hear it.
Do frane party of three to frame party
of three.
What happened to the do friends?
I said we started a search party.
Search party of four.
Yeah.
He,
his,
his pacing and his,
his style of talking.
It was the first comic that I ever heard
say ain't.
And it was,
it was poetic,
you know,
man,
I ain't even gonna do that.
Yeah,
he,
he had it down.
I would watch.
I would pay right now.
I'm not even joking.
If you said to me,
I have a,
a like a 30 for 30,
you know,
30 years 30 for 30 about mitch hedberg,
that's an hour and 20 minutes.
That covers all the,
all the I'd pay easily a thousand
dollars to watch it.
Wow.
Strong words.
I would.
I'm men it,
I find I should.
Interesting me too.
I wanted to do a series for comedy
central where we had like a,
almost like a podcast,
but we were where I would go to all the
comics and I would have them tell me
their best story,
their best hedberg story and then I'll
compile it all into episodes about
comics telling stories about a tell
comics,
telling the stories about mitch thomas,
telling stories about stan hope.
Like imagine if you did one with stan
hope and I just.
Everyone I had on my podcast,
I just took like five minutes aside and
was like,
tell me your best doug stan hope story
and then I just compiled that into a
three hour podcast.
We let doug listen to it and then at the
end of the story go objection.
That'd be a bad ass.
It would be bad ass.
Maybe I'll do that about stan hope.
It's not a bad one.
I got a gang of stories.
I'm sure he's always been a character.
I told stan hope story to marilyn manson
last night.
Did you?
YeAh.
Well I think.
Oh,
I got to take that back.
I told her on stage isn't weird hanging
out with marilyn manson.
Very fucking bizarre.
It was odd.
I shook his hand in the process of
shaking his hand.
I was like,
oh shit.
That's marilyn manson.
I walked into doug's like manson's in
there and I didn't think there was like
I was thinking of a guy from bubba,
the love sponge or something.
Oh,
okay.
And I was like,
And then we walked in and I went,
oh,
that's marilyn manson.
And I just like super easy to talk to.
Really smart fucking dude.
You know?
He's a really good artIst.
Ever.
See his work does work.
I bought,
I went to work at barnes and noble.
His book came out a book and I was just,
I was like,
he was from Florida.
I was from Florida,
so I read the book.
It's fucking really interesting.
It's an interesting way to write a book,
like a comic should do what he did.
He had a gallery,
a opening or showing of his work and I
went to check it out.
It's really interesting.
I mean,
he's super creative guy,
very creative,
so you can kind of see how it look at
that.
I mean that's really good.
Stuff like that.
That's beautiful art.
Yeah.
No,
he's a really good.
it's bizarre,
weird shit like that.
A hunter s thompson when he's got there,
he's got.
Look at that.
The one to the left that the hunter s
thompson one look at that is fucking
great.
He did it.
He did a video.
He did a video the these gesture day
about um,
about cutting a donald trump's head off.
Do you think he sells that as a far as I
know he did a video about cutting donald
trump's hat off and that is,
that is not going to fare well now.
Think that'S illegal now.
Like once when someone's,
the president,
I don't think you can make jokes about
killing and cut their heads off.
And then I was like,
oh,
I made a video too.
It's a little different.
And I showed him mine and it's me and a
thong coming out of a porta potty.
I saw tHat and he was like,
he goes,
yeah.
He laughed.
He was like,
oh,
that's funny.
That'S was really funny.
And I was like,
well,
how much did it cost you to shoot your.
Yeah,
yeah.
He got a rubber head.
The Whole deal that I'm hunter s
thompson from manson is fucking amazing.
I wonder if they have prints of that.
I bet you could call marilyn manson and
asked him if he has a predator that
would be annoying.
You don't.
Not at all.
Not from you.
It'd be annoying.
Like,
so he called me and said,
oh,
I get you a dvd.
Amazon.com.
Stupid.
Oh yeah.
What is that?
A thinly veiled request.
That's why I'm not famous.
I called marilyn manson.
He go,
do you know how I get one of your
albums?
Just download it on itunes.
People get mad.
Is there.
There are some bands that you can't buy
an itunes,
right?
Maynard maynard scott.
is that scott,
is that made a key mentor?
Keenan tool is dude the fucking the tool
album with prison sex on it.
Oh,
I love that.
The greatest fucking album.
I love that album.
Top to bottom was one of my favorite
albums.
That's when I got into ecstasy and coat
and carlo man,
that prison sex.
I used to listen to that shit when I
worked out because like that was like a
weightlifting song.
Oh,
you get foreign sober.
Ooh.
Good channels on that man.
That is a great fucking album.
That was a great podcast when you had
him on.
Yeah,
he's interesting.
He's a really interesting guy.
He's very smart dude.
Almost too smart.
Cool boots.
He's cool boots.
Boots.
He makes really good wine.
Yeah.
Really good wine.
Like I'm not,
I'm not obviously not as Somalia or
anything like that,
but I know like what tastes good and his
shit tastes really good and he,
he knows so much about it.
Like we talked to them about it,
like the way he describes it and
explains the process and he's super,
super into it.
He is,
I,
I'm fascinated by that guy.
Him and him,
marilyn manson.
Uh,
what was the other guy?
Trent reznor,
that whole.
There was a whole genre.
Now those guys turned into a club dJ say
go turn into diplo or scrillex back then
they made albums.
Well those guys may not know.
They do one song and release it and then
they toward.
Do you ever follow?
You don't.
Are you on snapchat at all?
No.
The diplo on snapchat is one of the most
interesting lives a human could live.
Really?
He is in my right.
He is on private jets.
I met diplo a long time ago before he
was,
I mean I'm sure he was famous,
but like he was going to a trade show
for travel channel and we went out and
he was so interested in hosting.
He's like,
I really want to get into hosting.
Thank fucking god.
they didn't pick up his show.
He travelS on private jets to helsinki,
then to tokyo,
then to ibiza.
Then to.
I mean he's,
when he's in,
he's in vegas once a week with skrillex.
They do a party and like,
it's the craziest fucking life man.
He's a super ball and he's super bawling
and he's done.
He doesn't look like he spends a ton of
money other than private jets.
But,
but he seems like he's got his shit
together.
He's a really sweet too.
They do a show in vegas every week
screaming scrillex I,
I watched,
um,
on,
on vice law vice land.
What'S the tv slant?
Viceland on noisy.
Uh,
the host
who I forgot his name,
but he's a great host of noisy.
He really is a fantastic host and I'm
speaking from a hosting perspective,
very laissez faire casual host.
he,
um,
I wish I knew his name.
I'd give him a shout out.
He went to vegas for a weekend and
partied with like all those guys and
just their lifestyle and how much money
they make.
I mean they were making,
you know,
and,
and then I didn't even know that dj am
you remember that guy?
Who did he die?
He died of a heroin overdose or.
But he was in the plane crash and he was
a great fucking dj,
like a legit great dj,
and I was like,
oh,
I just thought it was a reality star.
I didn't know dj.
Like he went on to big boy in the
morning I think and did a and was the
first person to do mashups of like run
dmc and sweet home Alabama.
And,
and he was playing sweet home Alabama on
the fucking breakfast club.
And everyone's like,
oh shit.
It was hits the fucking.
I got really into that.
That's one of my worm holes that I went
down,
was started googling everything about
these djs and then I end up watching a
girl doing drums.
HAve you seen these girls that do drums?
Fucking
baddest thing?
Well,
isn't an interesting what shows have
come to in vegas,
like a thing used to be in vegas is you
would go to vegas and you would see a
band and you still do that a lot in
vegas,
but more often than that you have djs
and these djs,
they have regular shows at these places.
Yeah,
well they do it all the time.
Would you take,
would you,
thiS is a silly question,
would you take a um,
were you looking for.
I was going to give you a bottle of it.
Got it,
got it.
Would you take a residency somewhere?
I don't think so.
I don't think that'd be as fun.
What if,
what if it was in la?
I think I'd like to do whatever the fuck
I want to do.
I like doing exactly how I'm doing it
now.
I don't,
I don't want to do a resident.
I don't want to be required to be in one
spot because I like,
I'd like to schedule phoenix one
weekend,
boston another weekend.
I like to do it like that.
I don't like to do it where I have to be
somewhere every week.
It's not a bad thing,
but if you can have freedom,
take freedom.
Always.
That's what if they said,
what if,
what if hypothetically being bilber doug
stanhope myself,
you fitzsimmons did once a month in
vegas and did that show in vegas like
that?
Like that?
Wow.
Yeah,
they have.
I would commit to that.
That would be so fine by the way.
I'd definitely commit to that because I
would be the one getting probably making
sure dinner was ready for everybody,
but why do we have to fly to vegas?
Why not do it here?
Want to do it exactly like we did last
night?
Yeah.
See,
don't complicate shit.
Oh yeah.
I guess.
Yeah,
we're in the store.
We all live here.
Fuck.
We're flying somewhere else.
Good point.
Sometimes I can complicate things just
because I go.
That'd be fun for us all in hotel rooms.
When you're thinking about it having a
reSidency,
you want to be like dean martin and
sammy davis jr.
New rat pack please.
Gentleman.
Everybody wants to be a new backpack.
Gang gang's all here.
The bro pack ropack out bro,
but doing a super show is that.
You know what?
Last night was like a podcast super
show.
Yeah.
We should definitely do that more often.
That was so much fun.
It was like one of the most fun things
I've ever done in my life.
It was so great because like when I did
my 200th episode,
I did it with tom and bill in my man
cave and we smoked cigars and halfway
through I went,
oh wait,
I've had the ability to do something
like this all the time is having my
friends come in together and us just
hang out and drink and bullshit,
but we can do that all the time,
but that,
that last night was just,
I'll never,
I will for the next week.
I'll remember moments of that and just
giggle.
I wish I was there for the sarah tiana
bill burr pornography fight.
Yeah.
Very bummed out that I had left when
that was going down.
It would've been.
It was an interesting.
It was an interesting debate.
I think it all started with condoms in
porn.
Yeah.
Well people get weird when it comes to
watching people.
Fuck.
Some people don't think you should be
able to do it.
I'm into the weirdest shit now.
I broke my gov.
Talk to me.
I'm fucking choking.
No,
no,
no.
Uh,
I was into.
I got into quicksand porn for a second,
but you remember we just can't come
unless the girls mascara's like covered
with sweat from gag and tears.
That doesn't turn me like my big.
My big thing is close up.
Orgasms cLose up like him close up.
Yeah,
because that's the way I see them in
real life.
My wife is one of the fucked me up.
She was like,
why was watching someone?
And it was like a guy in the girl's
gagging.
She was like,
I don't fucking gag.
And I was like,
no shit.
And then she was like,
oh my god.
uh,
she was like,
she's like,
yeah,
but that's so funny that you'd watch
something that you don't even do.
And I went,
what do you mean?
She was like,
you're watching something that's total
fantasy.
Like you have no attachment to that.
so it's almost like the sex you have is
something totally different than what
you masturbate too.
And I was like,
oh,
that's a good fucking call.
So I tried to really dial it in to like,
what is My,
what is the,
what are the things that actually turned
me on in real life and one of the things
is with my wife,
I have an orgasm,
I'm usually down there and that really
turns me on when that happens.
I'm like,
oh fuck.
So I got really close up org.
I just got super uncomfortable.
So does the rest of the world.
Everybody listening when jesus heard
there's another thing called it down
blouses.
Yeah.
But it's very,
it's very.
No,
I'm being serious.
Typing down bro.
like bend over to like fix your shoe or
something.
You looked down her blouse and sierra
ted's.
It's a genre of it,
but the genre I got into,
if you look on pornhub,
it's down bouncing and it's just girls
with loose fitting shirts,
cleaning,
which is the real like that is something
that I walked into the kitchen and my
wife will be like doing the dishes and
her paJama top shirt and you'll see like
a side tit and you'd be like,
Well I go tigers in here.
There's a tiger in the city.
Yeah,
see,
look,
look.
This is hilarious and that's all it is
is down her.
So it's like the women are working and
you see their tits accidentally while
they're working.
Yeah.
And it's.
And it's like 400,000
downloads.
So this girl was sitting there,
she's on her tits back and forth.
Yeah.
And just pretending it's working and
usually they're talking to you like
about just mundane stuff.
God hate to clean.
I really want to suck some cock.
Like there's a lot of these cars.
It's moments that you get in real life
when you see a woman's tit from a down
blouse and you're like,
whoa.
And it's not pervy you weren't doing it
on purpose.
It's very prayerful.
What are you talking about?
If little pervy is pervious?
Fuck.
It's like you can almost hear a nipple
but nah,
quiet.
Oh,
I just thought,
I just thought how come this is on the
youtube?
If you could just see a nipple,
how come it's only got 16,000
downloads,
views people.
Oh,
there's a need.
Donald trump straightaway it again.
Yeah,
they haven't found it yet.
It's in the youtube with that lady over
on the right with their big boobs.
It looks like you see her nipples to.
Yeah,
like you know that race car video where
the girls top pops open.
She's in a sports car and they're riding
fast as she was holding on and that are
top pops open.
There's something super sexy about that
and it's not watching a girl gagging a
cock sucker.
That girl,
jamie,
what's.
Hold on,
look at her.
She's like,
you went to see my tits?
Nope.
Psych.
I don't think so.
Psych,
it's like almost.
I'm going to do an equivalent equivalent
of this,
but with costco it's called down.
Digging down ticking and it's just me.
I barely see my dick.
Oh,
okay.
I get it.
It's not bad,
right?
No,
not at all at this girl.
Oh,
and you keep going.
Come on.
Move off to the side.
Yeah.
Down blessings.
But you into some weird shit.
I know.
Shit.
What happened?
Because I was watching.
I was watching regular porn and then it
just,
it just kind of escalated and it was
like truth be told,
I was with a dominatrix one time and she
showed me some videos.
It was bizarre shit.
She showed me a video that I was like,
I don't get it,
but then I got it.
Whoa.
Like it was a,
it was a girl in pantyhose and she was
like by the pool and her friend was
spraying with a hose and it wasn't even
like that's all they were doing,
but it just looks sexy.
And I was like,
oh shit.
It doesn't have to be hardcore porn.
It can just be something hot,
you know,
like something where you're like,
oh fuck.
And so I had that conversation with my
wife and I was like,
yeah,
I should find stuff to some more
connective.
Hm.
Here we're looking at growing borns and
you're like,
how does she not,
how did she get in?
They're like,
how come she just isn't being a model or
an actress?
Yeah.
Like,
she's so beautiful.
The fuck happened.
There's a girl that gives massages.
Do you know who the girl?
I'm talking about she's,
she's got black hair.
I've watched a lot of.
I'm going to share this one time because
you.
Would you like to share this video on
facebook?
You're like,
no,
I'm not to posted to my facebook
timeline.
It goes because when I was doing it two
in the morning,
um,
but uh,
there's a girl that gives.
She gives me massages and she's all in
white.
She wears all white and she is so
beautiful.
She might be as beautiful as anne
hathaway,
like that kind of just.
She looks like anne hathaway kind of,
if anyone knows this woman I'm talking
about,
send me a picture or just send it to
jamie.
Don't you think there's a bunch of them?
I know there's one girl specifically.
Well,
who would have thunk that that would be
a market that someone could corner the
massage on youporn that she's got that
down?
Yeah.
Whoever thought backroom,
casting couch,
whatever.
Be a show.
That's a whole thing.
Oh,
I watched.
Just because I try to figure out if it's
real or not.
I don't think he can be.
I think after signed papers,
I know by watch it the same way I
watched magician,
like I'm waiting to see the trick.
Right?
Right.
And we didn't see her slip up and go,
dave.
Seriously.
And he's like,
what?
How do you know my name?
I think I'd recognize that guy in the
locker room.
Hm?
Yeah.
Just from his voice and his hernia.
How strange that there's a that that is
a genre.
Like you're excited you're there with
them.
Wise casting these girls like,
uh,
let me see what you could do.
Okay,
now I do it now.
Yeah.
Get on your knees and your loan.
Your hotel room.
He says the same verbiage every time.
So I'm going to send this tape to
casting directors,
but a think first I'm gonna.
Need you to get naked and suck my dick
and you're and you're.
And you're just the look on her face
that comes out of so fast.
She's like,
huh,
and you and I go,
I go,
I go literally,
if this is real,
this is real.
And it's lasted.
Porn stars aren't that good.
Right.
As an actor,
as an actor,
they're not that good.
Well,
I'm sure if he's made a bunch of them
over the years,
he knows what he can do and not do.
So you can always get someone to sign
the paper after you do all this stuff.
He should start a youtube channel with
all the fails.
All the people that walk out on him.
Do you have within,
you can't use that footage or you borrow
their face?
Uh,
I guess I want to see the.
You'd want to see the reaction?
Yeah,
I don't think you'd do that.
There's like certain laws.
Yeah.
And you know,
the laws are different in different
states.
Do vegas,
you can do crazy shit in vegas.
That's why they did crank yankers there.
Yeah.
Have you seen,
have you seen,
um,
uh.
Oh shit.
What's the step?
What's the pr?
Impractical jokers?
No,
I have not.
It's a funny fucking show.
I keep hearing it's really good.
I don't like prank shows,
but it is a funny fucking prank show.
I've never been a fan of pranking
people.
Now I'm a,
I'm a,
I'm a fan of doug stanhope and doug
stanhope fan of them,
so I,
I take it on by proxy.
Yeah,
I watched it because it standing out.
I wouldn't watch it because I'm like
prank shows,
but it's fucking hilarious.
Do you know we used to have a really
fucking good prank show.
Who?
Jamie kennedy.
Dude,
I remember that show.
Yes.
What was it called?
The x sometimes factor x factor?
No,
nothing was factor.
Jamie kenny did minimum experiment.
That's it.
And he used to say like,
you got axed or something like that at
the end when he didn't he say something
like that.
Jamie kennedy is an interesting guy
because he is extremely fucking
talented,
but he's not working right now or I'll
see him at least some of the store the
other day.
Didn't see a set though.
Yeah.
You don't hear about them that much?
It was,
it wasn't on that show.
That ghost show ghost whisperer show or
something like that.
Oh yeah,
because he started dating that girl.
That girl I think fucks everyone's head
up love.
What's her name again?
Jennifer love hewitt.
Oh yeah,
man,
I watched her day in the life on mtv and
it reeked of fucking crazy,
like reeked of crazy.
She was like,
I bought you a present to her friend and
her friend's like,
you don't need to buy me presents.
I'll,
I like you.
She's like,
I said,
what about your president?
Wow.
I'm jamie kennedy.
Did something.
I'm going to put this out to the
listeners.
If you can find this for me.
I swear to god it would be.
It would be the biggest gift in the
world.
He did a show with a,
uh,
with stu stone.
Do you know the name of that show?
Stu stone?
It was called a getting,
making it or something.
They were rappers.
It was a scripted reality show.
So it was,
it wasn't a reality show.
It was scripted,
but it was about them wanting to be hip
hop stars all blowing up,
blowing up.
And so there's an episode where they
were.
Jamie's doing a test,
he's going to do a tv show,
a movie with tracy morgan,
and to do,
to do the screen test.
He needs to get put in blackface.
He needs to be addressed as a black man,
so they,
they dress him as a black man and he
gets all dressed up as a black guy and
tracy morgan convinces them that he's
very convincing as a black guy and that
what he should do is him and stu stone
should both get in face paint and look
like by people and then go down to the
three,
six mafia show and freestyle for them
because as black men for the three,
six mafia will really appreciate it.
Oh,
and joe,
there is a moment where they're driving
in a car to long beach address,
black guys and they're talking to each
other and they're like,
do you think this is a good idea?
Is there a hidden cameras in the car?
He's like,
no man.
I mean,
we're just going to be trained in the
order snoop's go into the three six
mafia,
like
they start rapping and then he goes,
this jamie,
this is a black person.
Go out in front of the audience.
Joe got all black people and rap and how
good was it?
Who gives a fuck?
And I couldn't stop.
It
was the greatest thing I've ever fucking
seen and I saw jamie kennedy one time at
the ontario improv and I was like,
dude,
I gotta take two seconds and tell you
how hard that made me laugh.
And he was like,
yeah,
you can't find it anywhere.
Like mtv dropped it and they like burn
it.
You can't get it because he's in black
face because he's in black.
He is in.
He looks so much like a black man.
You can't even find an image,
a screen grab of that all.
No weird is that.
How weird is that?
But think how strange that is.
Like I get it that it was from minstrel
shows or black or white men would put on
black face and do these offensive
representations of black men,
but that's a different look.
When they were doing it,
they were doing like this big thing
where they were putting like white
around their lips.
It was like really exaggerated.
Do you receive that?
Uh,
what's this guy's name?
Al jolson.
Thank you.
Was received when he would do that.
Jamie,
pull up some video of al jolson in
blackface.
See if they take it off youtube,
do you think they take that shit down
now or do you think you can catch a
candidate that actually might be in the
public domain because it's like one of
the first,
but I would worry that it was offensive
that it violates their terms of service
on.
No,
it's already on youtube.
Okay.
Um,
didn't bill cosby like take down the
little rascals.
He owns a little rascals,
the little rascals and tucked it away.
So what I hear the rapists are going to
start airing it again.
Really rape the people that got raped
because getting them ready.
We're going to start airing them.
No,
I'm kidding.
Look at al jolson.
Holy shit.
Give me some volume.
Jamie.
Turn this up a little bit.
How crazy is this around?
Hi,
I'm a seven.
I'm wide open like he's moving into
tears,
like walk five miles.
This is so crazy
trying when
it doesn't do a good impression of a
black guy.
Well maybe black men were different in
the twenties.
He's using the words.
Is it a black guy would use,
but he's doing it as a white guy,
as a white guy?
Yeah.
Well,
it's just really bizarre.
First of all,
it's bizarre when you think that that
was top of the food chain entertainment
in 1927,
so less than 100 years ago.
Can you imagine if somebody went to.
You went to a concert and the dude was
wearing black paint on
with white stuff around his lips and he
was singing that song.
You would think you were in some sort of
a weird abstract,
modern performance art show,
you know,
some weird like alt hipster vincent
gallo would do that now.
It's something strange that.
But then he wasn't joking around that
was like,
he was trying to like be what a
wonderful song.
Al.
What a wonderful song.
Like those people were apes like just
from 19,
27.
They were so goofy.
That was fun for them to like,
we're gonna go see the al jolson movie
that al jolson's a hell of an
entertainer.
I love when he sings.
He's got a beautiful voice.
He just liked it.
It was the first talkie that was the
first movie was synchronized sound.
That one was mad.
Just all silent films until then.
Wow.
So that guy must have been balling.
I bet he was slinging that makeup cover
dick all over town.
I bet there's a part of him that was
like,
why do I need to put the makeup on man?
Me?
Yeah.
They probably wouldn't know who he was
at.
Other makeup.
Fuck.
That would suck.
Like gene simmons,
like you're,
you know,
if you had the kiss makeup on,
you went to a bar with.
No,
it's up.
Another barber watching them in that
first movie with that he did with tom
selleck with letters and I was like,
oh shit.
That's gene simmons.
Yeah.
He was a bad guy in a few movies and
he's still a bad guy.
He's a fucking asshole.
Fuck.
Oh I hate.
We've covered this.
Hey,
you had a bad experience with fuck him.
Yeah,
he blocked me.
They'll be a annuity blocks.
He blocked me.
Wow.
That was the height of his good looking.
This um,
did you ever have tom selleck,
tom selleck and gene simmons?
Did they ever have.
Well,
did you ever have a like this is gonna
sound crazy.
Maybe this was just Florida,
but did you ever have like people
dresses in black face for parties and
stuff for like halloween?
I'm sure I probably saw it when I was
young for sure.
Trying to remember a specific instance.
I can't really like.
That was a popular costume when I was a
kid was being a black person.
Okay.
You know what I know I remember I do.
Did a.
He played mr t.
Yeah,
so that was a,
that was a common one and they would
wear blackface and they would put a
bunch of gold chains on.
I'm mr t dot and you put shoe polish but
like black paint all over your face.
Yeah,
you'd have like a fake mohawk in.
In college.
They used to have it.
We used to have a social called weed,
a couple of socials.
We a social call,
pimps up hoes down where everyone would
just dress like black people.
I mean it's so politically incorrect,
but that's,
you know,
I don't think anyone in the insight.
We had a social called uncle,
google beluga,
and uh,
I remember I was the one that organized
it and I handed out like makeup so
people could put war paint on
and the one girl just took a picture
just has just put it on jesus.
I remember her walking.
Did you share that?
Just covered herself with it?
Facebook,
I swear to god she posted herself.
She's like,
why?
I remember this part.
It was like,
why would you post that up yourself?
How bizarre.
Yeah.
She,
uh,
but that was like,
I don't remember when
and did it,
and everyone was like,
oh,
you're not supposed to do that.
That's right.
He was like the last white guy to try
black face.
Yeah,
like publicly try it.
They,
the backlash was terrible and he thought
he'd get away with it because he was
dating whoopi goldberg and I think he
told a bunch of black centric joke.
Yes.
Yeah,
like racist jokes.
Yeah.
Woo.
Ted danson.
One thing like n word jokes.
How do we have,
do we have transcripts of his act?
Probably.
There's probably a video of it.
No,
I know there's a picture a guaranteed as
a video that shit.
No,
that's not when people have,
didn't have videos back where if you
took a video,
just get over real.
Yeah,
I remember watching it.
I remember watching video of it.
I think they filmed that event is for
the friars club,
right?
Something like that.
Yeah.
It is a weird ethnic group that you're
not,
you're not allowed to be asian and
you're not allowed to be a black guy,
but if you're a white guy,
you can become a redhead.
Nobody will get upset.
No.
Literally get upset.
They get upset.
If you were black,
you can dress in white face and no one
cares.
No one cares.
Um,
but if you're black,
you can't be a chinese guy.
That's offensive.
And if you're a chinese guy,
can't pretend to be black.
That's offensive too.
I was,
I used to live with this girl from Peru
and one halloween,
it was when I moved to New York,
this was probably 2000.
It was probably 19,
98 and nine.
And uh,
I went in,
we went in to a room at halloween and
she was dressed like a puerto rican,
but she was peruvian and she was like,
she's like all the horrible stereotypes
that you would say would be the things
that lowest common denominator puerto
rican woman to reduce you had all over.
And I was like,
val,
you can't do that.
And she was like,
why not?
It's good.
It's a good costume.
Right?
And I was like,
no,
they're,
those people exist and will be around
them tonight.
Like,
can you imagine someone dress?
One is valerie.
And she was like,
it wouldn't bother me.
I go,
yeah,
because you have a good job and stuff
like this.
Poor person's getting handed by life
every night.
And you're dressing as them culture
appropriation,
cultural.
What did you think about that?
Amy schumer cultural appropriation.
What about it or you didn't?
Did you know about it?
Know what you're talking about?
Her and goldie hawn did a video of them
singing a beyonce song,
but it's,
I guess it's the politicized beyonce
song.
Oh,
okay.
They shot a cover of them doing a
beyonce song.
And fucking the internet went after her
in a hard fucking way.
Amy schumer and who was with her?
Goldie hawn.
Okay.
So they're trying to be funny.
Yeah,
I guess.
I mean it's not very ms dot funny I
guess if you,
if you'd like for if I don't know.
I didn't do audience went after because
beyonce is black.
No.
Yeah.
And the song is about black women.
It's called formation.
Oh.
And it's about,
it's the song she did the super bowl
where she stepped up on the cop car.
And loni love went after her.
When she say she was like,
I don't know,
you can find the loni love clip,
but lonely love starts crying in it.
She's like,
she's like,
yeah,
how dare you take that from us.
This is not your story.
Oh shit.
Yeah.
Hm.
Cultural appropriation is interesting
because I've kind of been guilty of it
my whole life because I love hip hop.
Hmm.
What is.
Isn't that being a hip hop fan?
Like when does it become cultural
appropriation?
When you,
when you cover someone song,
it's cultural appropriation.
Doesn't that sound weird?
I guess if you're pretending that that's
your life that you're talking about,
but clearly she's not right.
She's just having fun singing a song
that beyonce sings because she's a fan,
I guess.
Isn't that the idea?
Yeah.
It looks like they're having fun just
doing it for the fuck of it.
I mean,
I'm looking at this.
I see people being silly.
What are we really getting offended by?
We're getting offended by this.
Wanda sykes is in it.
They
really offended.
I didn't.
Not only did I not care,
I couldn't sit through the video.
Well,
they're just being silly.
Yeah,
I mean,
it looks to me like they're just having
fun.
Who gives a shit?
If people were really upset about that,
like,
come on.
I guess there's.
I don't know.
I don't know,
man.
I think we're finding way too many
things to be upset with lately.
Not anymore.
None of that.
Now that trump is in office,
make all them fucking videos you want.
You know what it is,
man,
this is everybody getting a voice.
Everybody getting a voice.
The world has a voice and they're
looking for things to be upset by and
they see this and they go,
I think this is wrong.
You can't do that,
you know,
and they just decide they're gonna go
after.
You can't take that from us.
Like,
um,
she didn't,
she made her own copy of a video.
She made a parody video.
People do it all the time.
Who gives a fuck?
It's not.
It's like,
it's not like you can't still watch the
beyonce one and by the way,
if you don't like this,
you can make fun of it.
Who gives a fuck?
He's got 2 million downloads.
Good.
But people getting upset by it,
not good or,
or good,
like go ahead and get upset by it,
but it just,
at a certain point in time,
it gets real weird.
You know?
It used to be you could dress like a
cowboy and indian.
You can't do that anymore.
The combo is off.
You can't.
A girl cannot be pocahontas anymore.
If you're a pocahontas,
they'll accuse you of cultural
appropriation.
They used to be a popular halloween
costume.
Do it bitch.
You are not native.
How dare you?
Offensive piece of shit.
You cis gendered white privileged
asshole.
God dang.
Yeah.
When you could dress as a bomb.
You can't do that anymore.
Cultural appropriation of homeless
people.
Yeah.
We're way too sensitive,
but that's how this guy got elected.
That is a big part of it.
Big part of it.
There's a bunch of factors.
It's not one bunch of different reasons.
Got him elected,
but part of it is because we're tired.
People are tired.
My friend matt sent me something that's
so hilarious.
This a real thing that was on tumbler
where someone was talking about cultural
appropriation in terms of learning
languages and that we in,
unless you're chinese,
you shouldn't learn chinese because it's
cultural appropriation.
Really?
Yeah.
Look at this pro tip.
By the way,
anybody who says pro tip is a douche
bag.
Unless you're joking around and you say
pro tip,
and then you say something that's really
stupid.
Pro tip.
Don't learn a language.
If you do not come from the language
barriers,
what the language barrier.
The barrier of the language.
I don't learn french unless you're
french.
Not french.
Don't learn chinese.
If you're not chinese,
don't learn icelandic.
If you're not icelandic.
It just appropriate culture more.
That's fucking ridiculous.
It's hard.
It's awesome because it's so silly.
It's so silly.
I really think that's how guys like
president trump get into office.
Dude,
I'll tell you what,
I obviously I voted for hillary,
but I get angry like the way the guys
who voted for trump must feel the.
I get angry when I see stuff that's just
absurd.
Like there's a video of a doubt you've
seen,
but it's your name's in it,
so I thought you were in it,
so I clicked it and basically as a
social justice warrior,
going to an open mic and doing standup,
but instead of doing standup,
he just keeps repeating.
Your jokes are not funny.
The insults hurled are real.
These are real and it's like.
I think he's got you and jim norton are
in the title of it.
Jim norton,
joe rogan,
social justice,
justice warriors stand up.
And I was like,
I came up in my feed on the side.
I don't know.
So he's just using the stage he's using
out that people shouldn't tell jokes
because they're not funny.
Any joke intended to harm any joke that
has someone else's,
a target is harmful and that any joke
about anything po like racial,
sexual,
um,
any.
I guess that comedy is not funny.
I don't really know.
Did you see the,
you do you know the video too?
Don't even give it any attention.
I'm not going to be talking about.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But it's,
it's.
And I was like,
fucking that.
You get you're in bed and you're like,
then you're sitting upright and you're
like,
this fucking this fucking idiot fucking
guy exists.
Well,
there's people that find things
offensive,
right?
There's some people that don't find
anything offensive.
Some people would find anything
offensive.
And then along the,
there's a bunch of people on the
spectrum.
All of them have their own reasons why
they have a line that they draw and then
they don't like it anymore.
And you're allowed to have a line
anywhere you want.
Man,
if he.
But you,
when you impose that on other people,
that's the only time it becomes a
problem if you think for some reason
that just because some people like a
certain style,
whether it's a style of music or style
of art,
anything comedy is just one thing that
people make,
right?
If some people like that style and you
don't and you get mad at it and then you
start deciding that these jokes are
harming people and these jokes are
damaging people.
Well first of all,
every art form,
whether it's music or whether it's
movies,
every art form is allowed.
This sort of false is we have this
understanding that you've created some
fiction,
right?
We have this understanding that this is
not necessarily the person who's written
this book's exact thoughts on things.
Nor is it the person who makes this
movie who made a fictional movie that's
like,
it's a work of art,
right?
They've created these scenarios.
These people didn't really die.
No,
nothing really happened in that.
But in comedy for some reason you can't
say something ridiculously offensive.
Fulling knowing that,
you know,
in the audience knows you don't believe
it,
but when you do do it,
it's really funny.
Yeah.
So there's that weird thing where you'll
do something really funny,
that super offensive,
like your karate kid joke.
Really funny.
What was it about a mr miyagi?
Oh yeah.
I don't want to give it away,
but uh,
I don't care.
I'll tell them.
Okay.
You can.
Uh,
uh,
I was wondering if you think that at
some point a danielson's mom would be
like,
I think the janitor is trying to fuck my
kid.
It's true,
right?
I forgot about that tote.
It's funny and it's offensive.
Maybe that's not a good example because
that's actually logical joke.
But there's a lot,
right?
It's a logical,
totally logical,
but there's many times we say something
that's completely ridiculous.
He don't meet at all and you only say it
because it's a funny thing to say.
Yeah.
And you know,
to take that and to extract it and to
say that that's like a hate crime when
you know,
you know that that person just fucking
around like,
do you remember when tracy morgan got in
trouble?
Because it said if his son was gay,
stab them.
People get so fucking mad.
What's interesting is that there must've
been a few people that believed him.
He's so crazy though.
Tracy is always crazy.
I only met him once.
He's a madman and that crazy.
I've only met him one fucking time.
One story.
One time.
That's a great story though.
I can't wait time.
I,
I hope to run into them again.
I know he's heard the story and he
didn't like it and he was like never
happened,
but I can't wait to run into him.
Tony woods.
Tony woods got a couple people.
Ended up telling my story,
a couple,
like a number of people and already
worked with the guy was telling it and
saying that it happened to him as I
guess as what happened when it goes into
the ethos and tony was got fucking
pissed because tony was.
Tony woods was there the whole night and
tony's like,
that's our story.
I was like,
yeah,
I know.
He was like,
that's bullshit.
No one takes our story.
Burt and I was like,
yeah,
I don't know.
I'm sorry.
That's how that works,
I guess.
Yeah.
Wait a minute.
How can it be yours?
So he didn't want you talking about it
because he was talking about it.
No,
no,
no.
Tony was just like,
it's other people telling them what
something that happened to me in you.
How can that,
how can that be?
Right.
But you were there.
No.
Yeah.
Right.
So it happened to you too.
No,
no,
no.
He was saying that other people were
telling the tracy morgan story.
Oh,
other people,
other than you and me and him and tony
called that other thing.
Yeah,
he texted me and what was the number of
people who already worked with a guy in
Australia told it?
Um,
it just became something that people are
like,
well,
it's already been stolen.
What was just all take it.
That's hilarious.
Yeah.
And tony who was like really upset
because he came late to it,
you know,
tony and listen to podcasts.
He does his own fucking thing and he
just called me one time.
He's like,
yo,
sugar bear,
I'm in Australia,
the fuck are these people telling our
story for.
And I was like,
ah,
sorry,
tony,
just,
yeah,
I guess that happens who's in Australia?
And they were telling someone in
Australia told it and told he was in
Australia and he heard it.
Tony,
one of the greatest moments.
It like,
like we had last night I was in dc and
tony woods came in.
Tony lives in dc and for these you don't
know,
tony is one of the greatest comics.
Hilarious guy,
hilarious guy.
Very slow,
like meticulous,
like old school player.
And so tony comes in and in the back of
the room he's like,
hey,
why don't you tell that tracy morgan's
story?
And I was like,
is that tony woods?
My wife is there,
right?
And I go,
tony.
And he goes,
yeah,
I want to hear what it sounds like.
So I go,
why don't you come on stage and tell it
with me?
So he comes up on stage,
we have two mikes and I tell my side of
the story and he corrects me because you
know how everyone's got their side of
the story.
And like I remember it man.
I remember it very vividly that I was a
pastor by like I was just hanging on and
I was there for this story.
I didn't really do anything.
And tony's like,
that is not how that happened.
He was like,
you.
And then he said it.
He goes,
do you really think the.
He's like,
the reason he took his shirt off just
because you took your shirt off.
And I was like,
there's no fucking way he told you.
Remember,
is it totally different?
The only thing we agree on is the very
end of the story where when he said
that's how you get out of pain and
check,
that's the only thing we agree on.
Wow.
Yeah.
It's interesting how two people can
share an experience and it's being.
It'd be very similar in like the places
like we went to.
Madame sets the bar,
we were at [inaudible] and I told tony,
I was like started telling on stage.
Well,
the human memory super flawed.
Yeah,
it's really flawed.
They find that more and more that when
they're checking out crimes in
particular that a human experience like
memory is like one of the worst pieces
of evidence that you could ever have.
Neil degrasse tyson was talking about
it,
was tHat it's like the difference
between
an actual reality and how people
remember it.
It's sometimes significantly different.
Your brain just puts together a
narrative and sticks with it and then
you know,
if something weird happened to crazy
happen,
sometimes you're all jacked up on
adrenaline and your brain just create
some goofy ass scenario and then that
becomes your memory.
That becomes your realIty.
How weird,
dude,
we're so malleable.
Isn't that crazy?
Yeah.
Well hell,
you ever think of like manchurian
candidate type shit like that.
The idea that they could trick you by
putting a word in your head and if
someone says that work you fucking snap
and you turn it into an assassin was
pavlovian
it,
it's got to be connected to tableau.
Vion because.
Because when my wife's alarm goes off on
her phone at 5:45,
priscilla wakes up,
facility,
gets up and starts wagging her tail and
stands by the fridge.
She's ready to eat.
She heard leanne's alarm go off and she
goes,
now we eat.
This is how it.
And it's almost,
it's got to be similar,
but there are things you could say to
put me into a mood.
Yeah.
Like,
uh,
like,
I mean immediately when you were like,
this sounds.
This is gonna sound silly about to get
to the.
When I said I'm going to grab a beer and
you're like,
grabbed me one that makes my heart race.
I go our again.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I'm not doing it by myself.
I've got a partner obviously.
I like like certain things like that.
Those are pavlovian responses.
So give me.
You're like,
you want to get high?
I get excited.
I went,
oh yeah.
I would love to get out of that.
Like when,
like when stan hope when I see when my
phone rings and it's stan hope I get,
I get excited because I go,
it's one of the very few calls I don't,
I don't send to voicemail and I,
but even the voicemails or 10 million
times fucking better.
He gave me a fucking voicemail that I
want to play.
It's so good.
And,
and then sometimes you get one from him
and Johnny depp and you're like fucking
standups.
His fucking phone calls are the best.
So I see us or joey diaz is phone calls
because you know joey's d as a phone
call is going to take 16 seconds.
What's up?
What's up,
tarzan.
And then you fucking get back to me.
Caughlin.
Yeah.
Alright.
I love you brother.
I'll talk to you later.
Yeah.
Now we're lucky man.
He knows some weird people.
Are you nervous about the future?
Now that donald trump's president,
do you feel any differently because it
went down,
what did it went down?
It went down,
it went down.
Donald trump won the shit went down.
I was joking on stage this weekend
saying that it can't be that bad for me
as a white guy.
Like that's the truth is that he's not,
he's got my interest protected.
Like he's a white guy too.
he's not going to start out long white
guys and his son's a white guy and it's.
And it's going to be tax breaks for
people to make money,
you know.
But I just,
I just,
I just don't like,
like,
I like this.
Once again,
this will sound bad,
but I'm in my backyard.
I'm doing a press tour this morning in
every market,
you know,
everybody knows radio,
satellite tours and uh,
the guys that are building my house,
we're all mexican and I saw them come to
work and I thought,
man,
that sucks that,
that what he said about mexicans,
America,
America stood behind a tad bit.
And because these guys aren't rapists
and murderers were the coolest guys in
the world that are fucking killing
themselves so that I can have a better
life and they're doing it at wages that
quite honestly are affordable,
only [inaudible] their fear of losing
their stability in this country.
So they don't argue with standards.
That's kind of how immigrant labor works
a tad bit is they don't have,
they don't have an uh,
an uh,
a way out.
And I thought that really fucking sucks.
And I saw it for the first time that way
and I was Like,
these are all really cool dudes.
And it stinks.
That last night they saw that and they
were like,
we lost.
And maybe they didn't see it.
I don't fucking know.
No,
a lot of them did.
I know some mexican folks that were
pretty upset.
And here I am,
you know,
on the,
on,
on the winning team,
regardless,
like again,
I'm going to win.
Whoever wins.
If hillary wins,
I'm a liberal.
I want everyone for good things.
I win.
If Donald Trump wins,
I'm in that camp too.
I when their [inaudible] you know,
so you're a winner,
burke,
I'm the luckiest guy in the fucking
world.
[inaudible] the whole mexican thing is
very strange because it's real.
This is why it's really racist.
It's not like you're dealing with an
exorbitant percentage difference in the
amount of people that are of mexican
descent,
the commit crimes versus the amount of
people that are american born that he
didn't commit crimes.
Right.
We both agree on that.
It's probably not much difference at
all,
but when someone comes here from another
country and commits a crime,
we look at it far worse than if someone
who is born,
this patch of soil commits a crime.
You know,
we decide that that's a big deal.
We decided that it's a bigger deal when
someone from over there comes over here
illegally and commits a crime,
even if it's like the same percentage as
just people,
you know,
if you get like 20 percent of the people
commit crimes,
no matter,
no matter what are immigrant or
whatever,
you'll look at the immigrant ones as
being more significant because they
didn't even fuck it's supposed to be
here and they're doing those crimes.
It's sliding doors.
What if that person that just never come
here,
that's all
got it.
But it's probably a percentage of the
population no matter what.
And then it also depends upon what does
that person experienced.
Like if they're coming from the Congo or
some crazy fucking place.
I remember my friend went to high school
with some kid,
I want to say the kid was from Jamaica.
I'm pretty sure he's from Jamaica and
uh,
apparently he was a super violent kid.
This is first time the United States and
he got with a fight and a fight with
some boy.
He went out to his car and he got a
fucking giant kitchen knife and he
stabbed that kid right through the
stomach in front of everybody and
everybody for any cuts.
Some other kid,
the other kid ran away and he's chasing
him with a knife trying to cut.
Holy shit.
Yeah,
and this is his first days in America.
They just lead them into this school and
this kid went into his fucking trunk and
pulled out a knife and I guess that's
how he rocked it in Jamaica and that was
what he had been exposed to.
So they're that kind of situation.
If you're letting someone into a place
legally or illegally,
illegally.
I don't know how he got in.
I don't know the details of the storage,
know the story,
but then people are scared because
they're like,
oh,
this person's been living in the Congo.
Say or so,
what is the xenophobia?
Then based on the fact that they don't
subscribe to the same cultural rules,
we subscribe to that.
You can say that xenophobic or you can
say that you're very conservative and
nationalistic and you could look at it
as a proud traits.
I mean it's a real touch and go issue,
especially right now because what's
going on in Germany and a lot of parts
of europe where these syrian refugees
are coming in and they've opened their
arms to them in Germany and it's kind of
like really out of control.
Like germany's had some horrible
assaults and rapes and groups of men
that are actively targeting white blonde
women for rape.
Well,
that's the truth and I won't say any
place,
but there are places in this world where
the social norm of rape is.
Rape is a social norm.
Yeah.
Women just get raped and they believe
that's just what happens because there
were women and there's a lot of those
people.
There's a lot of those places.
A lot of those people too.
There's the.
The sheer numbers of humans that
subscribed to that kind of thinking
still in 2016 would shock you if you
could just look at it as numbers on a
board.
If you just looked at the worldwide
population and how many people would
accept something like that,
you'd be like,
whoa,
yeah,
we're just getting rid of beating a
child right now.
Adrian peterson did it and everyone
fucking attacked him and I'm sure he was
like,
I just hit him with a switch.
It was pretty brutal,
but now.
But there are places where in this
country where you could totally hit a
child,
no one would say anything,
and then there are places in the world
where you can hit someone and no one
would say anything.
Yeah,
and that's where it's enough.
That's part of like if you tried to
dissect xenophobia,
maybe it's that is that you go there.
Social norm is different than my social
norm and I don't want people.
I mean is that,
that sounds like I'm defending
xenophobia.
Well,
I have a theory that I've said several
times in the podcast.
Excuse me if you've heard it.
That's the cradle of civilization.
If you go to the middle east,
that's where civilization began.
It's the oldest written language,
the oldest form of mathematics,
like sumir,
like that's responsible for all these
different first first agriculture.
Like they,
they were like a really depending upon
when you think that human human
civilization was established,
whether it was reestablished,
but those people back then that,
that was a,
a really complicated civilization and it
was like 6,000
years ago.
Yeah,
I mean
we,
when we try to think about like how long
human beings have been on this planet
and how long we been living our lives
and what we've been doing.
This is a really,
really recent thing.
Very do think about this.
Slavery was just 200 years ago.
Yup.
18,
black people just got rights as humans
in the sixties that,
that's.
So like,
I like one of the things I watched roots
and one of the things that blew me away
was that,
uh,
what's it called when black people talk
like black people?
It was a robotics.
I remember when a bonox came out and
people,
conservatives were fucking up and arms,
hey,
learn the language,
speak the way we speak.
And then I thought,
hey motherfucker,
when we brought them here,
we didn't teach him how to speak at all
when when they were brought as slaves,
it was better.
Yeah,
they didn't speak english.
But you know what the problem with that
kind of thinking is on both sides.
Problem kind of thing is.
First of all,
you didn't bring any slaves over here.
I didn't bring anybody.
They weren't slaves.
So both things are fucked up,
but their ancestors were.
So we're acknowledging there's a ripple.
There's a giant ripple effect from being
brought over here as slaves.
That to me says that like what we should
have done and what we probably still
should do is figure out a way and not
just that ripple,
but the poor immigration ripple that's
in white neighborhoods,
russian neighborhoods.
You got to figure out a way to like get
neighborhoods that are like really
fucking poor.
Those are traps,
especially if their crime ridden
neighborhoods that are really poor.
We've got to clean those up,
have cuts that we just let scab up and
fester and we don't treat it and dress
the wound like that's kind of dangerous.
Crime ridden neighborhoods are there
like cultural wounds and we don't.
We don't do shit about him because it's
not us.
It's us.
It's can't fucking pay attention to
that.
But if presidents did that,
instead of fucking flying over to
Afghanistan and dealing with some
nonsense,
that has almost nothing to do with you
and me.
If you could make an argument that we
can intervene in Mexico right now,
if you.
If you really wanted to protect peace
and love.
I mean every time you go to juarez and
you see a bunch of dudes heads cut off
and they're hanging them from fucking
overpass with some sign,
they put some cops,
chop them up in garbage bags.
You know this,
this,
you know,
there's a good argument that you.
All the drugs are coming from these
people too.
It's a good argument.
You go to the war with them.
They never even bring that up,
that up.
Never.
It's right there.
God dang it.
You know what fucking sent me through
the roof and this election is the media
coverage.
The one of the things that I was I was
watching like I was laying in bed with
yesterday and I was just kind of
listening to the thing and they were.
There were saying statements like,
well,
Florida is definitely going to vote.
A torta is definitely going to vote
democratic because of the hispanic
population.
How rude.
I thought,
what I thought,
what an ignorant statement to assume
cubans and mexicans are identical,
stupid.
He didn't say I'm cubans are that he
said mexicans and I,
from my experience,
and this is limited,
but I did grow up in Florida and I do
live in la and that's where these the
differences.
Cubans will speak spanish in front of
you.
Mexicans don't speak spanish in front of
When you hang out with like two
mexicans,
you're standing in like say you're at
like in line or something.
Mexican is usually just try to
assimilate so they don't raise the red
flag.
It's all based on the fact that as a
cuban,
if you come over to this country,
if you step foot on the land,
you're automatically a citizen as a
mexican.
They don't want you here.
They want to send you back.
Is that the case still?
So if you're a cuban refugee and you
land in America,
the second you step foot,
you're,
you're naturalized citizen.
Oh,
weird.
And that is the bone of contention
between cubans and mexicans.
Is that.
And that's why cubans,
when you go to miami to cuban guys will
speak spanish right in front of you,
right in front of your face and you're
just like,
oh,
you guys talking about me or.
Well,
Cuba also,
cubans rather,
they tend to be more conservative.
Yeah.
Much more conservative vote.
Very republican,
very conservative.
Uh,
sort of having said that,
a lot of miami did vote democrat,
I think,
but I think that's predominantly the
jewish population,
the snowbirds that came down because it
started in like broward county and what
went down.
Yeah.
But I mean,
but I grew up in Florida.
Cubans were,
eh,
there's no,
there's no limit to just miami.
Yeah,
now all my best friends are cuban.
Did Cuba has an interesting kind of a
flair to it,
right?
Because it's got a different thing than
say Mexico.
Like you think like their,
their language has a little bit more of
a,
like a song type of thing to.
It took a little more flow to it,
you know,
they're all dancy and movie and shit and
they have incredible athletes.
Fucking incredible.
After you fucking write about that.
Like if you like,
if you were going to do a dance of the
two languages,
that's going to be like more like,
oh,
what cubans.
Like.
Oh wow.
Yeah,
they have a quicker sort of a.
There's a flare to those people.
Can we used to say words like cuban
phrases,
like a most lhasa or get bottle sits on
the mexicans out though is like how gay
kipato like a duck.
Are you allowed to say tHat still or is
that.
You can say it in spanish.
Oh yeah.
You're not racist if you're saying in
spanish.
Racist.
I said money on the,
on the,
on the radio the other day.
What is Monaco and again,
gay guy?
You can say that.
I guess.
I don't know.
We'll see if it come back to haunt you.
LEt's.
Let's run the gamut.
I'll say gypsy pikey and muddy going and
see if I get in trouble.
Pikeys still touchy if you're in
england.
Yeah.
I have a friend who lives in england and
their neighbor,
their friend actually lives also in
england,
had a bunch of pikeys moving next door
to them.
Oh,
they've told her the caravan.
They pulled up the caravan and they just
decided to live in this neighborhood and
then they,
uh,
there's an open lot.
So thEy pulled into this open loud the
caravan.
They stay up to 2:00
in the morning.
They started having parties and started
robbing the neighborhood.
And these fucking people have these bomb
ass country houses outside of london and
they're just living the dream,
you know,
they make this dope ass.
They make this dope ass house in this
beautiful countryside.
And the pikeys moving right next door.
I don't know if,
is that a bad word?
Pikey travelers.
I think they prefer to call themselves
so I'll be respectful so they.
The is move in.
they pull up the caravans which are
mobile homes.
They leave garbage everywhere,
they fucking steal shit and they can't
get rid of them.
They can't get them out of there because
there have,
because of their culture,
their culture is that they travel around
and so the european government or the uk
government has established there's
certain like things that they're allowed
to do and one of them is they're allowed
to just like live in a place where
nobody lives there so arbitrary within
reason.
I mean should they have like boundaries
where you're not supposed to go,
but next to this guy's fucking house,
they were allowed to lick and lose my
mind.
This guy's like this really wealthy guy
that bought this insane house out in the
london countryside and travelers moved
in right next door and they party all
night.
They have bonfires and shit.
Oh,
fucking bonfire.
They beat guys asses if they talk shit
to him,
you know,
maybe this isn't a good place to have a
fire at 2:00
in the morning.
They step up,
punch that dude in the face and laugh,
oh,
nobody can do shit.
They live at different world.
They live in a totally different life
than you or I,
but there are people.
People were just so malleable,
man.
That's what I was getting at before.
That's why one of the things that
concerns me about trump is that the
president becomes sort of the way the
people that follow him,
he leads the way they,
they sort of fall in and least in some
way he represents how we feel about
ourselves.
So if we feel about ourselves like a
really,
you know,
the wall just got 10 feet higher,
that kind of stuff that could encourage
some ridiculous douche baggery from
people that might otherwise be persuaded
to,
to relax and settle in.
Like people might go the other way now.
What do you mean?
People might get more aggressive and
more shitty now that trump is in office?
Oh dude,
I got.
I got to be really honest with you.
Trumping elected gave me a lot of
confidence.
Why?
I don't know.
I don't know because I just was like,
I just never thought that would happen.
Like I never thought that it happened.
Then I thought,
oh,
that's right.
Crazy shit happens all the time.
Like crazy shit happens all the time.
All the time.
Like,
no,
I'm not saying I want to be a movie
star,
but like I could be a movie star
tomorrow.
Like someone could go a couple of weeks
but I'll take a couple of weeks,
maybe take seven months.
But,
but like that could happen tomorrow.
I can have my own sitcom if I wanted it
tomorrow because that could happen
because trump became president and I got
real bounce in my step.
Wow.
It was.
Anything's possible.
Anything's fucking.
I really thought there was no fucking
way in hell that would ever happen.
I mean I almost thought last night was a
wash and I don't know why we're even
referencing the election and then all
the sudden bill burrs,
like they just took fucking Ohio.
Yeah.
It was like,
like a war.
Like you took Pennsylvania.
He took Florida.
Yeah.
There are still undecided in New
Hampshire.
Took Idaho.
What they saying that it was kind of
down to Alaska and when he got Alaska is
when someone said he just one boom,
they go,
he just got Alaska,
he won and that's the state that nobody
campaigns.
And that's what's interesting.
No one campaigns in Alaska.
Well I don't.
Maybe they do,
but I think for the most part they
ignore it because that's the last date
where you get the results in last.
It's way the fuck over there.
You know if you're looking at a map or
Alaska is.
Yeah,
you gotta go all the way up and then he
got to go left.
It's all the way the fuck up by Russia.
Way up there,
dude.
Have you gone hunting up there?
Yes,
dude.
It's amazing.
Except the bugs.
The bugs are brutal.
The mosquitoes are off the chain,
but nothing like in your life you can't
even breathe because they go in your
mouth.
Yeah,
they are.
And I went fishing.
We went salmon fishing uP there.
We did some gigs and we got out of the
car to get to the boat and when we got
out of the car,
literally opening the door,
there was a cloud of mosquitoes that
found us instantly in swarmed us.
WE panicked like little girls jumped
back in the car and shut the door.
We started to change our shoes while
we're in the car and there was 100
mosquitoes in the car with us.
It was the huggins.
Same.
They only have like a couple months to
live.
Yeah,
and they all come out in droves,
but I'll tell you what I like,
dude.
I like alaskan people a lot alike.
hazing.
I like,
uh,
people in anchorage a lot.
I liked the people at bars.
I like people that you met.
There's a certain feeling that they
have.
They're more alive because they have to
deal with nature.
deal with grizzly bears.
When we were there at grizzly bear
stumbled into some fucking school there.
The grizzly bear is walking the outside
perimeter of some school.
They were talking about it or they had a
fucking chase it off like what a giant
one,
like a big 10 foot grizzly bear was
wandering through some backyard area.
Moose walk onto college campuses all the
time.
When I came in and when I landed in
anchorage,
I got into the car from the.
I got in the car from the airport to the
hotel at a moose crossing the street on
the way to the hotel,
jesus by the airport.
It was by the airport and I went.
I freaked out.
I was Like,
are you shitting me?
And he was like,
yeah,
it happens all the time,
man.
You got to be real careful if you're
running a moose when it's running.
Like now when it gets cold out,
like right around late october,
probably mid,
mid,
late october.
But they get horny as fuck and they get
super aggressive and they'd get so
stupid like their dick is so hard and
they're so fucked up.
Imagine if You could only have sex once
a year.
Just imagine being a person.
You can only have sex once a year and
when you start getting towards that time
of the year,
you start growing weapons on your head.
You said that you said that on the
podcast,
so they don't always have horns.
No.
The antlers fall off.
These antlers are act.
We actually looked it up this weekend.
They're made out of bone there.
I heard this pop.
What did you do this with?
Dudley?
John Dudley
and I was a fascinating podcast.
Which has happened.
What happened to him?
What happened?
Did we go down?
Oh,
they just like light flicker or
something like that.
We gotta get the fuck out of here,
man.
Fucking trump,
Now that trump's in order,
he's going to hurt me making fun of his
hair.
I want to get to things to trump a razor
like one of those electric air buzzers
and a bag of mushrooms.
That's all I need from you,
buddy.
You're raising my taxes.
Just let me see thIs bag and do this to
your hair.
Would love to fuck with this hair.
Just shave it off,
man.
Let it go.
That's not nothing good going on up
there.
Good tweets today though.
Diddy?
No,
no,
no.
A comic's comics.
Oh,
would they say?
Yeah.
The ones that weren't too butthurt about
it with.
There's a lot of butter to it was so
ridiculous.
Like,
come on,
let it,
let it play out.
Let's see what this says.
Yeah.
Like friends of mine who I go,
I know we're funny.
We're just like,
like just saying,
just like really not even like trying to
be funny about it.
Like this isn't funny.
There's nothing funny about it.
You need to have a serious conversation
with your children about racism and rape
and you're like,
huh,
okay.
Well what about hillary clinton?
Then said,
whoa,
you want her in office?
Hillary clinton,
defendant a child rapist.
It was laughing about the child rapist
being able to pass a polygraph.
Do you remember when we were wIth norm
in the back of the comedy store and he
was talking about bill clinton's
charges.
I looked those up.
Yeah,
those are fucking legit.
Yeah.
There's a lot of stuff with.
I mean,
who knows how much of it is real.
They allegedly did a lot of shit and
allegedly,
you know what man,
who knows,
but not good.
None of it's good.
It's all gross.
So it's not like if Donald Trump didn't
get in,
we will hear out an angel,
you know,
anyone of that age set that's a weird
age bracket because like I'm the age,
I'm the generation where when I got to
college they came up with the phrase no
means no.
Just they explained date rape at my age.
I'm 44.
So you think anyone over 40 for any
woman over 44 probably dealt with date
rape and,
and,
and a lot of times there was a like a
stigma do not talk about it,
you know?
Yeah man.
And,
and,
and I'm just saying I'm the very
beginning.
There's a whole generation of girls my
age and just younger that have dealt
with it in the same way,
but now it's being brought to the
forefront and people are coming forward
and saying stuff.
Donald trump is what 70 did he,
I mean he,
I think he could hit women when he was a
kid probably.
They probably hit women,
they didn't think anything of it.
His dad throw his mom,
mom down a flight of stairs and no one
would say a fucking word.
The stairs is rough.
Yeah.
Maybe you're on the couch.
just thrown on the couch.
Just get off me.
Get off me.
Can you throw them somewhere nice and
soft and like you don't.
You decelerate when you let go.
Just like a light judo demonstration.
If you dated a judo check dated
ronda rousey and she just got mad at you
and start fucking hip,
toss it around the house right to the
coffee table,
right to the glass coffee table.
Like one of those lethal weapon movies.
Just fucking.
She is.
Grabs you and hip tosses.
You do.
We're in the front yard.
The sprinklers are going off the exact.
That lethal weapon.
He used the [inaudible] triangle choke.
That was the first time we ever saw a
triangle choke in a movie ever.
Mel gibson lethal weapon.
He played that crazy guy and he learned
from horian.
He learned jiu jitSu from horian gracie.
Really?
Yeah.
Horian gracie was the stunt coordinator
for that movie and he helped,
um,
that,
that movie sorta helped get him in with
a lot of hollywood people that wanted to
learn jujitsu.
I realized how effective they love to
party with mel gibson.
Oh man.
Just get them drunk and start talking
about jews.
JusT wind them up.
Yeah.
Just wind them up just to show what it
was.
Jews and money,
man.
Man,
I don't get it.
It's like lighting a bomb and walkIng
away.
It's funny,
man,
because he's a brilliant director.
He's giving them,
giving them another chance.
Oh,
here it is.
Is that gary busey?
Yeah,
it's gary bc.
He was on top.
It was gary busey.
Shitty jujitsu.
There's a lot of space there.
Boys.
He goes for the arm bar for terrible
guard.
Terrible guard,
and he gets punched a little bit here,
a little bit of ground and pound.
This is the.
Watch this.
Oh my god.
He goes to the triangle.
He grabs it,
secures it.
Let me see how he handles this here.
Gary boosie should just bite his dick
are no rules here.
I'll give this a terrible goddamn
triangle.
He doesn't even secure it underneath the
knee.
That'd be great if he was just kept the
crowd like nate diaz.
He makes mistake number one and
triangles.
He,
he Went with the calf over,
uh,
the,
the instep.
Touch the calf instead of go totally
behind the knee.
It's just not awkward to know better.
I can do a better trial.
he pushed,
he choked him to sleep.
No tap.
What happened there?
This is bullshit.
What is this?
That was it.
Let's go back again.
I believe it's come back again.
Now here's what you want to do.
You want to get an angle and then you
want to make sure that this insteps
underneath your neat.
That way it's locked in place.
He can't get out of that.
See,
watch,
watch.
Go before that.
See,
watch.
He throws the leg up.
See,
this is all sloppy shit.
He grabs a hold of his shin,
but what he's supposed to do for real,
grab a hold of his right foot.
Pull his right foot down until it locks
underneath his left leg.
See how it's all fucking loose and
sloppy fitch.
Nobody's getting stuck in that triangle.
Let's just hop right out of that posture
up and beat your fucking ass.
Now you're on the bottom.
Stupid.
If you have a jew,
if you have a triangle,
you got to do it right.
I don't know how and let him get away
with that.
They should have made them tighten that
up.
What is it a.
Is it a possibility that it's just a
weight class differences?
No,
no,
no.
It'S just a.
It's just a move.
It's like you do it right or you do it
wrong.
When you do a triangle and you got
somebody locked up,
right?
If you've got someone's arm in here,
if you do this,
you don't have any leverage.
You have no leverage,
but here,
mother fucker.
Where we going?
I wouldn't fit in there where you would
fit in there,
motherfucker.
I'll put you in there.
I'll squeeze you to sleep.
It's not a matter of when you're going
to fit.
I'm going to make you fit.
I'll fit you in there for sure.
I'll fit you in there.
And if someone like the bigger longer
legs day have fucking fit you in there
heart,
there's some horrible people to get
stuck in.
Their guard I think was a big.
This is my friend brian,
we should call him beast and brian has
he,
he's a big strong fucking do,
did a lot of kettlebells and shaves
about probably in the two twenties or
something like that or real athletic
dude.
And he waS all legs and this
motherfucker,
if you got in his guard,
it was just.
She's being constricted with giant bones
and huge muscles.
Just locked triangles in place.
So if you ever rolled with that guy,
you needed to stay the fuck away from
his guard because he's just all legs and
power.
Like the amount of strength that you
have in your legs.
Like people don't even recognize it,
but you don't.
You don't.
Unless you have rolled with someone who
has developed their leg muscles and the
dexterity to pull up jujitsu moves her
legs.
Like there's certain guys that get to a
point where they get really,
really good at that.
WHen you rolled with them,
you realize how much you take your legS
and you run upstairs to think of that.
You take your legs.
You could have a a package in your hand
and you could run up the stairs.
You're throwing your body like
plyometrics up these stairs.
You can't do that with your arms,
but you're so confident choking someone
with your arm.
Oh,
that's totally fucking true.
Your legs are always.
You always take advantage of your feet.
They're always working.
they're think you're,
you're carrying
yourself.
Everywhere you go,
your bodies carrying whatever it is from
your waist up.
You're carrying 100 plus whatever the
fuck it is,
pounds.
You know That's what your upper body is,
right?
Your legs are constantly getting word
out.
Like if you think about like joey diaz
or here's even better,
ralphie may,
you're not fucking strong.
RalphIe may's legs must be
fucking insane.
He has giant ass leg muscles.
Oh yeah,
he must.
Do you ever see a,
you know.
Oh,
I hear there's a comic.
He was good friends with daniel tosh and
he used to be overweight and uh,
and we were doing a voiceover thing and
I end,
he lost like 200 pounds,
but his calves were fucking yoked and
we're doing a voiceover that kept saying
his name is eddie eddie.
He's married to megan malanie.
Um,
he,
he's anyways,
casual yoga and um,
I kept going and we're in the voiceover
booth and tosh is listening to us do
voiceover and I kept going,
man,
your calves are huge.
He's a guy.
Yeah,
he'll know they're fucking.
Those are ridiculous.
I've never seen cows like that in my
life.
He's like,
he's like,
yeah,
I know.
Like a big house.
I go,
no,
I don't think you understand.
You have the biggest cat I'm looking at.
Tosh is in a sound booth laughing
hysterically and go,
you really
should enter a calf contest.
Those are the biggest calves.
And taj gives on the thing.
It was bert.
He used to be 380 pounds.
That's why he's got big calves.
And I was like,
oh,
this is uncomfortable.
That's a very good impression.
I felt tosh doing that.
His inflection sounds like the real guy.
Yeah,
but you could,
you know,
if you have the flexibility and the
dexterity,
you could do so much with your legs,
your legs control.
Like marcello garcia was one of the
greatest jujitsu players of all time.
I did not have a big upper body,
but he had these giant ass fucking legs
and he would squeeze the shit out of
dudes and control them with his legs.
That was a big part of his jujitsu game.
Was controlling your body legs.
I bet you would.
I used to.
I used to be able to,
um,
I used to be able to squeeze my legs on
when you'd wrestle with friends I can
get them in where I put my legs around
their waist and I remember my buddy came
in would be like,
oh shit.
My parents.
Oh yeah,
I'm going to take that too far.
Yeah.
Maybe that guy was going to shit.
Anyway.
I'm going to use this excuse to arrest
with pro wrestling with and just shit
myself.
Not some of the weird shit you did with
your friends.
Read nani's.
So
I have my friend paulie,
he whacked a stick against a tree,
you know,
kids are always doing shit like that and
the stick broke and it went to flip to
the air and hit my eye brow.
I can cut the shit out of my eye brow,
but like it was a half an inch from my
eyeball.
It was like the pointy part of this
stick that snapped off,
fd whacked against a tree,
went whipping through the air and I
think about that all the time.
I could have been blind.
yeah,
I could have been blinded and at one
dumb move in the woods.
My friend who was an 88,
he just wanted to hit a tree with a
stick.
Smacked me with this day.
Easily went blind from that.
I thought about that all the time.
Like that one fucking moment at one
moment.
Like if I just went like that,
if I just ducked a little or a raised up
a little rather just that's all I have
to do is raise up a little.
And would it went from here to here?
I'll have to do is move.
Oh,
that's terrifying.
Yeah,
I didn't see it coming.
Swat we used,
we used to put a hose up our ass and
shoot water at our out of our assholes
that each other.
Oh,
not good.
It's so not good.
Die from that.
We used to do it all the time.
kolai blown in each other's faces.
We'd go into each in new smyrna and you
get out of the from surfing and he'd
shoot the hose,
water up your ass and give yourself an
enema and then just shit on each other.
Burke caden was here right now.
Meet came in now and reagan used to shit
on each other.
Oh my god.
You do it when they weren't looking like
you'd do it to hold it in this bird to
enough and I'm not even looking.
I hear,
I heard a buckle.
You just hold it in there and then you
turn around and shit.
What the fuck man?
What the fuck are you talking about?
It was
Florida.
Jesus.
Everything is Florida.
It goes back to Florida,
but you guys did produce leonard
skinner.
No.
Fuck.
He did explain that.
Produce the greatest.
One of the greatest bands of all time,
give me three steps,
is an amazing fucking saul.
How about curtis lowe,
the ballot of curtis lowe song people
don't even talk about.
And you know what's even bigger is if
you grew up in Florida,
you remember that distinct.
I'm sure you they did is all over the
place,
but I distinctly remember bringing.
You could get a,
a metal metal or glass bottles if they
were worth ten cents each and I'm
bringing them back down to the circle,
k by my house.
and you walked down with like 10 glass
bottles on your fingers and walked down
to circle k get them in and you buy
candy that way.
Wow.
That's a.
He has about collecting old bottles and
bring them down.
So on it.
And I was like,
fuck man,
I did that shit.
Wow,
that's a great song man.
Really?
I got into that song once,
like three years ago.
You know,
you like sometimes you go on a trip and
for whatever reason,
you know,
like you're sitting on the beach or
something like that.
Relax and listen to your iphone.
Uh,
you know,
listening to music or something and you
had this one song that just resonates
with the moment.
For me,
it was that bow bow to curtis lowe.
I was in Hawaii.
I've listened to that song like 30 times
over the weekend.
Do such a good song.
You know,
this is a list is a little bit of a
stretch,
but I went through a period a couple
years ago where I'd all,
I'd listened to nxs wow.
What a great.
An excess if you haven't played them in
a while when you listened to.
Yeah.
I'm telling you that album that if you
get their best nxs it is such a great.
Yeah,
that kinda choked himself out,
jerking off.
That's how he died.
It's got to be,
feel good.
It can't feel that good and people were
dying for it.
It's got to feel good.
They just fucked up people just like
weird shit.
I watched the movie of them.
There's a movie of them that,
uh,
that was on a,
I forget what it's called,
but it was really great movie and I just
got onto this nxs phase.
I was riding motorcycles a lot at the
time and I was listening to nxs
motorcycle riding all the time.
Wow.
I would want to hear what the fuck is
going on around Me?
No,
I put it in noise reduction headsets.
These little ultiMAte ears plugged them
in and you're.
You're on the highway.
You can't hear anything anyway.
It's so fucking windy.
Oh,
okAy.
Biggest when you ride motorcycles,
all.
You got to be as tuned in just yet.
It's amazing how hypersensitive you are
to every other driver.
Doesn't have to be.
When you see those guys zipping in
between lanes,
which is a weird thing to be legal.
Does that freak you out?
Yeah,
because I've ridden motorcycles.
I'm very respectful.
If I see them,
I give them space.
He too.
I moved right over when I see them,
but sometimes you don't see him like you
hear you hear harley's,
which is real good,
but there's some of those smaller bikes,
like they're just there.
All the sudden you're like,
I didn't even see.
Especially if you listen to shit loud in
your car,
you know,
if you're fucking jamming
to the led zepplin immigrant song dot.
That's what I listened to when I get in
the cryo tank.
Really?
Yeah.
Come from the land of the license now
would've been like,
what about good times?
Bad times.
At the beginning of that song is one of
the best beginnings of a song ever.
Bill burke calls me up one day and he
goes,
you're not going to fucking believe it.
He goes,
led zepplin stole that music.
I went and listened to it.
It's heartbreaking.
It's heartbreaking if fucking thieves.
Dude,
I didn't want to believe it.
It's one of those things.
I was like,
no,
honey,
I didn't even want to listen.
And once I listened and I go,
come on.
Really?
And then I called them.
I really do like,
I can't believe I've added it.
So he called left a message with
spectrum people.
Left voicemail messages.
Yeah.
Well,
just a few years ago,
people who still haven't left a
voicemail,
leaving a voice message.
My shit's always full.
I don't ever.
He still says,
I'm out of the country.
If you know me,
you'll find me.
I don't need that.
You know joey diaz,
you can't even leave a voicemail.
He Beat your ass.
I've made that mistake.
You can't leave a text message either.
You got to call them dog.
I'll see you call me.
I'll call you back when you and when he
calls you,
you got to.
You got to return that call.
Yeah.
There's no like,
I'll get later to get to it later.
He's essentially our dad out of all of
us.
Joey's,
he's the elder statesman for sure.
You know what my phone does now is it
gives me a text of what the voice mail
says.
Yeah.
That's the new thing with iphone.
That's fucking crazy.
It's kinD of weird.
I'm,
I'm switching over.
I'm going to do an experiment for the
podcast.
I'm using a windows laptop and I'm a
trial,
an android phone.
Really?
I'm going to try this new google pixel
phone for a few months.
I'm going to try a windows 10 because I
look at people at the airport and they
have like windows laptops.
I'm like,
what do you do on that thing?
What's happening on that thing?
Is that any different like am I.
Are you experiencing anything that like
these are like 50 percent of the world
interfaces with completely different
devices and then the other 50 percent
got one side.
She was an iphone and max and some.
Some people use iphones and windows.
It is possible but they do sync up well
together,
so oftentimes if somebody has one,
they have the other and then you have
other people that are just using an
android phones and they're using
windows.
Computers were mac,
they can use whatever they want,
but windows.
Computers are a greater percentage of
the people using computers in the world
than anything and when you,
when you look at them,
they look like they look old.
They look like they have new ones now
that look better when you can touch them
and ship.
A lot of them are thick black.
What's the black computer?
That's what I bought.
Well it's silver.
I bought a think paD.
I bought a black thinkpad.
you'd always crazy.
I did this in philly.
I told everyone to put their phones on
the table.
Oh,
you did that thing.
You're only talking about.
No.
I went,
hey,
siri.
Set a reminder to watch bert kreischer
special at 10:00
PM on showtime.
November 11th.
Look at this.
They do it.
I'll remind you.
Whoa.
How fucking crazy
is that?
Well,
that's one of the reasons why I want to
try this google pixel because the google
pixel has this new thing called google
assistant that's supposed to be next
level.
Not only that,
it's contextual,
so like I can say,
hey siri,
call bert kreischer and then.
or it wouldn't be siri.
What's the,
what do you say to the.
It was darrell,
darrell,
daryl.
What up dog?
Hey dude.
How old's bert kreischer?
And then it'll say how old you are,
and then you could say,
where was he born?
And it knows who you're talking about.
And they'll say,
oh,
he was born here.
Really?
Yeah.
What is he?
What?
What have I seen him in?
Well,
if you go to is wikipedia,
you'll shut up.
Siri just keeps me to a website.
No,
next level.
It's contextual.
Meaning it knows what you're talking
about.
Like you can ask someone,
you can go,
okay,
well when's their birthday?
And it'll tell you their birthday.
You don't have to say,
when is burke crisis birthday?
It remembers you talking about for
christ.
That's fucking insane.
The coolest thing about series that I
can just be laying in bed and be like,
hey siri,
set an alarm for 5:00
PM and set an alarm for 5:00
PM.
That's pretty cool.
But you can always just set an alarm,
be lazy.
But nobody,
like if you're laying in bed,
you don't like to get up and swipe and
either your password and find five.
And uh hm.
I can imagine using a regular alarm
clock when I go to a hotel and I see
that stupid thing next to the bed that's
flashing 12,
I go,
what is this dumb thing that I have to
figure out?
Everybody has a phone.
Your phone is gonna.
You're gonna set an alarm on your phone.
Not only that,
your phone knows when you switch into,
um,
daylight savings time and it resets it
for you.
It just happened when I was in New York,
all the clocks were off and I was like,
fuck,
I'm late for the taping,
and then I looked at.
I was like,
oh my phone's fine.
Yeah,
that did it to me on sunday I woke up.
I thought it was late,
but it was actually an hour early.
That was great.
Yeah,
that our sleep,
they should do that every day.
It's something though that we have to
fucking change what time it is because
of when it's dark and when it's light,
so that's one of the reasons why those
people in Alaska superior,
they reached these stretches where it's
never dark.
YeAh.
They have these weird moments in july,
like when ari and I were there and we
went outside,
it was 2:00
in the morning and it was like 6:30
PM out here.
That's also arguably why there's so much
drinking in Russia.
Yes,
because I remember we were there during
the white knights and I remember being
like,
you'd get done your night and you'd be
it's time to go to bed,
but you go out and it'll be fucking
bright out.
You'd like go to your room and you'd
have to close all the blinds to get
dark.
It never got dark.
It's called the white knights.
As long as it lasts.
Twenty four hours a day.
No,
I mean for how,
how long of the year?
Probably I have to ballpark it at maybe
like a week,
maybe two weeks.
You're at nature's whim,
but a week or maybe two weeks,
but then for three months going in,
I'd say maybe maybe a month going in at
a month coming out.
It is.
Well,
like I remember walking around the
streets at like 11:00
at night and it was bright like 5:00
in the afternoon.
Do you remember 30 days and nights?
No,
it's a fucking great vampire movie that
takes place in Alaska.
They,
the vampires arrive in Alaska when it
doesn't get light out for 30 days.
The fuck up dude.
It's fun.
Fucking great that kill the power.
Started eating people and they're cool
vampires speaking some crazy dead
language and they have fucked up teeth.
They don't hAve like straight up vampire
fangs like her mouth is filled with all
these weird jagged tearing teeth.
And you know what I love also about
vampire movies,
vampire familiars,
that bitch cells everybody out.
There's always one dude who's a bitch
who winds up selling everybody out for
the hopes that he close up on that guy's
face.
You get to see what he is.
These vampires look like.
Just go to the full image view image.
Oh,
these aren't big.
Yeah,
there's some pictures.
You'll probably find some.
Find some way you could see how that's
just sloppy.
Sloppy as al jolson.
Hm.
There you can tell.
That's a good one.
That's a perfect one.
So there you go.
That's good.
Costume designer right there.
Fuck yeah.
Or hair,
makeup,
whatever that Is.
That's terrifying.
Yeah.
Tape fletchers in westworld.
He's in everything.
He's.
Have you been watching westworld?
Yes,
I got man.
I fucking geeked out.
I should have texted him or something,
but I'm watching westworld and I see the
guy in the fucking cave.
It was like a god damn fucking tape and
all of a sudden he gets out of the cave
and I'm like,
shut the fuck up that state.
And I'm like losing my fucking mind.
Tate's balling out of control.
So he's working all the time constantly.
Well,
he's got a great look.
There is no,
I'm jealous of his beard.
Strong beard.
It really isn't.
It's got like curls to it.
It's like if it's a perfect beard,
I wish I had the commitment.
He.
Well,
he pulls it off to it,
like it makes him,
it defines him better because this,
this,
that's what it's beards.
Like he's eccentric,
you know,
he's a beautiful eccentric person.
He's someone I was lucky like he's,
he's an example of why I'm happy to have
a podcast because I got,
I heard him on your show and then
reached out to him and so I'd love to
have you on my podcast and then spend
time with them.
And it was like,
I,
I love that guy.
He'S a great guy.
He really is a great fucking guy,
a super positive person,
like super positive,
super loving,
really good friend.
Always,
always love hanging around with and he's
friends with like any letterman.
He'll,
he's friends with a lot of people.
Do you know any comic?
Yeah,
like even got friends with like,
he's got a ton of fucking friends who
doesn't love tate tate's.
Awesome.
Yeah,
we know some good dudes.
Bert kreischer truth we've got to do.
And some good women to morgan murphy.
I'll fucking.
Funny.
Was she last night?
She's hilarious.
She really is.
She's fucking funny man.
I gotta get her on here.
Expose the
world.
She told.
She tweeted last night.
Uh,
I fucking hate the us.
I'm so glad I don't live there.
Hashtag [inaudible] los angeles.
And then right after that I started
noticing that cal exit.
Cal exit.
It's like the brexit bill.
They want California to separate.
Hilarious.
We're the sixth largest economy in the
world.
And so they,
they're like,
we could just separate and we'd be on
fucking trump.
Yeah.
Oh,
that's funny.
And then he was going to.
When Jerry Brown,
he's going to be our king.
That crazy assholes for today.
God will bring him back.
I'm back.
Yeah,
man.
Given full reign to look dude.
The best.
His last night when everyone started
admitting to having crushes on morgan
murphy.
I didn't see that part.
Oh,
that must've been when you were doing
your set.
Probably,
yeah.
Someone was like,
standup goes.
I just got to admit I've always had a
crush on morgan murphy and then someone
else goes a me too,
and I was like,
I'm married and I have a hardcore
corazon morgan murphy,
and morgan was like,
I don't know what to make of any of you
fucking drunks.
She was probably trying to avoid a gang
bang by negotiation.
Yeah,
she's great man.
She really is funny.
Do you remember what she did that?
That carloS garcia?
Yes.
How fucking funny was that?
Say the rest.
Say what?
It was sheet right after the beef broke
out where he was stealing and he got
caught.
By the way,
this is crazy.
I didn't know that happened in the olr.
Yeah,
I thought it happened in the main room
immediately.
I'm watching it because I never been a
club like that.
Um,
but she then said a carlos men's dia
stole from me too,
and she's
team that I made in 1939,
something like that.
And then she writes something like that,
something ridiculous like that.
And then she went into his bits,
but she did them all like she took his
worst material and did it super dead
pan.
Hello,
my name is morgan murphy.
I performed the jokes you're about to
see in the year 19,
23 cars.
See over for them in 2006 judge for
yourself.
But I certainly see similarities.
I worked very hard in this material,
specifically the line,
if you don't chill,
you're going to get it.
Morgan,
you don't chIli,
you're going to get it.
So how do we organize these podcast so
we do more of those live podcasts.
And when do we do?
How often do we do,
what do we call it?
I was just keep calling it the end of
the world called the end of the world
pug guests.
Yeah,
it's the end of the world.
The other world podcast is just the end
of the world and we're going to do,
we'll do live ones like we did last
night and we'll do them on a regular
basis.
Do it once a month,
do you think?
Yeah,
but next time we do it,
we can't just have people just walking
in and sitting down and grabbing
microphones.
It was just too many people as it is and
like burger got interrupted a bunch of
times.
Then fights broke out between people
that weren't even supposed to be there
and people that we want it to be there.
SO we'll fix that next time
we get stand up to come in once a month.
He'll do.
He loves being here.
He loves.
He flies in johnny lives right down the
street.
Fucking pop in there.
Yeah.
It doesn't happen again.
Have an apartment here.
Having good housing has stayed in homes.
Old apartment.
Yeah.
So
they'll,
he'll be here all the tIme,
but we could do those dude anytime we
want.
And we call him the end of the world
once a month.
Yeah.
Fuck.
The last time was so much fun and when
stan hope read that note at the
beginning where,
you know,
he was like,
he was panicking about it and it was
really
for worried and then I was like,
come on man,
it's just going to be easy.
Your response was perfect.
It's just,
it's just,
hey man,
don't worry.
We'll just hang out and talk.
We'll get fucked up.
Enjoy it.
Yeah,
easy.
This is going to be easy.
I think I,
man,
I'm,
I'm an end of the year podcast.
Once a month I'm fucking in.
Yeah.
Even if maybe not once a month,
man,
maybe we do it quarterly,
you know,
get people jazzed up for it.
Prime people up and have some reason to
do it.
You know,
we could do a gang of those.
Those are so fun.
And again,
it's one of those things were all
together like that.
We all just start making each other
laugh.
Like when we were laughing at burger,
you could see burst out ramping it up.
Like,
cause he,
he's got an audience of his friends too,
you know,
so we got all excited,
got to get ds on.
Ds was supposed to come by last night
but I think he had a spot somewhere at
10 and then was going to shoot over
there afterwards,
but it probably went long but you know,
it's hard to get him to go out when he
doesn't want it.
We'll just do,
we'll do it the wAy we like that.
It was the way it was supposed to go to
that site,
which is like we got the core of like
four guys or three guys,
four guys and then and throw out some
Invites to guys that we know that will
be fun on there.
Like jim jefferies shown up was great.
Minus the kids were like,
I wish you were looking at each other.
Like,
what in the fuck is going on here?
Is that a baby?
But jim was so confused.
He's like,
would be a good idea.
Yeah,
I'm down for a lot of stuff,
but I think I'm less the better
honestly.
I think for people's,
the maximum.
I think we were way over the top
yesterday,
you know,
and at times it was so difficult for
people,
not everything.
We did a great job considering of not
talking over each other,
but it was really hard.
Like there was a lot of times people
start a rant and someone would just shit
candidate and dive right into the rant
and then they would have to try to
restart the rant and then someone else
would recognize there is a weakness and
they try to step into and it's like,
oh,
this is bad.
That's what you need.
You need guys that are good at that.
I'm not saying that.
I'm not saying I'm perfect at it.
I definitely have flaws,
but like I will promise you when I got
on that stage I was like,
I was not there to interrupt joe,
bill,
greg or doug.
I just.
No one's trying to do it.
It's just like you might have something
really fun and to say and you've feel
like you've got it to get it out now,
but someone else still talking and
you're like,
fuck,
when is this guy gonna talk.
And then three other people are waiting
to talk like,
fuck,
I'm not gonna be able to get this out.
I'm gonna forgeT it.
It's hard.
And,
and,
and noticing when you go,
oh there's a punchline right there.
But in my head I go,
bird,
have you recognize that when you also
enjoy to hear what greg fitzsimmons take
on that very recognizable punchline will
be because it would be better than yours
maybe.
Maybe or you know,
either way he's talking,
you know,
like let them,
let them rent it out.
There's worse than someone
waiting while you're ranting because
then you feel them waiting and they're
like,
but it's,
it's,
it,
it.
And you're still doing it.
Like,
hey you're,
you're,
you're trying to dance with me,
motherfucker.
You're trying to step in on the dance,
you know?
And when you're in mid stride it's hard,
you know,
and the,
the person around you have to kind of
recognize that.
And one of the big differences,
the difference between someone who's
talking to you and with you,
like some people just talking to you and
they're waiting for their chance.
Like when you're done talking,
then I'm going to talk and some people
are talking with you like you're
talking,
and then they go,
oh,
okay.
And then they start asking you
questions,
they're talking with you and they might
have a rant and they might not.
They might have something funny to say
and they might not,
But they're having a conversation with
you that's way easier to listen to see
when people just start talking at each
other and they're not listening to the
other person that just waiting.
We're all guilty that sometimes
sometimes he fucking zone out,
you know,
when you're talking to people,
but if you,
if you're not engaged,
the people listening are going to be
aware of that too.
So it's going to be weird to listen to.
Yeah.
It would be weird to listen to.
I can't wonky.
I can't wait to listen to the podcast.
It's up right now.
Uh,
the youtube versions up.
Is the itunes version up?
No,
it's still rendering.
Okay.
We're going to upload it when this
podcast,
make sure it's up by tomorrow morning.
So I want to listen to all my flight.
I'm going to be pissing myself.
We'll have it up tonight.
Where are you flying?
Baltimore.
Oh shit.
Wait,
what are you doing out there?
I'm doing the comedy factory.
What does that.
Whereas I don't know.
You're gonna.
Have to google it guys.
Oh,
what'd already Just say?
I'll have my boy john rollo come visit
you.
Holy shit.
Ladies and gentlemen,
don't know.
I wouldn't say this out loud,
but this is our last podcast.
Take a look at that.
You can't say it out loud.
I mean,
I can.
I don't think he.
I don't know if he doesn't mind sharing
his numbers.
Oh,
he's just trying to pull those numbers
up.
No,
his.
That's what his downloads are for 16
hours.
That's pretty amazing.
That's fucking amazing.
Yeah.
Guys going already podcast.
If you're ever curious of me and our fat
shaming,
like,
oh,
this is the most recent one that you
guys did together as a middle already
did want an ra.
And I said,
made a bet me aryan.
And uh,
tommy made a bet by January 3rd.
We did our bmr and tom and I both
registered obese.
So.
So,
but tom's lying About his height,
but regardless he,
he's fucking five,
nine.
He says he's six foot.
He's like,
I'm six foot and a half.
You.
He's six foot jamie.
No,
right up next to me.
He's close,
but no,
no,
no.
You ever hung out with tom?
You tower over,
you know?
Exactly.
But he's taller than me.
I'm telling you.
Five,
five,
eight,
eight.
He's probably five,
10 minutes,
man.
I think he's.
He might be six feet.
It's possible.
I just don't see tommy line about
anything,
but he knows he's.
Oh,
he's done.
He's an ally.
It's a misinformation.
He feeds for himself to make himself
feel better.
Same way.
He says that I'm fat and he's skinny.
No,
no,
no.
He's really honest about that.
He even says like,
when this first started,
he goes,
who is fatter?
Me or,
or bert?
He's
like,
you said this on [inaudible] podcast.
That's another one.
And he was like me for sure.
Right.
And he's like,
yeah.
He goes,
that's what I think.
I was definitely faster than him.
He goes,
but he's faster than me now.
No,
we're the same weight right now.
We're the exact same way.
Right,
but you might be built different than
him.
He,
yes.
He has a cop body and I have more like
an olympic athlete in the thirties cop
buddy.
And so,
so a girl.
So we.
Our bed is ari.
Ari said that neither of us could get to
just simply being overweight on the bmi
scale.
You could definitely do that.
Just took to 25.
If you listen to me,
I can get you down to almost nothIng
done.
That's it.
What would you want away?
Like ideally what would you want to
away?
It was funny because tom said,
you know,
we should be weighing like one 92 that I
would look ridiculous.
My head will look huge.
Huge.
That is a weird thing that happens to
people when they gain weight.
Your head gets bigger.
Yeah.
My.
Oh,
do I have a size?
Hey,
have you ever seen up in my head is so I
can look at it right now.
No,
no,
no.
Put my hat on fuel.
How big that had is.
Well,
this is the amount of space between his
hat and my head is fucking ridiculous.
Look at this dude.
This like several inches.
Yeah,
like look at this.
I have a massive head look at this space
we're talking about here.
That's crazy in my head.
I mean,
I'm like,
no exaggeration.
It's a solid inch all around the front.
Yeah,
and so that's crazy.
You're giant.
I wouldn't like smarter.
How can we not smarter?
My mom says I am not tapping into it.
Maybe that's what the booze is.
You'll like too much information.
Smart.
I want to take a break.
I got my high school entrance,
exam number it registered.
I wanT to take my high school entrance
exam again and see if I've gotten dumber
or smarter or you definitely dumber for
sure.
You know,
it's not that you're dumber so you
forget all the stuff that you had to
remember eyes from.
I don't remember anything about
calculus.
You put a division problem in front of
me or percentage or imagine if your
brain kept growing and you have an issue
and she had it.
You got to kill brain cells by drinking
in order to keep your head from pressing
up the brain,
from pressing up against the side of
your head,
by the only way you can get past that is
to just fucking get hammered every
night.
And if you don't,
you have massive headaches or panic
attacks because that's what I'm saying.
Maybe that's what's going on in your
head is so big and your brain inside of
it keeps growing and that's why your
booze in it.
You just saw trying to kill the weeds,
kill the weeds in the feeling that makes
me feel lonely and kill all that stuff.
So anyway,
here's the bet with me and ren tommy.
So we're going to get just to just to
overweight,
which is like 2:25.
Why don't you guys just get healthy.
We're going to try.
But why do you say that?
You can do it.
I can do it.
I definitely Hundred percent.
You could do it.
Totally can do it.
So why don't you just do it.
I am doing it.
I'm doing it right now.
Do it right now.
Yeah.
You have three,
four,
four that's not doing it well.
Yeah.
Not right now.
None of those are diet.
These records,
these were extras and I don't know what
extra.
What is the difference?
Not really,
but anyway,
so here's the beto.
If rei,
if tom and I can get to under obese,
then already has to pay for a trip that
the three of us will take.
If tom or I can't get to under obese,
whoever can't or if both of us can,
then we've got to pay for the three of
us to go on a trip.
Who?
I like it.
Yeah.
You want to be in the bet?
Nope.
No,
I wouldn't bet against either one of
you.
I tried to help.
What would my diabete ketosis?
Yeah,
for sure.
One hundred percent and no sugar.
No alcohol?
No.
Exactly.
So you want to do it sunday?
I'm starting.
I'm starting a diet.
So you drinking is to squash anxiety?
Yeah,
for me,
mostly like when I'm on the road,
I'm not someone who can Just like chill.
I cannot just sit in a hotel room and
just sit there.
Like when I get off stage and I'm,
by the way,
and this sounds,
this is gonna sound like a lie,
but like I,
I don't really drink on stage.
I bring a drink on stage for the first
show.
I don't touch it cause I'm talking for
an hour.
I'm the only one talking.
Um,
I don't drink in between shows.
On the second show I'll definitely have
a drink,
but that's now that's one drink probably
I've had throughout the whole night.
So at midnight when I'm done working I'm
like,
I'm going to,
I'm going to have a couple beers because
I'm done working.
And then I'm like,
well I'm not going to go fucking sit in
my room sober.
I mean that's what I should do.
But like I definitely.
So you hit that minibar?
No,
no,
but I'll just sit at the club,
the club and have a few drinks and then
go back to my room.
Not fucking plastered but definitely
with definitely with probably 600 more
calories than I should have had.
And that's where the weight loss when I
stopped drinking,
it literally tears off of me.
Now.
How,
how long have you not drank?
Four.
What's the longest time?
I just didn't.
Wasn't drinking for three weeks.
How much weight you lose?
Uh,
I got down to three to 30 to 35 was the
lowest I got,
but I wasn't really working out at the
time.
How much weight do you usually way right
now I'm 2:42.
So he lost about 10 pounds or 10 pounds.
Eight to 10.
Just not doing anything.
I didn't even change my diet.
I was eating like shit,
but I stopped drinking just because we
were going under a renovation and a and
I was getting the allergies and I got
sick and I was like,
hey,
I'm not going to drink.
I want to get healthy.
So I didn't drink and I wasn't smoking
pot.
And then all of a sudden I was like,
this is boring.
I know shit.
Like I'm imagining.
Imagine watching a marching band,
but they don't have the instruments.
They just play the tape.
What I like is long periods of sobriety
followed by pot.
Like when I,
when I take a long time off,
like many days off and then I'll smoke a
little weed,
then I go on like adventures.
Yeah.
I can go on an adventure of the mind or
I'll go on a hike,
you know?
I like to get fucked up and go on and
walk up hills and shit like that really.
And when I don't do it for awhile and
then I do it,
then I get a different feeling out of
it.
Yesterday was the
first time I smoked pot in probably
three months.
Really?
It must have hit you so much.
Fucking fun.
That was good.
It was so much fun that I,
I remember sitting on stage.
It was really interesting.
I had like a very surreal moment was
sitting on stage and looking at the
light and look into people going,
you know what man?
this is.
Why would anyone not love this drug?
This is pure joy.
I'm happy.
I feel confident.
They feel good about myself.
Makes you friendly.
Yeah.
And it makes you a little anxious
sometimes.
What it does do that,
right?
I'll give you a little bit of anxiety or
a little bit of paranoia.
Yeah,
but yeah,
the three weeks was recent.
I didn't drink and but I wasn't working
out because I was sick so I.
But I just lost like eight pounds not
doing anything and eating kind of
shitty.
Yeah.
I don't know what to tell you
because if you keep,
if you want to drink all the time it's
going to be super hard to lose rate for
real.
But if you could go back to that,
go back to not drinking.
If you think you could perform and have
a good time and be you and you
definitely could.
I don't.
I don't have a problem performing
without alcohol at all.
No,
no,
no.
After the show.
But even then,
I mean if you just decided you wanted to
step away from that,
you could totally do it.
I would like to.
I would really,
really genuinely love to be able to
smoke pot by myself in a hotel room and
not lose my fucking mind.
What about candy?
Like pot cAndy,
like a small dose man.
I've done it and I sit in the,
I'm sitting on the couch and I'm stone
sober.
I'm like,
this is going to be my transition to
relaxing,
and then all of a sudden I feel my
asshole so mesh into the couch and I'm
like,
I ate too much,
and then I'm like,
okay,
I can't breathe.
All right.
You know what?
I'm going down to the bar,
I'm getting a glass of wine and I'm
going to fucking relax.
And then you down and you're weird and
some lady sits next to you.
Yeah.
Let's talk to you.
Do you think someone sneezes and you
say,
god bless you and now you live here.
You're christian.
Get nervous.
Ranya.
Yeah.
Xanax would be the alternative.
That's the.
That was my old school way of like,
just going back,
taking a half a xanax and going to sleep
or an ambien,
but that's fucking drugs.
I mean there's,
it's the same.
Same.
Mmm.
I know adults like several adults that
take adderall and ambien all the time.
A lot.
yeah.
That's the combo.
Parents as a combo,
and these guy lIke this guy,
if you knew him,
you know,
very uh,
successful tech guy,
you know,
he's one of those tech guys and he's
taken adderall every fucking day.
Takes it every day.
It gives me an edge and then he goes to
sleep.
Say I take a sleeping pill.
My,
a guy who used to work with,
used to take my daffodil every day.
Modafinil is interesting.
I've taken that before many times I've
taken,
it's called new vigil,
new visuals,
new reverse this provigil and nuvigil
haven't taken it to take it pro vigil
once,
I don't remember,
but I've taken new vigil several times
and it's weird because it doesn't pick
you up like a speed.
It's not like caffeine.
You have a crazy buzz,
but it's like you're awake,
you're like tuned into things.
It's actually,
it's illegal in the olympics.
So yeah.
Yeah.
So it has some of performance benefits
to it and apparently I might be
spreading disinformation near,
but that's nothing new.
Um,
google tHis for yourself if you want
verification.
Apparently it was invented as a
performance enhancing drug,
but they had to give it some sort of a
medical reason that we would take it and
they said a narcolepsy because it kind
of keeps you awake,
keeps you fired up.
But fighter pilots like it.
Apparently jimmy kimmel,
jimmy kimmel takes it.
Yeah.
Maybe that's,
by the way,
that's a rumor bro.
Information bros,
but bro science.
But uh,
yeah,
I've heard that he's narcoleptic and he
takes really a comedian that's
narcoleptic imagine that you're on stage
this,
but they'll
not to fall in the sleep in the middle
of one of his monologues,
you know,
hitting your fucking head,
falling down and hitting your head is no
joke.
That was the hillary clinton story from
2012.
That's also what happened at bingo.
Bingo.
Had some sort of a seizure recently and
fell and hit her head and she's in
really dire straits and stan hope I
think is flying back to her now,
but he was,
it was one of the reasons why he was
probably like a wee bit hostile this
tuesday.
He pulled me aside and when I got there
and he was like,
I'm barely holding it together.
Yeah.
He was like,
if we have a safe word,
if you noticed it to say,
hey,
doug could use a shot.
Yeah.
I mean he's keeping together better than
a lot of people would know much better
than me.
Yeah.
Love that guy.
I really loved that guy.
Alright.
So we committed to it the end of the
world.
So we'll do the end of the world.
Like we'll do it with four people.
Will do it every couple months and
we'll,
we'll swap people out.
Yeah,
that'd be the end of the world.
The other world life in the store
already.
I think we did three and a half hours.
Dude.
Shut the fuck up.
Are you serious?
Five?
Yeah.
Five 10.
Holy shit.
Yeah,
it's five.
Oh,
five per crash your friday night.
La machine.
November 11,
10:00
PM.
Show time.
Do not.
Fuck this up folks.
Set that dvr.
goddammit.
Get on please.
Please get on it when you guys were cool
as fuck.
Promoting it all throughout the podcast
last night.
Oh my pleasure.
My friend.
I know it's going to be hilarious.
I'm excited that you did it too.
I'm really excited that you're spending
more time and stand up.
You know,
I just think,
uh,
well it's like we were saying about your
show.
Your show is fun and I love doing it,
but you almost like not tap into your
potential as a comic because you're so
funny.
You got to do it right.
We have to do it.
So you don't forget to put in the work.
Yes.
Anything else telling these people about
a bird cast on twItter?
Yeah,
I got my,
like ari and I had been talking numbers
a lot.
And so for those of you who don't know,
rem in our texting our first day numbers
to each other just because we are full
fucking disclosure.
that's a beautiful thing about the
friendships I've had based on meeting
you.
A lot of my friends,
we tell each other how much we make.
We tell each other what our numbers are,
we so that we don't get fucked or they
can get better things all.
Yeah.
You got to be honest too.
It's like I think it's important like,
dude,
I did not sell good in cleveland or
something about cleveland or pittsburgh
was rough for me.
We opened up our lives in,
in front of each other and go through
our podcast and oh,
you had him.
You didn't do well with him.
How come I wonder why your numbers were
low on him?
Well,
what's really cool about podcast as
opposed to you might as well just keep
that song.
I'm just slightly lightly as opposed to
anything else is the numbers are so
hardcore.
Whereas like you get like ratings,
like,
oh,
we have a one point five on the
nielsens.
You don't even really know how many
people that is just guessing based on
this algorithm.
They created over a very small amount of
houses.
It's not that many people you're pulling
from.
It's certainly not 100 percent.
When you're getting a podcast and you
see that number,
that is a hundred percent of the people
that have downloaded it.
One hundred percent.
There's no if,
ands or buts.
it's very.
I mean,
some of them might have downloaded it
twice if they're crazy,
but for the most part,
without whatever percentage you have
that are repeats for most part,
that's unique people.
Yeah.
Uh,
tommy and I taught me,
me and you alWays talk about this and
they're the ones who said you need to
really focus on your podcast.
You're slipping on your podcast.
So I picked it out.
Every wednesday I focused on the guests.
I only get guests I want to talk to that
I'm interested in now I don't do
bullshit like,
oh,
he seems one of whatever.
Just get.
I need a guest.
I do guests I want and I released on
wednesday and man,
my numbers have a have tripled in,
in like five months and ari's numbers
are going through the roof.
Tom's numbers are fucking sick right
now.
Yeah.
Podcasts are exploding and we can people
reach your podcast.
How bert [inaudible] dot com.
Just a just type in broadcast.com.
And I'm going to step up my next.
I'm gonna step up to the next level,
step it up to the next level.
That's far.
I'm going,
I'm gonna.
I gotta get.
I gotta get a jamie.
You got to get a job and a studio.
Yeah,
I would love to get a fucking studio
studio.
Would love to get a studio.
Oh,
I'd love to get a fucking studio.
I need a fucking studio.
Needs a studio.
All right folks,
we'll be back.
This weekend is a ufc,
so I'm gone.
Have a good time and see you soon.
Guests next week.
So say bye.
That.