The Joe Rogan experience,
man,
when I,
when I used to make it taste good,
but now I don't even make the gel shake
taste good anymore.
Now I'm going to slam.
It just tastes terrible because I'd give
a giant chunks of ginger and garlic now
like I'll have like a,
like seriously?
Remember what pagers used to look like?
A chunk of ginger.
Just fucking camera shake.
Put in one shake.
You slammed that Ninja turtles have
about half of that in a week.
Shake.
Oh really?
No.
I slam it.
Slam it in four or five cloves of
garlic.
Smells so bad afterwards.
Smelling like garlic can take for sure.
Well,
good jokes man.
I smell
like garlic.
Just train you.
No,
just uh,
just ate some garlic loads.
Yeah.
Become horrible.
Let me know.
Next time you're in the
tests and mood to make a video
to youtube hits off of that.
All you'd have to do.
It's just I would come on the desk and
just dip your finger and go like that.
That's all you would have to do.
It's over
the you youtube would break.
I'm sure you've got the curdled kind
where you could just pick up.
No,
my login.
Very normal,
fertile time.
This shit took a lot of water,
dude.
Oh,
that's true.
Healthy.
My loads of quite fluid taste like
garlic and this is back at the academy.
Male crew right here.
Imagine if dudes or chicks,
whereas women have a certain amount of
eggs and then that's it.
It's over.
Imagine if dudes were like that.
We have a certain amount of loads.
You're like checking.
You pulled your balls up the sun to see
like where your load line is.
A lot of people that have to do.
A lot of people would have blue balls,
that's for sure.
The next day.
Oh Wow.
Girls would be like,
come on,
give me some low.
You're not worth it.
You're not worth.
It.
Should become until like a gambling
rational thing.
Guys would go in and they'd go,
tantric where you squeeze it down to
orgasm.
If that was the tip of your Dick and
like a lighter,
and if that was a case that was the
case,
guys would have more power and getting
laid.
That's true.
On the girls side of it,
you know,
like it's easy for easier for a girl,
it'd be a whole lot easier for a guy if
you had so many innocent.
If we all fucking band together,
we can make
this.
It's to start this right now with the
podcast.
Podcast is powerful to have a Dick
Union.
Take back your loads.
Save him.
It's important.
Not valued right now in the equation,
but dammit,
they should be stopped wasting them.
It's a key ingredient and making people.
Oh Man.
Without the loads.
You got nothing.
That's the problem though is that would
be like starting a fighters' union.
Like that's not really going to happen,
you know,
but just dude's like fuck them.
That's what dudes would say when it
comes to the Deq Union.
If we all got together and said,
listen,
we're gonna,
we're gonna.
We need to make our dicks more valuable.
Okay.
We need to make it harder to get to.
Let's work something out here.
Boys.
The first ones are going to sacrifice
big time and the ones that are starting
this thing because now they're the only
ones not getting laid.
You just start this whole trend,
you know,
same as with the fighter union.
You only one not getting paid.
I think you're right though.
It is really tough.
It's hard.
It's easy to say,
oh,
the voters are lazy or whatever they
should do,
but honestly,
like you said,
they got real lives to live and I
haven't got time for all this stuff and
that is a really big part of why we want
to make it simple.
You know,
we're assuming that people want to spend
less time doing this stuff,
not more time and I think a lot of the
kind of,
um,
organizations and people that have tried
to get people mobilized,
you know,
civic organization and the kind of
thing,
you know,
it's,
it's worked to a certain extent with
some people,
but for the majority of people they just
don't want to do it.
They can't do it actually.
There literally too busy with things
that are higher priorities,
like their kids and their family and
their job or whatever it may be.
Hobbies doesn't matter.
It's stuff that they choose to do and
that's fine.
That's their life and we shouldn't kind
of require that you have to spend ages
figuring out this political stuff and
that's why we're trying to make it
really simple for people,
but based on quite a lot of compost and
that's what technology allows you to do.
You can take quite a lot of complex data
and information like we're doing with
the campaign finance records where it's
literally hundreds of millions of pieces
of information and we're boiling it down
into one piece of information which is a
score like where is this candidate on
the.
On the scale of liberal to conservative,
where do they sit and where are they on
each issue?
That's what we're trying to do to make
it really simple.
Isn't it sort of analogous in a way to
what we were talking about about the
amount of people that you can keep in
your brain.
Dunbar's number is that if you lived in
a small tribe,
if safe,
we all live 50 of us together in some
small village somewhere.
We really wouldn't have votes about gay
marriage and we really wouldn't have
coats about could be a million different
things that would never be up for vote
and if someone really did start micro
managing everyone's lives,
you'd be.
You'd be like,
Hey,
you know,
Mike is an asshole.
We got to kick him out of his fucking
tribe.
This guy's trying to get people to wear
purple and you know,
where certain Nike's during different
moon cycles and make tribal rules and
rituals and make all these things
standard and you know,
for whatever reason he doesn't like men
sleeping with men.
Like he's got some weird thing.
You know,
he believes it's so true.
I just so agree with that.
One of my favorite things that I'm one
of these experiments that was in
Holland,
I think I've got that right in in,
in Europe and they did this brilliant
experiment with traffic where they are
in a town,
I think it was friesland or something
like that,
probably got that wrong where they
literally took away all the traffic
signals,
all of them,
everything,
right?
They took away traffic lights.
They even took you stop signs,
everything,
even the,
the markings on the road.
So they took away the white line in the
middle of the road,
everything all gone and their theory was
that without that kind of external rule
making and kind of stuff going on to
tell you what to do,
people would have to kind of relate to
each other as other people and just
figure it out amongst themselves.
So they would,
um,
you know,
have to look other people in the eye and
sort of work it out between them.
And they found they had this brilliant
effect,
which was the,
um,
accidents felt a zero.
The traffic improve,
the traffic speed was lower,
but the traffic flow was much better.
It just worked all around.
All the kinds of things that you try and
do when all these people thinking about
traffic planning and whatever.
They achieved those aims by literally
taking everything away and just allowing
people to relate to each other as
humans.
And was.
I thought it was such a great little
story and I think that you could do that
in all sorts of areas.
If you just leave it to people to figure
out on a small scale where they can
relate to each other,
you just get a much better result.